<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-20T13:51:07-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T13:51:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T13:51:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to stop a hate raid</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D5etykSdhcvMCO6XEjJmbMWHqtE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69754143/acastro_210115_1777_twitch_hate_raid_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SXcJQ2"&gt;Hate raids happen with little warning. A streamer will get a follow notification and instead of feeling joy that a new person has joined their community, dread sets in as their chat suddenly erupts into an uncontrollable geyser of hateful messages. Hate raids have infested Twitch over the last few weeks, primarily targeting marginalized streamers making life on the platform so miserable many are considering abandoning it altogether. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uqmm1W"&gt;Twitch has promised &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620874/twitch-implements-improved-chat-filters"&gt;new safety features are in the works&lt;/a&gt;, but streamers are upset and angry that more hasn’t been done to stop hate raids. Streamers are using the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23twitchdobetter&amp;amp;src=typed_query"&gt;#twitchdobetter&lt;/a&gt; hashtag to agitate for change, and they are creating and sharing resources to protect themselves against the seemingly endless tide of trolls bombarding streamers with racist, transphobic, and ableist messages. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with the streamers and Twitch community members taking the safety of marginalized creators into their own hands about the tools they’ve created to do battle against the trolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AKtq5U"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If Twitch Ambassadors aren’t safe, who can be?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dcCIoj"&gt;Raids are a normal part of Twitch culture and happen when a user on Twitch sends their viewers to another streamer, usually as a show of support. Every Twitch streamer is competing for more eyeballs on their channel, and raids are a way to spread the wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hU3Cj1"&gt;Hate raids are when people use the raid mechanism to abuse a streamer. Instead of another user’s organic audience, a streamer’s chat is flooded with hateful messages from bot accounts. Hate raids are difficult to deal with since a streamer or their mods have to ban hundreds of fake, bot-generated accounts at a time, slowing down the normal, everyday process of chat management. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Qo1Yb"&gt;To combat this, streamers are creating what they’re calling a “panic button” — a string of chat commands that are executed all at once at the press of a single button. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke to &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/queerlybee"&gt;Bee&lt;/a&gt;, a Twitch streamer who has experience with this “panic button” setup, to explain what it does and how streamers can use it to protect themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rMsYKU"&gt;“It’s a multifunction button on my &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22579144/elgato-stream-deck-mk-2-stand-faceplates-usb-c-valve"&gt;Elgato Stream Deck&lt;/a&gt; that disabled the alert box, disables on-stream chat, clears chat, switches to sub-only mode, creates a stream marker, slows chat down, and plays ads,” Bee says. “I also then have a reverse button to undo those actions for when things have calmed down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Seg8lI"&gt;For users who don’t have fancy equipment, Twitch streamer &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/EarthToBre"&gt;EarthtoBre&lt;/a&gt; created a program that does the same thing using &lt;a href="https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/lioranboard-stream-deck-animator.862/"&gt;Lioranboard&lt;/a&gt; — a free stream management tool that works similar to the Stream Deck. &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@earthtobre/video/6989351750478138630"&gt;She even made a tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LFEMkZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@earthtobre/video/6989351750478138630" data-video-id="6989351750478138630" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;"&gt; &lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@earthtobre" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@earthtobre"&gt;@earthtobre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;Reply to @pixeldaddie Trolls Be Gone button, but make it FREE!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - EarthToBre" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6989351668534020869"&gt;♬ original sound - EarthToBre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MmUL9y"&gt;Streamer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JustMeEmilyP"&gt;JustMeEmilyP&lt;/a&gt; took the response to combating hate raids a step further by creating a &lt;a href="https://hateraidresponse.carrd.co/"&gt;Hate Raid Response&lt;/a&gt; website full of useful tools like how to program a “panic button” and tips on what to do before, during, and after a hate raid occurs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rX3L8F"&gt;The Hate Raid Response website was created in January, long before this most recent hate raid boom. JustMeEmilyP told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; she actually created the website in anticipation of Black History Month, when Twitch promotes black streamers and consequently makes them targets for racist trolls. She saw anxiety from Black streamers ahead of Black History Month and acted accordingly. At first, the Discord she set up was relatively quiet and the resources were lightly used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Amvam"&gt;“That’s where we kind of sat all year until &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RekItRaven"&gt;Raven&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/08/11/twitch-do-better-hate-raids/"&gt;started #TwitchDoBetter&lt;/a&gt;. Folks came rushing in,” JustMeEmilyP says. “The hashtag has been a blessing because even the most veteran [streamers] among us have learned this past week!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tndKr2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CommanderRoot"&gt;CommanderRoot&lt;/a&gt; created a tool that lets users &lt;a href="https://twitch-tools.rootonline.de/follower_remover.php#"&gt;block or ignore followers en masse&lt;/a&gt;. Combine this program with &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/hackbolt"&gt;Hackbolt&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/19l_9rcxS6VSVka2WqvcjRbEDSPacEdKa/edit#gid=1331099117"&gt;Bots n Bigots&lt;/a&gt; spreadsheet that is a constantly updated catalogue of bots known to be involved in hate raids, and streamers can fight back. But increasingly, streamers are wondering why they have to fight in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FOyiRJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Hate raids makes marginalized content creators nervous.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kmBsFj"&gt;Hate raids aren’t a new phenomenon, but their recent explosion across the platform is causing anxiety and anger in the Black, trans, queer, and disabled creators they target because it seems that Twitch, knowing of this endemic problem, hasn’t done enough to stop them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7yZ6nS"&gt;“If [Twitch] Ambassadors aren’t safe, who can be,” asks Tanya C. DePass, founder of the non-profit I Need Diverse Games and the creative director of the RPG &lt;em&gt;Into The Motherlands&lt;/em&gt;. “[Twitch] can’t keep minority streamers safe. Why should we keep creating content on a platform that isn’t going to at least update and show as if they are working on something as a measure until a more permanent solution can be implemented?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sDIUPn"&gt;A lot of the resources being used to combat hate raids are shared on Twitter and in Discords with the attitude of, “If Twitch won’t do it, we will.” When Twitch announced a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1428476525570056202"&gt;Public Access Channel&lt;/a&gt; show on Twitter in the midst of the #twitchdobetter movement, the replies were filled with people complaining about what they saw as Twitch ignoring the problem to instead promote their products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ei7wM"&gt;But a spokesperson for Twitch confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that tools are in the works that will hopefully address this problem. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1425550620887375876"&gt;Twitch’s statement&lt;/a&gt; after the #twitchdobetter hashtag started gaining popularity alludes to solutions like improved account verification and ban evasion detectors. Twitch also has &lt;a href="https://safety.twitch.tv/s/article/Managing-Harassment?language=en_US"&gt;a page dedicated to offering tools&lt;/a&gt; to help streamers fight harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4R4zYR"&gt;But the promise of help to come doesn’t do much to combat what streamers are facing right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CvAdGc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Content Warning: Racial slurs)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7nRohq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Only took 7 hours but we did it yall!&lt;br&gt;Completed the Hard R speedrun at 100%&lt;br&gt;Thank you Twitch for making this all possible!&lt;br&gt;Couldn't do it without you!!!!&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TwitchDoBetter?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TwitchDoBetter&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/oMo6y3PcZV"&gt;pic.twitter.com/oMo6y3PcZV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— hymn (@visecs) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/visecs/status/1428164099167473666?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="5z6YUB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;So, streamed today. Chill BG3, no cam, just mic. And you guessed it! Attempted hate raid, AGAIN. CW: Nazi imagery in the screenshots below. So &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Twitch&lt;/a&gt; what y'all doin' about this? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Who else wants to ask if it's racially motivated. Who? &lt;a href="https://t.co/4ty5IejJ7v"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4ty5IejJ7v&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Cypher | Watch Game Changer on #BETHerTV (@cypheroftyr) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cypheroftyr/status/1427665867752579084?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e5VMNr"&gt;Images like the above are becoming all too common, and aside from the obvious distress such attacks can cause, there are other, more insidious ways hate raids are affecting streamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yGSJzd"&gt;“It makes marginalized content creators nervous,” says &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NYMG_saffista"&gt;Dr. Saffista&lt;/a&gt;, a games academic who streams as community outreach and research. “And in that trepidation they are either not streaming, putting things into place that ultimately limit community building and growth, or become so nervous every time their alerts go off that they are ‘off their game.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q1fp0a"&gt;Indeed, some of the solutions to hate raids are not tools streamers typically use. According to Twitch culture, such limitations (like turning on subscriber-only mode — a mode that limits who can speak in chat to those who have subscribed to the channel — or limiting chat to emotes only) inhibit a channel’s ability to grow. So this epidemic of hate raids has a one-two punch effect of harassing an already vulnerable group of people &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; making it that much harder for marginalized streamers to have the same kinds of success cis het white men (a demographic curiously unaffected by the recent rash of hate raids) have had on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gq4r1l"&gt;For the casual viewer interested in helping, there is a &lt;a href="https://www.change.org/p/amazon-twitch-do-better-stop-hate-raids-against-people-of-color-and-marginalized-creators"&gt;change.org petition&lt;/a&gt; and concerned Twitch users can always continue to support marginalized creators and uplift their voices when these things happen and in general. The tools outlined here will help streamers prepare for the possibility of a hate raid. Hopefully, they won’t need them for too much longer.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22633874/how-to-stop-a-hate-raid-twitch-safety-tools"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22633874/how-to-stop-a-hate-raid-twitch-safety-tools</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T13:44:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T13:44:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best smartphone you can buy for under $500</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cZYqwTfbX2vk4FqDWTzaFfIYSDU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67732462/vpavic_200805_4131_0086_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;You can get a great smartphone at this price, whether you want an iPhone, a big screen, or a great camera&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="J5m9NK"&gt;If you’re shopping for a new phone on a budget, we’ve got good news: there are more great, affordable phones on the market than ever. Companies like Apple, Google, and Samsung are spreading the wealth of features enjoyed by their flagships down to less expensive options. Other brands like OnePlus are finding ways to challenge more established manufacturers with budget devices that make smart sacrifices to keep costs down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tWFA5k"&gt;The bad news is this makes the job of picking the best budget phone that much harder. Bear in mind that it’s impossible to buy a phone that does everything at this price point; instead, prioritize the features that matter most to you. You’ll have an easier time deciding, and you’ll end up with a great phone that you should be able to use for years to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6JHLP0"&gt;Our pick for the best inexpensive iPhone is the 2020 edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21230308/apple-iphone-se-2-2020-review-features-specs-camera-price"&gt;Apple iPhone SE&lt;/a&gt;. Even though it’s well over a year old, we think it’s still the best bet for most people. While it does a competent job at everything, its standout feature is that it should last four or more years if treated well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5gY4Mp"&gt;If you’re looking for the best cheap Android phone, then the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22628205/google-pixel-5a-review-price-screen-battery-specs"&gt;Google Pixel 5A&lt;/a&gt; is our top choice right now. You won’t find a big, show-stopping screen here, or bells and whistles like a fast refresh rate screen. Instead, you get a phone that covers the basics really well, plus IP67 waterproofing and timely software updates — all at a lower price than last year’s model.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fQUJ3j"&gt;What most people are looking for in a sub-$500 smartphone are the same things people want in a more expensive model: long battery life, good screen, good camera, and decent performance. It’s difficult to get high straight A’s in every single one of those categories, but if you’re able to decide where you’ll tolerate the occasional B grade, you’ll find a phone you’ll love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wu38Dv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556638"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="2Gej3D"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10711280"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="GatTSx"&gt;
&lt;h1 id="xLIfAi"&gt;The best smartphone for under $500 in 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Apple iPhone SE is a great choice if you want a phone that lasts for years." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dBU6PLPRcKtVVTdfTrprm4mAigQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19916232/vpavic_042019_3980_0024.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple iPhone SE is a great choice if you want a phone that lasts for years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PEjixV"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21230308/apple-iphone-se-2-2020-review-features-specs-camera-price"&gt;Apple iPhone SE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="YvXuY9"&gt;The best smartphone under $500&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="bkDOPH"&gt;The phone that strikes the right balance of camera, build quality, speed, battery life, software, and longevity for most people is the Apple iPhone SE 2020. Even though it’s over a year old now, it should still give you an excellent return on your investment. We recommend upgrading to the model with 128GB of storage for $449, which is $50 over the base price but well worth it long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ZnehD"&gt;The iPhone SE follows a very tried and true formula. It has the same body and 4.7-inch LCD screen that Apple has been using since the iPhone 6. That puts the display on the smaller end of screen sizes today and also means the phone’s bezels are bigger than anything else sold on the market. High refresh-rate screens with smoother animations and scrolling have been trickling down into the budget class recently, and you definitely won’t find one here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aOgwn4"&gt;It’s a familiar design and not one that screams “modern.” But in exchange, you get a lot of value. The 2020 SE is part of the iPhone 11 generation, so its A13 Bionic processor is a year behind the latest and greatest. (That would be the A14 chipset in the iPhone 12 lineup.) However, it’s still one of the fastest processors you can get on any phone, but &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; one in this price bracket. Normally, speed isn’t something we prioritize on phones at this price point, but it’s nice to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9LjWN"&gt;Why that processor &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matters, though, is overall longevity. Apple consistently supports its phones for four or more years with software updates. (That’s in opposition to Android, where getting software updates on anything but the Pixel is still a struggle.) So Apple’s choice of a fast processor means, in a few years, the iPhone SE will still feel snappy and still be supported with iOS updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5TvHua"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As a total package, the 2020 iPhone SE is the best smartphone under $500 for most people&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tETMb0"&gt;Battery life is good but not best in class. It should last about a day. Luckily, this iPhone supports wireless charging, which is still uncommon at this price point. And because it has the exact same shape as the iPhone 6, 6S, 7, and 8, there is a huge ecosystem of chargers and cases for it. Unlike many inexpensive Android phones, finding compatible accessories for the iPhone SE will be a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cAfzxG"&gt;The iPhone SE has just one camera on the back and just one selfie camera on the front, 12 megapixels and 7 megapixels, respectively. Neither is great by 2021 standards, but both are significantly better than what Apple shipped in older iPhones. It’s also fairly good by the standards of sub-$500 phones, though the Google Pixel 4A continues to win this category by a knockout. You will get a lot of camera features on the iPhone SE, including portrait and HDR, but unfortunately, there is no night mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nB1ZXR"&gt;As a total package, the 2020 iPhone SE is the best smartphone under $500 for most people. If you think of it on a cost-per-year metric, it ends up being significantly less expensive than the competition because it’s likely to last four or five years if you take care of it. Just as importantly, it’s a great phone on its own merits. You get access to the vast array of iOS apps, Apple’s strong support network, and a huge ecosystem of accessories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="smYbEU"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OsDX3SyDEYXfF58kJLK4zYKEcXs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22781446/ajohnson_210813_4713_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pixel 5A’s 6.34-inch screen isn’t huge, but it’s just big enough to not look out of place next to the 6.5-inch competition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="B9aQm4"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22628205/google-pixel-5a-review-price-screen-battery-specs"&gt;Google Pixel 5A&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MeddEq"&gt;The best budget Android phone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="VAnoi0"&gt;The $449 Pixel 5A features a 6.34-inch OLED screen that’s on the smaller side for the budget class, but it’s bigger than the previous-gen 6.2-inch panel on the Pixel 4A 5G. There’s a bigger battery too, a 4,680mAh cell that will last through a full day of heavy use and well into day two if you’re a lighter user. The 5A also offers IP67 water resistance for added peace of mind in the event of accidental spills or tumbles into the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OMgcHa"&gt;That’s more or less the extent of the 5A’s improvements over its predecessor, and that’s fine. The 4A 5G was already a well-equipped midrange device and the 5A makes some strategic updates to its foundation. The dual standard / ultrawide rear-facing camera, Snapdragon 765G processor, and 6GB RAM / 128GB storage combination served the 4A 5G well and still deliver solid performance in this iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Hdocxa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The 5A is also getting somewhat of a limited release — it’s only available in the US and Japan&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iQBwQn"&gt;Another thing we can count on Pixel phones to do well is software, and the 5A is no exception. It ships with Google’s own Android 11 OS and is refreshingly free of the added clutter that other manufacturers sometimes pile onto it. The Pixel 5A is also guaranteed three years of OS platform upgrades and security updates, which isn’t quite as long as Apple or Samsung’s standard software support timespan, but is certainly better than a lot of the Android competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sQGX8e"&gt;There’s also, of course, 5G connectivity. You won’t get the super-fast mmWave flavor of 5G support, but that’s a highly range-limited network that’s still pretty hard to find. That’s fine, but there’s a weird question mark over whether Google will support another set of frequencies that AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon will start using later this year called C-band. The company isn’t committing to making the necessary software update to use it, despite supporting it in hardware. It’s a strange blemish on the 5A’s otherwise strong feature set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CHUScD"&gt;The 5A is also getting somewhat of a limited release — it’s only available in the US and Japan, and isn’t being sold through any of the major US wireless carriers. Taking all of that into consideration, the Pixel 5A is still the inexpensive Android phone that we’d recommend to most people. It’s not flashy, but it’s well priced and has it where it counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ykrqeX"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7jGjKdcssyDUAL1Vc67gH-WoCNo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22465667/ajohnson_20210419_4541_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy A52 5G offers a 120Hz fast refresh-rate screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qyhaRs"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399456/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-review-camera-screen-specs-price"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A52 5G&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7CPw9a"&gt;The best budget Android phone with a fast refresh-rate screen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="GW6KVJ"&gt;On the Android side, the Galaxy A52 5G is a great option, albeit at the very top of the price range considered in this guide. It includes some features that aren’t too common in a budget phone, like its fast-refresh rate screen, an IP67 water resistance rating, and for now at least, monthly security updates for fast access to bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s379P4"&gt;The A52 5G’s 6.5-inch screen is an OLED panel that’s bright with good contrast that’s generally nice to look at. But its best feature is a subtle one: a 120Hz refresh rate that gives a much smoother appearance to animations and content as you swipe and scroll through menus and social feeds. We’ll likely see this feature make its way into more budget phones soon, but for now the A52 5G is one of only a few to offer better than the standard 60Hz screen in its class, and it makes the experience of using the phone that much nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="grIaTf"&gt;The phone overall performs well for its class with a Snapdragon 750G processor and 6GB of RAM. You may notice the occasional hesitation or stutter with heavy tasks, but otherwise everyday scrolling, app switching, and navigating is handled easily. And even with a power-hungry display, the Galaxy A52 5G’s 4,500mAh battery should get you through at least a day of moderate to heavy use before needing another charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="RSNCy0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;if you want to make an investment in a phone that you can keep using years from now, the A52 5G is your best bet right now on Android&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NwHMHO"&gt;One of the A52 5G’s not-so-bright-spots is Samsung’s current take on Android, which puts a lot of pre-downloaded apps on your phone that you probably don’t want, and it even includes the occasional ad in places like the native weather app. For a cleaner or more grown-up Android skin, look to the Pixel or OnePlus. The Galaxy A52 5G’s camera is another consideration: it’s capable, but it tends toward an oversaturated look. If you prefer a more natural look to your photos, then the Pixel 4A is the winner here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fFmNNo"&gt;There’s also 5G, which we still don’t think is a feature you should run out and buy a new phone for, but it is nice to have the support here — particularly if you plan to hold on to your phone for a few years. This device doesn’t support super-fast mmWave 5G, but it’s hard to come by so that’s not a huge loss. Importantly, it supports more widely available sub-6GHz bands and should be able to take advantage of improving 5G networks in the US over the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOCh8W"&gt;You can buy a much less expensive device to get you through the next couple of years, and that’s just fine. But if you do want to make more of an investment in a phone that you can keep using three or four years from now, the A52 5G is your best bet right now on Android. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WTfxoR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10462499"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="JjjEKP"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 4A has an incredible camera." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uGMHIJ_EFkQE2rMcf3ISzHc3EYU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21691927/vpavic_4113_20200721_0041.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Google Pixel 4A has an incredible camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mjpWjB"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;Google Pixel 4A&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nCclP5"&gt;The best “get it while you can” affordable Android phone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Uc3Oon"&gt;If you want to spend a little less money, or just want the best camera, then the&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt; Google Pixel 4A is the obvious choice&lt;/a&gt;. Its screen is on the small side, lacks 5G support, and it doesn’t have the fastest processor, but it does have a clean version of Android and is first in line for updates from Google. The 4A came out in August last year, but it’s still guaranteed to get software updates until at least August 2023. It comes in either black or baby blue with 128GB of storage for $349 but you’ll have to act fast if you want one — with the Pixel 5A and Pixel 6 debuting this fall, Google won’t be selling the 4A for much longer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Huw9Ph"&gt;The Pixel 4A’s main claim to fame is its camera. It’s based on generation-old technology at this point, but it’s still the best in this class and it can go head-to-head with smartphones that cost $1,000 or more. That’s because Google does so much of the image processing in software. (The sensor itself is actually quite old and not very special.) That means the Pixel 4A can take night photos, do astrophotography, and has a passable portrait mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XiTOqY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Pixel 4A uses Google’s version of Android, which means it’s easy to navigate and free of extra stuff&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g65TGg"&gt;The rest of the Pixel 4A’s specs are good but not great. It has a 5.8-inch screen, just enough RAM to keep apps from closing in the background, and a headphone jack. There’s no wireless charging, no fancy face unlock, and the body is made out of plastic instead of something more premium like glass. The Pixel 4A doesn’t even offer any IP water resistance ratings (but a splash of water is probably fine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qrF1h5"&gt;The Pixel 4A uses Google’s version of Android, which means it’s easy to navigate and free of extra stuff you probably don’t want. More importantly, it means that Google can supply the software updates directly instead of waiting for another manufacturer or carrier to approve it, putting you first in line for Android updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XggNCE"&gt;Unfortunately, in a little over a year’s time, it’s quite likely that the Pixel 4A will be slowing down. Android phones generally don’t last quite as long as iPhones do because Android tends to bog down on older hardware more quickly. The Pixel 4A’s processor is fast enough today to not be a bother, but over time, it’s possible that it won’t age well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h7VV1d"&gt;But for all that, the Pixel 4A is probably the safest bet if you want to get an Android phone for well under $500. You’ll get better software support and a better camera for $350. Not a bad deal — while you can still find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rbmTPt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556642"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="0FM1jw"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ELb7UlH61XtlbtToEca90_7TpyY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22726849/jporter_210719_4669_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Jon Porter / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nord 2 covers the essentials with a couple of nice touches, like a 90Hz screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bFMC0d"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22586815/oneplus-nord-2-5g-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;OnePlus Nord 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Oj4ljX"&gt;A great midrange option if you’re outside the US&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hMRHe3"&gt;The OnePlus Nord 2 isn’t sold in the US, and that’s our loss because this follow-up to the original Nord checks all the right boxes for its £399 / €399 price. Even more so than last year’s model, the Nord 2 feels like a pared-down flagship that covers all of the basics well, with (almost) nothing that you don’t need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L8pZjK"&gt;The Nord 2 offers a 6.43-inch display with 90Hz refresh rate — a bit faster than the standard 60Hz, but not quite the buttery smoothness of a 120Hz screen. We were a little apprehensive of the MediaTek Dimensity 1200-AI chipset that OnePlus has opted for in favor of proven Snapdragon processors, but in testing, it was more than adequate for daily tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gfaweu"&gt;The 4,500mAh battery will comfortably get you through a full day’s use, and although there’s no wireless charging included (not a surprise at this price), OnePlus’ signature fast wired charging is supported. With the included charger, you can power the phone from zero to fully charged in well under an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZKaIkM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Nord 2 ships with OxygenOS 11.3, and is the uncluttered, unfussy experience we’ve come to expect from OnePlus&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xdTWar"&gt;OnePlus’ unfussy UI is another strong point. The Nord 2 ships with OxygenOS 11.3, and is the uncluttered, unfussy experience we’ve come to expect from OnePlus. The company says it will offer two OS upgrades and three years of security support for the Nord 2, which is a good, if not great update policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ir7jlU"&gt;You won’t find the Hasselblad branding of the OnePlus 9 flagships on the Nord 2’s cameras, and that’s no great loss. What you do get is a capable camera system consisting of a 50-megapixel main stabilized rear camera, an 8-megapixel ultrawide, and a questionably useful 2-megapixel monochrome sensor, along with a 32-megapixel selfie camera. Image quality is good all around — photos from the main camera lean into a slightly saturated, punchy look, but nothing distracting. Low-light photos aren’t up there with the Pixel’s, but they work in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ijydf9"&gt;It’s a shame that US customers can’t pick up the Nord 2 (technically you can import it, but it won’t work properly on our wireless bands so it’s not recommended), because it’s an ideal midrange device in a lot of ways. Our loss is the rest of the world’s gain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FtL0ba"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10711336"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="PNDiYl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BXMhOf_K6HW_6jVKD9akUraWoYk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22214229/ajohnson200104_4354_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The N10 5G is priced well under $500.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2pPPrl"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0wGhHB"&gt;If you want an inexpensive 5G phone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="zVN77Q"&gt;At $299, the N10 5G is well below the threshold for this category. Given its price, you might expect to see some significant sacrifices compared to a $400 or $500 phone, and OnePlus has made a few. But they’re smart sacrifices that add up to a device that’s really quite good for the money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vb4uVX"&gt;You won’t find a fantastic screen here, although its large 6.46-inch LCD does come with a faster-than-average 90Hz refresh rate. Worth noting is the device’s somewhat “tall” 20:9 aspect ratio, which is a little unusual at first glance but makes the phone slightly narrower and easier to use with one hand. Its processor is capable enough, though it sometimes shows its limits. It also ships with Android 10, which OnePlus says it will update to 11, and is only offering two years of security updates in addition to that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VXW2WO"&gt;On the camera side, the N10 offers a 64-megapixel main camera that’s surprisingly good in daylight and even moderately low light. There’s an 8-megapixel ultrawide, too, along with macro and monochrome cameras that aren’t really worth talking about. It’s not Pixel 4A-level good, but if you don’t push it too hard, the N10’s main camera takes good photos in the right light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y00B08"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529760/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-review-price-screen-specs"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A32 5G&lt;/a&gt; is also well worth considering in this price bracket for two very good reasons: it’s a bit less expensive and will be supported with security updates for the next four years. However, it lacks some of the N10’s nice features like a faster refresh rate screen, the camera isn’t as good, and its software feels more cluttered and bloated. The A32 5G is a better pick if you want to hang on to your phone for as many years as possible, but the N10 is a more likable device overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y5Ppnc"&gt;If budget is a major consideration, the N10 5G is about as good as it gets at this price. It offers the future-proofiness of sub-6GHz 5G support, a thoroughly decent camera, good battery life, a capable processor, and a fairly clean implementation of Android. It’s not a standout in any one way, but as a total package, it’s very hard to argue with its capabilities at this price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2zE49h"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10348332"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UcHD0D"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0vEWlb7XvHUYvgaOoRi3Ex_G3cw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290840/ajohnson_210205_4399_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2021 Moto G Power offers days-long battery performance but makes a lot of sacrifices for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Qq9tmB"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review"&gt;Motorola Moto G Power (2021)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tXDuyi"&gt;The budget phone with maximum battery life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="NSb4tw"&gt;The Moto G Power does exactly what it says it will: provide days and days of power on a single charge, thanks to its larger-than-average 5,000mAh battery. This is a slightly different version of last year’s phone with the same name, and it starts at a lower $200 price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H7tVXv"&gt;The lower price tag does come with trade-offs. It includes just 32GB of built-in storage, so adding a microSD card for some extra space is a must. There’s also a slightly slower processor on board, and while it’s capable enough for all of your daily needs, it’s a little laggy jumping between apps and opening the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8syWIE"&gt;As for the camera: it’s just okay. Motorola did away with the ultrawide in this year’s models, so you’ll just be working with the 48-megapixel standard wide and 2-megapixel macro cameras in addition to an 8-megapixel selfie cam. Photos in bright outdoor light look good with plenty of detail, though colors can be a little washed out. The camera struggles with high-contrast scenes and low light, but all things considered, it’s fine for a $200 phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5bJEGA"&gt;If top-notch battery performance is an extremely important feature in your smartphone, then the Moto G Power should be on your shortlist. It’s capable, and you really will get multiple days of battery life on a charge. But if you’re fine getting by on a battery that’s just average, then we think you’ll be happier with a more well-rounded device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cyQK5V"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10348305"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="jpOqcd"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sS7FviYLlQP2Kvj24XJklLhXhOY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22446425/ajohnson_20210412_4525_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto G Play covers all of the basics for well under $200.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zLkqZB"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22408041/motorola-moto-g-play-2021-review-price-screen-specs"&gt;Motorola Moto G Play (2021)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0rkwQp"&gt;The best phone under $200&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7Y8w9H"&gt;There are plenty of options for those shopping on a tighter budget, but the Motorola Moto G Play is the one that stands out to us. It covers the basics well with a big 5,000mAh battery and a Snapdragon 460 processor that does a good enough job handling daily tasks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bwHIya"&gt;The G Play has a generously sized 6.5-inch screen. It’s a lower-resolution panel at 720p and is difficult to see outside in direct light, but it’s more or less just fine. Camera specs are likewise basic: there’s just one rear-facing 13-megapixel camera that performs well in bright light but isn’t well suited for low-light photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HTXRvU"&gt;You’ll also want to strongly consider a microSD card purchase with this phone. It only includes 32GB of built-in storage, a lot of which is already occupied by system files. Motorola has only promised security updates for two years, but realistically, the G Play isn’t built to last much longer than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhtEOa"&gt;It has its shortcomings — the G Play’s performance doesn’t keep up with many phones that are just $50-100 more expensive, for example — but it’s hard to argue with what it does offer for its price: good, basic performance without any major flaws. If there’s flexibility in your budget to spend a little more, you’ll get some meaningful upgrades, like a better camera or a longer-lasting device. But for its price, the G Play does just what it needs to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Xrkyjl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10476249"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T12:59:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T12:59:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook hides friends lists on accounts in Afghanistan as a safety measure</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FYATfyB4B2BfUuqogfvNcmg1lwM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69753829/acastro_180720_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Facebook has started hiding friends lists from accounts in Afghanistan | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6GezXO"&gt;Facebook’s head of security policy said the company is putting into place &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ngleicher/status/1428474000611573762?s=20"&gt;security measures for users in Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;, including hiding “friends” lists and adding a tool to quickly lock down accounts. Nathaniel Gleicher said in a thread on Twitter that Facebook made the changes based on feedback from activists, journalists, and civil society groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DN1OWo"&gt;As the Taliban have regained control of the country over the past week, the group has found ways to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/18/technology/taliban-social-media-bans.html"&gt;push its messages on social media&lt;/a&gt;, despite being banned by YouTube and Facebook. &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/taliban-violence-drives-afghans-wipe-social-media-profiles-rcna1731"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt; reported Friday&lt;/a&gt; that people in Afghanistan fearful of the Taliban were deleting from their social media accounts and phones any photos that could show a connection to Western countries, the former Afghan government, or the Afghan military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P66HGR"&gt;People in Afghanistan will now have access to a one-click tool to lock down their Facebook accounts. “When their profile is locked, people who aren’t their friends can’t download or share their profile photo or see posts on their timeline,” Gleicher &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ngleicher/status/1428474006609399811?s=20"&gt;explained&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also removed the ability for users to view and search “Friends” lists for Facebook accounts in Afghanistan, to protect people from being targeted, he added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eBTs3L"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;4/ We’ve launched a one-click tool for people in Afghanistan to quickly lock down their account. When their profile is locked, people who aren’t their friends can’t download or share their profile photo or see posts on their timeline. &lt;a href="https://t.co/pUANh5uBgn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/pUANh5uBgn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nathaniel Gleicher (@ngleicher) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ngleicher/status/1428474006609399811?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BGUjHp"&gt;On Facebook-owned Instagram, Gleicher said, the company is adding pop-up alerts in Afghanistan that include steps for protecting accounts. He also urged people with friends and family in Afghanistan to tighten their own visibility settings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPjGPm"&gt;Gleicher added that it’s added a special operations center “to respond to new threats as they emerge.” The company is watching the situation closely, he said. “and will take steps to help protect people in real time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HHQUrx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22634209/facebook-hides-friends-lists-instagram-safety-afghanistan-taliban-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22634209/facebook-hides-friends-lists-instagram-safety-afghanistan-taliban-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T12:14:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T12:14:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: reviews for the Pixel 5A, Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 3, and Z Flip 3</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pl-UZF3I0gGaviuYt2XE737wkUY=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69753648/dseifert_4711_samsung_z_flip_3_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H16wid"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b0lasJ"&gt;This week on &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;, we’ve got a cast of Nilay, Dieter, &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;managing editor Alex Cranz, &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; reviewer Allison Johnson, and &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; deputy editor Dan Seifert. The crew discusses reviews for the Google Pixel 5A, Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 3, and Z Fold 3, as well as some other news in the tech world like the T-Mobile data breach that exposed the personal info of more than 47 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r7GZar"&gt;In the second half of the show, Alex, Dieter, and Nilay discuss the tech news you may have missed — like Intel’s new PC gaming GPUs, Facebook’s new metaverse conferencing software, and the interesting emails revealed from Apple, Google, and Epic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="STGTNk"&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP1346503730&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="04lW7I"&gt;You can listen to the full discussion here or in your preferred podcast player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="etxloE"&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WHAVGo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22628799/covid-vaccine-booster-biden-moderna-pfizer-fda-cdc"&gt;COVID-19 booster shots will be offered to Americans in September, Biden administration says&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wVkmL8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623600/cdc-covid-third-vaccine-immunocompromised"&gt;Immunocompromised people should get a third COVID-19 vaccine dose, CDC committee says&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fRMX4V"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627004/public-health-data-gaps-fax-email-politico"&gt;Go read this deep dive on why US public health data systems couldn’t handle COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="urQwiV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22628205/google-pixel-5a-review-price-screen-battery-specs"&gt;Google Pixel 5A review: boring, but better than ever &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="USWBG8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22627253/google-pixel-5a-specs-price-screen-battery-availability"&gt;Google Pixel 5A comes with a bigger battery and screen, smaller price tag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vz9Nng"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22628702/google-pixel-6-charger-not-included"&gt;The Google Pixel 6 won’t ship with a charger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FvBwNm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22629459/galaxy-watch-4-classic-review-bixby-google-wearos"&gt;Galaxy Watch 4 review: welcome to Samsung’s garden &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9o8WA0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22631125/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Z Flip 3 is the first folding phone for normal people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DFtTJw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22627058/samsung-galaxy-note-stylus-z-fold-3-a-series"&gt;There’s still a place for the Note in Samsung’s Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LiFNI0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630332/samsung-ads-default-stock-apps-weather-pay-theme-confirmed"&gt;Samsung confirms it’s removing ads from its stock apps later this year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v0awOb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22627099/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-apple-airpods-pro-ecosystem-lock-in-features-companion-app"&gt;How the latest and greatest Samsung and Apple earbuds lock you into their world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="A2AgFp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii"&gt;T-Mobile data breach exposed the personal info of more than 47 million people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hSnozG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22630319/microsoft-windows-11-default-browser-changes"&gt;Microsoft is making it harder to switch default browsers in Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1JowTM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"&gt;Apple’s been playing it too MagSafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Sd8nDN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630517/apple-podcasts-subscriptions-launch-dashboard'"&gt;Apple’s attempt at podcast subscriptions is off to a messy start &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eo45d3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22627032/ftc-facebook-amended-antitrust-complaint-monopoly-instagram-whatsapp"&gt;FTC says Facebook has been a monopoly ‘since at least 2011’ in amended antitrust complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lpwhAk"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22629942/facebook-workrooms-horizon-oculus-vr"&gt;Inside Facebook’s metaverse for work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DVbS2y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632818/google-project-hug-game-developers-play-store-millions-epic-lawsuit-complaint"&gt;Google’s ‘Project Hug’ paid out huge sums to keep game devs in the Play Store, Epic filing claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="chTgoM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632806/google-epic-premier-device-program-lg-motorola-hmd"&gt;Google gave phone makers extra money to ditch third-party app stores&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ACcQUm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631907/google-gaming-vision-android-windows-mac-cross-screen-controller"&gt;Google secretly had a giant gaming vision that includes bringing games to Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xrzFPJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22611236/epic-v-apple-emails-project-liberty-app-store-schiller-sweeney-cook-jobs"&gt;Sweetheart deals and plastic knives: all the best emails from the Apple vs. Epic trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z0vI6U"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631541/steve-jobs-email-apple-iphone-nano-epic-lawsuit"&gt;Steve Jobs email confirms Apple was working on an ‘iPhone nano’&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MXGhkm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626912/intel-arc-gpu-brand-alchemist-codename-release-date"&gt;Intel enters the PC gaming GPU battle with Arc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MZTwq6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631061/intel-arc-gpu-alchemist-xe-ss-super-sampling-ai-architecture-day-preview"&gt;Intel shows off its answer to Nvidia’s DLSS, coming to Arc GPUs in 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="d8AmsU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631059/intel-alder-lake-chip-hybrid-architecture-day-2021-desktop-laptop-preview-cores"&gt;Intel previews its Alder Lake chip, promises hybrid CPUs for desktops and laptops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RfmnBm"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22628925/water-semiconductor-shortage-arizona-drought"&gt;Water shortages loom over future semiconductor fabs in Arizona&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9gPIsD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/04/why-intel-tsmc-are-building-water-dependent-chip-plants-in-arizona.html"&gt;Why Intel and TSMC are building water-dependent chip factories in one of the driest U.S. states&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PzJcG9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631247/gm-att-5g-car-chevy-cadillac-gmc-2024"&gt;GM and AT&amp;amp;T are teaming up to bring 5G to Chevy, Cadillac, and GMC cars by 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="VXKMWp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633953/review-google-pixel-5a-samsung-galaxy-z-flold-flip-vergecast-podcast-463"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633953/review-google-pixel-5a-samsung-galaxy-z-flold-flip-vergecast-podcast-463</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T11:46:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T11:46:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Don’t overthink it: Elon Musk’s Tesla Bot is a joke</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CW2LEJettegsravy59OyDj-hYrc=/0x0:1060x707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69753469/robotics_1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VMybrN"&gt;After a dense presentation about the undeniably impressive work Tesla is doing with AI, the company’s self-anointed Technoking, Elon Musk, capped the evening by bringing out a dancer in a spandex suit. Behold, said Musk: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22633514/tesla-robot-prototype-elon-musk-humanoid-ai-day"&gt;my Tesla Bot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jN0wru"&gt;The dancer in the suit, he said, was the model for a new humanoid robot Tesla will produce in the near future. After the dubstep and applause had faded, the vaguest of briefing slides promised that the Tesla Bot will stand five feet, eight inches (1.7m), weigh 125 pounds (56kg), have “human-level hands,” and eliminate “dangerous, repetitive, boring tasks.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yXSEpk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A robot is just a Tesla without wheels, says Musk&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="a1axCd"&gt;Musk said that building a human-replacement robot — something no company in the world is close to achieving — was a logical step forward from Tesla’s work developing self-driving cars. “Our cars are semi-sentient robots on wheels,” he said. “It kind of makes sense to put that on to a humanoid form. We’re also quite good at sensors and batteries and actuators so we think we’ll probably have a prototype some time next year that basically looks like this.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VkCc3y"&gt;Even by Musk’s standards, it was a bizarre and brilliant bit of tomfoolery: a multipurpose sideshow that trolled Tesla skeptics, fed the fans, ginned up the share price, and created some eye-catching headlines. The latter being particularly important in a week when most Tesla news has focused on a federal investigation into a tendency of the company’s Autopilot software to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626819/tesla-autopilot-crash-emergency-vehicle-probe-nhtsa"&gt;crash into parked emergency vehicles&lt;/a&gt;. Forget about all that, says Musk, just look at the person in the spandex suit! Next year, it’ll be a real robot, &lt;em&gt;I promise&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rtm5a9"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Lmao this is how he made his announcement? &lt;a href="https://t.co/6Ktybjyeav"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6Ktybjyeav&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ryan Mac  (@RMac18) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RMac18/status/1428708172856918018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bycBkl"&gt;Do you believe him? &lt;em&gt;Should &lt;/em&gt;you believe him? I won’t answer that for you, but I want to restate the facts. Elon Musk got up on stage last night and promised that Tesla, a company whose driver assist software is unable to reliably avoid parked ambulances, would soon build a fully functioning humanoid robot. Musk said that the machine would be able to follow human instructions intuitively, responding correctly to commands like “please go to a store and get me the following groceries.” He outlined these scenarios and then said: “Yeah, I think we can do that.” This was minutes after he’d ushered away the best demo of the Tesla Bot available:&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;a dancer in a spandex suit. If nothing else, you have to admire the chutzpah. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v68mAM"&gt;To put Musk’s claims in context, remember that Boston Dynamics, a company which makes Atlas, the most advanced bipedal robot in the world, has never described its machines as anything but R&amp;amp;D. Atlas, says Boston Dynamics, is simply a way to push the cutting edge of robotics: it’s not even close to commercial deployment. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22628663/boston-dynamics-atlas-video-parkour-flips-falls-program"&gt;recent videos of the machine&lt;/a&gt;, the company showed how difficult building a bipedal robot is and how often Atlas trips and falls. It’s also worth noting that Boston Dynamics has been working on Atlas and its bipedal predecessors &lt;a href="https://robots.ieee.org/robots/petman/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;for more than a decade&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Musk thinks he can leapfrog their work in a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GS9FMH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“[Calling it] horse shit sounds generous, frankly.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f3zJxt"&gt;Carl Berry, a lecturer in robotics engineering at the UK’s University of Central Lancashire, put things to me in less uncertain terms: “[Calling it] horse shit sounds generous, frankly. I’m not saying that he shouldn’t be doing research like this, but it’s the usual overblown hype.” Berry stressed that deploying robotics and AI in manufacturing usually required making the simplest machine possible: not the most complex. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cKrMt0"&gt;“I’m not saying Tesla researching this stuff isn’t a good thing,” he said, “but between them and companies like Boston Dynamics they leave the public with unrealistic expectations of what robotics is currently capable of or will be for many years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBlmUr"&gt;I personally don’t doubt that if Musk wants to he can produce something that &lt;em&gt;looks&lt;/em&gt; like a Tesla Bot in 2022. It wouldn’t be hard to make a decent automaton — something on the level of Disney’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399471/disney-imagineering-robot-groot-bipedal-free-walking"&gt;more advanced theme park models&lt;/a&gt;, for example. Once he’s got it to walk out onstage he can even send it to space, just for the headlines. But if he does, it will be just another distraction. Robotics are having a huge effect on manufacturing, no doubt about that, but there’s no need to pretend that machines need to look human to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lm3qd0"&gt;This sort of bait-and-switch is often how Musk operates. Just think about how his plans for the Hyperloop changed over time. The technology was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/8/12/4614940/elon-musk-reveals-plans-for-high-speed-hyperloop"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; as a railgun-like train system that would move people from Los Angeles to San Francisco in less than half an hour. Over the years, these ambitions have shrunk until the project &lt;a href="https://la.curbed.com/2018/12/18/18147366/elon-musk-tunnel-tesla-test-opening-grimes"&gt;morphed into The Loop&lt;/a&gt;: a small tunnel that you can drive a car through, if you want. (Otherwise known as: a tunnel.)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xliRsH"&gt;What the Tesla Bot really reminded me of is Sophia: the mechanical chatbot that’s appeared on chat shows and magazine covers. Sophia relies on misdirection to fool audiences and is a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/18/16904742/sophia-the-robot-ai-real-fake-yann-lecun-criticism"&gt;regular target of AI experts’ scorn&lt;/a&gt;. But it also has a job to do. As one of the robot’s creators, Ben Goertzel, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/10/16617092/sophia-the-robot-citizen-ai-hanson-robotics-ben-goertzel"&gt;told me in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, Sophia works by priming our imagination, encouraging us to fool ourselves into thinking the future is closer than the evidence suggests. In the process, the robot generates funding and news coverage for its makers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXP9GB"&gt;“If I tell people I’m using probabilistic logic to do reasoning on how best to prune the backward chaining inference trees that arise in our logic engine, they have no idea what I’m talking about,” said Goertzel. “But if I show them a beautiful smiling robot face, then they get the feeling that AGI may indeed be nearby and viable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cdll6j"&gt;That feeling is what Musk wants to inculcate in his audience, be they investors or otherwise. His twist on the Sophia strategy is that he doesn’t even need a simulacrum of a robot to sell the dream. All he needs is a dancer in a spandex suit. Now that’s innovation. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633958/tesla-bot-elon-musk-ai-day"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633958/tesla-bot-elon-musk-ai-day</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T11:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Duolingo adds a family plan and new ways to learn non-Latin characters</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/laDyvJ0FLui1IRnGOu3g8kc0jU8=/0x92:1080x812/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69753378/1___Hero_Image.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Duolingo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2C4jLu"&gt;At &lt;a href="https://www.duolingo.com/duocon"&gt;Duolingo’s virtual conference&lt;/a&gt;, the company is announcing that it will add a family plan to its app, along with new games and puzzles to help people learn languages that use non-Latin alphabets, such as Japanese or Arabic. One of the main new features is a tab that will appear for some languages, which shows users a grid of letters in an alphabet, along with the sounds they make. (If you’re an Android user, the feature may sound familiar as it’s been available on that platform, but now it’s coming to iOS and the web.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="39JDZc"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://support.duolingo.com/hc/en-us/articles/360058962891-Family-Plan-FAQ"&gt;family plan&lt;/a&gt; will give six people (the subscriber, who becomes the family manager, and five others) the benefits of Duolingo Plus, which includes no ads, unlimited hearts, mastery quizzes, and more. It costs $120 a year, which isn’t bad compared to the individual Plus plan, which costs $80 a year when paid annually, or $12.99 a month, though there’s no monthly payment option for the family plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RqyuQm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Some languages will include games that involve tracing non-Latin characters&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iUX5M6"&gt;Duolingo says that the ability to tap on symbols and hear their sounds will be coming to languages like Korean, Russian, Ukrainian, Greek, Arabic, Hindi, Hebrew, and the newly added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22362723/duolingo-yiddish-language-classes"&gt;Yiddish&lt;/a&gt; (Japanese &lt;a href="https://blog.duolingo.com/learning-to-read-japanese-characters/"&gt;has had some of the features for a few months&lt;/a&gt;). In addition to the chart, there will also be lessons, and some languages will include games that involve tracing non-Latin characters or even building the character like a puzzle. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4b0zRj7v65CQeEbLJeVTbtTimc0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22793979/Korean.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Duolingo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exercises for languages may include listening exercises, tracing characters, and puzzles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="trAMmS"&gt;It makes sense that Duolingo is adding a family payment plan, which has been &lt;a href="https://forum.duolingo.com/comment/26245380/Suggestion-Duolingo-Plus-Family-membership"&gt;repeatedly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://forum.duolingo.com/comment/49499481/Starting-a-family-plan-please-help"&gt;requested&lt;/a&gt; by users, and new reasons to use its app given that the company &lt;a href="https://blog.duolingo.com/duolingo-ipo/"&gt;just went public at the end of July&lt;/a&gt;. As someone who’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22583950/duolingo-language-learning-anxiety"&gt;bounced off the company’s lessons&lt;/a&gt; for Russian and Japanese, though, I appreciate the additional lessons for the characters that I’ve struggled to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633335/duolingo-family-plan-plus-non-latin-character-practice"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633335/duolingo-family-plan-plus-non-latin-character-practice</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T11:24:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T11:24:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Stitch Fix stylists reportedly quit in droves as the company leans on algorithms to serve customers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Stitch Fix Illustrations As Earnings Figures Released" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o7CZhFEeV1TUX-Xe7FJjlRXcCvg=/0x2:4000x2669/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69753356/1233318623.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="weJeJK"&gt;Stitch Fix stylists — who choose outfits for its customers — quit in droves after the company ended its flexible scheduling policy, according to a new report from &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolineodonovan/stitch-fix-employees-quitting"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And at least one worker told &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt; that employees felt like they were “training the algorithm” which also helps choose customers’ clothing, suggesting the company may be heading toward relying more on computer-generated recommendations instead of human stylists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mPFS4e"&gt;&lt;a href="https://edge.media-server.com/mmc/p/4hqj866x"&gt;During a call with investors&lt;/a&gt; after its June earnings announcement, new CEO Elizabeth Spaulding (who started the job August 1st) said Stitch Fix stylists “play a very active role in training our machine learning models with our data science team for outfits, which our ability to generate algorithmic outfits in a feed is, we think, a real source of differentiation that requires that human touch to help build and train those models, as well as quality control.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iytt38"&gt;Stitch Fix is one of several online styling services. Customers take a “quiz” about their personal style, clothing preferences, preferred price range, and sizes, and a stylist picks out clothing based on those preferences which are then shipped to the customer. The customer can choose to keep the clothing and pay for it, or send it back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GwhHvp"&gt;The company used to allow its stylists, many of whom work part time remotely, to choose their own schedules. Indeed, as of this writing, &lt;a href="https://www.stitchfix.com/careers/styling"&gt;Stitch Fix’s careers page&lt;/a&gt; says its stylists “love the flexibility to set a work schedule that fits into their daily lifestyle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M53gqj"&gt;But earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.modernretail.co/retailers/stitch-fix-to-stylists-accept-scheduling-changes-or-resign/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modern Retail &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that the company told employees via internal message that it was making changes, and that part-time stylists had to be available to work a minimum of 20 hours per week, between 8AM and 8PM local time. There was no guarantee the workers would get 20 hours weekly, however. Previously, stylists could indicate how many hours they would commit to working on a given day, but with the changes, Stitch Fix required that they specify exactly when they would work those hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fsUET7"&gt;According to the internal message, stylists had the option of committing to the new schedule rules or resigning and receiving an “exit payment” of $1,000 if they signed a nondisclosure agreement. About 1,500 stylists left after the updated policy was announced, &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt; reported, roughly a third of its stylists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ewmIeh"&gt;Stitch Fix said in June it generated $535.6 million in revenue in &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/07/stitch-fix-sfix-reports-q3-2021-results.html"&gt;its third quarter&lt;/a&gt;, up 44 percent from the year prior, and grew its active client count 20 percent to 4.1 million people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HBmnR6"&gt;The stylists who spoke to &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt; said they noticed more customer orders being sent out with items chosen completely by an algorithm, with a human stylist involved only to write a note to the customer or if a customer complained. “We knew from the beginning we were teaching the algorithm,” one stylist told the outlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MwYIbA"&gt;Stitch Fix did not confirm how many stylists have quit over the new schedule rules, but said in a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that its stylists were “instrumental in building relationships with clients and creating the highly personalized experience Stitch Fix is known for.” The changes to operations, the statement reads, will allow the company to “better align with when and how clients will most likely want to connect” with stylists. “These changes, made in conjunction with our broader future of work plans, also support our DEI efforts and allow us to grow our teams in new markets and in new ways.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BqV3Ug"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 20th 12:17PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added comment from Stitch Fix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633846/stitch-fix-stylists-quit-algorithm-customers-schedules"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633846/stitch-fix-stylists-quit-algorithm-customers-schedules</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T10:53:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T10:53:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile’s massive data breach leaked info for 5.3 million additional customers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LJO03I3sABMpXk2L0YOJ51ERKuQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69753137/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="srbZRz"&gt;The news about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4"&gt;T-Mobile’s latest data breach&lt;/a&gt; is only getting worse, as the company &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fnetwork%2Fadditional-information-regarding-2021-cyberattack-investigation&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F20%2F22633853%2Ftmobile-data-breach-imei-sim-fcc" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announced new details&lt;/a&gt; from its investigation. While someone in possession of the leaked data &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22626270/t-mobile-investigating-report-customer-data-breach"&gt;said they had obtained information for as many as 100 million customers&lt;/a&gt;, including driver’s license info, IMEI numbers, and more, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4"&gt;T-Mobile’s first statement&lt;/a&gt; put the figure at 47 million or so and did not mention the IMEI / IMSI data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K81kUx"&gt;Now, T-Mobile has confirmed that for the 7.8 million on-contract, or postpaid, customers it already counted in the breach, data stolen includes the information mentioned Thursday (first and last names, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, and driver’s license / ID numbers), as well as phone numbers and IMEI / IMSI information. IMEI stands for International Mobile Equipment Identity and is a number that’s assigned to every mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Eib8BJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More than 50 million people have been included in the breach&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7mfsT0"&gt;IMSI stands for International Mobile Subscriber Identity and is the identifier for the SIM card to which your mobile phone number is tied. That kind of data could be used to track mobile devices or assist in SIM swapping attacks where someone hijacks your phone number to intercept two-factor authentication codes or other information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KDOsYC"&gt;Additionally, 5.3 million more postpaid customers have also been identified as part of the breach, but without revealing their driver’s license / ID or Social Security numbers. The same goes for an additional 667,000 accounts of former T-Mobile subscribers that are being added to the total. Former Sprint prepaid and Boost Mobile customers are still in the clear, however, 52,000 names tied to Metro by T-Mobile accounts were stolen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EUKXCT"&gt;An unspecified number of files contained “phone numbers, IMEI, and IMSI numbers.” According to T-Mobile that did not include any personally identifiable information, which is a questionable claim since it could be easy to tie someone’s identity to their phone number based on other leaked data or simply browsing publicly available listings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L3FAsX"&gt;The FCC already announced it’s investigating the incident, and at least one class-action lawsuit has been filed against T-Mobile, calling its response and promised two years of identity protection services “inadequate.” The investigation is still ongoing, but T-Mobile customers (current, former, or just prospective ones who filled out an application) can &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fbrand%2Fdata-breach-2021&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F20%2F22633853%2Ftmobile-data-breach-imei-sim-fcc" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633853/tmobile-data-breach-imei-sim-fcc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633853/tmobile-data-breach-imei-sim-fcc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T09:22:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T09:22:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>A four-pack of Tile Bluetooth trackers is $55 today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZplfkM7ZeVVdN1tTD69Oh-_Q5VM=/0x231:1500x1231/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69752573/Tile_Mate_on_an_Umbrella.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Tile Mate trackers feature replaceable batteries | Image: Tile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qoM4PT"&gt;Whether you use iOS or Android, the Tile Mate (2020) is a great Bluetooth tracker that’s designed to help you keep watch over your personal stuff. This $15 discount on a four-pack from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tile-RE-19004-Mate-4-Pack/dp/B07W73PTJB?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1749570688602172611#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; is a great value for people getting started with Bluetooth trackers or someone building an arsenal of them. Unlike Apple AirTags, they can remotely ping your phone and also have an innovative design, known as a hole, for easily attaching to things without additional accessories. Similar to AirTags, and to the benefit of humankind, they have user-replaceable batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WCnU6G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The search is over: smart trackers from Apple, Samsung, and Tile compared","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22570161/apple-airtag-samsung-smarttag-tile-pro-bluetooth-tracker-review-test-comparison"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="pAuWYX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10710059"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPeJ79"&gt;The Roku Streambar is an all-in-one solution for your TV’s streaming and audio needs, and is currently $30 off from several retailers, including &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Roku-Streambar-Streaming-Premium-Released/dp/B08G8JH836?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1749571467545583546#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1595571-REG%2Froku_9102r_streambar_stereo_soundbar.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1129183/2092?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Froku-streambar---hd-4k-hdr-streaming-media-player---38--premium-audio--all-in-one--and-voice-remote-with-tv-controls--2020-%2F-%2FA-79829328" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. The compact, wall-mountable soundbar doubles as a 4K HDR streaming device complete with HDMI, USB, and optical audio ports. It’s perfect for small rooms where space is at a premium, and it will sound better than the tinny speakers found on even some larger, high-end TVs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QBXmvz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10488551"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rwEMMT"&gt;Amazon’s Fire Sticks have become table stakes in the streaming device landscape, though, at this point you probably don’t want anything still topping out at 1080p in the year 2021. This deal for $12 off the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fire-TV-Stick-4K-with-Alexa-Voice-Remote/dp/B079QHML21?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K&lt;/a&gt; brings the price of the 4K streaming stick down to a level we haven’t seen since Amazon Prime Day. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/31/18044584/amazon-fire-tv-stick-4k-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yd76MS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10710076"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MneVE7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5W9QWZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1129183/2092?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-watch-se-gps-aluminum%2F-%2FA-81498739" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; are currently selling the Apple Watch SE (40mm, GPS) for $249, a price that has only been beaten during Black Friday. You can pick from either the silver or space gray configuration on Amazon, and Target also offers the gold colorway. This is the Apple Watch to get if you’re shopping on a budget... assuming you don’t want to deal with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419569/apple-watch-series-3-software-update-reset-bad-experience" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;firmware nightmares&lt;/a&gt; that accompany the Apple Watch Series 3. The SE offers the fast performance and battery life from 2019’s flagship Series 5 watches, but for much less. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="E3rdL5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple announces watchOS 8 with new health features","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="kEdddl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514947"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iA580U"&gt;If you missed the chance &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/19/22630760/apple-ipad-airpods-imac-m1-tetris-effect-netgear-wifi-6-router-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, the AirPods Pro are still $70 off at both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1133983/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;amp;_be_shelf_id=6890999&amp;amp;search_sort=100&amp;amp;facet=shelf_id%3A6890999&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. You don’t get a better deal than this outside of Black Friday times, and you don’t get a better overall experience with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;noise-canceling wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; on iOS or macOS than the AirPods Pro. They come with small, medium, and large silicone ear tips to ensure a comfy fit that seals out ambient noise, though transparency mode can be turned on to let the outside world back in. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nvy8my"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="YASLhl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/20/22632829/tile-mate-bluetooth-tracker-roku-streambar-amazon-fire-tv-4k-apple-watch-se-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/20/22632829/tile-mate-bluetooth-tracker-roku-streambar-amazon-fire-tv-4k-apple-watch-se-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-20T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-20T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>WarioWare is more chaotic than ever on the Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MEa0GJ9YxbZwAEeQ6wQq7M0C0F0=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69752440/Switch_WarioWareGetItTogether_screen_02.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qU97Fk"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;WarioWare&lt;/em&gt; series has always been about chaos. Its self-described micro-games are so fast and strange that by the time you understand what’s going on, the game has already moved on to something new. Switch owners will be able to get a taste of that with the upcoming &lt;em&gt;WarioWare: Get It Together&lt;/em&gt; — and from what I’ve seen, it might be the most chaotic take on the series yet. Nintendo recently took me through a brief hands-off demo of the game, running through a couple of different modes. The one unifying factor between them all seemed to be a desire to take the micro-game concept to absurd new levels of mayhem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOFxPP"&gt;The main change is that there is now a cast of characters you can play as, all plucked from the &lt;em&gt;WarioWare&lt;/em&gt; universe. And each has their own unique controls and specific abilities, which can make a big difference in the seconds-long micro-games you’ll play through.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8L3jXjpA82jGWvyaL7aHzx7LBAs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22794584/Switch_WWGIT_2021_MediaPreview_VarietyPack_SCRN_03_copy.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;“Daily grind” mode.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="aEcK9k"&gt;These characters impact the main story mode, which you can play cooperatively, but from what I saw it looks like the “variety pack” mode will be where most of the fun is. Nintendo describes it as a “hub of party games,” which basically means that you’ll play through playlists that feature a series of themed challenges. One pack, called “daily grind,” features a handful of side-scrolling levels that get progressively stranger and more challenging. You start out as Wario but can collect power-ups that randomly turn you into another character, each of which has a completely different style of movement. One is on a skateboard, for instance, and will roll forward automatically, while another is a flying witch that can shoot magic spells. When you grab a power-up, you’ll have no idea which one you’ll transform into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lD2Ty1"&gt;Another pack, called “puck ‘er up,” starts out like a game of air hockey. But every time you score a goal you’ll be transported to a random micro-game. That game actually appears as a tiny window in the middle of the screen, and while the player who scores tries to finish it, everyone else can mess with them, knocking the window around or squashing it so small that the game becomes virtually unplayable. It was stressful just watching; I can only imagine how wild it would be to actually play. I foresee a lot of arguments in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5Bh731iZkYNY59yPwDiSWiBKDQI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22794585/Switch_WWGIT_2021_MediaPreview_VarietyPack_SCRN_05_copy.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;“Puck ‘er up” mode.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rdjWTX"&gt;As random as it is, &lt;em&gt;Get It Together&lt;/em&gt; does give you the option to prepare, at least a little. There’s a “play-o-pedia” mode, which is exactly what it sounds like: a playable encyclopedia. Here you get a feel for how each character controls, as well as play through endless versions of each micro-game you’ve encountered so far. It should help somewhat once you jump into the pure chaos of each game mode, where you never know what’s coming at you on a moment-to-moment basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dwj1YB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get It Together&lt;/em&gt;, which will be the first new entry in the series in three years, is launching on the Switch on September 10th, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1428525951302918145"&gt;Nintendo just released a demo on the eShop&lt;/a&gt; that you can play right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CMBvnU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mXhG00"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22632465/warioware-get-it-together-nintendo-switch-preview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22632465/warioware-get-it-together-nintendo-switch-preview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
