<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-22T12:01:12-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:01:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:01:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Our favorite things: gear, gadgets, and other stuff</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9_-_OPGsDKHCXstCcg0HgiZ-4Rc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006425/acastro_201105_4277_50guide_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We ask The Verge staff what they like to work with, play with, and cook with&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="cQDcJj"&gt;We all have our favorite stuff. It could be a laptop that you’ve used for several years or the snazzy new one that just arrived last week. It could be the headphones that deliver your favorite music and podcasts, the controller that helps you win your games, or the app that puts a weird background on your Zoom calls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DeeD2"&gt;Of course, we’re not just talking tech. We’re also talking about your favorite coffee maker, the TV shows that you binged through the pandemic, the hiking boots that have never given you a blister, and the immersion blender that your friend gave you for your birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OTJ1qT"&gt;We’ve talked to the people who work at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and asked them to tell us about their favorite stuff, whether it be for working at home, cooking, or playing. Some of these things may be what you already like to use; others may give you ideas of the kind of items you could use for yourself. Either way, we hope you enjoy reading about the things we use and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29ICxX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22344288/favorite-gadgets-tech-lgear-aptops-headphones-kitchen-recommendations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22344288/favorite-gadgets-tech-lgear-aptops-headphones-kitchen-recommendations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:00:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:00:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube is testing automatic product detection in videos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sf6qQvXKbhxDN66DLzy-UrMsfps=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006419/acastro_180403_1777_youtube_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r3Juxw"&gt;YouTube is always running experiments. One of its latest: testing an automated list of products detected in videos uploaded to the site. As of March 22nd this year, that test is being expanded to “people watching videos in the US,” according to &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/18138167?hl=en"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. (An early version of the feature was tested midway through last year, though that test was very small, reports &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/03/22/youtube-experiment-will-auto-detect-products-in-videos-and-provide-related-content-links/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nYPqi2"&gt;In one of its &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/18138167?hl=en"&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt;, a YouTube representative gave a little more detail about how this particular feature will be deployed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="azF21n"&gt;We are experimenting with a new feature that displays a list of products detected in some videos, as well as related products. The feature will appear in between the recommended videos, to viewers scrolling below the video player. The goal is to help people explore more videos and information about those products on YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="mPQyKH"&gt;Presumably, it’s a move intended to give Google its own piece of the incredibly lucrative affiliate link market, while also tying commerce directly to video uploads. These lists could function as a second recommendation algorithm, with YouTube serving videos that feature similar products. It would also put YouTube in the same shopping space as other social platforms (like &lt;a href="https://business.instagram.com/shopping"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;). Who knows! As with most experiments, it’s a little up in the air — at least until the results come in.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344553/youtube-shopping-recommendation-products-instagram"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344553/youtube-shopping-recommendation-products-instagram</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Creating WandaVision’s visual effects, from old-school sitcom gags to Vision’s CG face</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k9c_naY-UzWJO406HwF1j4aUbKo=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006382/wandavision.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="11MGML"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; was an important moment for Disney. It was the company’s first attempt to expand its Marvel Cinematic Universe to its streaming service, &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt;, after over a decade focused on theatrical releases. And a big part of keeping that continuity was the visuals. &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; was a relatively strange show, with a storyline that spanned a few decades of sitcom history, and it had the aesthetics to match. But it managed to combine black-and-white &lt;em&gt;Bewitched&lt;/em&gt;-style visuals with classic, city-spanning MCU battles in a way that somehow felt natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Yhr9u"&gt;According to Tara DeMarco, a visual effects supervisor on the show, the approach to &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;’s special effects wasn’t any different because it was destined for living rooms. “The visual effects for Marvel features and streaming [shows] are treated very similarly in terms of the expectation for the quality. And really, we’re all in service of a story,” she tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s just that some of our stories are longer than others.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e8pMNY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315094/wandavision-finale-marvel-mcu-scarlet-witch-doctor-strange-captain"&gt;Now that the show has wrapped&lt;/a&gt;, I had the chance to talk to DeMarco about creating those classic sitcom effects, designing the ever-present Hex that surrounds the town of Westview, filming those big superhero battles, and, of course, Vision’s CG face. Here are some highlights from our chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G4tFpN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This story contains light spoilers for &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WandaVision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;’s first season.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Mc94uP"&gt;On the classic sitcom visual effects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="MoC02m"&gt;The early episodes were a collaboration between all the departments — but particularly, production design and special effects and visual effects — to determine what could be achieved with puppeteers in each set. And then special effects would go away and rig the different props that we might be given by props, and then we might do different wire works as elements and combine them later. We determined ahead of time that we would get as many practical puppeteered effects as we could, and visual effects would either combine them or enhance them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFhz5v"&gt;Puppeteered effects are used in television sometimes — you just don’t know. And it’s really a way of getting an object for someone to act against and to have something real in the scene that you can take and maybe then duplicate or create in CG in another way. But we often use wires to put objects in scenes. The difference is that we were paying homage to shows that had very specifically put wire gags in that the audience would know. So the plate that heals itself is a great tip of the hat to how they would’ve done it in the era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="EpDEkx"&gt;DeMarco also notes that, while the team did plenty of research on how effects were originally done on those shows, they had some help: Dan Sudick, head of the special visual effects department, grew up with a neighbor who worked as a puppeteer on &lt;em&gt;Bewitched&lt;/em&gt;. “We had an inside source,” DeMarco says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kOsW8s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10405789"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5CA6Jp"&gt;On the Hex that covers Westview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="N7xmUG"&gt;The Hex was really driven by the story point of each scene. So that first view of it, when Monica gets pulled in, where we see the sort of invisible wall and it’s a mystery, was meant to really unsettle the audience. And so we wanted it to be slightly invisible, slightly visible, unknown, and for it to affect her in an unknown way, but using the language of television. That was driven by [director] Matt Shakman and what he wanted the tone of the scene to be, in terms of what the audience should take away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rUS5HS"&gt;Each progression of the Hex was similar in that, in the next episode, we wanted to showcase that Wanda was angry that Hayward had flown a drone into her home. So at the end of the episode, we made it red, violently red, to showcase both her power and that it was meant to be a hard boundary. She wasn’t messing around. And then in the subsequent Hexes, it was really what is important to show about Wanda either keeping people out or letting them in, and rewriting objects to fit within her Westview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PJWAX4"&gt;And each time we worked on the Hex, we just made sure that it was clear that it was made of the cathodic lines of old tube TVs and pixelization and a lot of cool RGB chromatic aberration effects so that you could see the colors split into three like the old Trinitron logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1HuR2O"&gt;DeMarco adds that keeping the Hex largely a mystery, particularly for the first few episodes, was important. “The idea was to not show it off too much,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lKrJpa"&gt;On that huge battle in the last episode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="yyR4kZ"&gt;All of the big scenes we start with first script, and then boards if we have them, and then [pre-visualization]. So there’s an evolution to all of those scenes so that we have an idea of what the work will be. Once we’ve gotten through a pre-viz scene, and [director Matt Shakman] likes the pre-viz, then we would break down each scene and try to figure out which pieces we could capture with a human or with a set, to keep as much real as possible, and then the next phase is what could we augment in CG, or what could we start with a human and then maybe do a digital double take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jbwTeM"&gt;Our last resort is an all-CG scene. Because we wanted as much real and in-camera as we could keep, knowing that it had to be big MCU beats. So we did fly a lot of actors on wires. We flew Visions on wires in a library set, we flew witches on wires on a green screen set. But we tried to get the basic elements with practical pieces as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id="RiUXey"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10405797"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="zVGjMv"&gt;On Vision’s CG face&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Wvt0WQ"&gt;I am most proud of all of our Visions. I am actually loving the fact that, after [Disney Plus behind-the-scenes documentary &lt;em&gt;Assembled&lt;/em&gt; aired], people didn’t seem to realize he had a CG face. So the fact that we were able to execute Vision through so many eras and so many looks — dead, white, on the operating table in pieces, through all of his sitcom emotion — and no one questioned that, they were focusing on Vision and the performance of the character and not on the fact that he had a CG face. That gives me the warm fuzzies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="rx0NJC"&gt;
&lt;aside id="obEAAL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus","description":"$6.99 per month or $69.99 if you pay annually","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344250/wandavision-disney-plus-visual-effects-interview-tara-demarco"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344250/wandavision-disney-plus-visual-effects-interview-tara-demarco</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T11:54:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T11:54:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Angry MacBook owners get class action status for butterfly keyboard suit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple has updated the options on the function row" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TcEZHNRHyTP-6dgttIU6jdb3xJE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006345/vpavic_4291_20201113_0428.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PqEMwp"&gt;A judge has &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.326502/gov.uscourts.cand.326502.306.2.pdf"&gt;certified a class action suit&lt;/a&gt; against Apple for its fragile butterfly keyboard design. The suit covers anyone who purchased an Apple MacBook with a butterfly keyboard in seven states: California, New York, Florida, Illinois, New Jersey, Washington, and Michigan. That includes people who bought a MacBook model dating between 2015 and 2017, a MacBook Pro model between 2016 and 2019, or a MacBook Air between 2018 and 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OSU6Sr"&gt;Judge Edward Davila certified the case with seven subclasses on March 8th in California, but the order remained sealed until late last week. It raises the stakes for a suit that was first &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2018/05/23/second-macbook-pro-keyboard-class-action/"&gt;filed in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, three years after Apple added the controversial butterfly switches to its laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ei0D91"&gt;The butterfly keyboard was slimmer than Apple’s previous design, which used industry-standard scissor switches. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/1/17366334/macbook-pro-keyboard-not-working-faulty-butterfly-lawsuit-wwdc-2018"&gt;many disgruntled MacBook users&lt;/a&gt; found that Apple’s revamped keyboard failed when even tiny particles of dust accumulated around the switches. That resulted in keys that felt “sticky,” failed to register keypresses, or registered multiple presses with a single hit. Apple tweaked its butterfly keyboard multiple times, but after continued complaints, it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246223/macbook-keyboard-butterfly-magic-pro-apple-design"&gt;abandoned the switches&lt;/a&gt; in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="eiZilm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“No matter how much lipstick you try to put on this pig ... it’s still ugly.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PistL0"&gt;This suit claims Apple knew for years that its butterfly switches were defective — and that its incremental changes weren’t fixing the core problem. It cites internal communications inside Apple, including an executive who wrote that “no matter how much lipstick you try to put on this pig [referring to the butterfly keyboard] . . . it’s still ugly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BC1CG"&gt;The plaintiffs accuse Apple of violating several laws across the seven states mentioned above, including California’s Unfair Competition Law, the Florida Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act, and the Michigan Consumer Protection Act. They aren’t asking for a nationwide certification at this time, but the law firm behind the suit has invited &lt;a href="https://www.girardsharp.com/work-pending-macbook"&gt;any US buyer&lt;/a&gt; of an affected MacBook to complete a survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qxH9XS"&gt;Apple argued against class action certification, saying one consolidated suit shouldn’t cover multiple tweaks to the butterfly keyboard. But the plaintiffs successfully argued that all butterfly keyboards may have the same fundamental problems due to their shallow design and narrow gaps between keys. “None of the design differences that Apple points to changed the tight spaces between the keys, nor the low-travel aspect of the design,” the order reads. Apple will have to argue later, in court, that these basic features didn’t actually make the design unreliable — and that it didn’t spend years knowingly making defective keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344397/apple-macbook-butterfly-keyboard-switches-defective-class-action-lawsuit-certified"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344397/apple-macbook-butterfly-keyboard-switches-defective-class-action-lawsuit-certified</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T11:44:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T11:44:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Time made a hypey crypto cover and is selling it as an NFT</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Three Time magazine front covers reading “Is God Dead?,” “Is Truth Dead?,” and “Is Fiat Dead?”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gSEwXEgfP2xr0EuuIbNNru24jyI=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006233/IMG_6850.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Time is auctioning three magazine covers as NFTs. | Image: Time&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vp4D1N"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; is the latest brand &lt;a href="https://time.com/5948741/time-nft-covers/"&gt;to jump on the NFT craze&lt;/a&gt;, with auctions for three magazine covers — including its iconic 1966 front page asking, “&lt;a href="https://superrare.co/artwork-v2/time-is-god-dead-21612"&gt;Is God Dead?&lt;/a&gt;” A more recent spin on the cover, “&lt;a href="https://superrare.co/artwork-v2/time-is-truth-dead-21650"&gt;Is Truth Dead?&lt;/a&gt;” from 2017, is also up for auction, as is a brand-new “cover” that’s not actually appearing on the magazine: “&lt;a href="https://superrare.co/artwork-v2/time-is-fiat-dead-21652"&gt;Is Fiat Dead?&lt;/a&gt;” — a phrase that sounds like catnip for the type of crypto enthusiasts likely to bid on these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uusByy"&gt;The three covers are selling on the NFT auction site SuperRare, with bids running through Wednesday evening. A minimum price of 10 Ether, or close to $18,000 USD, has been set for each cover. The “Fiat” cover is already at double that as of press time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="9yzmCS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OWLYdr"&gt;NFTs, or non-fungible tokens, are essentially blockchain-based certificates validating that someone owns a piece of digital art. Buyers typically get limited rights to display the artwork digitally, but actual creative rights generally remain with the artist. The tokens have blown up over the past month, culminating in an NFT from Beeple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325054/beeple-christies-nft-sale-cost-everydays-69-million"&gt;selling for $69 million&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z35lnj"&gt;As the format has exploded, brands have been quick to cash in on the buzz. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319868/taco-bell-nfts-gif-tacos-sell"&gt;Taco Bell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/17/22336115/charmin-nft-toilet-paper-cryptoart-marketing"&gt;Charmin&lt;/a&gt; both sold branded NFTs and donated the proceeds. Pringles sold &lt;a href="https://www.foodandwine.com/news/taco-bell-pringles-food-brands-nfts"&gt;a digital can of chips&lt;/a&gt;, and Pizza Hut Canada &lt;a href="https://www.eater.com/22337808/pizza-hut-nft-marketplace-jpeg-pizza-art"&gt;sold digital slices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EfmXOd"&gt;While those were purely marketing stunts, &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt;’s cover sale doesn’t seem all that far off. It’s a quick way to make money and get the magazine some attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SdT3lu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; didn’t indicate if the proceeds would be donated or whether it would be offsetting the environmental impact of the sales.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344403/time-nft-auction-is-fiat-dead-cover"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344403/time-nft-auction-is-fiat-dead-cover</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Resident Evil Village is coming to Stadia, and Google will give you free hardware if you buy this version</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5c1jLxze7MrGRoPhPZxRyfhSZRc=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69005987/EsRryLBXIAAE_Yd.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Q8u65h"&gt;We already knew that &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt; will release on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242218/resident-evil-8-village-release-date-trailer-ps5-ps4-xbox-pc"&gt;a slew of platforms&lt;/a&gt;, including the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S. And today, Google announced that the game will also arrive on Stadia. To encourage you to buy this version, Google will throw in a free Stadia Premiere kit to anyone who preorders &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt; before May 21st. The promotion is available for both the Standard and Deluxe Editions of &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt;, which cost $60 and $70, respectively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I6DlPc"&gt;Normally priced at $100, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1735364132370054225#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google’s Stadia Premiere Edition&lt;/a&gt; features a white Stadia controller, a Chromecast Ultra, and, for new users, a one-month trial subscription to Stadia’s Pro-tier service. Stadia Pro includes 4K streaming and a growing collection of free games, similar to Sony’s PlayStation Plus service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="PPIVzf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google had a similar promotion last year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DLVKa0"&gt;Google had a similar promotion last year when it offered &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/11/19/21572301/cyberpunk-2077-google-stadia-free-premiere-kit-preorder-deal"&gt;complimentary hardware if you preordered the Stadia version of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt; promotion announcement comes at an interesting time as Stadia’s future looks questionable. In February, Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260803/google-stadia-game-development-studio-shut-down-jade-raymond"&gt;shut down its internal Stadia development studio&lt;/a&gt;. That same month, reports from &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-26/google-video-game-unit-stadia-struggled-to-be-googley-enough"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-stadia-games-entertainment-collapse/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; shed light on some of the tech giant’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303496/google-stadia-struggle-wired-bloomberg-reports-studios"&gt;failures in building its cloud gaming platform&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H52v52"&gt;Before &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt; arrives on May 7th, Google also announced today that Stadia Pro members can redeem a free copy of &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 7 Gold Edition&lt;/em&gt; when the game launches on the cloud gaming service on April 1st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gmyaCj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22340624/resident-evil-village-google-stadia-free-premiere-kit-preorder-promotion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22340624/resident-evil-village-google-stadia-free-premiere-kit-preorder-promotion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Poco’s new phones have new-ish Snapdragon processors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mzt4Y7lQSTgD5NhCWmDF6E_REj0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69005989/DSCF7676.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FXJ9tW"&gt;Xiaomi-owned Poco has returned with two new phones that have some notable processor choices at low prices. Both the X3 Pro and the F3 use new Qualcomm chips that are essentially updated and repurposed flagship-class processors from the past couple of years, which make them an interesting price-performance proposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7002et"&gt;First up is the Poco X3 Pro (pictured above and below), which is essentially identical to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21426866/xiaomi-poco-x3-nfc-hands-on-price-specs-release"&gt;last year’s Poco X3 NFC&lt;/a&gt; but with a new processor. That means there’s still a 6.67-inch 120Hz 1080p LCD, a 5,160mAh battery with 33W fast charging, and a quad-camera setup headlined by a 48-megapixel primary sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZO4fOD"&gt;What’s new is the Qualcomm Snapdragon 860 SoC, which hasn’t previously been announced. The processor appears to be a new version of the Snapdragon 855, Qualcomm’s flagship part from two years ago found in phones like the Galaxy S10 and the Pixel 4. It uses the same Kryo 485 core based on ARM’s Cortex-A76 CPU, but the clock speed has been slightly bumped to up to 2.96GHz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LNOKrC"&gt;Poco describes the 860 as “the leading 4G flagship processor in 2021,” which doesn’t strike me as a field with a whole lot of competition. Still, it will likely outperform newer mid-range 5G chips like the 765.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/seAR_5vKNHpwmjslPQBEQtNKlH8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388255/DSCF7678.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OMJJS7"&gt;The Poco F3, meanwhile, is a higher-end device that’s one of the first phones to use Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 870, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22233584/qualcomm-snapdragon-870-865-plus-refresh-processor-smartphones-2021"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; a couple of months ago. The 870 is a similar idea to the 860 but based on the one-year-newer 865, which was Qualcomm’s highest-end chip in 2020. The CPU clock speed has again received a slight bump to a max of 3.2GHz. The 870 won’t be as fast as the 888, but another way to think of it is that it would’ve been the fastest Android phone chip in the world a couple of months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ybBjzu"&gt;The F3 itself is a rebranded version of Xiaomi’s Redmi K40, which was recently released in China. It has a 6.67-inch 120Hz 1080p OLED display, a 4,520mAh battery with 33W fast charging, and a triple-camera setup including a 48-megapixel main sensor, an 8-megapixel ultrawide, and what seems to be the same 5-megapixel “telemacro” found on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310843/xiaomi-mi-11-review-samsung"&gt;the Xiaomi Mi 11&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gh2NyF"&gt;Poco hasn’t announced full global release details yet, but the X3 Pro costs €199 for a model with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage (or €249 for 8GB/256GB), while the F3 is €299 for 6GB/128GB and €349 for 8GB/256GB. Those are early-bird prices — all models will be bumped up by €50 after April 1st for the X3 Pro and April 6th for the F3. Even after that, though, they look like very good value for their segment. Both phones will go on sale later this week.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344126/poco-f3-x3-pro-snapdragon-860-870-announced-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344126/poco-f3-x3-pro-snapdragon-860-870-announced-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Razer sets new goals to cut down its climate pollution</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Designs for a video game controller" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eIycHyO98DgNU3u7s38dhZt9iz0=/0x1:1504x1004/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69005985/Raiju_2017_design_story__2_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Razer says it will design products to create less climate pollution. | Image: Razer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gJLIzo"&gt;Razer announced today that it plans to become carbon neutral by 2030, meaning it plans to reduce and offset its carbon dioxide emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4rinai"&gt;As part of that goal, the company says its global offices will run on renewable energy by 2025. It also says it will design products to create less climate pollution and will slash emissions from its manufacturing processes. Razer is also trying to reduce waste by eliminating single-use plastics from its offices this decade and switching to biodegradable packaging for its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/razer"&gt;products&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="DYMIMD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Razer is the latest tech company to announce new climate goals for the decade&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O1ExLD"&gt;It’s the latest tech company to announce new climate goals for the decade. Razer competitor Logitech also recently made commitments to cut down on its greenhouse gas pollution. It set a goal of powering all of its electricity consumption globally from renewables by 2030. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21284528/logitech-carbon-impact-labels-products-packaging"&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt;, it started labeling its products with how much carbon dioxide they generate across their entire lifespan — from manufacturing to usage and disposal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPm70l"&gt;Larger tech companies have set even more ambitious goals. Microsoft has been carbon neutral since 2012. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254483/microsoft-climate-change-pledge-update-carbon-dioxide-removal"&gt;recently pledged&lt;/a&gt; to remove more carbon dioxide from the atmosphere than it releases by 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TWGu0z"&gt;All of these commitments are supposed to prevent climate change from getting much worse than it already is. Global carbon dioxide emissions need to reach close to zero by 2050 in order to avoid the worst effects of climate change, &lt;a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/2018/10/08/summary-for-policymakers-of-ipcc-special-report-on-global-warming-of-1-5c-approved-by-governments/"&gt;according to leading climate scientists&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="01Ioer"&gt;To keep the world on track, companies like Razer will need to be transparent about their progress toward their new goals. Razer hasn’t specified what proportion of its emissions it plans to actually cut versus how much it will try to offset or cancel out by investing in things like forest conservation projects. The company said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that reducing emissions by turning to renewable energy is “a priority” — but when that’s “not available or possible,” then it will rely on things like forest-related offsets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="e95cZM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Razer will need to be transparent about its progress&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LUTADp"&gt;Razer recently pledged to “&lt;a href="https://press.razer.com/company-news/razer-and-the-global-gaming-community-push-to-save-one-million-trees-with-sneki-snek/"&gt;save&lt;/a&gt;” 1 million trees by fundraising for the nonprofit group Conservation International. It’s selling plushies of its mascot “Sneki Snek” and other merchandise to raise money for the effort. Trees &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; trap and store carbon dioxide — but relying on them to save our butts from climate change has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/31/21115862/davos-1-trillion-trees-controversy-world-economic-forum-campaign"&gt;faced criticism from scientists&lt;/a&gt;. There’s been a history of &lt;a href="https://features.propublica.org/brazil-carbon-offsets/inconvenient-truth-carbon-credits-dont-work-deforestation-redd-acre-cambodia/"&gt;forestry projects failing&lt;/a&gt; to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in the long term. That means for Razer to have the biggest impact on the climate, it will have to follow through on cutting down emissions as much as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344344/gaming-razer-climate-change-goals-carbon-neutral-energy-waste"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344344/gaming-razer-climate-change-goals-carbon-neutral-energy-waste</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>DoorDash will let you order at-home COVID-19 testing kits delivered to your door</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iq-ByWCgYFEMr89hi7KUNXdg1PU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69005664/acastro_190724_1777_doordash_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Rwwgy8"&gt;DoorDash has partnered with two US-based digital health companies, Vault Health and Everlywell, to help distribute at-home COVID-19 test kits across the country, the company announced on Monday. The partnerships will allow DoorDash customers to order the testing kits directly from the company’s app in 12 markets or, conversely, to order the kits from &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vaulthealth.com%2Fcovid&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F22%2F22340706%2Fdoordash-covid-home-testing-kits-delivery-vault-health-everlywell" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Vault Health’s website&lt;/a&gt; in 20 markets with same-day delivery from DoorDash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AZ8N9x"&gt;Both kits contain polymerase chain reaction (PCR) tests, which is a molecular test and considered the most accurate of the testing varieties on the market. Both kits have also received emergency use authorization from the Food and Drug Administration for at-home testing. The Everlywell testing kit ($109) is a self-administered nasal swab that can be done unsupervised, while the Vault Health kit ($119) is a saliva test that involves supervision from a staffer over Zoom. Both companies promise to return results within 24 to 48 hours. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P4I_CNNHLXjnkCyXjuu2DR-ZMY4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22388449/PRImage_COVIDTests.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: DoorDash&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HC5VXK"&gt;The markets supported by the DoorDash app include Baltimore, Chicago, Cleveland, Dallas, Denver, Minneapolis, and Phoenix, with more cities to be added soon, the company says. Vault Health’s direct online order option will be supported in Baltimore, Chicago, Houston, Las Vegas, Phoenix, and San Diego, among other markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4dUolQ"&gt;The initiative is part of DoorDash’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/5/21355625/doordash-dashmart-convenience-store-launch-snacks-groceries"&gt;DashMart convenience store platform&lt;/a&gt;, a new type of virtual marketplace the company launched last summer as the pandemic was in full swing. DashMarts act similar to a CVS or 7-Eleven but they’re available at all hours of the day from the DoorDash app for ordering convenience store items, light food and groceries, and other products you’d typically find at a corner store or pharmacy. The stores also source from a variety of different vendors, so there’s just not one list of limited inventory to choose  from. In some cases, DoorDash even sources local restaurants’ products to give DashMart the feel of a boutique store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ixwCgZ"&gt;Now, in addition to buying supplies, food, and other items, you’ll also be able to start buying COVID-19 testing kits in what DoorDash is positioning as a push into health products. “Amidst the pandemic, one of our priorities has been to make health and wellness essentials more accessible for customers, with the goal of helping businesses leverage our last-mile logistics infrastructure to provide more convenient and timely access to their health supplies,” Anna Katherine Barnett-Hart, director of new verticals at DoorDash, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22340706/doordash-covid-home-testing-kits-delivery-vault-health-everlywell"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22340706/doordash-covid-home-testing-kits-delivery-vault-health-everlywell</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T09:58:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T09:58:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Get an unlocked Google Pixel 4 or 4 XL starting at $250 on eBay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tJLWl5AOHdNzJa3tD-JMv9oF3i4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69005650/vpavic_191018_3725_0231.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eB088h"&gt;A well-rated eBay seller is offering the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20923660/google-pixel-4-xl-review-camera-radar-face-unlock-90hz-display-telephoto"&gt;Google Pixel 4 and 4 XL&lt;/a&gt; phones at very reasonable prices for a limited time. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2FGoogle-Pixel-4-64GB-White-Factory-Unlocked-LTE-Smartphone-Open-Box%2F124640555584%3F_trkparms%3Daid%253D1110006%2526algo%253DHOMESPLICE.SIM%2526ao%253D1%2526asc%253D231488%2526meid%253D6058a787dee94b6bafe322d3ec1fdd0a%2526pid%253D101195%2526rk%253D1%2526rkt%253D12%2526mehot%253Dpf%2526sd%253D143980997914%2526itm%253D124640555584%2526pmt%253D1%2526noa%253D0%2526pg%253D2047675%2526algv%253DSimplAMLv9PairwiseUnbiasedWebDarwoV3%2526brand%253DGoogle%26_trksid%3Dp2047675.c101195.m1851%26mkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338421468%26toolid%3D20008%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F3%2F22%2F22344285%2Fgoogle-pixel-4-xl-amazon-target-sale-nintendo-switch-pro-controller-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 4 in white with 64GB of storage costs $250&lt;/a&gt;, while the larger &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2FGoogle-Pixel-4-XL-G020J-64GB-Just-Black-Unlocked-OpenBox-%2F143980997914%3Fmkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338421468%26toolid%3D20008%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F3%2F22%2F22344285%2Fgoogle-pixel-4-xl-amazon-target-sale-nintendo-switch-pro-controller-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 4 XL in black with the same amount of storage costs $280&lt;/a&gt;. Each of these phones will arrive factory unlocked and be usable with most carriers that support 4G LTE. They’re in new / open-box condition, which the seller indicates as meaning the phones show no signs of wear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KV6GXu"&gt;eBay allows up to 60 days to make a return, and the phones are covered with a 90-day warranty. It’s unclear if these models are still covered by Google’s one-year manufacturer warranty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D6AlOh"&gt;This could be a good deal for you if you have either the Pixel 2 or Pixel 3 and want to extend how long you’ll get major software updates without breaking the bank. (The Pixel 2 won’t get Android 12, while it’s the last big update for the Pixel 3.) For the price, the Pixel 4 offers better performance than the Pixel 3A and 4A, as well as a 90Hz refresh rate screen to make everything animate more fluidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mrDlTK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10405822"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TE4ztayY5HkGf_xhrrHcIBNB8sw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22263301/play_your_way.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: IO Interactive&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="se5WOo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fbuy-2-get-1-free-mix-match%2F-%2FN-93tfb&amp;amp;subid1=TheVergeDailyDealRoundup3222021"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/promotion/A23GESP2UC1NP8"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; are both offering “buy two, get one free” promotions on books, music, movies, and video games. The deal works the same way regardless of where you shop: add a total of three items to your cart, then the one with the lowest price will be marked down at checkout. You can filter the view at each store to show you just movies, or just video games, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0dAKQ"&gt;Some inclusions that might be of interest to &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers are &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings Trilogy&lt;/em&gt;  on 4K Blu-ray, &lt;em&gt;Hitman 3&lt;/em&gt; for PS5, &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt; on PS4, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6yrravQwglpzWOC1tZVT479bwzQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/8028811/jbareham_170221_1475_0010.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kuTwx3"&gt;Speaking of video games, if you have a Nintendo Switch, you owe it to yourself to get the best controller made for that platform. Nintendo’s own Switch Pro controller is usually $70 (rarely dropping in price), but it’s $59 at a few retailers right now. I know, that’s the price of a new game, but if you value comfort, long-lasting battery life, and just all-around good build quality, you should pick this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IuNbm0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10397609"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/22/22344285/google-pixel-4-xl-amazon-target-sale-nintendo-switch-pro-controller-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/22/22344285/google-pixel-4-xl-amazon-target-sale-nintendo-switch-pro-controller-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
