<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-25T14:25:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T14:25:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T14:25:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch, owned by Amazon, pulls Amazon’s anti-union ads</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fkl2h5YThPKwhZbXStIkKlp8S48=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68875431/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="90e0WO"&gt;Twitch is removing the anti-union ads that its parent company, Amazon, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MorePerfectUS/status/1364318690271969285?s=20"&gt;was running on the platform&lt;/a&gt;. The ads showed Amazon employees talking about why they want to vote no on unionization and directed viewers to Amazon’s “DoItWithoutDues” website. A Twitch spokesperson said the ads “should never have been allowed to run on [the] service,” as they violate its political advertising policies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qhGp1D"&gt;Twitch also says that it is “evaluating [its] review processes to ensure that similar content does not run in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UcC1Vz"&gt;The ads were reported by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MorePerfectUS/status/1364328210771681293?s=20"&gt;More Perfect Union&lt;/a&gt;; their removal was first reported by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Slasher/status/1365007592754466825?s=20"&gt;Rod Breslau&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NTaiST"&gt;The ads were the latest entry in a long campaign aimed at disrupting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272213/amazon-union-bhm1-alabama-rwdsu-vote-begins"&gt;organization efforts at an Amazon warehouse outside of Birmingham, Alabama&lt;/a&gt;. Those efforts involve pulling employees into mandatory meetings, near-daily texts to employees, relentless anti-union posters in the workplace, and even reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287191/amazon-alabama-warehouse-union-traffic-light-change-bessemer"&gt;changing the timing of traffic lights to disrupt a union drive&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon running the ads on a streaming platform it owns, however, was a very public move. It’s unclear if the company was targeting certain streams or viewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IiOUkB"&gt;Neither Amazon nor the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union was immediately available for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vE19Pj"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Amazon is running a second ad on Twitch in Alabama urging its workers in Bessemer to vote no on the union. &lt;a href="https://t.co/q3wTc0o7Im"&gt;pic.twitter.com/q3wTc0o7Im&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— More Perfect Union (@MorePerfectUS) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MorePerfectUS/status/1364328210771681293?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xfhlPP"&gt;The union has also been having its own media push, with &lt;a href="https://www.al.com/news/2021/02/danny-glover-bessemer-amazon-union-effort-a-strategic-moment-for-labor.html"&gt;actor Danny Glover&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/staceyabrams/status/1363282664384520193"&gt;Georgia politician Stacey Abrams&lt;/a&gt; encouraging workers to vote “yes.” Both talked about their connection with the South and how their upbringings and parents gave them respect for unions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YpDr4s"&gt;The unionization fight comes after a string of troubling news for Amazon workers: the company allegedly forced its warehouse workers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266369/amazon-ten-hour-overnight-shifts-warehouse-workers"&gt;to work 10-hour overnight shifts&lt;/a&gt;, made plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22265031/amazon-netradyne-driveri-survelliance-cameras-delivery-monitor-packages"&gt;install always-on surveillance cameras in its delivery vehicles&lt;/a&gt;, and is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287204/new-york-amazon-lawsuit-worker-safety-failures"&gt;being sued by the state of New York&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly failing to keep its frontline workers safe during the COVID-19 pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VpowZT"&gt;The Alabama unionization vote began on February 8th and is scheduled to conclude on March 29th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301352/twitch-removes-amazon-anti-union-ads"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301352/twitch-removes-amazon-anti-union-ads</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T14:17:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T14:17:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>A $329 Nvidia RTX 3060 was impossible to find, but you could give Newegg’s raffle a try</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3-PwdazZRscIXFarS_Pr3zZt3yM=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68875373/shollister_200224_4441_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fCqybd"&gt;Nvidia &lt;em&gt;supposedly&lt;/em&gt; launched a $329 graphics card today, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22300659/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-review"&gt;the GeForce RTX 3060&lt;/a&gt;, but I’ve yet to see much proof. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HDbKA7"&gt;Orders began today at 9AM PT / 12PM ET for a card whose listed prices ranged from $329.99 &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-floods-us-retailers-starting-from-329-to-629"&gt;all the way up to $629.99&lt;/a&gt;, averaging $471. Those aren’t scalper prices, mind you. They’re the retail prices set by Nvidia’s partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0lTz8Q"&gt;As far as I can tell, the only places that actually claimed to stock a card for $329.99 were Newegg and EVGA’s own website, and neither simply put the card on sale: Newegg is only raffling off chances to buy the cards, and EVGA has a queue where you hit a “notify me” button. In both cases, you wait for the company to hopefully email you back with good news.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3_3NgODyeeBdicylvMKe2l_grWU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22328790/newegg_3060.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newegg listings pointed you straight to the Newegg Shuffle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eqZqkM"&gt;The raffle and queue are good things, in my opinion! It means you might maybe possibly have a chance to actually get one. You have until 12PM PT / 3PM ET today to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fproduct-shuffle&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F25%2F22301391%2Fnvidia-rtx-3060-launch-supply-demand-newegg-shuffle" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;enter the Newegg Shuffle&lt;/a&gt;, which features a PS5 bundle as well, and you’ll know by 2PM PT / 5PM ET if you luck out. But it also means we’ll have little evidence that $329 is the actual price of this GPU. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQCoPd"&gt;There’s also a question of whether Nvidia initially managed to ship many 3060s. Queues and raffles aside, today seemed to have some of the most sparse GPU availability yet, with some accusing Nvidia of a “paper launch” &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/amds-radeon-rx-6800-cards-sell-out-instantly-sparking-cries-of-paper-launch"&gt;much like AMD’s RX 6800 series in November&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;PCGamer&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/news/live/where-to-buy-nvidia-rtx-3060-graphics-card/"&gt;gave up live-blogging the launch&lt;/a&gt; after an hour of failure. Best Buy barely had them. At some other retailers, they never showed up. I saw listings for some versions straight-up pulled off the web. Micro Center only had them in store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9kBB1h"&gt;One bright spot (for US gamers anyhow): Best Buy wound up restocking a variety of &lt;em&gt;other &lt;/em&gt;Nvidia GPUs today, with the 3060 Ti, 3070, and even the hardest-to-find 3080 popping up from time to time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RO1N3D"&gt;In fact, it may have shown just how rough the RTX 3060 launch is: I was sitting &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/falcodrin"&gt;Falcodrin’s Twitch channel&lt;/a&gt;, a popular hangout where people try to track down the cards and share their success, and Falcodrin ran a poll where &lt;em&gt;only two people &lt;/em&gt;admitted to nabbing a 3060 at all:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kE7FT3E2zy5M7r_NWUbtjbTZu4Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22328803/falcodrin_poll_600.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Falcodrin’s poll.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jaNeOp"&gt;It’s also worth noting that at least two of the four supposedly $329.99 graphics cards look suspiciously like token offerings to meet that price. EVGA has a second near-identical version of the 3060 with a very slightly higher boost clock that retails for $390.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NYoPw_FT5gqiSdOjT__oRWh1wmY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22328825/evga_cards.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ll let you guess which one’s the less expensive “Black” model.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nNA5JU"&gt;And while Newegg might be listing Zotac’s 3060 Twin Edge for $329.99, Zotac itself lists it and briefly sold &lt;a href="https://www.zotacstore.com/us/zotac-gaming-geforce-rtx-3060-twin-edge-zt-a30600e-10m"&gt;the exact same card&lt;/a&gt; this morning for $479.99. (I saw the add to cart button on one refresh, but Zotac’s website crapped out, and it was out of stock as soon as I returned.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cqI2jk"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22300659/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-review"&gt;The RTX 3060 is a good card&lt;/a&gt;, but even at $330, I think you might want to wait and see what’s next since the 3060 Ti is so much better. At $400 and up, that goes double. But maybe you didn’t have a choice to begin with. We’re asking Nvidia if it has more thoughts, and we’ll let you know what we hear. EVGA would only confirm that it’s shipping a $329.99 GPU, and that “we have more supply on the way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="qeVYnz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nvidia GeForce RTX 3060 review: $329 with an asterisk sign","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22300659/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="7bVNT1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AV6H2e"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301391/nvidia-rtx-3060-launch-supply-demand-newegg-shuffle"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301391/nvidia-rtx-3060-launch-supply-demand-newegg-shuffle</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T14:04:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T14:04:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>The House’s three big ideas to take on tech power</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Second Senate Impeachment Trial Of Donald Trump" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ARqdgguGZbwlc-wI_fDxWkHRMlo=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68875284/1231142725.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AulRfL"&gt;Last year, House Judiciary Committee lawmakers topped off a yearslong investigation into anti-competitive behavior in the tech industry by bringing in some of the most powerful chief executives in the market. Apple CEO Tim Cook, Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos, Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg, and Google CEO Sundar Pichai headlined one of the biggest must-watch hearings last summer and they faced tough lines of questioning from lawmakers who (for the most part) did their homework, prepped with thousands of pages of evidence alleging illegal business practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DMzajB"&gt;Lawmakers shined a light on some of tech’s shady business practices, and now they’re getting ready to finish the job. On Thursday, the House Judiciary’s subcommittee on antitrust returned for a far less flashy hearing with experts. It’s the beginning of a second and far more important phase of the committee’s work, pinning down new rules that would address those practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJiO1D"&gt;On paper, Thursday’s hearing was about analyzing how big tech platforms act as gatekeepers and create barriers to entry — but really it was about testing out three new avenues for keeping tech companies in line and seeing which ones might gain support from tech-skeptical Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1Y76bA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;WATCH IT LIVE: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HouseJudiciary?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@HouseJudiciary&lt;/a&gt; Holds Hearing on Proposals to Address Gatekeeper Power and Lower Barriers to Entry Online&lt;a href="https://t.co/JowR9n9JY0"&gt;https://t.co/JowR9n9JY0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— House Judiciary Dems (@HouseJudiciary) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HouseJudiciary/status/1364954993783144457?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="esBtra"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT IT MEANS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="67hO7r"&gt;Arguably, the most revealing parts of last year’s hearing with tech CEOs had to do with their abilities to shove competitors out of the market. Zuckerberg was pressed over an email from former Instagram CEO Kevin Systrom saying that the Facebook CEO would go “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21335706/antitrust-hearing-highlights-facebook-google-amazon-apple-congress-testimony"&gt;destroy mode&lt;/a&gt;” if Instagram didn’t sell. Bezos said he couldn’t “guarantee” that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21347083/jeff-bezos-amazon-tech-antitrust-hearing-jayapal-questioning"&gt;Amazon employees weren’t looking&lt;/a&gt; at data from independent sellers to help develop their own products. Cook and Pichai &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21335706/antitrust-hearing-highlights-facebook-google-amazon-apple-congress-testimony"&gt;were both&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21346999/google-sundar-pichai-antitrust-hearing-business-model-david-cicilline-questioning"&gt;pressed on reports&lt;/a&gt; that they used their platforms to squash competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jKhC0h"&gt;But at Thursday’s hearing, the subcommittee moved beyond calling out bad behavior and laid out three big areas where Congress could actually take action. They’re still general ideas instead of specific proposals, but you can expect to see these same ideas in whatever tech regulation bills come forward over the next few months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uubzd3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big three: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XUWG9Z"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Data interoperability and portability:&lt;/strong&gt; Users should be able to take their data elsewhere with ease. &lt;em&gt;Example: Think about how you can move your phone number between carriers. Before the 1996 Telecommunications Act, that wasn’t always an option!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MFGxaV"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nondiscrimination:&lt;/strong&gt; Basically, a dominant platform shouldn’t be able to preference its own products over those of its competitors. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SJJWNg"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Structural remedies:&lt;/strong&gt; Breaking apart different lines of business or platforms under one company. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="wfwDLE"&gt;Portability and interoperability rules are the measure that’s least threatening to tech companies. A bunch of those products were released in the wake of the GDPR, and it’s easy for Facebook and Google to develop more without touching their core businesses. Nondiscrimination is a little scarier — particularly for Apple and Amazon — but it’s still workable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DgnFWU"&gt;Some of those ideas might even get bipartisan support. &lt;a href="https://buck.house.gov/sites/buck.house.gov/files/wysiwyg_uploaded/Buck%20Report.pdf"&gt;In his Third Way&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;report last year&lt;/a&gt;, Rep. Ken Buck (R-CO) called for data portability and more funding for antitrust regulators at the Justice Department and FTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="57n7tn"&gt;But the antitrust wing of the Democratic Party won’t be satisfied with a few new app store rules and a little more money for the FTC. In &lt;a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=3429"&gt;their recommendations last October&lt;/a&gt;, Democrats on the committee called for a kind of Glass-Steagall Act for the internet, breaking apart different lines of business in response to monopoly concerns. It would lay the groundwork for splitting off Instagram from Facebook or Amazon Web Services from Amazon — basically leveling the tech landscape by force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yUPsdV"&gt;This is the worst-case scenario for tech companies — and as much as Republicans complain about Jeff Bezos, they still largely oppose the idea. It’s hard to imagine a trust-busting bill attracting support from fence-sitters like Rep. Buck, much less the more tech-friendly members of the caucus. Just like in the stimulus and minimum-wage fights, Democrats have to decide whether to play for a bipartisan fix or push through a more progressive policy on their own. But judging from this hearing, Democrats aren’t ready to give up on a full-scale breakup just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gwkehJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT DIDN’T THEY ASK? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="cpjLoI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22222637/amazon-workers-aws-stop-hosting-services-parler-capitol-violence"&gt;Amazon kicked Parler off its web hosting service&lt;/a&gt; after last month’s deadly attack on the Capitol. Parler was a popular platform with the rioters who stormed the Capitol, and without Amazon’s web hosting, the platform was effectively kicked offline until it could &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/15/22284036/parler-social-network-relaunch-new-hosting"&gt;find a new company to host the site in mid-February&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OSJJfA"&gt;Since Parler was deplatformed, &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; Republicans have turned away from Section 230 reform and toward antitrust as a remedy to their beef with a focus on Amazon. Republican FCC commissioners have used the incident to make shaky comparisons to network neutrality and cloud infrastructure. But after Parler went down, Ranking Member Buck tweeted that he would be “introducing legislation this Congress to hold Amazon accountable for their anticompetitive behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SA55Jh"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Amazon crushes small businesses. They cheat and steal. Now they want to join Google and Facebook in censoring. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I will be introducing legislation this Congress to hold Amazon accountable for their anticompetitive behavior. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BigTechReckoning?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#BigTechReckoning&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/lChxvMFFuZ"&gt;https://t.co/lChxvMFFuZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Congressman Ken Buck (@RepKenBuck) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepKenBuck/status/1348105739760504834?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lG5k0b"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s what I would have liked to hear from Republicans:   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="HsyKfQ"&gt;How do cloud services like AWS fit into antitrust reform outside of just providing an additional line of revenue for companies? What if Amazon deplatformed a nascent e-commerce platform using its services?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iLxvq7"&gt;What are the ramifications of stripping companies like Amazon from their cloud services? Should this be included in any measures the committee proposes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZGg5aN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT’S NEXT? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ctIafC"&gt;The House Judiciary Committee’s subcommittee on antitrust &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/house-begins-brewing-new-tech-antitrust-laws-ae61ef26-12d2-4516-89df-6797bfecd249.html"&gt;still has two more hearings&lt;/a&gt; to complete before they start filing legislation. They’re expecting to start introducing those bills this spring, but that doesn’t mean they’ll become law anytime soon. There will likely be even more hearings and a markup process before those bills get close to votes on the floor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4boLNR"&gt;We also need to hear what the Senate is thinking. Sen. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN), the chair of the Senate’s antitrust panel, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/04/klobuchar-unveils-sweeping-antitrust-bill-laying-out-her-vision-as-new-subcommittee-chair-.html"&gt;introduced the Competition and Antitrust Law Enforcement Reform Act&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month that doesn’t do nearly as much as the House is considering for legislation. Klobuchar’s bill would provide antitrust enforcers with more resources to bring cases to trial and conduct extensive reviews of markets and merger effects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="odMhz0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301453/antitrust-facebook-google-amazon-apple-reform-cicilline-buck"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301453/antitrust-facebook-google-amazon-apple-reform-cicilline-buck</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T14:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T14:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How one of Google’s massive undersea cables detects earthquakes  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T9DSPP8IIwTaDZ-2NHHSlD2R1wQ=/0x5:2040x1365/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68875224/GettyImages_695501024.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An operator works during the mooring of an undersea fiber optic cable at Arrietara beach near the Spanish Basque village of Sopelana on June 13, 2017.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Ander Gillenea / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Em5EY7"&gt;The web of undersea cables that transmit data around the world could one day be used to track earthquakes and tsunamis, according to new research. During a test run last year, one of Google’s fiber-optic cables was able to successfully pick up on nearby earthquakes by detecting distortions in light pulses sent along the cable. It’s a new approach to an idea that researchers have been working on for the past several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="K0myoE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Can we find a less expensive way to cover the ocean with geophysical sensors? &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W1VWT5"&gt;“Can we find a less expensive way to cover the ocean with geophysical sensors? There’s already this telecommunication cable infrastructure out there. If you can turn them into sensors, that’s wonderful — and that’s what we’re doing now,” says Zhongwen Zhan, an assistant professor of geophysics at the California Institute of Technology and lead author of the research published today in the &lt;a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/cgi/doi/10.1126/science.abe6648"&gt;journal &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dJrhz7"&gt;On top of their main job of sending data all over the world, these cables could one day send early warnings to people on shore when a tsunami is barreling their way. They could also give seismologists and geophysicists a closer look at earthquakes that occur underwater. Since nearly all the sensors currently used to detect earthquakes are on land, these cables could fill in huge gaps in scientists’ ability to observe seismic activity. The novel approach doesn’t even require installing any new equipment to the existing web of more than a million kilometers of fiber optic cables that cut across the seafloor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2QVdAl"&gt;The new approach capitalizes on what the cables are already designed to do. When a transmitter at one end of the cable sends out a light signal transmitting data, light waves are oriented in a particular direction. If an earthquake hits, it might shake, bend, or twist the cable — and that changes the orientation of the light waves. At the other end of the cable, Google notices distortions and corrects them. Now, it wants to share its data, changes to what’s called the “state of polarization” of light, with seismologists like Zhan so they can study the earthquakes that caused the distortions.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGh9tM"&gt;Between December 2019 and September 2020, Zhan’s research team documented roughly 20 moderate to large earthquakes using Google’s 10,500-kilometer-long cable, Curie, which runs from Los Angeles, California to Valparaíso, Chile. The cable was also able to pick up swells in the ocean caused by storms. That suggests the technique can also be used to spot tsunamis, which earthquakes can trigger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="5Yq75Q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The ability to see tsunamis while they’re still far from shore could save lives&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Cme1Hw"&gt;The ability to see tsunamis while they’re still far from shore could save lives. Beyond having a better view of the ocean than the small number of existing sensors specifically designed to look for tsunamis, fiber optic cables can also send warnings to shore much faster — perhaps in a matter of milliseconds, according to Google. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0YHEEb"&gt;“We’re humbled and excited by the possibility of collaborating with the optical, subsea and seismic research communities to use all of our cable infrastructure for greater societal benefits,” Google wrote in a &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/infrastructure/using-subsea-cables-to-detect-earthquakes"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; last July, shortly after the company had reached out to Zhan to further develop the new approach to seismic sensing on the seafloor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BB6UzU"&gt;“We hope this new approach can really give people a better chance of catching those events early on, so that people have more time to react,” Zhan says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FuJdxQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/06/seafloor-cables-carry-world-s-internet-traffic-can-also-detect-earthquakes"&gt;In 2018&lt;/a&gt;, similar research was published that showed that seafloor cables had the potential to detect earthquakes and tsunamis — but that approach came with some limitations. Cables needed to be fitted with specialized equipment to shoot lasers down the cable. In comparison, this new approach saves money because it doesn’t require any new infrastructure. There were also concerns that adding equipment to the cables could open the door to security breaches, allowing bad actors to access data sent across the network. Zhan says that’s not an issue with the new approach; scientists can’t see information about the transmitted content when studying the polarization of light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EEjWrA"&gt;“It’s a perfectly safe way of leveraging pre-existing infrastructures to do something that is good for the society and science,” Zhan says.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22301097/google-undersea-cable-detects-earthquakes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22301097/google-undersea-cable-detects-earthquakes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T13:46:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T13:46:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Jeff Bezos’ Blue Origin delays New Glenn debut to late 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nnW9X2nmaDTeEOnzpq5TgjwP0Cs=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68875122/blueorigin_newglenn_launch_web.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;An illustration showing Blue Origin’s New Glenn rocket standing on its launchpad in Cape Canaveral, Florida. | Blue Origin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UBjdDT"&gt;Blue Origin is delaying the debut launch of its massive, centerpiece rocket New Glenn to late 2022, the company announced Thursday, citing a key Pentagon contract it lost out on to rival firms SpaceX and United Launch Alliance as the reason for the delay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m0PxOB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/4/21164469/blue-origin-payload-fairing-nose-cone-new-glenn-rocket-completed"&gt;New Glenn&lt;/a&gt; is a massive, partially reusable heavy-lift rocket designed to launch anything from national security payloads and commercial satellites. Its first flight was previously slated for sometime in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xT0fhY"&gt;“The current target for New Glenn’s maiden flight is Q4 2022,” the company &lt;a href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/new-glenns-progress-towards-maiden-flight"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in a statement on Thursday. “The Blue Origin team has been in contact with all of our customers to ensure this baseline meets their launch needs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MsA78Q"&gt;Jeff Bezos, Blue Origin’s founder and &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/16/jeff-bezos-reclaims-spot-as-worlds-richest-person-from-elon-musk.html"&gt;currently&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the world’s richest man, has invested billions into the New Glenn program, which has involved the construction of sprawling rocket production facilities in Cape Canaveral, Florida and an extensive renovation to the Space Coast’s Launch Complex 36, which Blue Origin leased in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Vs9vOH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;That loss “was a big hit for us”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SzbocS"&gt;The company bid for hefty launch contracts under the Air Force’s next-generation national security launch program, which guaranteed two winning rocket companies multibillion-dollar contracts and a share of all Pentagon launches between 2022 to 2027. The Air Force &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/7/21359219/spacex-ula-us-defense-department-award-rocket-launch"&gt;announced its decision last year&lt;/a&gt; — Blue Origin lost out to SpaceX and United Launch Alliance (a joint venture between Boeing and Lockheed Martin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YVXUl8"&gt;That loss “was a big hit for us,” Jarrett Jones, Blue Origin’s senior vice president for New Glenn, &lt;a href="https://spacenews.com/blue-origin-delays-first-launch-of-new-glenn-to-late-2022/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;SpaceNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, claiming it cost Blue Origin up to $3 billion. The design of New Glenn was partially tailored to send Pentagon satellites to space, and Blue Origin executives “had to consider the economics” when the Air Force went with other companies instead, Jones said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7GWuUa"&gt;“We hope to launch [national security] payloads in the future, and remain committed to serving the U.S. national defense mission,” a Blue Origin statement said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WboQsA"&gt;Blue Origin received $255 million of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/10/17961832/defense-department-launch-service-agreement-ula-blue-origin-northrop-grumman"&gt;$500 million award from the Air Force&lt;/a&gt; as part of a precursor program to aid New Glenn development. As planned, the company was cut off from the award’s full amount after losing in the subsequent program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DNpHff"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Freed from Amazon, Bezos is expected to refocus on Blue Origin&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jnkm20"&gt;But Bezos, unshackled from Amazon after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263039/amazon-new-ceo-jeff-bezos-andy-jassy-executive-chair-board-q3-2021"&gt;announcing his decision to step down as CEO&lt;/a&gt;, is now expected to ramp up his involvement in managing Blue Origin, which he founded as a passion project in 2000. He &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/5/15200102/jeff-bezos-amazon-stock-blue-origin-space-travel-funding"&gt;said in 2017 he was liquidating $1 billion a year&lt;/a&gt; in Amazon stock  to help fund Blue Origin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o5GIbN"&gt;Though it has yet to reach orbit and has fallen well behind SpaceX, which Elon Musk founded in 2002, Blue Origin in recent years has stepped up its competitive footing in the space industry. It’s currently leading a team of established defense companies in a bid to provide &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22258815/nasa-moon-lander-awards-biden-spacex-blue-origin-moonshot"&gt;NASA’s next ride to the moon&lt;/a&gt; with its human lunar lander Blue Moon. SpaceX is also vying for that award with its Starship rocket system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MFAcb3"&gt;Another crucial business line for the company is its liquid BE-4 rocket engine that powers New Glenn. That engine &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/27/17909342/blue-origin-be-4-engine-united-launch-alliance-vulcan-rocket"&gt;will also power United Launch Alliance’s rocket, Vulcan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;— the same one that beat New Glenn to a lucrative Pentagon contract. Vulcan is on target for a late 2021 debut launch. And after some development hiccups last year, Blue Origin is expected to ship the flight-ready BE-4 engines to ULA in mid-2021 to keep Vulcan on schedule. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4jal3gQUxSKzR_5h1weKUMvscrs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22328673/blueorigin_floridacampus_aerial_2021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Blue Origin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An aerial view of Blue Origin’s massive rocket factory in Florida, just outside the gates of NASA’s Kennedy Space Center.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JZCFBK"&gt;In the meantime, Blue Origin is taking its time with New Glenn (its motto, Gradatim Ferociter, is Latin for “Step by step, ferociously”). A test version of a New Glenn first stage briefly &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WordsmithFL/status/1360246535225810945?s=20"&gt;emerged from the company’s Florida facilities&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month, giving rocket enthusiasts one of the first major peaks at some New Glenn hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iBBVt3"&gt;And the company’s new Tank Cleaning and Testing facility, toured in a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/blueorigin/status/1364968720364429317?s=20"&gt;video it tweeted&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, has become one of the only buildings tall enough to share the Cape Canaveral skyline with NASA’s behemoth Vehicle Assembly Building, which stands tall a few miles away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wwj5t4"&gt;Blue Origin said its expanse on Florida’s Space Coast has led to “more than 600 jobs” and represents an investment of $2.5 billion, which includes $1 billion to revamp Launch Complex 36, “which is nearing completion.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301172/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-delays-new-glenn-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301172/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-delays-new-glenn-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T13:33:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T13:33:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter planning a feature to let you auto-block and mute abusive accounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yMhBh6q_mT1LeR1BX2CSpVlLSMc=/0x83:1898x1348/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68875042/twitter_auto_block.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Twitter safety mode mockup. | Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dgZp9v"&gt;Twitter plans to introduce a way for you to automatically block and mute abusive accounts, the company announced at its Analyst Day presentation on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T6TFyA"&gt;It appears the feature will be a toggle you can turn on in a new “safety mode,” according to a slide in the &lt;a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/826641620/files/doc_presentations/Analyst_Day_2021/3_AnalystDay2021_Kayvon-Dantley.pdf"&gt;Analyst Day slide deck&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s Twitter’s description of how the toggle will work if you flip it on: “Automatically block accounts that appear to break the Twitter Rules, and mute accounts that might be using insults, name-calling, strong language, or hateful remarks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bi2JPu"&gt;With the new safety mode, Twitter will automatically detect accounts that “might be acting abusive or spammy” and limit how those accounts can engage with your content for seven days, according to the slide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KsNNmW"&gt;We’ve asked Twitter for more information about the new features and will update this article with anything we hear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H3xAsg"&gt;Twitter has historically struggled with abuse on its platform and has released a number of features over the years to help reduce offensive content, such as letting people &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20874847/twitter-feature-launch-us-japan-rollout-hide-replies"&gt;hide replies&lt;/a&gt; and letting users control &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21362514/twitter-reply-limiting-features-all-users-harassment-rollout-available-now"&gt;who can reply to an individual tweet&lt;/a&gt;. The company also has some automated tools in place to remove abusive tweets, and it said in 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/24/20929290/twitter-abusive-tweets-automated-removal-earnings-q3-2019"&gt;that it removes&lt;/a&gt; more than 50 percent of abusive tweets before users report them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301388/twitter-auto-block-mute-abusive-accounts-safety-mode"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301388/twitter-auto-block-mute-abusive-accounts-safety-mode</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T13:26:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T13:26:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter announces paid Super Follows to let you charge for tweets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WsLOAzuzeofpXnNtsKmWeJqECQY=/0x92:1842x1320/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68874995/Screen_Shot_2021_02_25_at_1.11.21_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Twitter’s mockup of its Super Follows feature. | Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7DOSFJ"&gt;Twitter announced a pair of big upcoming features today: the ability for users to charge their followers for access to additional content, and the ability to create and join groups based around specific interests. They’re two of the more substantial changes to Twitter in a while, but they also fit snugly into models that have been popular and successful on other social platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GQj3iG"&gt;The payment feature, called Super Follows, will allow Twitter users to charge followers and give them access to extra content. That could be bonus tweets, access to a community group, subscription to a newsletter, or a badge indicating your support. In a mockup screenshot, Twitter showed an example where a user charges $4.99 per month to receive a series of perks. Twitter sees it as a way to let creators and publishers get paid directly by their fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AZ2aha"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Communities could be Twitter’s take on Facebook Groups&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0ffzf8"&gt;Direct payment tools have become increasingly important for creators in particular in recent years. Patreon has been hugely successful, and other platforms including Facebook, YouTube, and even GitHub have all launched direct creator payment features. Twitter will presumably take a cut — the company has been hinting at subscriptions features that would offer it a new source of revenue — though it doesn’t appear to have said yet what that fee will be.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rrxiJo9sR0o8dc_YDuazMlZhZ90=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22328742/twitter_communities.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter.&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Twitter’s mockup of its Communities feature.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ccH4m7"&gt;Twitter also announced a new feature called Communities, which appear to be its take on something like Facebook Groups. People can create and join groups around specific interests — like cats or plants, Twitter suggests — allowing them to see more tweets focused on those topics. Groups have been a huge success for Facebook (and a huge moderation problem, too), and they could be a particularly helpful tool on Twitter, since the service’s open-ended nature can make it difficult for new users to get started on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AXBJ5l"&gt;There’s no timeline yet for when either of these features will launch. Twitter listed them as “what’s next” for its platform during a presentation for analysts and investors this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301375/twitter-super-follows-communities-paid-followers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301375/twitter-super-follows-communities-paid-followers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T12:57:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T12:57:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Where to buy Nvidia’s RTX 3060 graphics card </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N_xC0e_-R_mHspcZBFq1U1sCY88=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68873032/shollister_200224_4441_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;EVGA’s RTX 3060 graphics card | Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Kfxa6U"&gt;Nvidia’s new RTX 3060 will be available to purchase starting on Thursday, February 25th at 9AM PT / 12PM ET. Unlike other GPUs in the RTX 30 series, Nvidia is not making a Founder’s Edition of the RTX 3060, but other manufacturers like EVGA and Gigabyte are making their own iterations of the RTX 3060. The price is said to be $329, but as has been the case for the past year, it’s unlikely you’ll be able to find it available for that. Retailers that have posted listings are already marking up 3060 cards to $390 or more, which is much closer in price to the step-up 3060 Ti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mbzG6g"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s Sean Hollister &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22064700"&gt;reviewed EVGA’s iteration of the RTX 3060&lt;/a&gt; and noted in his review that although the GPU’s price makes it more competitive to buy, you’re sacrificing more than a little bit of performance compared to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21768294/nvidia-rtx-3060-ti-when-where-how-to-buy-gpu"&gt;RTX 3060 Ti&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LG09Kn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10360060"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aSEuLX"&gt;So far, Best Buy, Micro Center, and Newegg (&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fproduct-shuffle" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Newegg Shuffle&lt;/a&gt;) are the only retailers that have put listings up for the RTX 3060. We will continue to update the list of cards and retailers selling them as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HhnqeJ"&gt;BEST BUY NVIDIA RTX 3060 LISTINGS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="8o7rCu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1733236785240891134" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;EVGA’s GeForce RTX 3060 for $380&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gfzKqB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1733236980532373336" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MSI’s GeForce RTX 3060 Ventus 3X for $500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0AREQH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1733236875440916424" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PNY’s GeForce RTX 3060 single fan GPU for $625&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="W4rBHG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1733236993068596491" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PNY’s GeForce RTX 3060 dual fan GPU for $630&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oSbz3e"&gt;MICRO CENTER NVIDIA RTX 3060 LISTINGS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="SvqeBQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/634181/evga-nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-xc-gaming-dual-fan-12gb-gddr6-pcie-40-graphics-card"&gt;EVGA's GeForce RTX 3060 for $390&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="n0EOpn"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/633840/msi-nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-ventus-2x-overclocked-dual-fan-12gb-gddr6-pcie-40-graphics-card"&gt;MSI’s GeForce RTX 3060 Ventus 2X for $485&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fsAQH7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/633747/asus-nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-tuf-gaming-overclocked-triple-fan-12gb-gddr6-pcie-40-graphics-card"&gt;Asus’ TUF Gaming GeForce RTX 3060 for $490&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0rQsZt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/633835/zotac-nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-twin-edge-overclocked-dual-fan-12gb-gddr6-pcie-40-graphics-card"&gt;Zotac’s GeForce RTX 3060 for $500&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="u0qjUR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/633746/asus-nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-rog-strix-overclocked-triple-fan-12gb-gddr6-pcie-40-graphics-card"&gt;Asus’ ROG Strix GeForce RTX 3060 for $510&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="40Y78b"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/633838/msi-nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-gaming-x-overclocked-dual-fan-12gb-gddr6-pcie-40-graphics-card"&gt;MSI’s GeForce RTX 3060 Gaming X for $515&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7ueZmQ"&gt;NEWEGG NVIDIA RTX 3060 LISTINGS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="en3zN1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fevga-geforce-rtx-3060-12g-p5-3655-kr%2Fp%2FN82E16814487538%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-487-538-_-Product%26quicklink%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;EVGA’s Geforce RTX 3060 (model 3655) dual fan for $330&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pLTgMa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fgigabyte-geforce-rtx-3060-gv-n3060eagle-12gd%2Fp%2FN82E16814932399%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-932-399-_-Product%26quicklink%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gigabyte’ GeForce RTX 3060 OC for $330&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NP5aKx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fzotac-geforce-rtx-3060-zt-a30600e-10m%2Fp%2FN82E16814500509%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-500-509-_-Product" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zotac Gaming’s GeForce RTX 3060 Twin Edge for $330&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s9rjqt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fgigabyte-geforce-rtx-3060-gv-n3060eagle-oc-12gd%2Fp%2FN82E16814932403%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-932-403-_-Product" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gigabyte’s GeForce RTX 3060 for $460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZtAOyI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fgigabyte-geforce-rtx-3060-gv-n3060gaming-oc-12gd%2Fp%2FN82E16814932402%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-932-402-_-Product%26quicklink%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gigabyte’s GeForce RTX 3060 Eagle for $480&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uVla6q"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fzotac-geforce-rtx-3060-zt-a30600h-10m%2Fp%2FN82E16814500508%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-500-508-_-Product" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zotac Gaming’s GeForce RTX 3060 Twin Edge OC for $490&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xzBUY0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fasus-geforce-rtx-3060-tuf-rtx3060-o12g-gaming%2Fp%2FN82E16814126491%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-126-491-_-Product" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Asus’ TUF Gaming GeForce RTX 3060 for $500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kFNhRE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fasus-geforce-rtx-3060-rog-strix-rtx3060-o12g-gaming%2Fp%2FN82E16814126492%3FDescription%3Drtx%25203060%26cm_re%3Drtx_3060-_-14-126-492-_-Product" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Asus’ ROG Strix GeForce RTX 3060 for $520&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="5HOssH"&gt;You may also be able to find it at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Nvidia+GeForce+RTX+3060&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fgeforce%2Fgpu%2F%3Fpage%3D1%26limit%3D9%26locale%3Den-us%26category%3DGPU%26gpu%3DRTX%25203060%2520Ti&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F25%2F22285433%2Fnvidia-rtx-3060-gpu-graphics-card-where-buy-stores-retailers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nvidia&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/51926/1036?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fl%2F%3Fsearchinfo%3Drtx%25203060%26sel%3DItem-Condition_New-Items&amp;amp;sharedid=vergenvidiartx3060howtobuy02242021"&gt;Adorama&lt;/a&gt; in the US; &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.currys.co.uk%2Fgbuk%2Fsearch-keywords%2Fxx_xx_xx_xx_xx%2Frtx%2B3060%2Fxx-criteria.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F25%2F22285433%2Fnvidia-rtx-3060-gpu-graphics-card-where-buy-stores-retailers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Currys&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebuyer.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Drtx%2B3060&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F25%2F22285433%2Fnvidia-rtx-3060-gpu-graphics-card-where-buy-stores-retailers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ebuyer&lt;/a&gt; in the UK; or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.ca%2Fen-ca%2Fcollection%2Frtx-30-series-graphic-cards%2F316108&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F25%2F22285433%2Fnvidia-rtx-3060-gpu-graphics-card-where-buy-stores-retailers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy CA&lt;/a&gt; if you live in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g6WzC6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22285433/nvidia-rtx-3060-gpu-graphics-card-where-buy-stores-retailers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22285433/nvidia-rtx-3060-gpu-graphics-card-where-buy-stores-retailers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T12:48:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T12:48:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Xbox Series X and S are available again at Target</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FXDQGXbNNrsbvR5KPh1_jS-zfQU=/7x0:2034x1351/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68867788/twarren_200908_4177_0013.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ikctbP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 25th, 2021 12:48PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both GameStop and Target have run out of stock. If you are looking to buy the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X%2F443574645&amp;amp;subid1=vergenextgenrestocks02252021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, Walmart plans to restock the console at 12PM PT / 3PM ET today. You can find additional information &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301306/xbox-series-x-walmart-restock-time-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TtyNLT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 25th, 2021 09:07AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;GameStop has run out of stock, but Target now has supply available for both the Xbox Series X and Series S. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SQNYsH"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-series-x-console%2F-%2FA-80790841&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-series-s-console%2F-%2FA-80790842&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Series S&lt;/a&gt; consoles have been available to purchase since last fall, but actually finding one to buy has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;extremely difficult&lt;/a&gt;. If you are looking to buy either console, Target has both models in stock, and they are available for preorder while supplies last. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZpQOHY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10226823"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cfRAwj"&gt;Regardless of which console you buy, you may want to consider picking up a few accessories that will help you get the most out of your new gadget, most notably &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08DF26MXW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;an additional controller&lt;/a&gt; if you are playing a game with a local co-op with a friend or family member. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="v4Zgyt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562380"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P06Nfx"&gt;As far as storage goes, both consoles have rather limited storage. If you plan to download some older games that do not take full advantage of the next-gen hardware and don’t want to deplete your limited SSD storage, you can grab an external hard drive. You can buy a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Seagate-Game-Drive-Xbox-Special/dp/B072LX7WLP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;4TB external hard drive from Seagate for $100&lt;/a&gt;, and it includes two months of Xbox Game Pass, a Netflix-like digital video game subscription service for Xbox consoles. Or you can buy &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Game-Pass-Ultimate-Membership/dp/B07TGNFVWV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three months of Xbox Game Pass&lt;/a&gt; if you don’t have any games you’re interested in buying yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gpa4v9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546609"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QOq3lx"&gt;Of course, you can also upgrade your SSD as well, but there are a few things to keep in mind. Seagate is the only one with an SSD expansion card compatible with both consoles. Additionally, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Seagate-Storage-Expansion-Solid-State/dp/B08K3S6WJM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SSD expansion card only comes in 1TB&lt;/a&gt;, and it is very expensive, costing $220. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SE84Lx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562459"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="A07hUv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Xbox Series S review: small console, big potential","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"},{"title":"Here’s every game coming to the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021"},{"title":"Xbox Series X review: a next-gen PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22295791/xbox-series-x-s-restock-gamestop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22295791/xbox-series-x-s-restock-gamestop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-25T12:36:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T12:36:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s where and when you can buy the Xbox Series S and Series X consoles</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ex-5CndmZqOiQxMH1SbbYK2sEo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67448810/vpavic_4275_20201030_0050.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mlkkez"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 25th, 2021 12:36PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Walmart plans to restock both the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X%2F443574645&amp;amp;subid1=vergenextgenrestocks02252021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; today. You can find additional information &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22065347"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oZoKH5"&gt;The Xbox Series S and Series X consoles are officially out. Due to the pandemic, combined with the high demand for these consoles, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551484/best-buy-playstation-5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-store-sales-holiday-2020"&gt;retailers like Best Buy and Target are only selling online&lt;/a&gt;. That means you won’t be able to walk into a store to pick one up — unless you’ve purchased it already online. Only then will you be able to arrange an in-store pickup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5s3rFB"&gt;Until we hear updates on stock replenishing from retailers, I recommend keeping it locked to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08H75RTZ8/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=sl2&amp;amp;tag=verge-evergreen-20&amp;amp;linkId=e8ef14f64e0e9e1dacba6db0add8b578&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fxbox-series-x-video-games%2F-%2FN-fd2hh&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21437954%2Fxbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fconsoles" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fxbox-series-x%2Fconsoles" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fpromotions%2Fgaming%2F20-1310%2Findex.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Newegg&lt;/a&gt;, and (if you have memberships) &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/xbox-brand-showcase.html"&gt;Costco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsclub.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-series-x%2Fprod24980179&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21437954%2Fxbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sam’s Club&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1723309405282483811" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy encourages shoppers to visit its site&lt;/a&gt; to order instead of showing up at its stores. It doesn’t have set time slots for when it expects stock to be available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lVxesu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="hLH7PZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444130"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ejjLHa"&gt;If you’re trying to decide between the Xbox Series S or Series X, my colleague Tom Warren recently reviewed both consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cqFv0O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Xbox Series X review: a next-gen PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"},{"title":"Xbox Series S review: small console, big potential","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h1 id="hCC7LP"&gt;Buy with the Xbox All Access plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="tnxiJL"&gt;As an alternative to paying full price upfront for each console, you can pay a monthly installment for either of them through the Xbox All Access plan. It’s a financing option that lets you get the console upfront at no cost. You’ll be billed one monthly payment for the console and Xbox Game Pass Ultimate together ($24.99 per month for the Series S, $34.99 per month for the Series X) for 24 months. Available at the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-all-access%23findaretailer" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fxbox-one%2Fxbox-all-access%2Fpcmcat1579299055180.c%3Fid%3Dpcmcat1579299055180&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fxbox-all-access%2F8571041&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fxbox-all-access%2F-%2FN-he40f&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21437954%2Fxbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21437954/xbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21437954/xbox-series-x-s-preorder-us-retailers-microsoft-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
