<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-13T11:00:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T11:00:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T11:00:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>MSI’s 2021 gaming laptops get Nvidia’s RTX 3000 series mobile graphics cards and Wi-Fi 6E support</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A gamer, wearing headphones and an MSI-branded jacket and facing away from the camera, plays a game on the GP66 Leopard on their lap." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7k0B-U1-gCvLD7j385yKFu9j0s8=/0x0:9504x6336/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661370/GP66_GP76_scenario_photos__7_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The GP66 Leopard starts at $1,799. | MSI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2C7kzo"&gt;MSI has introduced its early 2021 lineup of portable gaming laptops during CES on Wednesday. The big news is that all the new releases have been outfitted with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226544/nvidia-rtx-3080-laptops-gpus-ces-2021"&gt;Nvidia’s brand-new GeForce RTX 3000&lt;/a&gt; series graphics cards. In addition to improved frame rates and ray tracing, these chips will deliver Nvidia’s latest features, including its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226560/nvidia-resizable-bar-support-intel-amd-smart-access-memory-feature"&gt;resizable BAR technology&lt;/a&gt;. They’re also getting support for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"&gt;Wi-Fi 6E&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HtHwDT"&gt;Headlining the thin-and-light lineup is the new GS66 Stealth. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21348101/msi-gs66-stealth-gaming-laptop-review-rtx-2070-super-300hz"&gt;Last year’s GS66 Stealth&lt;/a&gt;, powered by Nvidia’s RTX 2000 graphics, was a capable 15.6-inch rig, but it couldn’t quite produce the frame rates to compete with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21499199/razer-blade-15-advanced-edition-gaming-laptop-2020-review"&gt;Razer’s Blade 15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Wm0jwE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;MSI says you’ll be able to play games in 4K&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bzBQJ7"&gt;Presumably, MSI hopes to keep gaining on Razer with these new chip upgrades (especially since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22215119/razer-blade-15-17-laptops-screens-graphics-gaming-price-release-date"&gt;the Blade 15 Advanced is also getting the RTX 3000 series&lt;/a&gt;). The company claims the new GS66 will be able to run games at playable frame rates in 4K, which is unusual to see in a modern laptop. Models come with an RTX 3060 through an RTX 3080 Max-Q. You can pair those with a 10th Gen Intel Core i7, and a 15.6-inch FHD 240Hz or 300Hz FHD screen. You can &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/633495/10014?prodsku=6448270&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmsi-gs66-15-6-240hz-gaming-laptop-intel-core-i7-nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-1tb-ssd-16gb-memory-black%2F6448270.p%3FskuId%3D6448270&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;preorder the GS66 Stealth now&lt;/a&gt; to ship on February 2nd — models start at $1,799.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NFyOfn"&gt;MSI’s midrange GP Leopard line also has new inductees: the 15.6-inch GP66 and 17.3-inch GP76. These can both come with a GeForce RTX 3070; the GP66 has RTX 3080 configurations as well. In terms of processor, all models have a Core i7-10875H except the base GP66, which can come with a Core i7-10750H. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k6Fugb"&gt;MSI has made the Leopards thinner (the GP66 is 0.92 inches thick, and the GP76 is 1.08 inches thick) and says they’re easy to open with one hand. Ports have also been rearranged: there are now some on the rear, as well as batches on the left and right side. You get seven in total, including an HDMI 2.0 and a USB-C with DP1.4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhAmNX"&gt;The GP Leopard is available to preorder now, with a release date of February 5th. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fcore-black-msi-gp-series-gp66-leopard-10ug-268-gaming-entertainment%2Fp%2FN82E16834155714%3FItem%3DN82E16834155714&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228325%2Fmsi-gs66-stealth-gp66-leopard-laptops-gaming-price-release-date#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GP66&lt;/a&gt; starts at $1,799, and the GP76 starts at $2,299. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9uZ7iRyr-qQO-tshcN_J-GlW5Ns=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232623/GP66_GP76_scenario_photos__9_.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XdA1sd"&gt;If you’re looking for something even thinner, you may prefer the Stealth 15M, which MSI claims is the world’s thinnest 15-inch gaming laptop at 0.63 inches thick. That seems fair to me — I can’t think of a thinner 15-inch rig — but if you include multipurpose devices that can still run games like the &lt;a href="https://www.techradar.com/reviews/dell-xps-15-2-in-1"&gt;Dell XPS 15 2-in-1&lt;/a&gt;, you get close. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FE2rcR"&gt;Still, it’s a heck of a lot thinner than most 15-inch gaming laptops you’ll see, and at 3.75 pounds it’s on par with portable 14-inchers like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21197761/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;ROG Zephyrus G14&lt;/a&gt; weight-wise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gn5URW"&gt;The big news with this is that the 15M will be one of the first gaming laptops powered by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225370/intel-11th-gen-h-series-chips-ultraportable-gaming-laptop-ces-2021"&gt;Intel’s 11th Gen H-Series mobile processors&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, that means you’ll have to wait a bit to receive one of these. You can &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1597873-REG%2Fmsi_stealth_15m_a11sdk_063_stealth_15m_i7_1185g7_gtx1660ti.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228325%2Fmsi-gs66-stealth-gp66-leopard-laptops-gaming-price-release-date#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1597873-REG%2Fmsi_stealth_15m_a11sdk_063_stealth_15m_i7_1185g7_gtx1660ti.html&amp;amp;xcust=verge#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;eorder the Stealth 15M now&lt;/a&gt; starting at $1,399, but it’s not going to ship until &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fp%2FN82E16834155722%3FItem%3DN82E16834155722&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228325%2Fmsi-gs66-stealth-gp66-leopard-laptops-gaming-price-release-date#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;March 8th&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A user stands on the roof of a building wearing a white T-Shirt, sunglasses and sweatpants. They carry a white MSI Stealth 15M under their right arm while looking off to the left." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/llHCBS4MqSDMBXbj4SWD6mBDdq4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232635/e847cbd3_Stealth_15M_Scenario_Photo_37.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: MSI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Style is the name of the game with the Stealth 15M.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="56Se2R"&gt;Finally, there are new GF75 and GF65 Thin models for gamers looking for more affordable devices. &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmsi-gf65-15-6-144hz-gaming-laptop-intel-core-i5-nvidia-geforce-rtx3060-512gb-ssd-8gb-memory-black%2F6448272.p%3FskuId%3D6448272&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GF65 models&lt;/a&gt; start at just $999 and&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fcore-black-msi-gf-series-gf65-thin-10ue-071-gaming-entertainment%2Fp%2FN82E16834155716&amp;amp;u1=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; GF75 model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fcore-black-msi-gf-series-gf75-thin-10uek-048-gaming-entertainment%2Fp%2FN82E16834155715%3FItem%3DN82E16834155715&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228325%2Fmsi-gs66-stealth-gp66-leopard-laptops-gaming-price-release-date#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;s&lt;/a&gt; start at $1,299 — they all come with an RTX 3060 or an RTX 3060 Max-Q as well as a 144Hz screen. Not bad for that price. You can preorder them now to ship on February 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="54S3on"&gt;Here’s a video MSI made about the GF Thin series, so you can see what they look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="s5sFp9"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1mP12A9WjnVwt3o0OKQpXjo0X7jiJsCMf/preview" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; picture-in-picture; gyroscope"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="141tzr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228325/msi-gs66-stealth-gp66-leopard-laptops-gaming-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228325/msi-gs66-stealth-gp66-leopard-laptops-gaming-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ring adds end-to-end encryption to protect your video streams</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Ring end-to-end encryption menu in app" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tLslQfcff_8TDnlcn8l80gKX_aA=/0x0:2456x1637/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661331/OTS_Press_Kit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Ring&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rKnFDW"&gt;Ring is starting to add support for end-to-end encryption to its cameras. The feature will keep video streams encrypted from the camera all the way to the device it’s being streamed to, so it won’t be accessible to anyone in between. The feature, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/24/21453581/ring-end-to-end-encryption-video-neighbors-app-amazon"&gt;first announced in September&lt;/a&gt;, will start rolling out today as a “technical preview” on nine Ring cameras, including doorbell, indoor, and outdoor models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ctfMVc"&gt;“End-to-end encryption is really about user choice, to create that advanced layer of security,” Josh Roth, Ring’s chief technical officer, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Some people like a second or third deadbolt on their house.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="rW1bEC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Some people like a second or third deadbolt on their house.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D3IsE4"&gt;Footage from Ring cameras is currently encrypted when it’s being transmitted to Ring’s servers and then again when it’s sitting around on Ring’s servers. But Ring still has to be able to access that footage in order to enable various features, like sharing videos through its website or streaming clips to any device you’re signed into. Ring says that it does not view customer videos without permission, but the company does have the technical capability to do so (and has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/10/18177305/ring-employees-unencrypted-customer-video-amazon"&gt;been accused of doing so&lt;/a&gt; without permission in the past). If law enforcement received a search warrant for your footage, Ring would be able to hand it over, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6mFET3"&gt;End-to-end encryption removes any visibility that Ring has into your footage, offering more protection for particularly privacy-conscious users. But the feature comes with some drawbacks that add hurdles and limitations to how the cameras can be used. Some devices, like the Echo Show, won’t be able to display Ring video feeds because they can’t (currently, at least) be set up to support the end-to-end encrypted streams. Other features, like sharing videos, become more complicated because you’ll have to download and manually re-upload videos, rather than just changing the sharing settings on Ring’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e4GIvI"&gt;The feature also adds some friction to Ring’s Neighbors app, which allows Ring users to share video with people nearby and for local law enforcement to request access to footage. With end-to-end encryption enabled, camera owners can still share video to the Neighbors app — which &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/5/7/18528014/fear-social-media-nextdoor-citizen-amazon-ring-neighbors"&gt;has been criticized&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qvyvzd/amazons-home-security-company-is-turning-everyone-into-cops"&gt;containing racist comments and reports&lt;/a&gt; — but they’ll have to manually download and upload the footage, adding some steps before they can post a recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3GdfRy"&gt;At launch, end-to-end encryption will be available on Ring cameras that are plugged into power. Those cameras are able to process computer vision features, like person detection, locally on the device, whereas battery-powered Ring cameras offload those features to the cloud — something that can’t be done with end-to-end encryption turned on. No subscription is required in order to use it, but it’ll only be available in the US initially. End-to-end encrypted videos can be streamed to recent phones and tablets with the Ring app installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ajdmfM"&gt;Over time, Ring plans to expand access to everyone and add in a few additional missing features, like snapshots. End-to-end encryption won’t be enabled by default, but Roth said Ring would notify customers when it becomes available. It can also be turned on and off on a camera-by-camera basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H0G9B2"&gt;“End-to-end is one of those features some users are going to love,” Roth said, “and some will say they don’t need it.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22225716/ring-end-to-end-encryption-video-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22225716/ring-end-to-end-encryption-video-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>MSI’s new Creator 15 comes with RTX 3000 graphics </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="MSI Creator 15 open on a white background. The screen displays a purple background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1N3L2uUYUrL-q8CKpkUvQP6bTJ4=/0x834:5000x4167/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661357/MSI_NB_Creator_15_Touch_photo14.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;This is the touchscreen model of the MSI Creator 15. | MSI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NFKSlQ"&gt;MSI has introduced its 2021 Creator 15, a portable laptop designed for creative work. It includes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226544/nvidia-rtx-3080-laptops-gpus-ces-2021"&gt;Nvidia’s brand-new RTX 3000 mobile graphics cards&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p1X2h1"&gt;The new Creator 15 starts at $1,899 — a 21 percent increase from the 2020 model, which started at &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/reviews/msi-creator-15"&gt;$1,499&lt;/a&gt;. It will start shipping on January 26th. MSI calls the Creator 15 “an excellent all-around laptop, built for the most demanding creations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4QxBPW"&gt;A color-accurate display is an important aspect of any creator-focused laptop. This 15.6-inch 4K panel covers 100 percent of the Adobe RGB gamut, and MSI says it’s “guaranteed to provide a true-to-life visual experience.” The chassis also includes a UHS-III SD slot for easy transfer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Falc4"&gt;Here’s a video MSI made to show off the new Creator: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aOqCaY"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1hai3Ji_9Fi99oyG72f82FRGwnUYL-qJ5/preview" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; picture-in-picture; gyroscope"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bSAti1"&gt;The intent of the Creator 15 is to help you get work done on the go, whether you’re out at a coffee shop, walking around a conference, or just lounging around at home. Like its predecessor, the new Creator 15 carries a 99Wh battery, the biggest battery you can bring on a flight. The previous Creator 15 received &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/reviews/msi-creator-15"&gt;strong reviews&lt;/a&gt; for its long battery life. And at 4.63 pounds (2.1 kg), the Creator 15 is portable enough to bring from place to place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B9CLni"&gt;In addition to the big battery and next-gen GPUs (which can be an RTX 3060 or RTX 3070 Max-Q), the Creator 15 includes a Core i7-10870H, up to 32GB of RAM, and 1TB of SSD storage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DTQsli"&gt;The Creator 15 is just the latest of the dump of gaming- and creator-focused laptops to adopt Nvidia’s new RTX 3000 graphics, following their release at CES 2021. These laptops will use the third generation of Nvidia’s Max-Q design, which is engineered for thin gaming and content laptops. The new GPUs also include a new Dynamic Boost 2.0 technology that leverages AI to balance power between CPU, GPU, and GPU memory in real time. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227846/msis-creator-15-nvidia-rtx-3000-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227846/msis-creator-15-nvidia-rtx-3000-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>MSI’s new GE76 Raider Dragon Edition Tiamat is a tribute to an ancient goddess</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The lid of the MSI GE76 Raider Dragon Edition." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yLeT2nPyv5wV2HGUQrrG7XXv-UQ=/0x834:5000x4167/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661364/GE76_Raider_Dragon_Edition_Tiamat12.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Here’s the lid of the GE76 Raider Dragon Edition, which MSI says represents “the fusion of old and new spirits.” | MSI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oUdhNL"&gt;MSI has announced the GE76 Raider Dragon Edition Tiamat (yes, that’s the full name), which undoubtedly has one of the most unique laptop designs you’ll see this year. Take a look at the eye-catching pattern in the picture above — it’s actually engraved into the 17.3-inch GE76’s lid. MSI says the design is inspired by the ancient goddess Tiamat, who was known in Mesopotamia as the mother of all gods. Why Tiamat? Like her, MSI claims, the GE76 Raider represents “supreme power.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="16QUXy"&gt;If you’re confused, settle in — this kind of thing is MSI’s shtick. Last year, the company released a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536996/msi-ge66-raider-dragonshield-edition-gaming-laptop-review-rtx-2070-super-300hz"&gt;“Dragonshield Edition” of its GE66 Raider&lt;/a&gt; designed to look like a spaceship. (Or rather, a panel that fell off a spaceship. There’s a story and it comes with a model, it’s a whole thing.) Hey, it won’t be for everyone, but I love that the company’s thinking big. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pxWUSu"&gt;In addition to the Dragon Edition, MSI has unveiled a few other devices for its GE Raider series including a regular GE76 Raider (no fun lid design) and an updated 15.6-inch GE66 Raider. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9a46Y"&gt;The big news is that the GE Raiders have been upgraded to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226544/nvidia-rtx-3080-laptops-gpus-ces-2021"&gt;Nvidia’s new GeForce RTX 3000 graphics cards&lt;/a&gt;. The GE66 and the Dragon Edition can include an RTX 3070 or RTX 3080; the standard GE76 goes down to a 3060 as well. This means they’ll have access to Nvidia’s modern technologies, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226560/nvidia-resizable-bar-support-intel-amd-smart-access-memory-feature"&gt;resizable BAR technology&lt;/a&gt; and Dynamic Boost 2.0 (which leverages AI to balance power between the CPU, GPU, and GPU memory on a per-frame basis). The new Raiders will pair those GPUs with Intel’s 10th Gen Core i7 processors (the Dragon Edition has a Core i9 option). MSI claims the laptops can “masterfully handle all triple-A games.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vX0xDV"&gt;They’re also among the first laptops in the industry to support the latest &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"&gt;Wi-Fi 6E&lt;/a&gt;, or 6Hz Wi-Fi that’s meant to offer better bandwidth with less interference. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The MSI GE76 Raider open, angled to the left on a black table with a purple background. The LED strip and keyboard are illuminated. The screen displays a black hole with the slogan “Light ‘em up” in the bottom right corner." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qcpn5IXcTN-djnfZ76upw5Rnw_w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22231918/GE76_Raider_Scenario_Photos__12_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: MSI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the regular GE76 Raider.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LWgKp6"&gt;Chips aside, the most noticeable feature of the GE Raider series is the colorful LED bar around the front edge of the chassis. Together with a customizable RGB keyboard, it creates a flashy splash of color. They also have plentiful port selections: I count 10, including two USB-C ports, three USB-A ports, an audio jack, an HDMI 2.0 port, Mini DisplayPort 1.4, an Ethernet port, and an SD card reader. All models can come with a 1080p 300Hz or 240Hz IPS display — the Dragon Edition also has a 4K UHD option, and the standard GE76 has a 1080p 144Hz option. Both GE76s have an MSI-developed “Duo Wave” speaker with noise cancellation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yECSiW"&gt;And they all have a 99.9Wh battery, the largest battery you can bring on a plane (and consequently the largest size you’re likely to see in a consumer device), though I still only got about four hours out of the 2020 GE66 in my testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1TXZD"&gt;Pricing on the GE76 Raider Dragon Edition is still to be announced, but it’s supposed to hit shelves in mid to late February. You can preorder the regular &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Ftitanium-blue-msi-ge-series-ge76-raider-10ug-232-gaming-entertainment%2Fp%2FN82E16834155720%3FItem%3DN82E16834155720&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22227970%2Fmsi-ge76-raider-dragon-edition-ge66-tiamat-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3000-series#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GE76&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Ftitanium-blue-msi-ge-series-ge66-raider-10ug-211-gaming-entertainment%2Fp%2FN82E16834155712%3FItem%3DN82E16834155712&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22227970%2Fmsi-ge76-raider-dragon-edition-ge66-tiamat-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3000-series#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GE66&lt;/a&gt; models now. They’ll start at $1,499 and $2,199, respectively. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227970/msi-ge76-raider-dragon-edition-ge66-tiamat-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3000-series"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227970/msi-ge76-raider-dragon-edition-ge66-tiamat-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3000-series</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:48:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:48:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Airbnb blocks and cancels all DC metro area reservations, citing reports of ‘armed militias’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/paHDC2vdDZW5mL6aKGU0m7W6y6o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661283/akrales_161202_1327_A_0122_v2.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oxFPM7"&gt;Airbnb is &lt;a href="https://news.airbnb.com/airbnb-to-block-and-cancel-d-c-reservations-during-inauguration/"&gt;blocking all reservations&lt;/a&gt; in the Washington, DC metro area during inauguration week after regional officials asked people not to travel to the city due to concerns of additional violence. The company said it was aware of reports “regarding armed militias and known hate groups” attempting to travel to the region to disrupt the inauguration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lL2QhN"&gt;Existing Airbnb reservations in the area are being canceled, and Airbnb is blocking any future bookings. Guests will receive full refunds, and Airbnb says it will pay hosts what they would have earned for canceled bookings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ynBJUE"&gt;Reservations made through HotelTonight, a hotel reservation site &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/7/18254988/airbnb-hoteltonight-acquisition-deal-hotel-booking-platform"&gt;owned by Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;, are also being canceled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="btT8wF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Airbnb says it’s working to block Capitol attackers from returning to Washington, DC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227028/airbnb-block-capitol-attackers-returning-dc-gofundme"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="z86U6g"&gt;“Due to the unique circumstances surrounding the 59th Presidential Inauguration, including last week’s violent insurrection as well as the ongoing and deadly COVID-19 pandemic, we are taking the extraordinary step of encouraging Americans not to come to Washington, D.C. and to instead participate virtually,” DC Mayor Muriel Bowser, Maryland Gov. Larry Hogan, and Virginia Gov. Ralph Northam said in &lt;a href="https://www.governor.virginia.gov/newsroom/all-releases/2021/january/headline-891291-en.html"&gt;a joint statement&lt;/a&gt; on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gGdLsw"&gt;Airbnb said yesterday that it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227028/airbnb-block-capitol-attackers-returning-dc-gofundme"&gt;working to ban members of the mob&lt;/a&gt; that attacked the Capitol from using its platform. The company now says it’s issued bans for some people who were either part of the mob or associated with known hate groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SffDu"&gt;Major online platforms have been reviewing their policies ahead of the inauguration next Wednesday, concerned that their services may be used to help organize another attack. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225643/facebook-stop-the-steal-ban-inauguration-day-capitol-mob-attack"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; said Monday it is blocking the term “stop the steal,” while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221730/apple-removes-suspends-bans-parler-app-store"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22221648/google-suspends-bans-parler-play-store"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228675/amazon-parler-takedown-violent-threats-moderation-content-free-speech"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; have removed distribution of the right-wing social media app Parler over its failure to moderate.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228798/airbnb-washington-dc-inauguration-reservations-blocked-cancelled"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228798/airbnb-washington-dc-inauguration-reservations-blocked-cancelled</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:46:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:46:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game is still one of the best licensed games around</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jRfCkwjITU5I8AWmTXLt7oKTizQ=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661270/SP_screen_1_200910_945PM_CEST.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SqbhY1"&gt;It’s hard to think of a licensed game that fit its source material better than &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game&lt;/em&gt;. First released in 2010, the game felt exactly like an interactive version of Bryan Lee O’Malley’s cult comic book. The story was pared down, but the vibe was the same, thanks to incredible character sprites from Paul Robertson, a banging chiptune soundtrack from Anamanaguchi, and classic beat ‘em up action from a small team at Ubisoft. The problem was actually playing it: a few years after it debuted on the PS3 and Xbox 360, the game was delisted from digital stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94DaYl"&gt;This week, that finally changes. More than a decade after it first came out, &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game&lt;/em&gt; is coming to a huge range of new platforms: the Nintendo Switch, PS4, Xbox One, PC, and even Google Stadia. The new version bundles all of the original downloadable content — no paying extra for Knives Chau — and introduces online co-op, but otherwise it’s the same game. Which is exactly as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QysjiE"&gt;So what’s the big deal? For starters, a video game adaptation just makes too much sense. (The game is based on the comics, not the movie.) Not only is &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim&lt;/em&gt; jammed with gaming references, it’s structured like a classic game, too, with seven main bosses — in this case, Ramona’s evil exes — to defeat along the way. It all fits very well with a 16-bit style game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="37mykI"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim&lt;/em&gt; game plays a lot like &lt;em&gt;Streets of Rage&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Double Dragon&lt;/em&gt;. You wander through city streets and movie sets, fighting a whole bunch of “bad guys,” ranging from bus drivers to paparazzi. You can jump, punch, and kick, and pick up many objects to use as weapons, whether it’s a snowball or a baseball bat. You can also play as most of the main cast of characters, and they’ll each learn some new abilities as you progress. There are even level and character select screens ripped straight out of the 8-bit &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; games, and &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter&lt;/em&gt;-style car smashing mini-games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MYriGb"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wUU_wRjdi2I?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wtrw3v"&gt;The gameplay is solid, if not as deep as some of its contemporaries or more recent titles like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/30/21242538/streets-of-rage-4-review-ps4-xbox-steam-switch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Streets of Rage 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But, like the movie version of &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim&lt;/em&gt;, it’s also incredibly stylish. Fighting enemies is really just an excuse to see the gorgeous pixel art and listen to the amazing soundtrack. Sometimes, after clearing out a wave of enemies, I’ll just sit for a second to soak in the sound and visuals. I’ve been playing on the PS5 via backwards compatibility, and the experience holds up extremely well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oDn9P6"&gt;I also have to note that &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game&lt;/em&gt; is the most prominent video game ever to be set in my hometown of Toronto, so it holds a special place personally. I can’t think of another game where you have to dodge TTC buses or collect toonies ($2 coins) to buy a poutine. My friends from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549085/spider-man-miles-morales-review-ps5-ps4"&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/12/21319047/watch-dogs-legion-ubisoft-hands-on-preview-hacking-open-world-london-gameplay"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/16/17242280/yakuza-6-song-of-life-review-ps4"&gt;Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; can play through huge, nearly photo-realistic versions of their homes, but I’m pretty happy to stick with what &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim&lt;/em&gt; has to offer. It’s certainly very Canadian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IdeI27"&gt;Time has been surprisingly kind to the &lt;em&gt;Scott Pilgrim&lt;/em&gt; franchise (even if Scott remains a dick). The books hold up well, and the movie went from a box-office bomb to a cult classic; Kid Cudi even sampled it on his most recent album. Meanwhile, the game now has a second chance after being doomed to obscurity years ago. If nothing else, at least O’Malley can &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bryanleeomalley/status/1304140871516876802"&gt;finally stop answering questions about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ReKjl9"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Scott Pilgrim vs. The World: The Game&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; launches January 14th on the Switch, PS4, Xbox One, PC, and Stadia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228652/scott-pilgrim-vs-the-world-the-game-review-switch-stadia-ps4-xbox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228652/scott-pilgrim-vs-the-world-the-game-review-switch-stadia-ps4-xbox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:41:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:41:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077 is nearly half off on PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BmhLxYOk7Yj4_-e2pHy3lot1Kw4=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661237/Cyberpunk_2077_screen_6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="smbdPT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;released in early December 2020, and — controversy surrounding its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;notoriously poor performance on consoles&lt;/a&gt; aside — it’s a fun, gorgeous game on PC, especially if you have Nvidia hardware that enables ray-traced graphics. If you’re still thinking about picking it up, you can snag the DRM-free version of the PC game that’s redeemable on &lt;a href="http://GOG.com"&gt;GOG.com&lt;/a&gt; from Eneba (a marketplace that sells codes — we’ve featured it several times for its excellent deals on PS Plus memberships). Normally a full $60, &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=verge&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fgog-cyberpunk-2077-gog-com-key%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it costs $35.18 at the time of publishing&lt;/a&gt;. It’s worth noting that this key will work globally, according to Eneba, not just in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eX0VnU"&gt;The game might not be in the best state right now (though its many glitches do make for &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/8RSuhJrSGZs?t=542"&gt;wonderful Highlight Reel content&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube), but developer CD Projekt Red has promised a few big updates coming in early 2021 that should address the most glaring issues that still linger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uBAGLb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10197689"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="lazLfF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"I have not played Cyberpunk 2077 but it’s my favorite game of the year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197547/cyberpunk-2077-glitches"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="KRnOKg"&gt;Sony’s WH-1000XM4, its latest flagship noise-canceling headphones, are available for a great price at eBay if you’re willing to go the refurbished route. Normally $350 outside of a deal (going as low as $278 for a new set), &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Frover.ebay.com%2Frover%2F1%2F711-53200-19255-0%2F1%3Fmpre%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.ebay.com%252Fitm%252FSony-WH-1000XM4-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Over-the-Ear-Headphones-Black%252F274493598619%2523viTabs_0%26campid%3D5338421468%26toolid%3D20008&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228682%2Fcyberpunk-2077-pc-sale-deal-gog-sony-headphones#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;these are just $210&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTvgWb"&gt;The seller, who has a 99 percent positive rating on eBay, says that these headphones are in like-new condition, and all original accessories are included. The seller provides free shipping and allows for a 30-day return window. If you live in the US, they’ll have a two-year warranty through Allstate. As someone who owns the WH-1000XM3, this deal has me tempted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J0nHQ9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9549570"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ereNwMrAwiDfxDpKrhqsmyg0wuA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232632/dellusbcdock.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bUGUGo"&gt;There are more affordable USB-C hubs out there, but Dell’s puck-shaped model might be the one that suits you best. Normally around $75, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B079MDQDP4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729315959542062315" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; are currently selling it for $60. It features an HDMI port and full-sized DisplayPort (with support for up to a 4K 60Hz monitor), a USB-C and USB Type-A port, Ethernet, and, last but not least, a VGA port. It does not support USB-C power passthrough to charge devices, though, so you’ll need to keep your laptop powered another way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1PczHC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/13/22228682/cyberpunk-2077-pc-sale-deal-gog-sony-headphones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/13/22228682/cyberpunk-2077-pc-sale-deal-gog-sony-headphones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:22:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:22:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Amazon Echo deals right now </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mj7LGifJ1euP-dbrplwPMhD36I4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67781485/dseifert_191123_3810_0012.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Echo Show 5 (left), Echo Show 8 (middle), and the Echo Show (right) | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TNieh7"&gt;When it comes to the Echo smart speakers, Amazon has a slew of devices to choose from. With so many Echo devices currently available, there is a device for every occasion. Maybe you simply want to add Alexa to a room, or you are looking for an Echo device that will allow you to easily manage your other smart home products. Regardless of the reason, these are the best Echo deals currently available right now. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CJm2GwlbGF56gpDmNhJwIgppWKg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989898/dseifert_201025_4263_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon Echo Dot with LED display&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zNwIju"&gt;Echo Dot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="maQ5h0"&gt;Last year, Amazon released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21538043/amazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-2020-review-alexa-smart-speaker"&gt;4th generation of the Echo dot&lt;/a&gt;, which looks more like a sphere than an actual dot. But if you prefer the previous design, don’t worry — Amazon has not discontinued the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/12/17965806/amazon-echo-dot-3rd-gen-review-alexa-price-specs-features"&gt;3rd-gen Echo Dot&lt;/a&gt;, which still retains the familiar dot shape. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KKAXTh"&gt;Currently, the 3rd-gen Echo Dot gets frequent price drops, and right now, you can get it for $25 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Echo-Dot/dp/B07FZ8S74R/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=1760a049c05833dc1017f6d4057815bf&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725321348360875873" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-dot-3rd-generation%2F-%2FA-54148143&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FyVkKL"&gt;During Black Friday and Cyber Monday, we saw the 4th-gen Echo Dot go down to its lowest price of $30. That deal is still available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Staging-Product-Not-Retail-Sale/dp/B084J4MZK8/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=9&amp;amp;imprToken=02bb7b89-6329-50a3-a29&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21988756%5Br%5Dtheverge.com%2Fauthors%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=1bb3f1fd7fd46e44af2bcb7b4e69ac37&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724598862588130784" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-smart-speaker-with-alexa%2F-%2FA-81795702&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. If you buy the fourth-gen Echo Dot at Amazon, the retailer is currently running a promotion that allows you to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Staging-Product-Not-Retail-Sale/dp/B084J4MZK8/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=6&amp;amp;imprToken=02bb7b89-6329-50a3-a29&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=a703bc6b8141b27e290f322ffa1dd1f6&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21988756%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/authors%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy two for $50&lt;/a&gt; (before tax) when you enter the code &lt;strong&gt;DOT2PACK&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QG96M6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9607515"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zX6pQw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21538043/amazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-2020-review-alexa-smart-speaker"&gt;Echo Dot Kids Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LzhwpX"&gt;The 4th-gen Echo Dot Kids Edition is as spherical as its adult version but is designed to look like a tiger or panda. The device also comes with a year of Amazon’s Kid Plus service, which provides access to a slew of kid-friendly content, like audiobooks and games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LmKSqg"&gt;Right now, you can get this device for $40 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Echo-Dot-4th-Gen-Kids/dp/B084J4QQK1/ref=as_li_ss_tl?th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=3b2eb028219e410a9d64a5272c5f5c00&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725323423176814123" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-dot-4th-gen-kids-edition-with-parental-controls%2F-%2FA-81795703%3Fpreselect%3D81502548%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MJlccr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9574374"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3wlc-Ltveym1Cj192vf7w6zK8BU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989890/dseifert_201025_4263_00010.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon Echo Dot (left) and Echo (right)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3GbSWO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21527664/amazon-echo-2020-alexa-fourth-gen-review"&gt;Amazon Echo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wOHvPj"&gt;The 4th-gen Amazon Echo smart home hub has also gotten an updated look. Like the 4th-gen Echo Dot, the 2020 Amazon Echo also includes a sphere-shaped design, but it’s noticeably bigger than the Echo Dot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JjodUT"&gt;There are no active deals right now for a single Amazon Echo smart speaker, but you can get it right now for its usual price of $100 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085HK4KL6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=2dfe20818827f68bbc17c1bb24f2a7a8&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724598980020491868" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-4th-gen-smart-home-hub-with-alexa%2F-%2FA-81795705%3Fpreselect%3D80770247%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon also has a few bundles going on right now; for $100, Amazon is also offering a bundle, which includes &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08KVFM2XM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one Echo smart speaker, plus two Philips Hue Bulbs&lt;/a&gt;. For $160, the e-commerce website will sell you &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08NSWKV7L/ref=as_li_ss_tl?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=dd19e87897c55799869b8b7ea50eada5&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one Echo device plus two Echo Dots&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xiNGuc"&gt;If you are looking for two Amazon Echo devices, Amazon is currently running a promotion that allows you to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Staging-Product-Not-Retail-Sale/dp/B084J4MZK8/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=6&amp;amp;imprToken=02bb7b89-6329-50a3-a29&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=a703bc6b8141b27e290f322ffa1dd1f6&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21988756%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/authors%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy two for $50&lt;/a&gt; (before tax) when you enter the code &lt;strong&gt;DOT2PACK&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1723589613981487950" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy is also selling an Amazon Echo two-pack for $180&lt;/a&gt;, which knocks $20 off its normal retail price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xR7jKq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508352"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bWxMRCIzkMkj1C2m89z7LaAIYx4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16389069/dseifert_190620_3500_5249.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Echo Show 5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oiVOWB"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/24/18714432/amazon-echo-show-5-alexa-smart-alarm-display-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Echo Show 5&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="WiqTO4"&gt;If you are looking for an Echo device that functions more as a smart clock than an entertainment speaker, the Echo Show 5 is one of two smart displays to consider. The Echo Show 5 includes a 5.5-inch display, making it easy to fit just about anywhere inside your home. Not only does the device include a built-in camera, but there’s also a physical shutter on the device, allowing you to block the camera’s view while keeping the always-on microphone active. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wsps6q"&gt;The Echo Show 5 usually costs $90, but right now, you can buy the device at its best-ever price of $45 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HZLHPKP/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=d1731cf9b61b13aa734867a184283f9a&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1723589653641321861" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-show-5-smart-display-with-alexa%2F-%2FA-77282772%3Fpreselect%3D76612867%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Wwkfpq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513095"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y-HAXm642VQW_d5RzagUQ5LApMM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19407237/dseifert_191123_3810_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Echo Show 8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GGyBnu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/26/20983661/amazon-echo-show-8-review-alexa-smart-display-price-specs-features"&gt;Echo Show 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="efoU4U"&gt;Amazon’s Echo Show 8 features an eight-inch display; it costs $40 more than the Echo Show 5. When stacked up against the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/22/18005724/google-home-hub-digital-photo-frame-review-specs-features-price"&gt;Google Nest Hub&lt;/a&gt;, which is its closest competitor in terms of price and functionality, the Echo Show 8 is the better option for a few reasons: it has a slightly larger display, better speakers, and a camera, allowing you to use it as a video chatting device, this includes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22188551/amazon-echo-group-calling-video-voice-calls-feature-available"&gt;Zoom calls&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hcMAEq"&gt;Normally, this device costs $130, but it has seen some good price reductions in the past. We have seen the device go down as low as $65. But if you are looking to buy the device now, you can get it for just $80 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PF1Y28C/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=9dd29d118d711aac9ce70db04cc48e45&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1723589734209430134" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-show-8-hd-8in-smart-display%2F-%2FA-81795783%3Fpreselect%3D78656158%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YdQbrX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9573987"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bbKXWtxA9zwezs99vz-E5lCIzNQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19327365/cwelch_191028_3746_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Amazon’s Echo Buds&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bh4M1B"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20937559/amazon-echo-buds-wireless-earbuds-review-features-bose-noise-reduction-price"&gt;Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TQX4oe"&gt;In 2019, Amazon released its first pair of true wireless earbuds: the Echo Buds. The Echo Buds offer superb sound quality, a comfy fit, and Bose’s noise reduction features. And, of course, they also include Alexa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="itnaQP"&gt;Right now, there’s no active deals on the Echo Buds, but you can get them for its usual price of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Echo-Buds/dp/B07F6VM1S3/ref=as_li_ss_tl?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=3619c9cbf19d90024732c6f012617549&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$130 on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cEllxY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625473"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mMzA5wUbZl8ZMBU3z3ww9GStrjw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19336245/dseifert_191031_3770_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon’s Echo Studio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XqDD6Q"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20950100/amazon-echo-studio-smart-speaker-alexa-3d-audio-test-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Echo Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="cZGT85"&gt;If you’re interested in an Alexa smart speaker with better audio quality and Dolby Atmos support, the Echo Studio is the Amazon product you may want to purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u8dmbf"&gt;Currently, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Echo-Studio/dp/B07G9Y3ZMC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725325990660946512" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; are selling a new Echo Studio for $170. Best Buy is also selling a bundle, which includes an &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725326053000014488" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Echo Studio and a Fire TV Stick 4K for $220&lt;/a&gt;, $30 off this listing’s normal price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="D411Fi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9536569"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21546591/best-amazon-echo-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21546591/best-amazon-echo-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:17:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:17:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>These are the violent threats that made Amazon drop Parler</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mYb5VPUBEAqvkOb5jwfTszcNXsA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68661034/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YCalFW"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.294664/gov.uscourts.wawd.294664.10.0_1.pdf"&gt;In a filing on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon responded to Parler’s claims that it acted unfairly in taking down the social network — and in the process, gave outsiders a new look at the content that provoked Amazon to suspend Parler’s web services account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kUbKTY"&gt;Amazon Web Services &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223335/parler-amazon-terminates-web-hosting-aws-google-apple-capitol"&gt;suspended service to Parler on January 9th&lt;/a&gt;, effectively shutting down the social network. It’s failed to secure a replacement web host, and it argued in court that Amazon was exercising unfair monopoly power in taking down the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GpWfBn"&gt;Amazon’s decision to suspend Parler’s service has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22224860/parler-trump-deplatformed-capitol-raid-moderation-censorship-facebook-amazon-twitter"&gt;provoked ongoing debate&lt;/a&gt; about AWS’s power as a hosting provider and whether such suspensions pose a threat to free speech. But while many had seen the suspension as a knee-jerk response to the mob attack on the US Capitol, Amazon’s response makes clear that the service had lodged complaints with Parler long before the raid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qJpp28"&gt;“AWS reported to Parler, over many weeks, dozens of examples of content that encouraged violence,” the company argues in the filing, “including calls to hang public officials, kill Black and Jewish people, and shoot police officers in the head,” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8GMxRZ"&gt;To drive home this point, the complaint includes 15 examples of such posts, which include graphic calls to violence against tech CEOs, school teachers, and professional athletes. In some cases, the comments also refer to specific dates and targets for violence, encouraging users to form militia groups and “acquire targets.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lkTSCv"&gt;Amazon says it submitted more than 100 such comments to Parler in the weeks leading up to the suspension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gWDR4Y"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Content warning: these threats are graphic, violent, and racist; use discretion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HF2_ly2PmKh9wGoJQA9SXVNqJ4Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232524/Screen_Shot_2021_01_13_at_9.35.11_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-2dNK3eWHw82nyWVVBFFgzOqbNg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232526/Screen_Shot_2021_01_13_at_9.35.00_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WM69gp"&gt;The filing gives more background to Amazon’s previous claims that the suspension was in response to escalating calls for violence on Parler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZIcrS"&gt;“It is clear that there is significant content on Parler that encourages and incites violence against others, and that Parler is unable or unwilling to promptly identify and remove this content, which is a violation of our terms of service,” the company said in a statement on January 9th. “We made our concerns known to Parler over a number of weeks and during that time we saw a significant increase in this type of dangerous content, not a decrease, which led to our suspension of their services Sunday evening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lxLdrG"&gt;In the filing, Amazon emphasized that it had suspended service rather than terminating it entirely and was open to restoring service to Parler if the company began moderating content in compliance with AWS’s terms of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s0i3jJ"&gt;Apple CEO Tim Cook made a similar point on Wednesday &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/video/apple-ceo-tim-cook-says-trump-should-answer-for-his-part-in-capitol-hill-violence/"&gt;in an appearance on CBS&lt;/a&gt;, explaining that Apple had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221730/apple-removes-suspends-bans-parler-app-store"&gt;removed Parler from the iOS App Store&lt;/a&gt; because of its failure to moderate its content according to Apple’s terms. “All we’re asking is he meet the Terms of Service,” said Cook. “Our hope is that they do that and get back on the store.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228675/amazon-parler-takedown-violent-threats-moderation-content-free-speech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228675/amazon-parler-takedown-violent-threats-moderation-content-free-speech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:05:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:05:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s first major racial equity investments include a Detroit developer center and HBCU tech hub</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bqB2hEUoyV4fu7JPXwzaF6MrS50=/225x0:2655x1620/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660972/apple_racial_equity_justice_initiative_propel_center_render_01132021_Full_Bleed_Image.jpg.large_2x.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A render of the Propel Center. | Image: Propel Center&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Trabhq"&gt;Apple is announcing &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F01%2Fapple-launches-major-new-racial-equity-and-justice-initiative-projects-to-challenge-systemic-racism-advance-racial-equity-nationwide%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228580%2Fapple-detroit-developer-academy-equity-center-hbcu-tech-hub#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the next big investments&lt;/a&gt; to come out of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/11/21287999/apple-racial-equity-justice-initiative-amount-cook-lisa-jackson"&gt;$100 million commitment to racial equity and justice today&lt;/a&gt;: the launch of an Apple Developer Academy in Detroit; founding support for an Atlanta tech hub for historically Black colleges and universities; and new grants, scholarships, and investments for Black and brown students and entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YxDIzQ"&gt;The Apple Developer Academy in Detroit will be the “first of its kind in the US,” Apple wrote in a press release, after previously partnering on &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/05/16/apple-developer-academy/"&gt;a similar program&lt;/a&gt; in Italy. The academy is focused on “young Black entrepreneurs, creators, and coders” and will offer training in iOS app development. The plan is to offer a shorter 30-day program that introduces students to “what it means to be a developer” and then to offer an “intensive” 10- to 12- month program meant to help aspiring developers gain relevant skills to get tech jobs or start their own businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="g6ARRI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Propel Center will offer in-person and online courses&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WgMimC"&gt;Apple expects the academy to teach around 1,000 students each year. It’s supposed to open later in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1QmSuM"&gt;In Atlanta, Apple is partnering to help launch the Propel Center, a tech-focused hub for HBCUs. The center will offer in-person and online courses focused on technology, entertainment, and business. It’ll be located in the Atlanta University Center that links four HBCUs — Clark Atlanta University, Spelman College, Morehouse College, and the Morehouse School of Medicine. Apple and Southern Company, an Atlanta-based energy giant, will each contribute $25 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P64QZI"&gt;Other tech companies and major donors have made similar contributions to HBCUs over the past year. In September, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2020-09-17-IBM-Establishes-First-Quantum-Education-and-Research-Initiative-for-Historically-Black-Colleges-and-Universities"&gt;IBM announced&lt;/a&gt; it was putting $100 million into technology, skill development, and other resources for HBCUs alongside the launch of an “IBM Quantum education and research initiative.” The same month, Michael Bloomberg &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/03/business/dealbook/bloomberg-black-medical-schools-donation.html"&gt;announced plans&lt;/a&gt; to give $100 million to four historically Black medical schools, focused on easing student debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ew5eF"&gt;Apple also announced a number of new grants and investments today. It’s investing $10 million with Harlem Capital, a VC firm with the goal of “investing in 1,000 diverse founders over the next 20 years,” and $25 million in Siebert Williams Shank’s Clear Vision Impact Fund, which is focused on minority-owned businesses. Apple is launching grants for HBCU engineering programs and is expanding its scholarship program with a focus on underrepresented communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZlE5d"&gt;Today’s announcements are part of a $100 million commitment Apple made in June 2020, as companies across the US began reflecting on how they could better combat racism following the death of George Floyd and protests against police brutality. Apple VP Lisa Jackson was put in charge of the initiative, which was meant to “challenge the systemic barriers to opportunity and dignity that exists for communities of color and particular for the black community,” Apple CEO Tim Cook said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bn6s6v"&gt;Facebook, Microsoft, Google, and other tech giants &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21362540/racial-justice-tech-companies-donations-apple-amazon-facebook-google-microsoft"&gt;have made similar pledges&lt;/a&gt;, putting millions of dollars toward racial equity initiatives. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228580/apple-detroit-developer-academy-equity-center-hbcu-tech-hub"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228580/apple-detroit-developer-academy-equity-center-hbcu-tech-hub</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
