<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-03T15:52:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T15:52:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T15:52:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Today I learned you can surf YouTube on old Chromecasts with a hidden phone remote</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_z5iz2MVB7F30OanoCvntH1FHKk=/0x0:4032x2688/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225907/PXL_20211203_200442272.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="O8oknN"&gt;Did you know the YouTube app on your older Chromecast has a hidden remote control that lets you surface an entire YouTube app that you can scroll?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I824Fk"&gt;You just need to start casting something to your TV in the YouTube app with the Cast button up top — then hit the Cast button a second time to access a menu where you’ll find a button labeled Remote. Then, you get a full D-pad to move around, a voice search button, and the all-important Back button you’ll need to back out of that video and access a full YouTube interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vJiZDP"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  Watching YouTube on your TV with Google Chromecast? You can use your phone as a remote to cast and control the YouTube app on your TV. Here's how: &lt;a href="https://t.co/LdVa3Peyw3"&gt;https://t.co/LdVa3Peyw3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/nAaYUKx0Sy"&gt;pic.twitter.com/nAaYUKx0Sy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— TeamYouTube (@TeamYouTube) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TeamYouTube/status/1466572963507957760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dzSm8F"&gt;Originally, the Google Chromecast HDMI dongle required you to control it largely from your phone, “casting” each and every video you wanted to watch to your TV screen instead of browsing — until the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21495609/google-chromecast-2020-review-streaming-remote-control"&gt;2020 Chromecast with Google TV&lt;/a&gt; added its own physical remote.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r6Obq5"&gt;But apparently, that changed. &lt;a href="https://chromeunboxed.com/youtube-chromecast-remote-hidden-ui-google-tv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrome Unboxed&lt;/em&gt; reported in February&lt;/a&gt; that the YouTube app on Chromecast had added a browsing experience with the hidden remote, and sites &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/12/03/youtube-app-chromecast-ultra/"&gt;like &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/google-brings-the-full-youtube-app-experience-to-your-older-chromecast/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are now reporting that it’s broadly rolling out to older dongles like the third-gen Chromecast and Chromecast Ultra. That’s a nice bonus &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22790946/google-stadia-birthday-premiere-edition-price-free"&gt;if you recently nabbed the Ultra for $22.22&lt;/a&gt; in the Stadia sale.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oOXk9a2pITMYhEwCY8KjeqSPIJ0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23061469/PXL_20211203_200908381.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0j1mdo"&gt;I can’t confirm when it rolled out, but I do see that &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7640706"&gt;Google’s support page has officially added instructions for using the remote&lt;/a&gt;, something that the Wayback Machine tells me wasn’t yet there back on, say, &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211005012925/https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7640706"&gt;October 5th&lt;/a&gt;, and the company &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TeamYouTube/status/1466572963507957760"&gt;tweeted about the feature&lt;/a&gt; yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NH8Va3"&gt;The phone remote is a little laggy compared to using a dedicated remote or even using an iPhone to control an Apple TV, but it works fine so far on my Chromecast Ultra. I’d probably use it a lot if I valued YouTube’s recommendations more. (I don’t understand why it keeps recommending videos I’ve already watched and ones from many years ago.) I wish it were available in Netflix, where I do tend to scroll a lot, but I didn’t see the option there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EU4e5X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816424/youtube-chromecast-update-phone-remote-control"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816424/youtube-chromecast-update-phone-remote-control</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T15:26:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T15:26:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Best gaming laptop in 2021: seven laptops to get your game on</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptops 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 gaming laptop" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dFgjUrUVReawUz4BcRUID8XTWDI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68856650/akrales_210226_4440_0019.9.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The best gaming laptop is the Asus ROG Zephyrus G15.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The best gaming laptop at every size and price&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="23pZwg"&gt;The best gaming laptops are changing every year. The early days of mobile gaming were largely desktop replacements — clunky chassis, multiple power bricks, and RGB lighting galore. But the top contenders now are different. Manufacturers are finally putting powerful specs in sleeker, more portable, and more professional builds. They have excellent, fast refreshing screens that are necessary for a great gaming experience. These laptops aren’t just great for gaming, but for everyday work as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qiHviH"&gt;The best gaming laptop of 2021 is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt;. It can handle the most demanding games on the market today and also makes a great daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VRi2QJ"&gt;We’ll be updating this page regularly as the best gaming laptops hit shelves throughout this year. Some exciting updates are on the way. AMD and Nvidia have announced their next-gen series of mobile processors and mobile graphics cards — the Ryzen 5000 series and the GeForce RTX 3000 series, respectively — and we’re already seeing them in premium gaming laptops across manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGRnFN"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22217171/gaming-laptops-qhd-screens-display-fast-refresh-rate"&gt;QHD screen&lt;/a&gt; is another feature to watch for in the best gaming laptops. A growing number of manufacturers are releasing configurations with 1440p displays, even in gaming laptops under $2,000. These options can hit a sweet spot for many gamers: a better experience than 1080p without the price premium or raw horsepower required for a 4K display. You can expect decently high refresh rates from these panels as well, depending on the model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5KtNO"&gt;One more thing to keep in mind with the best gaming laptops is the power you can expect. Not all chips with the same name are created equal — the RTX 3070 in one laptop may not deliver the same frame rates as the RTX 3070 in another laptop due to its wattage (as well as other factors like the processor and cooling). Nvidia now requires companies to disclose clock speeds and graphics power on each model’s product page, but plenty of manufacturers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266921/nvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs"&gt;haven’t done that yet&lt;/a&gt;. Your best bet, if you can’t find those numbers on a company’s website, is to read some reviews and make sure the model you’re considering will deliver the frame rates you’re looking for. We will note the wattage used in any laptops we review with the new RTX graphics cards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1WSZi"&gt;If you’re not sure what to play on the best gaming laptops, check out our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22158504/best-games-2020-ps5-xbox-nintendo-tlou2-animal-crossing-miles-morales"&gt;best games of 2020&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re looking for a more multipurpose device, check out our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptop&lt;/a&gt; page. If you’re an Android gamer, we’ve also got a list of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt; you can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="NqFABt"&gt;Best Gaming Laptop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VQOCHc"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptop 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 gaming laptop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WQts40hc8DMLBo4BPnPjc4j4RSI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341895/akrales_210226_4440_0125.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 is the best gaming laptop of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oTToOm"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rE8ByG"&gt;The best gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="dqOSgQ"&gt;Asus’s ROG Zephyrus G14 was our top gaming laptop pick for quite a while. It did just about everything right, and we weren’t sure whether Asus could ever replicate its resounding success. But somehow, the company managed to make the G14 just a bit bigger, and a heck of a lot better. In doing so, it’s created the ROG Zephyrus G15, the best 15-inch rig you can buy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsXGzm"&gt;At just over four pounds, the Zephyrus G15 is one of the lightest 15-inch gaming laptops you can buy. But you’re not making any compromises on performance for that portability: it’s powered by the top mobile chips that AMD and Nvidia have to offer, and includes a fast 165Hz QHD (1440p) display. Together, those components can handle even the toughest AAA titles at QHD resolution. The panel has excellent color reproduction as well, so your games will look great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HMlhzT"&gt;But it’s not just the gaming; almost everything else about the G15 is great, too. The audio (pumped from a six-speaker array) has strong percussion and bass, the keyboard and touchpad have a satisfying click, the port selection leaves little to be desired, and the battery can last for a whopping eight and a half hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MktsFD"&gt;The G15 won’t be the laptop for everyone. There’s no webcam, which is a significant oversight, and some may prefer something more affordable, or with a flashier aesthetic. But as a package, the G15 is the one to beat. Not only is it the best gaming laptop you can buy, but it’s also one of the best laptops you can buy, period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uMAFCa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10385239" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="PEmMiz"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Razer Blade Pro 17 gaming laptop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Hw1GXC0JJNr36nQ6K4vzlWTH-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21820230/mchin_181119_4158_0015.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade Pro 17 is a monster of a gaming laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yzdsDK"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21405760/razer-blade-pro-17-2020-review"&gt;Razer Blade Pro 17&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jT5h16"&gt;The best big-screen gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="E8Fdz3"&gt;The Blade Pro 17 delivers some of the best gaming performance you can find in a laptop — but that’s not even its superpower. What makes Razer’s 17-inch flagship so impressive is it packs that unbelievable power into a thin and attractive chassis. It’s just 0.8 inches thick and only requires one charging brick — so you can carry it around in a backpack or briefcase without compromising on power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQQiQ0"&gt;This year’s model comes with an FHD 360Hz screen — the highest refresh rate you can get on a laptop. It also has a customizable per-key RGB keyboard, which adds a touch of color without being too intense for the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsGaDN"&gt;The Blade Pro 17 certainly isn’t cheap, but it’s the laptop to buy if you want the best of the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wsMJEI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505921"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XCwzkS"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Asus ROG Strix G15 Advantage Edition gaming laptop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4-MFImj_bClitaOWhNkct_TSxqo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22552472/mchin_20190821_4609_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 Advantage Edition is powered by an impressive AMD processor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2kvoth"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465565/asus-rog-strix-g15-advantage-edition-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Strix G15 Advantage Edition&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="SAASF8"&gt;The best AMD gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HhOl4t"&gt;The ROG Strix G15 Advantage Edition is one of the few gaming laptops you’ll find that includes both an AMD processor and an AMD GPU. Not to worry — it delivers gaming performance on par with what you’ll see from laptops with Nvidia’s top GPUs. It also delivers one of the best gaming battery experiences we’ve ever seen — it was able to maintain playable frame rates on &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2 &lt;/em&gt;for over an hour with no charger attached. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHVLju"&gt;Speaking of battery, we averaged nine hours and 16 minutes of work use between charges, which makes the Strix G15 far and away one of the longest-lasting gaming laptops on the market. That’s doubly impressive because it’s powering a ton of flashy LEDs, including a per-key RGB keyboard and a colorful light strip around the front edge of the deck. If you’re looking for a jazzy, bold design and you’re all-in on AMD, the Strix G15 Advantage edition is a great gaming laptop for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="p8WbEf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10641674"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="tOxdNl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptop 2021: Razer Blade 14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BcbK0DjFD3FXDpcXKnqg9-2Nzxk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22675596/mchin_210621_4641_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade 14 is the best 14-inch gaming laptop of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QEpIQu"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22548663/razer-blade-14-review-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen-9-5900hx-nvidia-rtx-3070"&gt;Razer Blade 14&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="OCz9wT"&gt;The best gaming laptop in a 14-inch chassis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="OanWnj"&gt;If you’re looking for a powerful 14-inch device that can keep up with the best 15-inch gaming laptops on the market, the only place you’ll find that is the Razer Blade 14. This slim and portable device includes Nvdia’s RTX 3070 and RTX 3080, Nvidia’s top-of-the-line mobile GPUs, as well as a powerful eight-core AMD chip. It’s a gorgeous device, with a QHD 165Hz display option and a classy RGB keyboard. There’s even a reasonable port selection, including HDMI 2.1 as well as two USB-C ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xwEKhI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10803512"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ncjeoh"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q85Q-sLwALCr0V01cfBqOIkh-Vo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22859891/akrales_210916_4757_0204.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Alienware X17 is a powerful but surprisingly thin and quiet gaming device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="J74U3a"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22765258/alienware-x17-review-4k-17-inch-gaming-laptop"&gt;Alienware X17&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lzKwju"&gt;A gaming laptop with a 4K screen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="m6FWbU"&gt;There’s finally a laptop that can deliver an enjoyable gaming experience in 4K — as long as you’re prepared to fork over some real cash. The Alienware X17 (currently starting at $2,199) can run all kinds of modern titles at playable frame rates at its native 3840 x 2160 resolution. It could even stay close to 60fps with ray tracing on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ULSQ9m"&gt;The X17’s power isn’t its only standout quality. Dell has also managed to cram that power into an impressively thin and sleek chassis. It’s just 0.84 inches thick, with an RGB keyboard that isn’t too obnoxious and a touchpad that lights up when you press it. And it’s quite cool and quiet, even under heavy gaming loads.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lpAXv8"&gt;On the other hand, the X17 would not be a good choice to double as a daily driver (though it did do well in our Premiere Pro testing). The webcam is mediocre, and the touchpad is a bit small, especially for a 17-inch notebook. Battery life only averaged around four hours in our testing. And while the chassis is compact, it’s still not light, weighing in at over six pounds. But if you’re looking for a 4K laptop that is, first and foremost, great at running games, this device should top your list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vlDZW0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10901040"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="9xsdU2"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Asus ROG Strix Scar 15 gaming laptop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aTzXemr0v3qrt3uxufTnb2q6HSA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22183653/mchin_190314_4347_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ROG Strix Scar 15 is a colorful laptop with a premium price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="E7sNUb"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22195676/asus-rog-strix-scar-15-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Strix Scar 15&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7lPrCK"&gt;The best laptop with flashy RGB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="SK7elL"&gt;If you’re looking for a “traditional” premium gaming laptop with colorful, flashy panache, the ROG Strix Scar 15 is for you. The Strix’s keyboard isn’t just one of the most comfortable that we’ve ever tested on a gaming laptop; it also has some of the coolest per-key RGB lighting we’ve ever seen with all kinds of effects. There’s also a colorful light strip wrapped around the front of the deck (customizable as well) and a colorful glowing logo on the lid. In short: if you use this in public, people will notice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZuwqX"&gt;Of course, the Strix is great on the inside as well, delivering some of the best frame rates you’ll find from a 15-inch laptop with Intel’s and Nvidia’s top chips. You’ll get the full benefit of their power with a 300Hz screen option as well. And the Strix comes preloaded with various programs to help customize your gaming experience. You can personalize color profiles, bandwidth allocation, and more based on the type of game you’re playing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YAnMj2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10355468"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="BYdZ6R"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Razer Blade 15 Advanced gaming laptop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JEuLWwA7yrXUTplilCC7i1YKquw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21922571/cfaulkner_200929_4214_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade 15 is the 15-inch gaming laptop to beat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="n9BvYP"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22723299/razer-blade-15-advanced-late-2021-review-specs-features-design"&gt;Razer Blade 15 Advanced&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wzRw2D"&gt;A great thin and light gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="EcPuJg"&gt;The Blade 15 isn’t as powerful as its 17-inch sibling, but it may be a more pragmatic purchase for many people. If you’re looking for a balanced combination of performance and portability, the Blade 15 may hit that sweet spot. It still packs the top chips on the market and comes with a 240Hz QHD display, but at just 4.39 pounds and 0.62 inches thick, it’s comparable in size to a number of 15-inch productivity machines like the Dell XPS 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8vpQe"&gt;In addition to its reliable gaming performance, the Blade 15 works well as a productivity machine. We’re big fans of its keyboard, which is quite comfortable to use and has per-key RGB lighting, and the touchpad, which is roomy with a satisfying click. Our primary complaint is that this Blade got quite hot during our game testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5s4KmJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591143"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ugRlFl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptop 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z2ey3YUIDkL6V41wJdA4TQbMxhs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22804769/akrales_210824_4724_0022.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 is a portable, powerful gaming device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gXl1tL"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21197761/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G14&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ibDYbq"&gt;A gaming laptop with an exceptional keyboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="PjVXGI"&gt;The ROG Zephyrus G14 is no longer the best 14-inch gaming laptop you can buy, but it’s still great. For well under $2,000, the Zephyrus crams one of the most powerful mobile processors on the market into a super portable 14-inch chassis. With capable cooling to boot, the laptop delivers frame rates we’ve never seen in a laptop of this size before. It handled every game we threw at it without breaking a sweat.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LRoiIm"&gt;But aside from its excellent gaming performance, the G14 makes a great daily driver. The touchpad, display, and port selection are all excellent, and the keyboard is one of the absolute best you can buy on the market. Even the battery life is good — something we almost never get to say about gaming laptops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yypId"&gt;There are a few downsides to the G14, but they’re fairly small and user-dependent. The most significant note is that it lacks a webcam; you’ll need an external one if you plan on taking video calls. There’s also some bleed in the backlighting, there’s no Thunderbolt connectivity (since it’s an AMD system, and that’s an Intel standard), and the fans can get louder than most under load. But these are very much nitpicks that won’t have a large impact on plenty of people’s gaming experience. Overall, though the Razer Blade 14 delivers better raw performance, we still have very few complaints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3eM7Jm"&gt;Asus recently collaborated with DJ Alan Walker on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22629096/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-alan-walker-edition-dj-deck-gaming-laptop"&gt;Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition&lt;/a&gt;, with a box that becomes  DJ deck. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EigMsz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505867"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T15:24:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T15:24:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter losing design and engineering leaders in restructure under new CEO</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter’s blue bird silhouette logo on a black background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fCYS89FOa_XVNru1ooRkb-yqohc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225764/acastro_180827_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4joFLG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808756/twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-jack-dorsey-bluesky-moderation"&gt;Twitter’s new CEO&lt;/a&gt; is reorganizing the company, with two top executives being removed as part of the shakeup. A &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterIR/status/1466852838286381056"&gt;regulatory document&lt;/a&gt; explains that Twitter is restructuring its Consumer, Revenue, and Core Tech divisions under individual leaders in an attempt to “drive increased accountability, speed, and operational efficiency.” Kayvon Beykpour, Bruce Falck, and Nick Caldwell will lead those three teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pZ9jZF"&gt;As part of the change, Twitter’s engineering lead, Michael Montano, and its design and research lead, Dantley Davis, will be leaving their positions at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gEkc12"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90674877/death-threats-misinformation-and-racism-in-silicon-valley-meet-the-designer-shaping-the-future-of-twitter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fast Company &lt;/em&gt;profile of Davis&lt;/a&gt;, published in September, describes him as “the first Black executive to report to the CEO since Twitter went public.” &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/16/technology/twitter-culture-change-conflict.html"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he joined the company in 2019 to help make big changes to the company’s culture in an attempt to fix stagnation. Some employees reportedly found the changes he made to be unpleasant, saying that they weren’t used to being asked to criticize each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WQiHgc"&gt;Beykpour, Twitter’s head of consumer product, was quoted by &lt;em&gt;Fast Company&lt;/em&gt; as saying that “Dantley joining this company is one of the most important inflection points I believe we’ve had.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ltFnDV"&gt;This shakeup will be the second big change at the company this week. On Monday, Twitter founder Jack Dorsey &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22807578/jack-dorsey-rumor-resign-twitter-ceo-square-web3"&gt;announced he was stepping away from the company&lt;/a&gt;, leaving then-CTO Parag Agrawal in charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LSHGzp"&gt;Twitter said the reorganization is meant to speed up the company’s decision making. “Parag is focused on operational excellence and setting Twitter up to hit its goals; these changes were made with that in mind,” Twitter spokesperson Laura Alexander told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="25UoxM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 3rd, 3:38PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added comment from a Twitter spokesperson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816362/twitter-reoganization-consumer-revenue-tech-dantley-davis-parag-agrawal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816362/twitter-reoganization-consumer-revenue-tech-dantley-davis-parag-agrawal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T15:11:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T15:11:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Courtney Love says she has Elon Musk’s private emails</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Rockin’1000 In Florence" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h1n6mLZLra_Rd3dG-6PdR7ZUGts=/0x0:3648x2432/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225643/1006037968.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Courtney Love, ladies and gentlemen | Photo by Francesco Prandoni/Redferns&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="R97gmj"&gt;Courtney Love Cobain, Elon Musk, Bernie Sanders, and Kendall Roy are all in the running to be Friday’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maplecocaine/status/1080665226410889217?s=20"&gt;Main Character on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; after a single tweet where the queen of ’90s grunge music Twitter-scolded the Tesla CEO for his mean reply to the Vermont senator (we’ll get to Kendall in a sec). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GCmhDX"&gt;According to Love, she was bcc’d on Musk’s “str8, male, PayPal mafia email group” for months. “With that information in mind, don’t you think in a ‘civilized society’ one should embrace paying our fair share of tax?” she tweeted on Thursday. She attached a screengrab of Musk’s November 14th reply to Sanders’ tweet that asserted, “We must demand that the extremely wealthy pay their fair share. Period.” Being one of those extremely wealthies, Musk apparently took umbrage and replied to the 80-year-old senator: “I keep forgetting you’re still alive.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Tm3o2"&gt;That didn’t sit right with Love, apparently. “Don’t pick on Bernie. It’s Kendall Roy shit,” she instructed him, adding the name of the erstwhile Number One Boy from the HBO drama &lt;em&gt;Succession.&lt;/em&gt; Kendall, you see, has tried to score points in the court of public opinion by calling out the many misdeeds of his family’s company, especially patriarch Logan Roy. If you have watched &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt;, you know how ludicrous it is for Kendall to depict himself as the “good” guy (if you have not watched it, remedy that asap) and that he is a very wealthy, generally weaselly fella who, for some reason, craves approval, sometimes seeking it from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/successionreact/status/1455610105098027016?s=20"&gt;random tweets&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/successionreact/status/1451577048519036932?s=20"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pse4cI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@elonmusk&lt;/a&gt; you know your str8, male, PayPal mafia email group? I was on bcc for MONTHS on that thing   With that information in mind, don’t you think in a “civilized society” one should embrace paying our fair share of tax? Don’t pick on Bernie. It’s Kendall Roy shit. &lt;a href="https://t.co/cW4gRCxvjU"&gt;pic.twitter.com/cW4gRCxvjU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Courtney Love Cobain (@Courtney) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Courtney/status/1466471486345158665?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="he3Cur"&gt;The internet waited with bated breath for Love to spill the tea (she even put a teapot emoji in the tweet) on what was actually in those emails from the str8, male, PayPal mafia, but its collective hopes were dashed when she &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Courtney/status/1466471818336813073?s=20"&gt;later tweeted&lt;/a&gt; she was a “GOOD Queen,” noting that capitalism and the American dream had been good to Musk, and he should be good to it in return by paying taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y4HYgr"&gt;Lest you think this is a pop-culture lesson with no moral to the story, Love actually raises a point that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768364/elon-musk-poll-twitter-tesla-10-percent-billionaires-capital-gains-tax"&gt;Musk himself has mulled&lt;/a&gt; to his 65 million followers: how much he does or doesn’t pay in taxes. Musk has been a vocal critic of a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-the-billionaires-income-tax-would-work-11635325201?mod=article_inline"&gt;proposal to tax unrealized gains&lt;/a&gt; on publicly traded assets for some of the wealthiest Americans and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768364/elon-musk-poll-twitter-tesla-10-percent-billionaires-capital-gains-tax"&gt;said in a tweet thread&lt;/a&gt; last month that the only way for him “to pay taxes personally is to sell stock.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wRCHda"&gt;We know that Love is all too aware of the power of Twitter; her former attorney Rhonda Holmes sued her (unsuccessfully), saying an errant DM that Love tweeted publicly had damaged Holmes’ reputation. A jury found in 2014 that &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/courtney-love-wins-twitter-defamation-673972/"&gt;Love shouldn’t be held liable&lt;/a&gt; for the since-deleted tweet. It seems unlikely she’d tweet about having private emails without the receipts to back up her claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZrXDt"&gt;We also know that Love knows her &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt;; in a recent episode, Kendall rigged speakers to interrupt his sister Siobhan (Shiv, to her friends) as she gave what was to be an important speech to employees. Playing on the speakers was “Rape Me,” a controversial song by &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hTWKbfoikeg&amp;amp;ab_channel=NirvanaVEVO"&gt;Nirvana, the seminal grunge band&lt;/a&gt; that was fronted by Love’s late husband, Kurt Cobain. &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/music/news/courtney-love-kurt-cobain-proud-succession-nirvana-rape-me-1235103939/"&gt;Love said on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; she had “never been so proud of approving one of Kurt’s songs” for the show to use. “I’m sure wherever he is he’s proud of this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zSVc7c"&gt;As of this writing, Musk has not replied publicly to Love, but he has her email address apparently, so perhaps they’ve sorted things out privately. If she felt like fwd’ing any of those bcc’d emails, the fallout from doing so would surely rival even the wildest of &lt;em&gt;Succession’&lt;/em&gt;s episodes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XK2Oxr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816202/courtney-love-elon-musk-bernie-sanders-kendall-roy-succession-taxes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816202/courtney-love-elon-musk-bernie-sanders-kendall-roy-succession-taxes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T14:43:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T14:43:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valve says DayZ and five other games are now anti-cheat ready for Linux (and Steam Deck)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/whEbcF56vIcAGHnrHFZZfXz_7_k=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225471/steam_deck.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aceLth"&gt;Valve’s Steam Deck handheld &lt;a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/steamdeck/faq"&gt;won’t have any exclusive games&lt;/a&gt;, but it is slowly filling in some holes in its Windows game library — &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/group/4145017/view/3104663180636096966"&gt;Valve says&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Arma 3&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; DayZ&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Unturned&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Planetside 2&lt;/em&gt; now have functioning BattlEye anti-cheat when you’re using the Proton compatibility layer to play Windows games in Linux. That brings the total to six games, including &lt;em&gt;Ark: Survival Evolved&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mount &amp;amp; Blade II: Bannerlord. &lt;/em&gt;(Those two already had support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22737127/valve-steam-deck-battleye-anti-cheat-pubg-dayz-r6-siege"&gt;as of November 8th&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jGOeGB"&gt;That compatibility is important for Linux in general (and the Steam Deck handheld specifically) because they don’t play Windows games out of the box &lt;em&gt;unless&lt;/em&gt; they work with Proton, and third-party anti-cheat software is known to interfere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E78wga"&gt;But for two of the most popular flavors of anti-cheat, this shouldn’t be a difficult fix! Epic Games has said enabling Easy Anti-Cheat (EAC) in Proton should take “just a few clicks” in the game developer portal. Valve has said enabling BattlEye is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22737127/valve-steam-deck-battleye-anti-cheat-pubg-dayz-r6-siege"&gt;as easy as sending an email&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2lRxXp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Destiny 2 feels like an obvious Steam Deck candidate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O6tZoA"&gt;And yet, the developers in charge of many of the top anti-cheat games on Steam have been unwilling or unable to confirm whether they’ll actually send that email or make those clicks, including Bungie, Crytek, EA, Krafton, Microsoft, and Ubisoft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PEyPN3"&gt;While many top games run on the Steam Deck, we do not currently know if &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends, Destiny 2, Halo,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; will be among them, for example. Epic would also not commit to &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, despite enabling Easy Anti-Cheat for Proton in general. That’s not a Steam title, though, and Epic does see Valve as a competitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NkC2Om"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709918/valve-steam-deck-supported-games-anti-cheat-proton-eac-battleye-epic"&gt;Here’s our full running list of responses from game studios with top anti-cheat games&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="5FTGt9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Steam Deck: Five big things we learned from Valve’s developer summit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22779252/steam-deck-things-we-learned-from-valve-developer-summit"},{"title":"This is the Steam Deck’s box","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/2/22814910/steam-deck-box-package-power-adapter"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="EF9A89"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Steam Deck: a Switch-like portable gaming PC|103274" data-volume-uuid="2d2697872" data-volume-id="103274" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-833" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816279/valve-proton-battleye-anti-cheat-dayz-linux-steam-deck"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816279/valve-proton-battleye-anti-cheat-dayz-linux-steam-deck</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T14:41:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T14:41:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>US State Department phones were reportedly hacked by NSO spyware</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iYl3CTius06V-4PQrxvyFxyHDf4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225455/acastro_170621_1777_0006_v4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="npOy6x"&gt;At least nine employees of the US State Department working in or with Uganda had their iPhones hacked with spyware made by NSO Group, according to &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-us-state-department-phones-hacked-with-israeli-company-spyware-sources-2021-12-03/"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s unclear who carried out the attacks, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;NSO Group says&lt;/a&gt; it only sells its software to government organizations that have gotten approval from the Israeli government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CjB8yZ"&gt;NSO has claimed that its spyware isn’t able to target US phone numbers (that is, numbers with a country code of +1). This case doesn’t seem to disprove that claim — &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reports that, while the people targeted were employees of the State Department, they were using foreign telephone numbers. Still, the devices were used for official State Department business, suggesting NSO may now be implicated in an espionage effort against the US government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0GCDk"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, the attacks happened in “the last several months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fPIev3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pegasus is powerful spyware that could infect phones without the user noticing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aeITGI"&gt;NSO’s Pegasus spyware is capable of remotely logging data from an infected iOS or Android device and can be used to covertly turn on a phone’s microphones or cameras. It’s also designed to infect phones using a “zero-click” attack, in which spyware can be installed without the target clicking a link or otherwise taking action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hjxCuD"&gt;Pegasus is also not supposed to leave any traces, though investigators have developed some methods to determine if a phone was hacked by it. You can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;read our explainer on it here&lt;/a&gt;, which goes into the media investigations of its usage by governments to target journalists, politicians, and activists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S2nLMU"&gt;NSO, based in Israel, has to get approval from the Israeli Ministry of Defense before it sells its software to another government agency. NSO co-founder Shalev Hulio has insisted that the company doesn’t know who its clients are spying on using its software. The company also says that it will investigate clients if they’re using Pegasus on off-limits targets and cut off the client’s access to the software if there’s evidence of abuse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="smQ4B7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pegasus is meant to be used against criminals and terrorists but has a long history of abuse&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="axdAIx"&gt;An NSO spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; that the company would be investigating its reports, and the Israeli embassy told the outlet that a government targeting US officials with Pegasus would be “a severe violation” of its licensing agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ISa9ZP"&gt;The US recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761565/nso-group-pegasus-spyware-entity-list-us-government-human-rights"&gt;added NSO to its entity list&lt;/a&gt;, which puts heavy restrictions on American companies being able to sell their products or services to the group. In the private sector, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798917/apple-nso-group-spyware-pegasus-cybersecurity-research"&gt;Apple filed a lawsuit against NSO Group&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that the company broke Apple’s terms of service by creating over a hundred iCloud accounts to send malicious data via iMessage. Apple says that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus"&gt;patched the specific vulnerability NSO used&lt;/a&gt; to install Pegasus with iOS 14.8 and that it had added additional protections in iOS 15, which the company says it hasn’t seen Pegasus breach yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zeNci"&gt;When the company announced its lawsuit, Apple said it would also notify users who had been targeted by a state-sponsored spying campaign. Ugandan politician Norbert Mao &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/norbertmao/status/1463364241688305664"&gt;tweeted in November&lt;/a&gt; that he received one of the notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ex6GDO"&gt;There are also reports that the US government is working on an initiative with other countries to prevent surveillance tools and technology from being sold to authoritarian governments. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/biden-us-china-export-surveillance-human-rights-11638471880"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the effort will focus on export controls and will likely be announced at the Summit for Democracy, which starts December 9th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816068/us-state-department-officials-nso-pegasus-uganda-government-spyware"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816068/us-state-department-officials-nso-pegasus-uganda-government-spyware</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T14:36:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T14:36:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>As warehouses take off, they need to kick natural gas </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Snarled Supply Chain Is Making U.S. Warehouse Shortage Worse" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GiFfAeeseSNyi_u4b-N2PUGqfxg=/2x0:4199x2798/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225425/1236465519.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Warehouses in Redlands, California, U.S., on Sunday, Nov. 7, 2021.&amp;nbsp; | Roger Kisby/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RFMCX3"&gt;Warehouses are increasingly dominating the commercial building landscape in the US, which could have ramifications for efforts to tackle climate change. According to &lt;a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=50496"&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; recently released by the US Energy Information Administration (EIA), warehouses and storage units have become the most common commercial buildings in the country — outpacing offices. That has the potential to cause greenhouse gas emissions to climb or tumble, and it largely hinges on whether warehouses can ditch natural gas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S82waM"&gt;Compared to office buildings, warehouses that store everything from food to clothes tend to rely more heavily on gas heating systems because upfront costs of those systems are cheap, and they’re easy to install, an expert tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Even though warehouses typically use less energy than offices, there’s a risk that their reliance on gas could increase the share of emissions coming from commercial buildings, which are already responsible for &lt;a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/buildings/about-commercial-buildings-integration-program"&gt;16 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the country’s greenhouse gas pollution. For the Biden administration to reach its goal of &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-sets-2030-greenhouse-gas-pollution-reduction-target-aimed-at-creating-good-paying-union-jobs-and-securing-u-s-leadership-on-clean-energy-technologies/"&gt;halving&lt;/a&gt; America’s&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;planet-heating carbon pollution compared to 2005 levels by 2030, it’ll have to work to clean up warehouse operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2KGMsi"&gt;“If the building sector itself has moved, that means our strategy has to be adapted,” says Bing Liu, building subsector leader at the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory. “If you look at space heating energy use, because [warehouses use] less efficient technologies, it’s actually concerning.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="nJqZsp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;E-commerce has fueled the boom in warehouses&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NSXp8z"&gt;E-commerce has fueled the boom in warehouses. Online retail giants like Amazon use massive distribution centers to sort and send out their goods. Every $1 billion in online sales generates 1.25 million square feet of warehouse space demand, according to commercial real estate firm &lt;a href="https://www.cbre.us/research-and-reports/2021-US-Real-Estate-Market-Outlook-Industrial-Logistics"&gt;CBRE&lt;/a&gt;. The square footage of storage spaces in the US has ballooned from just over 10 billion square feet in 1999 to roughly 17 billion square feet in 2018 (the most recent year for which the EIA has data). That’s more floorspace than more than 295,000 football fields would cover.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TbmGFs"&gt;While we don’t have data yet from the EIA beyond 2018, the pandemic has driven up demand for warehouse space even further. Online shopping became even &lt;a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/the-great-consumer-shift-ten-charts-that-show-how-us-shopping-behavior-is-changing"&gt;more popular&lt;/a&gt;. And with consumers still demanding quick deliveries despite kinks in supply chains, retailers are increasingly &lt;a href="https://12exx71wc3m46es1m3w8fvx1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ElionPartners_iREOCMemberReport_Jun2020.pdf"&gt;storing excess inventory&lt;/a&gt; in warehouses. At the same time, demand for &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/02/business/economy/remote-work-manhattan-storefronts.html"&gt;retail&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/29/nyregion/remote-work-coronavirus-pandemic.html"&gt;office&lt;/a&gt; space has taken a hit during the pandemic because of remote work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hrap2p"&gt;There is a lot of room for warehouses to improve when it comes to their impact on the environment. Liu says warehouse developers can take the lead of office buildings that have been quicker to electrify and switch from natural gas heating systems over to electric&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;heat pumps. Some climate-conscious cities, starting with Berkeley, California, in the US, have moved to ban natural gas hook-ups in new construction — efforts that the gas industry is &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/02/22/967439914/as-cities-grapple-with-climate-change-gas-utilities-fight-to-stay-in-business"&gt;trying to derail&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5ItLgY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There is a lot of room for warehouses to improve&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jRJyu6"&gt;Other trends could make pollution from warehouses’ gas heating a bigger problem. A lot of e-commerce warehouses are clustered in sunny Southern California, where &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808388/amazon-target-port-congestion-pollution-maritime-shipping"&gt;Amazon sends much of its imported goods&lt;/a&gt;. But there’s recently been more warehouse growth in colder regions in the midwest — which raises the urgency for transitioning warehouses to cleaner heating, according to Liu. On top of that, warehouses tend to be less insulated against the elements than office buildings.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;And as the Biden administration moves to keep &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22800410/black-friday-holiday-shopping-supply-chain-pollution-ports-warehouses-california"&gt;ports open 24/7&lt;/a&gt; to ease supply chain backlogs, that might mean bigger heating bills for warehouses because of longer operating hours stretching into colder evenings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cw0wKX"&gt;On the other hand, if warehouses sort out the heating issue, their rising popularity could potentially drive down greenhouse gas emissions for the commercial building sector. Unrefrigerated warehouses, which make up the biggest chunk of storage buildings, typically use less than half as much energy per square foot compared with office buildings, according to the EIA. That’s because there aren’t so many computers to keep running or people to keep comfortable with air conditioning and hot water. Ultimately, having a larger share of less energy-intensive buildings like warehouses “has the potential to bring down total commercial energy use,” Zack Marohl, an economist at the EIA, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mx2wQw"&gt;There are, of course, other environmental issues to tackle with warehouses. Building materials and construction are responsible for about &lt;a href="https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/34572/GSR_ES.pdf?sequence=3&amp;amp;isAllowed=y"&gt;10 percent&lt;/a&gt; of global greenhouse gas emissions, so Liu says finding sustainable alternatives to materials like cement should be a priority this decade. What’s more, warehouses can be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22800410/black-friday-holiday-shopping-supply-chain-pollution-ports-warehouses-california"&gt;magnets for tailpipe pollution&lt;/a&gt; from diesel trucks — which can pose health threats to nearby neighborhoods. That only underscores the extra benefits turning to clean energy can have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kDmo6o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Satellite images show online shopping’s growing footprint ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21611862/satellite-images-online-shopping-growing-footprint-warehouses"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="nveQMH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon and Target play ‘outsized’ role in port congestion and pollution, report finds ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808388/amazon-target-port-congestion-pollution-maritime-shipping"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="v8lPXO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d23HoE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816131/warehouses-natural-gas-emissions-climate-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816131/warehouses-natural-gas-emissions-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T13:46:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T13:46:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook Messenger is getting a built-in bill splitting feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7vu6_71DkSn7mMgUKxYsr4lArrY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225139/acastro_180522_facebook_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lhLLC8"&gt;Facebook parent company Meta is introducing a &lt;a href="https://messengernews.fb.com/2021/12/03/close-out-the-year-with-messengers-new-expression-tools/"&gt;built-in bill splitting feature&lt;/a&gt; in Facebook Messenger that it will test with users in the US beginning next week. The feature could be useful for situations like divvying up a restaurant bill with your friends or splitting a bill with roommates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gf2zN6"&gt;With the feature, you can ask for money from people right in a group chat and see who has paid their portion of the request. You can see how it all works in a series of screenshots below from Meta. The feature arrives shortly after David Marcus, Meta’s cryptocurrency chief and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/9/5794548/david-marcus-leaves-paypal-to-lead-facebook-messaging"&gt;former Messenger lead&lt;/a&gt;, announced he would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22810220/facebook-crypto-david-marcus-novi-diem-meta"&gt;leaving the company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5FCgifFJor5OSLcdLmHdQf2WTrw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060856/Messenger_Split_Payment.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook Messenger’s upcoming bill splitting feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0rpZBS"&gt;Meta has also added new Group Effects, which let people on Messenger and Instagram video calls use &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22737991/facebook-messenger-group-calls-ar-effects-augmented-reality"&gt;the same augmented reality effects together&lt;/a&gt;, it has made with popular creators. Three are available now, including one that makes it look like your connection is buffering created with Zach King, and one from Emma Chamberlain arrives on December 6th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x98iFQ"&gt;Meta recently introduced new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578633/facebook-messenger-sound-emoji-soundmojis"&gt;“soundmoji”&lt;/a&gt; as well. Two are inspired by &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; (ahead of the new season &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/6/22765226/stranger-things-4-netflix-trailer-eleven-netflix-release-date"&gt;coming out next summer&lt;/a&gt;) and one that plays a clip from Taylor Swift’s “Red.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815981/facebook-messenger-bill-splitting-feature-meta-group-effects"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815981/facebook-messenger-bill-splitting-feature-meta-group-effects</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T13:38:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T13:38:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>NASA funds three companies to develop commercial space stations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DGb_5d8qwbn9neXjfnd4Dd0KZvM=/256x0:1635x919/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225086/cdff_awardee_3.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Northrop Grumman space station | Image: Northrop Grumman&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tsBh4d"&gt;NASA &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-selects-companies-to-develop-commercial-destinations-in-space"&gt;announced the selection&lt;/a&gt; of three US companies that will receive government funding to further&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;develop private space stations on Thursday. From a set of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HhrrzNiauZg"&gt;11 proposals&lt;/a&gt;, NASA selected Blue Origin, Nanoracks LLC, and Northrop Grumman to receive over $400 million in federal funds through three separate Space Act Agreements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9jQaCw"&gt;NASA &lt;a href="https://spacenews.com/nasa-seeks-proposals-for-commercial-space-station-development/"&gt;began seeking proposals&lt;/a&gt; in July for its Commercial Low Earth Orbit Development (CLD) program, which aims to support the development of commercial space stations. It is a part of a bigger plan to eventually replace the International Space Station (ISS) with commercial space stations. Through this model, NASA would be a customer of the commercial space industry, allowing it to save on costs and focus on basic research and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwdfrY"&gt;Blue Origin is set to receive $130 million to develop Orbital Reef, a free-flying space station concept the company first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744526/blue-origin-space-station-orbital-reef-announcement"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; in October. Orbital Reef is being developed in partnership with Sierra Space, maker of the winged spaceplane Dream Chaser. Blue Origin says the station&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will be operational by the second half of the decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mdTxZX"&gt;Nanoracks LLC is receiving $160 million for its Starlab station concept. Also announced in October, Starlab is a &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/"&gt;collaboration with&lt;/a&gt; Voyager Space and Lockheed Martin. Designed to hold up to four astronauts and conduct advanced research on biology, materials science and more, Starlab is targeted for launch in 2027 on a single flight, according to the NASA press release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SnsLhB"&gt;Northrop Grumman’s $125.6 million award will give it the opportunity to develop a commercial space station using existing technologies like its Cygnus spacecraft, which currently ferries cargo to the ISS. Northrop is working with Dynetics on its concept for a modular space station, with other partners to be announced in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SFxCTg"&gt;Axiom Space, a Houston company that was the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-selects-first-commercial-destination-module-for-international-space-station"&gt;first awarded&lt;/a&gt; funds in January 2020 to develop its commercial module to be added to the ISS, said &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Axiom_Space/status/1466504467113816065/photo/1"&gt;in a statement &lt;/a&gt;on Twitter that it did not bid to receive one of the CLD awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9d1Q4k"&gt;According to NASA, the awards are the first part of a two-phase approach to ensure a smooth transition to commercial stations in LEO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QGghu3"&gt;The first phase, expected to continue through 2025, will allow the grant recipients to create a plan and designs that meet both private sector and government needs. During the second phase, NASA wants to certify these stations for human astronauts to use and, ultimately, start using them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815695/nasa-space-act-award-recipients-commercial-space-development"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815695/nasa-space-act-award-recipients-commercial-space-development</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T13:08:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T13:08:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook took down a fake Swiss scientist account that was part of an international misinfo campaign</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="facebook stock art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V7uzEkVOjzTOwjK9H9FpjPV8FVw=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70224911/acastro_180928_1777_facebook_hack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Pi9PXp"&gt;Buried deep within Facebook’s November report on &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/November-2021-CIB-Report.pdf"&gt;Coordinated Inauthentic Behavior&lt;/a&gt; is a tale of international intrigue that seems more like a Netflix drama than an attempted disinformation campaign (although the way &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815541/netflix-thanksgiving-mom-viral-twitter-thread-feature-film"&gt;Netflix mines social media&lt;/a&gt; for ideas these days, maybe stay tuned). On July 24th, a Swiss biologist named Wilson Edwards claimed on Facebook and Twitter that the US was pressuring World Health Organization (WHO) scientists studying the origins of COVID-19. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qbV7TG"&gt;His claims spread quickly on social media, as such claims are wont to do, and within a week’s time, the &lt;em&gt;Global Times&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;People’s Daily&lt;/em&gt;, two state-run Chinese media outlets, were denouncing Wilson Edwards’ claims as “intimidation” by the US. Wilson Edwards created his Facebook account two days after &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2021/07/22/1019244601/china-who-coronavirus-lab-leak-theory?t=1633552763404"&gt;China refused to accept a plan&lt;/a&gt; by the WHO for a second phase study into the origins of the coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="id__nda7cd9rc3b"&gt;Have you guessed the plot twist yet? Turns out, according to the Swiss Embassy in Beijing, that there is no such Swiss citizen by the name Wilson Edwards. “If you exist, we would like to meet you! But it is more likely that this is a fake news, and we call on the Chinese press and netizens to take down the posts,”&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SwissEmbChina/status/1425042973289504770"&gt; the embassy tweeted&lt;/a&gt; from its official account on August 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0e1mGK"&gt;Facebook investigated and removed the Wilson Edwards account the same day the Swiss embassy tweeted. Ben Nimmo, global IO threat intel lead (excellent title for our drama) at Facebook parent company Meta, writes that the Wilson Edwards account was part of a misinformation campaign that originated in China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R1vtFyjn_XFgxbp6TglvnkpiTd0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060925/wilson_edwards.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faked profile picture of one of the fake accounts Meta says liked the post by “Wilson Edwards”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rmGT7e"&gt;“In essence, this campaign was a hall of mirrors, endlessly reflecting a single fake persona,” Nimmo says. Meta’s investigation found that nearly the entire initial spread of the Wilson Edwards story on Facebook was inauthentic: “the work of a multi-pronged, largely unsuccessful influence operation,” which brought together hundreds of fake accounts as well as some authentic accounts that belonged to employees of “Chinese state infrastructure companies across four continents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cqvOaw"&gt;Only a handful of real people engaged with Wilson Edwards, Meta says, despite the 524 Facebook accounts, 20 Facebook pages, four Facebook groups, and 86 Instagram accounts that the company has removed as part of its investigation. The scammers spent less than $5,000 on Facebook and Instagram ads as part of the campaign and used VPNs to conceal the accounts’ origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ToF13y"&gt;“This is consistent with what we’ve seen in our research of covert influence operations over the past four years: we haven’t seen successful IO campaigns built on fake engagement tactics,” Nimmo says. “Unlike elaborate fictitious personas that put work into building authentic communities to influence them, the content liked by these crude fake accounts would typically be only seen by their ‘fake friends.’” (And we all know what &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_txiRmH8NDY&amp;amp;ab_channel=FallOutBoy-Topic"&gt;happens to sham friends&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wTWjyk"&gt;The cluster of fake accounts that Meta connected to the Wilson Edwards scheme, along with some people associated with information security firm Silence in China, apparently has made (unsuccessfully, Meta says) other attempts at influence operations that were “typically small-scale and of negligible impact.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LGzWbD"&gt;It’s not the most exciting end to our story, but at least Wilson Edwards won’t try to catfish any other international health organizations. Now, if we could just get someone to rein in the tenacious people who keep &lt;a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/blog/2021/05/hang-auto-warranty-robocalls"&gt;calling about the car warranty&lt;/a&gt; I didn’t know I had... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YCae1L"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815906/facebook-meta-instagram-fake-swiss-scientist-account-china-misinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815906/facebook-meta-instagram-fake-swiss-scientist-account-china-misinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
