<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-01T10:36:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T10:36:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T10:36:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon acknowledges its Appstore is breaking on Android 12</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AoMc426aD7M_71OloY2DiWSIeBI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214687/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lg3d3V"&gt;Shortly after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22708720/android-12-review-features-pixel-update-software"&gt;Google rolled out the Android 12 update&lt;/a&gt; in October, users started noticing that they’re unable to use any of the apps in the Amazon Appstore, as reported by &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/30/amazon-appstore-is-broken-on-android-12/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Reports of the issue cropped up on the &lt;a href="https://www.amazonforum.com/s/question/0D56Q000087E2wvSAC/amazon-appstore-not-working-after-android-12-update"&gt;Amazon forum&lt;/a&gt; over a month ago, and there’s no timeline for a possible fix (via &lt;a href="https://liliputing.com/2021/11/android-12-launched-a-month-ago-and-amazon-appstore-still-wont-run-on-it.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liliputing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HP9zpX"&gt;“We are aware and working to resolve an issue impacting&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;app performance and launches for the small number of Amazon Appstore users that have upgraded to Android 12 on their mobile devices,” Amazon spokesperson Troy Edwards told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “This issue does not impact Amazon Fire Tablets or Fire TV devices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdfI7B"&gt;One user, Lovingboth, describes their experience with the issue in the thread on &lt;a href="https://www.amazonforum.com/s/question/0D56Q000087E2wvSAC/amazon-appstore-not-working-after-android-12-update"&gt;Amazon’s forum&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="NAMbmR"&gt;My rain radar app from the Amazon Appstore is still happily running and giving me alerts via notifications, but I can’t actually see them because it is being prevented from running full screen by the Amazon Appstore’s failure to run properly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Mvh230"&gt;Additionally, some users say no apps appear when they open the Amazon Appstore, while others cite receiving prompts to update their apps when no update is needed. An Amazon staff member also responded to complaints in the forum, noting that the “technical team is still investigating the issue,” but doesn’t offer much of an explanation of what went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SaBTLe"&gt;As pointed out by &lt;em&gt;Liliputing&lt;/em&gt;, the issue may stem from a lack of compatibility between Amazon’s built-in DRM and Android 12. One user on the Amazon forum, Eduardo S, highlights a workaround that points to DRM as the root of the issue. He notes that — for the technologically savvy — you can try downloading an app’s APK on another device that has an older version of Android. From there, you can decompile the app’s code, comment out lines referring to the DRM, repackage it with a self-signed certificate, and then install the APK on your Android 12 device. Easy, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LLMOuv"&gt;While the issue may be affecting only a “small” number of users now, that number will only continue to grow. Google first launched Android 12 on just Pixel devices, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782772/samsung-one-ui-4-android-12-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-release-date-features"&gt;Galaxy S21 users&lt;/a&gt; also received the update in mid-November. Samsung is planning to bring the update to more of its phones in the future and so are other device manufacturers, further complicating things for Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1sxzyS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0UskVv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wbJgnf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811710/amazon-android-12-appstore-drm-issues"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811710/amazon-android-12-appstore-drm-issues</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T10:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T10:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new always-on smartphone camera is a privacy nightmare</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lACklgffxG8nz2hmhVQIaneWy-g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214589/akrales_190819_3594_0298.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The front-facing camera on a Samsung smartphone. Next year’s Qualcomm processor will allow these cameras to always scan for your face, even when you’re not using the phone.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CytRJa"&gt;“Your phone’s front camera is always securely looking for your face, even if you don’t touch it or raise to wake it.” That’s how Qualcomm Technologies vice president of product management Judd Heape &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/3H6tfcZLHfg?t=10758"&gt;introduced the company’s new always-on camera capabilities&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809687/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-chip-smartphone-processor-specs-details"&gt;Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 processor&lt;/a&gt; set to arrive in top-shelf Android phones early next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5nmar7"&gt;Depending on who you are, that statement can either be exciting or terrifying. For Qualcomm, it thinks this new feature will enable new use cases, like being able to wake and unlock your phone without having to pick it up or have it instantly lock when it no longer sees your face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SzXm3P"&gt;But for those of us with any sense of how modern technology is used to violate our privacy, a camera on our phone that’s always recording images &lt;em&gt;even when we’re not using it&lt;/em&gt; sounds like the stuff of nightmares and has a cost to our privacy that far outweighs any potential convenience benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="TBcjBh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A camera that records your image even when you’re not using it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eyu2fQ"&gt;Qualcomm’s main pitch for this feature is for unlocking your phone any time you glance at it, even if it’s just sitting on a table or propped up on a stand. You don’t need to pick it up or tap the screen or say a voice command — it just unlocks when it sees your face. I can see this being useful if your hands are messy or otherwise occupied (in its presentation, Qualcomm used the example of using it while cooking a recipe to check the next steps). Maybe you’ve got your phone mounted in your car, and you can just glance over at it to see driving directions without having to take your hands off the steering wheel or leave the screen on the entire time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hrZO2W"&gt;The company is also spinning it as making your phone &lt;em&gt;more secure&lt;/em&gt; by automatically locking the phone when it no longer sees your face or detects someone looking over your shoulder and snooping on your group chat. It can also suppress private information or notifications from popping up if you’re looking at the phone with someone else. Basically, if you’re not looking at it, your phone is locked; if it can see you, it will be unlocked. If it can see you &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; someone else, it can automatically lock the phone or hide private information or notifications from displaying on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ngEJ0r"&gt;But while those features may sound neat and perhaps even convenient, I’m not convinced that having an always-on camera is worth the tradeoff in privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V6biDe"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3H6tfcZLHfg?rel=0&amp;amp;start=10758" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xrqwzE"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;The always-on camera features are discussed at hour three of Qualcomm’s four-hour presentation introducing the Snapdragon Gen 1 system-on-chip.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qwLEwb"&gt;Qualcomm is framing the always-on camera as similar to the always-on microphones that have been in our phones for years. Those are used to listen for voice commands like “Hey Siri” or “Hey Google” (or lol, “Hi Bixby”) and then wake up the phone and provide a response, all without you having to touch or pick up the phone. But the key difference is that they are listening for specific wake words and are often limited with what they can do until you do actually pick up your phone and unlock it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xePhtk"&gt;It feels a bit different when it’s a camera that’s always scanning for your likeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vTo21a"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An always-on camera is a step beyond the always-on microphones already in our phones&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wRk5tL"&gt;It’s true that smart home products already have features like this. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/9/20855944/google-nest-hub-max-review-assistant-smart-display-price-specs-features"&gt;Google’s Nest Hub Max&lt;/a&gt; uses its camera to recognize your face when you walk up to it and greet you with personal information like your calendar. Home security cameras and video doorbells are constantly on, looking for activity or even specific faces. But those devices are in your home, not always carried with you everywhere you go, and generally don’t have your most private information stored on them, like your phone does. They also frequently have features like physical shutters to block the camera or intelligent modes to disable recording when you’re home and only resume it when you aren’t. It’s hard to imagine any phone manufacturer putting a physical shutter on the front of their slim and sleek flagship smartphone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mgoU53"&gt;Lastly, there have been many reports of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22322122/verkada-hack-150000-security-cameras-tesla-factory-cloudflare-jails-hospitals"&gt;security breaches&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/18/21028092/amazon-ring-camera-hack-password-security-privacy-access-2fa"&gt;social engineering hacks&lt;/a&gt; to enable smart home cameras when they aren’t supposed to be on and then send that feed to remote servers, all without the knowledge of the homeowner. Modern smartphone operating systems now do a good job of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22634128/privacy-android-12-dashboard-apps-sensors"&gt;telling you when an app is accessing your camera or microphone&lt;/a&gt; while you’re using the device, but it’s not clear how they’d be able to inform you of a rogue app tapping into the always-on camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G3UlWw"&gt;Heape said that “always-on camera data never leaves the secure sensing hub while it’s looking for faces,” implying that the data isn’t sent to the cloud and that apps on the phone won’t be able to access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AjTYfM"&gt;Another Qualcomm Technologies vice president of product management Ziad Asghar told my colleague Chaim Gartenberg that users will also be able to disable the always-on camera feature or possibly even select which features they want to use and which they don’t. “The consumer has the choice to be able to pick and choose as to what is enabled and what’s not enabled,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TP4UtH0DVT_0Q539UAZ_GsuJDKM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16257180/vpavic_190510_3415_0161.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 7 Pro hid its entire camera system in a motorized pop-up module. Perhaps it’s time to bring this idea back.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SFe78n"&gt;It’s also possible that the smartphone manufacturers using the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 won’t even enable this feature at a hardware level. Since Qualcomm doesn’t actually make the smartphones its chips go in (outside of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22568641/qualcomm-asus-smartphone-snapdragon-insiders-technology"&gt;one-off novelties&lt;/a&gt; that aren’t widely purchased), companies like Samsung, OnePlus, and Xiaomi can customize which features are enabled on their phones and which aren’t. Some of those companies already bypass Qualcomm’s image processing components in favor of their own solutions — it’s not hard to see them just skipping the criticisms of privacy concerns and forgoing this feature as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="0jhcqA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An unsettling and uncomfortable precedent&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UPTiXp"&gt;But even if it’s not found in every phone next year, the mere presence of the feature means that it will be used by someone at some point. It sets a precedent that is unsettling and uncomfortable; Qualcomm may be the first with this capability, but it won’t be long before other companies add it in the race to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lugMRK"&gt;Maybe we’ll just start having to put tape on our smartphone cameras like we already do with laptop webcams.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22811740/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-always-on-camera-privacy-security-concerns"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22811740/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-always-on-camera-privacy-security-concerns</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T10:05:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T10:05:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung refreshes two budget A-series phones with 5G and higher prices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy A13" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fMVe7Us2BfT5wo5TScRlxJDJnaU=/120x0:4620x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214532/GalaxyA13_5G_Green_Lockup_RGB_copy.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy A13 will be an AT&amp;amp;T exclusive starting December 3rd, 2021, before being available on T-Mobile and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="http://Samsung.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; in early 2022.&lt;/em&gt; | Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ArTaVC"&gt;With 2022 and CES just around the corner, Samsung is ready to introduce new updates to its popular and budget-friendly A-series, which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749880/samsung-q3-2021-earnings-record-revenue-memory-mobile"&gt;helped keep sales strong&lt;/a&gt; for the Korean company despite supply woes for the flagship Galaxy S21. This time around, both the Galaxy A13 5G and A03S are getting a bit more expensive while confirming some new hardware and 5G connectivity for the A13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r26Tc7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung Galaxy A13 5G&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pC9P83"&gt;Unlike the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21628573/samsung-a12-a02s-phones-budget-price-specs-2021"&gt;4G-only Galaxy A12&lt;/a&gt;, the new A13 will be able to access 5G networks, specifically, with the sub-6GHz bands available on T-Mobile and AT&amp;amp;T. The A13’s 5G readiness partly explains its new $249.99 price. That’s a whopping $70 increase from its $179.99 predecessor and slightly cheaper than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529760/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-review-price-screen-specs"&gt;$279.99 Galaxy A32 5G&lt;/a&gt; with similar specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PE9zXH"&gt;Its higher price makes it possible to bring some premium features to the A13, as the relatively low-resolution 6.5-inch Infinity-V HD Plus display will feel smoother with its 90Hz adaptive refresh rate. This is up from the standard 60Hz of the A12 and keeps pace with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547482/oneplus-nord-n200-5g-review-screen-price-specs"&gt;$239.99 OnePlus Nord N200 5G&lt;/a&gt; that offers a 1080p display with 90Hz refresh. Thanks to its more up-to-date MediaTek Dimensity 700 processor, the A13 is better equipped to multitask and handle various mobile games than the &lt;a href="https://nanoreview.net/en/soc-compare/mediatek-helio-p35-vs-mediatek-dimensity-700"&gt;A12, which shipped last year with a chipset from 2018&lt;/a&gt;. The A13 also promises an updated triple-camera system with a 50-megapixel main camera, plus a macro and a depth sensor for bokeh effects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy A13 5G’s side fingerprint sensor" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yKa0PfMZkzh5p2eF9xR6aNNf5MQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055054/GalaxyA13_5G_Black_RSide_RGB.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy A13 5G features a fingerprint sensor embedded into its power button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wxgMx2"&gt;It’s a bit disappointing that the A13 will only have 64GB of internal memory — yes, its microSD slot will support up to a 1TB card — and Samsung has not specified how much RAM this model has (the A12 had 3GB RAM). That said, you’ll be able to plug wired headphones into its 3.5mm audio jack, make contactless payments via NFC, enjoy a 5,000mAh battery, and use the side fingerprint sensor to unlock your phone (there is no face unlock option). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y3iXvD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung Galaxy A03S&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fP8FvF"&gt;Samsung is not revealing nearly as many details about the upcoming Galaxy A03S, only confirming that the A03S will cost $159.99 when it ships in 2022, while the base A02S debuted at just $109.99 last year. With scant details about the A03S’s new hardware to justify this $50 price increase, the press release hints that it’ll have “a long-lasting battery, triple camera system, and fingerprint security.” You can probably expect an updated processor from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21628573/samsung-a12-a02s-phones-budget-price-specs-2021"&gt;A02S&lt;/a&gt;, and perhaps 32GB of storage in the base model, but you’ll have to wait for CES or a potential Samsung Unpacked event to find out more, including what it looks like because we don’t have pictures of it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HWXuoD"&gt;Both phones will ship with Android 11, but it’s unclear whether they will receive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;four years of regular security updates&lt;/a&gt; like Samsung has guaranteed for some A-series phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E3zlTZ"&gt;The new A13 5G will be an AT&amp;amp;T online exclusive starting on December 3rd, 2021, with T-Mobile and Samsung.com following suit in early January 2022. If you prefer the ultra-budget A03S, you’ll need to wait until early January 2022, when it’ll be available on AT&amp;amp;T, T-Mobile, Verizon, and Samsung.com. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3KejH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810665/samsung-galaxy-a13-5g-a03s-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810665/samsung-galaxy-a13-5g-a03s-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s new Big Brain Academy turns brainteasers into a party game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gz8_0oKAuS8S25DaLKU8ZQTOdII=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214182/Switch_BBABvB_Reveal_TRL_SCRN_02_bmp_jpgcopy.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eLmz1d"&gt;2021 is shaping up to be the year of party games on the Switch. This year, Nintendo has released new entries in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22632465/warioware-get-it-together-nintendo-switch-preview"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WarioWare&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22749548/mario-party-superstars-nintendo-switch-oled-kickstand"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Party&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; franchises, and now it’s completing the party trilogy with &lt;em&gt;Big Brain Academy: Brain vs. Brain&lt;/em&gt;. It’s the continuation of a series that started with &lt;em&gt;Brain Age&lt;/em&gt; on the Nintendo DS, which, alongside the likes of &lt;em&gt;Wii Sports &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Wii Fit&lt;/em&gt;, helped solidify the company’s “blue ocean” strategy of reaching a nontraditional gaming audience. Each “Brain” game is exactly what it sounds like: a collection of digital brainteasers. The twist in the latest is that its focus is almost exclusively on multiplayer play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aEB1ZI"&gt;At its most basic, &lt;em&gt;Big Brain Academy&lt;/em&gt; is a mini-game collection where each of the games is divided into five different categories: identify, memorize, analyze, compute, and visualize. The idea is that the games all test different parts of your brain. One mini-game involves popping numbered balloons in the correct order, while another has you choosing the right shapes to complete an image. There’s a pretty basic single-player mode where you can practice each of the mini-games, complete a “test” that involves each of the five categories, or compete against the ghosts of either friends or players online. Doing well earns you high scores and new looks for your avatar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QiZVTI"&gt;It’s nothing like, say, a classic &lt;em&gt;Brain Age&lt;/em&gt; with a structure that encourages you to come back and keep improving. (Though the game does rate the weight of your brain after tests.) Instead, the single-player feels more like a warmup for the party mode, where up to four players can compete. This mode works well for a few reasons. To start, the games are pretty simple but with a nice progression, so they work well for a timed competition where you’re trying to solve problems as quickly as possible. It can get surprisingly intense when all the players in a room are trying to be the first to identify a slowly unraveling photo of a zebra.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kc2nMMmH08bvDb9BnFmA9xO32ns=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23053914/Switch_BBABvB_Reveal_TRL_SCRN_02_bmp_jpgcopy.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ey9zrt"&gt;The thing that sets &lt;em&gt;Brain vs. Brain&lt;/em&gt; apart from the Switch’s other party games, aside from its less zany mini-games, is just how adjustable the difficulty is. It’s really something you can play with the whole family. When you start up a multiplayer match, each player gets to choose their own difficulty level, making it possible to balance the experience for people of different ages. I spent an afternoon playing with a six- and eight-year-old, and each of us was playing on a completely different difficulty level. When we play &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart&lt;/em&gt;, for instance, I’m usually forced to turn the speed down all the way, which is fun for the kids but boring for me. But in &lt;em&gt;Brain vs. Brain&lt;/em&gt;, you can fine-tune the experience to each player so that they can both compete against each other &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; challenge themselves. It’s a nice change of pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6datqr"&gt;I should also note that this is the rare Switch game that I actually prefer playing with a touchscreen. It’s just a lot faster in most games to tap the correct answer than move a cursor around. Unfortunately this isn’t really possible if you have a bunch of people playing, but there is a single-Switch touchscreen mode that works really well for two players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B3twx9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brain vs. Brain &lt;/em&gt;isn’t revolutionary by any stretch, but it does open up the possibilities for who can play together, which is an important change from its contemporaries. It’s also not the kind of game I see myself playing solo all that often. Instead, it’s more like a board game that I’ll stick on the shelf and pull out when everyone gets together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTw54l"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Big Brain Academy: Brain vs. Brain&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; launches December 3rd on the Nintendo Switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810735/big-brain-academy-brain-vs-brain-review-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810735/big-brain-academy-brain-vs-brain-review-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Big tech’s first generation of founders starts to step aside</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Jeff Bezos’s India Visit Marked By Probe and Protests" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V_R7fyPRCD47GK1go_CdRw566v4=/0x0:2138x1425/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214184/1193819818.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JC8jKS"&gt;Massive tech companies like Google, Amazon, Netflix, and more have had a huge impact on the way we live our lives, and have had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22770569/alphabet-google-market-cap-hits-2-trillion"&gt;incredible levels&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://companiesmarketcap.com/"&gt;financial success&lt;/a&gt;. Another thing many of these companies have in common is that their founders are no longer necessarily in control; they’ve either stepped down, started sharing power with others, or in some cases possibly even been pushed out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6hAI6N"&gt;This week alone, Twitter co-founder &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22807651/jack-dorsey-steps-down-twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-replacement"&gt;Jack Dorsey stepped down as CEO&lt;/a&gt;, and Salesforce founder Marc Benioff &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/30/salesforce-promotes-bret-taylor-to-co-ceo.html"&gt;became a &lt;em&gt;co&lt;/em&gt;-CEO&lt;/a&gt;. They’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="EujqeX"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amazon &lt;/strong&gt;— In July 2021, Jeff Bezos officially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22563671/andy-jassy-amazon-ceo-jeff-bezos"&gt;handed the CEO position of Amazon over&lt;/a&gt; to former Amazon Web Services head Andy Jassy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LI0HDf"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Apple &lt;/strong&gt;— Tim Cook was &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2009/01/14Apple-Media-Advisory/"&gt;temporarily left in charge of Apple&lt;/a&gt; in 2009 while Steve Jobs underwent medical treatment. Jobs returned to the company, but then put Cook in charge for another leave of absence in 2011, before permanently making him CEO later that year. Around the time of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22639629/tim-cook-apple-ten-years-decade-steve-jobs-legacy"&gt;his 10-year anniversary as CEO of Apple&lt;/a&gt; in 2021, Tim Cook said he doesn’t intend to run the company for another decade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="03YCHp"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ByteDance — &lt;/strong&gt;Zhang Yiming, founder of the company that owns TikTok, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445212/tiktok-bytedance-ceo-zhang-yiming-steps-down"&gt;announced he’d be stepping down as CEO&lt;/a&gt; this May. In an internal letter, he said he worried about “relying too much on the ideas I had before starting the company.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nPcfNv"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt; — In August 2015, Google co-founders Larry Page and Sergey Brin &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/4/20994361/google-alphabet-larry-page-sergey-brin-sundar-pichai-co-founders-ceo-timeline"&gt;moved on to overseeing Alphabet&lt;/a&gt;, the holding company for Google’s disparate properties. The shakeup was seen as them taking their hands off the search engine company, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/10/9128083/sundar-pichai-ceo-google-larry-page-sergey-brin"&gt;leaving Sundar Pichai in charge&lt;/a&gt;, and in 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/3/20994218/google-alphabet-ceo-sundar-pichai-larry-page-sergey-brin-step-down-control-management"&gt;Pichai took over as CEO of Alphabet as well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="geIrqO"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Instagram &lt;/strong&gt;— In September 2018, Instagram’s co-founders Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger announced they were stepping down, reportedly after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2019/4/17/18411363/why-instagram-founders-quit-hamburger-button-location-tracking"&gt;major disagreements with Facebook and Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8zbaph"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft &lt;/strong&gt;— Microsoft founder Bill Gates’ departure happened in many stages, with him first stepping down as CEO in 2000, then leaving his full time position at the company he helped found in 2008, and finally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/13/21179214/bill-gates-steps-down-microsoft-board-philanthropy"&gt;stepping down from his position on the board last year&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft is currently being run by Satya Nadella, who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22537683/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-chairman-bill-gates-john-thompson"&gt;acts as both CEO and chairman of the board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="boWSkR"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Netflix&lt;/strong&gt; — In July 2020, Ted Sarandos &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21327550/netflix-ted-sarandos-ceo-netflix-reed-hastings-board-member-originals-tv-movies"&gt;joined Netflix co-founder Reed Hastings as co-CEO&lt;/a&gt;. The company said that Sarandos was already helping lead (he’d been &lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/02/03/outside-the-box-2"&gt;with the company for twenty years&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/co-ceos-are-out-of-style-why-is-netflix-resurrecting-the-management-model-11594987416"&gt;was in charge of its original programming&lt;/a&gt;), and that him joining Hastings as CEO was just a formalization of his role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sw7urw"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Salesforce&lt;/strong&gt; — Bret Taylor, who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22807651/jack-dorsey-steps-down-twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-replacement"&gt;replaced Jack Dorsey&lt;/a&gt; as Twitter’s chairman of the board on Monday, is also becoming the co-CEO of enterprise tech giant Salesforce, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/30/salesforce-promotes-bret-taylor-to-co-ceo.html"&gt;according to CNBC&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not the first time Marc Benioff, the company’s CEO and founder, will be sharing power, but it’s another instance of a former deputy starting to gain more power within a tech giant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UUkvbR"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Twitter &lt;/strong&gt;— On Monday, November 29th, Jack Dorsey &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22807651/jack-dorsey-steps-down-twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-replacement"&gt;announced he was leaving Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and said “I’ve decided to leave Twitter because I believe the company is ready to move on from its founders.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="NzRxzQ"&gt;There are, of course, exceptions to the trend. The most notable is Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg’s complete control over Meta. He &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22749919/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-meta-company-rebrand"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in October&lt;/a&gt; that he doesn’t have plans to give up his job, and it’d be pretty much impossible for shareholders to force him out, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/27/opinion/tech-dual-class-stock.html"&gt;thanks to the company’s stock structure&lt;/a&gt;. Aside from Zuckerberg, a couple other CEOs come to mind: Jensen Huang is still in charge of Nvidia (until it &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/nvidia-faked-part-of-a-press-conference-with-a-cgi-ceo/"&gt;replaces him with a digital AI avatar&lt;/a&gt;), and Snapchat is still helmed by Evan Spiegel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F94x1X"&gt;Obviously, tech companies can survive and thrive without their founders — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753251/microsoft-apple-market-cap-business-valuable-company"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/19/21375223/apple-2-trillion-market-cap-first-us-company-stock-price"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; are the two most valuable public companies in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EA086j"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810769/big-tech-founders-stepping-down-trend-salesforce-tiktok-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810769/big-tech-founders-stepping-down-trend-salesforce-tiktok-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T08:48:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T08:48:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Apple Watch Series 6 is still available for $100 off at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="There’s a new “artist” watch face" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pwo-krebX5FSpEg-K5CpOf96Zls=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214134/vpavic_200929_4216_0121.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&amp;nbsp;last-gen Apple Watch&amp;nbsp;Series&amp;nbsp;6 is just $299 at Best Buy.&lt;/em&gt; | Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oBXrF4"&gt;Cyber Monday may be over, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22560704"&gt;Cyber Week continues&lt;/a&gt;. If at any point this past weekend you missed out on an Apple Watch deal you were keeping tabs on, fret not, you can still pick up the 40mm, GPS version of the Apple Watch Series 6 for just $299 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6P6nRg8YX?u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com%2Fgood-deals%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a $100 discount on the otherwise $399 wearable, which offers built-in sleep tracking, a blood oxygen sensor, and an always-on display. It’s a more affordable alternative to Apple’s new Series 7, with features you won’t find in the similarly priced Apple Watch SE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n6eNhN"&gt;For new subscribers, Best Buy’s also throwing in six months free of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22299628/apple-fitness-plus-review-price-classes-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Fitness Plus&lt;/a&gt;, an exercise service that integrates nicely with the Apple Watch and offers fitness classes. Note, however, this deal is only available on the watch sporting a blue aluminum case with a deep navy sport band. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4bGXYc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10869070"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5Ubcln"&gt;If you’re looking for a good holiday gift for the gamer in your life, the PlayStation Store is currently discounting several PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 digital titles by up to 80 percent as a part of its &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/category/e5204033-886e-42f1-a51c-641b8f051988/1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“End of the Year” sale&lt;/a&gt;. PS4 owners can, for example, pick up a digital copy of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512337/mortal-kombat-11-ps4-xbox-switch-ed-boon-interview" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat 11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for just &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1018-PPSA01617_00-00MORTALKOMBAT11" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$10&lt;/a&gt; ($40 off) or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/4/17817392/spider-man-marvel-ps4-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel’s Spider-Man: Game of the Year Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;for &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP9000-CUSA02299_00-MARVELSSMGOTY000" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$20&lt;/a&gt; ($20 off). Both PS4 and PS5 owners can also enjoy 60 percent off of the $80 Deluxe or $100 Gold editions of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/12/21319059/assassins-creed-valhalla-hands-on-preview-pc-xbox-one-ps4-gameplay-ubisoft-rpg" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Valhalla&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which are on sale for &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0001-PPSA01491_00-EDITIONDELUXE000" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$32&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0001-PPSA01491_00-EDITIONGOLD00000" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$40&lt;/a&gt;, respectively. The sale will last through December 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="e3HeC6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10325914"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ZtpQJM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10894786"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ww8097"&gt;For gamers who are on the market for Nintendo Switch titles, Best Buy also &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6UqhIxGzh" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;has a great sale going on&lt;/a&gt;. Right now, you can buy two games from a small selection of popular titles and get the third game of equal or lesser value for free. The bundle also applies to some games that are already on sale, which could translate to even greater savings. Current standouts include physical versions of &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6UojaxBHm" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60), as well as &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6XpzmpvQv" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario Odyssey Standard Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($38) and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6UpIJQOQV" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong Country: Tropical Freeze&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45). Just hit “Build my package” at the top of the screen to customize the promo to your liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4zc4rU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10894882"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="JevUJd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild review","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/2/14787082/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-review"},{"title":"Super Mario Odyssey review: an absolute delight","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/26/16552118/super-mario-odyssey-review-nintendo-switch"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OnEuOk"&gt;We saw a lot of great deals on wireless earbuds this past week, though, sadly, many of them have already expired. Thankfully, &lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-13142092?sid=VergeDailyDeals113021B&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fsamsung-galaxy-buds2-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot&lt;/a&gt; is selling Samsung’s Galaxy Buds 2 — the most recent addition to Samsung’s Galaxy Buds lineup — for just $100 in various styles through December 3rd or while supplies last. That matches the lowest price we saw on the earbuds during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, but it’s worth noting that these have a 90-day Woot warranty, not the full one-year warranty against manufacturer defects from Samsung. If you’d rather have that longer coverage, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf7eCx2C2YN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Wireless-Cancelling-Bluetooth-Lightweight/dp/B0942DM32W/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; have them for just $10 more, totaling $110.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2l43za"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In our review&lt;/a&gt;, we noted that these lightweight, entry-level earbuds offer active noise cancellation, wireless charging, and a small, low-profile design. They also showcase good audio quality, making them an easy pick for many Android users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hpDz1I"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10707231"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7KD7Xp"&gt;If you managed to score a great deal on an iPad this week, why not make using it even more fun with some great discounted accessories? Apple’s Smart Keyboard Folio makes it easier to use your iPad Pro or iPad Air more like a traditional laptop, and right now it’s selling for its lowest price to date. Typically $179, the basic accessory is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08635GZ8H?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently going for $99&lt;/a&gt;. Note that the case is only compatible with the first, second, and third generations of the 11-inch iPad Pro, as well as the fourth-generation iPad Air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YqSeOV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10459883"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EdNQFR"&gt;But wait! There’s more! Here are some other notable deals happening:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="K4yb26"&gt;The $50 Chromecast with Google TV streaming device is currently selling for $40 at the &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/config/chromecast_google_tv?hl=en-US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google Store&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F482924%2F1185236%2F9383%3FsubId1%3DVergeBlackFridayDealsStillHappening112721%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FChromecast-with-Google-TV-Streaming-Entertainment-in-4K-HDR-Snow%2F403830906%26veh%3Daff%26subId2%3D%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6Ykbo6GBZ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to offering support for Dolby Atmos and Dolby Vision, it can cast media from your phone via the Chromecast app. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21495609/google-chromecast-2020-review-streaming-remote-control" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mLfPn1"&gt;The Bose QuietComfort 45 headphones offer best-in-class comfort and terrific active noise cancellation. Right now they’re available for their best price to date, selling for $279 instead of $329 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B098FKXT8L/?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=94&amp;amp;imprToken=4cbeb974-fe6d-c120-db4&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6YkPFiFER" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FBose-QuietComfort-45-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-Headphones-Black%2F376188834" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22698629/bose-quietcomfort-qc-45-headphones-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="waAahU"&gt;Typically $450, the Google Pixel 5A is currently &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/product/pixel_5a_5g?hl=en-US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$400 at the Google Store&lt;/a&gt;. As we noted in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22628205/google-pixel-5a-review-price-screen-battery-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, the 5G-compatible Pixel 5A features one of the best cameras available in a midrange smartphone, while boasting 128GB of onboard storage and IP67 water resistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9TlG97"&gt;The Yeedi K650 is a great, budget-friendly robot vacuum that is currently &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Yeedi-XXL-Size-Compatible-Boundary-Self-Charging/dp/B08BJ315DM/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale for $120&lt;/a&gt; instead of $180 when you clip the coupon on the page. While it doesn’t offer lidar or virtual boundaries, it can handle the basics well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vBQA64"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf6X5USrQtA" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Echo-Dot/dp/B07FZ8S74R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; are selling Amazon’s third-gen Echo Dot for just $20, down from $40, a great deal on a still good speaker to control your smart home. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/12/17965806/amazon-echo-dot-3rd-gen-review-alexa-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jwej4P"&gt;For a limited time, both &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22560704%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/good-deals%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.gamestop.com/search/?pmid=27758" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/promotion/psp/A24B03B7FGGMRG" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon will take $10 off&lt;/a&gt; when you spend a minimum of $100 on select gaming products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hbbNpd"&gt;Until December 4th, RavPower is taking 35 percent off several chargers, like this &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.ravpower.com/products/rp-pc150-2-pack-20w-usb-c-pd-wall-charger?variant=33008876912715&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/22796663/cyber-monday-2021-best-deals-still-available-laptops-phones-tvs-headphones-gaming&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__p_22560704__t_w__r_theverge.com/good-deals_" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ravpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frp-pc150-2-pack-20w-usb-c-pd-wall-charger%3Fvariant%3D33008876912715&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22809884%2Fapple-watch-6-ps5-ps4-switch-games-galaxy-buds-2-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;28 two-pack of 20W iPhone 13 chargers, which you can buy for just $13&lt;/a&gt; when you use promo code &lt;strong&gt;RT50.&lt;/strong&gt; Alternatively, you can pick up &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ravpower.com%2Fproducts%2Frp-pb232-90w-2-port-pd-3-0-qc-3-0-power-bank%3Fvariant%3D39402579558475&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22809884%2Fapple-watch-6-ps5-ps4-switch-games-galaxy-buds-2-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this 90W battery bank for $58 instead of $89&lt;/a&gt; using promo code &lt;strong&gt;CM35&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="56xmvV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/1/22809884/apple-watch-6-ps5-ps4-switch-games-galaxy-buds-2-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/1/22809884/apple-watch-6-ps5-ps4-switch-games-galaxy-buds-2-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T08:11:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T08:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>California is getting its first real autonomous delivery service thanks to Nuro and 7-Eleven</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hlBPA6Yzuz_R0-w9gYFKgnA2BqI=/6x0:5787x3854/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70214032/Nuro_7_11_partnership_image2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4xkfw4"&gt;Nuro, a leader in autonomous delivery vehicles, is kicking off a new service in California in partnership with 7-Eleven. The company will deliver convenience store products to customers in its autonomous Toyota Prius vehicles, which will include a safety driver behind the wheel, before eventually shifting over to its fully driverless R2 delivery vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="COGQT9"&gt;The service will only be available to residents who live in proximity to the 7-Eleven store at 1905 Latham Street in Mountain View, from 8AM–9PM, seven days a week. Customers can order items like pizza, chips, beverages, and household items through 7-Eleven’s “7NOW” delivery app, although age-restricted items, like alcohol and cigarettes, won’t be available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vu4PI0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Orders will be delivered in 30 minutes or less&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AsqGdW"&gt;Orders will be delivered in 30 minutes or less, and customers will have to leave their home to retrieve the items from the delivery vehicle while it’s parked on the street. (The Nuro safety driver will not bring the items to the door, as the company is aiming to simulate a completely human-free delivery process.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ar9UJJ"&gt;Nuro wouldn’t disclose the number of vehicles it will deploy as part of this early version of its service, nor would it say how soon it plans to shift deliveries to its R2 robots. “Nuro and 7-Eleven will make the joint decision to introduce R2 into the delivery fleet as soon as possible,” a spokesperson said. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h46lj46MwinFL6_Xdkr_9gKkyWY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23054133/Nuro_7_11_partnership_image1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4tOVto"&gt;Nuro, which is valued at $5 billion, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16936548/nuro-self-driving-delivery-last-mile-google"&gt;was founded in 2016 by Dave Ferguson and Jiajun Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, two veterans of the Google self-driving car project that would go on to become Waymo. Nuro is one of the few US companies to be operating fully driverless vehicles — that is, vehicles without safety drivers behind the wheel — on public roads today. Its R2 vehicle is about half as wide as a compact sedan, shorter than most cars, and there’s no room inside for human passengers or drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="s9UbAC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Its R2 vehicle is about half as wide as a compact sedan&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lO7kn9"&gt;The R2 is an updated version of Nuro’s original R1 prototype, with around 50 percent more capacity (which translates into about 18 more grocery bags). The company plans on producing a third-generation vehicle at its new facility in Nevada once it is fully operational in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2bKno"&gt;The company is relatively unknown compared to its rivals in the autonomous vehicle space, mostly because of its focus on delivery and not ferrying human passengers in robotaxis. Still, Nuro has made progress on the regulatory front, becoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/6/21125358/nuro-self-driving-delivery-robot-r2-fmvss-exemption"&gt;the first company to receive a special exemption from certain federal safety requirements&lt;/a&gt; and recently getting the green light to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197980/nuro-licensed-autonomous-deliveries-california"&gt;charge money for its deliveries in California&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9s6If6"&gt;Nuro vehicles are already being used for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/14/18265397/nuro-robot-delivery-houston-texas-kroger"&gt;grocery deliveries&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379853/nuro-self-driving-robot-delivery-dominos-pizza-houston"&gt;pizza&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/28/21272966/nuro-cvs-autonomous-medicine-delivery-robot-houston"&gt;deliveries from CVS Pharmacy&lt;/a&gt; stores in Houston, Texas. In 2020, Nuro used its vehicles to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21231466/nuro-delivery-robot-health-care-workers-food-supplies-california"&gt;transport medical supplies around two California stadiums&lt;/a&gt; that were converted into treatment facilities for patients with COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810674/nuro-7-eleven-autonomous-vehicle-delivery-california"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22810674/nuro-7-eleven-autonomous-vehicle-delivery-california</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T07:21:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T07:21:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s new ‘Party Worlds’ put the focus firmly on socializing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V6ayrhANsdLmUVT54BLfFAzZrF8=/0x0:1618x1079/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70213870/fortnite_creative_walnut_world_by_fivewalnut_1920x1080_f43bf22cda3c.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Walnut World is one of the two debut Party Worlds.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Epic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Ucv83"&gt;“Party Worlds” are new spaces coming to &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; which are designed to focus on socializing over combat, the game’s developer &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/introducing-fortnite-party-worlds"&gt;Epic Games has announced&lt;/a&gt;. “These are experiences that are designed as places for players to hang out, play fun mini-games, and make new friends,” the developer says, adding that Party Worlds cannot be centered on “combat or damage.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ile7me"&gt;To kick off the initiative, Epic has collaborated with community members fivewalnut and TreyJTH on a pair of example Party Worlds. One is an amusement park called Walnut World, and the second is called Late Night Lounge and has more of a nightclub vibe. The developer says it’s taking submissions for more community-made spaces. Just use the tag “Party World” for an island, and submit it through &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/creative/submit-island"&gt;this submission form&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HF1E7z0y3cbPFe5UsUEpnSi6Ygo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055139/fortnite_creative_late_night_lounge_by_treyjth_1920x1080_2fc0f4dd2a28.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Epic Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s a second Party World called ‘Late Night Lounge.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GIfsbz"&gt;Party Worlds are Epic’s latest attempt to transform &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; from a competitive online game into a broader online social space. This has already resulted in numerous features ranging from one-off events like an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21233637/travis-scott-fortnite-concert-astronomical-live-report"&gt;in-game concert from Travis Scott&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21241414/fortnite-party-royale-ltm-mode"&gt;combat-free Party Royale mode&lt;/a&gt;. Users can also already create islands to serve as social spaces rather than arenas using the game’s &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/help/th/fortnite-c75/creative-c96/what-is-creative-mode-in-fortnite-how-does-it-work-a3428"&gt;Creative mode&lt;/a&gt;. But with its latest initiative, Epic appears to be explicitly promoting and encouraging users to make these social-first spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KWZRTz"&gt;Party Worlds also don’t link out to other islands, so they’re meant as a destination rather than a “discovery tool.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pFVwia"&gt;And yes, this all ties in to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417697/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-1"&gt;Epic’s plans to create a so-called “metaverse,”&lt;/a&gt; a fully integrated 3D online space for people to exist in. Epic is now far from the only company explicitly targeting this future (see also: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;Meta&lt;/a&gt;), but the maturity of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s technology, not to mention the game’s enduring popularity, mean Epic’s ambitions deserve to be taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4LGssT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QInAut"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811673/fortnite-party-worlds-islands-metaverse-social-space"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811673/fortnite-party-worlds-islands-metaverse-social-space</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T07:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nothing’s debut earbuds now come in black</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EYEoYOebik4SywnYml22NOK-fMk=/0x0:7695x5130/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70213816/Nothing__1__black_edition_closed_case.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ear 1 earbuds and case, now in black.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nothing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OJRzMS"&gt;Nothing’s Ear 1 earbuds, which launched earlier this year in a fetching white and transparent plastic color scheme, will soon come in black. The new Nothing Ear 1 black edition still features transparent plastic in its construction, but now it’s accompanied by matte black plastic. The new color scheme will be widely available from December 13th at the same price as the original white versions: $99 / £99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S787BT"&gt;Aside from the new design, these earbuds are functionally identical to what Nothing released earlier this year. You still get up to 5.7 hours of battery life from the earbuds with noise canceling turned off, dropping to four hours if you turn it on. Alongside the case, you get a maximum of 34 hours. The earbuds are also IPX4 water resistant and can be charged wirelessly using Qi.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HJacn-BBp2zk5sxSgV_0ByVlPsE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23042764/ear1_smoke_still_G_F_001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nothing&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A close-up of the earbuds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="njiWfP"&gt;The company is styling the new color as a “limited edition” but added that it hopes it’ll become “a permanent addition to its range.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IGOB1d"&gt;Nothing also claims that its Ear 1 earbuds are now carbon neutral, and that it’s worked with third-party certification company &lt;a href="https://www.sgs.com/"&gt;SGS&lt;/a&gt; to help assess and neutralize its carbon footprint. But the company is also accepting payment for them in cryptocurrencies, whose payment networks are notoriously energy-intensive to run. The Bitcoin network alone is estimated to use about the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/09/03/climate/bitcoin-carbon-footprint-electricity.html"&gt;same amount of electricity annually as Washington state&lt;/a&gt;, and anywhere from 25 to 60 percent of this reportedly comes from nonrenewable sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n5YO1I"&gt;When I asked Nothing about this apparent contradiction, it pointed me toward the &lt;a href="https://cryptoclimate.org/"&gt;Crypto Climate Accord&lt;/a&gt;, an effort to make the crypto industry produce net-zero emissions in nine years’ time in 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o0PZNf"&gt;If you’d like to buy Nothing’s “carbon neutral” earbuds with cryptocurrency, the company will accept Bitcoin (BTC), Ethereum (ETH), USD Coin (USDC), and Dogecoin (DOGE) for purchases made via its own online store in select countries including the US, UK, Canada, and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dX2IqG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22802107/nothing-ear-1-black-edition-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22802107/nothing-ear-1-black-edition-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Polaris’ new Ranger XP Kinetic is an all-electric side-by-side with a lot of horsepower</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7z5BRyLGLWJGXmqtCLu_JZ_hEjc=/0x1:2000x1334/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70213690/2023_ranger_xp_kinetic_icy_blue_pearl_image_riding_SIX6631_04983.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="61yhyN"&gt;Polaris has unveiled the Ranger XP Kinetic, an all-electric side-by-side and the first vehicle to emerge from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21473587/polaris-zero-motorcycles-electric-ev-off-road-vehicle-snowmobiles"&gt;collaboration between the Minneapolis-based company and Zero Motorcycles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Rtq0H"&gt;Polaris is hoping the electric Ranger will help attract new customers to the world of power sports vehicles, which also include ATVs, snowmobiles, personal watercraft, and heavy motorcycles. The segment, which currently represents over $9 billion in sales globally, is expected to grow to over $12 billion by 2027, &lt;a href="https://www.fortunebusinessinsights.com/powersports-market-105156"&gt;according to market researchers&lt;/a&gt;. And Polaris, through its partnership with Zero Motorcycles, is hoping to expand its lineup of electric vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LX4www"&gt;&lt;q&gt;two trim levels, Premium and Ultimate, priced at $24,999 and $29,999&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ts9FAx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22302725/polaris-electric-ranger-utv-zero-teaser"&gt;The first will be the electric Ranger&lt;/a&gt;, which comes in two trim levels, Premium and Ultimate, priced at $24,999 and $29,999, respectively. Packing 110 horsepower and 140 pound-feet of torque, Polaris claims the Ranger XP Kinetic will be the most powerful utility side-by-side it’s ever produced. That represents 35 percent more power and two times more torque than any other utility side-by-side on the market, Polaris says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZJALn7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10895027"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1hfubF"&gt;Unlike ATVs, which are recognizable for their straddle-seated position and handlebar steering, UTVs are used more for work than recreation. The large, powerful vehicles are commonly used to haul equipment and supplies in locations that make using a truck impractical or impossible. They are also called side-by-sides because they can accommodate both a driver and a passenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="unTPtk"&gt;The new Ranger will have a towing capacity of up to 2,500 lbs and a hauling capacity of 1,250 lbs. That’s a similar towing capacity to the company’s gas-powered Ranger XP 1000, which starts at $18,799. Towing in an electric vehicle also drains the battery at a faster rate, which reduces range and requires more frequent charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rMgidA"&gt;To help with charging, Polaris is teaming up with Qmerit to consult with customers on home charger installation. The Ranger XP Kinetic comes with a Level 1 and 2 charging cable that enables charging from either a 120-volt or 240-volt plug.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JvL1iq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The electric Ranger’s noise profile — or lack thereof — is also being presented as a selling point&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gydQtx"&gt;In many ways, the Ranger XP Kinetic is the lightweight, versatile electric vehicle that farmers, hunters, and outdoorsy types may find over time they actually prefer over heavier, higher-profile EVs, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22442777/ford-f-150-lightning-electric-truck-specs-price"&gt;Ford F-150 Lightning&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, the Ranger won’t be able to match the electric F-150’s towing capacity and range, but it will certainly handle a wide variety of tasks while taking up far less space and costing tens of thousands of dollars less than Ford’s upcoming EV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhQoIW"&gt;The Ranger’s two trim levels represent different battery capacities. The Premium trim is equipped with a 14.9kWh battery, offering an estimated range of up to 45 miles, while the Ultimate trim sports a 29.8kWh battery allowing an estimated 80 miles of range. The Ultimate trim also features a seven-inch infotainment screen powered by Polaris’ connected vehicle software and dash-mounted speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zt3Ruy"&gt;The electric Ranger’s noise profile — or lack thereof — is also being presented as a selling point. Polaris notes that the quiet-by-comparison electric motor will allow for “stealthy trips to remote hunting spots; quiet operation around horses, livestock and other animals; and landowners can do yard work and other property maintenance early in the morning without disturbing the neighbors or family.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lHjafK"&gt;Polaris’ gas-powered Rangers generally range in price between $20,000 and $22,000 and are popular vehicles with agriculture workers, hunters, and other outdoor lovers. Whether customers will be willing to pay 25 percent more for their vehicle may come down to more than just a lack of engine noise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bG65BW"&gt;To that end, Polaris is also hoping that the prospect of cheaper maintenance costs — 70 percent cheaper, by the company’s estimate — will be enough to sway its customers to the higher price tag. The electric Ranger doesn’t require oil changes, filter replacements, spark plugs, or clutch maintenance, Polaris says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d4H1xt"&gt;The Ranger XP Kinetic has been “torture-tested in extreme conditions and treacherous terrain” but will still come with a one-year factory warranty, three-year electric powertrain coverage, and five-year battery coverage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mlJ0Zo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Ranger XP Kinetic has been “torture-tested in extreme conditions and treacherous terrain”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7jG1bq"&gt;Polaris and Zero Motorcycles signed a 10-year agreement last year to produce a range of electric vehicles, including ATVs, UTVs, and snowmobiles. Both companies hope to seize upon what they think has been an overlooked market for electrification, starting with off-road vehicles and snowmobiles, with the ultimate goal to completely electrify Polaris’ lineup by 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u2UkwX"&gt;Zero has been occasionally described as the “&lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/hannahelliott/2014/06/24/meet-the-latest-from-the-tesla-of-motorcycles-the-zero-sr-streetfighter/#48312984394b"&gt;Tesla of motorcycles&lt;/a&gt;” and has established itself over the years as a top-tier maker of electric motorcycles. The Santa Cruz, Calif.-based company currently sells a number of models priced between $10,000 and $17,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3inHdW"&gt;The electric Ranger is being designed and developed by Polaris and Zero at a facility in Wyoming, Minnesota, with manufacturing to take place at Polaris’ facility in Huntsville, Alabama. The first vehicles are expected to roll out to dealerships early next year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22809628/polaris-ranger-xp-kinetic-electric-utv-price-specs-zero"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22809628/polaris-ranger-xp-kinetic-electric-utv-price-specs-zero</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
