<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-02T10:03:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T10:03:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T10:03:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s most affordable iPad is down to $299 at select retailers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r7IDkNUcMvlN8mW-gkyE2nzNFq0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68897212/DSC01911.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sTFZsa"&gt;At $329, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;Apple’s eighth-generation iPad&lt;/a&gt; is the most affordable tablet offered by the tech giant. But if you want to save some additional cash, you can buy the base model, which includes 32GB of storage, for only $299 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J65DST5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon in space gray only&lt;/a&gt; (in stock March 28th). &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-2-inch-iPad-8th-Gen-Wi-Fi-32GB-Silver%2F460189043%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDeals03022021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; is price-matching the e-commerce giant, but you have the option to buy it for $299 in space gray or rose gold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZ8xJd"&gt;This iPad includes a 10.2-inch display and features an A12 Bionic processor. The tablet also includes a Touch ID fingerprint sensor and a Smart Connector, allowing you to connect it to a Smart Keyboard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="n7gye8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508346"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cU93e5"&gt;March is a great month for PS4 and PS5 owners. If you have an active PlayStation Plus subscription, you can snag &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22302776/finalfantasy-7-remake-free-playstation-plus-march-2021"&gt;a free digital copy of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you need to buy a subscription or renew your membership this month, you can grab a &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergePlayStationDeal020121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one-year membership to the service for only $28 at Eneba&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TrQuag"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lC8KI3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Crucial-NAND-NVMe-Internal-3400MB/dp/B087QRVVVH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1733765654307480607" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; have discounted Crucial’s P5 internal SSD. You can grab a 1TB configuration for only $110, the lowest price yet. It’s a good option for PC owners looking to upgrade their systems or improve their games’ loading times. Crucial says the P5 SSD promises up to 3400 MB/s read speeds and 3000 MB/s write speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FvBeGD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10369478"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="Kpwe2H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308968/apple-ipad-2020-playstation-plus-one-year-crucial-p5-ssd-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308968/apple-ipad-2020-playstation-plus-one-year-crucial-p5-ssd-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Aliens: Fireteam is a co-op shooter about surviving a Xenomorph attack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OyRuVg7cUHOQ9gR1K8RWgHXof5Q=/200x0:2360x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68897145/Aliens__Fireteam_Screenshot10.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6iDMIo"&gt;The next &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; video game will be cooperative. Today, developer Cold Iron Studios revealed &lt;em&gt;Aliens: Fireteam&lt;/em&gt;, a multiplayer third-person shooter about surviving an onslaught of Xenomorphs set a few decades after the original &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8VUDci"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fireteam&lt;/em&gt; is a class-based shooter — where players take on roles like gunner, demolisher, or technician — and Cold Iron says there will be a huge range of enemies to take on, including 11 types of Xenomorphs, as well as some of those pesky Weyland-Yutani synthetics. Here’s the basic premise:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="TyoDlw"&gt;Set 23 years after the original &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; trilogy, &lt;em&gt;Aliens: Fireteam&lt;/em&gt; drops players into the role of a Colonial Marine aboard the USS &lt;em&gt;Endeavor&lt;/em&gt;, recently tasked with answering a distress call from the outer colonies. Deploy to overrun facilities, abandoned ruins, and strange alien landscapes as you battle terrifying enemies across four campaigns with two friends or AI teammates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id="bix7ET"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B63_ljZ91Mc?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uZVhev"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; franchise has a mixed history in video games, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/10/3/6897307/alien-isolation-review"&gt;2014’s &lt;em&gt;Alien: Isolation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is regarded as a high point. But whereas that game channeled the original &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; and its horror roots, &lt;em&gt;Fireteam&lt;/em&gt; is looking to evoke the action-heavy sequel, &lt;em&gt;Aliens&lt;/em&gt;. “This is the action game &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; fans have been waiting for,” Cold Iron Studios head Craig Zinkievich said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fyaeRy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aliens: Fireteam&lt;/em&gt; is expected to launch this summer on the PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X / S, and Steam.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308034/aliens-fireteam-co-op-shooter-pc-ps4-ps5-xbox-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308034/aliens-fireteam-co-op-shooter-pc-ps4-ps5-xbox-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Surface Pro 7 Plus review: built for business</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Removable SSDs, built-in LTE, and a familiar design&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="xIz7VQ"&gt;You could now line up five years’ worth of Surface Pro devices next to each other and it would be all but impossible to tell them apart. Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 7 Plus keeps the same familiar design, which is likely just to satisfy corporate customers who want to standardize their hardware for years at a time. That might be good news for business customers, but for the rest of us who want slimmer display bezels and a more modern design like the Surface Pro X, then the wait continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uLaB4k"&gt;It’s no surprise then that Microsoft is limiting sales of the Surface Pro 7 Plus exclusively to businesses and schools. Consumers won’t be able to purchase this from a store, and it’s really for businesses and schools looking to upgrade older machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TtieZW"&gt;While I’ve bemoaned the current design of the Surface Pro for a couple of years now, there are some changes inside the Surface Pro 7 Plus that will appeal to many. Microsoft now offers built-in LTE on select models, and the SSD is now removable, much like the Surface Laptop 3 and Surface Pro X. Intel’s latest processors also promise better performance and battery life. It’s nearly everything you’d want from a Surface tablet in 2021, but I still wish it looked like a Surface Pro X with an Intel chip inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Zt6kW5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10369398"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="ggpzYz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10369401"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nDAYCP"&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus starts at $899.99, which is a $150 premium on the price of the Surface Pro 7. Thankfully, the base model is now the Intel Core i3 version, with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage. Microsoft has dropped the 4GB of RAM option for the Plus model. I’ve been testing a Core i5 model with 16GB of RAM, 256GB of storage, and built-in LTE connectivity, which is a steep $1,649.99 before you add a keyboard or stylus. The cheapest option for LTE is the $1,149.99 model with a Core i5 processor, 8GB of RAM, and 128GB of storage. Microsoft offers all 11 models in the classic silver option, but oddly the black version isn’t available with built-in LTE. You’ll also need a separate Surface Type Cover, and the business versions are priced at $159.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PlGs9q"&gt;Overall, the hardware on the Surface Pro 7 Plus is almost identical to the Surface Pro 7. There’s the same 12.3-inch (2736 x 1824) touchscreen with its 3:2 aspect ratio, a single USB-C port, and the regular USB-A port. Microsoft still hasn’t made the switch to Thunderbolt 3 or 4 here, so you can’t hook this tablet up to an external GPU or use many of the Thunderbolt drives and docks available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EWRQq0"&gt;The real changes to the Surface Pro 7 Plus can be found inside. Microsoft has moved to Intel’s latest 11th Gen processors, and you can pick between Core i3, Core i5, or Core i7 variants. I’ve been testing the Core i5 model, and it has remained cool even when using heavy apps like video or video-editing software. Like other Core i5 Pro 7 models, this has no internal fan, so it’s also silent while working.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r3kotNhVimXSdmp-JOohyddMeU8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22329291/twarren_210223_4439_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s Surface Pro 7 has a familiar design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MbSDWy"&gt;These latest processors also include Intel’s Iris Xe graphics. While it’s not enough to turn this into a portable gaming laptop, it does help make the Surface Pro 7 Plus feel a lot snappier in a variety of tasks. Combined with improved SSD read and write speeds, lightweight photo and video editing is certainly faster than what I’m used to with the regular Surface Pro 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xgmtn7"&gt;The biggest new hardware addition is built-in LTE, though. It’s the first time the Surface Pro lineup has included this for a few years, but unfortunately there’s no 5G support. Microsoft is using Qualcomm’s older Snapdragon X20 LTE modem inside the Surface Pro 7 Plus. There’s a dedicated SIM slot at the side of the device, which replaces where you’d normally find the microSD slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ptic8A"&gt;As England has been in a pandemic lockdown for months, I haven’t ventured outside enough to really push the LTE connectivity to its limits, but I didn’t find it impacted battery life too much in my limited tests. LTE connectivity is a great option to have on a device like the Surface Pro, especially for those who normally work remotely, visit clients, or just want something to replace really bad Wi-Fi connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4v8wWeiE-cggYG8TZ-m5MdGe-q0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22329296/twarren_210223_4439_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus has removable SSDs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4KPJ7E4N8JZzUK7KyAvZv6uyDPY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22329295/twarren_210223_4439_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s even a new SIM slot for built-in LTE connectivity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="uX6vYt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10369413"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3XiqKg"&gt;The other significant hardware change on the Surface Pro 7 Plus is removable SSDs. This is really designed for commercial users to swap out faulty SSDs or to retain corporate data. The SSD is easily accessible from an access door at the rear of the Surface Pro 7 Plus, and a simple SIM tool will open it up. Microsoft’s reseller network has &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/surface-it-pro-blog/introducing-ssd-commercial-spares-for-surface-pro-7/ba-p/2147128"&gt;started selling SSD kits&lt;/a&gt;, with 128GB, 256GB, 512GB, and 1TB options, so there’s even the option to upgrade storage space here. It’s encouraging to see Microsoft make this so easy to do, which makes it far quicker for IT admins to get a machine up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HSAHkg"&gt;All of these internal hardware changes also mean that Microsoft has managed to squeeze a bigger battery (46.5Wh to 50.4Wh) inside the Surface Pro 7 Plus. The company now promises 15 hours of battery life, compared to the 10.5 hours on the original Surface Pro 7. I haven’t noticed any drastic improvements in battery life during normal usage, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="36a2Z6"&gt;I typically got around seven to eight hours of battery life during my testing, which includes a mix of apps ranging from Chrome, Discord, and Netflix to Adobe Photoshop. If all you’re doing is watching videos, then you’ll probably see closer to Microsoft’s 15-hour promise, but realistically this is still just enough to get you through a regular day of work. I’m still hoping that one day a Surface Pro will reliably hit 10 hours, so I never have to worry about traveling without a charger.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-9rT_ZPMxIsCob_M0RwR0Hn7d60=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22329293/twarren_210223_4439_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s Surface Pro 7 Plus is only available to businesses and schools.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="52OAPW"&gt;I’m still a big fan of the Surface Pro, despite the lack of design changes. Microsoft is clearly catering to a specific audience here, and the Surface Pro 7 Plus has been built for businesses. I hope that means we’ll soon see a consumer-focused Surface Pro that mixes everything that’s great about the Surface Pro X with the power and performance of Intel’s chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2N6n6a"&gt;Built-in LTE and removable SSDs are great additions to the Surface Pro lineup, but we’ve still been waiting years for basics like Thunderbolt 3 support. And while LTE is a great option to have once again, it’s odd that Microsoft isn’t including more futureproof 5G connectivity. If you’re using an older Surface Pro and looking to upgrade, it might not look like a lot has changed over the years, but these subtle hardware changes do make a small difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="V6J4jn"&gt;Microsoft completely redesigned the inside of the Surface Pro this year to include this LTE support and removable SSDs. I’m just hoping a complete redesign on the outside is on the way. It’s still the 2-in-1 to beat, but the Surface Pro could offer so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qS7icW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wOIoeu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9VpFPT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aiUK04"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22309005/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22309005/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:21:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:21:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to import your passwords to Chrome and the Google Password Manager</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G6P7a_up-tHjfUvAKkTjmeuuzAg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68896888/acastro_200207_3900_chrome_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6H1EGD"&gt;If you’re &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295354/lastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho"&gt;moving from LastPass&lt;/a&gt; (or another password manager you’re dissatisfied with), you may be tempted to simply go with the password manager that comes with your browser or operating system. It’s certainly an easy solution, and a reasonable one, depending on your point of view. Until recently, third-party password managers were known to be more secure, but Apple and Google have been working to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/23/21299007/google-password-checkup-security"&gt;make their built-in password managers more secure&lt;/a&gt;, while Microsoft is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178026/microsoft-authenticator-autofill-feature-password-manager"&gt;adding one to its authenticator app&lt;/a&gt;. So it could be a viable choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BIrfb8"&gt;One way, however, that these built-in password managers don’t stand up to their independent competitors is how tricky it can be to get preexisting passwords into their systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xUIylU"&gt;If you tend to hang out in the Google ecosystem and / or you have an Android mobile device, that means you can be using the Google Password Manager to store and synch your passwords via the Chrome browser. Unfortunately, like Apple’s Safari, Google Chrome makes it extremely difficult to import passwords from a CSV file. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="O2F5EW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to import your passwords to Apple’s iCloud Keychain via Safari","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22301046/passwords-import-how-to-keychain-safari-apple-lastpass"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oKDU7F"&gt;The only way to do it that I could find was to try to enable a disabled Chrome feature that allows you to import passwords. After searching online, I found several methods to enable it, depending on which version of Chrome you’re running. I am currently running version 88, and while I was able to use the following method to add the import command to Chrome (&lt;a href="https://www.guidingtech.com/import-passwords-csv-google-chrome/"&gt;thank you to &lt;em&gt;Guiding Tech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for pointing me toward this possible solution), my copy of Chrome was never able to actually import the CSV file I had downloaded from LastPass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vTWCMh"&gt;Be that as it may, here is the process I used. Perhaps you’ll have more luck. I’ll let you know how I finally managed to get my passwords into Chrome right afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="VvVbcT"&gt;In Chrome’s top address bar, type in chrome://flags. This will bring you to the Experiments page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f9dtFh"&gt;In the “Search flags” box on top, type in “password import.” (Probably just typing “password” will be enough.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In Chrome’s Experiments page, you can enable the Import feature" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RHFD7GIsWY6-p5jp3Nt1YvWJPT4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22337454/Screen_Shot_2021_03_01_at_2.56.30_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Chrome’s Experiments page, you can enable the Import feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="g9zjeM"&gt;Find “Password import” and click on the drop-down menu on the left (it will probably be labeled “Default”). Select “Enabled.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xDXe7D"&gt;Select “Relaunch.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TwDwHmh8o06yhuZgrCTpcc9wnBQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22337453/Screen_Shot_2021_03_01_at_2.56.52_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="vV3KsE"&gt;Now that you’ve added the import function, go to to your Chrome Settings (by selecting the three dots in the upper right corner and choosing “Settings”). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vDiKwL"&gt;Find “Passwords” (which will be in the “Autofill” category) and click on the arrow on the right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xLC1Ge"&gt;Look for “Saved Passwords,” and click on the three dots on the right. You should see a drop-down that includes the selection “Import.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Chrome should now have an Import selection under Saved Passwords" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NqZ35oLiyL2wS1oRrFN0OXDOthk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22337560/Screen_Shot_2021_03_01_at_3.32.11_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrome should now have an Import selection under Saved Passwords.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="VksRQg"&gt;Click on “Import.” You’ll be able to select a CSV file from your file manager — and hopefully, import your passwords.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="6fbrrx"&gt;If that works for you — great! If not, then there is a last desperate way to get your passwords into Chrome, which is the one that finally worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="CFEYLv"&gt;Download Firefox (if you don’t have it already) and start it up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Er87a4"&gt;Click on the three lines in the upper right corner and select “Logins and Passwords.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3dWPXr"&gt;Click on the three dots in the upper right corner and select “Import from a File.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Y1Lysz"&gt;Select your CSV file and import it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Firefox has no qualms about importing a CSV password file" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oaBNvwODilDQLjVRTcaQ9oijBqc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22337610/Screen_Shot_2021_03_01_at_3.38.07_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Firefox has no qualms about importing a CSV password file.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="930KB9"&gt;Now that your passwords are in Firefox, you can transfer them easily to Chrome:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="rmNvOf"&gt;In Chrome, click on the three dots in the upper right corner and go to “Bookmarks” &amp;gt; “Import Bookmarks and Settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5MJBqE"&gt;Select Mozilla Firefox in the drop-down menu, select “Passwords” (and “Autofill form data” if you had any), and click on “Import.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Chrome has no problem importing passwords from rival browsers" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x5Znuv5s85vZbOPIC_KDLDZzXVs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22337615/Screen_Shot_2021_03_01_at_3.43.17_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrome has no problem importing passwords from rival browsers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7jwnMI"&gt;That (phew!) should do it! But if you don’t want to go through all that, there are always free alternative password managers that you can try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="RI2EEm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Six free alternatives to the LastPass password manager","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22285499/password-manager-lastpass-free-bitwarden-zoho"},{"title":"How to leave LastPass and move to another password manager","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22295354/lastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22303614/chrome-google-password-manager-import-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22303614/chrome-google-password-manager-import-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:02:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The 25-year-old billionaire building the future of self-driving cars</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JjPoXdaL1GlVD82ivX9LR0XSXfM=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68896818/VRG_ILLO_4442_Decoder_Austin_Russell.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Luminar’s Austin Russell on the technology that will drive the future&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="aK7t5l"&gt;Austin Russell is the 25-year-old founder and CEO of Luminar, a startup in Silicon Valley that makes LIDAR sensors for self-driving cars. LIDAR technology had been used for short-distance mapping, but Luminar claims to have a functioning LIDAR that works at 250 meters, which is a breakthrough. Luminar recently went public, making Austin today’s youngest self-made billionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3INBNr"&gt;And when it comes to self-driving cars, youth is definitely an advantage — Austin told me we’re still years if not decades away from fully self-driving cars, and there’s a lot of work to be done to make them safe, effective, and ubiquitous. That work is racing ahead — Luminar has deals with Volvo, Audi, Toyota, and others — but building a complete self-driving car is still a long-term project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HQZlxR"&gt;Here we go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6ejY5x"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/5BP05eqblkzy5NK0MeMomc" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gHvu9C"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This transcript has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M1SikB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austin Russell, you’re the founder and CEO of Luminar. Welcome to the show.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZqKbl7"&gt;Thank you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IC8EFU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m very excited to talk to you. You are, as far as the last thing I read, the youngest self-made billionaire in America, your company just went public in a SPAC [special purpose acquisitions company]. How old are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UUaZS7"&gt;I am 25 currently. And come Pi Day, 26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hX4QbL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You were born on Pi Day?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aJk9oQ"&gt;Yeah, exactly. March 14th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iuFr05"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s just a lot of things coming together for you there. That’s great. And auspicious. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJ1zBf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, Luminar, it’s a company that makes LIDAR sensors. You have a number of deals to supply LIDAR sensors to major automakers. I want to talk about all of that. One thing that I always get frustrated by in origin stories is no one ever really talks about act two. In 2012 you were at Stanford, you had this idea to do LIDAR sensors. Something happened. Now you’re a public company with hundreds of employees and you’re a billionaire. I want to talk about act two for a little bit. Just that middle part of going from “I’ve got a great idea,” to “This company is actually up and running and functional.” So give me a sense of, at the beginning you were a student at Stanford, you got a Thiel Fellowship from Peter Thiel. What was the next step? Did you sit down and build a LIDAR sensor? Did you have the components for it? Were you like, “I’ve got to make a laser.” What was the next step?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W4Quqr"&gt;I think when it comes down to it, there wasn’t any kind of miracle step, so to say, involved in that but rather these were already somewhat ongoing projects, even at the time when I went into Stanford, when I got the Thiel Fellowship, everything was already somewhat in motion. But it all starts with that innate passion and desire to be able to want to build, to create, to innovate and invent. And in my case I just had a specific interest around optics and photonics and other types of systems that can end up making a huge difference in these kinds of new products and saw the application opportunity for autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="TY6Vuh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9545330"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AejEfC"&gt;So [I] really just went all in on that. And it’s one of those things that if you knock it out of the park, it really is a trillion-dollar industry opportunity with — not to mention the humanitarian aspect of 1.3 million lives lost on the road every year, to be able to have an opportunity to impact that and make a difference. It maybe seems like a crazy long shot at the time for that to happen and materialize. But at the same time, I think you just have extreme focus around what you want to do, and continue to solve for it, build for it, learn from all the folks around you and just continue to deliver. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysQewv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the thing, this is the act two. You got the fellowship, you got the check, what did you do the next day?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XVYKXD"&gt;What did I do the next day? That’s what I’m saying, it’s like the same thing that it was otherwise doing. I don’t know how much it fundamentally changes other than accelerates the exact same thing you’re doing. And you just keep accelerating, and accelerating, and accelerating, and you have this compounding exponential effect that you can grow and snowball into something much bigger. And that’s really what happens. And by the way, for things like the Thiel Fellowship, don’t get me wrong. The 100K check is great, but there’s multiple ways you can generate 100K income to be able to start a business, the real value is the network. How do you learn from the most successful entrepreneurs on the planet to be able to build this kind of business and scale this kind of business? And like I said, it takes a lot more than a great technology and concept to build a great business and that’s what’s required if you want to actually have your tech see the light of day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OY7wPU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was just you at the beginning, you had this interest in optics and photonics. You saw the market opportunity for LIDAR, particularly in self-driving cars. At the time, 2012-ish, those systems were really big. I think Luminar’s advancement is that you’ve made them smaller and easier to manufacture. You’ve made them more of a useful device. Here’s a simple question. Who was the first person you hired?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDBZge"&gt;Oh, a couple of key folks. One of them, I worked with originally from a consulting perspective, and then ultimately brought on as a co-founder into this. So it’s a guy named Jason Eichenholz, who’s our CTO, and responsible for a lot of now forward-looking R&amp;amp;D programs and projects that we have going on from the LIDAR standpoint. He actually helped to establish the Orlando, Florida office that we have outside of the Silicon Valley presence that we had. And that was where we really started to scale up the hardware team out there and were able to build out a capability. It turned out the highest concentration of these types of LIDAR engineers out of anywhere in the world was in Orlando, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wdOquF"&gt;So, you go where the people are. It’s a Space Coast, defense industry, Cape Canaveral and all that, that I really brought in a lot of the talent from. Actually another interesting one, I did end up hiring my uncle, who was an electrical engineer and someone that I had admired. I didn’t know him super well previously, but my parents pointed it out and said, “Hey, you know your uncle does that electrical engineering thing.” And I was like, “Yeah!” So he’s certainly good at rapid prototyping and definitely helped out early on as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sHIknr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So just walk me through: you’ve got your early prototypes, a small team of people, you think it can be productized. How’d you go from that to, you’ve got a manufacturing operation at scale that can obviously support the size of a public company now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V4W9yu"&gt;Yeah, so it definitely is a shift going from the core technology development, which we did for the first handful of years, to being able to have a scalable operation that can build automotive-grade product into series production. And the most important thing that’s always been our goal and focus, the reality is that even, effectively, all the autonomous vehicle companies today that are built building products, it’s really much more meant for R&amp;amp;D than it is for something that’s ever actually going to make its way into a production vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WxRt02"&gt;And that’s a key distinction here, of where you have to follow automotive process, and the work around how you can build these sensing systems up. And that’s where for us, we leverage the core expertise around how you can successfully assemble these and doing the process engineering and the manufacturing engineering and everything, to be able to get to a stage where we can have a formula for not just the technology itself, but how to be able to build the technology and build it at scale. And that was where we also built out that capability, in Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWnzmb"&gt;We have about 100,000 square feet worth of space that we’ve been using for our facility. That’s where the manufacturing process that we have is developed, which ultimately, we will transfer and are transferring to the relevant contract manufacturers to be able to do the final assembly for series production. So that way we’re not taking on thousands upon thousands of employees ourselves; as we scale up there too, we get to leverage outside resources for the more “commodity” aspect of assembly of the device itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J6ujwg"&gt;Whereas the formula, the automation and how you build it successfully, that’s important to what we’ve had to do to keep in-house. So it’s a hybrid model. And that’s something that just takes a lot of work, a lot of expertise with the right people to build it up. And that’s always been core to the philosophy by the way, is make sure you get the right people on board that have huge domain expertise in the key areas that you really need it in. It’s easier said than done, but at the same time, if you have the right people there, it can scale that like we did in this case, it makes all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9Ahlm"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much time do you spend with your engineering team doing engineering stuff versus with the business and commercial side of the company?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gWYeq8"&gt;Still quite a decent amount. Obviously in the beginning it was all that, 100 percent just diving deep with the team. As we scale up, it’s still absolutely critical to not just keep a pulse on product and product development, but still to be able to shape that with the same vision that you have and make sure that stays on track, make sure that we can easily drive forward with all the new inputs that you have and continuously shape the future of how you see that playing out. And that’s something that I absolutely still am hands on in. I don’t think that’ll ever change. But there’s no question that there’s a lot of balls to juggle. There’s a lot of stuff that has to happen, but they’re all synergistic. You can’t do engineering in a vacuum, or product management in a vacuum, or commercial work in a vacuum. They all have to tie closely together. And this is where it’s critical to have the frame of mind that combines all the different areas of the business and all the different aspects of a product and everything that comes into play and having the technical understanding of that as well, which is not always a given, in order to be able to succeed and scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n8xk0O"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As you’ve been growing at the company, one of the tropes of early internet company founders is that they hired grownups. Mark Zuckerberg hired Sheryl Sandberg, Larry Page and Sergey Brin hired Eric Schmidt. It’s just a cliche. Have you put yourself in that mode? Have you thought, I need to hire some grownups that are going to help me go public, I need to hire some grownups that are going to help me operate a large company, or have you been more targeted?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l7odPs"&gt;You know, it’s a great question for that. The key thing here is that it’s something that we’ve been doing. It’s something that I’ve been doing, to be frank, this whole time throughout our journey. As it relates to step-by-step through all of this, I don’t think there’s any single person that is actually hired to take the reins of the grownup doing X, Y or Z, rather [it’s]: Build the rock star team of all the respective leaders in their field, and build a cross-functional org structure where you have a clear set of responsibilities for each one of these folks. Where it’s really my job to synthesize all of that information and be able to make corresponding business and technical decisions based on that path, and rely on the team from an execution perspective, to be able to see that vision through. So it’s a little bit of a different setup than maybe you would have with some of those folks, but at the same time, not uncommon at all. You mentioned [Jeff] Bezos here, [he] just finally handed that off, which is great to be able to see. But [he] had a similar type of cross-functional org structure for a huge period of time throughout Amazon’s growth trajectory and curve, and among many other companies that really set that up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LcdyGw"&gt;You’ve got to get the right insight into the right folks in terms of how to set this stuff up. The hard part about this business though, is this isn’t like your average internet company here. Where they’re having people that have built internet-related companies and social media-related work and had executed on paths and visions for those different types of businesses. For this, this really is something that from a technological perspective, as well as business perspective, it’s never been done. Even just carving out the fundamentals of the business ball. When you take a look at, where does all of Google’s and Facebook’s revenue come from? Ads, really that’s what... You take a look at all these fancy, crazy technology developments and everything, and like, “Okay, what’s with this model? It’s ads?” This is a completely different level of complexity that requires a different level of cross-functional understanding, all the way from the fundamental aspects of how the technology works, all the way up through the staff, and that’s why it makes it a little bit different and very important for leadership and whoever is leading the company to be able to have that full staff understanding and be able to drive the business forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hvWac"&gt;And I do think that’s why there have been some great celebrated leaders within the overall autonomous vehicle space. It’s not just purely based on that basic understanding rather than sometimes even any execution at all, but it’s just so valuable in this space to be able to have that understanding, it drives forward a lot of the different ideas in the industry. But that’s what I’d say is the case for me. I’m continuing to bring on other great team members, expanding the overall executive leadership team that we have, but it’s been a very effective structure for how we’re executing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yb6Imv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One question I ask every CEO who comes on the show is, what’s your decision-making framework? And I think that question is particularly interesting with you because you started the company when you were very young. You’ve obviously scaled to this point. I imagine you’ve learned a lot of lessons along the way; particularly, you’ve almost certainly hired people who are older and have more experience than you. How has your decision-making framework evolved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2K5z0o"&gt;I would say just over time, as you build and scale a business, you have to go from being comfortable with decisions with nearly 100 percent of the information to being comfortable with decisions with effectively, what evolves to a smaller and smaller fraction of that for given things. You have to have greater levels of delegation, you have to have greater levels of talent and quality of talent as you build it up, and you have to continuously just keep raising the bar in terms of what you’re going to be doing. And I would say from a decision-making framework standpoint, it goes at the same time in a parallel thread beyond just increased delegation, more shifted towards going from technology-driven decisions [to] just trying to do whatever you can to create the best product. It’s like, “Okay, well, what do you do?” You have the best product, how do you make sure it sees widespread adoption in the industry?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZB9HnA"&gt;And that’s where it becomes focused around being able to successfully enable that over the long run and being able to establish strategic initiatives and plans to be able to drive that forward to realization. So that’s where you have to apply, always, a business or financial mindset to all of these things to make it work. Because if you miss even part of one of the pieces of the puzzle, you effectively end up with zero. It’s like a binary equation here. You have to get everything almost perfectly right. And that’s why this is just so impossibly hard. Going from the R&amp;amp;D stage to actually realizing this through into a real product and business case and everything around it is a huge challenge, so that’s what you have to keep your eye on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AcSTTT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You were talking about prioritizing the product and we were talking about decision-making frameworks. So give me an example, you were saying you’re shifting from building the product, building the prototype to strategic decisions to make sure you can get to market. Give me an example of a trade-off you’ve made along the way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="34lJkj"&gt;Well, the ultimate goal of the balancing act is to try and minimize one-to-one trade-offs and to be able to scale the business side as much as you can scale the technology side in parallel. But nevertheless I would say, for example, we have no shortage of ambition in terms of what we’re trying to solve or what we knew we could build and make a difference on, beyond just the LIDAR sensing system. And I think there’s probably some desire to accelerate our software roadmap beyond our hardware roadmap, even faster than we ultimately did. Actually, much faster. But at the same time, you have to be careful about stacking too many parallel programs together and too much parallel risk and taking it step-by-step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4nlap"&gt;And as exciting as it can be to have something that you know you can solve for, ultimately, that was a trade-off that we had to say, “Okay, remain focused, solve the LIDAR problem, see it through. Yes, we’ll continue to build up the software stack in parallel for ultimately a more turnkey solution to the autonomous vehicle problem, but take it step by step.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bS12Ha"&gt;And that’s effectively what we did, and it was a decently long journey, eight years with this. So I think that’s where the last few years went, we spent more time really ramping up the commercial side and ramping up the software side as well. One other interesting trade-off that we made — taking it from a totally different angle, from a marketing perspective a lot of times — I know being in stealth mode for some period of time is really cool these days. But at this point back when I first founded the company, a lot of times you would have people that are announcing every stage. And I think it’s still usually the case now, every phase of their journey, oftentimes before you actually have anything to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flCcL2"&gt;At some stage, it goes back to a core philosophy versus like show, not tell. Because it’s really easy to have a lot of claims. And by the way, there is no shortage of claims in the overall autonomous vehicle space. In part, it’s because it’s easy to say things, because you don’t actually always show it or have to show it. People have ways to easily evaluate if it’s actually real or not. It’s some of the reason why you’ve seen some of the recent activity from companies that maybe couldn’t even raise private capital, now getting to a stage where [they’re] trying to enter the public markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uYCQzQ"&gt;But nevertheless for us it was always heads down, focus on delivering, don’t let any noise affect you. And by the way, don’t try and give any people a reason for a head start here either. Oftentimes it doesn’t actually benefit you. At least initially, consumer or even OEM [original equipment manufacturer] awareness is less relevant because you have to actually finish the product first. You want the first impression to be really good. And that’s basically what we spent the first five years doing. Deep down in stealth mode, building out the core product and technology and getting to a stage where we could actually launch the company and scale this up. And that’s really what we did starting in 2017, five years in, after we had developed the laser, the receiver, the scanning mechanism, processing electronics, all of our own chips that we had in the system. And it came together, it all worked. Somewhat miraculously, somewhat unexpectedly, at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjEhmZ"&gt;So that’s where I think we were able to capture the attention of some of the world’s largest automakers in terms of showing the art of what is possible. We had a system that had specifications that people thought there was no way this was even doable from a physics perspective, much less something that could be economically produced. So that was the start of where we gained a lot of interest from beyond just the technology, but from a commercial angle as well, and a key catalyst for scaling this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Azu3sC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So I want to dive in on the first trade-off you mentioned, which is going too far, too fast. You said you held yourself back from overthinking building the turnkey autonomous driving system, where, I’m Patel Automakers, which is a longstanding dream of mine—&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NfUcAt"&gt;There you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H5p4Tt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I’m like, “Man, I really want this car to drive itself. I’m going to put out bids to Luminar, to Velodyne, to Siemens, for a self-driving car stack, I’m going to buy it, I’m going to integrate it into my car and I’m off and running.” And I didn’t actually do any of that work myself. You want to be that kind of player in the end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2QZqye"&gt;Yeah, absolutely. We want to be a turnkey solution for this, and to some extent have already started evolving into that for these different OEMs. And really the reason why is, to be able to build an autonomous vehicle, the LIDAR is just one part of that holistic solution. Now it is a key bottleneck that’s been preventing the deployment of, in large part, this industry just by way of having something that meets the performance requirements, that meets the economic requirements, that can actually be scalable here. But at the same time the LIDAR itself doesn’t drive your car. You need the software to go along with it, as well as some of the rest of the ecosystem there to be able to push forward with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PEdGDj"&gt;Now there’s some argument that some would say of like, “Okay, what on earth? Why are you guys screwing around with software?” There’s like “Yeah, okay. You carved out your value proposition in hardware, but you have folks like Waymo and Cruise and all these multibillion-dollar software development companies that are taking that on.” And here’s the key distinction though. I think if that was applicable to all the same things that you’re doing, all the same OEMs that we’re working with? Yeah, we wouldn’t be in that game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WHcN3n"&gt;But the key distinction here is that seeing the difference of, for example, it was very clear that everyone, virtually every company in the autonomous vehicle space, has been focused on robotaxis specifically, and all the big guys there. And that’s their primary application, that’s what they’re developing the software for, but it’s actually very different developing the software for a highly complex urban robotaxi scenario ... and building R&amp;amp;D cars for that, because that’s the most advanced stage that they’re at today, with like $100,000 roof racks full of sensors and stuff, versus building something for a production vehicle in a more constrained application. Something that could be deployed in the relative near term, with an auto grade quality code that you can put your life in the hands of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="44IWNJ"&gt;So it’s a different trajectory, and that’s why we really focused around developing this full-stack solution for OEMs, for the automakers themselves, as opposed to us trying to do some rogue deployment with a robotaxi company or like a ride-sharing company, like building our own network of vehicles. Don’t get me wrong, that’s going to be a great route. It’s going to be huge value at the end of the day that’s created based on that and based on ride-sharing, but we don’t see that feasibly happening even with ours... We have customers in that domain and we’re helping accelerate, but it’s still like a decade-long problem, [more] than it is something that’s going to be deployed next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MehNnS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isn’t that just a function of cost? Or the cost versus the revenue opportunity? So if you’re Waymo, you buy a Chrysler Pacifica for $50,000, you put $200,000 worth of stuff on the roof to make it drive itself — No one’s buying a quarter-million dollar Chrysler Pacifica. I can’t imagine who would buy that. There’s probably some hardcore Pacifica blog that’s going to write this up now, I’m hoping — But you use that as a taxi. Your quarter-million dollar minivan starts generating money. You’ve built a business that eventually returns profit as you scale down the cost of the roof rack. You’re saying you’re going to take on all of that cost and then sell a turnkey solution to automakers so they can ship a $55,000 SUV to an average family that can drive itself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RpRtJx"&gt;Absolutely. The whole point is to have a solution. You take that $100,000 roof rack full of stuff, or $200,000 roof rack, and effectively put it into a package that’s more on the order of $1,000 than it is $200,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZT0BQ"&gt;So that’s a huge part of the equation. No question. Is the cost and the economics there? But it’s also just as much building a solution that’s tailored for production vehicles that actually can be put into a car in an auto grade solution, in capacity, and having the software that’s focused around the use case in the application and the domain. You’re going to have a completely different level of software complexity trying to build for an urban environment than you are for the highway environments that we’re focused on for the initial deployments with OEMs. And the whole point is, how do you do all of that on the sensing side? And the software side, you solve that problem. You also need to make sure that doesn’t require a supercomputer in your trunk to actually process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5mbRFO"&gt;And that’s where being able to get all of that work on the same kind of Nvidia GPU that people are embedding into their production vehicles, that’s key. And that’s effectively what we’ve had to solve for as part of the full stack solution. Now, is it going to be driving you everywhere from point A to point B, anywhere you want? Absolutely not. But is it going to be enabling some level of autonomy that’s reachable by consumers and dramatically improve safety on your vehicle that can be put out onto billions of production cars? Absolutely. So then that’s how you start generating a real business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KJ3uCW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the things I always think about with what I would call foundational technologies: sensors, display technologies, batteries, is we tend to build software and products around the limitations of those technologies. And then sometime along the way, there’s a huge shift in foundational technologies and our entire belief about what the products can do changes. And we have to build entirely new software. A really dumb example is the transition from CRTs to LCDs. There was a whole conception of what the world of technology would look like when CRTs were the display technology, we shifted to LCDs and now literally everything is an Android computer. Do you worry that LIDAR is one of those foundational technologies that will get disrupted in that way? Or is it that end-all be-all of sensing around you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sCAiUh"&gt;It’s a good question. And I think it’s foundational technology itself, but also the economics of those technologies, the performance of those technologies, what are the theoretical limitations in terms of what you can actually achieve with each of these different systems. And I would actually say that LIDAR is the perfect example of what we’re just talking about here, of a technology that’s entirely disrupted the mindset in a business model around what was even possible from an autonomous perspective. For example, historically LIDAR has been very limited in terms of the range performance of what you can actually do, how far out you can see. That was part of the reason why people were focused on urban environments for their autonomous vehicle setups for the robotaxis operating at low speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ky5sug"&gt;Now, when you can see very clearly out to 250 meters into the distance, different story. You can start to operate on highway speeds. You can now enable a different operating domain and something that actually ends up being more simple if you have the range to be able to do it. And at the same time, for example, the economics: If you have something that isn’t that huge $100,000 roof rack full of stuff, and you can actually have it embedded in a production vehicle for something more on the order of $1,000, then it makes all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uGRqt2"&gt;We’re pricing our sensors today at that mark for many of these applications. So that’s where, seeing this actually happen in a production vehicle, it completely shifts the mindset in terms of what’s possible. And I’m not even sure that all of these companies would have the same business model that they do today if they knew this was possible from the beginning. I actually don’t think that a lot of the robotaxi companies would at all. But when it comes down to it, anything beyond that, if you’re talking existential perspective, about not just LIDAR disrupting LIDAR, or something disrupting not just improvements of the technology, but disrupting it altogether, the reality is that the autonomous vehicle problem, and being able to try and solve all of these different edge cases, is really, really hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qOF9Sr"&gt;People try to say, “Oh yeah, we’ll solve it. It’s easy. We’ll figure it out in 2022 or ‘23, whatever it is.” No, this stuff is really hard and no one has ever actually solved it at this point to date for the kind of application domain that you’re looking at. Now, you really need to throw everything you can get out at it. There was definitely an idea a few years ago that it would be something that would be solvable by just time and data collection and just what it takes. But the reality is it just requires a lot of raw, intense performance of a system to be able to understand what’s going on. And required even much better performance from a LIDAR standpoint, to be able to enable the capabilities, to have your understanding of everything going on around you very far out, and with the level of resolution performance that’s needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l2ldzZ"&gt;On top of that, of course, there’s continuing software capabilities that need to improve. It is improving, it’s getting better, but the software is not going to be there for a while, for more of these urban environments and constraints, regardless of what anyone might say, if you want to try to have a car go from point A to point B in these environments. It’s going to take time even with our sensors, it’s going to take a lot of time. But the point is how do you get this out there sooner than later? That’s where you’ll go for the more constrained environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gUtvyn"&gt;Now listen, of course when talking about disruptiveness, you sometimes have confusion that can arise— there’s a very bright line between there. There’s assisted driving and there’s autonomous driving. One requires the driver constantly in the loop, ready to take over the wheel at any given moment whenever it makes a mistake, as it’s following a couple of lanes on the road ahead. This is the equivalent of things like Tesla autopilot — or the systems that the company Mobileye has been providing to OEMs for the better part of a decade now. They don’t always enable the same full functionality that Tesla does more aggressively — versus true self-driving, true autonomy. Hands-off, eyes off, read a book, use your phone, work on your laptop, watch a movie, take a nap, that kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yDEzVI"&gt;That’s autonomy and that’s the key step function value. And that’s what this enables, that’s the whole point of what this LIDAR enables. You don’t need a LIDAR at all if you want your car to follow a couple lanes in the road ahead of you and keep your hands on the wheel and eyes on the road. This is what it enables and it doesn’t matter what you call your assisted driving system. You can call it autopilot, full self-driving, whatever it is. Or like I said, the other OEMs that conservatively name their systems more appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HQfzGc"&gt;So, that’s the key distinction there. The more performance you get, the safer the vehicle is. And I don’t think anybody’s going to stop and say, “Yeah, I think we can just decrease the safety of these vehicles by 100X.” Even if you got to a point where you could achieve that human-level safety threshold, why would you make your vehicles that much less safe? It doesn’t make any sense. So that would be not just in the near term, but I’m talking even a 50-year type time horizon. You don’t really see it being disruptive. You see, how do you continue to strive for even better performance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EFGObq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right. You’re saying if we made a fully autonomous car now that drove as well as me, a human, that’s not worth it. Because on average, humans are not good drivers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CSzDnW"&gt;Yeah. So you’re saying with LIDAR or you’re saying without LIDAR, for example, just in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IRDqUE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just in general. As a goal, as a marker. We made a car, it doesn’t have a steering wheel, it can drive as well as the average person, probably.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iIURrd"&gt;Absolutely. No, 100 percent. Now, you have to start somewhere with it. But the point is, is that people aren’t going to stop there, it’s not going to be good enough. Good enough, at least in our view, is driving the 1.3 million lives lost every year. By the way, just putting that in perspective. That’s like in the same vicinity of the crazy pandemic that we’ve had over the past year, in terms of lives lost, and it happens every single year and it completely doesn’t discriminate against underlying conditions, or whatever. It’s insane how accepted this is, just in everyday life. And that’s where if we can have the opportunity to be able to solve for that and drive that towards zero, that’s the mission that we should be going towards, that we all need to be rallying around, as opposed to just the human level, that safety is rational. Now that’s not to say that, like I said, you’re going to be 10X better, or 100X better off the bat, but you’ve got to keep pushing for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PkxcOz"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So I cleverly opened the door to the Tesla conversation and you walked your way through it. So the reason I asked about foundational technologies, and I think the reason you brought up full self-driving or autopilot or whatever Tesla is going to call it, is Elon Musk, who I think his office is just out your back windows over there.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3INHOJ"&gt;I can see it right over across the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ejBIsS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He has famously said LIDAR is a local maximum, it’s the wrong approach. It’s going to hit some ceiling of performance and that’ll be that. And the right answer for vision in automobiles is having a bunch of cameras and doing it in software at a high rate. Next to that is the other thing you brought up, which is Google and Waymo saying, “We’re going to use a bunch of technologies, we’ll have an enormous amount of data that we’ll measure by miles driven, and we’ll collect all that data and we’ll run it through machine learning. And that is the correct approach.” And they’re very proud of that approach. But let’s start with Tesla, Elon Musk and the local maximum comment. Is his approach to just using a bunch of cameras, does that actually have a higher ceiling, or do you think that you can catch up to it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9IRIMy"&gt;So just a couple of things just to level-set with that. You gave the Waymo example here and the Tesla example. It’s all about, what problem are you trying to solve? Like, what application are you trying to enable? What feature set are you trying to enable? For example, from what Waymo is trying to enable, being able to build these robotaxis for urban use cases and solving for that, they’re absolutely doing the right thing. They’re doing everything step-by-step that you should do and executing on it, probably someone in the industry would argue better than anyone else. Which I’d agree with, or maybe at a quicker pace as it relates to that. Obviously you have to be conscious around what is the application and also what are the different subcomponents that are there, that it’s still a long road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QmTALT"&gt;There’s other things like higher performance LIDAR that help accelerate you there much more quickly and are something that you ultimately need to enable. But nevertheless, I think that’s the point for [an] urban robotaxi development program. When you take a look at something like Tesla, it’s again, how does what you build align with the product you’re trying to develop? And it’s the same thing about assisted driving systems versus autonomous driving systems. If you want to build a great assisted driving system, you should be doing exactly what they’re doing. Everything spot on, collect lots of data, build the model, build everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="veQMRE"&gt;Now arguably, their system was originally powered by Mobileye some time ago, as with pretty much all the other major automakers, they broke out from that. It was initially worse. Now it caught up to what Mobileye had. But this is nothing like, fundamentally, a breakthrough, or novel in the context of having an assisted driving system that does these things. The real challenge is when you try and cross a threshold and call things autonomous. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s6n0uB"&gt;But the reality is that the threshold for an assisted driving system versus an autonomous system, it’s orders of magnitude different. It’s not even kind of close. It really is a factor of... If you want to improve to a point of where it’s safer than a human level, where you would never need to take over, you need to take that disengagement rate from once every 20 miles to once every 2 million miles plus — disengagement meaning you have to take over the wheel to prevent otherwise some incident or accident like in the current assisted driving systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S7SAoa"&gt;So the whole point of where LIDAR comes into play is to solve that problem. Obviously anyone that tries to, or even just a single person that tries to promise that without irony, the hard part is, you back yourself into a corner if you’ve been saying the same thing for five years, and it will come out. It’s supposed to come out every year, the next year. But, I don’t want to have any respect loss for the incredible things that new players in the EV world and even folks like Tesla built and disrupted on the EV side, it’s absolutely fantastic. But at the same time when it comes to autonomy, we just need to make sure we get the terminology and what’s actually possible straight, because that’s ultimately beneficial to consumers. The last thing you want is people misusing the technology and thinking it’s capable of certain things when it’s not. So it’s a really hard problem. It’s a long way to go. Even with the best performing LIDAR, it’s still a long way to go, much less trying to make it a hundred times harder without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QGZpvk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You think it’s 100 times harder without LIDAR?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oXoVeR"&gt;That’s probably an underestimate. Now, okay, let’s clarify here. If you have a really low-performance LIDAR that only gives you like a handful of points out there in the environment, maybe it’s only incrementally more helpful. The whole point of the LIDAR is that it gives you a 3D map of everything around the world, in real time, you know exactly where every object is. The hard part with cameras alone is that they give you a 2D view of what’s going on. You never really know where the objects are. You effectively have to guess, and people have made software that gets better and better and better at guessing. And this is what Mobileye and what Tesla and these companies have been doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gDfWiw"&gt;But the thing is that it gets to a point of where you approach like 99 percent accuracy on it. Here’s the problem, even at 99 percent, they’re still not quite there. But even if you get there, it’s still not even remotely close to being good enough. You need like 10 nines worth of reliability in there. And it gets exponentially harder with each nine. It’s like, is it acceptable to run over one out of every 100 people because you didn’t see them and guess where it is? Any rational person would say no. And that would not make it anything close to the same safety threshold as a human. So that’s the whole point around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DURsUt"&gt;And the LIDAR, assuming you have really high performance, long range, high resolution, that you have to have to get a clear understanding of everything going on, but if you know exactly where everything is, like we do down to a centimeter level of precision, it makes all the difference. And there’s no question it’s like, “Yes, it’s another sensor on board the vehicles, but there’s a good reason why effectively every autonomous vehicle company has been going down this.” And to your question on data, there’s no question that more data and better data absolutely helps, but the whole point is when you have a more limited quality of data set, for example, with cameras, it absolutely tapers off in terms of the utility of it. Like even OEMs, the Mobileyes of this world, only use a really small fraction of that overall data that’s collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QRXGLY"&gt;And it has a marginal utility curve that only helps you so much. But let’s say, even if you were able to continue an amazing growth rate, like 50 percent improvement year over year for these kinds of systems, when you’re trying to solve a gap of like 10,000X in safety … it’d be like a century or two by the time you got there. So that’s the distinction. And that’s where I think there can often be a gap between the understanding of where this kind of... And I just mean more broadly, where autonomous-related technology is today and where it actually needs to get to, and how we successfully close that gap, because there is a huge gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2bj9XZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s put into context what you mean by LIDAR performance. So right now I think the easiest way for an average person to get a LIDAR sensor in their life is to go out and buy an iPhone. The Pro models of the iPhone have a LIDAR sensor on the back. They’re very small, but—&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fcEKAM"&gt;It’s so awesome, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7WPpim"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s cool that they’re there. They don’t do a whole lot. They help with some picture stuff, and there’s a bunch of AR gimmicks, but that’s how you can get a LIDAR sensor in your life. Just put the performance of the iPhone LIDAR sensor on a spectrum with what you’re hoping to achieve or what you’re building.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A7AgYd"&gt;Okay. So still, for example, an iPhone LIDAR sensor, you’re talking about seeing single-digit meters out into the distance. And of course in this case, it actually depends on whether it’s daylight outside, or whether it’s night. We have to see regardless of the condition, 250 meters out in the distance. So even if the sun is shining into the sensor. So you’re talking up to 100 times the range here of what you would see on an iPhone LIDAR, with orders of magnitude more resolution performance and something that’s in an auto grade mass producible device. By the way, it’s a square function. So the farther you go out, if you’re 100 times the distance, it actually requires exponentially more output power from a radiometry perspective of, you actually have to square that. So you’re talking like more on the order of 10,000 times the amount of performance that you have to have out of LIDAR just to be able to get that distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J3Nw6f"&gt;So that gives you a spectrum of comparison of why this is actually really, really hard. And by the way, you have to do all of this and see not just bright white reflective objects, but you have to see the really dark objects too. Because what happens if there’s a tire on the road, a black car, or a person in dark clothing, anything, those are actually really hard to see, to get light reflected off of, which makes it another 100 times harder too, than a bright white reflective object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NHUqQy"&gt;So these compound and compound. The whole point is there’s no off the shelf parts or components that you can buy for a LIDAR that enable you to do this today. It doesn’t exist. This is the whole point of why we had to actually build it entirely from the ground up, we had to make all of our own components, we had to solve for all of that in order to actually make this work. You have to do that again at the same time, while having to be economical enough that it’s not tens or hundreds of thousands of dollars to actually build, and to be able to put it into a production vehicle. So that was what we had to solve for. We were fortunate enough that we were able to, over that five-year period of really deep, intense work and meeting all those different, very stringent requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7U5Nw6"&gt;And yeah, I think that having that be commercialized into production vehicles, that’s the whole thing of what’s next, is that once you meet all those specs and once you get the commercial step right, it’s all about getting into serious production. And we were fortunate enough to be the first and only company to really be able to enable autonomy in the series production from these different programs out there, starting with Volvo and then cascading to some of the other OEMs that we’re working with as well. So it’ll be a good start. That gives you an idea around the performance of what it takes to make it commercially viable as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XbHXpc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I ask every self-driving car CEO this, and you don’t make cars, but I feel like you have a good handle on it. How long until I can buy a car without a steering wheel?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BKvXMd"&gt;Probably I would say early 2030s, realistically. A couple of different observations here. ... There’s a key distinction to that question of, when can you buy a car without a steering wheel? It’s not clear that people will actually be selling these cars without steering wheels. If you get to a point where you don’t have to have a steering wheel, then it likely will be deployed in a more robotaxi-type application initially as it scales up and then ultimately be offered to consumers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZqixTy"&gt;But here’s the thing, is that interestingly enough from a regulatory perspective, it actually gets a lot more complicated when you start ripping out steering wheels, changing all the different functionalities of the core of the vehicles to be able to establish what you could see for a futuristic version of autonomy on these cars versus just enabling autonomous capabilities on existing production vehicles. And that’s going to take some time. I would say, in theory you could probably buy a car without a steering wheel, that’d take you from point A to point B in a more limited geographic capacity, by between 2025 and 2030. But the question is, would you really want that, would you buy a car that can only take you to certain limited destinations, and it’s safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RSvNVV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I feel like there’s a lot of people who would move farther away from New York or San Francisco if they had a car that could reliably and quickly move them back and forth from work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nagv9Z"&gt;Absolutely. But here’s the thing, that’s the whole point of exactly what we’re doing for 2022, not even 2030, 2022 on these different production vehicle platforms, is enabling highway autonomy. The whole point is, you take your car, let’s say you’re living out farther into the suburbs there and commuting into the city, take your car, manually drive over to the freeway. Once you’re on it, engage autonomous mode, hands-off, eyes-off, and be able to recover that time ...everything from using your phone to taking a nap, and then a few minutes before the final exit, have a planned manual takeover and then drive to the final destination. And that’s that hybrid of a problem and a solution there. Whereas if you eliminate the steering wheel altogether, then it’s only going to be able to work on whatever routes that it’s effectively pre-programmed to be able to work on. And that’s going to be a much tougher distinction there as it relates to that. So this is just going to be a normal car otherwise, that you can also use any day, anytime. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Auxq6x"&gt;It also has dramatically improved safety because it will now actively take over in an instance where it’s predicting an accident could occur as well, which is something that really hasn’t been seen before on vehicles. And another really interesting aspect of how you can start saving all these lives without having autonomy. You don’t have to have autonomy everywhere to start doing that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4HctLF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve got a handful of big partners, Audi, Volvo — which of those companies should we see Luminar technology in first, in a shipping product?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4IH6W"&gt;You know, Volvo is certainly there first with these programs. We’re driving towards basically a start of production with the programs sort of around the corner next year in 2022; by the end of that we should be able to deliver this autonomous solution that can be enabled, or really, I should say, these LIDAR-enabled vehicles here. Those are things that you can actually buy, and that is a key distinction when it comes down to it. So it’s something that is definitely going to be the first to market in terms of any level of autonomous capabilities that are functional and tangible as well, for that matter, by consumers or otherwise. So it’ll be exciting to help enable that to happen. We have a host of other great partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tJJ06A"&gt;Even most recently, just in the second half of this last year, over the past handful of months, [we] announced Daimler trucks as a lead partner on the truck side, just as Volvo is a lead partner on the car side. And then also Mobileye is a lead ecosystem partner, including their foray into robotaxis as well, which I think is going to be super promising. So that’s where we’re delivering against, but Volvo really helps set the clock for everybody. And frankly, a lot of the rest of the industry timing-wise, from our product perspective and how we scale that into the rest of the other OEMs. But I think they’ve had a really strong safety and brand focus around this and just see this as too critical to be able to mess around with, and be able to have the best technology and the best program and make it economical for their vehicles. So it’s going to continue to get better and better over time, via over the air software updates. But it’s certainly going to be a great start to the whole new era of autonomy in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fCcXEU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So we’ve had this long conversation about how you started the company very early, very young. You were in stealth for a long time. You came out of stealth, you announced you have a product. Now you’re a public company CEO at a remarkably young age, for a lot of people, that’s the whole startup journey. You did the whole thing. Is that done for you? Do you see another stage of this journey that isn’t... Like most startup founders when they get here, they start to get antsy, but I’m wondering if you’re feeling that or not.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9LwEn8"&gt;I think it’s a good, and reasonable question, for any founder along the way. And I think there’s some folks that scale better than others at different parts of the journey, you have different types of personalities along the way. A lot of times early on founders, CEOs, will go and take a more technologically or R&amp;amp;D-focused role along the way or not really handle the business side of the equation with this. At least for me personally, the way that I’ve always seen it is that you have to have a system-level technological solution as well as a really strong business case and mentality if you want to be able to see this build and successfully scale.  A lot of the great entrepreneurs of our era, the Zuckerbergs of this world, or even the Bezoses, took their companies up to this point and scaled them incredibly well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZkCvy"&gt;And I think that’s where... I have a similar mentality and drive and desire to be able to build ultimately to that level and scale of this kind of company. And I mean, certainly if there’s any industry that’s ripe for disruption, has the ability to enable this as a trillion-dollar space, and is evolving, it is autonomy, and that’s where absolutely we’re going to be continuing to drive towards. So it’s a good question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODMvcI"&gt;The most important thing is you bring in the key and relevant top-notch, A-plus team members on board to be able to successfully execute. You can have the best vision on the planet, and just the best strategy, the best product, the best commercial landscape, but you need to execute still. We still have a lot of stuff to execute on, and that’s where we make sure to get just rock star team members from across the board to be able to do exactly that. And whereas a lot of entrepreneurs, maybe you see [an] IPO as like the end of the journey, you’re talking about phase one, phase two, all of this. All of this was our phase one. Now we’re onto phase two. So that’s where it really is the beginning of a long journey. Being on the younger side, I’m in a fortunate position a lot of times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUAEoX"&gt;I think when talking about different public companies out there, a lot of times you have CEOs that only plan to have a tenure on the order of like five years or whatever it may be. I think [I’m] in a fortunate enough position — I’m probably the youngest public company CEO — to be able to have a time horizon and a vision more on the order of 50 years than five years. As we see this through, I don’t plan on, frankly, doing anything different. Now the scope of what Luminar will do, we will expand over time, but we have the time. And you just take it step by step and be absolutely committed 100 percent to see it all the way through, until every car has these kinds of autonomous capabilities and is accelerated by way of being powered by Luminar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nE23OZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I very much look forward to the interview we do when you’re 75 and I’m 90, and I play clips from this interview back at you. That’s going to be a good time. Well, Austin, it’s been terrific to have you on &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decoder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. I look forward to talking to you much more as time goes on. I personally cannot wait to have a car that will drive into New York City. So hurry up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="W20b7A"&gt;Fantastic. Yeah, that’ll be awesome. All right. Well, thanks so much for having me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SX1Qgc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="bhdyQP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Decoder with Nilay Patel&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;","description":"A new podcast from The Verge about big ideas and other problems.","label":"Subscribe now!","url":"https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/decoder-with-nilay-patel/id1011668648?i=1000496212371"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22298001/luminar-austin-russel-ceo-interview-self-driving-cars"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22298001/luminar-austin-russel-ceo-interview-self-driving-cars</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Glitch workers sign tech’s first collective bargaining agreement </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fZWU-wCMiE133EKoePt9gv5eNHc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68896723/acastro_210301_4454_glitch_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aP4HV5"&gt;Glitch workers have signed a collective bargaining agreement with the company — a historic milestone for the tech industry. The contract, which was ratified overwhelmingly by union members, will last for 11 months. It’s the first agreement signed by white collar tech workers in the United States, according to a press release from the Communications Workers of America (CWA). The contract went into effect on February 28th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BmBWwq"&gt;The agreement — a legal contract between the union and the company — does not include higher wages, which weren’t a focus for union members. Union representatives say they might try to include these in a future contract, but for now they recognize that Glitch is a small startup operating during a pandemic with pay and benefits that are already generous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hAhWkH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The agreement ensures “just cause” protections for Glitch employees&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H1yiVe"&gt;The agreement does include significant working protections, as well as codifying the benefits that currently exist. Among other measures, the agreement ensures “just cause” protections for Glitch employees — meaning workers can only be fired or disciplined through a specific process. That’s particularly important in the United States, where most employment contracts are at-will. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cv5nHE"&gt;It also establishes recall rights for employees laid off during the pandemic, a provision specifically aimed at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21268007/glitch-layoffs-substantial-number-coding-platform-union"&gt;18 people Glitch laid off in May&lt;/a&gt;. Glitch must now offer those employees their jobs back if it plans to rehire for the positions, according to the agreement. At the time, the company said it had to “significantly cut operating costs” due to the pandemic. On Twitter, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anildash/status/1263942626178449409"&gt;CEO Anil Dash emphasized that it was an economic decision&lt;/a&gt;, and not one that reflected the value of the employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="c7iIyT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We didn’t want to hamstring Glitch”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EU3Gic"&gt;“There’s a lot of fear that you can’t be nimble with a union in the tech industry, but this shows there are ways to do it,” says Sheridan Kates, a senior software engineer and bargaining committee representative. “We have an 11-month contract, we didn’t focus on wages and benefits. We didn’t want to hamstring Glitch. We wanted to see ourselves as partners with management and codify the things that are important to us as a union.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aj8iYk"&gt;The news comes nearly a year after Glitch workers voted to unionize with the Communications Workers of America Local 1101. After 90 percent of employees indicated their support, the union was voluntarily recognized by Glitch management. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vM402d"&gt;It’s a stark contrast to companies like Amazon and Kickstarter, which have gone to great lengths to discourage employees from unionizing. In Alabama, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287191/amazon-alabama-warehouse-union-traffic-light-change-bessemer"&gt;Amazon has been running a brutal anti-union campaign for months&lt;/a&gt; as warehouse workers in Bessemer organize. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://slate.com/technology/2019/09/kickstarter-union-organizing.html"&gt;Kickstarter fired two highly visible union organizers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BctFZp"&gt;Food service workers in the tech industry have been able to secure union contracts, however. In 2018, Facebook cafeteria workers ratified their first agreement, winning higher wages for contractors.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jj1REy"&gt;Kates says the company’s decision to voluntarily recognize the union changed how each side went into contract negotiations. “Having voluntary recognition helped us not have to go into this in an adversarial way,” she says. “We recognized that we were coming to the table from a place of wanting to do right by each other.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1aWltD"&gt;It’s a point of view shared by Dash, who says voluntary recognition was a positive experience for both sides. “For us, it was very effective and we were very aligned,” Dash tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “I’m really glad that’s the case and I’m glad that was our workers’ experience.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q7Io6f"&gt;News of the agreement comes amid a rush of organizing activity in the tech industry. In January, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/04/technology/google-employees-union.html"&gt;workers at Google formed a solidarity union&lt;/a&gt; in affiliation with CWA. The following month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278684/medium-union-unionizing-communications-workers-america"&gt;Medium workers announced plans to unionize as well&lt;/a&gt; (the organization recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307415/medium-union-effort-stalls-one-vote-short-majority-cwa"&gt;failed to win majority support in a third-party election&lt;/a&gt; and is momentarily pausing organizing activities). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="621xFj"&gt;The Kickstarter union, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/kickstarter-workers-vote-form-first-union-tech-industry-n1138006"&gt;which won a hard-fought election in February 2020&lt;/a&gt;, is still negotiating its first contract. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22307671/glitch-workers-sign-historic-collective-bargaining-agreement-cwa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22307671/glitch-workers-sign-historic-collective-bargaining-agreement-cwa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Volvo’s second electric vehicle will be the slimmed down C40 Recharge </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r6TUocodqVuI8iMIvEH_3iO_Deo=/937x0:8617x5120/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68896805/03_Volvo_C40Recharge_profile_driving.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mDQSqL"&gt;The Volvo XC40 Recharge is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195499/volvo-xc40-recharge-ev-suv-first-drive-specs-price"&gt;barely out of the gate&lt;/a&gt; and the Swedish automaker is already unveiling its next electric vehicle. The C40 Recharge is only Volvo’s second pure battery-electric car. A slightly shorter and more streamlined version of the XC40 Recharge, the C40 Recharge will be built on the same modular platform as the automaker’s first EV and will go into production at Volvo’s Ghent, Belgium, factory in fall 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NmzNLa"&gt;Volvo says that the C40 Recharge “has all the benefits of an SUV but with a lower and sleeker design.” The roof line is lower and the rear portion tapers off more gradually than the XC40 Recharge. The most significant difference is the height, with the C40 Recharge measuring a full three inches shorter than its predecessor. Volvo won’t go so far as to call it a hatchback or wagon, but it does appear to share some characteristics with Volvo’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.volvocars.com%2Fmm%2Fcars%2Fnew-models%2Fv40&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F2%2F22307699%2Fvolvo-c40-recharge-electric-vehicle-ev-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;discontinued V40&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8IP6Xc"&gt;The release of the C40 Recharge gets Volvo one step closer to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/16/20915841/volvo-xc40-recharge-electric-suv-specs-miles-range-reveal"&gt;goal of electrifying half of its lineup by 2025&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier today, Volvo said it would go &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308851/volvo-electric-cars-only-2030-online-sales"&gt;100 percent electric by 2030&lt;/a&gt;. The automaker has also said it will slash the life-cycle carbon footprint — effectively the CO2 emissions the car will produce during its life with both manufacturing and usage taken into account — on each car by 40 percent by the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tuWASr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;one step closer to its goal of electrifying half of its lineup by 2025&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IvqZEp"&gt;The C40 Recharge is estimated to get the same range — 210 miles based on the EPA’s standard or 420km based on Europe’s WLTP — as the XC40 Recharge. Volvo says that range will improve with over-the-air software updates in the future. Will the price be the same as the XC40 Recharge, too? We don’t know yet because Volvo is not releasing that information at this time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yz0LJB"&gt;Volvo also didn’t provide any images of the interior, but we can probably assume it won’t be too different from the XC40 Recharge. The company says the C40 Recharge’s infotainment software will be powered by Android Automotive, meaning it will use popular apps like Google Maps and Google Assistant as its default features. This is also similar to the XC40 Recharge and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21365032/polestar-2-hands-on-first-drive-electric-android-automotive-photos-range"&gt;Polestar 2&lt;/a&gt; from Volvo and parent company Geely’s joint performance brand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="raBKCL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10368359"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zv2VJm"&gt;The C40 Recharge will run on two electric motors, one in the front and one in the rear of the vehicle. A 78kWh battery pack — 75kWh of which is usable — powers the dual-motor powertrain with a total of 402 horsepower and a 0-to-60 mph time of 4.7 seconds. The headlights are brand new as well, featuring “state-of-the-art” pixel technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X9CYGT"&gt;The battery charges from zero to 80 percent of its capacity in 40 minutes on a 150kWh/DC fast-charger system, the automaker claims. On an AC charger with 11kWh, the C40 Recharge’s battery will take eight hours to get to 80 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bgdUQO"&gt;Car dealers have been known to be reluctant to stock and sell electric cars for years, and Volvo aims to sidestep this issue by offering the new C40 Recharge for sale online only. The automaker &lt;a href="https://www.media.volvocars.com/global/en-gb/media/pressreleases/271095/volvo-cars-aims-to-transform-retail-business-with-integrated-onlineoffline-consumer-experience"&gt;has also said&lt;/a&gt; it aims to sell 50 percent of its global volume online by 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qLeSjK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;online only&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="35LPzD"&gt;Hopefully, the C40 Recharge will be able to avoid some of the software problems of its predecessors. Yesterday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;reported that an unknown number of XC40 Recharge SUV deliveries were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307866/volvo-xc40-recharge-delay-software-update-on-call-ota"&gt;delayed by a crucial software update&lt;/a&gt; that was keeping them held up at US ports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zN0zRj"&gt;Among its bold environmental pledges, Volvo has also said it will reduce the carbon output of its entire operations by 25 percent, including its suppliers, also by 2025. If everything goes according to plan, the amount of recycling and reuse of materials in Volvo’s supply chain will dramatically increase. By 2025, Volvo expects every vehicle to contain 25 percent recycled material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GovFf9"&gt;Since Volvo made its pledge to electrify half of its lineup, other automakers have upped the ante. GM said it would only sell electric vehicles by 2040, while Ford recently announced it would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287284/ford-electric-vehicles-ev-europe-2030"&gt;EV-only in Europe by 2030&lt;/a&gt;. The Volkswagen Group, which owns Audi, Skoda, Porsche, and others, says its entire lineup will be electric or hybrid by 2026.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22307699/volvo-c40-recharge-electric-vehicle-ev-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22307699/volvo-c40-recharge-electric-vehicle-ev-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Teams is getting end-to-end encryption support</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W835pV5bzKoOwTWj96bGTsuawEo=/0x0:2640x1760/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68896738/microsoftteams.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jwBRd3"&gt;Microsoft is finally adding end-to-end encryption support to Microsoft Teams later this year. A preview of end-to-end encryption in Teams will be available in the first half of this year for commercial customers. It will be available for 1:1 unscheduled Teams calls and is designed for more sensitive conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yda2vk"&gt;This will mostly be useful for confidential conversations between employees or for scenarios like an IT admin providing an employee their password over a call. The initial preview will be limited to 1:1 unscheduled calls, but Microsoft plans to expand this to scheduled calls and online meetings over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VJpFJa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A preview will be available for commercial customers first&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H1BOJR"&gt;Currently, Microsoft Teams does not support end-to-end encryption for meetings. Data is encrypted in transit and at rest, and this allows authorized services to decrypt content for data retention record purposes. Microsoft currently uses SharePoint encryption to secure at-rest files and OneNote encryption for notes stored in Microsoft Teams. All chat content in Teams is also encrypted in transit and at rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kNGO5X"&gt;Microsoft Teams’ main competitor, Slack, doesn’t use end-to-end encryption, either. Zoom started to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/27/21535818/zoom-end-to-end-encryption-e2ee-security-privacy-video-conferencing"&gt;implement the technology in October&lt;/a&gt; and is gradually adding more features to its preview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DjiHFr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308915/microsoft-teams-end-to-end-encryption-support-e2ee"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308915/microsoft-teams-end-to-end-encryption-support-e2ee</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Teams will soon let you pretend to be a news reporter during meetings</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6FA0CdIZ75rvrOVliFeMpSQY8eo=/106x0:1365x839/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68896716/Presenter_Mode___Weatherperson.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Teams is getting a new presenter mode.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BkqUhd"&gt;Microsoft Teams is trying to make video calls a little less boring during the pandemic era of remote working with new presenter modes. These allow you to customize how you appear when you’re presenting in Teams. Three new modes will be available soon, including a “Reporter” option that lets you place content above your shoulder as a visual aid, much like a news anchor during a TV segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3msx9b"&gt;Standout mode lets you float above content as a silhouette on top of a slide deck. And the third option, Side-by-side, displays your webcam feed alongside content you’re presenting. Standout will roll out this month, with Reporter and Side-by-side modes available soon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w1iybbhFKDk7cmxvuZNYpu_fjvo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22339342/presentermode.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Teams’ new presenter mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YS9FfE"&gt;All three modes are part of a bigger push from Microsoft to respond to feedback around making meetings more engaging during remote work. “The way I look at it now, is we need to make presentations more like TV shows,” says Nicole Herskowitz, general manager of Microsoft Teams, in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We really have to find ways to make those digital experiences more powerful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBaDpM"&gt;These new modes take advantage of the technology that Microsoft uses in its Together Mode to remove all the background behind you on a webcam. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/8/21317526/microsoft-teams-together-mode-dynamic-view-new-features"&gt;Together Mode was one of the first big changes to Teams&lt;/a&gt; designed for pandemic meetings, placing meeting participants side by side in a virtual environment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ynk3OyN7g6HwiEY2V3Hpp5qQTYs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22339344/koMfeMI.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PowerPoint Live in Microsoft Teams.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="U0rSK6"&gt;Alongside the new presenter modes, Microsoft is also launching PowerPoint Live in Microsoft Teams today. It’s designed to make presenting with PowerPoint slides a lot easier for both the presenter and meeting participants. Presenters will now be able to see notes, slides, and a meeting chat all in a single view, and attendees can navigate the slides themselves. That’s great if you missed a particular slide and want to skip back, and it’s a huge boost to accessibility for those with learning disabilities who want to read and learn at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308927/microsoft-teams-presenter-mode-powerpoint-live-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308927/microsoft-teams-presenter-mode-powerpoint-live-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Intelligent Speakers deliver its promised meeting room of the future</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FseQSREtYszQ8XLevrXQU-qpqss=/0x11:2022x1359/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68896712/intelligentspeaker.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s new Intelligent Speakers.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BLm9M9"&gt;Microsoft demonstrated prototype hardware a few years ago that promised meeting rooms of the future with automatic speaker identification, transcription, and even translation. Microsoft now claims it’s delivering this for real with new Intelligent Speakers, small puck-like devices that can identify up to 10 different voices in a Microsoft Teams meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AHzsvY"&gt;These speakers will automatically generate a transcript during a meeting, with individual identification of those speaking. They will also help remote attendees follow along and see who’s talking in a meeting. Microsoft has teamed up with Yealink and Epos to create the hardware, and it even supports translation if you want to follow a meeting in a different language.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rUB9-9apKin1BF7JYCbBD_PdCbo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22339364/intelligentspeakers.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;These Intelligent Speakers identify who is speaking and automatically transcribe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EtnozL"&gt;Microsoft first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/7/17327596/microsoft-meeting-room-demo-build-2018"&gt;demonstrated a concept for this exact scenario at Build in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Although these devices were clearly originally designed for a time before the pandemic, they could help bridge the frustrating gap of working remotely and trying to participate in and follow in-person meetings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UMRKzs"&gt;Microsoft hasn’t announced pricing or exact availability just yet, but the company’s Surface Hub is also certified as a device capable of being an Intelligent Speaker. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308962/microsoft-intelligent-speaker-teams-translation-transcription-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308962/microsoft-intelligent-speaker-teams-translation-transcription-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
