<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-29T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>A new wave of lo-fi games is reshaping horror</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jZk_ucYrLUYRnBo3mikdqLOCEr8=/200x0:2360x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70063156/If_on_a_WInter_s_Night_Four_Travelers_alt.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If on a Winter’s Night Four Travelers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Indie developers are turning pixels into scares&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="I2bUwl"&gt;Something writhes in video game horror’s dark underbelly; it has been doing so for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="81ooOV"&gt;But lately, convulsions have grown violent and the hideous mass threatens to spill over into the mainstream where more respectable nightmares reign. The likes of &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Alan Wake&lt;/em&gt; are now adhering to the same rules governing spectacle as the latest &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; installment, terrifying you at pristine 4K resolutions. This is the ninth console generation currently shaping our entertainment landscape, after all, and there are certain expectations as regards visual fidelity. Have you seen how the sun’s rays reflect on Castle Dimitrescu’s marble floors?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZJa2Ct"&gt;New retro horror scoffs at such notions of verisimilitude. It will draw the curtains to keep volumetric lighting out and puke all over the exquisite tiling so you’re not distracted by its intricate patterns. A steady procession of brash alternatives to the handful of dominating franchises (as well as the mid-budget imitations) has been making its presence felt recently. These games are inspired by long-obsolete genres implementing unconventional mechanics and evoking memories from the medium’s rich past. Wildly divergent, this new generation of lo-fi horror games is united by a shared philosophy: treating earlier, era-specific styles from the crude polygons of the original PlayStation to 1-bit monochrome palettes not as intermediary failures on the path to some dubious ideal of “realism,” but embracing them as valid aesthetic springboards in their own right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B3XMRJ"&gt;And people have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21120144/world-of-horror-steam-panstasz-lovecraft-early-access-launch-preview"&gt;paying attention&lt;/a&gt;. In the last couple of years, the scene has exploded. Puppet Combo — who has been turning his favorite childhood VHS slashers into low-poly gore-fests for about a decade — has just started his own production company, &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/search/?publisher=Torture%20Star%20Video"&gt;Torture Star Video&lt;/a&gt;, mobilizing his popularity to highlight the talents of other creators in the niche. Two ongoing anthology series, &lt;a href="https://hauntedps1.itch.io/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Haunted PS1 Demo Disc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/bundle/18324/Dread_X_Collection_Year_1_Bundle/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dread X Collection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, have revitalized a format oddly neglected in the medium. And themed game jams have imposed time and theme constraints on developers consistently producing some of the most imaginative work in the field, exemplified by Teebowah’s Game Boy-inspired creepy excursion in &lt;a href="https://teebowah-games.itch.io/fishing-vacation"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fishing Vacation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Ben Jelter’s trailer-park enigma of &lt;a href="https://benjelter.itch.io/opossum-country"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opossum Country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But what has prompted the sudden surge of popularity for such archaic iconography? And why the disproportionate focus of such efforts on horror?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JzvMpsagW7JGwDW7WdChDw_g76w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22962894/Dread_Delusion_alt.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dread Delusion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nOlwNT"&gt;A partial answer to the first question is glaringly obvious. Nostalgia has emerged as a pervasive cultural force in the last decade, from synthwave YouTube playlists to &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt;. Why should gaming be exempt from its influence? Under the alias -IZMA-, Adam Birch released &lt;a href="https://izma.itch.io/deadeus"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadeus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the Game Boy in 2019, a Lovecraftian small-town mystery in the vein of classic JRPGs. He admits nostalgia is part of what motivates him. “When I was a kid growing up, I had a Game Boy and had friends with Mega Drives and SNES. That era is seared into my brain because of [these consoles]. It stands to reason that, when people finally achieve the ability, they’d attempt to make games similar to those that made them fall in love with it all in the first place.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P3Myy6"&gt;The generational angle is certainly consistent with the timeline of the phenomenon. Roughly a decade separates the establishment of pixel art as a viable aesthetic even for mainstream games (such as the 2011 iOS hit &lt;em&gt;Superbrothers: Sword &amp;amp; Sworcery EP&lt;/em&gt; which sold more than a million copies) from the crude polygons and grainy video currently in the ascendant. The time span neatly corresponds to the gap between the heyday of the 8-bit platforms referenced by the former and the release of Sony’s groundbreaking PS1 console that inspires the latter — or the period during which a new crop of indie developers could have come of age. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="LA5Ilz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There’s also something about the tactility of physical media which is gratifying.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F2jX9A"&gt;James Wragg, creator of standout &lt;em&gt;Haunted PS1 Demo Disc&lt;/em&gt; entry &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1574240/Dread_Delusion/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dread Delusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, corroborates, albeit with an important caveat. “A lot of it is nostalgia, sure — the PlayStation start-up music will forever stimulate a cluster of neurons in my head. [But] there’s also something about the tactility of physical media which is gratifying; just as book lovers will relish the smell of a new book, flipping through a manual before you pop a disc in a PS1 drive is a more enticing ritual than clicking a ‘download’ button.” Nostalgia may be a universal impulse, but its siren call is most effective when it responds to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/02/smarter-living/why-we-romanticize-the-past.html"&gt;a certain lack&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0qW6LY"&gt;Birch believes the lack is not so much about the paraphernalia that used to accompany a game’s packaging (even as he catered to that need by also releasing &lt;em&gt;Deadeus&lt;/em&gt; as a physical cartridge) but of a sufficiently diverse range of stories and experiences within the blockbuster sphere. “It has almost become a cliche that there will be a bloated overworld map with 1,000 similar tasks and some watchtower to climb. This on top of a climbing price tag and an almost ‘safe’ approach to subject matter all paves the way for completely off-the-wall, cheaper indie games to go down some dark story paths and fill the void.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RGMkO-ymgBSN-2ClulNWI99mbAY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22962898/FAITH.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faith.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ispzvr1UwH34vvGhcZD14DIB_hI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22962899/FAITH_alt.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faith.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lVJpka"&gt;As for developers, a different sort of lack may account for new retro horror’s appeal: the ability to compete with big-budget spectacle. “Using low-poly models or creating 1-bit visuals is a much more sensible option for most indie devs who might be more interested in telling a story or inducing specific feelings than in movie-realistic graphics,” says Laura Hunt, co-creator of the decidedly unrealistic but visually stunning cosmic-horror adventure &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1603980/If_On_A_Winters_Night_Four_Travelers/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;If On A Winter’s Night, Four Travelers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While she has worked on perennial favorite Adventure Game Studio, a wider range of accessible specialist tools are increasingly facilitating the creation of perfect simulacra of a Commodore 64 or an SNES title. Birch even acknowledges that the genre and mood of &lt;em&gt;Deadeus&lt;/em&gt; were shaped by the limitations of GB Studio, the engine he experimented with while developing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wsf7T"&gt;While arguments based on generational nostalgia apply equally to most retro-styled games, the growing availability of intuitive middleware points to an aspect of the phenomenon that is more horror-specific. Ted Hentschke, the mind behind the &lt;em&gt;Dread X Collection &lt;/em&gt;project, believes that, as with the flood of found-footage movies that followed &lt;em&gt;Paranormal Activity&lt;/em&gt;’s wide release in 2009, “the current popularity of retro-styled horror games has less to do with nostalgia than it does with the idea that any one of us can do it. When you look at Airdorf’s &lt;a href="https://airdorf.itch.io/faith"&gt;&lt;em&gt;FAITH&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, that little pixel guy walking around, it doesn’t seem impossible that I could do that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="BqzH43"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They can prime the player’s mind to be surprised and creeped out.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2pr6Cq"&gt;There’s a reason for that. &lt;em&gt;Faith&lt;/em&gt; may be one of the most famous titles in the scene, an exorcism simulator that put to rest any silly notions that pixel art can’t scare the wits out of you, but it looks as if it could run on a 1982 Atari console. Mason Smith, better known as Airdorf, has an explanation for the capacity for such unorthodox visuals to unsettle that circles back to the blockbuster-fatigue argument. “Since retro-styled graphics have this innocent lo-fi quality to them, I think they can prime the player’s mind to be surprised and creeped out when the game goes after the player themselves, more so than your advanced 3D graphics.” While the homogeneity of marquee franchises will put off a segment of the audience in any genre, it is horror that, by its very nature, thrives on the unexpected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W7eFV0"&gt;This framing also serves to illuminate a deeper link between new retro horror and the cursed-media fad manifesting in the form of &lt;em&gt;Ringu&lt;/em&gt;-inspired movies, explicitly meta games (such as Ivan Zanotti’s &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/429720/IMSCARED/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imscared&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and umpteen creepypasta threads. As &lt;em&gt;Faith&lt;/em&gt; oscillates between pixel-art gameplay and jarringly incongruous rotoscoped cutscenes, the latter are so much more obviously advanced that they generate an impression of the game clambering up the ontological ladder and coming alive. Airdorf concedes that “although it was never meant to be a ‘cursed’ meta-game, I still admired the long-lasting effects those had on players. There are a few details that came from the ‘cursed’ game phenomenon, like the chromatic aberration effect that glitches the screen a little bit when something spooky happens.” Paradoxically, the flexibility of retro visuals allows for a broader arsenal of scares than the mandates of realism dictating the direction of big-budget horror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5U3OXg"&gt;At the same time, the question arises whether, with an expanding fan base and the arrival of the PS1 as an in-vogue reference point, the scene is inching toward an impasse. The long-running appeal of pixel art has already led to it being assimilated into the mainstream and, to some degree, stripped of its power to surprise. Could that be the future for other strains of new retro horror? More fundamentally, while people will always feel a personal sense of nostalgia for the console they grew up with, the PS1 was arguably the last piece of hardware to effect deep cultural change while introducing an instantly recognizable iconography. It is not that it’s too early to adopt, say, an Xbox 360 aesthetic; it’s that the very notion of it seems inconceivable. It is not unreasonable to suspect that we are running out of distinct visual styles to reclaim from the medium’s history, but whether that spells doom for the movement as a creative endeavor remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SHFTJy"&gt;Wragg offers a thoughtful rebuttal. “Like impressionism in painting, the PS1 style portrays reality through the subjective vision of an artist. With smaller budgets and less at stake, these artists are free to create worlds that are surreal, strange, or uniquely beautiful in a way that you might not see in the mainstream industry. The intentional jankiness of the scene is like when punk music incorporates noise and reverb, a postmodern acceptance of the seams and imperfections within art that becomes part of the artwork itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="4GIsmA"&gt;In this light, it’s not the fondness for a particular era’s visuals that defines this haphazard movement whose instruments of revolution consist of blocky pixels, garish colors, and a whole lot of visual static. Instead, it’s the impetus to seek a language of creative expression outside accepted conventions. New retro horror is just the latest iteration of that never-ending quest. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22750586/lo-fi-retro-horror-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22750586/lo-fi-retro-horror-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Chatziioannou</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T11:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to make a modern slasher movie</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JT5lr-wG-JXn7MsGwuybaFZ8FYA=/0x2:7952x5303/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062845/TSIYH_20190829_01578r.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s Someone Inside Your House.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: David Bukach / Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="InoNQm"&gt;When Stephanie Perkins sat down to write her first horror novel, &lt;em&gt;There’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Someone Inside Your House&lt;/em&gt;, she looked somewhere very specific for inspiration: slasher movies. “I loved those movies as a teenager, and they had a huge influence on me,” she says. “There actually aren’t a ton of slashers in novel form, and I learned while trying to write one that there’s a pretty good reason for that: it’s a really visual and auditory medium.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MFEeGa"&gt;The book tells the story of a killer in a small Nebraska town who loves a gruesome murder and centers on high school student Makani, who recently moved from Hawaii for a fresh start after a tragic incident. The book has since been turned into a slasher movie itself, which debuted this month on Netflix. &lt;em&gt;There’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Someone Inside Your House&lt;/em&gt; is part of a resurgence for the subgenre — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579993/fear-street-netflix-horror-trilogy-summer-movie"&gt;earlier this year, Netflix turned a &lt;em&gt;Fear Street&lt;/em&gt; trilogy into a summer movie event&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722404/scream-smart-home-locks-phones-apps-horror"&gt;classic franchises like &lt;em&gt;Scream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Halloween&lt;/em&gt; are making a comeback — and it’s a great example of how slashers are being updated for modern audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CrnYBq"&gt;First, the big question: just what is it that makes slashers in particular so enduring? The genre is best exemplified by iconic characters like Jason Vorhees and Michael Myers, who came into existence in the late ’70s and early ’80s and expanded to classics like &lt;em&gt;Candyman&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Child’s Play&lt;/em&gt;. For Perkins, what makes slashers work so well, and what has made them popular for so long, is that they’re the most approachable form of horror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E4H6Yv"&gt;“There’s this catharsis and a space to explore dark ideas,” she explains. “One of the things that I personally get out of the slasher genre is that it typically comes with a good sense of humor, and there’s often a romantic element to it as well. Even if it’s your baseline ‘teen couple having sex.’ Those elements — the humor and the romance — they tend to provide a pretty good balance and make it a good entry point for people who maybe don’t consume a lot of horror. I really feel like slashers are horror-light, and they tend to have a broader audience because of that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="udRwV8"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IdZ43OuZXjQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pHvRWD"&gt;Henry Gayden, the screenwriter for the film adaptation of &lt;em&gt;There’s Someone Inside Your House&lt;/em&gt;, adds that “[t]he other component that makes them endure is the age range of the characters in them. Usually — not always — they’re teenagers. And I think that’s for a reason. The ones that really endure are usually somewhat coming of age stories.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oz5NNA"&gt;The trick to making a new one, he says, is finding a hook to set it apart from the many, many blood-soaked slashers from the last few decades. (As part of preparing to adapt the novel, Gayden says he watched 153 different slasher movies for research, from genre-defining titles to more obscure and forgotten fare.) In the case of &lt;em&gt;There’s Someone Inside Your House&lt;/em&gt;, there are a few things the movie tries to do differently. One is pulled directly from the source material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="3o5tlA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10834353"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hknVve"&gt;“What really made me want to write a slasher movie was the way Stephanie wrote the book,” he says. “Most slasher movies, with the exception of the big ones — &lt;em&gt;Halloween&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Scream&lt;/em&gt; — don’t really have memorable characters, don’t really care about emotional investment. What her book brought was that background into a genre that doesn’t usually have feelings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vaK9wX"&gt;This, in turn, connected to the most fun part of the genre: the kills. Gayden was able to not only come up with inventive and gruesome ways for characters to die but also find ways for those deaths to connect to the hidden secrets that caused them to be targeted in the first place. (In an unsettling twist, the movie’s killer wears a 3D printed mask of the impending victim.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RYi7Ad"&gt;“I wrote the first two set-pieces first because I wanted to figure out the tone and make them scary and funny if I could,” Gayden says of the process for coming up with kills. “I wanted to have something emotional in those two, which is why I brought this idea of not only are you killed by someone, but you’re going to be killed by someone who knows the one thing about you that you don’t want anyone else to know. And when you die, they’re going to tell the world about it. Not only that, they’re wearing your face.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wGI-HFbg19TvFq4DLFP1qqG2ZCg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964519/TSIYH_20190830_02063r2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: David Bukach / Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s Someone Inside Your House.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XKWGrG"&gt;For the original novel, Perkins had a slightly different mandate for the deaths. “What’s the grossest way that I can do this? That’s what I was genuinely interested in,” she says. “For me, that was the most fun part. It’s like a cartoon level of violence; it’s not something we typically see in the real world. So as someone who watches lots and lots of horror, I really do get — as terrible as it might sound — really excited to see cool deaths.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2Oqept"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’ve always been afraid of the same things.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XaoeDN"&gt;One of the great things about horror is how the core element — the scares — often stands the test of time. The classics persist because they still have the ability to frighten, even if they’re lacking in modern special effects. The slasher movie canon is filled with movies that are almost timeless in a strange, blood-soaked way. And Perkins has a theory for why that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9hS9Y"&gt;“We’ve always been afraid of the same things,” she says. “And those are never going to go away. You’ll see things change in the genre, in terms of victimology or how we’re discussing the characters, but if you can scare someone 40 years ago, you can scare them with that same material now.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22751349/theres-someone-inside-your-house-netflix-slasher-movie-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22751349/theres-someone-inside-your-house-netflix-slasher-movie-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T11:11:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T11:11:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Toyota’s new electric SUV has a solar roof and a steering yoke like Tesla </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9nPj8avbV75HdD4puDDG6vd0f2k=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062765/20211029_01_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="n9LvNC"&gt;Toyota released new details about its upcoming electric compact SUV, the BZ4X, which includes an optional solar roof and a steering yoke similar to the one featured in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528963/tesla-model-s-plaid-ev-price-specs-range-speed"&gt;the latest version of the Tesla Model S&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ALZr9h"&gt;The steering yoke, which Toyota describes as having a “wing-shape,” employs a steer-by-wire system, where there is no mechanical connection between the steering wheel and tires. The yoke only needs to turn up to 150 degrees from side to side and the driver doesn’t ever need to remove their hands. This will eliminate the need to change grips when steering, which the company argues will make U-turns and other maneuvers easier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZBSBh7"&gt;Toyota first revealed the BZ4X &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391738/toyota-electric-vehicle-strategy-bz4x-concept-subaru"&gt;earlier this year at the Shanghai Auto Show&lt;/a&gt;, along with an electric vehicle strategy that the company said will result in 15 new battery-electric vehicles released by 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Mcp6uC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The yoke only needs to turn up to 150 degrees from side to side&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vXBFTd"&gt;The BZ4X will be built on a flexible platform that it developed in partnership with fellow Japanese automaker Subaru. (Toyota currently owns a small stake in Subaru.) The e-TNGA platform will enable several characteristics, including a steer-by-wire system, all-wheel drive, improved visibility, and a regenerative braking system that is common among electric vehicles. Toyota said the BZ4X would be released globally by the middle of 2022. Subaru is said to be designing its own electric vehicles built on the e-TNGA platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GneHBJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10834580"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W7nxeU"&gt;The BZ4X will also come with a standard steering wheel and system, for those not interested in going full yoke. (The Model S yoke has been controversial, with &lt;em&gt;Consumer Reports &lt;/em&gt;saying it can make driving awkward.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4OJErI"&gt;The interior of the car features a unique instrument cluster, with the screen set back from the steering wheel in a way that Toyota says will improve driver visibility. The central infotainment screen appears to be floating above the dash as opposed to embedded within it. And there are a number of physical buttons in the center console and on the steering wheel, proof that Toyota is not fully embracing the digital user experience like companies like Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E4recZ"&gt;Toyota’s designers took some inspiration from the hammerhead shark when outlining the BZ4X’s exterior. That said, it still retains a conventional shape and appears to be similar in size to a Toyota RAV4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nGYsx9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Toyota’s designers took some inspiration from the hammerhead shark when outlining the BZ4X’s exterior&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XklZvB"&gt;It will come with two powertrains: a 201-horsepower front-wheel-drive, and a 215hp all-wheel-drive that will have estimated ranges of 310 and 286 miles per charge, respectively. (Those estimates are based on the global WLTC rating, which tends to be higher than the EPA’s estimates.) The vehicle is equipped with a 71.4kWh battery pack, which is on par with the Volkswagen ID 4 and the Nissan Ariya in terms of energy capacity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qNKejk"&gt;There are other quirky options, including a solar roof that Toyota says can generate electricity “equivalent to 1,800 km of driving distance per year.” It’s also capable of bidirectional charging for vehicle-to-home capacity, much like the Hyundai Ioniq 5 and Ford F-150 Lightning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RUiMy0"&gt;The electric SUV is expected to land first in Japan in mid-2022, though Toyota hasn’t said whether it would be available in the US. More details about pricing and production are expected in the coming months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xgoBQq"&gt;The news comes on the heels of Toyota’s announcement that it will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662236/toyota-battery-investment-electric-cars-hybrids-2030"&gt;invest around $13.6 billion in battery tech&lt;/a&gt; over the next decade, including a $9 billion investment in production, as it attempts to electrify its vehicle lineup. Although the company was an early leader in gas-electric hybrid cars with the Prius, it reportedly viewed hybrids as a &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/toyota-whiffed-on-electric-vehicles-now-trying-slow-their-rise/"&gt;stopgap measure&lt;/a&gt; until hydrogen fuel cells became competitive. Now, the company is playing catch-up with the likes of Nissan and has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594235/toyota-lobbying-dc-ev-congress-biden-donation"&gt;reportedly lobbied&lt;/a&gt; to slow the US’s transition to electric vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752539/toyota-bz4x-electric-suv-steering-yoke-solar-roof"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752539/toyota-bz4x-electric-suv-steering-yoke-solar-roof</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch SpaceX’s Crew-3 mission to the International Space Station</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L9Fdq2cbCOno63VPkrLW_l1q9i4=/0x114:3722x2595/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062458/51637033819_8899737def_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;(From L to R) ESA astronaut Matthias Maurer, along with NASA astronauts Tom Marshburn, Raja Chari, and Kayla Barron during a dress rehearsal ahead of flight.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA/Joel Kowsky&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BFPCCc"&gt;SpaceX is launching another crew to space this weekend, sending four astronauts to the International Space Station for a six-month-long stay in orbit. Traveling inside SpaceX’s Crew Dragon spacecraft, the crew will get an early start on their mission, with liftoff scheduled for 2:21AM ET on October 31st out of Cape Canaveral, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5T1RE"&gt;The mission is called Crew-3, and it will carry NASA astronauts Thomas Marshburn, Raja Chari, and Kayla Barron, as well as European Space Agency astronaut Matthias Maurer. This will be the first trip to space for Maurer, Barron, and Chari — the mission’s commander. For Marshburn, this will be his third flight to space, and for each of his missions, he’s flown on a different vehicle. His first flight was on the Space Shuttle and his second flight was on Russia’s Soyuz spacecraft. Now he’ll get to experience the Crew Dragon, which the astronauts have nicknamed “Endurance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="erkIUc"&gt;Crew-3 is SpaceX’s third operational crewed flight for NASA as part of the space agency’s Commercial Crew Program — an initiative to use private vehicles to ferry NASA astronauts to and from the International Space Station. As part of its initial contract with NASA, SpaceX is slated to perform up to six crewed flights for the agency, with two flights tentatively scheduled for next year. However, NASA recently indicated it is already thinking of how to transport astronauts beyond those initial missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Rkf4Sp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;it’s actually the company’s fifth time launching people to orbit&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uUrHY9"&gt;While this is SpaceX’s third operational mission, it’s actually the company’s fifth time launching people to orbit on the company’s Crew Dragon spacecraft. In order to prove the Crew Dragon’s safety for NASA, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/30/21269703/spacex-launch-crew-dragon-nasa-orbit-successful"&gt;SpaceX launched two NASA astronauts to the ISS&lt;/a&gt; in May 2020. That first successful test flight paved the way for SpaceX to start doing routine flights with Crew Dragon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qmXRG8"&gt;And in September, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675793/spacex-inspiration4-launch-first-all-civilian-private-crew"&gt;SpaceX launched a crewed flight called Inspiration4&lt;/a&gt; that carried four non-NASA astronauts to orbit. Touted as an all-civilian crew, the passengers included a tech billionaire — who paid for the trip — a childhood cancer survivor, a professor, and an engineer. The foursome, who stayed in orbit for just three days, used the launch as a way to raise charity for St. Jude’s Children’s Hospital. It was SpaceX’s first truly private human spaceflight mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MkObwH"&gt;Though Inspiration4 wasn’t a NASA mission, SpaceX learned a few things from that flight that will help with the upcoming Crew-3 trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pih5I7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A NUMBER ONE PROBLEM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="POENO3"&gt;The Crew Dragon that flew the Inspiration4 flight operated pretty smoothly, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/18/22681339/spacex-inspiration4-crew-return-earth-splashdown"&gt;except for one key element&lt;/a&gt; inside the spacecraft: the toilet. This week, SpaceX revealed that a tube in the toilet that transports urine into a storage tank came unglued. This caused urine to spray into the toilet’s fan system instead and pool under the floor. It wasn’t really a problem during the flight itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BqaRu5"&gt;“We didn’t really even notice it; the crew didn’t notice it until we got back,” William Gerstenmaier, vice president of build and flight reliability at SpaceX, said during a press conference ahead of flight. “We got the vehicle back, we looked under the floor, and we saw the fact that there was contamination underneath the floor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="DeEBBl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We didn’t really even notice it; the crew didn’t notice it until we got back.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PFcVb6"&gt;After seeing this, SpaceX worried that the same problem might be happening on the Crew Dragon used for Crew-2, which is currently docked with the International Space Station. Sure enough, the astronauts on the space station went inside that Crew Dragon and found similar urine contamination under the floor of the toilet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6hFNFEZz19ju3KBbqe8cZrij2VM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22966250/51137531971_c3db77a39c_o.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: ESA / NASA / Thomas Pesquet&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse at the toilet inside the Crew Dragon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lsOEbW"&gt;The main concern with this pooling is that it’s not just urine collecting under the floor; SpaceX adds a compound to the urine called Oxone, which removes the ammonia from the liquid to help get rid of odor and prevent bacteria from growing. But SpaceX became worried that the mixture of Oxone and urine in the floor could actually corrode the spacecraft itself. The company did tests that involved combining the urine and Oxone mixture with aluminum — the primary metal used to make Crew Dragon — inside a chamber that simulated the same temperature and humidity on board the spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5I071"&gt;The toilet issue was more of a problem on Inspiration4, since the crew spent their entire mission inside Crew Dragon, using the bathroom for multiple days, leading to more potential corrosion. Most of SpaceX’s other Crew Dragon missions send people straight to the International Space Station, so astronauts are typically&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;only using the toilet before docking. Also SpaceX claims that the aluminum alloy it uses on Crew Dragon is “very insensitive” to corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PMn9zN"&gt;SpaceX opted to fix the toilet issue anyway by making the toilet an “all-welded structure” so that there are no longer any parts or tubes that can come unglued. That way no unwanted liquids will cause any trouble again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IgarsV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A SIX-MONTH STAY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3WYsrg"&gt;Crew-3 is set to take off from SpaceX’s launch site LC-39A at Kennedy Space Center. The crew will then spend a little less than a full day in orbit before rendezvousing with the International Space Station. Crew Dragon is designed to dock autonomously with the ISS, but the astronauts can jump in during the process if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O5u8doCKF4fPM69k5Iljy1QZ4VY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22966270/51634067771_6e46bf9d92_o.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA / Joel Kowsky&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket and Crew Dragon, at the company’s LC-39A launch site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="agdKd7"&gt;Once Crew-3 arrives, there will be a changing of the guard. The four Crew-2 astronauts already on board the space station will greet the incoming astronauts and get them settled. Then in mid-November, the Crew-2 members will climb into their own Crew Dragon and return back to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jPXkLz"&gt;As for the Crew-3 astronauts, they’ll be on board the ISS for six months, scheduled to come back sometime in the spring of next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7AaTft"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT TIME IS SPACEX’S CREW-3 LAUNCH?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="czmgig"&gt;SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket will take off on Sunday, October 31st, from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZWQqcV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled launch time:&lt;/strong&gt; New York: 2:21AM / San Francisco: 11:21PM / London: 7:21AM / Berlin: 8:21AM / Moscow: 9:21AM / New Delhi: 11:51AM / Beijing: 2:21PM / Tokyo: 3:21PM / Melbourne: 5:21PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QcT0EO"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW TO WATCH SPACEX’S CREW DRAGON LAUNCH LIVE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NLS82h"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Livestream:&lt;/strong&gt; NASA’s livestream coverage can be found &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=21X5lGlDOfg"&gt;on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/nasalive"&gt;on the agency’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KbXSoB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22747319/spacex-liftoff-crew-3-nasa-iss-how-to-watch-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22747319/spacex-liftoff-crew-3-nasa-iss-how-to-watch-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T10:28:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T10:28:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Geralt fights giant monsters, and Jaskier befriends rats in new Witcher season 2 trailer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J5PDuBW28YSEzQbw5Z3WdVIpmNE=/285x0:1938x1102/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062441/Screen_Shot_2021_10_29_at_10.02.18_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AfZ6Hx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WX6e6ZLNmtA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;’s second season&lt;/a&gt; has gotten its official, full-length, real trailer today, giving the best look yet at the monsters, magic, and mayhem that await Geralt of Rivia (Henry Cavill), Ciri (Freya Allan), and Yennefer of Vengerberg (Anya Chalotra) when the show arrives on Netflix on December 17th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SST9dg"&gt;The new trailer teases a lot more about what to expect from the upcoming second season, including the upcoming war with the Nilfgaardian Empire, Ciri’s training to become a witcher, Geralt’s usual monster hunting, and the long-awaited return of everyone’s favorite bard, Jaskier (Joey Batey).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-crTYTOwhfbd2fvV4S6qiP4E8F8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22966537/W_202_Unit_01821_RT20210913_4450_f7e3m6.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oeoeIt"&gt;It’s also the latest salvo in Netflix’s marketing bombardment for the show, which has so far included &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570627/the-witcher-season-two-teaser-trailer-netflix-henry-cavill"&gt;the teaser trailer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22691354/witcher-season-2-blood-origin-trailer-teaser-watch-premiere-date-netflix"&gt;first look clips and behind-the-scene videos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22462967/the-witcher-season-2-trailer-netflix-geeked-week"&gt;brief Twitter teases&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22566778/the-witcher-season-2-release-trailer-netflix-henry-cavill"&gt;the release date announcement&lt;/a&gt;. It’s no wonder that Netflix is going all-in on &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;’s second season, though — the first season was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/21/21075927/netflix-the-witcher-viewer-numbers-length-metrics-q4-2019-earnings"&gt;one of its most popular series ever&lt;/a&gt; (even if it’s since been surpassed by other shows like &lt;em&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DwY9qh"&gt;The expanded &lt;em&gt;Witcher&lt;/em&gt; universe isn’t stopping with season 2, either. Netflix has already released a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22638162/the-witcher-nightmare-of-the-wolf-review-netflix"&gt;prequel anime film, &lt;em&gt;The Witcher: Nightmare of the Wolf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/25/22692068/netflix-tudum-season-3-anime-film-kids-family-series"&gt;announced a third season of the main series&lt;/a&gt;, a second anime film, and a family-friendly series set in the world of the show. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752488/the-witcher-season-2-trailer-netflix-december-17th-geralt-ciri-henry-cavill"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752488/the-witcher-season-2-trailer-netflix-december-17th-geralt-ciri-henry-cavill</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T10:18:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T10:18:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>India will get this $87 JioPhone Next instead of the Pixel 6</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mm3IS7wIeZ_bGX__tklWV6kXoxI=/0x197:720x677/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062385/jiophone_next_blue_edition.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The new JioPhone Next is a collaboration between Google and Indian telecom Jio Platforms. | Jio Platforms&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Rlzir3"&gt;Google and Indian telecom company Jio Platforms finally unveiled their budget smartphone for India on Friday, the JioPhone Next. The phone is designed as an affordable 4G device to serve “the unique needs of the Indian consumer,” Android India engineering lead Ram Papatla said in a blog post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1f5mRA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/google-pixel-6-india-3042428/"&gt;India won’t be getting&lt;/a&gt; Google’s new Pixel 6 and 6 Pro, and those phones’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750387/google-pixel-6-pro-review"&gt;premium prices&lt;/a&gt; put them out of reach of many smartphone consumers in the country. But Google and Jio have designed this new device as a more affordable 4G option. It’s priced at 6499 Indian rupees, or $87, and is available at Jio Mart retailers in India or &lt;a href="https://www.jio.com/jiophone-next/specifications"&gt;on Jio’s website&lt;/a&gt;. Google said users can also put a down payment of 1999 rupees and choose a payment plan through Jio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o0eJsl"&gt;The JioPhone runs Pragati OS, which Google says is an optimized version of Android, and can access apps in the Play Store. The device has read-aloud and language translation for on-screen text, a camera with India-centric Snapchat Lenses, and embedded voice-first features that support 10 different languages spoken in India. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R4GaAJ"&gt;“Among the many rich features of JioPhone Next, the one that has impressed me the most — and one that will empower common Indians the most and take their digital journeys to the next level — is its contribution to India’s linguistic integration. India’s unique strength is our linguistic diversity,” said Mukesh Ambani, chairman and managing director of Reliance Industries, which operates Jio Platforms. “Those Indians who might not be able to read content in English or in their language can get it translated, and even read out, in their own language on this smart device.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hyvRem"&gt;The phone has a 5.45-inch HD plus Corning Gorilla Glass 3 display, a 60Hz refresh rate, a 13-megapixel rear camera with support for HDR, an 8-megapixel autofocus front camera, a 3,500mAh battery, a Qualcomm quad-core QM-215 chipset, with 2GB of RAM, and 32GB of expandable storage. It’s dual-SIM capable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iblSns"&gt;The JioPhone Next will be available beginning November 4th, which is the first day of Diwali, the Hindu festival of lights holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T8X2Yg"&gt;Google and Jio announced their collaboration on a budget smartphone in 2020, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21325343/google-reliance-jio-investment-india-4-5-billion-dollars-7-percent-facebook"&gt;Google providing a $4.5 billion investment&lt;/a&gt; in the telecom company. Google CEO Sundar Pichai said Friday that the JioPhone Next was “inspired by the belief that everyone in India should benefit from the opportunities the internet creates.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TcUDyf"&gt;India passed the US as the world’s &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/chart/25207/countries-with-the-highest-number-of-smartphone-users/"&gt;second-largest smartphone market&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, with more than 400 million smartphone users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FkALRg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update October 29th 12:33PM ET: Adds details of payment plan price option for the JioPhone Next&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752388/india-google-smartphone-jiophone-pixel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752388/india-google-smartphone-jiophone-pixel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T10:11:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T10:11:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cricket Wireless removes speed caps from several plans and offers 5G to everyone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="SPAIN-TELECOM-WMC" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lfQs7GcvbqyYi3yy4Rxla4kgcNQ=/4x0:4924x3280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062348/1233713968.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by JOSEP LAGO/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uzij4E"&gt;Cricket Wireless suddenly has several more options if you’re looking for access to 5G on a prepaid wireless plan. That’s because starting today, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cricketwireless.com%2Fthe-cricket-connection%2Fsubscriber-milestone.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F29%2F22752383%2Fcricket-wireless-5g-att-mvno-speed-limit" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it will offer nationwide 5G access across all of its plans&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/22/21397001/cricket-wireless-5g-samsung-att"&gt;launched a year ago with support for only one device&lt;/a&gt; and only on its more expensive unlimited plans. Cricket Wireless also revealed it’s added 2 million customers in the last two years and is now serving some 12.4 million subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wzFH24"&gt;The other big change for Cricket Wireless is removing an 8Mbps speed cap on its cheaper $30, $40, and $55 &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cricketwireless.com%2Fcell-phone-plans&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F29%2F22752383%2Fcricket-wireless-5g-att-mvno-speed-limit" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;plans&lt;/a&gt;. How much bandwidth Cricket Wireless can reliably provide — using AT&amp;amp;T’s network — after the caps go away is something we’ll only find out as people try it out. Reading the fine print at the bottom of the announcement points us to Cricket’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cricketwireless.com%2Fmap.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F29%2F22752383%2Fcricket-wireless-5g-att-mvno-speed-limit" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;coverage map&lt;/a&gt;, as well as lists of &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cricketwireless.com%2Fsupport%2Fgreat-big-network%2F5g-compatible-phones.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F29%2F22752383%2Fcricket-wireless-5g-att-mvno-speed-limit" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;compatible 5G devices&lt;/a&gt;. It also points out that the $55 per month plan still carries a stipulation that “Cricket may temporarily slow data speeds if the network is busy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OnyUSw"&gt;Of course, the benefits customers see from 5G, no matter which wireless carriers they use, have been pretty disappointing so far. With the changes, now you can potentially get 5G access for as little as $25 per month, per line, on a plan with four phone lines. And with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22746708/att-5g-plus-expansion-tmobile"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T’s plan to expand the reach of its mid-band 5G connections over the next couple of years&lt;/a&gt;, even if things aren’t significantly faster for you right now, that could change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="g3dnYg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"So you got a 5G phone, but is your plan ready?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22194419/5g-phone-plans-us-carriers-guide"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752383/cricket-wireless-5g-att-mvno-speed-limit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752383/cricket-wireless-5g-att-mvno-speed-limit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple MacBook Pro 14 and 16 review: return to form</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Apple’s new pro laptops right the wrongs of the past half decade&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="1T949o"&gt;Let’s start simply: the new MacBook Pros with M1 Pro and M1 Max chips are incredible — the fastest laptops we’ve ever tested in some tasks, with some of the longest battery life we’ve ever seen. Apple’s big bet on moving away from Intel CPUs and AMD GPUs in favor of its own Apple Silicon chips is paying off in meaningful ways, and if you can afford one of these machines, you will be very happy with them. They’re great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uQBber"&gt;That said, the new MacBook Pros are not without their quirks, and the Mac software ecosystem is still catching up to Apple Silicon in general and Apple’s pro hardware GPU ideas in particular. So things aren’t quite as simple as our first impression of the MacBook Air with an M1 chip last year — depending on your needs and the tools you use, the Mac software ecosystem might not let you actually get the most out of these machines for a while yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZR96Q7"&gt;But make no mistake: the performance Apple has delivered with these machines combined with the battery life we’ve seen in our tests means that there’s a new standard in the industry — one that Intel, AMD, Nvidia, and every other laptop maker will be hard-pressed to reach anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4wYkT4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10834286"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="tzzpM6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10834290"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3nktvm9VipSbg-OXh6bRe6D_G1A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22965897/akrales_211028_4820_0523.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new MacBook Pro 16 (left) and 14 have bright Mini LED displays that support Apple’s ProMotion 120Hz high refresh rate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="qz1Ars"&gt;We reviewed three of the new MacBook Pros: a $4,399 16-inch model with an M1 Max processor with 32 GPU cores, 64GB of RAM, and 2TB of storage; and 16- and 14-inch models with M1 Pros with 16-core GPUs, 32GB of RAM, and 1TB of storage that list for $3,099 and $2,899 respectively. These are expensive computers from the jump: even the base model 14-inch starts at $1,999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F0wt43"&gt;The first thing you’re going to notice after you take a deep breath and spend the money is that these new MacBook Pros are much more substantial than the outgoing models. They’re bigger and heavier than previous MacBook Pros, and they are more squared off. The 16-inch is even just a little thicker than the older 16-inch MacBook Pro. Surprisingly, the extra thickness is mostly in the display — the actual body is only ever so slightly thicker than my old 16-inch Intel MacBook Pro, but you can really see it in the lid because it no longer tapers at the edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GHZMWY"&gt;This is good news. Apple has made so many compromises in the name of thinness for so long that it was about time for the pendulum to swing back, and the extra thickness allows for better cooling and the return of some useful ports. On the right side, you’ve got a Thunderbolt 4 port, an HDMI port, and a full-size SDXC slot; on the left side, you’ve got two Thunderbolt 4 ports and a MagSafe power connector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XW1Zrh"&gt;The ports are wonderful, and I’m glad they’re back. A few people on our video team said the SD card slot is enough of a reason to upgrade all by itself. But be warned that the ports aren’t top-spec: it’s an HDMI 2.0 port, not 2.1, and the SD card slot is only UHS-II, not the faster UHS-III or SD Express.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A side profile of the MacBook Pro 16 showing its full-size SD card slot, Thunderbolt 4 USB-C port, and HDMI port." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iiNwvEfKeYRv7wxhPp-iD1CHHtQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22965874/akrales_211027_4820_0121.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now departing Dongletown.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c1q3ONclBy-y1_pfbExaQRZSNPk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22965886/akrales_211027_4820_0310.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MacBook Pro 16 can only fast charge with a 140-watt or higher charging brick connected to its MagSafe port.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8vPQM9"&gt;So yes, the ports are definitely more convenient, and totally fine for most situations, but there are still reasons to visit dongletown. For example, macOS Monterey now supports variable refresh rate external displays using a Vesa standard called Adaptive-Sync, but Apple tells me you’ll need a Thunderbolt to DisplayPort dongle for that. I also ran into a strange bug where sending audio out over HDMI resulted in stuttering video and glitchy audio, which Apple says it is looking into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NA57lx"&gt;The MagSafe 3 connector is great, a true classic. It’s strong enough to drag the MacBook Pro along a desk if you pull it straight, but instantly disconnects if it’s yanked at an angle. I missed it terribly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ah0lIm"&gt;The confusion arises at the other end of the MagSafe cable, which is USB-C. You can charge all of these machines over USB-C using any of the ports, and you can fast charge the 14-inch MacBook Pro using a 100-watt USB-C adapter and a USB-C cable that supports that much power. But you can only fast-charge the 16-inch MacBook Pro using the Magsafe connector connected to a 140-watt-or-higher power brick — MagSafe is the only port that supports the newest high-power USB-C PD standard. The other ports do not. What’s more, there’s no indicator anywhere that you’re fast charging, so you just have to plug in and hope for the best. At this point, “plug in and hope for the best” is the unofficial USB-C slogan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ybkfPq"&gt;USB-C charging is overall one of the most confusing parts of the entire confusing USB-C ecosystem, and it appears Apple is using MagSafe as a way around it — the power adapters are still interchangeable, but you’ll definitely know if your cable supports fast charging because there’s a MagSafe connector on it. It’s smart, but after years of USB-C nonsense, it’s also just funny we’re back here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWDKt8"&gt;Lastly, there’s the keyboard, which is blessedly drama-free. Apple finally shed the hapless Touch Bar, added full-height function keys, and restrained itself from trying to reinvent anything else. It feels like every other scissor-switch Apple keyboard I’m used to, which is welcome news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DUQkM8NMRqv5OHmXMCuIDgqk24U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22965883/akrales_211027_4820_0244.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MacBook Pro’s display can reach up to 1,600 nits of brightness, but that’s localized to only HDR content. The rest of the time, the screen has a more standard 500 nits peak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Alv8cS"&gt;The displays in these new MacBook Pros are also all-new, and they are terrific. In fact, I like looking at these displays far more than I like looking at Apple’s own $5,000 Pro Display XDR. But as with the rest of the new MacBook Pros, there is complexity involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lUiHC"&gt;First, there’s the notch, which houses a 1080p webcam, the camera LED, the TrueTone light sensor, and the ambient light sensor at the top of the display. But to me, rather than thinking of the notch eating into the display, I think of the display getting larger except in that one spot. The MacBook Pro effectively has a 16:10 display with a little extra bit at the top where the menu bar and the notch live. You stop noticing it after just a few minutes, just like you stopped noticing the iPhone notch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ojoHG"&gt;If you hate the notch, there are already free utilities to black out the menu bar and hide it, and you’ll have the exact same display experience as any previous MacBook. So we promise: the notch is not worth overthinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xev9vn"&gt;That said, it can be a little odd in practice. There are &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SnazzyQ/status/1453143798251339778"&gt;already videos of weirdo notch bugs&lt;/a&gt;, which feels like what happens with every new iPhone notch — it takes a minute for apps to catch up. We are not too worried about it, overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wiIiI9"&gt;Now, would it have gone down easier if Apple had added Face ID to the MacBook Pro? Yes, but at least there’s Touch ID, which is very fast on these machines. Would the notch have gone down easier if the webcam was as good as an iPhone front camera, instead of just, like, pretty good? Certainly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g6GA62"&gt;Is it also strange that Apple is leaning into display notches as branding elements on both the MacBook and iPhone, allowing them to be distinctively Apple products without having to put logos anywhere? That seems clearer than ever, actually.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Notch on new MacBook Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WFde5UyfBxFRamE7rmfu9q2Hv5w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22948752/pesposito_170722_4803_0032.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You stop seeing the notch after a day, just like the iPhone’s notch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lqmtO7"&gt;This display is way more interesting than the notch, though. It’s now a Mini LED screen, which means the backlight is composed of ten thousand tiny LEDs, grouped into over 2,500 local dimming zones. That means blacks can get really black on this display — up to a million to one contrast ratio, just like an OLED screen. (When you black out the notch, it’s really black — gone.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FC0uX6"&gt;And just as we found with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;Mini LED display on the iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;, that backlight still has limitations — if you go looking for something called blooming, where there’s a little halo around bright elements on an otherwise black screen, you’ll find it. But you have to go looking for it — in this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AYtvehF9-Z8"&gt;YouTube torture test&lt;/a&gt;, you can see the backlight chasing this little square around the screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="txfHO6"&gt;If you’re watching a movie, you might see a little blooming when the controls come up over black, especially if you’re looking at the display off-axis. We got some questions about whether closed captions would cause blooming when watching a video, and the answer is it’s a non-issue: YouTube captions display over a gray box anyway, and Apple TV and Netflix captions mostly display over the video itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ENLloE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Peak brightness of 1,600 nits is limited to HDR content only; the rest of the screen will peak at 500 nits&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xkE17e"&gt;Apple made a big deal about how bright this display can get — it’s an XDR display, just like the Pro Display XDR. And just like the Pro Display XDR, it can reach a peak brightness of 1,600 nits, with a sustained brightness of 1,000 nits. But it’s not quite what you think: the display mostly runs at a max of 500 nits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pbjJTN"&gt;Out of the box, the new MacBook Pros are set to a display profile called Apple XDR Display, which allows it to hit that 1,600-nit peak brightness, but only when viewing HDR content. The rest of the system is the same as every other MacBook Pro and runs at a max of 500 nits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wA5TuF"&gt;If you have a newer iPhone, you already know what this looks like: you open a photo, and it brightens up. That’s more or less what’s going on with this display: when you have HDR content, it can get a lot brighter and hit that 1,600-nit maximum, but everything else is still SDR, and displays at a maximum of 500 nits. In fact, if you choose the standard Apple Display profile and limit the whole system to 500 nits, you won’t be able to tell the difference until you open an app or play a video that calls for HDR. I asked Apple about this; the company confirmed that the XDR system is content-dependent and designed to run at 500 nits for most tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3iumm"&gt;The good part is that all of this works really well: HDR video works in every app I tried, including YouTube in Chrome and Safari, and it looks terrifically bright with great colors and saturation. The HDR brightness levels even follow the content around the screen seamlessly, showcasing that Mini LED backlight in action. On a technical level, this display is extremely impressive and way more seamless than any HDR support we’ve seen on the Windows side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHTbzN"&gt;The bad part is that Apple’s marketing is confusing, and functionally this is a 500-nit display that can reach much higher brightness levels with the right content, not a 1,000-nit display, which is what a lot of people are taking away from that spec line. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GkjqWs"&gt;The upshot of all this is that most Mac users will find this display to be mostly familiar with some meaningful upgrades, but if you’re a Windows person using one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22675550/hp-elite-dragonfly-max-2021-review-tile-test-specs-price-features"&gt;1,000-nit laptops available in that ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;, you shouldn’t expect to sear your eyeballs off with this thing in most situations. We did a quick test working outside and it was fine, but if that specific spec is important to you, you’ll have to go look at one of these in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="6x9rwa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The ProMotion high refresh rate is only barely perceptible in person&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CZkB35"&gt;The last bit of display nerdery is ProMotion, Apple’s variable refresh rate system that lets the display run at anything from 24 to 120Hz. But I could only just barely see the improvement that 120Hz offers in normal, non-gaming use, and only when really looking. It’s just less obvious when it’s not a touchscreen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pu3Ydt"&gt;All in all, this display looks great, and a little minor blooming is a fine tradeoff for these black levels. Again, I think this display looks better than Apple’s Pro Display XDR, which has fewer dimming zones, more blooming, and off-axis color and brightness shifts that our team really doesn’t like. This display has none of those issues: it’s bright, accurate even, and generally a pleasure to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zT5Hqe"&gt;Lastly, the speakers on these new MacBook Pros are terrific. The first thing we did with these when we got them was open up a video to check out the new displays, but the first thing we &lt;em&gt;noticed&lt;/em&gt; was that the speakers are so good. They are clear and crisp, with some actual low-end from four woofers, and they get super loud. It’s impressive — and while the 14-inch speakers are really good, the 16-inch models in particular have the best speakers we’ve ever heard on a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ws07o80wpykku6lndDXgqmmuMVA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22965876/akrales_211027_4820_0151.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The thicker and heavier designs for this year’s models are welcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="uYb3Tu"&gt;I’ll just cut to the chase: for content creation and creative work, these are the most powerful laptops we’ve ever tested. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rbp4rW"&gt;The basic M1-family chip design is easy enough to understand, even though it’s a new kind of chip architecture compared to x86, since the fundamental parts are all the same. Apple has three kinds of processor cores — efficiency, performance, and GPU — and all the M1 chips are different combinations of those exact same cores with unified memory between them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cRF975"&gt;For example: the 13-inch MacBook Pro we tested last year had a regular M1 with four efficiency cores, four high-performance cores, and eight GPU cores. The M1 Pro and M1 Max change that around a little, with two efficiency cores and up to eight high-performance cores. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="acqXzi"&gt;The really big difference is in GPUs: the regular M1 has up to an eight-core GPU, while the M1 Pro has up to a 16-core GPU, and the M1 Max is available in 24- and 32-core setups. Again, those GPU cores are the same on all the chips — you just get more of them as you go up the range, along with things like faster memory with higher total limits and additional specialized video encoders. (The M1 Max machines have a little toggle for something called “high power” mode in system settings; Apple told me that simply allows the fan to spin faster for better cooling.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ybfdnH"&gt;And… it turns out that adding a bunch of cores and specialized video encoders makes these chips incredibly fast for creative work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="18gFET"&gt;The synthetic benchmarks we ran were extremely impressive. The M1 Max got a &lt;em&gt;gigantic &lt;/em&gt;score on PugetBench for Premiere Pro, which tests live playback and export performance at 4K and 8K — beating Nvidia’s RTX 3080 and AMD’s 5900HX. The only computers that even come close are &lt;em&gt;desktops&lt;/em&gt; that use vastly more power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A bar graph showing 1,170 result in the PugetBench for Adobe Premiere Pro with the 16-inch MacBook Pro M1 Max, 1,072 for the 14-inch MacBook Pro M1 Pro, 1,000 for the 16-inch MacBook Pro M1 Pro, 872 for the Alienware X17 R1, and 538 for the ROG Strix G15 Advantage." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V-qZ92lwhSx_fGzXpFviAT2z5jU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22966211/Bench2___PugetBench_Premiere.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PugetBench for Premiere Pro test results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SqGaWN"&gt;You simply will not find better Adobe Premiere performance from any AMD or Nvidia  laptops on today’s market. This system is generating performance in a tiny laptop chassis that, in the past, we’ve only seen from huge desktop machines with enormous power supplies. And it’s doing that even when it’s &lt;em&gt;unplugged&lt;/em&gt;: when we ran all these benchmarks on battery, we didn’t see a difference in scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XB7ncG"&gt;When it comes to Cinebench, as well as Geekbench and other tests that stress the CPU, the M1 Max and the M1 Pro are neck and neck, since they have the same 10-core CPU block. Where the scores start to diverge is on tasks that leverage the GPU, like our export test, PugetBench, Geekbench Compute, and gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A bar graph showing a 12,368 score in Cinebench R23 multi-core 30-minute loop test for the 14-inch MacBook Pro M1 Pro, 12,363 for the 16-inch MacBook Pro M1 Pro, 12,316 for the 16-inch MacBook Pro M1 Max, 8,500 for the 16-inch MacBook Pro 2019, and 7,729 for the 13-inch MacBook Pro M1." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jEh_t4NJk9Q2ftQ3Pnurkt16pXs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22966216/Bench3___Cinebench_R23.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even when running long benchmarks, like this 30-minute Cinebench test, the MacBook Pro’s fans rarely spun up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sZyDpX"&gt;This makes sense, since the M1 Max has the same CPU block as the M1 Pro with more GPU cores and higher memory bandwidth. But it underscores the primary question that should be on your mind if you’re deciding whether to buy the Pro or the Max: how much GPU performance do you need? Things will be the same for an office workload or anything CPU-bound, but the Max has a clear advantage if you have specific GPU-optimized workloads. (You’ll take a battery life hit for those extra GPU cores, though — I’ll come back to that in a bit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zP0j2E"&gt;Of course, synthetic benchmarks only tell part of the story, so to see how well a laptop performs a real-world task, we ran an export of the same five-minute, 33-second 4K video clip in Adobe Premiere Pro. I also gave the machines to &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; senior video director Alix Diaconis to edit and use them for a week to see how they worked for our real video production needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fyKmaP"&gt;In that setting, these MacBooks were the fastest laptops we’ve ever seen. The 16-inch with the M1 Max was more than twice as fast as any previous MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A bar graph showing a 1 minute 46 second time to export a 5 minute 33 second 4K video from Premiere Pro on the 16-inch MacBook Pro M1 Max, 2 minutes 50 seconds for the 14-inch MacBook Pro M1 Pro, 2 minutes 51 seconds for the 16-inch MacBook Pro M1 Pro, 3 minutes 38 seconds for the Razer Blade 15 Advanced 2021, 5 minutes 28 seconds for the 13-inch MacBook Pro M1, 7 minutes 6 seconds for the Razer Blade 14 2021, and 7 minutes 52 seconds for the 16-inch MacBook Pro 2019." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VnLBFYB068GVRlQdKgjyLM4Wl-M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22966220/Bench1___Premiere_4k_export_test.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MacBook Pro models put up the fastest times in our export test we’ve ever recorded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iMfIAs"&gt;It’s not just the export speeds, either. Here’s what Alix had to say about working with them in Premiere Pro:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jV88Kc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Premiere ran smoothly with 4K footage — on both the 14-inch and 16-inch M1 Pro machines, I could play back the timeline at full resolution at 2x speed. But to no surprise, when I added graphics and adjustment layers with color, Premiere started dropping frames. It was minor, but after 20 seconds a frame or two would drop. There was also a short but noticeable lag from hitting the spacebar to the timeline actually playing. It was about one second, as if the computer was thinking before it played. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HCYJs0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overall, the editing experience was very similar to my regular work machine, a 27-inch iMac from 2019 with an eight-core Intel Core i9, 64GB of RAM, and a Radeon Pro 575x graphics card; the M1 Pro machines were actually choppier during 2x timeline playback.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q5daH2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the M1 Max with 32 GPU cores, there was no lag between hitting the spacebar and playing, and Premiere ran noticeably smoother than my iMac or the M1 Pro laptops. Scrubbing through the timeline was great — I didn’t notice it drop a frame until 3.5 hours in of editing, which is very impressive. It did slow down with big graphics, though.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="3KJBml"&gt;The big caveat about all this performance is that you need software optimized to take advantage of it, and we’re still in the middle of the Apple Silicon transition. For example, Adobe’s software isn’t nearly as optimized as Apple’s. Final Cut Pro is heavily optimized for these chips, and it was &lt;em&gt;over 10 minutes faster&lt;/em&gt; than Premiere Pro exporting a 14-minute 4K clip in ProRes 422.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uytM0s"&gt;Although parts of Adobe’s flagship creative software suite have been partially updated for Apple Silicon — Apple even pre-installed Premiere Pro on our review units — some important apps are not yet updated. This was underlined sharply by an After Effects update that arrived in the middle of our testing, which enabled better multi-core acceleration. After Effects is still an Intel app, which runs in the Rosetta emulation mode on these machines, but the update allowed the app to light up all 10 CPU cores and all 32 GPU cores, cutting export times on our test from 4:29 to… 41 seconds. (It also substantially sped up performance on our Intel-based Mac Pro, which is nice.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7h8mvN"&gt;That kind of performance increase is worth real money — it’s the kind of thing that lets our team &lt;em&gt;do more than they could with other machines&lt;/em&gt; because they aren’t spending so much time waiting around for things to export. And as we’ve seen, Adobe’s software isn’t even as heavily optimized as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Liv54d"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The performance increase is the kind of thing that lets our team do more than they could before, simply because of how much time is saved&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kf1wTV"&gt;In short: the performance improvements on unoptimized software are notable; on heavily optimized software, they’re incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBbb2A"&gt;There’s another category of apps that haven’t (and may never be) fully optimized to take advantage of Apple’s GPUs: gaming. The M1 Pro and the M1 Max are groundbreaking chips, but they’re also built to do creative work really, really well — they haven’t made the MacBook Pros into serious gaming laptops. We ran the &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; benchmark on the three units we have at its highest settings at 1920 x 1200. The M1 Max averaged 84fps on that benchmark, which is good, but it’s also the exact score we got from the Zephyrus G14 with an RTX 3060 chip, so it’s not beating Nvidia’s top guns. We’ve also seen much better from AMD’s GPUs: the Strix G15 with AMD’s RX 6800M averaged 94fps on this game. You could buy two Zephyrus G14s or two Strix G15s for the price of our M1 Max model and have a lot of money left over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P6dY8v"&gt;(The two M1 Pro machines did way worse here: they both averaged 46fps on the &lt;em&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; benchmark, which is way closer to the 2019 Intel MacBook Pro than it is to the M1 Max.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bdb8vQ"&gt;So: don’t buy these for gaming. They’re not gaming laptops; most games aren’t optimized for them. Buy something else if you want to play games. But if you want to get a lot of creative work done quickly, there’s nothing better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The new MagSafe 3 cable plugged in to the new MacBook Pro 16." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xiSYPHj2vPjMlJSLj8_grXyEjVw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22965873/akrales_211027_4820_0099.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Battery life on the new MacBook Pro 16 with the M1 Pro chip is as impressive as its raw performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="genDxM"&gt;All that performance is excellent, but here’s what’s really impressive: the 16-inch MacBook Pro with the M1 Pro ran for 16 hours on its battery during continuous use, making it the longest-lasting laptop we’ve ever tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KupG42"&gt;To test battery life, we just use the machines during the work day, without plugging in, and without letting the display go to sleep. So that 16 hours involved jumping between a dozen-ish Chrome tabs, using apps like Slack and Spotify, and often running Zoom calls and YouTube videos over that. At one point we were worried we’d fall asleep before the MacBook Pro did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="lvFoVy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There is a noticeable difference in battery life between models with the M1 Pro and those with the M1 Max&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Za9COQ"&gt;The other two MacBook Pro models didn’t last quite this long in similar testing — but their results are still exceptional. The 14-inch model with the M1 Pro lasted just over 10 and a half hours during normal use, and the 16-inch M1 Max model ran for just over 10 hours. A lot of you asked about battery life with an external display plugged in; when I worked for a day with the TV I use for Zoom intermittently plugged into the HDMI port on that M1 Max machine, battery life fell to seven hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9SQi6R"&gt;These results make sense when you look at what’s inside these devices: the two 16-inch models both have a 100-watt-hour battery, which is the biggest laptop battery you’re allowed to bring on an airplane, while the 14-incher has a smaller 70-watt-hour battery. But the M1 Max has a whole bunch of extra GPU cores to power, and that drains the battery faster. I asked Apple, and the company confirmed the M1 Max uses more power both when idle and when active, but it noted that the M1 Max might potentially be more efficient if you run specific multi-core GPU workloads all day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0yrvb"&gt;A lot of you asked whether the extra money for the M1 Max is worth it, and after all that, we think the answer is: no, not for most people. Carrying around all those extra GPUs has an impact on battery life whether you’re using them or not. Unless you can identify a specific part of your workflow that would benefit from serious multithreaded GPU acceleration, the reality is that you’re probably not going to use them. I recommend really thinking about whether the battery penalty of the M1 Max is worth it for what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The back of a space gray MacBook Pro 14 next to the back of a silver MacBook Pro 16." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RwX_yBFt_XM0QGWyiIzPoHAS5jU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22965898/akrales_211028_4820_0563.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can still get the MacBook Pro models in either dark gray or silver.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="gKO1yJ"&gt;So: those are the new MacBook Pros. They are some of the best laptops we have ever tested, with an unbeatable combination of lightning fast performance and tremendous battery life. And Apple seems to have come back to reality in terms of design — well, apart from that notch. But adding some useful ports and ditching the Touch Bar are just smart, practical choices, and honestly worth the upgrade for many people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="enovCL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s no denying how expensive these computers are&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="46bUyK"&gt;So what are the knocks? The biggest one is that these machines are expensive. If you’re an actual pro, the prices are perhaps easy to justify given the performance, but if you’re just doing everyday productivity work, you can get a lot of great laptops for less than the $2,000 starting price of the 14-inch MacBook Pro. And Apple only putting 16GB of RAM in the base models and charging $400 for an upgrade to 32GB is just ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MnFzWT"&gt;The other is that Apple is still in the midst of the transition to its own chips, and the software ecosystem isn’t totally there. These machines feel like the future, but parts of that future are still a little bit hazy. Will Apple’s GPU ideas get fully supported by app developers? We’ve been asking that question for a while, and we still don’t know the answer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="6UaXGa"&gt;But all that said: the new MacBook Pros are excellent. And we’ve all hopefully learned an important lesson about ports and buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="K2IaY8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10834312"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T09:50:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T09:50:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft acquires Two Hat, a moderation company that helps keep Xbox clean</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="microsoft logo stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MA2tE0AB4Ct_IR0CWHLUq1EUhQo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062209/DSCF1179.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sam Byford / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dJXXt0"&gt;Microsoft has acquired Two Hat, a content moderation provider that’s helped keep harmful content off Xbox. Founded nearly 10 years ago by a former Disney Interactive security specialist, Two Hat uses AI to classify and filter billions of human interactions across messages, images, usernames, videos, and more. Microsoft has been working with Two Hat for the past few years to improve its Xbox communities, but the terms of the deal were not disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="glT0Bn"&gt;“For the past few years, Microsoft and Two Hat have worked together to implement proactive moderation technology into gaming and non-gaming experiences to detect and remove harmful content before it ever reaches members of our communities,” &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2021/10/29/microsoft-acquires-two-hat-to-collaborate-on-online-safety-and-digital-wellness-solutions-for-online-communities/"&gt;explains Dave McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;, head of Xbox product services. “Two Hat’s technology has helped to make global communities in Xbox, &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; and MSN safer for users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0n2o1L"&gt;The acquisition is designed to improve Microsoft’s first-party content moderation in gaming, and even extend to the company’s consumer services. Microsoft has big plans for consumer services, after hiring a former Uber exec to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22628689/microsoft-manik-gupta-hire-uber-consumer-teams-skype-groupme"&gt;lead a new consumer apps effort earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WG3LAf"&gt;Microsoft has been trying to acquire popular communities recently, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352309/microsoft-tiktok-acquisition-deal-why-us-countries-data"&gt;TikTok&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22277845/microsoft-pinterest-acquisition-azure-cloud-services-rumors"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22352028/microsoft-discord-acquisition-analysis-report"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;. CEO Satya Nadella has expressed an interest in Microsoft focusing on creators and communities, and moderation plays a critical part in any online community-based service. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d0heIEBuaQlo_viiocKkVn-2PcY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19285103/1wKBN51.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox network has text filters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qPgwea"&gt;Two Hat also has a number of its own customers, and Microsoft isn’t planning to stop supporting them. “This is a deep investment in assisting and serving Two Hat’s existing customers, prospective new customers and multiple product and service experiences here at Microsoft,” says McCarthy. “With this acquisition, we will help global online communities to be safer and inclusive for everyone to participate, positively contribute and thrive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07C5Zw"&gt;Microsoft launched a number of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/14/20913323/microsoft-xbox-live-content-filters-messages-party-chat-moderation"&gt;text-based filters for its Xbox network&lt;/a&gt; three years ago, after Xbox chief Phil Spencer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/20/18629892/microsoft-xbox-phil-spencer-video-games-industry-effort-toxicity-abuse-harassment"&gt;outlined a plan for fighting toxicity&lt;/a&gt; in gaming. Two Hat has been assisting with some of these Xbox moderation efforts, and Microsoft also has a much broader goal of being able to filter out Xbox Live party sessions in the future so live audio calls can be filtered with real-time bleeps similar to broadcast TV.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752421/microsoft-two-hat-acquisition-xbox-moderation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752421/microsoft-two-hat-acquisition-xbox-moderation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-29T09:48:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-29T09:48:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s latest iPad Pro and Pencil are cheaper than ever today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MqsAO2SovViJDbjhWjZoAabSUG8=/4x0:1852x1232/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70062201/Screen_Shot_2021_10_28_at_12.02.42_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can pick up the second-gen Apple Pencil today at Verizon for $100 instead of $130.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nVibj5"&gt;The latest 11-inch iPad Pro with an M1 processor is more affordable than ever before today at Amazon. The retail giant is currently selling the Wi-Fi version with 1TB &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0931Z3CWQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $1,299&lt;/a&gt; (the space gray color sadly costs $1,429). As noted in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt;, we loved the 2021 iPad Pro’s blazing-fast M1 processor, its smaller form factor, and Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395325/ipad-pro-pan-zoom-video-conferencing-microsoft-teams"&gt;Center Stage feature&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks you in the frame while on video calls to keep you centered. It compensates for the fact that Apple still puts its selfie cam at the top of the tablet instead of along its side bezel. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zbbu8i"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10833256"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VZYmYc"&gt;If you want a capable stylus that’s compatible with the latest &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22696652/ipad-mini-2021-6th-gen-review"&gt;iPad Mini&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"&gt;iPad Air&lt;/a&gt;, you can find the second-gen Apple Pencil for $100 instead of $130 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MU8F2AM-A-Pencil-Generation/dp/B07K1WWBJK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/1141873/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Pencil-2nd-Generation%2F949679706" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-11365093?sid=VergeDailyDeals102821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-pencil-2nd-generation-ipad-pro%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt;, matching its record low price. Unlike the original model, the second-generation version features gesture controls and can wirelessly charge when magnetically attached to the side of your iPad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rMWek1"&gt;Be aware, however, that the new Apple Pencil does not work with the newest entry-level iPad that costs $329. If you want one that is compatible with the iPad, consider picking up the &lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-11365093?sid=VergeDailyDeals10282021Second&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-pencil-for-ipad-pro%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;first-generation stylus&lt;/a&gt;, which Verizon is currently selling for $80 instead of $100. Note that to charge the original model, you’ll need to plug it into the iPad’s Lightning connector — a design that remains &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/12/8/9872746/apple-bad-hardware-design-iphone-case-pencil-magic-mouse"&gt;cringe-worthy&lt;/a&gt; to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1aUma8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10500002"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="gLVQui"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10832871"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="TIasGP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Apple Pencil 2 has gesture controls and charges wirelessly from the iPad Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/30/18023772/new-apple-pencil-2-2018-ipad-stylus-price-release-date"},{"title":"Here’s how the $329 iPad compares to its last-gen predecessor","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22678374/apple-ipad-2020-vs-2021-comparison-upgrade"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WFPMDk"&gt;Our pick for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"&gt;best-sounding noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; for non-Apple users are selling at an all-time low today on Amazon. Typically $400, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VW98ZKG/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon is selling the Sennheiser Momentum 3 Wireless headphones&lt;/a&gt; for just $250, a 37 percent discount. As we wrote in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, we found that the comfortable headphones offer detailed, bass-rich sound while providing 17 hours of playback per charge. They even come outfitted with a USB-C port for charging, and they fold up in a compact manner. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="X3iAJD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OsnZKa"&gt;We’ve got another great deal for non-Apple users, this time on a touchscreen laptop. In her &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22392778/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-15-inch-review"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, my colleague Monica Chin called the latest Surface Laptop 4 “a pretty damn good buy” in comparison to other 15-inch laptops, praising its performance, excellent battery life, and tall 3:2 aspect ratio display that lets you see more on-screen at once. What makes it an even better value is that you can currently purchase the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08YX1WLVN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;15-inch Microsoft Surface Laptop 4&lt;/a&gt; for its lowest price to date. Typically $2,400, Amazon is selling the matte black-colored model with 32GB of RAM, 1TB of fast PCIe storage, and Intel’s 11th Gen Core i7 processor for $2,250, a cool $150 off the list price. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22392778/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-15-inch-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WRAjBo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10832863"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZgjekP"&gt;If you don’t have room in your home or your budget for a large-screened OLED, a couple of retailers are now selling the 48-inch version of LG’s C1 OLED at a record low. Both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WFK81RH/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1176910/2092?subId1=VergeDeals102921&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Flg-48-34-class-4k-uhd-smart-oled-hdr-tv-oled48c1%2F-%2FA-82219816"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; are offering the 48-inch LG C1 for $1,097 and $1,100, respectively, down from $1,297. This model has all of the same perks as larger C1 models, including a 120Hz refresh rate, Dolby Vision HDR support, and HDMI 2.1 ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wO6emr"&gt;If you do want something bigger, the larger models are still discounted, too, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/28/22748849/apple-airpods-pro-samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-lg-c1-oled-roku-streaming-stick-deal-sale"&gt;as we wrote about previously&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon is also offering a six-month subscription to HBO Max when you buy the 55-inch and 65-inch versions of the LG C1. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WG4HKKY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;65-inch is selling for $1,797&lt;/a&gt; instead of $2,500, while the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-OLED65C1PUB-Alexa-Built-Smart/dp/B08WFV7L3N/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch is $1,297&lt;/a&gt; instead of $1,500. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0aERus"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10833105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X7wtDQ"&gt;If you’re into gaming, Eneba is currently offering &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeDeals102921&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states%2Fgamepilot%3F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one year of PlayStation Plus&lt;/a&gt; service for just $37 (the price can fluctuate just a bit) instead of its typical $60 retail price when you use promo code &lt;strong&gt;365DAYS &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout. The popular gaming subscription offers access to a range of perks, including exclusive discounts, access to online multiplayer, and complimentary games every month. PlayStation 5 users will get instant access to the PlayStation Plus Collection, which lets you play &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us&lt;/em&gt;, and other blockbuster PlayStation 4 titles without paying an additional fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vqT0Dp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NuIuo0"&gt;If you’ve got an Xbox, you might be interested to hear that Eneba’s selling a &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeDeals102921&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fxbox-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-3-month-membership-xbox-one-windows-10-xbox-live-key-global%2Fbest-pick" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-month subscription to Xbox Game Pass Ultimate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeDailyDeals10282021&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fxbox-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-3-month-membership-xbox-one-windows-10-xbox-live-key-global%2Fbest-pick" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;for $28 (once again, the price can fluctuate) instead of its usual $45 when you use promo code &lt;strong&gt;90DAYS &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout. Like the aforementioned PlayStation Plus deal, Xbox Game Pass Ultimate gives Xbox owners access to online multiplayer and exclusive deals, as well as many EA Play tiles and Microsoft’s cloud gaming service, xCloud, which is now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554267/microsoft-xcloud-game-streaming-xbox-pass-ios-iphone-ipad-pc"&gt;widely available on PC, Android, and iOS&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps the biggest perk of Game Pass Ultimate is that it lets you access more than 100 Xbox titles for a flat, monthly fee, including &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;when it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22637945/halo-infinite-release-date-launch"&gt;finally launches on December 8th&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="O10eLP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10833343"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="D23eso"&gt;More great deals happening now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="title"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07KXQX3S3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SanDisk’s 128GB microSDXC card is $22&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon right now, the second-best price we’ve seen on the Nintendo-licensed storage solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kasHm2"&gt;Normally $379, Bose is currently offering a refurbished pair of the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.bose.com/en_us/products/headphones_outlet/noise-cancelling-headphones-700-fr.html#v=noise_cancelling_headphones_700_fr_black" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bose Noise Cancelling Headphones 700 for $279&lt;/a&gt;. They may exhibit a few minor scuffs and blemishes given their refurbished condition, but the excellent headphones come with a one-year warranty and a 90-day, risk-free trial. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/19/20700627/bose-noise-cancelling-headphones-700-redesigned-microphones-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zD22WC"&gt;If you’re looking to expand the storage capacity of your PlayStation 5, the 1TB version of Gigabyte’s Aorus NVMe Gen 4 SSD is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/GIGABYTE-PCI-Express-Interface-Performance-GP-ASM2NE6200TTTD/dp/B07TJWZGL9?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;down to $170 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, its best price to date. We haven’t tested it, but the &lt;a href="https://www.gigabyte.com/us/Solid-State-Drive/AORUS-NVMe-Gen4-SSD-1TB/sp#sp"&gt;company says&lt;/a&gt; it’s compatible with Sony’s next-gen console and runs at 5,600MB/s when plugged in. If you already have an SSD but still need a compatible heatsink, per Sony’s requirements, Micro Connectors Low Profile Heatsink is also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Micro-Connectors-Low-Profile-Cooling-NGFFM2-HS804-BK/dp/B07GNJQ37N/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Amazon for $10&lt;/a&gt; and measures a mere 5mm thick. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22602046/best-ps5-playstation-5-m2-ssd-compatible-drives"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full PS5 SSD buying guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UELHxn"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfTerCoehCu" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-pack of Philips Hue white and color A19 bulbs&lt;/a&gt; is $100 at Best Buy, the lowest price we’ve on the popular smart bulbs outside of Amazon Prime Day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vPNfZD"&gt;Vizio’s 55-inch OLED is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfTeSj2KlG0" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Best Buy for $1,000&lt;/a&gt;, its lowest price to date, for a limited time. Despite the price, the budget-friendly OLED still manages to pack in a few features suited for next-gen gaming, namely support for HDMI 2.1. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L0tKTi"&gt;A three-pack of Eero 6 dual-band Wi-Fi mesh router and extenders is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/treasuretruck" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;just $181 today on Amazon’s Treasure Truck&lt;/a&gt;. This is not the lowest price ever on Eero’s popular Wi-Fi 6-equipped mesh system, but it is lower than the usual deal price we see around $220 and much lower than the standard $279 retail price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="WlBkxT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="xIUVbE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wElrOR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hrDPDq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VW3dNE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/29/22750870/apple-pencil-microsoft-surface-laptop-4-lg-c1-oled-ipad-pro-playstation-plus-xbox-gamepass-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/10/29/22750870/apple-pencil-microsoft-surface-laptop-4-lg-c1-oled-ipad-pro-playstation-plus-xbox-gamepass-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
