<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-27T09:05:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-27T09:05:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-27T09:05:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony’s PlayStation Network experiencing outage Saturday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="PlayStation controllers" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4VWGtPF3ocYat744ztWuSliD_UU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68884441/vpavic_191127_untitled_0059_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qAjehf"&gt;An outage of Sony’s PlayStation Network that began Friday afternoon appeared to be persisting on Saturday morning. According to an &lt;a href="https://status.playstation.com/"&gt;update on the status page&lt;/a&gt; timestamped 6:33PM (not clear what time zone that is) on February 26th, the affected platforms are PS Vita, PS3, PS4, and PS5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SZKN9e"&gt;“You might have difficulty launching games, apps, or network features. We’re working to resolve the issue as soon as possible. Thank you for your patience,” the update reads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mwO4MO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/psn-is-down-ps4-ps5-022654065.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that the outage may be affecting some games but not others; &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; appeared to be accessible but &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt; were not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b3iaWD"&gt;The PlayStation Network outage began a day after Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301763/xbox-live-down-sign-in-issues-microsoft-support"&gt;Xbox Live service suffered a global outage&lt;/a&gt; for five hours. On February 10th, the PlayStation Network &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277439/sony-playstation-network-global-outage"&gt;was down worldwide&lt;/a&gt; for about an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pyqHFh"&gt;We’ve reached out to Sony for details about what’s causing the outage, how widespread it is, and when it may be resolved, and will update when we learn more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAdqqM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304492/sony-playstation-network-outage-saturday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304492/sony-playstation-network-outage-saturday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-27T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-27T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are this week’s best gadget deals all in one place</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ml73VgVNXPJGXMpiCWJMbElq9nI=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68884376/FINAL_FANTASY_VII_REMAKE_E3_2019_screenshot_6.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Square Enix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="P4HP5U"&gt;This week’s batch of deals runs the gamut of gadgets and games. Whether you’re a music fan who’s looking to outfit their tech repertoire with new headphones or a big, powerful Bluetooth speaker, or a gamer, this roundup is for you. There still aren’t any deals on hard-to-find graphics cards, but the good news is at least AMD’s powerful Zen 3 processors are in stock right now (but perhaps not for long). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8mT0YM"&gt;If you aren’t finding what you’re looking for in today’s roundup, keep a lock on our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; Deals coverage&lt;/a&gt; throughout the week and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VergeDeals"&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for the moment-to-moment deal alerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="RuLbSh"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OdOtr0"&gt;Get the best-ever price on Beats Solo Pro on-ear headphones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sgpO1I"&gt;Beats Solo Pro noise-canceling headphones are still available for $150 through Woot. You can get either the dark blue or light blue colors. Since they’re new, the one-year manufacturer warranty is directly through Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2Te9oC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625639"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ihWUiw"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="byhs2x"&gt;Ultimate Ears Hyperboom brings the noise, and it’s $59 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6cqmqe"&gt;Ultimate Ears makes good Bluetooth speakers. Its latest model is its biggest yet: the Hyperboom. It’s waterproof and portable with its built-in strap. You can connect up to two Bluetooth devices to it, and its digital optical port means it can serve as a home theater system in a pinch. This is a pricey speaker, but it’s a versatile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vqZyXJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10359731"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="vbcNB9"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XXk6hf"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; for PS4 / PS5 is half off its usual price&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="p6esZ3"&gt;Sony announced Friday that &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22302776/finalfantasy-7-remake-free-playstation-plus-march-2021"&gt;will be available as a free download&lt;/a&gt; for PS Plus members in June. This seems like perfect news, given Square Enix just revealed that the PS4 version can be upgraded to the PS5 version for no extra cost later in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22274549/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-ps5-update-graphics-expansion"&gt;June 2021&lt;/a&gt;. But, there’s a catch: this complimentary version can’t receive the free upgrade. Only by purchasing the game on disc or through the PS Store digitally can you earn the upgrade when you move to PS5. (Confusing, no?) In that case, this $30 deal for the disc-based version is a good price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mGqYRF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546364"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="JLGLZ6"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yCKvDP"&gt;AMD’s high-end Zen 3 processor is back in stock&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pjCPbV"&gt;If you’ve been a-swingin’ and a-missin’ on every opportunity to get some new PC components, including a processor, check this out. Several retailers have AMD’s latest Ryzen 7 5800X eight-core processor. It’s based on Zen 3 architecture, and it’s about as next-gen as processors come at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5Uj31E"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10363165"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="QknE2X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/27/22303086/final-fantasy-vii-remake-ps4-ps5-deal-beats-solo-pro-noise-canceling-headphones-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/27/22303086/final-fantasy-vii-remake-ps4-ps5-deal-beats-solo-pro-noise-canceling-headphones-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T20:31:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T20:31:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this report about how selling safe masks online is surprisingly hard</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Subway Train in New York City" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vFUVExSu58ZWcEkk-gdXPo3P3gc=/0x31:5379x3617/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68883202/1257624399.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Gary Hershorn/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OiAaun"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/26/health/n95-masks-facebook-sale-amazon.html?smtyp=cur&amp;amp;smid=tw-nytimes"&gt;A new report from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times’&lt;/em&gt; Andrew Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;digs into how mask policies on tech platforms that have allowed novelty masks like scrunchie masks to flourish while some mask-makers making high-filtration masks have had trouble selling their wares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ho563T"&gt;Even if you’re vaccinated, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/04/dr-fauci-on-why-its-important-to-wear-a-mask-after-getting-your-covid-vaccine-.html"&gt;wearing a mask is still recommended&lt;/a&gt;. It seems like a problem, then, that many masks widely advertised on Facebook, Instagram, and Amazon are novelty varieties that might be less safe than medical-grade N95s. Facebook and Amazon say they are following guidelines from the Center for Disease Control and Prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6MPLJ0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/7/21169109/facebook-instagram-bans-ads-face-masks-coronavirus"&gt;Facebook prevented mask sellers&lt;/a&gt; from advertising and selling masks to the masses early in the pandemic, when they were in short supply. The idea was to reserve N95s for medical professionals instead. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/10/21286724/facebook-cloth-face-mask-ad-ban-lifted-supply-workers"&gt;That policy eventually changed&lt;/a&gt; so that non-medical masks, face coverings, and plastic shields could be advertised. Some mask-makers who manufacture their own medical-grade masks told Jacobs they aren’t able to advertise on the platform, while fabric masks that can fold pocket squares or transform into scrunchies are. Which might not be a problem if these sellers where reaching hospitals directly. Many told Jacobs they’re not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="9DjPXa"&gt;“I’d be happy to sell my masks to health care workers, but right now hospitals aren’t exactly banging down my door,” said Brian Wolin, the chief executive of Protective Health Gear, a year-old company in Paterson, N.J., that has a half million unsold N95 masks at its factory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Ix7nrQ"&gt;Amazon’s policies pose a different problem, according to Jacobs’ report. Large manufacturers have an easier time reaching customers on Amazon because the company buys their products in bulk to ship from its own warehouses, Jacobs’ writes. But the company’s policy around selling masks and the algorithms that govern how they appear in search are difficult for smaller companies to navigate. Less safe alternatives like KN95 masks are readily surfaced in search, while other manufacturers offering N95s on Amazon’s storefront have been buried by the algorithm, the report says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p1Suqy"&gt;In the end, Jacobs’ piece illustrates a disappointing arrangement: online platforms are frequently the safest way to purchase PPE, but they don’t always provide the safest product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QCEDYE"&gt;Check out Jacobs’ report on &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/26/health/n95-masks-facebook-sale-amazon.html?smtyp=cur&amp;amp;smid=tw-nytimes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times’ &lt;/em&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;for&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;the full picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnKZPt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303935/mask-selling-facebook-amazon-instagram-kn95-n95"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303935/mask-selling-facebook-amazon-instagram-kn95-n95</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T19:32:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T19:32:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Stadia version of Terraria is back in production after developer reconciles with Google</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qIfw1oiKMhz8KQIMFJNMWU9zbDQ=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68882686/ss_ae168a00ab08104ba266dc30232654d4b3c919e5.1920x1080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Re-Logic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UmvDnk"&gt;Earlier this month, &lt;em&gt;Terraria &lt;/em&gt;co-creator Andrew Spinks announced that his studio Re-Logic would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272502/terraria-google-stadia-port-canceled-deceloper-locked-out"&gt;cancel a Google Stadia port&lt;/a&gt;. However, the developer announced today that the Stadia port is now back in development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1HsPaM"&gt; ”As you may have noticed, we had a ton of issues to kick off the year stemming from the locking-down of Redigit’s entire Google account in early January,” Re-Logic said in a &lt;a href="https://forums.terraria.org/index.php?threads/terraria-state-of-the-game-february-2021.103428/"&gt;recent &lt;em&gt;Terraria &lt;/em&gt;forum post&lt;/a&gt;. “After a month of pushing (and with the immense support of our fans), Google finally reached out and was able to provide a lot of transparency around the situation and to restore access to all of our accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RQoNTg"&gt;After publication, a Google spokesperson confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that a Stadia port for &lt;em&gt;Terraria&lt;/em&gt; was currently in development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t46quC"&gt;On February 8th, Spinks fired off a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Demilogic/status/1358661840402845696?s=20"&gt;series of tweets&lt;/a&gt; expressing frustration that he was locked out of his Google accounts for weeks, which included losing access to his Gmail and Google Play account. Spinks first noted that he lost access to his accounts on or around January 16th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DO3Us3"&gt;Re-Logic has yet to announced when &lt;em&gt;Terraria&lt;/em&gt; will launch on Google Stadia, but the game being back in development is good news for fans of Google’s cloud gaming service. On Friday, two reports from &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-26/google-video-game-unit-stadia-struggled-to-be-googley-enough"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-stadia-games-entertainment-collapse/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; shed light on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303496/google-stadia-struggle-wired-bloomberg-reports-studios"&gt;some of Google’s failures in building Stadia&lt;/a&gt;. And earlier this month, Google announced it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260803/google-stadia-game-development-studio-shut-down-jade-raymond"&gt;closing its in-house&lt;/a&gt; development studio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WUD1lA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 26th, 7:32PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Included information from Google confirming that a Stadia port of &lt;/em&gt;Terraria&lt;em&gt; is in development.   &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303868/terria-stadia-version-back-development-canceled-google"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303868/terria-stadia-version-back-development-canceled-google</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T17:54:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T17:54:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>This TikTok Tom Cruise impersonator is using deepfake tech to impressive ends</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QCe2t_Rd-Fwy9kFz_iw1DvWl3rU=/13x91:898x681/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68882612/Screen_Shot_2021_02_26_at_2.24.11_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not pictured: Tom Cruise&lt;/em&gt; | Image: @deeptomcruise on TikTok&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="df7yVy"&gt;What’s better than an ultra-high-tech, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v1Y4CubBi60"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible&lt;/em&gt;-style mask&lt;/a&gt;? The deepfake technology this TikToker is using to impersonate Tom Cruise, apparently (&lt;a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/shockingly-real-tom-cruise-deepfakes-are-invading-tiktok?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;The Daily Beast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@deeptomcruise"&gt;deeptomcruise account&lt;/a&gt; appears to feature someone who’s pretending to be the famous actor, and the impression isn’t just jaw-dropping because of how well the person replicates Cruise’s famous laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nEgEWR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@deeptomcruise/video/6932166297996233989" data-video-id="6932166297996233989" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;"&gt; &lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@deeptomcruise" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@deeptomcruise"&gt;@deeptomcruise&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sports!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - Tom" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6932166350203357957"&gt;♬ original sound - Tom&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M5ZnkY"&gt;How can you tell it’s not actually Tom Cruise using some sort of strange Twitter name? First, his voice is close, but it’s not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; there, especially since the lip-syncing is a tiny bit off at some points. You can hear what the real Cruise sounds like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G1wsCworwWk"&gt;in this video&lt;/a&gt; (unless, of course, James Corden also deepfaked him in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DQ0f6K"&gt;Second, while the tracking and lighting on the face are darn near immaculate — especially&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;when the actor passes something in front of his face — there are still a couple of telling glitches, notably in &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@deeptomcruise/video/6932166297996233989"&gt;the golf one&lt;/a&gt; where the sunglasses disappear and his mouth morphs for a frame or two. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_6WCa-EnHql3t-exNNS7V2z3EHE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22332191/NotCruiseHQ.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Gif: The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s not perfect, but it’s close.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QFeXqF"&gt;Even with these minor blips, the effect is still spooky. I’m not going to yell from the rooftops that deepfakes will be ruinous to society, but the fact that someone is posing, almost believably, as a famous actor on TikTok (and gaining 236,000 followers in the process) shows that it’s still hard to track deepfakes. While the account pretty clearly indicates that it’s a fake by using “deep” in its name, the next one to pop up might not. TikTok didn’t immediately respond to an email from&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt; asking whether this type of account is allowed under its terms of service, but its TOS explicitly call out impersonations as forbidden:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="xH768Y"&gt;You may not: [...]&lt;br&gt;impersonate any person or entity, or falsely state or otherwise misrepresent you or your affiliation with any person or entity, including giving the impression that any content you upload, post, transmit, distribute or otherwise make available emanates from the Services&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="FcBSPj"&gt;That said, this account does seem to be a bit of relatively harmless fun. If you’re reading this, person who runs deeptomcruise (or the real Tom Cruise), please show us if this tech can keep up with your best Tom Cruise run, or if it can handle you &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G2UVsyVLLcE"&gt;dancing and lip-syncing to Bob Seger&lt;/a&gt;. Just whatever you do, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Slrfkruvnk8"&gt;leave Oprah, deepfaked or not, out of it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22303756/tiktok-tom-cruise-impersonator-deepfake"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22303756/tiktok-tom-cruise-impersonator-deepfake</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T17:22:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T17:22:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Persona 5 Strikers is a perfect excuse to reunite with the Phantom Thieves</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NJwmEthDHWA6-LNqRcflhkn9jhY=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68882493/ss_8ab45ed170a4f44838dbd3fa4a8978c3a2313e62.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h4SHdY"&gt;Atlus is a master of weird spinoffs. In the past, the developer has revamped its RPG series &lt;em&gt;Persona&lt;/em&gt; as dungeon crawlers, brawlers, and rhythm games. Heroes have bounded through space and time for fanfiction-worthy team-ups, all in service of giving players a reason to see their favorite characters again. &lt;em&gt;Persona 5 Strikers&lt;/em&gt; goes one step further, turning an action-heavy adventure into a road trip that feels right at home with the original game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwjauG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persona 5 Strikers&lt;/em&gt; is a direct sequel to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/29/15098458/persona-5-review-ps4-ps3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, set months after the Phantom Thieves hung up their masks. The gang reunites for a long-overdue vacation, only to have it interrupted by the appearance of Jails — warped versions of reality where one person rules, not unlike the Palaces they encountered in the original game. To solve the mystery of these jails, the Phantom Thieves get an RV and take their investigation across Japan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ek8Uts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strikers&lt;/em&gt; is an action-RPG take on the game in the vein of Omega Force’s other spinoffs of popular series, like Hyrule Warriors. It trades in the careful turn-based strategy of the original for button-mashing through mobs. Players are no longer confined to controlling only the game’s hero, Joker, and can swap between party members like Makoto or Ann at will. In addition to elemental abilities specific to their personas, like nuclear or wind attacks, each has special physical attacks to help you through battle. Characters I barely used in the original &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;, like Ryuji, became my go-to for mobs I wanted to melee; I rarely needed Morgana’s magic but loved his ability to turn into a car and mow down shadows. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F8l-4oIoOJLBrNd4qPvBIMIn7c4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22332030/ss_71b63fbbd55221007aabf84fd4c150a6125329da.1920x1080.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xOaeF5"&gt;Despite being able to swap between characters, the game’s mash-heavy gameplay can become monotonous at times. On a good streak, I would string together combos, pile on follow-up and all-out attacks, and zap enemies with magic attacks — but mostly, I just spent a lot of time frantically hitting buttons. The amount happening on-screen can sometimes be dizzying if not tough to follow, between characters talking during battle and zipping around a screen smashing enemies in the face. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p1OS8u"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persona 5 Strikers&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t offer as robust an experience as the original game — there are no personality traits to improve, and relationships are distilled down to a single “Bond” metric that applies to your entire team — but it offers a solid array of ways to break up your playtime. New cities mean sidequests, shops to visit, and recipes to find for you to cook with; party members often want to visit special restaurants and attractions. The constraints of a deadline are gone as well. You can pop in and out of jails as often as you wish to go hang with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Kqx1R"&gt;The experience feels like a streamlined version of &lt;em&gt;Persona&lt;/em&gt;, the video game equivalent of a summer vacation. It’s a way to spend extra time with a world I fell in love with over the course of dozens of hours, and a welcome expansion to the game’s mythos. Where &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;’s Palaces were desires pushed to their extreme and corrupted, Jails revolve around trauma. In order to defeat the monarchs of each jail, you’ll need to first uncover and understand the pain that birthed them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oZzchCMAWTSi674NC0iwn4eW9Hc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22332031/ss_473822957f4077b28c5a81bfeb74e5b5cacba8ca.1920x1080.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SkRept"&gt;It’s a welcome change, a turn that makes people’s cruelty more interesting. &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;’s examinations of people at their darkest sometimes ran up against the cartoonish villainy of it all. The rulers you faced were so exaggeratedly evil that taking them down needed no justification. But &lt;em&gt;Strikers &lt;/em&gt;offers a more complex alternative: that hurt people hurt people. The monarchs have manipulated and deceived, yet they’re still a path for them to learn and grow from their mistakes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ey92nC"&gt;As a sequel, &lt;em&gt;Persona 5 Strikers&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t offer much in the way of big revelations — but it doesn’t have to. Like the series’s many other spinoffs, the allure is the opportunity to play in their world a little longer. Clearing a jail is fun, but it still can’t compare to a night out with your friends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DDS80s"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persona 5 Strikers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt; is available on Nintendo Switch, PC, and PlayStation 4.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wKHONs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xyPqVh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22303746/persona-5-strikers-review-ps4-pc-nintendo-switch-atlus-omega-force"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22303746/persona-5-strikers-review-ps4-pc-nintendo-switch-atlus-omega-force</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T17:21:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T17:21:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V9cZCU"&gt;Apple AirPods are among the most popular headphones on the market. They’re compact, easy to pair with your devices, and offer reliable connectivity, which can sometimes be a problem with truly wireless earphones. So there’s a chance that you might be looking for a deal on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR97R2"&gt;Surprisingly, they’re no stranger to the occasional price cut. There are often discounts on even the more expensive AirPods Pro, which offers noise cancellation and better sound quality than the standard second-generation model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;We’ll run through all three of the current models below, including the standard AirPods, the more expensive AirPods that include a wireless charging case, and finally, the AirPods Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZuVjFm"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple AirPods 2 review: even more wireless|63428" data-volume-uuid="c798b260f" data-volume-id="63428" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-997" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VFDHZw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="R1mQdI"&gt;These are Apple’s entry-level wireless earbuds. They are a reliable pair of wireless earbuds with a one-size-fits-most design. The AirPods usually retail for $160, which is not a bad price, but this model frequently gets discounted.  You can currently find Apple’s most affordable AirPods for $129 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_0bkRzx3mmxyLTxrwUx0Mo389UkET95QnWQ-N3A0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3D0bkRzx3mmxyLTxrwUx0Mo389UkET95QnWQ-N3A0%26sharedid%3Dverge%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestiPadDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or $130 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191097%3Fclkid%3D7eebb553N627e11ebb06342010a246e3d%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodsDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yHjw-MSSOE9krvMa6cC9qYmHU9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993019/akrales_190327_3315_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PK1JRu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods (with wireless charging case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;The AirPods with wireless charging case are identical in every way to the standard AirPods, save for one: their charging case can be charged on a Qi wireless pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYNUWv"&gt;You’ll need to provide your own wireless charging pad to take advantage of this feature (if you have no use for it, just get the more affordable option above), but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2017/10/27/16554680/best-wireless-charger-qi-ravpower-samsung-anker-mophie"&gt;even the best ones are fairly inexpensive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="glqkTs"&gt;Most of the time you can find this version for less than Apple’s sticker price of $199, but keep a lookout for deals that bring the price down to $160 or below. You can get them for $160 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodsDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OGXtAu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Uv43TD"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="AirPods Pro review: the perfect earbuds for the iPhone|73652" data-volume-uuid="c840e1e11" data-volume-id="73652" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-232" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s9Ofwq"&gt;Apple’s high-end truly wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, have better sound quality than the other models described above, include noise cancellation, and now support Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. We think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;they’re the best wireless earbuds that iPhone owners&lt;/a&gt; can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaMGwU"&gt;The AirPods Pro are frequently available for less than their $249 retail price, and in fact, sometimes drop down to $200 and lower. Right now, if you don’t mind buying refurbished, they are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1730154636955201273" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$190 at Best Buy (Geek Squad Certified)&lt;/a&gt;. If you want a new pair, the lowest price you can get them for currently is $219 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodsDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. You can also get them for $220 at &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html%2FDFF%2Fd10-v21-t1-x995659%2FSID%2F66960X1514734X399deab46224a444932767312ff6c84b#donotlink"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, but if deals at those retailers sell out, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-pro%2F-%2FA-54191101%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodsDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; has them for $235.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdTSzD"&gt;If you want to get an Apple Care Plus protection plan for your wireless earbuds, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1570785-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink"&gt;B&amp;amp;H is selling a bundle that includes both for $235&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TuBiVT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FDsE87"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c9yAKy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T17:06:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T17:06:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Johnson &amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine backed by independent FDA committee</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L4ACLMGJRclSmaphdngThgriOUM=/0x0:2757x1838/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68882429/1230137617.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Jason Armond / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="j5gwnb"&gt;An independent committee of vaccine experts has unanimously recommended that the Food and Drug Administration authorize the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298855/covid-vaccine-johnson-effective-fda-south-africa-variant"&gt;one-shot COVID-19 vaccine&lt;/a&gt; for people 18 and older, taking it one step closer to use in the United States. The FDA is expected to authorize the vaccine within days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dWfkUz"&gt;“I think it’s a relatively easy call,” said committee member Eric Rubin, an immunologist at the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health. “It’s nice to have a single-dose vaccine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q7GSfo"&gt;The Vaccines and Related Biological Products Advisory Committee (VRBPAC) met today to discuss the data from clinical trials of this vaccine, which the FDA evaluated over the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22267984/covid-vaccine-johnson-fda-one-dose-review"&gt;past three weeks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vmnE5l"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298855/covid-vaccine-johnson-effective-fda-south-africa-variant"&gt;The FDA’s analysis&lt;/a&gt;, released earlier this week, showed that the vaccine was safe and 85 percent effective against severe cases of COVID-19 globally. No one who received the vaccine was hospitalized with or died from COVID-19. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rJ1uQA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I am pleased to have been part of VRBPAC for review of the vaccine.  We must not let a narrative take hold that this is a "lesser" vaccine than the mRNA vaccines. This vaccine prevents severe disease and death and in the crisis we are in that the most important thing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/YIfnAd44Bv"&gt;https://t.co/YIfnAd44Bv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— James E.K. Hildreth (@JamesEKHildreth) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JamesEKHildreth/status/1365423896212692994?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="32TMJB"&gt;When more moderate cases are included, the efficacy dropped to 72 percent in the US and 64 percent in South Africa, where a coronavirus variant that may partly evade immune protection is spreading. But even for people who did get moderate cases, the trial had some very positive results. People who still got sick with COVID-19 after being vaccinated had fewer symptoms than people who got sick and who weren’t vaccinated, according &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/146219/download"&gt;to an analysis&lt;/a&gt; from Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i1phmX"&gt;Early data about the vaccine showed that it seemed to be less effective in older adults or people with health conditions like HIV, but FDA officials noted that there was less data available in those subsets of trial participants. As more cases were added to the analysis, the differences between those at-risk groups and the rest of the people in the trial started to  shrink, said Rachel Zhang, a medical officer with the FDA, during a presentation on the data today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qUpVgO"&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson’s vaccine only takes one dose to give people protection against COVID-19, which makes it easier to distribute than the Moderna and Pfizer / BioNTech vaccines, which each need two shots. “It simplifies the process. People only have to make one appointment for their complete vaccination. A one dose vaccination decreases the burden on the health care system and health care providers,” Greg Poland, director of the Mayo Clinic’s Vaccine Research Group, said during the company’s presentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P9t9vC"&gt;The company is also running clinical trials to see if two doses of their vaccine would be even better than one. VRBPAC member Paul Offit, a vaccine researcher at the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia, pointed out that it would be tricky to switch the vaccine to two doses if that regime turned out to be more effective. “You can see where that would be confusing to people,” he said during the meeting. Rubin raised the same issue. “It seems like a big logistical problem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gPJuwk"&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson will also run additional trials to test its vaccine in adolescents, children, and pregnant women. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAc9qU"&gt;The company says it has &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/covid-vaccine-johnson-and-johnson-short-doses/"&gt;4 million doses&lt;/a&gt; of the vaccine ready to ship on authorization. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2wrmt5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303158/covid-vaccine-fda-indepenedent-committee-johnson"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303158/covid-vaccine-fda-indepenedent-committee-johnson</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T17:05:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T17:05:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best iPad deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tK0LbEtEShHQh97Hs1ENU1d_fQg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66899976/bking_200322_3945_0023.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Brennan King / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1E6t41"&gt;Deals on Apple’s iPad are more common than you might think. Whether you’re after the affordable iPad, the high-end iPad Pro, or something in between like the iPad Air or iPad Mini, there’s usually some sort of price cut happening somewhere. Of course, it’s difficult to know exactly where you can find those deals unless you’re looking around at all of the major retailers. But that’s what we’re doing each day when we hunt for deals, so let us help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uzVhpS"&gt;Below, we’ve listed each of the current iPads available for purchase. Most of the time, there’s some sort of discount happening on a new or refurbished model. When there is a deal we think worth telling you about, we’ll let you know, along with any info you need to keep it in context. If there isn’t a current deal, we’ll tell you how much the most recent sale price was for, so you’ll know when to take the plunge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLLRFN"&gt;If you need a little help figuring out exactly which iPad is best for you, we’ve got you covered &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21280856/apple-ipad-mini-air-pro-comparison-how-to-choose"&gt;with a comparison post featuring all of the latest models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rFr0TF"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad 2020 review: here we go again, again|95745" data-volume-uuid="d243cb26d" data-volume-id="95745" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-193" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hb2n3u"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="q5ZrvP"&gt;This is Apple’s most affordable iPad, usually costing $329 for the model with 32GB of storage or $429 for the 128GB model. Each has a 10.2-inch display and features the A12 Bionic processor, a Touch ID fingerprint sensor, and a Smart Connector for connecting a Smart Keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="T559mJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The new 2020 iPad isn’t enough for Zoom school","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5m6ZrK"&gt;You can currently get the base iPad with 32GB of storage at Amazon for $320 ($9 off) in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J5J9699?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J65DST5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more space to store things like apps, you can grab a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J5J7BF1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;128GB model for $400 if you buy it in gold&lt;/a&gt;, which is $29 off its usual price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="s2PEas"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508346"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="pxIjz0"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad mini 2019 review: the best small tablet|63300" data-volume-uuid="e735355f0" data-volume-id="63300" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-953" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fmPtFu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad mini (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MgBOt3"&gt;Apple released a new iPad mini in early 2019, equipped with the same 7.9-inch display and design as previous iterations, but with refreshed internal specs. It has the A12 Bionic processor found in the base iPad, along with Wi-Fi support. Apple sells 64GB and 256GB models of the iPad mini, with prices set at $400 and $500 respectively. If you want LTE connectivity, the starting price is $530.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="X7SsrD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s new iPad mini is a terrific small tablet with no competition","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="QD0sMe"&gt;Sales on the basic Wi-Fi model are rare, but you can buy the 64GB iPad Mini in gold for as low as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PRD48RS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$385 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PRD48RS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PRD2NQ7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt; only) or for &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1468029-REG%2Fapple_muqy2ll_a_7_9_ipad_mini_early.html"&gt;$394 at B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WEZSI9"&gt;Amazon also has the 256GB model on sale for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07NHN9W4J?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$529 in space gray&lt;/a&gt;, or just $1 more, you can get this model in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07PQ8XKZC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07PSK4LGQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PSFYBw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515887"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="WfS02T"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad Air (2020) review|96393" data-volume-uuid="6c97cb5b6" data-volume-id="96393" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-804" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="66nPkj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad Air (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="v5sW0N"&gt;The 2020 iPad Air has a slightly larger 10.9-inch display compared to the prior model’s 10.5-inch screen, and features thinner bezels around the display. It has relocated the Touch ID fingerprint sensor to the power button, located on the top of the device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="u6ZCyC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple iPad Air (2020) review: take it from the Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VGT87b"&gt;Like its predecessor, the fourth-gen iPad Air model comes in 64GB or 256GB storage configurations. The Wi-Fi models start at $599 and $749 respectively, making the starting price slightly more than last year’s models. The model that supports LTE starts at $729. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ByT0LP"&gt;The best deal you can currently get on the iPad Air fourth-gen is at Micro Center. The retailer has the most competitive sale price right now, where you can grab a 64GB model in all five colors (&lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/628782/apple-ipad-air-4---green-(late-2020)"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/628780/apple-ipad-air-4---rose-gold-(late-2020)"&gt;gold&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/628779/apple-ipad-air-4---silver-(late-2020)"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/628781/apple-ipad-air-4---sky-blue-(late-2020)"&gt;sky blue&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/628778/apple-ipad-air-4---space-gray-(late-2020)"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzykEb"&gt;Amazon currently has the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J61FCVN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;fourth-gen iPad Air 64GB model with Wi-Fi in all colors on sale&lt;/a&gt;, ranging from $549 to $570 depending on the color you select. Walmart has the same configuration on sale for $559 if you buy the 64GB iPad Air with Wi-Fi in &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-9-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Green%2F968764839%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestiPadDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-9-inch-iPad-Air-Wi-Fi-64GB-Rose-Gold%2F149437127%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestiPadDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wn6zsS"&gt;The 256GB configuration has also been discounted at Amazon; you can get this model for $699 ($50 off) in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J63W44Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J6FTH75?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;rose gold&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J6FVJMX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sky blue&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J6LJMT4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7jir3Q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546269"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="nFcTiz"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPad Pro (2020) review: beyond the trackpad|75424" data-volume-uuid="a90d1f137" data-volume-id="75424" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-112" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7PfM3l"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iPad Pro (2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VbsKiA"&gt;Apple’s 2020 iteration of the iPad Pro looks a lot like the 2018 model, aside from its dual-lens rear camera array. Unlike the less expensive iPad models, the iPad Pro ditches the headphone jack and uses a USB-C port instead of a Lightning port. It also has Face ID to help you unlock the tablet instead of relying on the Touch ID fingerprint sensor; it also has a high refresh display. In fact, the iPad Pro has the most stacked spec sheet of Apple’s entire iPad lineup, which comes at a price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="B73hce"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple iPad Pro review 2020: small spec bump, big camera bump","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="MHHxDV"&gt;The 11-inch model with 128GB of storage starts at $800; bumping the screen size up to 12.9 inches raises the price to $1,000. Each model supports up to 1TB of storage, with the top-spec models going for $1,299 (11-inch) and $1,499 (12.9-inch). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g8em56"&gt;If you are looking to pick up the 11-inch model at a discounted price, Amazon has the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B08639YQTV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB configuration on sale for $849&lt;/a&gt;. You can get &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B0863BD9FH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB of storage for $1,049&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon in silver or for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B0863BT4DD?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,050 in space gray&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G5QUP2"&gt;Of course, if you have money to spend and want a ton of storage, you can buy the 11-inch &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B08631TDC3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB configuration in space gray for only $1,249 in space gray;&lt;/a&gt; that’s $50 off its usual retail price of $1,299.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eK4A7f"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="48UoRv"&gt;If you want a slightly bigger screen, Amazon has the 12.9-inch iPad Pro on sale &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862JF4KR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starting at $949&lt;/a&gt; for the base model, which includes 128GB of storage. If you need more storage, you can get the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862HNWGK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB model for &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fdp%2FB0862HNWGK%2Fref%3Das_li_ss_tl%3Fie%3DUTF8%26th%3D1%26linkCode%3Dll1%26tag%3Dtheverge02-20%26linkId%3Dffc689de651b8297993943adb5f6d337%26language%3Den_US&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21280354%2Fbest-ipad-deals-apple" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$999&lt;/a&gt; or you can buy the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862JK4BQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB for $1,199&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2My51r"&gt;The 12.9-inch 1TB model with Wi-Fi only is also discounted at Amazon. You can get it in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08637TYPT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray for $1,394&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08631SHQJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,399 if you buy it in silver&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G0kMgB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737960"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-26T17:01:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T17:01:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix teams up again with Ghost in the Shell studio Production I.G for a Terminator anime</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J0l3c-c5DsM-WBleC3ghu0Bwfyg=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68882411/t2_judgementday.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: TriStar Pictures&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rFWUFy"&gt;Netflix is pairing up with renowned Japanese anime studio Production I.G for an animated TV series set in the &lt;em&gt;Terminator &lt;/em&gt;universe. The company is billing the project as a team-up between Matt Tomlin, the writer of the Netflix superhero film &lt;em&gt;Project Power&lt;/em&gt;, and the studio best known for producing TV adaptations of legendary manga &lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell&lt;/em&gt;, though little else is known about the show or when in the complex &lt;em&gt;Terminator &lt;/em&gt;timeline it may take place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flyDHY"&gt;This isn’t Netflix’s first time working with Production I.G. Beyond its &lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell &lt;/em&gt;work, the studio is known as the animator of the &lt;em&gt;Psycho-Pass series &lt;/em&gt;and the wildly popular sports anime &lt;em&gt;Haikyu!! &lt;/em&gt;But with Netflix, Production I.G produced an original series called &lt;em&gt;B: The Beginning &lt;/em&gt;(originally pitched under the name &lt;em&gt;Perfect Bones&lt;/em&gt;), which debuted in 2018 with a long-awaited second season arriving on Netflix next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DIh1Zo"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The most terrifying killing machine in sci-fi history is back, just like it promised. Project Power’s Mattson Tomlin and legendary anime studio Production I.G are teaming up for an animated series set in the Terminator universe.&lt;/p&gt;— NX (@NXOnNetflix) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NXOnNetflix/status/1365406286557380611?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZdsMZ4"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Terminator&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most iconic sci-fi stories ever created–and has only grown more relevant to our world over time,” John Derderian, Netflix’s vice president of Japan and anime, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/terminator-anime-series-netflix-1234916466/"&gt;said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “The new animated series will explore this universe in a way that has never been done before. We can’t wait for fans to experience this amazing new chapter in the epic battle between machines and humans.” In addition to Production I.G, Netflix has reportedly brought in Skydance Media, too, the production company behind the last two &lt;em&gt;Terminator &lt;/em&gt;films. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1DBnKT"&gt;Netflix is no stranger to anime. The all-encompassing anime umbrella, which includes animated works of various styles and genres, has been one of the hottest streaming service content categories of the last half-decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="giZXs1"&gt;Numerous platforms have shelled out big money over the last few years to both acquire the rights to stream existing anime series and also develop new, exclusive ones that can draw in new subscribers, with Netflix arguably leading the pack while longtime anime distributors like Funimation and Viz Media have become major players in the streaming licensing business. Late last year, Sony paid nearly $1.2 billion to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166585/sony-buy-anime-streaming-service-crunchyroll-at-t-funimation"&gt;acquire anime streaming service Crunchyroll&lt;/a&gt; from AT&amp;amp;T, yet more evidence of the entertainment industry fervor surrounding anime. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bI4X8Q"&gt;It’s paying off, too: more than 100 million households watched at least one episode of an anime on Netflix between October 2019 and September 2020, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/streaming/asia/japanese-anime-is-growing-success-netflix-1234816488/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variety &lt;/em&gt;reported last fall&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iGMMTq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303713/netflix-terminator-anime-production-ig-announced-tv-series"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303713/netflix-terminator-anime-production-ig-announced-tv-series</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
