<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-20T06:13:51-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T06:13:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T06:13:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Brave browser replaces Google with its own search engine</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t5nq2mDdz775UnPGUvQGALJAMkw=/0x0:1244x829/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70019452/image2_1_980x829.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brave Search launched in beta earlier this year.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Brave&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XFlq9C"&gt;Brave, the privacy-focused browser that blocks third-party ads and trackers by default, is switching to using its own search engine by default, &lt;a href="https://brave.com/search-and-web-discovery/"&gt;the company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. The change will be applied for new users, and will affect which search engine is used via the browser’s address bar. Brave Search will replace Google in the United States, United Kingdom, and Canada, Qwant in France, and DuckDuckGo in Germany. More countries will be switched over in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mG9AvH"&gt;It’s a significant step for Brave’s fledgling search engine, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547158/brave-search-beta-browser-private-independent-index"&gt;launched in public beta&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, since most people just take what they’re given. The search engine set as the browser default is a valuable promotion tactic, and so important that the practice has become a significant focus of antitrust scrutiny. In Europe, Google now offers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525688/google-europe-android-search-provider-selection-choice-screen-pay-to-play-auction"&gt;a choice of search engines&lt;/a&gt; for Android users after it was fined &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/18/17580694/google-android-eu-fine-antitrust"&gt;$5 billion by EU regulators&lt;/a&gt; for, among other things, illegally tying Google search to Android. Over the years, Google has also paid companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21310591/apple-google-search-engine-safari-iphone-deal-billions-regulation-antitrust"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/15/21370020/mozilla-google-firefox-search-engine-browser"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; to be the default search engine in their browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="lwI2wT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“As we know from experience in many browsers, the default setting is crucial for adoption”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IYBvni"&gt;“As we know from experience in many browsers, the default setting is crucial for adoption, and Brave Search has reached the quality and critical mass needed to become our default search option, and to offer our users a seamless privacy-by-default online experience,” Brave’s co-founder and CEO Brendan Eich said in a statement. He added that its search engine now handles “nearly 80 million queries per month.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkCwnt"&gt;Although the switch will boost Brave Search’s prominence with Brave users, the browser’s marketshare is so small that it doesn’t even register against established competitors like Chrome, Safari, Edge, and Opera, according to &lt;a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share#monthly-202105-202105-bar"&gt;data from StatCounter&lt;/a&gt;. Nevertheless, as of September 2021, &lt;a href="https://brave.com/transparency/"&gt;Brave claims&lt;/a&gt; that its browser had almost 40 million monthly active users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eNOxJT"&gt;As well as boosting the prominence of Brave’s search engine, the move is a sign of its confidence in the new privacy-focused service. Brave Search is notable for being built on Brave’s own independent index of the web, whereas many competitors rely on a mix of results from larger indexes like Microsoft’s Bing (although Brave has said it will pull in results from other providers where it can’t produce enough of its own). The company says its search engine does not track “users, their searches, or their clicks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFzJ21"&gt;Alongside the change in default search engine, Brave is also launching a new opt-in system for users to contribute their data and help improve its search results. Brave claims its Web Discovery Project collects search and browsing data in a way that can’t be linked to individual users, and that cannot be sold to advertisers or handed over to the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XkUHQ0"&gt;Brave Search is currently free to use and does not show any ads, but the company says that it plans to roll out ads in its free version in the future, as well as launch an ad-free premium service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1P62nz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V24Zrg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736142/brave-browser-search-engine-default-google-quant-duckduckgo-web-discovery-project"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736142/brave-browser-search-engine-default-google-quant-duckduckgo-web-discovery-project</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How NFTs are creating a generational divide between platforms  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lbyBZicF2WurRzWSfUKeTjt3YFA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70019384/acastro_210319_1777_nft_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RrQZNW"&gt;Today, let’s talk about a fault line that’s beginning to open up in the gaming world, one I suspect will soon be coming to most platforms and app stores. It’s a divide that begins with a simple question: will your platform allow NFTs? Crypto payments? You know … &lt;em&gt;blockchain stuff&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldZEbU"&gt;Like it or not, the rise of non-fungible tokens as an engine for fun and profit has been one of the tech world’s big stories in 2021. Using &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22654785/blockchain-explained-cryptocurrency-what-is-stake-nft"&gt;the blockchain&lt;/a&gt; to create unique digital objects with verifiable, transferrable ownership has opened up new possibilities in art, digital trading cards, and gaming. At least for the moment, it seems likely that other forms of media will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n6IMGp"&gt;Recently I’ve written about ways in which NFTs are challenging the current generation’s assumptions about gaming: building a game from the bottom up rather than the top down, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22655077/loot-social-network-open-source-nft"&gt;as the Loot project is doing&lt;/a&gt;; or enabling players to make money directly from their gameplay, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22725083/axie-infinity-sky-mavis-blockchain-economy-game-pokemon"&gt;as Axie Infinity is&lt;/a&gt;. Aleksander Larsen, chief operating officer of Axie’s parent company, told me that he hopes the game will come to mobile app stores, including Apple’s, within the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wMGAWb"&gt;But on Friday, it became clear that such games won’t be welcome everywhere. Here’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728425/valve-steam-blockchain-nft-crypto-ban-games-age-of-rust"&gt;Mitchell Clark here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Wljyvf"&gt;Games that use blockchain technology or let users exchange NFTs or cryptocurrencies won’t be allowed on Steam, according to a rule added to &lt;a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/gettingstarted/onboarding"&gt;Valve’s “What you shouldn’t publish on Steam” list&lt;/a&gt;. The change &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io/status/1448713803680473089"&gt;was pointed out by SpacePirate&lt;/a&gt;, a developer working on an NFT-based game, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io/status/1448713807312801796?s=20"&gt;who said&lt;/a&gt; that the change was because the company doesn’t allow game items that could have real-world value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="qKCfIF"&gt;Steam, if you’re not familiar, is the largest distributor of PC gaming software in the world. With &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-01-14-steam-has-over-120m-monthly-active-users"&gt;more than 120 million monthly users&lt;/a&gt;, it’s the default place for most PC gamers to buy digital downloads. And last week, as some blockchain-based games had begun to appear on the platform, Steam pulled out the rug from underneath them. Parent company Valve has yet to make a comment beyond its update to the Steam rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HI1me2"&gt;The developer of &lt;em&gt;Age of Rust&lt;/em&gt;, a forthcoming adventure game that will award NFTs to players who solve puzzles, was among those whose titles were removed from the platform. The developer, SpacePirate Games, lamented the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fi6Zuu"&gt;“Steam’s point of view is that items have value and they don’t allow items that can have real-world value on their platform,” the game’s official account &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io/status/1448713805723099137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1448713807312801796%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es2_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F15%2F22728425%2Fvalve-steam-blockchain-nft-crypto-ban-games-age-of-rust"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “While I respect their choice, I fundamentally believe that NFTs and blockchain games are the future. It’s why I started this journey with all of you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vEOGEW"&gt;But when one app store door closes, another opens. The Epic Games Store, a Steam rival that the &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; maker introduced in 2018, quickly said that it is “open” to considering NFT-based games. Here’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22729050/epic-game-store-open-to-blockchain-cryptocurrency-nft-games"&gt;Clark again&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="CfWzy8"&gt;When we asked about allowing games that featured NFTs, Epic told us there’d be some limitations, but that it’s willing to work with “early developers” in the “new field.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHGuVM"&gt;Epic says that the games would have to comply with financial laws, make it clear how the blockchain is used, and have appropriate age ratings. It also says that developers won’t be able to use Epic’s payment service to accept crypto; they would have to use their own payment systems instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="53fGLF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="laAM25"&gt;Among the reasons this came as a surprise is that just weeks earlier, Epic CEO Tim Sweeney had seemed to wash his hands of the blockchain altogether. “We aren’t touching NFTs,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1442519522875949061"&gt;he tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, “as the whole field is currently tangled up with an intractable mix of scams, interesting decentralized tech foundations, and scams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ao6tU5"&gt;Sweeney is well within the mainstream of tech commentary when he worries that NFTs are scammy. When I wrote about &lt;em&gt;Axie&lt;/em&gt; last week, a lot of you shared similar sentiments with me in the &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/announcing-sidechannel-a-new-community"&gt;Sidechannel Discord server&lt;/a&gt; and in your email replies. Aren’t these NFT projects fundamentally pyramid schemes, you wondered; Why does any of this have to be on the blockchain at all? There are other ways to represent digital scarcity beyond the blockchain, you told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iAqySP"&gt;In any case, grinding for several hours a day to make money playing a &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; clone hardly sounds like most people’s idea of a good time. If it’s a full-time job, can you really even call it a game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="geyIdM"&gt;Despite those objections, though, the development continues. Each day brings with it a fresh round of funding announcements for blockchain-based projects, with hundreds of millions of dollars being allocated into crypto-focused startups and VC funds. Games, which have proven to be one of the first crypto projects to attract a user base that does something other than trade money back and forth, often figure significantly in those fundraising announcements. (Here’s $4.6 million for &lt;a href="https://medium.com/yield-guild-games/ygg-raises-4-6m-from-a16z-to-accelerate-play-to-earn-gaming-7f5cbccce657"&gt;a company that rents &lt;em&gt;Axie&lt;/em&gt; monsters to players in exchange for a slice of their income&lt;/a&gt;, for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HWfXJh"&gt;All of which is soon going to put platforms into the same position that Steam found itself in. Do we let these things into the store or not? The easy thing to do is to say “no” — but doing so creates an opportunity for anyone willing to say yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KALzk9"&gt;To be sure, the sale of in-game items has a checkered history. Blizzard’s popular dungeon crawler &lt;em&gt;Diablo III&lt;/em&gt; set up an official in-game auction house a decade ago to let players sell rare swords, armor, and other goods that they had earned in virtual battle. These items weren’t unique in the way NFTs are, but they were rare and had real-world value. Unfortunately, though, Blizzard found that its auction house broke the game entirely: all of a sudden, people could simply pay to win it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5YG9TG"&gt;Here’s &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/2013/09/diablo-auction-house/"&gt;Bo Moore writing in &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt; in 2013, when the auction house was shuttered&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="zRO779"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diablo&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t have more dungeons, more bosses, etc. Players just play the same procession of levels on harder and harder difficulty levels, picking up better and better loot. In other words, the loot isn’t just a helping hand towards their ultimate goal – better loot &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the ultimate goal. And with the auction house, players found that the best way to obtain it was to just buy it. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PJvGPu"&gt;And the next thing you know, they’re not playing the game anymore. Why would they, when the reward structure that would otherwise motivate them to play was no longer there? Without the promise of better stuff, &lt;em&gt;Diablo&lt;/em&gt; was all stick and no carrot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="k6XffQ"&gt;Games that develop this “pay to win” dynamic are among the most-loathed titles around — but they are &lt;a href="https://fictionhorizon.com/best-pay-to-win-games/"&gt;very much around&lt;/a&gt;. Games that offer free downloads, as many mobile games do, often allow players to pay to gain advantages over their freeloading rivals, even as it worsens the experience for most of the user base. More respectable games, like &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, sell only cosmetic items. But the pay-to-win economy is real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R7tPv7"&gt;Of course, there’s no reason that in-game NFTs bought from third parties have to give players advantages in gameplay. A unique &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; skin created by a popular artist might have value to both the person who sold it and the person who bought it, and the balance of gameplay wouldn’t change at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="98piSU"&gt;But even for platforms inclined to support blockchain integrations, there remain a number of hurdles to clear on the policy and user experience side. How and where does the buying and selling take place? Does the platform get a cut of the sale? And if NFTs do affect how the game is played, rather than simply how it looks, how does the developer ensure the game is balanced and accessible to a large number of players?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Kjp5Jj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Platforms will be faced with a choice&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UcoQSg"&gt;The questions are coming to gaming first, but it’s easy to imagine them cropping up elsewhere in the new economy. And when they do, platforms will be faced with a choice: shut it all down, as Steam did, and bet that the whole crypto craze will some day fall into the ocean; or be curious about it, the way Epic is, and see if there’s a way to channel all this developer enthusiasm into something creative and profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mex7uP"&gt;It’s worth noting that most big believers in the tech world’s &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; big prediction about the future this year — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;the metaverse&lt;/a&gt; — come down firmly on the side of NFT integration. Mark Zuckerberg described for Facebook employees this summer a world in which people would one day rent NFT art as decorations for parties in virtual reality. The idea of unique NFT skins that people can dress up their avatars in, and take from place to virtual place, is foundational to the metaverse as futurists most often describe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="adcdTS"&gt;Maybe that will all fall into the ocean, too. But one way or another, I think digital scarcity is coming to platforms. And when it does, they’ll have a lot of re-thinking to do. For now, Valve loses nothing by leaving NFTs behind. But there may come a day soon when it’s companies like Valve getting left behind, and developers like SpacePirate laughing all the way to the bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Irlgpb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Platformer by Casey Newton","description":"&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;This column was co-published with&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a class=\"ql-link\" href=\"https://www.platformer.news/\" target=\"_blank\"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Platformer&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;","label":"Subscribe here","url":"https://www.platformer.news/"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22735719/nft-generational-divide-steam-epic-gaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22735719/nft-generational-divide-steam-epic-gaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T00:09:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T00:09:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix boss says he “screwed up” over Chappelle special fallout</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pBxNE5fsWQNw8aJuMe2O8JuGU3o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018988/acastro_181101_1777_netflix_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fMxCI1"&gt;Mere hours before a planned walkout from Netflix’s trans and allied workers over comments made by Dave Chappelle in a recent special, co-CEO Ted Sarandos has said he “screwed up” over his response to employees over outrage from within the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ryo4xU"&gt;Chappelle’s special &lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt; debuted on the streaming service earlier this month and immediately came under fire from members and allies of the LGBTQ+ community as well as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720724/netflix-suspends-trans-employee-tweeted-dave-chappelle-the-closer"&gt;Netflix employees&lt;/a&gt; who criticized the special as being transphobic. Sarandos, for his part, has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720724/netflix-suspends-trans-employee-tweeted-dave-chappelle-the-closer"&gt;stood by the special&lt;/a&gt;, telling employees that Netflix doesn’t allow titles on its service “that are designed to incite hate or violence, and we don’t believe &lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt; crosses that line.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8JERKz"&gt;In an interview with &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/film/news/dave-chappelle-netflix-ted-sarandos-i-screwed-up-1235093098/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; published on the eve of the planned walkout, the Netflix executive says he “should have led with a lot more humanity” in his internal responses to his employees, though he continues to defend the special on the grounds of “creative freedom and artistic expression.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RhvFi3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I should have led with a lot more humanity.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0NuYa5"&gt;“Meaning, I had a group of employees who were definitely feeling pain and hurt from a decision we made. And I think that needs to be acknowledged up front before you get into the nuts and bolts of anything,” Sarandos tells the publication. “I didn’t do that. That was uncharacteristic for me, and it was moving fast and we were trying to answer some really specific questions that were floating. We landed with some things that were much more blanket and matter-of-fact that are not at all accurate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XvzbKQ"&gt;When asked to define how Netflix defines hate speech, Sarandos said that the company draws the line “on something that would intentionally call for physically harming other people or even remove protections. For me, intent to cause physical harm crosses the line, for sure.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WgW4qh"&gt;Separately, Sarandos spoke with &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/netflix-ted-sarandos-dave-chappelle-walkout-1235033910/?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — also for an interview published late Tuesday ahead of the planned walkout. As he did in his interview with &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;, Sarandos makes it clear that he stands by the special but characterizes his response to criticism of &lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt; as a “just very clumsy, internal communications that went public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2EoE9"&gt;In both interviews, Sarandos says he’s been meeting with Netflix employees about their position on the special. But he reiterates repeatedly in both that the company heavily values what he characterized as “artistic expression” and adds that Netflix would continue to stand by that position as part of its ethos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mDGwTh"&gt;Sarandos spoke with other publications as well, including &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/10/netflix-ted-sarandos-speaks-up-dave-chapplle-the-closer-controversy-interview-1234858762/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/netflix-co-ceo-says-he-screwed-up-when-defending-dave-chappelle-special-11634696007"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. His comments remain, by and large, the same in all of his quoted conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22735949/netflix-boss-screwed-chappelle-special-the-closer-walkout"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22735949/netflix-boss-screwed-chappelle-special-the-closer-walkout</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T00:02:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T00:02:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo reportedly developing own chips for flagship phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FRZORTnZ9nDo2ASDfyNolvOwtAg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018964/DSCF7705.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Oppo’s current Find X3 Pro flagship phone. | Photo by Sam Byford / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XUEALA"&gt;Oppo is developing its own high-end chips for flagship mobile phones, &lt;a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Tech/Semiconductors/China-s-Oppo-joins-race-to-develop-own-smartphone-chips"&gt;according to a report in &lt;em&gt;Nikkei&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Two people who spoke to the newspaper said that the plan was to release custom SoCs in 2023 or 2024 “depending on the speed of development.” Oppo reportedly wants to use TSMC’s advanced 3nm process technology for the chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jBVSiO"&gt;If plans come to pass, Oppo would be the latest major smartphone manufacturer to take control of its own SoC design. Yesterday Google launched the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro, its first phones with a custom SoC called Tensor. Apple and Samsung also design their own smartphone chips, as did Huawei before US sanctions decimated its mobile business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Z7C5N1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sundar Pichai and Rick Osterloh think the Pixel 6 is Google’s breakout phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22733159/sundar-pichai-rick-osterloh-google-pixel-6-interview-podcast"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vXhS7y"&gt;Oppo currently uses chips from Qualcomm and MediaTek, like all other Chinese smartphone vendors since the crackdown on Huawei. Xiaomi designed and released a low-end SoC called the Surge S1 for its budget Mi 5C phone in 2017, but since then its chip design efforts have been limited to secondary components like image signal processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYRst8"&gt;As Qualcomm laid bare in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728062/qualcomm-pixel-6-google-tensor-snapdragon-meme"&gt;salty Google subtweet&lt;/a&gt; last week, it would stand to lose out if major companies like Oppo were to take on SoC design themselves. Oppo is the fourth largest smartphone maker in the world by shipments, according to IDC, and given it shares a supply chain and ownership with Vivo, Realme and OnePlus, Oppo-developed chips could quickly find their way into phones from multiple brands.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22735935/oppo-own-chip-development-google-tensor-qualcomm"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22735935/oppo-own-chip-development-google-tensor-qualcomm</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T23:27:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T23:27:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>The IATSE’s strike-averting deal means better pay on streaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="los angeles iatse union film strike" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1orzywPxpvjdbwdmWMEgCnui-Mk=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018878/1235538479.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Myung J. Chun / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TyhxQH"&gt;Streaming services may pay up to 30 percent more to production workers as part of the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees’ (IATSE) deal with major Hollywood studios to avert a strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kFiIrw"&gt;The union tweeted a document that specifically outlined the new streaming terms of the tentative Basic Agreement. According to the one-sheet, the new agreement would secure higher wages for episodic streaming productions, including longform miniseries with runtimes longer than 66 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZweH5c"&gt;Payouts on some miniseries could increase up to 30 percent, which will depend on how the project is classified. Longform productions that cost between $20 and $32 million, meanwhile, will no longer get a discount on account of the production heading to a streaming service. This type of production, too, will see a rate increase of up to 30 percent in some cases, the union said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EXbSm2"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NEW: We are releasing our first three one page documents explaining how the new tentative Basic Agreement addresses the priorities members identified early in the bargaining process.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a non-exhaustive set of member priorities, more soon.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1. STREAMING IMPROVEMENTS &lt;a href="https://t.co/ACLP5cbLiv"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ACLP5cbLiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— IATSE // #IASolidarity (@IATSE) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IATSE/status/1450646990279282689?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nuMNS0"&gt;Production crew represented by IATSE who are working on low-budget productions of 20 minutes or longer will get better wages, terms, and conditions, but the details are vague. The document specified only that this category of productions was tentatively to be “set at no less than the mid-budget wages, terms and conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKTizU"&gt;The union also tweeted fact sheets related to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IATSE/status/1450647001922670593/photo/1"&gt;wages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IATSE/status/1450646995790598146/photo/1"&gt;workplace conditions&lt;/a&gt; — both points of contention as the union worked to negotiate with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers (AMPTP) for better labor protections for its members. Much is left unclear by the one-sheets, however, particularly where it relates to streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mPJjr6"&gt;“We intend to provide as much information [as] possible, and as soon as possible,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IATSE/status/1450647003403374594"&gt;the union said in a tweet&lt;/a&gt;. “That way, each of us will have a chance to get the full picture and make an informed decision regarding our shared future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V3DzGR"&gt;As negotiations between the IATSE and AMPTP stalled prior to last week, the union’s members &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22711567/iatse-strike-authorization-negotiations-resume-streaming-pay"&gt;voted nearly unanimously&lt;/a&gt; to strike — an event that was planned for this week should contract negotiations continue to be held up. The strike was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/17/22731087/hollywood-union-reaches-contract-agreement-iatse-avoids-strike"&gt;narrowly avoided&lt;/a&gt; when a tentative agreement was reached between the two organizations over the weekend. The contract must be ratified by the union’s members, however, some of whom have characterized the terms as &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/film/news/iatse-deal-backlash-nothing-changed-1235091286/"&gt;failing to meet their demands&lt;/a&gt;. Members could ultimately choose to vote against it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735892/iatses-tentative-basic-agreement-streaming-pay"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735892/iatses-tentative-basic-agreement-streaming-pay</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T22:14:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T22:14:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is planning to rebrand the company with a new name</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fBUh6E31xNvLxZx6U-nbWG7s13k=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018751/acastro_072121_4674_zuckerberg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge Photo by Justin Sullivan / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3BQkSw"&gt;Facebook is planning to change its company name next week to reflect its focus on building the metaverse, according to a source with direct knowledge of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dN7MdP"&gt;The coming name change, which CEO Mark Zuckerberg plans to talk about at the company’s annual Connect conference on October 28th, but could unveil sooner, is meant to signal the tech giant’s ambition to be known for more than social media and all the ills that entail. The rebrand would likely position the blue Facebook app as one of many products under a parent company overseeing groups like Instagram, WhatsApp, Oculus, and more. A spokesperson for Facebook declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="roHgyg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook intends to transition to “being a metaverse company”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fJZxHn"&gt;Facebook already has more than 10,000 employees building consumer hardware like AR glasses that Zuckerberg believes will eventually be as ubiquitous as smartphones. In July, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview"&gt;he told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that, over the next several years, “we will effectively transition from people seeing us as primarily being a social media company to being a metaverse company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JSxAWP"&gt;A rebrand could also serve to further separate the futuristic work Zuckerberg is focused on from the intense scrutiny Facebook is currently under for the way its social platform operates today. A former employee turned whistleblower, Frances Haugen, recently leaked a trove of damning internal documents to &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710539/facebook-whistleblower-hearing-instagram-child-safety-congress"&gt;testified about them before Congress&lt;/a&gt;. Antitrust regulators in the US and elsewhere are trying to break the company up, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22702798/verge-tech-survey-2021-trust-privacy-security-facebook-amazon-google-apple-pandemic"&gt;public trust&lt;/a&gt; in how Facebook does business is falling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hB6AhR"&gt;Facebook isn’t the first well-known tech company to change its company name as its ambitions expand. In 2015, Google reorganized entirely under a holding company called Alphabet, partly to signal that it was no longer just a search engine, but a sprawling conglomerate with companies making driverless cars and health tech. And Snapchat rebranded to Snap Inc. in 2016, the same year it started calling itself a “camera company” and debuted its first pair of Spectacles camera glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rl2grI"&gt;I’m told that the new Facebook company name is a closely-guarded secret within its walls and not known widely, even among its full senior leadership. A possible name could have something to do with Horizon, the name of the still-unreleased VR version of Facebook-meets-Roblox that the company has been developing for the past few years. The name of that app was recently tweaked to &lt;a href="https://uploadvr.com/facebook-horizon-changes/"&gt;Horizon Worlds&lt;/a&gt; shortly after Facebook demoed a version for workplace collaboration &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22629942/facebook-workrooms-horizon-oculus-vr"&gt;called Horizon Workrooms&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ww3bJx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook has been laying the groundwork for a branding change&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PiMXev"&gt;Aside from Zuckerberg’s comments, Facebook has been steadily laying the groundwork for a greater focus on the next generation of technology. This past summer it set up a dedicated metaverse team. More recently, it announced that the head of AR and VR, Andrew Bosworth, will be promoted to chief technology officer. And just a couple of days ago Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/facebook-plans-hire-10000-eu-build-metaverse-2021-10-17/"&gt;announced plans&lt;/a&gt; to hire 10,000 more employees to work on the metaverse in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7m6rI"&gt;The metaverse is “going to be a big focus, and I think that this is just going to be a big part of the next chapter for the way that the internet evolves after the mobile internet,” Zuckerberg told &lt;em&gt;The Verge’&lt;/em&gt;s Casey Newton&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;this summer. “And I think it’s going to be the next big chapter for our company too, really doubling down in this area.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="av8JCk"&gt;Complicating matters is that, while Facebook has been heavily promoting the idea of the metaverse in recent weeks, it’s still not a concept that’s widely understood. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;The term was coined&lt;/a&gt; originally by sci-fi novelist Neal Stephenson to describe a virtual world people escape to from a dystopian, real world. Now it’s being adopted by one of the world’s largest and most controversial companies — and it’ll have to explain why its own virtual world is worth diving into.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T19:30:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T19:30:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Activision Blizzard is trying to get the discrimination suit thrown out of court</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Activision Blizzard employees stage a walkout in the response from company leadership to a lawsuit highlighting alleged harassment, inequality" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WG-BdiDrd3SmWZfeUX5KmcGmAHI=/10x0:4191x2787/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018394/1234304012.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Zy4EVP"&gt;Activision Blizzard, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597113/activision-blizzard-california-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-discrimination-employee-action"&gt;facing a discrimination lawsuit from the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing&lt;/a&gt; (or DFEH), has filed an application to stay that lawsuit so it can investigate claims that DFEH lawyers engaged in ethical misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ib1oil"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21088626-activision-blizzard-et-als-ex-parte-application-to-stay-the-case/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="ACTIVISION BLIZZARD, ET AL.'S EX PARTE APPLICATION TO STAY THE CASE (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6zB7gp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j7VHZD"&gt;The application claims that the DFEH is represented in the case by lawyers who previously worked for the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (or EEOC)  — a federal agency that investigates claims of workplace abuse. The application additionally claims such an arrangement is in violation of a California State Bar conflict of interest rule that says, “a lawyer who has formerly served as a public official or employee of the government [...] shall not otherwise represent a client in connection with a matter in which the lawyer participated personally and substantially as a public official or employee.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7SPcln"&gt;The application basically alleges that DFEH lawyers should be disqualified from participating in this case against Activision Blizzard since those lawyers previously worked on a similar, prior case against the company when they were employed by the EEOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06wp5V"&gt;Activision Blizzard &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697341/us-eeoc-sues-activision-blizzard-sexual-harassment-discrimination"&gt;recently settled&lt;/a&gt; another discrimination lawsuit brought forth by the EEOC for $18 million. The DFEH is trying to block that settlement, and it’s actually the EEOC that raised ethical concerns against DFEH lawyers (perhaps to maintain its win). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ahjdh"&gt;“The EEOC claims that two of the DFEH attorneys who have appeared in this case (and who currently ‘play leadership roles within the [DFEH]’) ‘previously served as EEOC [REDACTED],’ during which time they ‘helped to direct the EEOC’s investigation’ against Activision Blizzard,” the application states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7DRnRk"&gt;If the court upholds the stay and decides that DFEH lawyers did violate conflict of interest rules, Activision Blizzard claims the case could be in serious trouble. According to the company’s filing, “Violation of these rules could lead to the disqualification not only of the two attorneys at issue, but of the entire group of DFEH attorneys with whom they have worked. It also calls into question the integrity of the underlying investigation itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpZOho"&gt;This move comes just as Blizzard announced 20 employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735413/activision-blizzard-employee-terminations-harassment-discrimination"&gt;“exited” the company&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of harassment investigations and reprimanded some 20 more. In the months since these lawsuits were made public, some Blizzard employees have continued to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598410/activision-blizzard-employee-walk-out-protest-sexism-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;agitate for a more equitable workplace&lt;/a&gt;, making demands of the company to end forced arbitration and provide greater pay transparency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZHbSbD"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our demands remain as follows and chief suite still fails to acknowledge them. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ABetterABK?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ABetterABK&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EndAbuseInGaming?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#EndAbuseInGaming&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;a href="https://t.co/4Tk7aV9DjD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4Tk7aV9DjD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— ABetterABK   ABK Workers Alliance (@ABetterABK) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ABetterABK/status/1433466353726361603?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KmeZxZ"&gt;The EEOC and the DFEH didn’t immediately respond to requests for comment, and neither the DFEH nor the EEOC have had a chance to formally challenge Activision Blizzard’s claims: neither have filed responses to this application in the courts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RMmKNQ"&gt;A Blizzard spokesperson says of the filings, “We look forward to resolving the case with the DFEH fairly in an appropriate court. We share the EEOC and DFEH’s goal of a safe, inclusive workplace that rewards employees equitably and remain committed to the elimination of harassment and discrimination in our workplace.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="isd4s9"&gt;A hearing on the application will take place October 20th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735273/activision-blizzard-requests-stay-in-harassment-lawsuit-alleging-conflict-of-interest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735273/activision-blizzard-requests-stay-in-harassment-lawsuit-alleging-conflict-of-interest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T19:20:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T19:20:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: the MacBook Pro 14-inch’s $20 power brick upsell is probably worth it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NIO_tKL0ve33zAqcLcjYg4abcPg=/147x0:1761x1076/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018348/lcimg_f1ce43fd_90a7_4584_bc4f_63c9935d516b.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dSAcBZ"&gt;If you’re looking at buying the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;$1,999 base model MacBook Pro 14-inch&lt;/a&gt;, there’s one upgrade that you may really want to make — the $20 one that gets you the 96W power adapter instead of the 67W included power adapter. That’s because, according to some wording on &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/macbook-pro/14-inch-space-gray-8-core-cpu-14-core-gpu-512gb#"&gt;Apple’s MacBook Pro configuration page&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/19/apple-67w-adapter-cant-fast-charge/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), you’ll need the more powerful charger if you want to take advantage of the computer’s fast charging feature, which can charge the laptop up to 50 percent in half an hour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="om07HD"&gt;Is it ridiculous that Apple is basically taxing the people who want to buy its least expensive (but still very pricey!) new MacBook Pro? Yes, absolutely — but you should still probably pay it if you want to charge your laptop up quickly. The exception is if you already have a charging brick capable of 100W USB-PD power delivery: Apple tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that you can fast charge via Thunderbolt as long as your power brick provides enough power. If you already have a beefy power brick, you can skip the upsell.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MVvDLva6vYe47MyboXqOnpcfEkM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940510/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_3.41.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This may be the best $20 you can spend on an accessory for your new MacBook Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qZIY2O"&gt;I know it probably doesn’t feel great to encourage Apple’s nickel-and-diming, but if you want fast charging, this will likely be the best way to get it. There may be, somewhere in the world, a 100W USB-PD charging brick that sells for $20, but there’s no way I would trust it enough to charge a very expensive computer. (If it was $20, I might not even trust it not to burn down my house). I’d pick the upsell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CjWk18"&gt;The one silver lining is that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733119/apple-new-macbook-pro-magsafe-back"&gt;this is only a problem on the base 8 CPU core / 14 GPU core model&lt;/a&gt; — if you do any processor upgrades, you’ll get the 96W brick for “free.” Please note, though, that upgrading just the RAM and/or storage on the base MacBook Pro won’t get you that upgrade, but if you’re in the configuration screen anyways, you should absolutely check that box unless you hate fast charging.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22735545/macbook-pro-14-base-model-usb-c-adapter-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22735545/macbook-pro-14-base-model-usb-c-adapter-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T18:47:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T18:47:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Pixel 6 doesn’t come with five years of Android updates — only three</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nSPoNXX5eOm7F6oh4iKbTkaetyA=/152x0:1768x1077/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018216/qMm7BP1Fye.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VerlUH"&gt;For the first time ever, Google’s new phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22710844/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-ai-speed-specs-details"&gt;are powered by a Google-designed chip&lt;/a&gt;, giving the company an Apple-like level of control over the inner workings of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;the new Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro.&lt;/a&gt; But if you were hoping that meant they’d also get an Apple-like level of new OS updates, the company is throwing a bit of cold water on that. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/4457705#zippy=%2Cpixel-xl-a-a-xl-xl-a-a-g-a-g%2Cpixel-pixel-pro-phones"&gt;Google’s support page shows it’s only promising&lt;/a&gt; to offer Android updates through October 2024 (via &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/google-pixel-6-three-years-os-updates-five-years-security-patches/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;), &lt;/em&gt;a total of three years after release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l4ikZY"&gt;“Users will still get at least 3 years of OS updates, after which we’re committing to ensure that Pixels will stay up-to-date and secure,” Google tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The frequency and categories of updates will depend on the capabilities and needs of the hardware.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7M9vCk"&gt;While Google prominently announced during its Tuesday keynote that the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro would get five years of &lt;em&gt;security&lt;/em&gt; updates — two years more! — it seems that Android version updates (like Android 11, Android 12, etc) are another story. And though Google is technically saying it will offer new versions of Android until “at least” October 2024, the company hasn’t historically gone above and beyond those sorts of promises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qv8tNy"&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523351/ios-15-iphone-6s-plus-se-compatibility"&gt;the six-year-old iPhone 6S recently got an update to iOS 15&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735485/google-pixel-6-three-years-android-updates-security-feature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735485/google-pixel-6-three-years-android-updates-security-feature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T18:19:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T18:19:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>A future update to Facebook’s Portal will stop kids from watching content unsupervised</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Facebook Enters Living Room With Video Chat-Focused TV Box" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SYIaiMdcZYpnobu6AzEss0_7C50=/0x2:3000x2002/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018131/1169034208.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="B7hcVR"&gt;Facebook is delivering an update to Portal devices that will make it possible to turn off the Watch Together feature during calls in Household Mode. The update comes shortly after&lt;em&gt; a &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/katienotopoulos/facebooks-portal-go-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; article criticized Facebook’s blatant oversight of not including an “off” switch for the feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wy6TwE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/14/21433086/facebook-messenger-watch-together-video-messaging"&gt;Watch Together lets you watch shows, music videos, or funny clips&lt;/a&gt; with distant friends or family members. Choose a video from Facebook’s selection, and it’ll be simultaneously presented to you on your Portal and on your friend’s device, whether that may be a phone, tablet, or Portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ytp59q"&gt;Watch Together may sound like a great idea, but it obviously isn’t ideal for parents who want to keep their kids away from videos on the internet. When a Portal device is in Household Mode, everyone in the house has access to it, and that includes kids. The Watch Together feature remains hidden in Household Mode, but it reappears during calls. This can be a recipe for disaster, as &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; noted, since kids can grab ahold of the device, start up a call, and begin watching videos with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JfQNk3"&gt;Right now, there’s no way to disable Watch Together during calls in Household Mode — likely leaving some parents feeling frustrated — but that’s all about to change. In response to the &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; report, Andrew Bosworth, the vice president of Facebook Reality Labs, sent out a tweet that says Facebook is working on a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k2pXz4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;All Portal devices are for families to use together and not designed for kids to be used without parental supervision. That said, ask and you shall receive, we are rolling out the ability to turn off Watch Together in calls via Household Mode in December.&lt;/p&gt;— Boz (@boztank) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/boztank/status/1450494485536788485?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nMNm8E"&gt;Users will get the ability to disable Watch Together during calls in Household Mode in December, but it’s sort of disappointing that it didn’t come with this feature in the first place. It feels like an oversight that could’ve — and should’ve — never happened, especially because Facebook is catering &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22732472/facebook-portal-go-10-inch-2021-review"&gt;the new Portal Go&lt;/a&gt; to kids. If the device is so kid-friendly, why does it require you to have a Facebook account to use it, and why didn’t it come with stricter parental controls out of the box?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735364/facebook-turn-off-watch-together-during-calls-household-mode"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735364/facebook-turn-off-watch-together-during-calls-household-mode</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
