<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-24T19:31:23-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T19:31:23-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T19:31:23-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mission: Impossible release dates have been pushed back again</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eTjyIbqk_pDZCfue_Sz_xJKJzuE=/856x0:7336x4320/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427872/mi6-ff-h055rb.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Mission: Impossible Fallout | Photo: Paramount Pictures&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C0xfy1"&gt;The release dates of the seventh and eighth installments of the &lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible&lt;/em&gt; series have been pushed back again due to pandemic-related delays, &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2022/01/mission-impossible-movies-new-release-dates-covid-1234917458/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. The two flicks are the latest in a long list of movies to be delayed by the pandemic, which upended Hollywood as it has struggled to deal with closed movie theaters and halted or scaled back productions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3knJpq"&gt;The films &lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible 7&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible 8&lt;/em&gt;, both co-produced by Paramount Pictures and Skydance, are the latest installments in the film series that began in 1996, starring Tom Cruise as Ethan Hunt, an agent for Impossible Mission Force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MNEWY9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible 7&lt;/em&gt; was supposed to be released last year on September 30th but is now set for July 14th, 2023, and &lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible 8’s&lt;/em&gt; original release date was &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2022/film/news/mission-impossible-7-8-postponed-until-2023-2024-covid-pandemic-1235159996/"&gt;most recently&lt;/a&gt; set for July 7th, 2023 but was pushed to June 28th, 2024. &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/mission-impossible-7-8-no-longer-shooting-back-to-back-1234693984/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadline &lt;/em&gt;reported in February 2021&lt;/a&gt; that the original plan called for the two movies to be shot back-to-back, but according to &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;’s sources, Paramount changed the plan because the release schedule at the time was still so uncertain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qj0XEi"&gt;Another Cruise movie, &lt;em&gt;Top Gun: Maverick, &lt;/em&gt;the sequel to the 1986 blockbuster &lt;em&gt;Top Gun&lt;/em&gt;, was initially set to be released in 2019 but also was delayed several times. It’s currently still on track to be released this year, on May 27th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899256/mission-impossible-7-8-delayed-movie-tom-cruise-paramount"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899256/mission-impossible-7-8-delayed-movie-tom-cruise-paramount</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T18:37:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T18:37:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Philips Hue outdoor lights add an old-timey vibe to your smart home</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OAmjK-t1ZHqplaTlAsDnzPbAPoE=/0x88:3500x2421/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427724/Philips_Hue_Inara.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philips Hue’s new smart outdoor light fixture the Inara harkens back to a less high-tech time.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Signify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nzLh4h"&gt;Spring is coming (soon, we promise), and smart lighting company Philips Hue has some new products that can help you spruce up your outdoor space, so you can enjoy spending more time outside when the ice finally melts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y0i0Tf"&gt;Signify, which owns Philips Hue, has announced three new additions to its outdoor smart lighting line, all arriving in the US on March 1st, 2022. Plus, two new lighting effects are scheduled to arrive on the Hue app later this year to add features to its indoor smart bulbs.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oK2l6m"&gt;The Philips Hue Inara wall light ($99.99, available on March 1st) is a vintage-style outdoor wall light featuring a filament bulb. Also known as an Edison bulb, a filament bulb has its “electric” filament visible through the bulb, resembling that first incandescent bulb designed by Thomas Edison. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EAg009"&gt;This traditional look is popular in fixtures that feature an exposed bulb, and they’ve been everywhere indoors for a while now. This is the first outdoor version we’ve seen, but you can’t buy the outdoor bulb alone and pop it into an existing fixture since it’s only available inside the Inara’s black vintage-style lantern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Dpnii"&gt;The Inara doesn’t have the color-changing options of Hue’s signature bulbs, instead, you can adjust the brightness of the filament bulb in the app, with a remote control (sold separately), or with your voice (it’s compatible with Amazon Alexa, Apple’s Siri, and Google Assistant voice assistants.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gZCfgeqkgbfJC6eXV7zcUm3x3NI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23192417/Philips_Hue_Lucca.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Signify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philips Hue’s new Lucca wall light has color-changing and white lighting options.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ANuagd"&gt;For something more colorful and a lot more contemporary, the new Lucca wall light ($99.99, available on March 1st) is an outdoor wall fixture with a round shape and black bands wrapped around it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X4G9mr"&gt;The Lucca offers white or color-changing light and is designed to be bold and bright, making it a good choice for smart lighting on a porch or balcony space where you want to be able to see what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0fuxHn9WxfEU6VGv72hrLthJy-I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23192427/Philips_Hue_Resonate.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Signify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Resonate wall light in black is another new option for smart outdoor lighting from Philips Hue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OZoa1d"&gt;The third new product is the Resonate wall light in black (available March 1st for $159.99). This is more of an atmospheric addition, with a minimalist design that casts either white light or colored light up and down a wall. This type of light is commonly used for highlighting architectural features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="73vg2i"&gt;All the new light fixtures work with the Philips Hue app and require the Philips Hue Bridge for automations such as turning on the lights as you arrive home. Hue offers an outdoor motion sensor that can pair with any of its lights for automatic activation. Hue products also work with Amazon Alexa, Google Home, Samsung SmartThings, and Apple HomeKit smart home platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i3SK4Z"&gt;Signify also announced that the Philips Hue app is getting an update in the first quarter of 2022. Two new effects are coming to the company’s indoor bulbs, candle and fireplace, which will let you set your Hue bulbs to mimic the glow of candlelight or a fireplace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UtSC8j"&gt;Third-party apps have offered these features for Hue bulbs for a while, and candlelight was part of the &lt;a href="https://labs.meethue.com/formulas/huelabs/candlelight-romance"&gt;Hue’s Labs section of its app&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s now making its way to the main app. Candle and fireplace effects will work on all compatible Philips Hue lights (both the hub-based Zigbee versions and the stand-alone Bluetooth bulbs). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899576/philips-hue-smart-outdoor-filament-light-price-release-date-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899576/philips-hue-smart-outdoor-filament-light-price-release-date-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T18:20:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T18:20:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Apple Watch Series 7" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u4_l39DGwYmgazbTsBa7JXG8W0E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66976955/vpavic_211006_4796_0061.15.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 currently starts at $349 instead of $399.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ozqXgk"&gt;Thinking about picking up a new Apple Watch to help you achieve your New Year’s fitness goals? It might be tempting to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22722533/apple-watch-series-7-review-screen-watchos-features"&gt;order one of the Series 7 models&lt;/a&gt;, but new hardware always comes at a premium. Apple’s latest wearable offers a slightly larger display and some improvements to durability but is largely the same Apple Watch we’re familiar with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxsAXI"&gt;Thankfully, each Apple Watch model offers ample functionality and has seen its fair share of discounts over the last year. So which ones should you consider if you’re in the market for Apple’s popular smartwatch while trying to shop smarter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FtR5HF"&gt;There are currently four Apple Watch models to choose from, all of which support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463618/apple-watchos-8-features-watch-wwdc-2021"&gt;watchOS 8&lt;/a&gt;. The highest-end is the Apple Watch Series 7, which starts at $399. Last year's model, the Series 6, has received a modest discount at some retailers since its release but is still usually found starting at $399 as well. If either of those models seems too expensive, however, you can save about $120 by opting for an Apple Watch SE, which will set you back $279.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="44jktU"&gt;Finally, there’s the aging &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;Series 3&lt;/a&gt;, the most affordable Apple Watch to date. It has a starting retail price of $199, but it frequently goes on sale. However, if you want something more future-proof, you may want to consider Apple’s newer watches, as it’s not clear how much longer Apple will issue software updates to the Series 3 beyond watchOS 8. Regardless of which model you prefer, we’ve rounded up the best Apple Watch deals below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Yen8lP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="hdRa4b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10741666"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OlUIlK"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;Apple Watch Series 3&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="c2iEiy"&gt;The regular price for the 38mm Series 3 is $199. It’s a decent entry-level Apple Watch if you are looking for a smartwatch with reliable battery life and solid build quality — especially if the SE, Series 6, and Series 7 seem out of your price range — but it’s also not one we would recommend picking up at this point. The design is aging, the processor is slower, and its paltry 8GB of internal storage hampers some of the more recent features introduced to the Apple Watch, like the ability to store music and podcasts for offline listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DSKChG"&gt;If you still want to go this route, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1229763/9383?subId1=TheVergeAppleWatchDeals172022&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Gen-3-Series-3-38mm-Space-Gray-Aluminum-Black-Sport-Band-MTF02LL-A%2F706203065%3F&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; is discounting the 38mm, GPS-enabled Series 3 in black by $30, bringing the price down to $169. If you prefer the bigger, 42mm configuration with GPS, it’s on sale at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-42mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F742230355%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; for $179 in white instead of $229. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="N8sVLO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514914"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="zc5j8W"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10741240"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3G29qi"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features"&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GaARPa"&gt;Starting at $279 for a 40mm version or $309 for the 44mm, the Apple Watch SE is a good midrange wearable that shares some features found on the like-minded Series 6 and Series 7, including a built-in accelerometer and hand-washing detection. However, it doesn’t have the always-on display found on Apple’s latest flagships, nor does it feature blood oxygen monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ryWZk"&gt;We’ve previously seen this wearable sell for as low as $219. At the moment, however, you can only buy the 40mm, GPS-equipped Watch SE with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-Cellular-40mm/dp/B09G93BDQP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gray aluminum case and the black Sport Band&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-Cellular-40mm/dp/B09G9FS5YN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold aluminum case with a white Sport Band&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon for $249 ($30 off). Meanwhile, at Walmart, you can buy the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1066108/9383?subId1=TheVergeAppleWatchDeals1242022&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-Cellular-44mm-Space-Gray-Aluminum-Case-with-Midnight-Sport-Band-Regular%2F637826600&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LTE version of this style&lt;/a&gt; — or one with a &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1207177/9383?subId1=TheVergeAppleWatchDeals1242022&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-Cellular-44mm-Space-Gray-Aluminum-Case-with-Midnight-Sport-Band-Regular%2F166559805" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold aluminum case and white Sport Band&lt;/a&gt; — for $299 instead of $329. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MYmSlw"&gt;Amazon is also selling the LTE versions for $299 in select styles, which is the lowest the retailer has sold these for. These include the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-Cellular-40mm/dp/B09G9FWZ28/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold model with the same Sport Band Walmart is selling&lt;/a&gt;, as well as one with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-Cellular-40mm/dp/B09G93YNKL/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;yellow-white Sport Loop&lt;/a&gt; and another with the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-Cellular-40mm/dp/B09G94T2R2/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gray aluminum case and gray Sport Loop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ebnXzp"&gt;For larger wrists, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-Cellular-40mm/dp/B09G9DT2KW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1229763/9383?subId1=TheVergeAppleWatchDeals172022&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-40mm-Silver-Aluminum-Case-with-White-Sport-Band-Regular%2F634588522&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; are both selling the bigger, 44mm, GPS model with the silver aluminum case and blue Sport Band for $269.49 instead of $309. Amazon is also discounting the 44mm, LTE-equipped model with the gray aluminum case and gray Sport Loop by $30, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-Cellular-40mm/dp/B09G998V5P/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;knocking the sale price down to $329&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k7Seuv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514947"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Dmq74g"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10966490"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xtEsXh"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-44mm-Gold-Aluminum-Case-with-Pink-Sand-Sport-Band-Regular%2F804932402%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"&gt; Watch Series 6&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oTrUCf"&gt;While &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/8/22716438/apple-watch-series-6-removes-lineup"&gt;it’s no longer officially a part of Apple’s wearable lineup&lt;/a&gt;, you can still buy the Apple Watch Series 6 at several retailers. The Apple Watch comes in two sizes, 40mm and 44mm, which start at $399 and $429, respectively. The Series 6 features built-in sleep tracking, a great ecosystem of third-party complications, and more sensors than previous models, including one that allows the device to detect your body's blood oxygen levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PfLoQg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9432291"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="60XJAV"&gt;Deals often come and go quickly on the Series 6. Right now, Walmart is selling the 40mm, GPS-enabled model for $349 in &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1167790/9383?subId1=VergeBestAppleWatchDeals012422&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;ps=60&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-40mm-Blue-Aluminum-Case-with-Deep-Navy-Sport-Band-Regular%2F386345423&amp;amp;_be_shelf_id=9987250&amp;amp;search_sort=100&amp;amp;facet=shelf_id%3A9987250&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;cat_id=0" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pink&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1219877/9383?subId1=TheVergeAppleWatchDeals172022&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-40mm-Blue-Aluminum-Case-with-Deep-Navy-Sport-Band-Regular%2F478251261&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;red&lt;/a&gt;. However, given the fact the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HDYWTPV/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;41mm Series 7 with GPS is on sale for the same price&lt;/a&gt;, we suggest picking up that model instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TZUJcQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our over 42,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="hZHCRf"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22722533/apple-watch-series-7-review-screen-watchos-features"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="iK520N"&gt;With a slightly altered design and larger display, the new Series 7 comes in either a 41mm configuration starting at $399 or a 45mm model starting at $429. Right now, you can pick up the 41mm, GPS-equipped model at Amazon for $349 in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HF1DC1J/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HF7W3N6/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;black&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HDYWTPV/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;red&lt;/a&gt; with various color Sport Bands. Both Walmart and Amazon are also selling the cellular version for $449 ($50 off) in the green (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HF6QF5J/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1115493/9383?subId1=TheVergeAppleWatchDeals&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-7-GPS-Cellular-41mm-Midnight-Aluminum-Case-with-Midnight-Sport-Band-Regular%2F414229489&amp;amp;typeahead=clea&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;) and black (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HDTHSDN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1207177/9383?subId1=TheVergeAppleWatchDeals&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-7-GPS-Cellular-41mm-Midnight-Aluminum-Case-with-Midnight-Sport-Band-Regular%2F792968586" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;) colorways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uBoAQG"&gt;If you prefer the larger, 45mm variant with GPS, it’s currently available in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HF6XBPF/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;black&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-Midnight-Aluminum-Sport/dp/B09HDW92NZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;white&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon for $379 instead of $429. The retailer is also selling the 45mm model with LTE for $479 instead of $529 — its lowest price to date — in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09HFM35F9/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;red&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09HDTBYFP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4m59DD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860351"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="rwvKCC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860357"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="0vo8YZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple Watch Series 8 may not have a body temperature sensor after all","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22876324/apple-watch-series-8-body-temperature-smartwatch"},{"title":"Light sensors on wearables struggle with dark skin and obesity","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/21/22893133/apple-fitbit-heart-rate-sensor-skin-tone-obesity"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h3 id="J2hTVr"&gt;A note on the more premium models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7aHrsm"&gt;While all of the Apple Watch models and colorways covered here are encased in aluminum, Apple does make a more premium range built out of stainless steel and titanium. These offerings have similar designs to their aluminum counterparts, with slightly refined colors and finishings — polished for the stainless steel, brushed for the titanium. However, they start at much steeper prices of $749 and above, and they are functionally the same, save for some exclusive digital watch faces Apple reserves for these premium models. Overall, the upmarket stainless, titanium, and Hermès edition Apple Watches also don’t usually get the discounts and sales as the aluminum models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hjNY0P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T18:12:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T18:12:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Steam Deck’s new cloud saves could be the system’s best feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TMRdn4gwfCsq1W2486D3C-Of8sI=/149x0:1703x1036/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427591/Screen_Shot_2022_01_24_at_1.44.26_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;When you put your Steam Deck into sleep mode, Dynamic Cloud Sync will upload modified save data to the cloud.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Valve&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zq98hF"&gt;Ahead of the Steam Deck’s launch, Valve has detailed a new feature for Steam’s cloud saves that should carry over your progress from your Steam Deck back to your PC (or another Steam Deck) even when you put your Steam Deck into suspend mode without fully exiting a game. Valve has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22779252/steam-deck-things-we-learned-from-valve-developer-summit"&gt;talked about this intriguing idea before&lt;/a&gt;, but now it has a name — Dynamic Cloud Sync. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CV2B3G"&gt;Here’s how it should work: when you put your Steam Deck into sleep mode, Dynamic Cloud Sync will automatically upload “all modified save game data” to the cloud, &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/groups/steamworks/announcements/detail/3142949576401813670"&gt;Valve explained in a blog post published Monday&lt;/a&gt;. That way, you can pick up your save when you sit down at your PC or another device with Steam. The Steam Deck will also automatically download save updates when you wake up the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sdGJrt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Others have struggled with seamless cloud saves&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EHAB9O"&gt;The feature sounds very handy, and if it works as advertised, it could make the myriad of mobile promises made by the Steam Deck feel attainable. Seamless cloud saves is something rivals (like the Nintendo Switch) have struggled with. That said, Valve says developers will have to manually enable Dynamic Cloud Sync in their games, so it might take time for the feature to be available in some of your favorite titles, and it’s guaranteed to require internet connectivity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VpXI9i"&gt;If Dynamic Cloud Sync &lt;em&gt;isn’t&lt;/em&gt; enabled, Steam will still track progress you make on your Steam Deck. “However, any user who suspends their Deck while your game is running and then tries to resume that game on a different device will be prompted to first return to their Deck to close the running process or continue without their most recent save game progress,” Valve says in the post intended for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BAE3kG"&gt;Dynamic Cloud Sync could be one of the Steam Deck’s best new features, and hopefully, we won’t have to wait long to try it for ourselves, as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774888/steam-deck-delayed-two-months-february-2022-launch-shipping"&gt;device’s February 2022 launch&lt;/a&gt; is nearly here. But if you haven’t already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582617/new-steam-deck-reservations-q2-q3-valve-hand-held"&gt;secured a reservation&lt;/a&gt;, you might be waiting a bit longer to get your hands on the handheld gaming PC, as Valve’s expected order availability for new reservations is currently a vague “after Q2 2022.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899721/valve-steam-deck-dynamic-cloud-sync-games-pc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899721/valve-steam-deck-dynamic-cloud-sync-games-pc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T17:48:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T17:48:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Giant iceberg releases 152 billion tons of fresh water around remote Atlantic island </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="photo of iceberg" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SR8ENtj7Xzxdp39HCdWscc8xo-E=/2x0:1534x1021/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427517/A68a_in_distance_Povl_Abrahamsen_BAS_1536x1021.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: British Antarctic Survey/Povl Abrahamsen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wCn28l"&gt;An iceberg that was once the largest on the planet, dubbed A68a, recently released 152 billion tons of fresh water close to the sub-Antarctic island of South Georgia, potentially impacting the region’s ecosystem,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;a &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425721005757?via%3Dihub"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published earlier this month found. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kX4f5U"&gt;A68a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/5/15925154/larsen-c-ice-shelf-iceberg-antarctica-climate-change"&gt;captured the world’s attention&lt;/a&gt; in 2017 when it broke off the Larsen-C ice shelf, located near the tip of the Antarctic Peninsula.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The largest iceberg in the world at the time of its formation, it initially floated around the Weddell Sea close to Antarctica before making its way its way across the Drake Passage between southern South America and the northern reaches of Antarctica. As it approached the southern Atlantic island of South Georgia in December 2020, researchers became concerned that it would disrupt wildlife in the remote region.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="a visual of the a 68 a glacier close to the region of south georgia" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RnHqLH_eDQ4SCQqCCyBnoFhRlpE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191355/A_68A_s_position_on_17_December_pillars.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: European Space Agency&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jtsrXo"&gt;The new study shows that the colossal iceberg did have a big effect on the local environment. Over a three-month span between 2020 and 2021, A68a melted rapidly as it encountered warmer water in the Drake Passage. While researchers initially feared that the keel of the iceberg, the part of the iceberg beneath the water’s surface, would run aground on the seafloor, blocking currents and predator foraging routes, that doesn’t appear to have happened,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bas.ac.uk/media-post/a68a-mega-iceberg-released-152-billion-tonnes-of-fresh-water-into-ocean/"&gt;according to the British Antarctic Survey&lt;/a&gt;. But the giant pulse of fresh water released by the iceberg likely still impacted the South Georgia ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BgenCq"&gt;The next step is to determine exactly what that impact looked like, Anne Braakmann-Folgmann, the lead author of the study, says. Braakmann-Folgmann also noted that A68a’s route across the Drake Passage could help researchers learn more about future icebergs and “how they influence the polar oceans.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p7t6d1"&gt;That will be valuable information to have, considering climate change is expected to accelerate ice shelf collapse, leading to more big icebergs breaking off Antarctica in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22895124/iceberg-south-georgia-melt-fresh-water-climate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22895124/iceberg-south-georgia-melt-fresh-water-climate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T17:42:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T17:42:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>At long last, Nvidia and AMD GPU street prices are beginning to drop </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vZ7vXyqJCaNKILKrD9n2T0keHTw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427494/shollister_201117_4303_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rZ593e"&gt;We’re not out of the woods yet — not even close — but it looks like the prices of Nvidia and AMD GPU prices may finally be coming down. &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/gpu-prices-plummet-along-with-crypto"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tom’s Hardware&lt;/em&gt; in the US&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.3dcenter.org/news/news-des-2223-januar-2022"&gt;&lt;em&gt;3DCenter.org&lt;/em&gt; in Germany&lt;/a&gt; have been charting eBay and local retail prices, respectively, and they’re each seeing the same thing: a substantial dip for nearly every new graphics card that Nvidia and AMD make. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UjVwU9"&gt;Want an Nvidia RTX 3080? Just two months ago, that might have cost you $1,773 on the street — over two and a half times the manufacturer suggested retail price. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22797788/price-ps5-xbox-nvidia-amd-rtx-gpu-scalpers-ebay-update"&gt;As we reported in November with our own chart&lt;/a&gt;, that was typical of the hottest graphics cards, and &lt;em&gt;Tom’s Hardware&lt;/em&gt; shows things got slightly worse in December. But in January, those prices have dipped 11 percent&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;to just under $1,600 on average. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iyUZwZ"&gt;The RTX 3080 isn’t alone: most every other RTX 3000 and AMD Radeon RX 6000 graphics card dipped between around 5 and 10 percent, with the RX 6900 XT being the sole exception whose price went up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Y1ECR7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Meet the Nvidia and AMD GPU hunters who turned battling bots into a full-time job","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22698588/falcodrin-gpu-hunters-nvidia-amd-graphics-card-tricks-bots-scalpers-miners-gamers"},{"title":"Why the global chip shortage is making it so hard to buy a PS5","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22648372/willy-shih-chip-shortage-tsmc-samsung-ps5-decoder-interview"},{"title":"Everything you need to know about 2022’s biggest chips","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878059/chips-processors-cpu-gpu-2022-intel-amd-nvidia-qualcomm-apple-arm-x86"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="YyH6fh"&gt;Mind you, &lt;em&gt;Tom’s Hardware&lt;/em&gt; also shows the &lt;em&gt;volume &lt;/em&gt;of sales went down considerably on eBay, and some cards were barely trading to begin with: just nine units of the Radeon RX 6800 changed hands in a week. It’s possible prices are coming down because some people are giving up, unwilling to pay scalper fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QcdSLj"&gt;Or, perhaps it has to do with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/22/22896232/nyc-mayor-bitcoin-crypto-market-eric-adams"&gt;the nosedive that cryptocurrency has taken recently&lt;/a&gt;. It’ll be interesting to see if the recent slump drives GPU prices down dramatically since they won’t be nearly as valuable to miners now. Miners will often sell large quantities of graphics cards when they can’t put them to work. This batch of eBay data is from last week, so it doesn’t contain the full impact of crypto quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qI0D9L"&gt;But &lt;a href="https://www.3dcenter.org/news/news-des-2223-januar-2022"&gt;&lt;em&gt;3DCenter.org&lt;/em&gt; shows&lt;/a&gt; the dip isn’t just happening when GPUs are sold on the secondhand market, but at German retailers as well:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Prices of Nvidia and AMD GPUs have dipped to 177 percent and 167 percent of MSRP respectively, according to this chart." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fK8qiHos5fssZcexYACN0Ff45lI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23192381/AMD_nVidia_Retail_Price_Trend_2021_2022_v2.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Chart by 3DCenter.org&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iXNjxN"&gt;Between these two reports, it feels like a good omen — even if you’ll still pay more than double MSRP for an RTX 3060 Ti right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9Hzcm"&gt;While we haven’t seen any major indications that supply has caught back up to demand (these GPUs remain incredibly hard to find at anything save exorbitant prices), Nvidia and AMD have been repeatedly signaling that they expect supply to improve in the second half of 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aALE73"&gt;On the console front, the PS5 and Xbox Series X are also seeing their secondhand eBay prices sinking. I ran some eBay numbers for the past three months, and both Sony and Microsoft’s flagship consoles have dropped $100, from an average price of $800 to an average of around $700. Here are the charts, in case you’re curious.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XJrKMR-sh6LsXpb3BKbaaTUtlB8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23192448/ps5_ebay_jan_2022.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS5 average eBay sale price, last 90 days&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dLdpSoSdxxJBTSiqGA3LCbTy9OQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23192449/xbox_series_x_ebay_jan_2022.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xbox Series X average eBay sale price, last 90 days&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899527/nvidia-amd-gpu-rtx-3080-radeon-price-drop-ebay-ps5-xbox-series-x-playstation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899527/nvidia-amd-gpu-rtx-3080-radeon-price-drop-ebay-ps5-xbox-series-x-playstation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T17:02:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T17:02:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin goes its own way</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mkKE1gKP61M_k3VTchzaNZQ0JZE=/0x58:2828x1943/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427336/SOPFFO_January_Key_Art.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MPzXEe"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22532295/final-fantasy-origins-square-enix-team-ninja-trailer-e3-2021"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; looks like Square Enix’s biggest departure yet for the long-running &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; series. Though the name &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy &lt;/em&gt;has been synonymous with RPG for the last 35 years, &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; is an action game focused on challenging and fast-paced combat. With only two months to go before launch, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with its developers to talk about &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; and the unique place it occupies in the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oacwmp"&gt;More than setting itself apart by being an action game, &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; looks and feels vastly different from its numbered siblings with its bloody aesthetic. Most &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy &lt;/em&gt;games entice by offering a bright world to explore with beautiful people to befriend. &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt;, by contrast, lets you know right up front that your goal is to murder the shit out of everything that moves — a marked departure from &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy’s&lt;/em&gt; traditionally hopeful tone. Jin Fujiwara, a producer on &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt;, understood that players might not be interested in such a violent game, especially in a world that’s experiencing its third straight year of a devastating pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZtcbAK"&gt;“It is quite a challenge, taking this sort of dark tone for the overall story for sure,” Fujiwara told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Though the initial glance definitely emphasizes the violence and the dark tone of the conflict, we do want to make sure that [players know] not all hope is lost.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12lLCI"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; team knew getting &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; fans to buy in on a drastically different take on the series would be a hard sell. But they worked hard to create a game that pulled from the series’ rich 35-year history to make the foreign feel familiar. “The dungeons pay homage to some of the mainline &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; titles,” Fujiwara said. “Some of them are very recognizable; some might be more subtle compared to the others.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/75egbGx-IKTpBthsiz6i3jayUVo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191971/sop.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bWB6Ge"&gt;Co-developed with Team Ninja, known for its work on &lt;em&gt;Ninja Gaiden&lt;/em&gt; and, more recently, &lt;em&gt;Nioh 2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; draws on a genre of action RPGs known for its punishing difficulty. Fumihiko Yasuda, a Team Ninja producer on &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt;, cited influences from  &lt;em&gt;Dark Souls&lt;/em&gt; and Capcom’s &lt;em&gt;Onimusha&lt;/em&gt; series but also said the team looked primarily at &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy’s&lt;/em&gt; own expansive history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MNEVVS"&gt;“I think our strongest inspiration was just the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; series overall,” Yasuda said. “We were trying to look at the aspects of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; and see how we can reinterpret that for this action game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="R16cql"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Though the initial glance definitely emphasizes the violence and the dark tone of the conflict, we do want to make sure that [players know] not all hope is lost.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E3y5Mx"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; developers hope to court new fans totally unfamiliar (strangers, if you will) with the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; series. When asked if they were intimidated by trying to do something so new in light of the recent success of “traditional” &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; entries, the team replied that the numbered games have their place and spinoffs like &lt;em&gt;Strange of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; are specifically for this kind of out-there experimentation, both in gameplay and story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3hvSde"&gt;“[&lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt;] is a separate saga,” Fujiwara said. “That allows for us to capture new fans and to expand on the lore.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sdwYe3"&gt;The only lore most fans would associate with the game right now is Jack’s burning desire to defeat Chaos. When the game was announced, the internet &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/chaos-chaos-chaos-1847088973"&gt;swiftly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.thegamer.com/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-chaos-memes/"&gt;brutally&lt;/a&gt; latched onto the protagonist frequently and enthusiastically shouting about “Chaos!” turning it into a meme instantaneously. One thing that may have gotten lost amidst rampant &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/were-here-to-kill-chaos-chaosposting"&gt;Chaosposting&lt;/a&gt; is that it’s a retelling of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy I&lt;/em&gt; from the villain’s — Garland’s — perspective. Fans were somewhat amused and bemused by a &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; protagonist with such a boring un-&lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt;-like name — Jack — but his full name is actually &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/heLn5URnZCc"&gt;Jack Garland&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u1bDtWcFRs-i7CFTOg6jD0wK68s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191983/sop1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;My name’s Garland, Jack Garland&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WO1ZOB"&gt;The revelation of Jack’s full name and &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709720/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-demo-playstation-square-enix"&gt;other notable quirks&lt;/a&gt; (remember the pulsing butthole monster?) is the kind of information that makes it such an alluring game. &lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise&lt;/em&gt; contains big “this might be crazy enough to actually work” energy, and that energy is further crystallized in the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ZqLa5qOVsQg"&gt;game’s newest trailer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vUTc1M"&gt;The trailer contains more interactions between Jack and Princess Sarah and introduces a new character Astos. It’s still unclear what purpose Astos and Sarah serve, but the trailer makes it seem like these characters will be integral to Jack’s journey and his possible descent into madness... er, &lt;em&gt;chaos&lt;/em&gt;. What rockets this trailer straight from typical to “I am now paying rapt attention” is the inclusion of the Frank Sinatra cover of “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/qQzdAsjWGPg"&gt;My Way&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5n5CgI"&gt;“My Way” is a song popular at funerals, karaoke nights, and &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/6tKcvww9cHI"&gt;with mobsters&lt;/a&gt;. It is not the song you’d associate with a &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; of any flavor. The tonal dissonance between such a classic American hit and one of the most iconic blockbuster Japanese RPGs (that already has its own pretty &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/b3SuYFYPe4Y"&gt;damn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/O8IBoFIFE-E"&gt;iconic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1gq-uEtyQ2U"&gt;music&lt;/a&gt;) starts at bewildering, then wraps all the way around the gamut of emotions before landing at perfect. Jack wants to defeat Chaos his way, and the developers at Square Enix and Team Ninja want to create a new &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; experience their way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IyFkgD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stranger of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin&lt;/em&gt; launches on PlayStation, Xbox, and Epic Games Store March 18th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898351/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-developer-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898351/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-developer-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T17:00:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T17:00:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter’s ‘close friends’ feature could share tweets with up to 150 select users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gyFGBkzFmt1Agw1_CdboQKxF754=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427319/acastro_180827_1777_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="53t3qn"&gt;Twitter appears to be working on a feature that lets you share tweets with a specific group of people (via &lt;a href="https://www.inputmag.com/tech/twitters-new-flock-feature-takes-aim-at-instagram-close-friends"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Input&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). If this sounds familiar, it’s because &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/30/18117718/instagram-close-friends-stories-favorites"&gt;Instagram’s Close Friends feature&lt;/a&gt; lets you do the exact same thing — but in Twitter’s case, you’ll be limiting your tweets to your “Flock.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kllA5p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558731/twitter-trusted-friends-facets-features-pre-announce"&gt;Twitter first gave us a glimpse&lt;/a&gt; of the feature last July, which it called “Trusted Friends” at the time. Since then, mobile developer Alessandro Paluzzi has been keeping track of Twitter’s progress, and it’s really starting to take shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Omqltk"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Twitter?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Twitter&lt;/a&gt; continues to work on Twitter Flock by adding an explanation of how it works  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;ℹ️ You can choose up to 150 people to include in your Twitter Flock  &lt;br&gt;ℹ️ People won't be notified if you remove them from the list   &lt;a href="https://t.co/xtGcDiHgxS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xtGcDiHgxS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Alessandro Paluzzi (@alex193a) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1484377272731590656?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 21, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RDjpzv"&gt;Paluzzi’s most recent findings give us some insight into how the feature might operate — Twitter seems to be working on a page that shows more information on Flock, which explains you can add up to 150 members. Only these users can view or reply to tweets sent out to your Flock. And in case you decide you don’t want someone in your Flock anymore, Twitter notes you can remove people from your list at any time, and they won’t get a notification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GWy6Rs"&gt;If you’re in someone’s Flock and they send out a tweet, Paluzzi noticed &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1482124555934179330?s=20"&gt;a label&lt;/a&gt; that may appear beneath that tweet, reading: “You can see this Tweet because the author has added you to their Flock.” This should make it easy to distinguish between close friends versus everyone else you follow on Twitter. To send a tweet to your Flock, it looks like Twitter will &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1469468272487813124?s=20"&gt;display an audience option&lt;/a&gt; before you send it out, letting you choose between all of Twitter and your selected users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFKFKV"&gt;Twitter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661649/twitter-releases-communities-facebook-groups-reddit-competitor"&gt;launched invite-only Communities&lt;/a&gt; back in September, a similar feature that lets you connect with users with shared interests. Just like you can limit your tweets to your Flock, you can send out tweets to a specific Community rather than all your followers. It’s still unclear when Twitter’s “close friends”-like feature will reach all users, but, hopefully, it won’t &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577166/twitter-fleets-shuts-down-stories-clone"&gt;flop like Fleets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YoVHnk"&gt;“Twitter is always working on new ways to help people engage in healthy conversations, and we’re currently exploring ways to let people share more privately,” Twitter spokesperson Tatiana Britt told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We don’t have any further news to share about the feature at this time, but we can confirm ‘Twitter Flock’ is just a placeholder name.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hYQNpz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899387/twitter-flock-tweet-privacy-trusted-friends"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899387/twitter-flock-tweet-privacy-trusted-friends</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T16:35:23-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T16:35:23-05:00</updated>
    <title>Costco has PlayStation 5 consoles on sale for members right now (update: sold out)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C_t7EyBxrTY8H-YoUcRbrp2bK50=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427226/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8b03dj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 24th, 4:56PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Costco’s listing sold out at this time and has been removed from its site for now. We are continuing to keep an eye out for more restocks happening soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EZ8EBo"&gt;The Sony PlayStation 5 comes and goes fast, with high demand at each and every restock opportunity. If you have not landed one yet, your options can be slightly improved by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22771984/ps5-restock-xbox-best-buy-walmart-amazon-subscription"&gt;paying for subscriptions to select retailers&lt;/a&gt; that give special access. If you are a Costco member then you already do just that, and your time is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZBaZmr"&gt;You can order a &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/sony-playstation-5-gaming-console-bundle.product.100834763.html"&gt;PlayStation 5 console from Costco&lt;/a&gt; right now, bundled with additional accessories and 12-month PlayStation Plus membership card. You must be a paid Costco member to place this order. A membership starts at $60 per year and &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/join-costco.html?redirectLogin=true"&gt;can be purchased here&lt;/a&gt;. Consoles are some of the items at Costco that are exclusively for members, while some other products can be ordered by non-members with an additional fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mwt1J5"&gt;As we always suggest, it’s best to add your billing and shipping address to your account beforehand to save time. If you miss out on this one, be sure to have it saved for the next go-around. We are continuing to keep an eye on the latest console restocks, and you can also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/pages/newsletters"&gt;subscribe to our &lt;em&gt;Verge Deals&lt;/em&gt; newsletter&lt;/a&gt; for the latest tech and gadget deals delivered straight to your inbox weekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Q2vKtJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PlayStation 5 review: a big, confident step into next gen","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"},{"title":"Sony’s ‘Spartacus’ could be PlayStation’s answer to Xbox Game Pass","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816087/sony-playstation-5-game-subscription-service-xbox-games-pass-now-spartacus"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="lrRhp6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10909136"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CqIeky"&gt;PlayStation games to accompany your console&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="pcE7K2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10892449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="9ey6Es"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10687661"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Xng9V7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10835147"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="HkhKni"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22824105/sony-playstation-ps5-console-restock-costco-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22824105/sony-playstation-ps5-console-restock-costco-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T16:03:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T16:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The iconic silver bullet Airstream camping trailer has returned as a remote-controlled EV</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r-wOSM73QbyfDmvKvmHdDLUWWIk=/0x0:800x533/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70427131/a7b99afa_c165_4f6d_a788_a0a75e343571_DSC_5776.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Airstream eStream concept by Thor Industries — being towed by a Tesla Model X | Image: Thor Industries&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="krXCFd"&gt;Recreational vehicle manufacturer Thor Industries &lt;a href="https://www.thorindustries.com/innovation-estream"&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; last week an electric tow assisted “eStream” trailer concept under its Airstream brand and also a battery-powered RV with a range of up to 300 miles (&lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2022/01/19/electric-airstream-concept-is-the-rv-industrys-iphone-moment/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;via Electrek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0m9xkS"&gt;The Airstream eStream trailer could be like any other camper that you tow — but this one can be detached and remotely moved around a campsite. That could make maneuvering easier and improve safety. While it may seem similar to such gimmicks as a Tesla’s remote parking feature, the eStream’s electric propulsion enables other advances, such as the ability to synchronize with a towing vehicle to help increase range between recharging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wWPJ65"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rUvIpUygzaY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5RGw7S"&gt;Nowadays, electric vehicles have expanded range capabilities, but if you’ve ever tried towing a trailer behind a Tesla, you might find it to lose a &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/2021-tesla-model-y-long-term-update-range-towing/"&gt;significant&lt;/a&gt; amount of range. The eStream could be a stark improvement for those seeking an all-electric lifestyle out on the open road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MrFlhf"&gt;Many campsites offer 240-volt service, where the eStream and an additional EV could be recharged. When not plugged in, the eStream also has solar panels that can regain power to the camper’s 80 kWh battery system (no more diesel generators powering campers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oLAbXO"&gt;Thor industries also &lt;a href="https://www.thorindustries.com/innovation-vision-vehicle"&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; the Thor Vision Vehicle concept — a Ford Transit van converted to an EV with a futuristic tech-filled interior plus a large tablet-style infotainment system with trip planning and other internet-connected features seen in many modern electric cars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mDQSsR"&gt;The Thor Vision also has solar panels, but its surprise power source is a fuel cell that can charge the batteries for extended dry camping periods. Other features include voice control using Alexa, which can do anything from giving a charge status to adjusting lighting and temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Fw0j58"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uWDImj5YJJo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7MN0B4"&gt;Winnebago is another company working on a fully outfitted electric RV van (built on a Ford Transit as well). And although this concept seems realistically ready for production, its 125 miles of range seems ever so anemic for the use-case compared to the Thor Vision’s 300 miles target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7prPZM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Winnebago's new Transit-based EV camper has a range of 125 miles. Research suggests 54% of new RV buyers prefer to stay within 200 miles. Still, is that enough? &lt;a href="https://t.co/QAnvKAmFdK"&gt;https://t.co/QAnvKAmFdK&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/eNhQhDVnCq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/eNhQhDVnCq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Autoblog (@therealautoblog) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/therealautoblog/status/1483888742683213829?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TcSxKD"&gt;As with all concepts, it remains to be seen when and if the eStream camper and the Thor Vision vehicle reach production — so don’t get too hyped about having that all-electric off-grid lifestyle just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899010/thor-vision-airstream-estream-battery-powered-motorhome-rv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899010/thor-vision-airstream-estream-battery-powered-motorhome-rv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
