<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-28T18:04:59-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T18:04:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T18:04:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Space community mourns the death of Apollo 11 astronaut Michael Collins</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Michael Collins Studying Flight Plans" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GkE4stmIsKUKEK68OdCmV0i5Q1g=/0x20:3989x2679/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201988/517427560.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kuQOSQ"&gt;Michael Collins, the witty “forgotten” astronaut of NASA’s legendary Apollo 11 mission to the Moon, died of cancer on Wednesday, his family said. An icon of space exploration and an eloquent storyteller (who, arguably, had the best sense of humor among the Apollo 11 crew), Collins passionately advocated for further exploration of other worlds. Astronauts, NASA officials, and others in the space community who are heeding his advocacy mourned his death today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BKtfx9"&gt;Collins was the Columbia command module pilot who stayed in orbit around the Moon in 1969 while his crew mates, Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin, descended to the lunar surface and became the first two humans to set foot on another world. Aldrin, now the only living Apollo 11 astronaut, mourned his fellow crewmate in a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NreQh8"&gt;“Dear Mike,” Aldrin said, “Wherever you have been or will be, you will always have the Fire to Carry us deftly to new heights and to the future. We will miss you. May you Rest In Peace. #Apollo11”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="okhfg7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Dear Mike,&lt;br&gt;Wherever you have been or will be, you will always have the Fire to Carry us deftly to new heights and to the future.  We will miss you. May you Rest In Peace.  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apollo11?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apollo11&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/q4sJjFdvf8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/q4sJjFdvf8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Dr. Buzz Aldrin (@TheRealBuzz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheRealBuzz/status/1387451395461292037?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KPjUPI"&gt;After the Apollo 11 mission, Collins was given an informal nickname, the “forgotten astronaut,” and went on to write several books, including a 1974 memoir, &lt;em&gt;Carrying the Fire&lt;/em&gt;, where&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;he relived the feeling of utter loneliness as his Columbia module flew into the remote darkness of the Moon’s far side. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvKM5o"&gt;“I like the feeling,” he wrote in his memoir. “Outside my window I can see stars — and that is all. Where I know the moon to be, there is simply a black void.” He called his perch in the capsule his “beautiful little domain” in a 2019 interview with &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, adding “It was all mine. I was the emperor, the captain of it, and it was quite commodious. I had warm coffee, even.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7J2MvI"&gt;Collins had a long career, even beyond NASA. During his 90 years on (and off) Earth, he also served as an Air Force colonel, head of the State Department’s public affairs bureau, and director of the Smithsonian’s National Air and Space Museum. “He helped shepherd the Smithsonian Air and Space Museum from a rickety old hut on the National Mall to its present premises,” said Tom Ellis, a teaching fellow at the London School of Economics who studies space history. His stint as the museum’s director, Ellis said, “demonstrated that he was a rare spacefarer who truly understood just how ‘historic’ the space age was. Someone whose post-space career was as impressive as his time as an astronaut.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wKCYmc"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We mourn the passing and celebrate the life of our former director and astronaut Michael Collins. His vision and extraordinary achievements helped define our museum, and his wit, warmth, and wisdom will always be a part of our work. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Z8VPRSfabs"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Z8VPRSfabs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— National Air and Space Museum (@airandspace) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/airandspace/status/1387453338363568129?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yZWGVC"&gt;NASA’s acting administrator Steve Jurczyk said Collins was “a friend of all who seek to push the envelope of human potential,” citing a famous quote from the astronaut: “Exploration is not a choice, really, it’s an imperative.” Jurczyk added: “Whether his work was behind the scenes or on full view, his legacy will always be as one of the leaders who took America’s first steps into the cosmos. And his spirit will go with us as we venture toward farther horizons.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ktFgnR"&gt;NASA is investing billions into its Artemis program, which aims to return astronauts to the Moon and establish a long-term presence that can inform future missions to Mars. The space agency &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387887/elon-musk-spacex-win-nasa-lunar-lander-contract-artemis"&gt;signed&lt;/a&gt; a $2.9 billion contract with SpaceX this month to deliver the first crew of astronauts to the lunar surface since the last Apollo Moon mission in 1972. Past attempts to build on the Apollo program’s legacy and return to the Moon were squashed by shifting presidential priorities — but the Artemis program, started in 2019 by the Trump administration, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22323621/trump-moon-program-artemis-biden-nasa-timeline"&gt;won embrace&lt;/a&gt; by the Biden administration as well, making a crewed return more likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HfvpOq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We will continue Carrying the Fire, Mike.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vVrMw0"&gt;Pam Melroy, a retired NASA astronaut of three shuttle missions and President Biden’s nominee for NASA Deputy Administrator, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Astro_Pam/status/1387457744224014341?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;: “So, so sad at the passing of my favorite astronaut, @AstroMCollins. A hero just outside the spotlight. We will continue Carrying the Fire, Mike.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7PJhIB"&gt;Mark Geyer, director of NASA’s Johnson Space Center, NASA’s astronaut HQ, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DirectorMarkG/status/1387475108004962304?s=20"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; “many people here at JSC will remember his wit, humor, and their interactions with him with both admiration and affection.” Geyer recalled Collins’ visit to JSC in 2019, during the 50th Apollo 11 anniversary: “Mike said he primarily remembers not having time to relax and enjoy the view for long, but in the moments when he did he look out his window at Earth, he realized how delicate it was.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZqWuxT"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/28/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-michael-collins/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;, President Biden said Collins “lived a life of service to our country” who “both wrote and helped tell the story of our nation’s remarkable accomplishments in space.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePnvLc"&gt;“From his vantage point high above the Earth, he reminded us of the fragility of our own planet, and called on us to care for it like the treasure it is,” Biden said. “Our prayers are with General Collins’ family. Godspeed, Mike.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408090/apollo-11-astronaut-michael-collins-death-nasa-mourning"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408090/apollo-11-astronaut-michael-collins-death-nasa-mourning</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T17:46:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T17:46:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook temporarily hid posts calling for India’s prime minister to resign</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NejP3qeOZaAQUaLrvkqiS_3MN7c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201908/acastro_180828_1777_facebook_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kLTZoh"&gt;When Facebook users tried to view a hashtag calling for the resignation of Indian prime minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday, they &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/srinivasaiims/status/1387472195316711426"&gt;instead saw a message&lt;/a&gt; saying that Facebook was temporarily hiding the posts in order to keep the community safe. &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/facebook-blocking-posts-hashtag-resign-modi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed News &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that the posts were hidden for about three hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3qohU"&gt;Facebook has now restored the posts and told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; it is “looking into what happened,” echoing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andymstone/status/1387491715171422215"&gt;a public statement&lt;/a&gt; from a member of its communications team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QeLMIH"&gt;The temporary suspension of the hashtag is likely to fuel concerns about the influence that Modi’s BJP party wields over Facebook operations and social media in general. Last weekend, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/24/22400976/twitter-removed-tweets-critical-india-censor-coronavirus"&gt;Twitter hid tweets critical of various officials&lt;/a&gt; after receiving an emergency order from the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="foSR7N"&gt;India is currently currently seeing another wave in COVID-19 cases, which has lead to critical medical supplies being in short supply. Many of the Facebook posts with the ResignModi hashtag include references to the coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2MMbby"&gt;Facebook has blocked hashtags in the past — during the 2020 US election &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551717/facebook-tiktok-block-election-conspiracy-theory-hashtags-twitter-monitoring"&gt;it blocked the  “StopTheSteal” tag&lt;/a&gt;, showing users a similar message to the one seen in India today. The hashtag for “Qanon” is also blocked, as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21504887/facebook-qanon-ban-all-apps-pages-groups-instagram-accounts"&gt;part of Facebook’s fight&lt;/a&gt; against the conspiracy-based social movement. Unlike the ResignModi hashtag, the StopTheSteal and Qanon tags are still blocked, with the message citing content that goes against community standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eqaH8A"&gt;Facebook India has been a sore point for the company in recent months, with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/27/21536149/ankhi-das-facebook-india-resigned-quit-bjp-hindu-muslim-conflict"&gt;controversial policy chief resigning&lt;/a&gt; last October. Critics pressured her to leave, claiming that, under her guidance, Facebook India had failed to moderate hate speech that led to anti-Muslim pogroms in Delhi. More broadly, there were concerns that her public alignment with the ruling BJP party had led to unfair application of Facebook policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="162nQO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408334/facebook-hides-modi-resign-posts-restore-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408334/facebook-hides-modi-resign-posts-restore-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T17:06:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T17:06:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook expects ad tracking problems from regulators and Apple</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2r1HaM-7DVxkDsuWX56glio-d28=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201604/acastro_180522_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YMzHQN"&gt;Facebook’s ad revenue was up more than 45 percent during the first three months of 2020, soaring to $25.4 billion — or about seven times what Twitter makes in an entire year. But the company sees some potential problems on the horizon that could limit continued growth: regulators are closing in on ad tracking practices, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"&gt;a feature launched this week by Apple&lt;/a&gt; could harm its ability to target ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H1BP9s"&gt;“We continue to expect increased ad targeting headwinds in 2021 from regulatory and platform changes,” Facebook CFO Dave Wehner writes in the company’s &lt;a href="https://investor.fb.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2021/Facebook-Reports-First-Quarter-2021-Results/default.aspx"&gt;Q1 2021 earnings release&lt;/a&gt;. Wehner specifically calls out iOS 14.5, which includes a feature that lets iPhone and iPad users easily stop apps from tracking them in certain ways. Facebook expects to start seeing an impact from the changes to iOS right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="E81iTS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why Apple’s new privacy feature is such a big deal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="nS41nB"&gt;Facebook believes its ad revenue will continue to grow over the rest of 2020 even with those changes, but it sees a slowdown coming in the second half of the year. Mostly, Facebook says, that’s because it did so well last year during the pandemic. But regulatory factors and Apple’s changes will play a role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rG8mSu"&gt;The new update requires apps like Facebook to proactively ask users to consent to being tracked for the purpose of advertising. Facebook and other companies &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theinformation.com%2Farticles%2Ffacebook-looks-to-take-its-fight-with-apple-to-court&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F28%2F22407728%2Ffacebook-q1-2021-earnings-apple-regulators-ad-tracking-problems" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;expect a lot of people to opt out&lt;/a&gt;, and there’s a possibility that’ll hurt their ability to accurately target ads. Facebook has criticized the feature as a threat to the businesses that rely on those ads. “Apple’s latest update threatens the personalized ads that millions of small businesses rely on to find and reach customers,” a Facebook website reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C583UN"&gt;On a call with investors, Facebook executives said the company was working on improvements to its ad tech that would allow for better ad targeting even with access to less data. Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg framed it as a “rebuilding” of the company’s tech; Wehner said Facebook was “making progress” on solutions with the goal to “maintain and even improve performance” in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ri403o"&gt;Meanwhile, the European Union’s data protection leader &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/eus-top-privacy-regulator-urges-ban-on-surveillance-based-ad-targeting/"&gt;has recommended&lt;/a&gt; a ban on ad targeting that’s based on tracked web activity. European lawmakers are &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/"&gt;planning a significant overhaul&lt;/a&gt; of digital marketplace regulations, and Facebook could come out with fewer available tools to target ads to individual users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fShQuV"&gt;But for the moment, Facebook continues to grow on all major counts. Daily users across Facebook’s family of products hit 2.72 billion, up from 2.6 billion at the end of the prior quarter, while monthly users hit 3.45 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6JwVdr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 28th, 6:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story has been updated with comments from Facebook’s earnings call.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407728/facebook-q1-2021-earnings-apple-regulators-ad-tracking-problems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407728/facebook-q1-2021-earnings-apple-regulators-ad-tracking-problems</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T16:44:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T16:44:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s iPhone 12 and Mac sales skyrocket despite ongoing pandemic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i99fSomk-kSyCJQESjrxlXCOLSM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201444/akrales_201018_4238_0194.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mEoNl7"&gt;Apple’s iPhone 12 lineup maintained enormously strong demand from consumers from January through March, according to the company’s fiscal Q2 earnings &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F04%2Fapple-reports-second-quarter-results%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F28%2F22407894%2Fapple-q2-2021-earnings-iphone-ipad-mac" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;posted today&lt;/a&gt;. Apple reported record March quarter revenue of $89.6 billion, up 54 percent year over year. The iPhone took in just under $48 billion, jumping up by 66 percent from a year ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eusbyT"&gt;Sales of Mac and iPad hardware also surged for yet another quarter, up 70 and 78 percent respectively, due in part to continued remote work and schooling necessitated by the COVID-19 pandemic. That success might slow down as some regions of the world return to a sense of normalcy, so most eyes — as usual — are on the iPhone. It’s been reported that the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22322843/iphone-12-mini-apple-low-production-numbers-decrease"&gt;iPhone 12 mini isn’t doing as well as Apple hoped&lt;/a&gt;, but other models are clearly hits with consumers. “This family of devices is popular with both upgrades and new customers alike,” Apple CEO Tim Cook said on the afternoon earnings call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9tiF6"&gt;These Q2 earnings follow a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252663/apple-q1-2021-earnings-iphone-12-mac-sales"&gt;historic, blowout December quarter&lt;/a&gt; for Apple that saw the company surpass $100 billion in revenue for the first time in its history. But now focus has shifted to how Apple will perform in the second half of the year and whether the iPhone 12 devices, Apple’s first to offer 5G data, have indeed sparked the huge upgrade cycle that some analysts had thought was likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DJ4THr"&gt;Just last week, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22384756/apple-spring-loaded-event-recap-biggest-announcements-airtag-ipad-pro-imac"&gt;Apple held its first event of 2021&lt;/a&gt; and introduced new products including a purple iPhone 12, a redesigned iMac powered by the M1 chip, updated iPad Pro tablets, a faster Apple TV 4K streaming box, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;long-rumored AirTag item tracker&lt;/a&gt;. The iPhone and AirTags go on sale April 30th, which is when Apple will begin taking preorders for its other newly announced hardware. An all-new MacBook Pro is expected to follow in the coming weeks — likely at Apple’s WWDC keynote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hlbgdn"&gt;Apple’s fiscal second quarter earnings come with a legal backdrop: the company faces an imminent courtroom battle with &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; developer Epic Games. Depositions from both companies have already been filed, and senior executives are expected to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22405894/epic-apple-store-fortnite-trial-kickoff-witnesses-list"&gt;provide extensive testimony starting next week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PbaNaY"&gt;Even with Apple’s services business — up to a record-high $16.9 billion from $13.3 billion in the year-ago quarter — and hardware on such an upward trajectory, investors and consumers continue to await the next major device that will push the company into a new product category. Rumors have long suggested that AR and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266190/apple-vr-headset-ar-glasses-8k-displays-cameras-hand-tracking-details-report"&gt;VR headsets&lt;/a&gt; are in Apple’s future; software boss Craig Federighi recently &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/video/series/joanna-stern-personal-technology/exclusive-apple-software-chief-explains-ios-145-app-tracking-defends-companys-reach/57D138E3-3677-4A78-9534-62DAD443FE97"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s Joanna Stern&lt;/a&gt; that mixed reality tech “deserves exploration.” In an earlier interview with Kara Swisher, CEO Tim Cook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22367715/tim-cook-augmented-reality-apple-car-hints-interview"&gt;described AR as “critically important” to Apple’s future&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WNSpTM"&gt;And then there are the long-running reports of an eventual Apple-made electric car; back in February, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271748/hyundai-apple-car-talks-stopped-report"&gt;Nissan and Hyundai both downplayed discussions&lt;/a&gt; the automakers were rumored to have held with Apple on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407894/apple-q2-2021-earnings-iphone-ipad-mac"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407894/apple-q2-2021-earnings-iphone-ipad-mac</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T16:17:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T16:17:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max’s cheaper ad-supported tier will reportedly cost $9.99 per month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The HBO Max logo against a dark background with white circles around it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7W_Kottu6-GW9TL6s3Y6YseMRd0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201296/acastro_200602_1777_HBOMax_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="c9C8jw"&gt;&lt;a href="http://voxmediapartner.go2cloud.org/aff_c?offer_id=2&amp;amp;aff_id=1&amp;amp;source=Verge&amp;amp;aff_sub=HBOMaxLoweringPrice042821"&gt;HBO Max’s&lt;/a&gt; upcoming ad-support tier will cost $9.99 per month, or $5 less than the standard $14.99 per month that the regular version of HBO Max costs, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/28/warnermedia-plans-to-charge-9point99-per-month-for-ad-supported-hbo-max.html"&gt;according to a new report from CNBC&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJHt8i"&gt;The upcoming ad-supported tier is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327217/hbo-max-ad-supported-tier-launch-date-international-price-subscriber-growth"&gt;still set to launch in June&lt;/a&gt; and will feature a few major differences from the $15 per month plan — including access to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"&gt;WarnerMedia’s same-day theatrical release strategy&lt;/a&gt; for films like &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Matrix 4&lt;/em&gt;, which will be limited to subscribers to HBO Max’s more premium tier. WarnerMedia CEO Jason Kilar has also confirmed in a March analyst event that HBO original shows won’t get ads added in, so customers won’t have to worry about &lt;em&gt;Euphoria&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; The Sopranos&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;/em&gt;getting interrupted by commercials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5gQoxy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;HBO, for less&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m8nakF"&gt;The $9.99 price tag would mark a new low price for access to HBO’s content, undercutting the $14.99 per month that WarnerMedia has charged for the service for years (whether purchased through cable companies or as a standalone streaming service).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dRq298"&gt;It also would allow for HBO Max — which, at $14.99 per month, is currently one of the most expensive streaming services — to better compete with or even undercut competitors like Disney Plus ($7.99 per month) or Netflix (which starts at $8.99 per month but offers pricier $13.99 and $17.99 per month plans, too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uR10PM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NpY2yb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408313/hbo-max-cheaper-ad-supported-tier-10-dollars-price-cut-june"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408313/hbo-max-cheaper-ad-supported-tier-10-dollars-price-cut-june</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T15:58:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T15:58:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>A fired Amazon worker is trying to unionize four NYC-area facilities</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kGHVD6YkLRw0dBd14-L-L5z3FDo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201196/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GMMI60"&gt;Amazon workers at four different facilities near Staten Island have begun the process of unionizing with the &lt;a href="https://amazonlaborunion.org/"&gt;Amazon Labor Union&lt;/a&gt;. The organizing effort is being led by Christian Smalls, a former warehouse worker who was fired in March after organizing a walkout to protest unsafe working conditions during the pandemic, &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/amazon-labor-union-staten-island"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BWGEe"&gt;The company has responded by posting anti-union messages on TV screens at JFK8, the fulfillment center where Smalls used to work. “KNOW THE FACTS BEFORE YOU SIGN A UNION CARD,” reads one of the messages &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/bvzx7v/amazon-launches-another-union-busting-campaign"&gt;obtained by &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “If someone asks you to provide your personal information or sign a union card, do not release your personal information without knowing all the facts.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fojuUz"&gt;Several hundred workers at JFK8 have already signed cards in support of the union, Smalls told &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;. In total, the warehouse employs roughly 5,000 workers. The union could present the cards to Amazon as early as June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpOjxz"&gt;The effort comes on the heels of a bitter defeat for Amazon organizers in Alabama. Earlier this month, warehouse workers in Bessemer voted against unionizing with the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU), although the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377142/bessemer-amazon-labor-union-loss-warehouse-rwdsu"&gt;organization is currently contesting the results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3yVM9p"&gt;After Smalls was fired, he filed a class action lawsuit against Amazon (the case is ongoing). He also created the Congress of Essential Workers, which grew into the Amazon Labor Union, according to &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q1tqp3"&gt;The Amazon Labor Union isn’t affiliated with a national group like the RWDSU, which could complicate the high-stakes unionizing effort. Typically, unions like RWDSU provide much-needed resources and experience to employees trying to organize their workplace. For now, most of that work is being done by Smalls and the various organizations he founded since leaving the company. The group has also &lt;a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/support-the-amazon-labor-union?utm_campaign=p_cp_url&amp;amp;utm_medium=os&amp;amp;utm_source=customer"&gt;set up a GoFundMe&lt;/a&gt; to cover organizing expenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tGVuYp"&gt;Smalls told &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt; that he thinks independence will be helpful. “We have nothing to compare ourselves to,” he said. “That puts us at an advantage. Workers can’t say we already tried it and failed. When talking to workers, we can say this is us creating this together as workers of Amazon. We’re all in this together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vaLnrh"&gt;Amazon did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408128/amazon-warehouses-unionizing-staten-island-jfk8-christian-smalls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408128/amazon-warehouses-unionizing-staten-island-jfk8-christian-smalls</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T15:31:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T15:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s who Apple and Epic are calling to testify in next week’s trial</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qHSF6qGdTTpPNsvPamHntQsTrj8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201001/vpavic_190224_Tim_Sweeney_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MAAnYH"&gt;Next week, Epic Games and Apple will appear in court for a long-anticipated legal battle. Epic argues that Apple unfairly kicked its hit game &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; off the App Store last year, exercising an illegal monopoly over the ubiquitous iOS platform. Apple claims Epic is trying to break the iOS platform’s vaunted safety and security for its own gain. Both parties have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373826/epic-games-v-apple-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-lawsuit"&gt;laid out how&lt;/a&gt; they expect to win their respective cases, and this week, they’ve provided near-final lists of the people they expect to call for testimony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AeudKo"&gt;Apple and Epic both filed revised tentative witness lists on April 26th. The lists don’t guarantee every witness will be called, and crucially, they don’t tell us &lt;em&gt;when &lt;/em&gt;we’ll see a given person on the stand. But with the closely watched trial kicking off on Monday — and likely running until the last week of May — they offer a good picture of each party’s planned strategy and what we can expect to see throughout the trial. An Apple spokesperson described its list as being a fairly reliable indicator of who it would call in the trial, while Epic said it could vary its strategy based on how the trial proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXjt4o"&gt;Unsurprisingly, the lists are heavy on Apple and Epic executives and other employees. That includes Epic CEO Tim Sweeney (who appears on both witness lists), Apple CEO Tim Cook (who appears only on Apple’s list), and other big names like Craig Federighi, Eddy Cue, and Phil Schiller. Since these figures were deposed before the trial, court documents have already revealed a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406303/imessage-android-eddy-cue-emails-apple-epic-deposition"&gt;few interesting details&lt;/a&gt; about the companies’ businesses — and we’ll probably see more as they take the stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bCX8QX"&gt;Epic and Apple are also preparing to call on outside parties with a stake in the app and gaming world. Both lists include Microsoft Xbox executive Lori Wright, for instance, and Epic is calling Adrian Ong from Match Group, which &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/21/google-and-apple-scare-us-app-makers-tell-congress.html"&gt;recently criticized Apple&lt;/a&gt; in a congressional hearing. However, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-27/facebook-s-gaming-chief-no-longer-testifying-in-epic-apple-trial"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;, Epic withdrew a request for testimony from Facebook’s gaming head Vivek Sharma — whose name doesn’t appear in the latest filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bh7ajS"&gt;Apple’s witness list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xJ7Bww"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple employees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Me3QnA"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tim Cook, CEO&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Apple’s corporate values; Apple’s business and operations; development and launch of the App Store; competition faced by Apple.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, 30 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1IK8dl"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Craig Federighi, senior vice president, software engineering&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “iOS operating system; competition faced by Apple; Apple’s investment and efforts to combat malware, spyware, and other issues relating to app security and iOS device user protection.” (Scheduled for two hours examination, one hour cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Kklu8i"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Matt Fischer, App Store VP&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “marketing of apps available in the App Store; competitors and competition in the sale of apps and the different app marketplaces; Apple’s business relationships with app developers.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="U3uyhD"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Eric Gray, director of commerce and payments&lt;/strong&gt; — covering the “design and operation of Apple’s payment processing policies and practices.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, 15 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oyk2im"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Trystan Kosmynka, senior director of marketing&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “App Store policies and guidelines; Apple’s app review and curation process and procedures; Apple’s investment in efforts to protect iOS device users’ safety and privacy.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="p8xt7S"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Phil Schiller, Apple fellow&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Apple’s business and operations; Development and launch of the App Store; App Store policies and guidelines; the App Store business model; the App Store commission; app distribution; iOS operating system; competition faced by Apple; design, development, launch, and marketing of the iPhone.” (Scheduled for six hours examination, three hours cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3TVCIc"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Michael Schmid, head of game business development, App Store&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “the tools, services, and benefits that Apple provides to developers, including to Epic; Apple’s relationship with Epic, Epic’s breaches of its agreements with Apple, and Epic’s other misconduct.” (Scheduled for 1 hour examination, 30 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="F9S6EG"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Scott Forstall, former senior vice president, iOS Software&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “differences between mobile devices and PCs; security and privacy considerations for mobile devices; historical App Store policies and practices.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="l60INF"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Phillip Shoemaker, former technology director, app review&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “App Store policies and guidelines; Apple’s app review and curation process and procedures; Apple’s investment in efforts to protect iOS device users’ safety and privacy.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="68vUok"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epic employees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="GvuBlN"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Steve Allison, Epic Games Store general manager&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “the Epic Games Store business model and financial projections; the Epic Games Store’s revenue split; the Epic Games Store’s market share.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Usjhx2"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Andrew Grant, engineering fellow&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “enforcement of platform rules; &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; anti-cheat measures; the importance to Apple’s brand of protecting user privacy and security; Epic’s use of Apple-provided tools and services; Epic’s interest in workarounds to undercut Apple’s 30% commission; Epic’s efforts to subvert app review; Epic’s campaign against app stores.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xpzaMM"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Joseph Kreiner, VP of business development&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “benefits of cross-platform play; Epic’s relationships with console manufacturers, including contractual terms, commissions paid by Epic, and payment processing terms; fraud on the Epic Games Store.” (Scheduled for 30 minutes examination, 10 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="H9h5Di"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Thomas Ko, senior director, head of online business strategy and operations&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s relationship with Samsung, including Epic’s contracts with Samsung, commissions paid to Samsung, and communications with Samsung; Epic’s campaign against app stores.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NrJ0bG"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mark Rein, VP of business development&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “the Epic Games Store business model and commission; benefits of Apple marketing and other support provided to Epic; Epic’s plans and practices concerning distribution through iOS, competing platforms, and alternative channels; Epic’s campaign against app stores.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9xsHl4"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tim Sweeney, CEO&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s business model, operations, and strategy; Epic’s financial performance; Epic’s dealings with Apple and competing platforms, including commissions paid; Epic Games Store profitability; Epic’s relationship with Samsung, including Epic’s contracts with Samsung, commissions paid to Samsung, and communications with Samsung; Epic’s campaign against app stores.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xUaxho"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Vogel, COO&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s exploration of sideloading on iOS and Android; Epic’s launch of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; outside of the Google Play Store; security of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; and the Epic Games Store, including the Xsolla payment processor; concerns over cross-platform arbitrage of ‘V-bucks’ purchases; Epic’s attempts to avoid Apple’s App Store review process; Epic’s campaign against app stores.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2uEh7a"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Weissinger, VP of marketing&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s pricing and marketing activities, including as to &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s profit margin; &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s weaknesses on mobile systems relative to game consoles; Epic’s campaign against app stores.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Werzho"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Joseph Babcock, former CFO&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s financial performance; Epic’s business model and strategy; Epic’s dealings with Apple and competing platforms, including commissions paid; Epic Games Store profitability.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="84qFTm"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Haseeb Malik, former marketing manager&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “tools, services, and benefits that Apple provided to Epic; platforms on which Epic makes its games available; Epic’s campaign against app stores.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fw1yZx"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;David Nikdel, online gameplay systems lead &lt;/strong&gt;— covering “engineering and technology benefits received from Apple; quality of non-iOS platforms; Epic’s direct payment hotfix.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="M9JBxm"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nick Penwarden, VP of engineering&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “the Unreal Engine business model; iOS and Android proprietary software and tools; engineering support from Apple; cross-platform play.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fvnpEp"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Alec Shobin, senior marketing manager&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “marketing for mobile games; the App Store review process; Epic’s campaign against app stores.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="l7kBsp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party witnesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MZ6reF"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Lori Wright, VP of Xbox business development, Microsoft &lt;/strong&gt;— covering “the Microsoft Store; Xbox video game console business and operations; Xbox cloud gaming; distribution of apps on the App Store.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GLme1Y"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Benjamin Simon, founder and CEO of Yoga Buddhi Co.&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Yoga Buddhi’s apps and business model; tools, services, and benefits that Apple provided to Yoga Buddhi; participation in the Coalition for App Fairness; App Store review process.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ozLcMI"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shelley Gould, president and co-founder of Neuro-Fin / SmartStops&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “SmartStops’ apps and business model; tools, services, and benefits that Apple provided to SmartStops; App Store review process; communications with Apple.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nY7M6G"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Aashish Patel, director of product management, Nvidia &lt;/strong&gt;— covering “tools, services, and support that Apple provided to Nvidia; distribution on competitor platforms and through alternative channels; communications with Apple; compliance with Apple’s App Review Guidelines; Nvidia’s affiliation with Epic.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Eeus9h"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Alphabet&lt;/strong&gt; — documents submitted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xUQmrH"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;App Annie&lt;/strong&gt; — documents submitted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SyflNd"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Roblox Corporation&lt;/strong&gt; — documents submitted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="uY4HwF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expert witnesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="bR2KR5"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Richard Schmalensee,&lt;/strong&gt; emeritus professor of economics, MIT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="h2CtAs"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Lorin Hitt,&lt;/strong&gt; professor of operations, information, and decisions, University of Pennsylvania Wharton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AF0XDt"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Francine LaFontaine&lt;/strong&gt;, professor of economics, University of Michigan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BRsuzy"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Rubinfeld&lt;/strong&gt;, professor of law, NYU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="U9c8Ib"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;James Malackowski&lt;/strong&gt;, CEO, Ocean Tomo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EPkSbZ"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Aviel Rubin&lt;/strong&gt;, technical director, Johns Hopkins University Information Security Institute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="weSh2D"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dominique Hanssens&lt;/strong&gt;, distinguished research professor of marketing, UCLA Anderson Graduate School of Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="cibsQa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GbCzKq"&gt;Epic’s witness list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="clapMh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epic employees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="kF7hg5"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Steve Allison, Epic Games Store general manager &lt;/strong&gt;— covering “Epic Games Store (business).” (Scheduled for 30 minutes examination, 30 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="udq7si"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Andrew Grant, engineering fellow&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s membership in the Apple Developer Program; engineering and development of Epic’s products for various platforms; Epic Direct Payment on iOS.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, 30 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UOqvz2"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Thomas Ko, senior director, head of online business strategy and operations&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s payment processing services; Apple’s payment processing services; Epic Direct Payment on iOS.” (Scheduled for 30 minutes examination, 15 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QU3NlS"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tim Sweeney, CEO&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s history and business; Epic’s business discussions with Apple and Google; Epic Direct Payment on iOS; App Store policies and practices; Epic’s marketing and promotional activities; Epic’s efforts to compete in app distribution and in- app payment processing.” (Scheduled for three hours examination, three hours cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LihKOH"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Weissinger, VP of marketing&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Epic’s marketing and promotional activities; marketing and promotional support services offered by video game consoles and mobile operating system providers, including Apple.” (Scheduled for 30 minutes examination, 30 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="2ACfZk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple employees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="jXsVV5"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Matt Fischer, App Store VP&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “App Store business strategy; App Store financial performance; App Store policies and practices; Apple’s market power over iOS developers; and/or the subjects of designated testimony.” (Scheduled for 45 minutes examination, one hour cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2dFvkB"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Trystan Kosmynka, senior director of marketing&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “App Store review policies and practices; iOS and macOS engineering, security and privacy issues; and/or the subjects of designated testimony.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, two hours cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xRKHJZ"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Eddy Cue, senior vice president, internet software and services&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “lack of competition among mobile devices and mobile operating system software; App Store business strategy; App Store financial performance; current and historical App Store policies and practices; Apple’s prior antitrust violations.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, 10 minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jfaig4"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Craig Federighi, senior vice president, software engineering&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “iOS and macOS engineering, security, privacy and competition issues; App Store policies and practices.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SZGEKG"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Scott Forstall, former senior vice president, iOS software&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “iOS and macOS engineering, security, privacy and competition issues; historical App Store policies and practices; Apple’s in-app purchasing function.” (Scheduled for one hour and five minutes examination, 10 minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XmQU7U"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Eric Friedman, head of fraud engineering, algorithms, and risk&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “App Store review process; fraud and other abuse in Apple’s ecosystem.” (Scheduled for 30 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NkytbE"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Eric Gray, director of commerce, subscriptions, and pricing&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “inefficiencies and lack of integration of Apple’s payment processing services; app pricing and inelasticity of demand; fraud and other abuse in Apple’s ecosystem.” (Scheduled for 15 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0SfA0O"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;C.K. Haun, senior director, developer technical services &lt;/strong&gt;— covering “App Store review policies and practices; iOS and macOS engineering, security and privacy issues.” (Scheduled for 50 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZisJ1k"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Ron Okamoto, former VP of worldwide developer relations &lt;/strong&gt;— covering “benefits Apple receives from other software developers, including Epic; Apple’s market power over iOS developers.” (Scheduled for 20 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CV3ix4"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Carson Oliver, director of business management, App Store&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “App Store policies and practices; Apple’s market power over iOS developers.” (Scheduled for 10 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="78Fz52"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shaan Pruden, senior director of partnership management and worldwide developer relations&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “benefits that Apple receives from other software developers, including Epic.” (Scheduled for 10 minutes examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FWytm1"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mark Rollins, finance manager&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “Apple financials; App Store profit and loss statements.” (Scheduled for 10 minutes examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NiBOF6"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Phillip Shoemaker, former technology director, app review&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “historical App Store review policies and practices.” (Scheduled for 55 minutes examination, 15 minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="JygLri"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party witnesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="67U2cG"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Lori Wright, VP of Xbox business development, Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “distribution of software; Xbox video game console business and operations; Xbox cloud gaming, including xCloud and Game Pass; interactions with Apple.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, one hour cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bE32yZ"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Benjamin Simon, founder and CEO of Yoga Buddhi Co.&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “app distribution; participation in the Apple Developer Program; App Store review process; interactions with Apple.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, 30 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fHAqxo"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Aashish Patel, director of product management, Nvidia&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “app distribution; Nvidia’s GeForce Now service and business model; differences between streamed apps and locally hosted apps; differences between native apps and web apps; App Store review process; interactions with Apple.” (Scheduled for 45 minutes examination, 45 minutes cross examination.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lloq8a"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Adrian Ong, senior VP of operations, Match Group&lt;/strong&gt; — covering “app distribution; participation in the Apple Developer Program; App Store review process; interactions with Apple; differences between native apps and web experiences; Match Group’s payment processing capabilities; effects of Apple’s 30% fee on Match Group and its users; user acquisition.” (Scheduled for one hour examination, five minutes cross examination, via deposition rather than live appearance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="7CZcqZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expert witnesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="8LmgU1"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Susan Athey,&lt;/strong&gt; economics of technology professor, Stanford University Graduate School of Business &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VrT659"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Ned Barnes&lt;/strong&gt;, managing director, Berkeley Research Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yGA7Un"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Michael Cragg&lt;/strong&gt;, principal and chairman, The Brattle Group &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Q4jZm2"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;David Evans&lt;/strong&gt;, chairman, Global Economics Group &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NkP2NN"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Wenke Lee&lt;/strong&gt;, chair, College of Computing, Georgia Institute of Technology &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="conGmy"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nancy Mathiowetz&lt;/strong&gt;, professor emerita, department of sociology, the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PAxvYe"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;James Mickens&lt;/strong&gt;, professor of computer science, Harvard University &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AMtI3m"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Peter Rossi&lt;/strong&gt;, professor of marketing, economics and statistics, UCLA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22405894/epic-apple-store-fortnite-trial-kickoff-witnesses-list"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22405894/epic-apple-store-fortnite-trial-kickoff-witnesses-list</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>General Motors has a solution for our crappy EV charging infrastructure</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jld3-uZAG3bfr1_U-yvnbJVdb84=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69200754/akrales_170405_1582_0603.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bc2evx"&gt;General Motors announced a “holistic charging approach” to electric vehicle charging that it’s calling the Ultium Charge 360. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CgX2nz"&gt;Much like Ford does with its FordPass network, the Ultium Charge 360 will integrate GM’s own vehicle apps and software with a variety of third-party charging services, such as Blink, ChargePoint, EVgo, Flo, Greenlots, and SemaConnect. The goal is to create a seamless experience in which an owner of a GM electric vehicle can drive up to a station, plug in, and start charging without having to juggle multiple apps or third-party memberships. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k7zRco"&gt;“There is a lot more to EV adoption than just buying the vehicle and just having a large connected network,” said Travis Hester, GM’s chief EV officer. “And our mission is to help every single person get over whatever anxiety they have, and help them into an EV in the most convenient way possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="n1fxUz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“our mission is to help every single person get over whatever anxiety they have”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4aknMk"&gt;Unlike Tesla or Volkswagen, GM does not own its own EV charging network. Owners of GM’s electric vehicles must instead rely on a patchwork of third-party chargers, each with their own software and membership requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJqOIt"&gt;The challenge, though, will be to ensure that it all works as advertised. A lot will depend on the level of service provided by these various charging services, an aspect that GM will have little control over. EV charging in the US is a bit of a mess, with broken chargers, fraying cables, and unreliable maps. While GM can’t solve some of the more intractable problems, it says it’s doing what it can to make charging a little less of a headache. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bqc3kC"&gt;A good comparison is to the FordPass network, which the automaker first introduced in 2019. The automaker claimed that Ford EV owners would have access to 12,000 public chargers. But the branding made it seem as if Ford were launching its own version of Tesla’s Supercharger network, when it was actually tapping existing stations from companies like Electrify America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2BvgKu"&gt;Speaking of which, Volkswagen’s subsidiary is noticeably absent from GM’s list of participating charging networks. The automaker said it was seeking to add additional charging providers into its Ultium network in the future.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hxkxIX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;GM said it was making good progress on this partnership&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dxd4Pg"&gt;GM wouldn’t say whether its forthcoming EVs would include Plug and Charge capabilities, a new technology standard that allows a much simpler way to charge your car. “We’re not announcing specifics on some of those features,” said Alex Keros, lead architect for EV infrastructure at GM, “but you could certainly imagine Plug and Charge really enabling that seamless experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q5eQqV"&gt;The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349614/general-motors-evgo-fast-charging-network-investment"&gt;announced that it would collaborate with EVgo&lt;/a&gt; to create a constellation of 2,700 electric vehicle fast-charging stations in cities around the country. GM didn’t specify the size of its investment in the charging buildout, and the partnership won’t be exclusive, meaning GM’s vehicles won’t get special access to them. GM said it was making good progress on this partnership, with the first stations already up and running in Washington, California, and Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5n9tYz"&gt;GM, the largest automaker in North America, is in the midst of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220574/gm-new-logo-electric-vehicle-brand-ces-2021"&gt;historic rebranding&lt;/a&gt; as an electric vehicle company. It has committed to spending $27 billion on electric and autonomous vehicles through 2025 — up from the $20 billion it announced before the COVID-19 pandemic. GM has also said it will launch 30 new electric vehicles around the world by that date, more than two-thirds of which will be available in North America. And it has set a goal to phase out its gas-powered vehicles and be a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254116/general-motors-carbon-neutral-vow-2040-tailpipe-emissions-ev"&gt;completely carbon neutral company&lt;/a&gt; by 2040. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWwc3x"&gt;GM unveiled two new EVs in 2020: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21357717/cadillac-lyriq-gm-ev-suv-touchscreen-size-specs-release-date"&gt;the Cadillac Lyriq SUV&lt;/a&gt;, expected to go into production in late 2022, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21525290/hummer-ev-electric-truck-gmc-price-specs-range"&gt;GMC Hummer EV&lt;/a&gt;, slated for late 2021. This year, it has revealed more details about an electric &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/3/22362072/hummer-suv-electric-price-specs-release-date"&gt;Hummer SUV&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/14/22280449/chevy-bolt-ev-euv-super-cruise-range-price-specs"&gt;two new versions of the Chevy Bolt&lt;/a&gt;. And GM has also said it would release an electric Chevy pickup truck with 400 miles of range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="63I0z0"&gt;Hester said the “major functions” of Ultium Charge 360 will be available by September 2021. He described the new features as “single click, one click to activate” an EV charger, as well as some “gamiefied activity” tied to a specific electric vehicle, adding, “I don’t want to spoil the vehicle news.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RjUYlm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407789/gm-ev-charging-general-motors-ultium-charge-360"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407789/gm-ev-charging-general-motors-ultium-charge-360</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T14:55:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T14:55:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s cash cow is PlayStation, not iOS, court documents reveal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XUz2pyjDWF8WgguKqTWOmjJpgXA=/417x138:1448x825/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69200693/Screen_Shot_2021_04_28_at_10.35.29_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lara Croft in &lt;/em&gt;Fortnite&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lKGtNM"&gt;Earlier this month, we learned that the iOS version of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; was a huge revenue driver for Epic Games — the game earned more than $700 million from iOS customers over the two years before it was pulled by Apple, according to &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364265/gov.uscourts.cand.364265.405.0.pdf"&gt;court documents (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; released ahead of Epic’s trial against the iPhone maker. But even though iOS &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; players brought in a staggering amount of money for Epic, iOS isn’t the biggest platform in terms of revenue for the game — apparently, it might even be &lt;em&gt;among the smallest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9AyB3"&gt;Court documents reveal that PlayStation 4 generated 46.8 percent of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s total revenues from March 2018 through July 2020, while Xbox One, the second-highest platform, generated 27.5 percent. iOS ranked fifth, with just 7 percent of total revenue. The remaining 18.7 percent would have been split between Android, Nintendo Switch, and PCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="NJ5beq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;iPhone and iPad accounted for just 5 to 7 percent of Epic’s Fortnite revenue&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0H0PPO"&gt;In 2020, iOS revenues were projected to be an even smaller piece of the pie: just 5.8 percent, compared to 24 percent for Xbox One and “almost 40 percent” for PlayStation 4, according to &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364265/gov.uscourts.cand.364265.495.0.pdf"&gt;a new deposition (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; of Epic Games’ David Nikdel, a senior programmer who works on the backend services for &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="62mPE3"&gt;“iOS was always the lowest or second lowest if Android was listed, correct?” lawyers asked Joe Babcock, Epic’s CFO until March 2020, in a separate deposition. The answer was yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="24QQvj"&gt;Babcock explicitly confirmed that the iOS version of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; earned less revenue, month to month, than: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Pi5iD0"&gt;PlayStation 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="C0aJSN"&gt;Xbox (presumably Xbox One)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="R4ma3j"&gt;Nintendo Switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GOr3kk"&gt;PCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="s46b3V"&gt;iOS’s low revenues compared to other platforms may not be entirely surprising, based on past comments from Epic CEO Tim Sweeney. &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364265/gov.uscourts.cand.364265.65.0.pdf"&gt;He said in a declaration&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on iOS represented 10 percent of the game’s total average daily players in the two years from when the game launched to when it was pulled from the App Store in August. And &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is considered to be a billion-dollar business all on its own: in 2019, it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/2/21046920/fortnite-revenue-drop-superdata-nielsen-2019-earnings"&gt;reportedly brought in $1.8 billion in revenue&lt;/a&gt; all by itself. (Epic projected company-wide revenue of $3.85 billion in 2020, to give you some idea of how big &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is compared to, well, everything else Epic does.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q4Nq3g"&gt;Thanks to these court documents being released ahead of the trial, we now have a better idea of where &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; makes most of its money — and despite the huge amount of dollars flying around mobile games right now, PlayStation and Xbox seem to account for the bulk of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s earnings. They could make Epic’s choice to fight Apple and Google make a bit more sense — even if they alienate the app store companies, Epic can bank on Sony, Microsoft, and Nintendo consoles continuing to rake in cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WgUrAn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VV5Lkh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407939/fortnite-biggest-platform-revenue-playstation-not-ios-iphone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407939/fortnite-biggest-platform-revenue-playstation-not-ios-iphone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T14:53:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T14:53:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s official Vtuber is part sheep and promotes anime</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A screenshot of Netflix’s video introducing N-Ko. It includes a picture of N-Ko and a description reading: “What is she? Sheep-human lifeform”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e7lBgcBzpBJiYVSTVd7_k-7HUNg=/184x0:2134x1300/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69200679/n_ko.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Netflix’s Vtuber, N-Ko. | Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ECFRde"&gt;Netflix has joined the Vtuber trend, &lt;a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/n-ko-mei-kurono"&gt;unveiling a virtual streamer&lt;/a&gt; this week who will host a weekly show on the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBSs9x2KzSLhyyA9IKyt4YA"&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; to promote its original anime series. The character is named N-ko Mei Kurono, and Netflix describes her as the company’s “anime ambassador.” She also happens to be a “sheep-human lifeform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WV6Lgh"&gt; Vtubers, or “virtual YouTubers,” are animated hosts who often vlog on YouTube or stream on Twitch. In general, these characters are operated by a single human, who will use motion capture software (and sometimes a motion-capture outfit) to transform themselves into a cartoony character on-screen. Some Vtubers have become hugely popular over the past year, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21591488/projekt-melody-twitch-ban-copyright-strike-digitrevx-vtuber"&gt;Projekt Melody&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22370260/codemiko-twitch-interview-stream-technician"&gt;CodeMiko&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0aO27U"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rE0-583WBcw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xPLCAk"&gt;Netflix is using the trend as a way to promote its growing interest in anime. The company said recently that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/27/22353848/netflix-launch-anime-ragnarok-zeus-resident-evil-streaming"&gt;plans to launch 40 anime series&lt;/a&gt; in 2021, following a year in which “the amount of Anime watched” on its service doubled in the US. Netflix is about to debut &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22373405/yasuke-netflix-flying-lotus-interview"&gt;a new anime from Flying Lotus&lt;/a&gt;; a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406600/netflix-pretty-guardian-sailor-moon-eternal-the-movie"&gt;new &lt;em&gt;Sailor Moon &lt;/em&gt;movie&lt;/a&gt; is coming to the service in June; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303713/netflix-terminator-anime-production-ig-announced-tv-series"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Terminator &lt;/em&gt;anime&lt;/a&gt; is now in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="luJjkg"&gt;N-ko, the Vtuber, is played by a Netflix employee who works on their anime lineup. Though her primary purpose is promoting Netflix series, she’s also trying to fit in with the rest of the Vtuber community and become a figure viewers might want to watch for herself. “I love singing, dancing, and getting a massage,” N-ko says, “but I don’t like writing kanji or anything that contains elements of horror.” She plans to upload videos highlighting new shows, collaborate with other Vtubers, and maybe sing songs and do video game commentary, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SthzaY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"CodeMiko will see you now  ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22370260/codemiko-twitch-interview-stream-technician"},{"title":"What happens when a virtual streamer doesn’t own her body?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21591488/projekt-melody-twitch-ban-copyright-strike-digitrevx-vtuber"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408078/netflix-vtuber-anime-n-ko-youtube"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408078/netflix-vtuber-anime-n-ko-youtube</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
