<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-03T05:59:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T05:59:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T05:59:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clearview AI ordered to delete all facial recognition data belonging to Australians</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ud0r0rpmpxeY-60SLjM0Km24ufU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70084720/acastro_210512_1777_deepfake_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RBoJJZ"&gt;Controversial facial recognition firm Clearview AI has been ordered to &lt;a href="https://www.oaic.gov.au/updates/news-and-media/clearview-ai-breached-australians-privacy"&gt;destroy all images and facial templates&lt;/a&gt; belonging to individuals living in Australia by the country’s national privacy regulator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cr2CQz"&gt;Clearview, which claims to have scraped 10 billion images of people from social media sites in order to identify them in other photos, sells its technology to law enforcement agencies. It was &lt;a href="https://www.itnews.com.au/news/afp-admits-to-trialling-controversial-facial-recognition-tool-clearview-ai-546729"&gt;trialled by the Australian Federal Police&lt;/a&gt; (AFP) between October 2019 and March 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xQAnQF"&gt;Now, following an investigation, Australia privacy regulator, the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC), has found that the company breached citizens’ privacy. “The covert collection of this kind of sensitive information is unreasonably intrusive and unfair,” said OAIC privacy commissioner Angelene Falk in a press statement. “It carries significant risk of harm to individuals, including vulnerable groups such as children and victims of crime, whose images can be searched on Clearview AI’s database.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="I3o8Pw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“When Australians use social media or professional networking sites, they don’t expect their facial images to be collected without their consent”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hF4zbb"&gt;Said Falk: “When Australians use social media or professional networking sites, they don’t expect their facial images to be collected without their consent by a commercial entity to create biometric templates for completely unrelated identification purposes. The indiscriminate scraping of people’s facial images, only a fraction of whom would ever be connected with law enforcement investigations, may adversely impact the personal freedoms of all Australians who perceive themselves to be under surveillance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="emHVfC"&gt;The investigation into Clearview’s practices by the OAIC was carried out in conjunction with the UK’s Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). However, the ICO has &lt;a href="https://ico.org.uk/about-the-ico/news-and-events/news-and-blogs/2021/11/clearview-statement/"&gt;yet to make a decision&lt;/a&gt; about the legality of Clearview’s work in the UK. The agency says it is “considering its next steps and any formal regulatory action that may be appropriate under the UK data protection laws.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9th3t"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/nov/03/facial-recognition-firm-cleaview-ai-to-appeal-order-to-stop-collecting-images-of-australians"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Clearview itself intends to appeal the decision. “Clearview AI operates legitimately according to the laws of its places of business,” Mark Love, a lawyer for the firm BAL Lawyers representing Clearview, told the publication. “Not only has the commissioner’s decision missed the mark on the manner of Clearview AI’s manner of operation, the commissioner lacks jurisdiction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2fVxLu"&gt;Clearview argues that the images it collected were publicly available, so no breach of privacy occurred, and that they were published in the US, so Australian law does not apply. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EXHtX2"&gt;Around the world, though, there is growing discontent with the spread of facial recognition systems, which threaten to eliminate anonymity in public spaces. Yesterday, Facebook parent company Meta announced it was shutting down the social platform’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759613/meta-facebook-face-recognition-automatic-tagging-feature-shutdown"&gt;facial recognition feature&lt;/a&gt; and deleting the facial templates it created for the system. The company cited “growing concerns about the use of this technology as a whole.” Meta also recently paid a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304618/judge-approves-facebook-privacy-settlement-illinois-facial-recognition"&gt;$650 million settlement&lt;/a&gt; after the tech was found to have breached privacy laws in Illinois in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761001/clearview-ai-facial-recognition-australia-breach-data-delete"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761001/clearview-ai-facial-recognition-australia-breach-data-delete</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T21:44:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T21:44:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Happy Halloween! Theranos showed up in a Pfizer costume</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Theranos Founder Elizabeth Holmes Attends Criminal Trial" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V9XNLHV-2QhUZjDLMi-_TKc0_XI=/0x0:3999x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70082767/1235841403.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;With a logo on a memo and a little bit of language trickery, Theranos snookered rich investors&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="SGiMTW"&gt;Today we learned more about Theranos’ kink for corporate cosplay. The company liked to dress up its own reports in pharmaceutical companies’ logos, to use the present tense when the future tense would be more appropriate, and to reiterate its favorite buzzwords in PowerPoint slide after PowerPoint slide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xNLDNi"&gt;Elizabeth Holmes’ lawyers, in defending her against the wire fraud charges that the government has brought, resumed cross-examination of Lisa Peterson, who worked for the DeVos family offices and was involved in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22747918/theranos-devos-due-diligence-fraud-trial"&gt;approving their investment in the company&lt;/a&gt;. (Family offices are a rich people thing — an investment arm for all that sweet, sweet money.) The defense tried to discredit Peterson’s testimony from last week about a key Pfizer memo, which she said was crucial to thinking the company was onto something big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="62PsiF"&gt;The only problem? Pfizer didn’t write it. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-elizabeth-holmes-trial-former-pfizer-scientist-says-theranos-used-pharma-logo-without-permission-11634942227"&gt;A former scientist at the company testified&lt;/a&gt; that Theranos changed a report the blood-testing startup had made to include the unauthorized use of the Pfizer logo. Pfizer’s actual findings were that Theranos’ conclusions in that report were “not believable,” the former Pfizer scientist had testified. But Peterson didn’t know that, and had relied on the memo as real validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="CRYdYs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;We wound up talking about verb tenses&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="99DYQz"&gt;Homes’ defense attorney Lance Wade pointed out that Theranos’ physical address and website were at the bottom of that Pfizer memo, in the footer. The text of the footer was considerably smaller than the Pfizer logo at the top of the page, suggesting the relative importance of each piece of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LpRI0K"&gt;When the prosecution got a chance to talk with Peterson again, they asked her if the footer information would have convinced her the memo wasn’t from Pfizer. No, she said — the logo on the top was big. When she and her colleagues were considering an investment, “we really relied on the fact that they had been doing work for pharmaceutical companies and the government for years,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nj3Bws"&gt;This was how we wound up talking about verb tenses. After establishing that Peterson knows what the future is, the prosecution went through some Theranos slides. “Theranos proprietary technology runs comprehensive blood tests from a finger stick,” one read. “Runs” is present tense and indicates that the tests are &lt;em&gt;currently &lt;/em&gt;happening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjWZNZ"&gt;In fact we ran through several slides to discuss verb tenses — all of which were present or past, not future. During the cross-examination, Wade had returned to an idea he’d floated earlier in the trial: that the investors in Theranos were sophisticated, and that they’d even signed paperwork saying that Theranos was a speculative investment. The implication seemed to be that Theranos wasn’t devious — Peterson was just sloppy, and Theranos was promising what it would do in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X7n2oC"&gt;But the language in the presentation undercut that idea. Somewhere, a grammarian rejoiced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="9onVHC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“On a couple of occasions I attempted to ask questions to other Theranos staff in the meeting and the response was interrupted by Ms. Holmes.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nvwGUN"&gt;After Peterson left the stand, we were treated to more Big Pharma testimony, this time from Constance Cullen, who worked at Schering-Plough, which was then acquired by Merck. In 2009, Cullen’s boss had asked her to evaluate Theranos’ tech. In the course of doing so, Cullen met with Holmes and other people at Theranos, but it seems Holmes did all the talking.  “On a couple of occasions I attempted to ask questions to other Theranos staff in the meeting and the response was interrupted by Ms. Holmes,” Cullen testified. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3D06jE"&gt;During the meeting, Cullen said she found Holmes’ answers to technical questions “cagey.” Originally, there was supposed to be validation data at that meeting, but it wasn’t actually delivered by Theranos until December 2009 — and since Theranos was the party conducting the validation studies, only Theranos’ logo appeared on the report. Neither she nor anyone else at Schering-Plough said its conclusions were accurate, she testified. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PLeA2G"&gt;Things were hectic for Cullen, since Merck had just acquired her company and she was now managing a larger team. She postponed discussing the report, and did not return to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EiiPTy"&gt;Still, Theranos approached Walgreens in 2010 with a version of that validation report. &lt;em&gt;This &lt;/em&gt;version had the Schering-Plough logo atop it. In an email accompanying the report, Holmes wrote, “As per our discussion, please find three independent due diligence reports on Theranos systems attached to this email. These reports are from GlaxoSmithKlein, Pfizer and Schering-Plough after their own technical validation and experience with Theranos Systems in the field.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="K7eU8X"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Goodbye, big bad needle.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iSCQzJ"&gt;The new version of the report had a new conclusion. While the original version said that Theranos devices “give accurate and precise results,” the new logo report said that Theranos devices “give more accurate and precise results… than current ‘gold standard’ reference methods.&lt;em&gt;” &lt;/em&gt;Schering-Plough hadn’t approved the old language; it certainly hadn’t approved the new language — Theranos had written both versions of the report. Schering-Plough hadn’t responded to the original in any way, and was likely unaware of the… let’s say &lt;em&gt;enhanced &lt;/em&gt;version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DvtiOF"&gt;The memos and slideshows resurfaced in the testimony of Daniel Mosley, who invested “a little under $6 million” in Theranos, after his buddy Henry Kissinger, a Theranos board member, asked him to evaluate the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="linHkc"&gt;Like Peterson, Mosley was won over by the work Theranos said it had done with the government and large pharma companies. In the memo Mosley wrote to Kissinger, he seemed very impressed by the not-Pfizer memo, even devoting an entire section of his own memo to its findings. It wasn’t just the logo that made him think Pfizer was behind the report; the conclusions read like they were from a third party, he testified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Rj7L6"&gt;Mosley also thought all Theranos tests were done by fingerstick, largely because of the materials Theranos provided him with. We saw a Theranos-generated slide of a child captioned “Goodbye, big bad needle” and another that read “Our certified labs perform precise tests on a sample 1/1,000 the size of a typical blood draw. No big vials to fill. No more searching for a vein.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="K2fGe1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Rob Walton ran into one of your board members over the weekend at the Grove.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9L42C6"&gt;At times, Mosley’s testimony felt like a live reading of the social register. He had worked at a famous and fancy law firm, Cravath, where his job was counseling rich people about how to stay rich. Some of his clients invested in Theranos — the DeVos family was in for $100 million; the Walmart heirs, the Waltons, were in for $150 million; the Cox family invested $10 million of its cable wealth; and Kissinger’s trust went in for $3 million. Andreas Dracopolous of the Stavros Niarchos Foundation went in for $25 million, and John Elkann, of the family that owns Ferrari, invested $5 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xScI9d"&gt;The testimony placed Mosley at the center of a group of extremely rich and influential people, but as if to drive home the point we viewed an email from him to Holmes. The day after talking with her for the first time, he offered to introduce her to the Walton family. Then, he followed up: “Rob Walton ran into one of your board members over the weekend at the Grove.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aj5tFH"&gt;I’m not sure which board member this was — the testimony didn’t specify — but by “the Grove,” Mosley meant the ultra-exclusive boys’ club &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/blogpost/post/bohemian-grove-where-the-rich-and-powerful-go-to-misbehave/2011/06/15/AGPV1sVH_blog.html"&gt;The Bohemian Grove&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately he did not get into the weird naked rituals or anything else of interest to us plebeians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="cWKReo"&gt;With Mosley, as with Peterson, the defense seemed to be suggesting that the Theranos investors were simply dimwitted — rich, dull, and incapable of checking up on the things they poured their money into. But between the language Theranos used in its presentations, its tweaked memos that weren’t &lt;em&gt;actually &lt;/em&gt;from pharmaceutical companies, and its continued emphasis that its tests were faster and better than anything else, it seems obvious that Theranos &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; its investors to believe the hype. Just because someone is sloppy doesn’t make it okay to try to trick them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760601/theranos-pfizer-schering-plough-logo-memo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760601/theranos-pfizer-schering-plough-logo-memo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T19:15:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T19:15:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Zillow reportedly needs to sell 7,000 houses after it bought too many</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cFRnEGEG8S8DUxEkOpI3I0tPVhY=/252x0:3252x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70076828/High_Res_Zillow_DeviceProductImage_b_01.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Zillow&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ODl9et"&gt;Zillow is trying to offload around $2.8 billion worth of houses onto investors after it bought them with the intent of selling them to hopeful homeowners and landlords, according to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-01/zillow-selling-7-000-homes-for-2-8-billion-after-flipping-halt?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;a report by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This follows &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-18/zillow-s-flipping-snag-spotlights-risk-in-cooling-housing-market?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;another &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; that the real estate browsing website had to stop buying houses when it found itself with excess inventory after the company told investors it planned on ramping up its flipping business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oAMtou"&gt;On Tuesday, Zillow announced in its earnings report that it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760080/zillow-offers-home-selling-ibuyer-wind-down-excess-inventory-losses-financial-results"&gt;winding down the practice entirely&lt;/a&gt;, and estimated that it’ll lose over half a billion dollars in value on the houses it owns. It also announced that it would be laying off about a quarter of its employees, and said that it had underestimated how unpredictable the housing market is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="PhdD68"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Zillow is moving out of the home-selling business ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760080/zillow-offers-home-selling-ibuyer-wind-down-excess-inventory-losses-financial-results"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oKPG4A"&gt;Some readers may be surprised that Zillow buys and sells houses, rather than just acting as a place for real estate agents to post listings — I was too when I first heard about it, but the company has actually been doing this for years through &lt;a href="https://www.zillow.com/offers/"&gt;its Zillow Offers program&lt;/a&gt;. According to its site, the idea is that Zillow will buy your house in cash, streamlining the process significantly. It’ll then deal with any repairs or quick renovations and then sell the house itself. It’s not the only one with this business model either — competing real estate site Redfin has a similar program, and there are entire companies dedicated to internet-based home-buying, like OpenDoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="PhbSLH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Zillow was in an “arms race” to scoop up houses throughout the summer&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XbmscU"&gt;In August, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93ymxz/zillow-other-tech-firms-are-in-an-arms-race-to-buy-up-american-homes"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; article detailed&lt;/a&gt; what it described as an “arms race” among tech companies that were trying to buy up as much real estate as possible as &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/9/16/22674410/housing-crisis-homelessness-poll"&gt;housing prices exploded across the country&lt;/a&gt;. According to the report, Zillow bet big, telling investors that it planned to buy thousands of houses throughout 2021 and turn its Homes division into a billion-dollar business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="syrXK4"&gt;As the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547454/2021-heat-wave-temperature-high-heat-dome"&gt;staggeringly hot summer&lt;/a&gt; came to an end, though, it seemed like Zillow’s Offers business was also cooling down — in October, &lt;a href="https://investors.zillowgroup.com/investors/news-and-events/news/news-details/2021/At-Operational-Capacity-Zillow-Offers-to-Focus-on-Signed-Customer-Contracts-and-Current-Inventory-Suspends-Signing-of-New-Contracts-Through-2021/default.aspx"&gt;the company told investors&lt;/a&gt; that it would stop buying houses, citing construction, renovation, and closing labor shortages. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, however, speculated that it &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-18/zillow-s-flipping-snag-spotlights-risk-in-cooling-housing-market?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;could also be motivated by excess inventory&lt;/a&gt; and reported that Zillow seemed to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-26/zillow-s-zeal-to-outbid-for-homes-backfires-in-flipping-fumble?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;sell a good number of houses at a loss&lt;/a&gt; instead of a profit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oTwoMQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The housing market has been on a wild ride, and it’s probably not Zillow’s fault&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C180e2"&gt;Now, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-01/zillow-selling-7-000-homes-for-2-8-billion-after-flipping-halt"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Zillow is looking to offload around 7,000 of the homes it bought. Unfortunately, it doesn’t seem like individual house hunters will be able to benefit from Zillow’s troubles — &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports that the company is trying to sell the homes to “institutional investors” (read: Wall Street-like firms) to the tune of $2.8 billion. To would-be homebuyers who have been turned down due to a seemingly endless supply of cash buyers, it &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22524829/wall-street-housing-market-blackrock-bubble"&gt;may feel like a slap in the face&lt;/a&gt;. However, it doesn’t seem like the housing market’s wild ride is entirely due to investment bankers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hheedq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22524829/wall-street-housing-market-blackrock-bubble"&gt;A report from &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; cites research that investors only made up about 20 percent of the home-buying market in 2020, and &lt;a href="https://www.zillow.com/research/zillow-ibuyer-report-q2-2021-30011/"&gt;Zillow says that it&lt;/a&gt; and its competitors made up around 1 percent of the housing market in Q2 2021. In some ways, those numbers are both terrifying and reassuring — a fifth of the housing market is a massive and influential chunk, but it also means that it likely wasn’t a private equity firm (or Zillow) that outbid you on your dream home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BLq9I"&gt;It’s hard to tell what will come of this sale and how it’ll affect Zillow’s home flipping plans in the future. However, it probably won’t stop &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22743258/home-buying-zillow-redfin-ibuyers-real-estate"&gt;the conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt; that Zillow is driving up prices on purpose, and if I’m any indication, it won’t make home hopefuls feel any better about their chances of scoring a place to live. Perhaps it’s just another data point for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744728/money-fandom-cryptocurrency-retail-trades-stocks"&gt;the argument that finances are a meme now&lt;/a&gt; and that betting big doesn’t mean you’re going to get what you’re hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wdNt0X"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 2nd, 7:15PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information about Zillow ending its Offers program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22758176/zillow-offers-ibuyer-housing-market-inventory-investors-real-estate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22758176/zillow-offers-ibuyer-housing-market-inventory-investors-real-estate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T18:25:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T18:25:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds are a go-to pick that’s often on sale&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HYaZ7v"&gt;Tis’ the season for AirPods discounts galore. Last week, Apple finally launched its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22671344/apple-new-airpods-3-spacial-audio-specs-price-release-date-features"&gt;third generation of AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, introducing a new AirPods lineup and dropping the starting price of the second-gen, entry-level AirPods from $159 to $129. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday&lt;/a&gt; are also just around the corner, meaning many retailers are also starting to discount the AirPods Pro, AirPods Max, and even the aforementioned third-gen model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hV5pag"&gt;Even this far ahead of the shopping holiday, there are sizable discounts to be had on the second-gen AirPods as well as the more expensive AirPods Pro and Max, which offer noise cancellation and better sound quality than the standard model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the best deals available on the entry-level AirPods, the AirPods Pro, the third-gen AirPods, and the AirPods Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TaIhNe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Which AirPods model should you buy?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy"},{"title":"The best early Black Friday deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="VFDHZw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10742787"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ej2msf"&gt;The best entry-level &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;AirPods&lt;/a&gt; (second-gen) deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eg29V6"&gt;Once $159, Apple recently lowered the list price of the second-gen AirPods — now the entry-level model — to $129. Moreover, it only sells the model with a wired charging case, which charges via a standard Lightning cable. What’s great, though, is that this version frequently gets discounted, so you can buy it for even less. Right now, for instance, you can find Apple’s most affordable pair of AirPods for $120 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_0lrWhTzc2xyIWSIWPUxqHXoGUkG0HdVMNz%253A%253AT00%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3D0lrWhTzc2xyIWSIWPUxqHXoGUkG0HdVMNz%253A%253AT00%26sharedid%3Dverge%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodDeals110221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747976896193620917" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;Although you can’t buy them from Apple, you can still also buy the entry-level AirPods with a wireless charging case elsewhere, which you can charge via a Qi wireless pad or a Lightning cable. Right now, you can get a pair for $150 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F482532021%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_0lrWhTzc2xyIWSIWPUxqHXoGUkG0Hf3UNz%253A%253AT00%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3D0lrWhTzc2xyIWSIWPUxqHXoGUkG0Hf3UNz%253A%253AT00%26sharedid%3D%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodDeals110221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; instead of their typical $199 list price. However, given the latest AirPods — which we’ll dive into just a minute — cost $30 extra and come with MagSafe support along with other perks, it may not be worth buying this model unless you’re truly strapped for cash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="AFyzAp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods (third-gen)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="d2yjBK"&gt;As previously mentioned, the newest pair of wireless earbuds support Apple’s MagSafe technology. The short stems allow for a more subtle design, while improved sound and features like sweat and water resistance, support for spatial audio with dynamic head tracking, and improved battery life render them a nice improvement over the last-gen model. Deals are currently hard to come by on the third-gen model given how recently they launched, however, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MME73AM-A-AirPods-3rd-Generation/dp/B09JQL3NWT/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; is selling them right now for $175. It’s a small discount, but also their lowest price yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Q2OXRZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10744075"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="qBADDX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on MacBooks right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="Iewbkw"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="S8o5q4"&gt;We think Apple’s premium true wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, are the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; that iPhone owners can buy, regardless of the price. They have better sound quality than the models above, offer active noise cancellation, and come with a wireless charging case. The earbuds also support Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;spatial audio&lt;/a&gt; feature, which adds an immersive surround sound effect to select content, and comes with swappable silicone tips. In addition, they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22713126/airpods-pro-conversation-boost-firmware-update" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recently received a firmware&lt;/a&gt; update that added Conversation Boost, an accessibility feature for those who are hard of hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bM8uVd"&gt;Additionally, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733183/apple-magsafe-charging-case-airpods-pro-qi" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recently launched a new version&lt;/a&gt; of the AirPods Pro with a wireless charging case that supports Apple’s MagSafe technology, just like the third-gen AirPods. These start at $249, but you can buy them right now for $190 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQMJHXY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. If you prefer, you can also purchase the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07ZPC9QD4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;older version&lt;/a&gt; without MagSafe compatibility — which still supports Qi-compatible wireless chargers — for a discounted $175 at Amazon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="THtgJp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="x5NHYH"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ESUeUd"&gt;The AirPods Max aren’t the iconic in-ear style that has become synonymous with the AirPods name. They’re large and luxurious, wrapped in aluminum, steel, and mesh fabric that remains comfortable during extended listening sessions. They also sport excellent noise cancellation, Apple’s spatial audio feature, and wide, balanced sound, even if they lag behind some of their peers when it comes to bass response. They’re not the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; for most people — blame the $550 sticker price — but it’s hard to find a pair of Bluetooth headphones that sound better and feature more intuitive controls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KBAAwB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361602"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="irGZgJ"&gt;Although the AirPods Max have been discounted to $449 at Amazon in the past month, there are currently no sales that deep to speak of. The Max are, however, currently available in all colorways at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-AirPods-Max-Space/dp/B08PZHYWJS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfThsYtSLBr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $479, one of their better prices in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Mpx47T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T17:56:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T17:56:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can now, technically, build your own USB-C iPhone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6ldEp4WZoNnialYf5G-AJwwWJ08=/0x0:1320x880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70081607/usbciphone.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rUhqOu"&gt;Robotics engineering student Ken Pillonel wowed the internet last month with a wild hack that managed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722123/first-iphone-usb-c-port-robotics-engineering-student-custom"&gt;put a working USB-C port&lt;/a&gt; inside an iPhone X for a fully functional USB-C iPhone. And now, Pillonel has published a far more detailed video showing just how he managed to pull off the hack, &lt;a href="https://github.com/kenp-io/not-for-iphone-usb-c/tree/master/ip-x"&gt;along with a Github repository&lt;/a&gt; with technical details, CNC instructions, and information on the custom PCB that he designed for anyone brave enough to try and put together a similar hack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qiIyLz"&gt;The 13-minute-long video shows off the nitty-gritty of Pillonel’s mod, which is simple in theory: combining a Lightning to USB-C connection together in a daisy chain to mimic a proper USB-C port. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="brDvJQ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FVEQJNRmfDQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Cumahx"&gt;The video shows off virtually the whole development process. It’s quite a journey, going from proof of concept prototypes, reverse engineering the Lightning connector (and eventually, reverse engineering a fake Lightning connector), ordering a custom flexible circle board, and machining the iPhone’s case to fit the physically larger USB-C connector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEhnb7"&gt;The video also shows off just how difficult it was to fit the extra circuitry, with the board bending around both sides of Apple’s Taptic Engine hardware to squeeze in all the necessary components. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DOKSKv"&gt;Pillonel is also &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F165161363347&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F2%2F22759704%2Fusb-c-iphone-hack-mod-open-source-github-repo-ken-pillonel-design-video" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;auctioning off his original prototype&lt;/a&gt; on eBay, where bidding has already reached $3,400 as of the time of publishing this piece, for anyone with deep pockets that’s interested in a USB-C iPhone of their own. Pillonel does note that whoever does buy the phone shouldn’t restore, update, or erase it, open it, or “use it as your daily phone.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rQr8ch"&gt;Lastly, Pillonel has made the whole project open source so that others can build on his existing work, whether that’s making more custom USB-C iPhone X models or porting the design to other iPhones down the line (although the full PCB design won’t be posted until after the auction finished). He also notes that he plans to continue to build on the design, with goals for improving fast-charging, waterproofing, and even enabling USB-C accessories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UGSJs6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759704/usb-c-iphone-hack-mod-open-source-github-repo-ken-pillonel-design-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759704/usb-c-iphone-hack-mod-open-source-github-repo-ken-pillonel-design-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T17:29:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T17:29:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Zillow is moving out of the home-selling business </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Zillow Application Ahead Of Earnings Figures" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_JbM13RHCqAp8tDFnV50xB8QKxw=/0x2:4000x2669/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70081459/1232667514.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C9xC1Q"&gt;Zillow has announced that it’s winding down the Zillows Offers program, a day after reports surfaced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22758176/zillow-offers-ibuyer-housing-market-inventory-investors-real-estate"&gt;it’s selling over 7,000 of the houses&lt;/a&gt; it purchased with the intent of flipping them to would-be home buyers. In &lt;a href="https://investors.zillowgroup.com/investors/news-and-events/news/news-details/2021/Zillow-Group-Reports-Third-Quarter-2021-Financial-Results--Shares-Plan-to-Wind-Down-Zillow-Offers-Operations/default.aspx"&gt;a press release announcing its Q3 results&lt;/a&gt;, the company says that Zillow Offers only served “a small portion” of its customers. CEO Rich Barton now says that “We’ve determined the unpredictability in forecasting home prices far exceeds what we anticipated and continuing to scale Zillow Offers would result in too much earnings and balance-sheet volatility.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nA4uDM"&gt;With the program shutting down, the company says it’s reducing the estimated value of the houses it’s purchased in Q3 or will purchase in Q4 by more than $500 million. Zillow also says that winding down the business in the coming months will mean having to let go of almost 25 percent of its employees — almost 2,000 workers, &lt;a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2021/zillow-shutter-home-buying-business-lay-off-2k-employees-big-real-estate-bet-falters"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;GeekWire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="rkaW8G"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Just months ago, Zillow was touting Offers as a growing part of its business&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gqfBm8"&gt;In August, Zillow’s &lt;a href="https://investors.zillowgroup.com/investors/news-and-events/news/news-details/2021/Zillow-Group-Reports-Second-Quarter-2021-Financial-Results/default.aspx"&gt;Q2 financial documents&lt;/a&gt; told a very different story — the company said that Offers was a particularly notable part of its business and that it had even secured &lt;a href="https://s24.q4cdn.com/723050407/files/doc_financials/2021/q2/Zillow-Q2'21-Shareholder-Letter_Exhibit-99.3.pdf"&gt;a loan for around $450 million&lt;/a&gt; to “continue funding [its] Zillow Offers growth.” It also touted its mass acquisition of homes as proof that its “pricing models and automation” for making offers was good for people selling their houses. &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93ymxz/zillow-other-tech-firms-are-in-an-arms-race-to-buy-up-american-homes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that there was an “arms race” between tech companies to scoop up real estate to sell to home hopefuls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7NoQwM"&gt;Despite Zillow’s enthusiasm, what benefited sellers didn’t necessarily help out the company.  &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-02/zillow-shuts-down-home-flipping-business-after-racking-up-losses"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the company lost over $380 million on its Homes division, which ran Zillow Offers. In its Q3 shareholder letter, the company said that trying to grow Offers at the scale it hoped would be “risky” and said that it’d provided “too little opportunity for return on equity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OXi2iT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Zillow Offers had problems under the surface&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MyILzf"&gt;There were signs that the program was in trouble — a report on Monday said that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22758176/zillow-offers-ibuyer-housing-market-inventory-investors-real-estate"&gt;Zillow was looking to offload over 7,000 homes&lt;/a&gt; it had bought, not to individual buyers but investors. In October, &lt;a href="https://investors.zillowgroup.com/investors/news-and-events/news/news-details/2021/At-Operational-Capacity-Zillow-Offers-to-Focus-on-Signed-Customer-Contracts-and-Current-Inventory-Suspends-Signing-of-New-Contracts-Through-2021/default.aspx"&gt;the company announced&lt;/a&gt; that it was going to stop buying houses, citing labor shortages as the reason for its excess inventory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pWqDOr"&gt;Zillow says in its press release and shareholders letter that it plans on focusing on its “core business” of providing a place to browse houses for sale and provide pricing estimates. It even goes as far as saying that its Offers program disappointed 90 percent of the people who didn’t end up selling their homes to the company, possibly hurting that core business by turning people who were in the market off from Zillow. The company doesn’t provide details on how it disappointed those potential sellers when it was offering what it calls a “fair market price.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760080/zillow-offers-home-selling-ibuyer-wind-down-excess-inventory-losses-financial-results"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760080/zillow-offers-home-selling-ibuyer-wind-down-excess-inventory-losses-financial-results</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T17:29:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T17:29:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Overwatch 2 and Diablo IV delayed again with no release date in sight</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RjV5pbQLDez7uCr_h66RGeBUSXY=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70081457/ow2__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SXs6pD"&gt;During Activision Blizzard’s third-quarter earnings call, the publisher announced that &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; will now launch later than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rHUhAh"&gt;“As we have worked with new leadership in Blizzard and within the franchises themselves, particularly in certain key creative roles, it has become apparent that some of the Blizzard content planned for next year will benefit from more development time to reach its full potential,” a Blizzard executive said during the call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cKxxtr"&gt;Activision Blizzard mentioned “higher voluntary turnover” and “the departure of a number of individuals across the company” as factors contributing to this new delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CvNEM6"&gt;Blizzard Entertainment suffered a large number of firings and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760136/blizzard-co-lead-jen-oneal-steps-down-mike-ybarra"&gt;high-profile departures&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620800/activision-blizzard-departures-lawsuit-diablo-4-director"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diablo IV &lt;/em&gt;game director Luis Barriga&lt;/a&gt;, after news broke of the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597113/activision-blizzard-california-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-discrimination-employee-action"&gt;multiple lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; alleging sexual harassment, assault, discrimination, and unfair labor practices. &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394116/overwatch-director-jeff-kaplan-activision-blizzard-departure"&gt;lost its director Jeff Kaplan&lt;/a&gt; right before the lawsuits were publicized. These departures have apparently affected Blizzard’s ability to develop and release these highly anticipated games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tBoDyD"&gt;While neither &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; nor &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267131/diablo-4-overwatch-2-release-date-2022-activision-blizzard-earnings"&gt;had concrete release dates&lt;/a&gt;, the company strongly hinted at a 2022 release window. Now it seems both games will likely not release until 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9ch7c"&gt;“While we are still planning to deliver a substantial amount of content from Blizzard next year, we are now planning for a later launch for &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; than originally envisaged,” Activision Blizzard said on the call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XIYn10"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qnMfzf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760118/activision-blizzard-delays-overwatch-2-and-diablo-4-again"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760118/activision-blizzard-delays-overwatch-2-and-diablo-4-again</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T17:21:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T17:21:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Blizzard co-lead Jen Oneal steps down three months after taking the role</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sl7X4i1s2cscVNksmyL0vvxWQrY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70081433/acastro_210729_1777_blizzard_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AmGx2R"&gt;Jen Oneal is stepping down as a co-lead of Blizzard just three months after taking the role in the wake of the sexual harassment lawsuit brought against Activision Blizzard by the state of California. Mike Ybarra, a former Xbox executive who had stepped into the co-lead role alongside Oneal, will now be the sole lead of the studio, effective immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aT4QdM"&gt;“I want you to hear from me personally that I have made the decision to step away from co-leading Blizzard Entertainment and will transition to a new position before departing ABK at the end of the year,” Oneal said in a &lt;a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/blizzard/23738005/a-message-from-jen-oneal"&gt;statement on Blizzard’s website&lt;/a&gt;. “I am doing this not because I am without hope for Blizzard, quite the opposite — I’m inspired by the passion of everyone here, working towards meaningful, lasting change with their whole hearts. This energy has inspired me to step out and explore how I can do &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; to have games and diversity intersect, and hopefully make a broader industry impact that will benefit Blizzard (and other studios) as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="uZ7oHa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’m inspired by the passion of everyone here, working towards meaningful, lasting change with their whole hearts.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Tw0Cts"&gt;Blizzard will be making a $1 million grant to &lt;a href="https://www.getwigi.com/"&gt;Women in Games International&lt;/a&gt;, where Oneal is a board member. Before she fully leaves Activision Blizzard, Oneal will work to “determine the first steps around how the grant will be utilized, and its structure,” she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VjKUdr"&gt;Activision Blizzard has undergone significant changes since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588215/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-sexual-harassment-discrimination-pay"&gt;the lawsuit was filed in July&lt;/a&gt;. Former &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607356/blizzard-president-leaving-harassment-protest-brack"&gt;Blizzard president J. Allen Brack&lt;/a&gt; (who Ybarra and Oneal replaced) and former &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608320/blizard-jesse-meschuk-leave-company-hr-svp"&gt;head of global human resources Jesse Meschuck&lt;/a&gt; left the company in early August. The company’s chief legal officer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686183/blizzard-chief-legal-officer-leaves"&gt;departed in September&lt;/a&gt;. And Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick took a massive pay cut and ended forced arbitration &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750450/activision-blizzard-ends-forced-arbitration-bobby-kotick-paycut"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G0nW3E"&gt;In addition to staffing changes, the company has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22746780/blizzard-blizzcon-harassment-cancel-warcraft-overwatch-blizzconline"&gt;paused plans for BlizzConline 2021&lt;/a&gt; and made changes to its games to remove references to problematic characters or themes. Blizzard changed the name of &lt;em&gt;Overwatch’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740836/blizzard-overwatch-jesse-mccree-name-change-cole-cassidy"&gt;Jesse McCree&lt;/a&gt;, who was named after a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620800/activision-blizzard-departures-lawsuit-diablo-4-director"&gt;former lead designer&lt;/a&gt;, and vowed to remove “references that are not appropriate for our world” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22597006/blizzard-world-of-warcraft-activision-remove-references-harassment-lawsuit"&gt;in &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jjmkqy"&gt;Activision Blizzard also announced Tuesday that &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Diablo 4&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760118/activision-blizzard-delays-overwatch-2-and-diablo-4-again"&gt;have been delayed again&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760136/blizzard-co-lead-jen-oneal-steps-down-mike-ybarra"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760136/blizzard-co-lead-jen-oneal-steps-down-mike-ybarra</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T16:46:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T16:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>If you haven’t gotten a Switch N64 controller yet, you’ll have to wait until next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M-ulPySXjLcbtlP8tjvL-mFaGWU=/0x20:1194x816/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70081235/114294_switch_nso_n64_controller_lifestyle_2000x2000.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nintendo Switch N64 controller.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="v0r6ZG"&gt;The special Nintendo 64 controller for the Nintendo Switch &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Wario64/status/1455558201416425473"&gt;briefly went on sale again&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, but if you missed buying one before they sold out, you won’t get a chance to pick one up until 2022, &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/nintendo-64-controller.html"&gt;according to the controller’s listing&lt;/a&gt; on Nintendo’s website. We don’t know exactly when it will be back in stock, as all Nintendo says is that “more controllers will be available in 2022.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W5nqlwcW-bZABn2A0ZbsKdLXeHg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22980526/Screen_Shot_2021_11_02_at_1.44.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Switch N64 controllers are out of stock until 2022. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Z1MnZo"&gt;The Nintendo 64 controller was released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728144/nintendo-64-sega-genesis-controllers-switch-online-expansion-pack-buy-order"&gt;in October&lt;/a&gt; ahead of the availability of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728113/nintendo-switch-online-plus-expansion-pack-price-n64-genesis-animal-crossing"&gt;Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack&lt;/a&gt;, a premium Nintendo Switch Online tier that gives you access to Nintendo 64 games and Sega Genesis games. You don’t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; the controller to play Nintendo 64 titles on your Switch, but players have found that the button layouts for some games &lt;a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/n64-games-for-nintendo-switch-online-have-some-issues/1100-6497396/"&gt;don’t translate well&lt;/a&gt; to Joy-Con or the Switch Pro Controller. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6mV0iJ"&gt;If you want to pick up a Nintendo 64 controller when they’re back in stock next year, make sure you’re a member of Nintendo Switch Online, as the controllers are only available to subscribers of the service. The Nintendo Switch Sega Genesis controllers &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/sega-genesis-control-pad.html"&gt;are currently in stock&lt;/a&gt; as of this writing, however, so you might want to pick one up so you can take a nostalgia trip while playing &lt;em&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog 2&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Gunstar Heroes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760049/nintendo-switch-64-n64-controller-in-stock-2022-next-year"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760049/nintendo-switch-64-n64-controller-in-stock-2022-next-year</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T16:30:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T16:30:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Googler who helped lead 2018 walkout will reportedly join the FTC </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yn4D1okjhjETHWi5LmoGt9C6e-4=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70081183/acastro_180320_1777_cambridge_analytica_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3OFSSD"&gt;Former Google employee Meredith Whittaker could soon be working at the Federal Trade Commission as an AI policy advisor, &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/former-google-activist-whittaker-expected-to-join-ftc-as-ai-adviser"&gt;according to a report by &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Whittaker may be best known for helping to organize a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/2/18057716/google-walkout-20-thousand-employees-ceo-sundar-pichai-meeting"&gt;2018 walkout at Google&lt;/a&gt;, where 20,000 employees protested against how the company handled alleged sexual harassment, and for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/16/20695964/google-protest-leader-meredith-whittaker-leaves-company"&gt;leaving Google afterward&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that it had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512413/google-employees-walkout-organizers-retaliation-punishment"&gt;retaliated against her and other organizers&lt;/a&gt;. Now, the FTC seems to be in the process of hiring her to help shape regulations around AI and Big Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nqcmYK"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;, Whittaker hasn’t been officially appointed yet, as steps like running a background check aren’t complete. If she is hired, though, she’ll bring a good deal of experience — she worked at Google &lt;a href="https://googlewalkout.medium.com/onward-another-googlewalkout-goodbye-b733fa134a7d"&gt;from 2006 to 2019&lt;/a&gt; and has done work around AI ethics since leaving the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RFaEuu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Whittaker accused Google of only caring about the appearance of ethics debate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xQp8u1"&gt;Besides helping with the walkout, Whittaker also advocated for Google to stop building AI for the military and spoke out against its ethics reviews, saying that it only gave the “appearance of an inclusive debate, rather than seriously contending with the problems in the company.” Upon leaving the company, she said that it was “clear” that it wasn’t a place where she could work toward tech accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wsa4S"&gt;Whittaker has also dealt with difficulties in the public sphere — she worked on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/15/18309437/new-york-city-accountability-task-force-law-algorithm-transparency-automation"&gt;New York City’s algorithm task force&lt;/a&gt;, which was designed to make sure that the city’s automated systems were equitable and had appropriate oversight and transparency. When NYC ended up releasing the report, though, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/20/20974379/nyc-algorithm-task-force-report-de-blasio"&gt;she called the effort “a waste,”&lt;/a&gt; echoing concerns raised by other members that dissenting opinions weren’t taken seriously or included. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XoNm1o"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The FTC has struggled to regulate Big Tech but now appears to be gearing up for a fight&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nKc6uW"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; points out, though, there are signs that the FTC could be a more hospitable place for her ideas if she actually ends up working there. The regulator’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22527709/lina-khan-ftc-commissioner-competition-facebook-amazon-google-apple"&gt;new chair, Lina Khan&lt;/a&gt;, has said she wants to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690176/ftc-chair-lina-khan-focus-antitrust-consumer-amazon"&gt;focus attention on tech giants and antitrust&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557456/amazon-lina-khan-recusal-petition-federal-trade-commission-antitrust"&gt;Amazon has even requested&lt;/a&gt; that she not be involved in cases involving the company because of her past statements about breaking it up. The current administration seems serious about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671880/biden-alvaro-bedoya-privacy-ftc-commissioner-facial-recognition"&gt;nominating experts to work at the agency&lt;/a&gt;, which has struggled to regulate Big Tech in the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d8O3CH"&gt;If the FTC is looking to bring on industry veterans like Whittaker, it could be a further sign that the agency is getting serious about regulating Big Tech. It could help give some say to people who have the technical knowledge and firsthand experience working at companies like Google, Amazon, Apple, or Meta, even if efforts to change things from within were largely ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759776/google-meredith-whittaker-ftc-nomination-ai-ethics-regulation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759776/google-meredith-whittaker-ftc-nomination-ai-ethics-regulation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
