<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-16T11:00:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T11:00:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T11:00:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Music pays a penny per stream</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A woman wearing headphones and a mask" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jEMkE3lC6O1SgypxlhXCPIbr9h4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69137161/IMG_0626-1.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FkhXC5"&gt;Apple Music’s payment rate for artists and labels is fundamentally a penny per stream, according to a letter from the company posted on its artist dashboard and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-music-reveals-how-much-it-pays-when-you-stream-a-song-11618579800?mod=pls_whats_news_us_business_f"&gt;first reported by the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. That payment rate is higher than Spotify, which has a confusing variable rate scheme that basically tops out at a half-penny per stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j3MQls"&gt;Announcing a penny-per-stream rate is a nice PR win for Apple Music, since it is 1. very simple and 2. Spotify hates talking about its per-stream payments, which the company insists are a misleading figure. Seriously, it just &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22336087/spotify-loud-clear-website-launch-pay-artists-streaming-royalities"&gt;launched an entire website&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href="https://loudandclear.byspotify.com/?question=spotify-pay-per-stream"&gt;Loud&amp;amp;Clear&lt;/a&gt; last month designed to help artists and fans understand how payments work, and a good chunk of it is devoted to explaining why per-stream rates are not the right thing to focus on. It’s a lot of copy like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="L4ZrlX"&gt;In the streaming era, fans do not pay per song and services do not pay per stream, so we don’t believe a “per stream rate” is a meaningful number to analyze. Still, we understand that artists find it useful to calculate an effective “per stream” rate or, in other words, a revenue-to-streams ratio — dividing the total size of the royalty pool on Spotify (&lt;strong&gt;the numerator&lt;/strong&gt;) by the total number of music streams on Spotify (&lt;strong&gt;the denominator&lt;/strong&gt;). Both of these numbers are growing incredibly quickly every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BFeifM"&gt;There are a number of factors that contribute to that ratio looking small, which we understand can &lt;em&gt;seem&lt;/em&gt; problematic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OoYiht"&gt;Right. It is important to note that Spotify runs a massive ad-supported music service with very different economics to the paid Spotify Premium tier, while Apple Music only offers a paid service. And Spotify is way bigger, with 345 million total users, of which 155 million are paying Spotify Premium customers. (It’s hard to put good numbers on how big Apple Music is currently; the company’s last public number is “more than 60 million subscribers” from June 2019, and &lt;a href="https://www.businessofapps.com/data/apple-music-statistics/"&gt;more recent estimates&lt;/a&gt; have it at 72 million.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRATzf"&gt;In any event, Spotify’s argument is that it pays lower variable rates on far more streams, while Apple’s happy to say that it pays a higher, simpler rate on fewer streams. Neither argument really solves the essential economic problem of streaming, which is that most artists can’t make a living on streaming royalties alone, which is why everyone is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22375289/the-week-in-nfts-ranked"&gt;out there selling NFTs&lt;/a&gt; and hoping the concert business comes back in force soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CQAVSU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lX9wT4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387453/apple-music-artist-payment-rate-per-stream-vs-spotify"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387453/apple-music-artist-payment-rate-per-stream-vs-spotify</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T10:36:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T10:36:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Peloton clarifies the Apple Watch GymKit mess</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pelton Bike Plus in an apartment" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zjAdzAkjfcIwKZeco-myaiedaDE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69136950/akrales210108_4344_0020.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5LoneU"&gt;Okay. Peloton sells a very famous stationary bicycle with streaming workouts, an app, and a whole fitness lifestyle situation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g44yeN"&gt;Apple sells a very famous smartwatch with heart rate tracking, apps, and the ability to sync with fitness equipment over a proprietary Apple system called GymKit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="znuAWI"&gt;The basic Peloton bike costs $1,895 and does not work with GymKit; the fancier Bike Plus, which works with GymKit, costs $2,495. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yqXoLI"&gt;A lot of people bought the more expensive bike to use it with their Apple Watches over GymKit! And yesterday all those people were dismayed to learn that Peloton had disabled Apple Watch integration for “bike bootcamp” classes, which combine cycling with strength training. (The integration still works just fine with regular old cycling, but you understand, again, that Peloton is an entire fitness lifestyle situation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SLF7Dz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Peloton Bike Plus’ GymKit support no longer works with Bike Bootcamp classes ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385515/peloton-bike-plus-gymkit-apple-watch-bootcamp-support"},{"title":"Apple Fitness Plus adds new workouts designed specifically for pregnant, beginner, and older users ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/platform/amp/2021/4/15/22385653/apple-fitness-plus-new-workouts-pregnant-beginner-older-users-jane-fonda"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="4010wh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385515/peloton-bike-plus-gymkit-apple-watch-bootcamp-support"&gt;Peloton’s statement yesterday&lt;/a&gt; firmly pinned the blame for this on Apple, with a spokesperson telling &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that “Peloton is committed to bringing the GymKit integration to all workouts and disciplines &lt;strong&gt;within Apple’s terms of service&lt;/strong&gt;.” (emphasis ours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iM9b43"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple’s GymKit terms have a clause limiting them to specific use cases&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7uqkKp"&gt;This predictably led to a lot of confusion. Since Apple’s terms of service for GymKit are not public, it was not clear what terms Peloton had violated, and, in general, “using your expensive smartwatch to sync your heart rate to your expensive stationary bike” is not the sort of thing that should require contract negotiations between huge companies. And obviously Apple runs Apple Fitness Plus, which is a direct competitor to Peloton, and does not suffer from any corporate politics-based heart rate tracking issues. (And, of course, Peloton just &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-22/peloton-buys-wearables-ai-hardware-companies-in-deal-flurry"&gt;bought Atlas&lt;/a&gt;, which is... a smartwatch company.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EPtTzw"&gt;Anyhow, irritating the huge group of wealthy people who own both an Apple Watch and a Peloton Bike Plus is &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pelotoncycle/comments/mrhhan/the_peloton_bike_plus_gymkit_support_no_longer/"&gt;a bad idea&lt;/a&gt;, so Peloton has a new statement today clarifying what’s going on. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="mxD9SM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple GymKit is designed to work with equipment-based cardio workouts. However, Peloton recently implemented GymKit with Bike Bootcamp, a multi-disciplinary class type that combines strength and cardio, which the feature does not support. Members can still use GymKit to sync their cycling-only workouts to their Apple Watch from the Bike+.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="C3ZZUB"&gt;So basically, the Apple Watch does not support switching from biking to lifting weights all in one workout. Fair enough. That said, if people want to use their Apple Watch in goofy off-label ways, it’s weird that Apple is stopping them in this way, no? And certainly adding a “bike bootcamp” workout mode to the Apple Watch fitness app would be relatively easy for Apple, the company that makes the Apple Watch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XFB44x"&gt;In conclusion, Apple retains iron-fisted control over its devices and the things that connect to them through its secret accessory contracts, and if anyone would like to send me those contracts, our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/a/tip-us-secure-contact-email"&gt;Securedrop is working again&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387412/peloton-apple-watch-integration-gymkit-statement-terms-of-service"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387412/peloton-apple-watch-integration-gymkit-statement-terms-of-service</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T10:19:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T10:19:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Project Veritas founder wants to sue Twitter for defamation over recent suspension</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="American Conservative Union Holds Annual Conference In Florida" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8j29m1O4oGT13neoHkFYljYODpU=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69136837/1304268713.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A maskless O’Keefe at CPAC in February 2021. | Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="v9mvIN"&gt;James O’Keefe, a conservative activist and founder of Project Veritas, should be able to take a break from Twitter after the company suspended his account for allegedly making fake Twitter accounts. O’Keefe has denied the claim and says he plans to sue Twitter over the suspension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="31ce9U"&gt;Twitter &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/james-okeefe-professional-person-impersonator-firmly-1846695009"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that O’Keefe was suspended for “misleading others” by “operating fake accounts.” &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/15/business/twitter-james-okeefe.html"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Twitter claims O’Keefe was operating multiple sockpuppet accounts to “artificially amplify or disrupt conversations.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QBKdLn"&gt;O’Keefe and his staff at Project Veritas have a long history of pretending to be someone else and failing to identify themselves as the journalists they claim to be. O’Keefe first came to notoriety &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/03/02/nyregion/02acorn.html"&gt;after dressing up like a pimp&lt;/a&gt; to secretly record ACORN staff in a series of videos. Then there was the time he and three others dressed as telephone workers and attempted to sneak into a federal building in Louisiana. &lt;a href="https://www.nola.com/news/crime_police/article_99fb784b-b4b1-5571-935b-c325c57d3f6a.html"&gt;They were arrested and pled guilty&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfDcew"&gt;O’Keefe’s latest attempt at journalism was to have a Project Veritas staff member create a fake account on Tinder. &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/04/14/cnn-staffer-tells-project-veritas-network-played-up-covid-19-death-toll-for-ratings/"&gt;As reported&lt;/a&gt; by the &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt;, the staff member pretended to be a nurse on Tinder and went on five dates with Charlie Chester, a technical director at CNN. The Project Veritas staff secretly recorded Chester as he claimed CNN produces “propaganda”. With rare exception, it's considered unethical to fail to identify yourself as a journalist when speaking with others and intending to report on what they say and do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NHKhER"&gt;Twitter isn’t a fan of people using its platform to impersonate others, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LGW10R"&gt;On Telegram, O’Keefe vehemently denied Twitter’s claim and announced his intention to file suit against Twitter for defamation on Monday, April 19. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pnjaban/status/1382903225007837184?s=20"&gt;He reiterated his intention&lt;/a&gt; when he appeared on Sean Hannity’s show alongside attorney Harmeet Dhillon, a former vice chairwoman for the California Republican Party. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FWWlUA"&gt;O’Keefe claims to be battling an oligarchy working to subvert the truth, but he’s also failed to address the profound ethical violations that he and his staff repeatedly perform. While O’Keefe says Twitter defamed him when it alleged he made sockpuppet accounts, he appears to have zero concern over his own staff making fake Tinder accounts to woo the soundboard guy at CNN. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387275/project-veritas-james-okeefe-defamation-lawsuit-twitter-suspension"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387275/project-veritas-james-okeefe-defamation-lawsuit-twitter-suspension</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T09:49:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T09:49:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Five little Google Sheets tricks I taught my dad</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/42XNv0crPO2ARaGX0IQxwJTAESw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69136629/vpavic_181102_3068_0053.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MIbUPS"&gt;I was recently working remotely next to my dad, and realized just how many time-saving little Google Sheets shortcuts I take for granted. These aren’t advanced formulas or pivot tables; just simple tricks to save you time if you work with basic organizational spreadsheets. Some of these are old Excel tricks; but some even my &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleagues only discovered recently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="srxFAx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easily rearrange rows and columns by dragging from the row number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuZ45G"&gt;If you want to reorder a row, you can do it in one step by first clicking on the row number to highlight the row, then clicking and dragging &lt;em&gt;from the row number&lt;/em&gt; to easily slot it wherever you want it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Reorder rows in Google Sheets by dragging from the row number" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JQrbOZ1OlS_R3TgObjvtJuJsTbA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22448443/Easily_reorder_rows_in_Google_Sheets.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Reorder rows in Google Sheets by dragging from the row number&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XPRwKs"&gt;Before learning this trick from my partner, who (full disclosure) was a one-time Google Docs product manager, I am embarrassed to admit that I wasted a lot of time reordering things by first inserting a blank row, then dragging the content to that new space, and finally deleting its old row. Don’t do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YCvOEc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start a new Google Sheet by typing “&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://sheets.new"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sheets.new&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;” into your browser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBiRqB"&gt;Google owns the top-level domain “.new,” so this also works for &lt;a href="https://docs.new"&gt;docs.new&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://sheets.new"&gt;slides.new&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://cal.new"&gt;cal.new&lt;/a&gt;, etc. They &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20932848/google-new-shortcuts-domain-register-websites-spotify"&gt;started letting other websites use the domain&lt;/a&gt; in 2019; so Spotify has &lt;a href="https://playlist.new"&gt;playlist.new&lt;/a&gt;, Medium has &lt;a href="https://story.new"&gt;story.new&lt;/a&gt;, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7zrIj9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quickly resize columns to fit the content by double clicking between the column headers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xr25Dy"&gt;This is as easy as it sounds — if you want your column width to automatically resize to the shortest or longest entry, just double click in between the column headers. This also works in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Resize columns in Google Sheets by double clicking between the column headers" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MnzwUExB2x1fCoekB-P3MowcBgU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22448453/Automatically_resize_columns_in_Google_Sheets.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Resize columns in Google Sheets by double clicking between the column headers&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AeKbn6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paste something with clear formatting with Command + Shift + v on Mac or Ctrl + Shift + v on PC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cNFFfQ"&gt;I pull data about &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; from a lot of different sources, which all have their own fonts and styling, so this trick comes in handy. By using &lt;strong&gt;Command + Shift + v &lt;/strong&gt;instead of&lt;strong&gt; Command + v &lt;/strong&gt;on Mac or&lt;strong&gt; Ctrl + Shift + v &lt;/strong&gt;instead of&lt;strong&gt; Ctrl + v&lt;/strong&gt; on PC, you can strip the old font and font sizes as you paste and insert clear text. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j_2LFwYqCkCn4e9LNh_-pdjsbgg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22448455/Paste_with_clear_formatting_in_Google_Sheets.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Paste with clear formatting in Google Sheets using Command + Shift + v&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pJgq4q"&gt;You can also paste plain values by double clicking into a cell before you paste, but that’s a little more cumbersome. To clear formatting from multiple cells at once, first highlight them and then use &lt;strong&gt;Command + \ &lt;/strong&gt;on Mac&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;or&lt;strong&gt; Ctrl + \ &lt;/strong&gt;on PC. There are a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; more keyboard shortcuts like this, which Google catalogs &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/docs/answer/181110?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="awo4Ln"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add multiple hyperlinks to one cell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V68djw"&gt;This one’s more of a PSA — for a long time, you could only hyperlink entire cells. My colleague Jay Peters &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21431536/google-sheets-hyperlink-individual-many-multiple-words-cell"&gt;recently discovered&lt;/a&gt; that this is no longer the case; you can now add as many links as your heart desires. Just click into the cell and highlight the word or phrase you want to hyperlink before adding your links.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Hyperlink multiple words in on Google Sheets cell" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a9VftOTbScENXLDA5Gu2DZGfJHk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22448465/Add_multiple_hyperlinks_to_one_cell_in_Google_Sheets.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Hyperlink multiple words in on Google Sheets cell&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="55QDxB"&gt;If you have other favorite Google Sheet tricks you want to share, leave a comment! And because I used my parents and sibling’s cats for my sample data set, here is my cat Olivia striking one of her signature poses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photo of cat striking very elegant pose with crossed paws" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w6_rwVKuVBKUKwXK7l5IJFBTrEY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22448487/Olivia_the_queen_of_cats.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo of my cat Olivia taken with a Pixel 4&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="J7tikc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22387316/google-sheets-tips-tricks-reorder-rows-resize-columns-links"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22387316/google-sheets-tips-tricks-reorder-rows-resize-columns-links</id>
    <author>
      <name>Helen Havlak</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T09:36:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T09:36:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>This week’s best tech deals this week include AirPods Pro, Echo Show 10, and a gaming monitor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8XOFbiUVzpSnlWVnu1dZbXdBAXs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69135936/dseifert_210219_4433_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0NI61y"&gt;Some weeks aren’t so great on the tech deals front. Thankfully, this hasn’t been one of those weeks. Each day, our deals roundups have been full of fresh discounts, like the best-ever price on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08M1N8522?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon’s new Echo Show 10&lt;/a&gt; smart display that can rotate to follow your movements around the room or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1621994-REG%2Flg_27gn800_b_27_qhd_ips_hdr10.html%23donotlink&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F4%2F16%2F22385758%2Famazon-echo-show-10-lg-27-inch-qhd-gaming-monitor-airpods-pro-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$100 off a 27-inch 1440p gaming monitor&lt;/a&gt; from LG. There are a few other deals to look through below, and they’re all good, so I won’t waste much more of your time. But in case you’re looking for a Mother’s Day gift, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22358371/mothers-day-gifts-ideas-best-mom-tech-gadgets"&gt;our gift guide&lt;/a&gt; (which is gorgeous, might I say) is full of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Dn5i0D"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3RCyyd"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; are $197&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QAn0mg"&gt;Apple’s top-shelf wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, are down to $197 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22149799%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https://www.walmart.com/ip/Apple-AirPods-Pro/520468661?irgwc=1&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_XyS0KeUAPxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkEVs713WQ-N3A0&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;wmlspartner=imp_482924&amp;amp;clickid=XyS0KeUAPxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkEVs713WQ-N3A0&amp;amp;sharedid=verge&amp;amp;affiliates_ad_id=565706&amp;amp;campaign_id=9383&amp;amp;irgwc=1&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_wq02e5wo0xyOWPQwUx0Mo38XUkEXYrwPlxjyx00&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;wmlspartner=imp_482924&amp;amp;clickid=wq02e5wo0xyOWPQwUx0Mo38XUkEXYrwPlxjyx00&amp;amp;sharedid=verge&amp;amp;affiliates_ad_id=565706&amp;amp;campaign_id=9383&amp;amp;sharedid=verge&amp;amp;subId2=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22149799%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, over $50 less than the MSRP and about $20 less than typical pricing. Apple is expected to refresh its non-Pro AirPods very soon, but if you’re looking for noise canceling, you’ll want to go with the Pro model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gvr4jS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="MaHW9K"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="18zrrK"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21400695/google-pixel-buds-2-2020-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"&gt;Google Pixel Buds&lt;/a&gt; are $50 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qXS8kG"&gt;If Google’s Pixel Buds are more your speed, they are available for $129 from several retailers, down from the usual price of $179. Any discount on the Pixel Buds is rare — this is one of the biggest we’ve ever seen. The Pixel Buds don’t have active noise cancelation, but they do offer hands-free Google Assistant access and easy pairing with an Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YGCM8B"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502839"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="yDZsb1"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="AC3jNK"&gt;LG’s 27-inch 1440p gaming monitor is a great value for $297&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LNyXqe"&gt;Normally around $400, LG’s UltraGear 27-inch gaming monitor that has 1440p resolution, G-Sync compatibility, and a 144Hz refresh rate is just over $100 off its usual price at Amazon and B&amp;amp;H Photo. If you have a gaming PC or console and want to step up to QHD, this monitor should be a good fit for you — and it costs far less than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kkT74u"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10429642"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="7tU1nD"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jes7o0"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22297810/amazon-echo-show-10-2021-review"&gt;Amazon’s latest Echo Show 10&lt;/a&gt; smart display is $50 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="DJVgFW"&gt;You can get the best-ever price on Amazon’s new Echo Show 10. What’s special about this one compared to previous generations is its motorized base, which allows its screen to rotate and follow your movements to stay in view. If you buy it through Amazon, you can get a free Ring smart bulb with the purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9QLwoh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10362085"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="CYGdaE"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OUKo5D"&gt;Check out The Verge’s Mother’s Day gift guide!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="k3SSGf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10443858"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/16/22385758/amazon-echo-show-10-lg-27-inch-qhd-gaming-monitor-airpods-pro-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/16/22385758/amazon-echo-show-10-lg-27-inch-qhd-gaming-monitor-airpods-pro-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T09:12:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T09:12:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: thoughts on Apple’s spring event, the Sonos Roam, and LG quitting smartphones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f0hQATa_kELpB17WYEWhmiEl8WQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69136315/RoamPint.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VFEXkz"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories. This week, Verge editor&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Chris Welch joins Nilay and Dieter in a phone and gadget-dominated episode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E2bxYT"&gt;The discussion starts with news of Apple announcing a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22310826/apple-april-20th-event-date-rumors-ipad-pro-macbook-tv-airtags"&gt;spring event coming up on April 20th&lt;/a&gt;. The crew reviews which products may or may not be announced next week — from an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379470/apple-tv-homepod-speaker-camera-video-call-soundbar-rumor-bloomberg"&gt;Apple TV with a camera&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379337/new-ipad-pro-mini-led-production-issues-date-report"&gt;new iPads&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375738/apple-podcast-the-line-us-navy-spotify-original-shows"&gt;more services&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bG1DY5"&gt;The gadget talk continues with a farewell to both LG phones and Logitech Harmony remotes. Last week, LG announced it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22346084/lg-exits-smartphone-business"&gt;exiting the smartphone business&lt;/a&gt;. A few days later, Logitech announced it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377015/logitech-discontinues-harmony-universal-remotes"&gt;discontinuing its line of universal remotes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bVyUuR"&gt;There’s a whole lot more in this episode — including a review of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22368487/sonos-roam-bluetooth-speaker-review-features"&gt;Sonos’ Roam portable speaker&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382715/us-carriers-ccmi-rcs-abandoned-sms-messages-texts"&gt;future of RCS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22380014/spotify-car-thing-release-voice-control-data-interactive-ads"&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22381820/amazon-echo-buds-2-features-price-release-date"&gt;gadgets&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381109/roku-express-4k-plus-voice-remote-streambar-pro-announced"&gt;pay&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370130/ikea-sonos-symfonisk-2021-lamp-wall-art-artwork-speaker"&gt;attention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22382887/sony-announces-xperia-1-iii-xperia-5-iii"&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; — so listen here or in your preferred podcast player to hear the full discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JhH1AV"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/6MH1Sq1wxOgSeVP4mAWi2K" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j85Lz2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fHEXnS"&gt;Stories discussed in this episode: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MMBaJF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381469/covid-vaccine-pause-blood-clots-johnson-fda-cdc"&gt;US recommends pause on Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine use over extremely rare blood clots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8Xn7hG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381875/covid-vaccine-johnson-pause-fda-cdc-coronavirus"&gt;How the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson pause could move the needle on vaccine fears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Wa2YFj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377030/side-effects-covid-19-vaccine-antivirus-newsletter"&gt;For many, COVID-19 vaccines come with a side of side effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oNJFed"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22382361/covid-carbon-dioxide-co2-ventilation-sensor-bars-restaurant"&gt;How CO2 sensors might help us return to ‘normal’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wVT5Lw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379885/airbnb-summer-responsible-travel-community-support-fno-parties-pandemic"&gt;Airbnb is trying to preemptively cancel post-pandemic bacchanals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DBn662"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22375608/covid-vaccination-pandemic-etsy"&gt;Celebrate your COVID vaccination with these off-the-wall tchotchkes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BMr1zY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373546/expedia-travel-restriction-tool-destination"&gt;Expedia launches a new tool to check coronavirus travel restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JsrhEl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22310826/apple-april-20th-event-date-rumors-ipad-pro-macbook-tv-airtags"&gt;Apple officially announces Spring Loaded event for April 20th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qe4X9S"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379337/new-ipad-pro-mini-led-production-issues-date-report"&gt;New iPad Pro still coming soon but supply could be short, says Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AFedFF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372016/apple-find-my-bluetooth-tracking-iphone-network-third-party-vanmoof-belkin-chipolo-uwb"&gt;Apple officially starts letting your iPhone help find lost third-party products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kk2f8B"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373410/samsung-galaxy-smarttag-plus-uwb-ar-bluetooth-price-release-date"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy SmartTag Plus with UWB to track items with AR is out April 16th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vqmrGI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377015/logitech-discontinues-harmony-universal-remotes"&gt;Logitech officially discontinues its Harmony remotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Aqie1t"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381067/apple-tv-plus-roku-remote-button-announced"&gt;Apple gets its own button on Roku’s latest remotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8sjX9r"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381109/roku-express-4k-plus-voice-remote-streambar-pro-announced"&gt;Roku announces Express 4K Plus streaming player and rechargeable Voice Remote Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z0XVNr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381535/roku-os-10-instant-resume-airplay-2-auto-gaming-setup"&gt;Roku OS 10 adds instant resume for streaming apps, brings AirPlay 2 to more devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z3JgaY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379470/apple-tv-homepod-speaker-camera-video-call-soundbar-rumor-bloomberg"&gt;Apple reportedly developing an Apple TV with a built-in camera and speaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qUjRN8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22346084/lg-exits-smartphone-business"&gt;LG is quitting the smartphone business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f2HG1E"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22367903/lg-smartphone-retrospective-hits-misses"&gt;LG had a few smartphone hits, but it’ll still be missed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8j92Qv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375938/lg-smartphone-business-exit-tcl-motorola"&gt;LG leaves behind more than a flip phone-shaped hole in our hearts &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WBS4E0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375780/google-announces-pixel-5a-5g-denying-rumors-cancelled"&gt;Google announces Pixel 5A 5G by denying rumors it’s canceled&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7rXtWn"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22382312/tcl-20-series-pro-5g-20l-plus-price-specs-features"&gt;TCL aims to build a better budget phone with the 20 Pro 5G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hBMTjs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383668/tcl-fold-n-roll-concept-rollable-phone-tablet"&gt;TCL’s Fold ‘n Roll concept transforms a 6.87-inch phone into a 10-inch tablet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c6ZzV8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22382887/sony-announces-xperia-1-iii-xperia-5-iii"&gt;Sony announces the Xperia 1 III and Xperia 5 III with variable telephoto lenses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="W6IlzO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382715/us-carriers-ccmi-rcs-abandoned-sms-messages-texts"&gt;US carriers have thankfully abandoned at least one bad plan for RCS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="14UD9j"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375128/apple-imessage-android-ecosystem-lock-in-epic-games-filings-app-store-dispute"&gt;Apple says iMessage on Android ‘will hurt us more than help us’&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="I4gwuY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22368487/sonos-roam-bluetooth-speaker-review-features"&gt;Sonos Roam review: portable potential &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="T7D1Hv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370130/ikea-sonos-symfonisk-2021-lamp-wall-art-artwork-speaker"&gt;Ikea is working with Sonos on a hidden speaker built into art you hang on the wall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HEmTzc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22380014/spotify-car-thing-release-voice-control-data-interactive-ads"&gt;Spotify’s Car Thing debuts as a limited release for selected US users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kxm20j"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22381820/amazon-echo-buds-2-features-price-release-date"&gt;Amazon announces new Echo Buds with more powerful ANC and better comfort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TVDfRs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22380322/oneplus-watch-review-price-specs-features"&gt;ONEPLUS WATCH REVIEW: BIG, BASIC, AND BORING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eDRHD9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22381390/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-features-price-specs-release-date"&gt;Microsoft announces Surface Laptop 4 with choice of Intel or AMD processor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6YqKIC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22380290/clubhouse-social-audio-twitter-facebook-platforms"&gt;Can Clubhouse keep the party going? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L1qiyD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22368541/apple-trade-in-phobio-macbook-white-spots"&gt;Apple trusts Phobio for its trade-ins, but maybe you should think twice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="U3bbdu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22370158/google-ai-ethics-timnit-gebru-margaret-mitchell-firing-reputation"&gt;Google is poisoning its reputation with AI researchers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="gVjdTL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387256/vergecast-podcast-448-apple-spring-loaded-event-preview-farewell-lg-phones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387256/vergecast-podcast-448-apple-spring-loaded-event-preview-farewell-lg-phones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T09:05:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T09:05:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Project CHIP will finally ship later this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Px2RW_KnVCBsWNH3ZKs802qxeM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69136257/dseifert_191123_3810_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Amazon’s Echo Show 8 smart display | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="x162Ri"&gt;Project Connected Home over IP (CHIP), the awkwardly-named-but-interesting smart home partnership between Apple, Amazon, Google, and over 170 other companies that’s supposed to make everything more compatible should finally start showing some results later this year. According to &lt;a href="https://zigbeealliance.org/news_and_articles/future-of-iot-is-now/"&gt;a webinar hosted by the Zigbee Alliance earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, companies participating in the program will be able to get smart home devices certified for the standard by late 2021, which means we might see some things on shelves for the holiday shopping season. That first wave of devices will include things like lighting, blinds, HVAC controls, TVs, door locks, garage door openers, security systems, and Wi-Fi routers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GCuST9"&gt;The CHIP standard is built around three technologies: Bluetooth LE for setup, WiFi for high-bandwidth use cases, like streaming video from a security camera, and the still-nascent Thread mesh network protocol for low-bandwidth devices such as motion sensors. (Thread has been a work in progress for a while, but it’s now on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review"&gt;Apple HomePod Mini&lt;/a&gt;, the newest &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22357214/google-nest-hub-2nd-gen-2021-assistant-smart-display-review"&gt;Google Nest Hub&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22193059/eero-pro-6-review-mesh-router-wifi-6-test-speeds-network"&gt;Eero routers&lt;/a&gt;, so maybe it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22310378/eve-smart-home-thread-plug-home-kit-weather-station-price-specs-features"&gt;finally going to happen&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FN5qtk"&gt;Manufacturers will be able to bring CHIP support to older products through bridges, as well, so there’s a chance that devices you already own might work with CHIP products in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ObgNCA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The first CHIP certified devices could be available by the holidays&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jU3Q7m"&gt;The program, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/18/21027890/apple-google-amazon-smart-home-standard-zigbee-connected-ip-project"&gt;first announced back at the end of 2019&lt;/a&gt;, has had some delays due to the pandemic. It was originally supposed to have products within the CHIP standard by the end of 2020, but then the group &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21427139/amazon-apple-google-zigbee-alliance-open-source-smart-home-standard-2021-launch"&gt;announced last September&lt;/a&gt; that we wouldn’t see anything until sometime in 2021. That time apparently is the &lt;em&gt;end&lt;/em&gt; of 2021, so it’s very possible this launch could slip even further into 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KeWmSm"&gt;The goal of CHIP is to offer a unified standard for smart home products so that customers don’t have to worry if a device they buy will work with the other devices they already own. Its technologies replace older smart home protocols such as Zigbee and Z-Wave and are designed to work with whatever voice assistant you prefer. Of course, a new standard &lt;a href="https://xkcd.com/927/"&gt;isn’t a guarantee to solve any confusion&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s very possible that the CHIP program will just add yet another option to the list of standards already out there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IJQ37K"&gt;Stacey Higgenbotham at &lt;em&gt;Stacey On IOT&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://staceyoniot.com/project-chip-embraces-a-timeline-and-the-blockchain/"&gt;has a deep dive on all the announcements&lt;/a&gt; made by the Zigbee Alliance this week, including how it plans to improve smart home security through... the blockchain, so I suggest reading her analysis for more on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387252/project-chip-will-finally-ship-later-this-year"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387252/project-chip-will-finally-ship-later-this-year</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What to expect from Apple’s ‘Spring Loaded’ event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gI7IK3nwguOVMw1RNdWJEfYaVTk=/0x0:1770x1180/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69136145/appleinvite.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qIR5T4"&gt;Apple has officially announced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22310826/apple-april-20th-event-date-rumors-ipad-pro-macbook-tv-airtags"&gt;“Spring Loaded” event&lt;/a&gt; for April 20th, its first major product announcement of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fs5b1a"&gt;Unlike a lot of Apple’s events, its spring events tend to be a bit more scattershot: one year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"&gt;might see high-end iPads&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/27/17155688/apple-event-2018-news-highlights-recap-ipad-education"&gt;another a more education-focused event&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/25/18277461/apple-event-2019-tv-plus-arcade-credit-card-streaming-news-oprah-recap-biggest-announcements"&gt;launch of a comprehensive service strategy&lt;/a&gt;. This year, rumors are pointing to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336917/apple-new-ipad-pros-mini-base-april"&gt;refreshed iPad Pro lineup&lt;/a&gt;, potentially with Apple’s first Mini LED panels — which would bring a big jump forward for the company’s tablet displays. But we could also see new AirPods, the company’s long-rumored AirTag trackers, a new iPad Mini, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6r3aba"&gt;The proceeding should kick off at 1PM ET on Tuesday, but if you’re looking for an early preview, here’s what you can probably expect to show up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HOEop9"&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JxMxJQ"&gt;It’s been over a year since Apple’s last refresh of the iPad Pro, and the 2020 model — a fairly iterative update to the 2019 version — is starting to get a little long in the tooth, especially compared to the beefed-up specs on Apple’s latest iPhones and M1 Macs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hGQQFx"&gt;Like last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336917/apple-new-ipad-pros-mini-base-april"&gt;Apple is expected&lt;/a&gt; to launch both 11-inch and 12.9-inch iPad Pro models; but the larger iPad Pro is expected to make a big switch in screen technology to debut Apple’s first Mini LED display. Additional rumors indicate that supply of the Mini LED panels might be hard to come by, that stock of the larger model may be limited at launch, or that Apple might delay the release of the 12.9-inch version until availability is better.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VweWqmZJChciB58wVMWio9GaXnA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19827375/bking_200321_3945_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Brennan King / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zBZGKi"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-17/apple-nears-launch-of-new-ipads-after-stay-at-home-sales-boost"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sheds more light on what to expect, too: while the overall design of the two tablets is expected to stay largely the same as last year’s model, Apple is expected to swap out the A12Z chip for a newer processor that’s said to be on par with its more recent M1 chipset. The new iPads are also said to upgrade to a Thunderbolt port (with faster data speeds and a wider peripheral selection than the standard USB-C port) and feature upgraded cameras. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lT9yk6"&gt;Apple could also potentially have a new Apple Pencil accessory in the works to go with the new iPad Pros. &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/03/03/new-apple-pencil-design-rumor-image/"&gt;Images of a new, glossy version&lt;/a&gt; of the stylus have been circulating on Twitter, and the “spring forward” teaser could imply that Apple might offer a spring-loaded tip, similar to what &lt;a href="https://estore.wacom.com/en-US/stroke-pen-nibs-5-pack-for-intuos-4-5-us-ack20002.html"&gt;Wacom offers on its pens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="b9AGzS"&gt;AirTags&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OuBNThklNinnRQHDa5mQsEMF1OQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16318924/apple_tag.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/06/04/ios-13-tag-device/" target="_blank"&gt;Guilherme Rambo / 9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="w4SDSr"&gt;One of Apple’s worst-kept secrets in years, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/2/21205994/apple-airtags-name-confirmed-tile-tracker-rumor-leak"&gt;Apple’s Tile-like AirTags&lt;/a&gt; have been rumored to make an appearance at nearly every Apple event and announcement since early 2019. Said to be small, circular tags with Bluetooth and ultra-wideband radio chips, AirTags would rely on Apple’s existing Find My app and network of iPhones, iPads, and Macs to allow users to track and find missing objects (similar to how users can currently track lost phones). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mPwHRX"&gt;AirTags would also potentially work with recent iPhone models’ U1 chip to allow for AR-based ultra-wideband tracking in local areas — something that Samsung has recently also began to offer with its Galaxy SmartTag Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GPigxw"&gt;There have been references to AirTags (or Apple Tags) in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/30/20841204/ios13-code-apple-tile-location-tracking-tag-find-my-app"&gt;iOS code leaks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/18/21142249/apple-tags-iphone-kuo-location-tracking"&gt;endless rumors&lt;/a&gt;, and even in an official support video that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/2/21205994/apple-airtags-name-confirmed-tile-tracker-rumor-leak"&gt;explicitly revealed the “AirTags” name&lt;/a&gt; as part of its offline finding feature last year. The only thing left is for Apple to officially announce them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Lz4zxj"&gt;iPad Mini&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hi8fI0"&gt;Also long overdue for an update is Apple’s oft-neglected iPad Mini, which was last refreshed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"&gt;over two years ago in March 2019&lt;/a&gt;. (Given that &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; update came after a four-year drought for the iPad Mini, a refresh this year would actually be beating par.) The current model features the exact outdated design that Apple’s been using for nearly a decade, with an older A12 processor to boot, so there’s plenty of room for Apple to improve things, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dQqFtD"&gt;Adding fuel to the fire is that both &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; and noted Apple analyst Ming-Chi Kuo have pointed at a larger iPad Mini (potentially with an 8.5-inch display, which could come from eliminating some of the chunky 2012-era bezels) for 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hXZT6d"&gt;AirPods 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="wAOlyD"&gt;A third-generation version of Apple’s AirPods has been rumored for months, set to feature shorter stems and replaceable ear tips, similar to the current AirPods Pro design. The updated AirPods are also said to feature better battery life than their predecessors. Apple has also been rumored to be working on a refreshed AirPods Pro design that would eliminate the earbud stem entirely, but as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/26/21534123/apple-airpods-3-pro-2-2021-chip-design-battery-life-true-wireless-earbuds-headphones-homepod"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg’&lt;/em&gt;s report&lt;/a&gt; notes, that redesign is further out — so they’re unlikely to make an appearance here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ADfaBj"&gt;Apple TV&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Avj54i8-cca5EZipGaQwJuZUvxQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9289303/akrales_170919_1976_0104.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cnc8SQ"&gt;The Apple TV 4K sits at a strange place in Apple’s lineup. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/21/16341876/new-apple-tv-4k-review-2017"&gt;Released in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, it’s one of the oldest Apple products still being sold. At $180, its price has since been lapped by Roku, Amazon, and Google, all of which offer comparable 4K streaming boxes at a fraction of the price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Qgrpg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-17/apple-nears-launch-of-new-ipads-after-stay-at-home-sales-boost"&gt;Apple is rumored to be working&lt;/a&gt; on a refreshed model for 2021, which would add a faster processor and a new remote to replace the infamous Siri Remote. Support for HDMI 2.1 and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22369056/apple-tv-2021-120hz-refresh-rate-support-4k-gaming-arcade"&gt;120Hz refresh rates&lt;/a&gt; could also be in the cards. But more than new features, the Apple TV 4K is in dire need of a price cut — something that Apple is historically more reticent to provide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xc2tHL"&gt;iOS 14.5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="qWXCM9"&gt;Given the pace of both developer and public betas, it’s all but certain that Apple will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267230/apple-ios-14-5-watchos-7-4-public-beta-unlock-iphone-apple-watch-mask"&gt;officially release iOS 14.5&lt;/a&gt; either at or immediately following the event (especially if it has new iPad hardware). The new software promises to add the ability to more easily unlock an iPhone while wearing a mask through an Apple Watch, new emoji, and Apple’s highly debated App Tracking Transparency feature that has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178068/facebook-apple-newspaper-ads-ios-privacy-changes"&gt;drawn particular ire from Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HjrMZ1"&gt;MacBooks and iMacs and Mac Pros (oh my!)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="n5xs2A"&gt;After the shockingly great debut of Apple’s first wave of Apple Silicon-powered computers last fall with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;M1 MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, Pro, and Mac Mini, all eyes are on Apple’s next steps in its ARM transition. The company is rumored to be working on plenty of new Macs as it looks to achieve its ambitious goal of switching fully from Intel’s chips within two years. That includes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;more powerful MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt; that would ditch the Touch Bar, bring back MagSafe and additional ports, and feature an improved M-series chip. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233191/apple-silicon-redesigned-imac-mac-pro-rumor-features"&gt;A new iMac and a smaller Mac Pro&lt;/a&gt; (also featuring M-series chips) are said to be in the works as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JT7aTR"&gt;With &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22320961/apple-wwdc-2021-event-date-software-updates-ios-ipados-macos"&gt;WWDC around the corner&lt;/a&gt;, though, it’s likely that we won’t hear more about new Mac hardware until then, especially if Apple is planning on debuting more developer and professional-friendly Apple Silicon-powered laptops and desktops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="XyOxwb"&gt;Something surprising&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="2WK14k"&gt;Of course, with Apple, you never quite know what to expect — which means that there’s always room for a surprise announcement or two at the Spring Loaded event that not even we saw coming. Could Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/11/20959066/apple-augmented-reality-ar-headset-glasses-rumors-reported-release-date"&gt;tease its long-rumored VR headset&lt;/a&gt;? A refreshed iPhone SE? A first look at the Apple Car? Whatever happens, stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;for all the details. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22385362/apple-event-ipad-airpods-pencil-tv-tags-rumors-spring-loaded"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22385362/apple-event-ipad-airpods-pencil-tv-tags-rumors-spring-loaded</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon is finally realizing it has a labor problem</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XqTxX508CfcTJsJfLvIu5fUZDhE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69136127/acastro_210208_4402_amazonVote.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9l6LKx"&gt;Today, let’s talk about the new tone Jeff Bezos is taking when talking about Amazon — and whether we can expect it to have any practical effect on the company after he turns over the CEO job to his successor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22264425/amazon-new-ceo-andy-jassy-replacement-jeff-bezos"&gt;Andy Jassy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B90Zc6"&gt;A recurring theme in this column is Amazon’s general indifference to public perception. Last month, it picked &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/why-amazon-picked-a-fight-with-congress"&gt;a losing fight with Congress&lt;/a&gt; over the unionization efforts at its Bessemer, Alabama fulfillment center. A year ago, &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; revealed that the company had &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-scooped-up-data-from-its-own-sellers-to-launch-competing-products-11587650015"&gt;lied to lawmakers&lt;/a&gt; about whether it used data from third-party sellers to inform product development. A couple years before that, it conducted&lt;a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/caseynewton/issues/amazon-misreads-the-room-144903"&gt; a sham search for a second “headquarters”&lt;/a&gt; that angered politicians around the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H2FUNW"&gt;The company has seen record growth every year since anyways, and it was&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21144680/verge-tech-survey-2020-trust-privacy-security-facebook-amazon-google-apple"&gt; the most-liked of all big tech companies&lt;/a&gt; even before the pandemic made people more depend on it. (Amazon picked up &lt;em&gt;50 million&lt;/em&gt; new Prime subscribers in 2020, an increase of about one-third in just 12 months.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AmczhY"&gt;Given Amazon’s tendency to dismiss most criticism, you might have expected Bezos’ last letter to shareholders to resemble an extended victory lap. Certainly it would be warranted: Amazon is one of the most extraordinary businesses ever built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYtSTI"&gt;But that’s not really Bezos’ style. His religious devotion to “&lt;a href="http://businessinsider.com/jeff-bezos-says-always-day-1-amazon-philosophy-2019-12"&gt;Day 1&lt;/a&gt;” — the idea that businesses ought to remain as paranoid and action-oriented as they were when they first born, lest they be defeated by entropy — precludes that sort of long walk into the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZLM9Wn"&gt;And so perhaps we should not be too surprised that he took labor issues at the company head on. Sure, Bezos has mentioned them before — his &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/2019-letter-to-shareholders"&gt;letter last year&lt;/a&gt; also devoted many paragraphs to Amazon’s support for the $15 minimum wage, re-training workers, and so on — but I’m not sure he has ever confronted critics quite so directly. Bezos writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="0s8sed"&gt;Does your Chair take comfort in the outcome of the recent union vote in Bessemer? No, he doesn’t. I think we need to do a better job for our employees. While the voting results were lopsided and our direct relationship with employees is strong, it’s clear to me that we need a better &lt;em&gt;vision&lt;/em&gt; for how we create value for employees – a vision for their success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QrFQld"&gt;If you read some of the news reports, you might think we have no care for employees. In those reports, our employees are sometimes accused of being desperate souls and treated as robots. That’s not accurate. They’re sophisticated and thoughtful people who have options for where to work. When we survey fulfillment center employees, 94% say they would recommend Amazon to a friend as a place to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="v20WKm"&gt;Bezos knows that there will be more efforts to unionize in Amazon fulfillment centers, and future ones might not be quite so easy to defeat. And so he sets two enormous goals for the Amazon of the future. The company should be “Earth’s Best Employer,” he writes, and “Earth’s Safest Place to Work.” And he plans to work on these projects personally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="d0e6Kt"&gt;In my upcoming role as Executive Chair, I’m going to focus on new initiatives. I’m an inventor. It’s what I enjoy the most and what I do best. It’s where I create the most value. I’m excited to work alongside the large team of passionate people we have in Ops and help invent in this arena of Earth’s Best Employer and Earth’s Safest Place to Work. On the details, we at Amazon are always flexible, but on matters of vision we are stubborn and relentless. We have never failed when we set our minds to something, and we’re not going to fail at this either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="yrAeGg"&gt;Is it just me, or does this sound like a man who has at long last gotten the message?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fuzHtE"&gt;It has taken long enough. Pushback on the company’s claims of being a friend to the working man has come from all corners, from Republican Sen. Marco Rubio to Democrats like President Biden and Sen. Elizabeth Warren. And despite Bezos’ note that 94 percent of employees say they would recommend Amazon as a good place to work, it’s the company’s own workers who keep bringing disturbing information about their job sites to light. (I’m &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; trying to unsee &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/k7amyn/amazon-denies-workers-pee-in-bottles-here-are-the-pee-bottles"&gt;the photos of pee bottles&lt;/a&gt; that workers used in the absence of bathroom breaks that they submitted to &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xPFz8M"&gt;Over the past year, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/fired-interrogated-disciplined-amazon-warehouse-organizers-allege-year-retaliation-n1262367"&gt;workers have filed at least 37 complaints&lt;/a&gt; to the National Labor Relations Board alleging interference with workers’ right to organize, more than triple the total in the previous year. Amazon&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/02/02/amazon-union-warehouse-workers/"&gt; mounted an anti-union campaign&lt;/a&gt; that included, among other things, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/05/technology/amazon-control-bathroom-breaks.html"&gt;firing organizers on flimsy pretexts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f5sptx"&gt;If workers were as happy at Amazon as Bezos says they are, you wonder why all of that was necessary. And maybe — finally — he does, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="54BjuF"&gt;There are technological ways of improving Amazon as a workplace, he says. The company can rotate workers who perform repetitive tasks to lessen the strain on their bodies, for example, using “sophisticated algorithms.” It will spend $66 million “to create technology that will help prevent collisions of forklifts.” It will invent more things like this under Bezos in his new role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0MlSR9"&gt;No tech giant deserves much credit for announcing a simple intention to do better. Amazon’s business requires punishing physical labor, along with ruthlessly seeking new efficiencies that chip away at workers’ dignity. The company is also leading the way in the use of automation technologies that will make those same workers’ jobs ever more precarious. It’s hard to even imagine how such a system could come to be seen as “Earth’s Best Employer,” no matter how good Amazon’s forklift management software someday becomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DQVsAe"&gt;But part of the unusual power that founder-led tech giants have is the way their creators can marshal internal goodwill, along with their limitless finances, to make investments that others won’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TmGKsn"&gt;Bezos’ promise to become “Earth’s Best Employer” is on some level insane, because it immediately becomes a cudgel with which lawmakers, the press, and the public can beat Amazon every time another labor issue is discovered. (I predict “Earth’s Best Employer” will become to Amazon what “don’t be evil” became for Google, or “move fast and break things” became for Facebook: a mission statement that ultimately became more useful to critics than it did to the company itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xB8IF7"&gt;The thing is, though, that Bezos is smart. Like, world-historically smart. He knows that he is setting the bar far above where it sits today, and he knows that he is going to be held accountable to it. Bezos’ version of the world’s best employer likely looks a lot different than mine, but I also imagine that it could lead to higher wages, safer working conditions, and better job training programs, at least for the workers who aren’t replaced by robots. Hopefully it will lead to less union-busting and bottle-peeing as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mXxCib"&gt;In the days after the Cambridge Analytica data privacy scandal, Facebook executives looked as tone deaf as Amazon has lately in response to its labor issues. Eventually, though, they realized their tone had to change — and their business practices had to as well. We can argue about how effective the 30,000 people hired to shore up the platform’s security have been, but it’s undeniable that Facebook transformed its approach to integrity between late 2016 and today. And it all started with a belated acknowledgement that the company had a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6qPJeu"&gt;Maybe the cursed @AmazonNews account will snipe at another member of Congress tomorrow in the coming days, and all of the above will seem moot. Or maybe Amazon has truly internalized that the time has come to shut up and listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4bPtYl"&gt;For now, it sure seems like Jeff Bezos is. And I can’t say I saw that one coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="CRAh8A"&gt;
&lt;p id="q9qLVV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This column was co-published with &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Platformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xlhbbp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22386992/amazon-is-finally-realizing-it-has-a-labor-problem"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22386992/amazon-is-finally-realizing-it-has-a-labor-problem</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-16T08:12:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-16T08:12:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V9cZCU"&gt;Apple AirPods are among the most popular headphones on the market. They’re compact, easy to pair with your devices, and offer reliable connectivity, which can sometimes be a problem with truly wireless earphones. So there’s a chance that you might be looking for a deal on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR97R2"&gt;Surprisingly, they’re no stranger to the occasional price cut. There are often discounts on even the more expensive AirPods Pro, which offers noise cancellation and better sound quality than the standard second-generation model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;We’ll run through all three of the current models below, including the standard AirPods, the more expensive AirPods that include a wireless charging case, and finally, the AirPods Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VFDHZw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="R1mQdI"&gt;These are Apple’s entry-level wireless earbuds. They are a reliable pair of wireless earbuds with a one-size-fits-most design. The AirPods usually retail for $160, which is not a bad price, but this model frequently gets discounted.  You can currently find Apple’s most affordable AirPods for $129 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or for $130 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191097%3Fclkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D1003525%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PK1JRu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods (with wireless charging case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;The AirPods with wireless charging case are identical in every way to the standard AirPods, save for one: their charging case can be charged on a Qi wireless pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYNUWv"&gt;You’ll need to provide your own wireless charging pad to take advantage of this feature (if you have no use for it, just get the more affordable option above), but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2017/10/27/16554680/best-wireless-charger-qi-ravpower-samsung-anker-mophie"&gt;even the best ones are fairly inexpensive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AFyzAp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="glqkTs"&gt;Most of the time you can find this version for less than Apple’s sticker price of $199, but keep a lookout for deals that bring the price down to $160 or below. You can get them for $160 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099%3Fclkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F482532021&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s9Ofwq"&gt;Apple’s high-end truly wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, have better sound quality than the other models described above, include noise cancellation, and now support Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. We think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;they’re the best wireless earbuds that iPhone owners&lt;/a&gt; can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bM8uVd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yaMGwU"&gt;The AirPods Pro are frequently available for less than their $249 retail price, and in fact, sometimes drop down to $200 and lower. The lowest you can grab a pair right now is for $197 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_XyS0KeUAPxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkEVs713WQ-N3A0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3DXyS0KeUAPxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkEVs713WQ-N3A0%26sharedid%3Dverge%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.staples.com/apple-airpods-pro-mwp22am-a-in-the-ear-bluetooth-headset-white/product_24422954?storeId=10001&amp;amp;AID=10921729&amp;amp;PID=4485850&amp;amp;SID=fa73db569d2011eb83a05281c35caba30INT&amp;amp;cvosrc=affiliate.cj.4485850&amp;amp;cvo_campaign=Coupon&amp;amp;cm_mmc=CJ-_-4485850-_-4485850-_-10921729&amp;amp;CID=AFF%3A4485850%3A4485850%3A10921729&amp;amp;CJPIXEL=CJPIXEL&amp;amp;cjevent=faa926699d2011eb824c01890a82b82a&amp;amp;dclid=CO2H2dLk_e8CFcmnnwod0Y4CCQ&amp;amp;userEnv=&amp;amp;tenantId=StaplesDotCom&amp;amp;locale=en-US&amp;amp;zipCode=21638&amp;amp;channel=WEB&amp;amp;encode=" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$199 at Staples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdTSzD"&gt;If you want to get an Apple Care Plus protection plan for your wireless earbuds, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1570785-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H is selling a bundle that includes both for $278&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
