<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-08T11:52:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T11:52:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T11:52:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Israeli army is using facial recognition to track Palestinians, former soldiers reveal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SOMstKOhEbENKkhkpmxuzHiioX4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70112184/acastro_210512_1777_deepfake_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PfwC4W"&gt;The Israeli military has deployed an extensive facial recognition program to track Palestinians in the Israeli-occupied West Bank, according to a new report by &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/middle_east/israel-palestinians-surveillance-facial-recognition/2021/11/05/3787bf42-26b2-11ec-8739-5cb6aba30a30_story.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SnDH76"&gt;Former Israeli soldiers told the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; about a smartphone technology called “Blue Wolf,” which takes photos of Palestinians and stores them in a large-scale database. Once an image is captured, Blue Wolf matches that picture to a person in its database, and as the&lt;em&gt; Post&lt;/em&gt; describes, soldiers’ phones will then flash a specific color that signifies if that individual should be arrested, detained, or left undisturbed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cyD7Me"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“People worry about fingerprinting, but this is that several times over”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r2whaZ"&gt;The&lt;em&gt; Post&lt;/em&gt; notes that the Israeli army has been filling up the database with thousands of images of Palestinians over the past two years, and it even held “competitions” that rewarded soldiers for taking the most photos of people. The database is essentially a “Facebook for Palestinians,” a former soldier told the&lt;em&gt; Post&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yZMPd3"&gt;The Israeli military has also set up cameras throughout the city of Hebron that scan Palestinians’ faces and identify them for soldiers at checkpoints. Meanwhile, a series of CCTV cameras, some of which point into people’s homes, provide live monitoring 24/7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lqRpMG"&gt;According to the&lt;em&gt; Post&lt;/em&gt;, the former soldiers were told by the military that the surveillance system was put in place to prevent terrorism. Either way, Israel’s system takes facial recognition to a dystopian extreme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="stCWmo"&gt;The largest city in the West Bank, Hebron has seen bitter and long-standing conflict between Israeli and Palestinian populations. A large portion of the city is administered directly by the Israeli military, which enforces curfews and other movement restrictions on the local population. But even in the context of the extreme security measures, the former soldiers who spoke to the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; found the facial recognition system alarming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ueid02"&gt;“I wouldn’t feel comfortable if they used it in the mall in [my hometown], let’s put it that way,” a former soldier told the&lt;em&gt; Post&lt;/em&gt;. “People worry about fingerprinting, but this is that several times over.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vmnx1L"&gt;There have been a number of similar systems implemented in other countries, and all have been controversial. China &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163499/huawei-uighur-surveillance-facial-recognition-megvii-uyghur"&gt;developed a similar facial recognition system&lt;/a&gt; to monitor the Uyghur minority population, although it’s unclear how widely the system was put into use. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728667/russia-face-pay-system-moscow-metro-privacy"&gt;Moscow recently added facial recognition payment systems&lt;/a&gt; to hundreds of metro stations, while the UK launched a similar &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732330/uk-schools-facial-recognition-lunch-payments-north-ayrshire"&gt;face-scanning payment system for schoolchildren&lt;/a&gt; at lunchtime.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769933/israeli-army-facial-recognition-palestinians-track"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769933/israeli-army-facial-recognition-palestinians-track</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T10:48:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T10:48:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fully’s standing desks, chairs, and more are discounted ahead of Black Friday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/brhIfyGLvHiqLOdlHNbx-Wg3Z7E=/0x170:2040x1530/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70111858/jpeters_210226_4457_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jay Peters / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xFMmaN"&gt;There are countless brands that make standing desks, but Fully makes some of the best. And now through November 30th, the day after Cyber Monday, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44880&amp;amp;u1=VergeFullyDeals110821&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;you can get 15 percent off every item available on its online store&lt;/a&gt;. That includes its Jarvis standing desks and handy accessories you might want with one, like a monitor arm, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44880&amp;amp;u1=VergeFullyDeals110821&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Faccessories%2Fpowered-grommet-cover.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;powered grommet covers that give you extra plugs and USB charging ports&lt;/a&gt;, and more. These deals don’t completely change that these are still pricey products, but if you have a home office, you stand to level up a few rungs on the ergonomic ladder by taking advantage of these deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T7BnUl"&gt;If you’re looking for a real wood tabletop for your desk instead of less durable MDF material, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44880&amp;amp;u1=VergeFullyDeals110821&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Fstanding-desks%2Fjarvis%2Fjarvis-adjustable-height-desk-bamboo.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Jarvis standing desk with a bamboo top starts at $484&lt;/a&gt; instead of $569. The cost goes up from there depending on the size of desk you’d like, along with several other customizations that make the price go up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2A9Luf"&gt;We haven’t reviewed standing desks at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252470/work-from-home-remote-gadgets-recommendations"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252470/work-from-home-remote-gadgets-recommendations"&gt;Fully’s Jarvis desk has been mentioned several times&lt;/a&gt; by a few of us here who own one (including myself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="n6pHIx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10852598"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="0O1PD5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"What’s on your Fully Jarvis desk, Jay Peters?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22310104/remote-work-desk-home-set-up-jay-peters-macbook-xbox"},{"title":"What’s on your Fully Jarvis desk, Dan Seifert?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22395531/remote-work-desk-setup-from-home-office-tech"},{"title":"The best early Black Friday deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="EPqPPB"&gt;Fully makes less costly desks, too, like the Remi laminate standing desk, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44880&amp;amp;u1=VergeFullyDeals110821&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Fstanding-desks%2Fremi-standing-desk.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;which now costs $390&lt;/a&gt; instead of $459. The company also makes several fixed-height desks, which are seeing a 15 percent price drop right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WqFQrT"&gt;Whether you want to go in on a desk or not, Fully’s accessories are compatible with more than its own creations. For people who are on their feet at a desk, the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44880&amp;amp;u1=VergeFullyDeals110821&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Faccessories%2Fstanding-desk-mats%2Ftopo-standing-mat.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Topo anti-fatigue mat makes that far less of a strain&lt;/a&gt;. Normally $99, it costs $84. The &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44880&amp;amp;u1=VergeFullyDeals110821&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Faccessories%2Fstanding-desk-mats%2Ftopo-mini-standing-mat.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;mini version costs $67&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dmnAfR"&gt;Another great addition to your work space could be &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44880&amp;amp;u1=VergeFullyDeals110821&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Faccessories%2Fjarvis-monitor-arm.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fully’s Jarvis monitor arm&lt;/a&gt; that fastens to your desk. It has a wide range of motion, even letting your monitor twist to the side if you’d rather orient your setup that way. Normally $129, it’s $110 now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MD4zg2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10852592"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="0tWdwK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22770024/fully-jarvis-standing-desk-chairs-accessories-black-friday-cyber-monday-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22770024/fully-jarvis-standing-desk-chairs-accessories-black-friday-cyber-monday-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple macOS 12 Monterey review: the best is yet to come</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;It’s fine, but Apple has unfinished business&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="8VNIdt"&gt;Downloading &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21564490/macos-big-sur-review-apple-macbook-pro-air-mac-ipad-m1"&gt;macOS Big Sur&lt;/a&gt; was a big change for me — visually, pragmatically, philosophically. It was the biggest macOS redesign we’d seen in years. And it was a new direction for the ecosystem in general; macOS looked and felt like iOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qlhZcb"&gt;Downloading macOS Monterey, by contrast, has not impacted my life much. I installed the first beta over the summer, forgot that I was using it within a few days, and tried to download it again the following week. It looks like Big Sur, with some tweaks here and there. Many of them seem to be catch-up efforts, equipping Monterey with features that iOS (or competitors) already had. A few of the features are useful for me, but they’re features you have to seek out and set up. And we’re still waiting on some of the most innovative parts of Monterey that Apple announced earlier this year to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vWJr5y"&gt;So my ultimate view on this operating system is, “Sure.” It’s a stable release that I’ve been using reliably for a few months. Nothing’s terribly broken. If you’re someone who prefers to exercise maximum caution and wait a while before upgrading, you’re also not missing all that much. As is often the case with releases directly following a major redesign, this is a building year for macOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="urYC6u"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple MacBook Pro 14 and 16 review: return to form","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review"},{"title":"Apple finally listened to the pros","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22733328/apple-macbook-pro-ports-professional-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="yxKxsM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10848473"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A blank MacBook desktop with a purple and pink gradient background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YwmUf3sTHLLQ3b7cz-kKzFHxKc0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989814/Image_11_5_21_at_4.27_PM.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the desktop of a MacBook running macOS Monterey. Look familiar?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8x3fR1"&gt;FaceTime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="YrJPaX"&gt;The tweaks that Apple seems to be most excited about concern FaceTime. While I won’t go so far as to insinuate that Apple is trying to make FaceTime a Zoom competitor, it’s certainly introduced a number of features aimed at making its service more viable for group calls. The significant one for me is that you can now create links to FaceTime calls (as you can with Zoom calls) and send them out to participants ahead of time. These links are very easy to create with a single button on the app’s home screen — certainly slightly less of a pain than they are in the Zoom client on macOS. (On the other hand, the FaceTime link is just a link; it doesn’t come with dial-in numbers and you can’t join from a landline.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEX1JA"&gt;These links also allow Android and Windows users to join such calls for the first time. Joining a FaceTime call from a Windows laptop is eerily similar to joining a Zoom or Google Meet call — you click the link, the call opens in your browser, you’re asked to enter your name, and you wait around until the host lets you in. Also in the vein of targeting the business market (or, at least, the calls-with-multiple-friends market), FaceTime now supports Grid View, which lays the faces of participants in front of you when you’re on a call (an option &lt;a href="https://support.zoom.us/hc/en-us/articles/201362323-Adjusting-screen-view-settings-during-a-virtual-meeting"&gt;Zoom also has&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eDefNl"&gt;There are a few other neat features that pop up in Control Center, including Portrait Mode (which blurs the background behind you), Voice Isolation (which mitigates background noise while you’re speaking), and Wide Spectrum (which picks up all of your background noise, if you’re doing a virtual guitar lesson or something). Portrait Mode, in particular, works quite well, is easy to toggle on and off, and is something I’ll continue to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A user faces the camera on a FaceTime call with their background blurred out. A drop-down menu from the Control Center indicates that Portrait Mode is active." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FSk6luq9rJYUC8aCy6NmdJXDSr0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989881/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_4.50.13_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s FaceTime blurring out my background on a call.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oQLqMt"&gt;These features are actually available for third-party apps to support as well, though who supports what seems to vary. I could use Portrait Mode in both Zoom and Google Meet but couldn’t use the microphone controls. I haven’t been able to find a list of apps that support these enhancements, but I have asked Apple for one, and I’ll update this review if they dig anything up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rKQeno"&gt;The most exciting new FaceTime feature, though — and the one that could really distinguish it from Zoom and other competitors when it comes to group calls — is still in beta. It’s SharePlay. SharePlay is a service similar to Teleparty, Scener, and Watch Together. It allows you and other people on your FaceTime call to watch or listen to streaming content together by syncing everyone’s video and playback controls. (So we’re both watching &lt;em&gt;Foundation &lt;/em&gt;separately on our own Apple accounts — but when I pause or rewind, your video pauses or rewinds as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of an Apple Music interface. A notification in the top right reads “Music: Content will SharePlay automatically”." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cPgYmk2ifvwLjeq3bc4WdznkcVk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989957/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_5.06.00_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you open up a supported service like Apple Music while you’re on a FaceTime call, content SharePlays automatically.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YDulur"&gt;SharePlay, unfortunately, doesn’t seem ready yet. For one, the official list of services the feature supports isn’t easy to find — I had to get Apple to send me this &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/story/id1583059388"&gt;App Store Preview page&lt;/a&gt;. The supported services are also relatively few, and it doesn’t include any non-Apple big players like Hulu, HBO, Netflix, or Spotify yet — which are the services that people I know reliably have. It also doesn’t have Apple’s own Podcast app yet. (It does include Tiktok, which is hilarious.) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522904/apple-shareplay-facetime-music-hulu-videos-tiktok-wwdc"&gt;Hulu,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673907/apple-event-2021-apple-tv-plus-streaming-wars"&gt;Spotify and HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; are supposed to be adopting SharePlay at some point, but Apple hasn’t given me a timeline for Podcasts support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HtiILL"&gt;That aside, the beta version of SharePlay is a nice experience — when it works. I played a few Apple Music tracks on a group call, and I would say SharePlay worked about 50 percent of the time. It was a good experience, and all parties could pause and skip without issue. But if I changed songs, my fellow callers would often stop hearing the audio I was trying to share and get stuck on a loading screen (while it continued to play on my end), and I’d have to quit and restart the Music app to get us synced up again. All told, I hope that Apple is able to polish SharePlay up before its final release — it still seems to be a beta feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of Safari with the sidebar open and The Verge Reviews homepage, with the combined URL and tab bar." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XtCNXc3f7SGXs-2WzVtY4QRt08Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989960/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_5.11.56_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s Safari with the combined tab bar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of Safari with the sidebar open and the Verge Reviews homepage displayed with separate tab and URL bars." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WvI-pHmGIYcgonPYEtwoOqfnf-8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989961/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_5.12.18_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here it is with the two bars separate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VyElJZ"&gt;Safari&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xqxfMb"&gt;The latest version of Safari isn’t limited to Monterey — you can install it on Big Sur, too, but Apple tends to update it around the same time that it updates macOS. This year’s edition redesigns the way tabs look — or, at least, it tried to. In the first few Monterey betas, Apple combined Safari’s tab bar and URL bar into a single row. People ended up hating this — the franken-bar was a bit cramped, and it was easy to close tabs instead of selecting them — so Apple has brought back the old, discrete bars for the stable release. The combined tab bar is still an option if you want it — you can swap in Preferences. I encourage you to try both layouts if you’re a Safari user. I actually like the extra browser space that the compact tab layout affords, though it gets a bit unwieldy if you have tons and tons of tabs open. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bz36nA"&gt;Apple’s made a few other tweaks to tabs. They look slightly rounder now, and you can hover over one to reveal its full page title and URL. Safari also now has “tab groups” (another feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/13/21257446/google-chome-tab-grouping-feature"&gt;Chrome has had for a while&lt;/a&gt;). If you have three tabs open, you can click a little icon in the top-left corner to make them into a tab group. Later on, if you open the sidebar on the left of the Safari window, you’ll see it listed under a “Tab Groups” heading; you can click on it to reopen those three tabs. Also in that sidebar live your bookmarks and your reading list. This is — finally — an area where I think Safari is now a step ahead of Chrome. I’ve always found tab groups in Chrome to be quite confusing and have never used them, but they’re so simple in Safari that I’ve already made them part of my routine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8CRIO4"&gt;Tab groups also sync across devices (as do Bookmarks, extensions, etc.), though I had to dig into Settings on all my Apple products and give iCloud permission to do that before it worked. There are also a few new security features, including Intelligent Tracking Prevention, which prevents “known trackers” from viewing your IP address, and HTTPS Upgrade, which automatically switches sites from HTTP to HTTPS when possible.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="II5wcz"&gt;And then there’s Quick Note. Quick Note ostensibly gives you an easy way to take notes on an article you’re reading — you can right-click highlighted text to add it to a Note, which will then pop back up whenever you return to that web page. I was excited about this when I tried it in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;early betas&lt;/a&gt;, but I never quite got the hang of them and haven’t actually ended up using it. It might be more useful for students who often have to take notes on long readings; I have trouble finding a use case for myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CeIQGG"&gt;The new Safari as a whole was quite stable and speedy. Things weren’t randomly crashing or quitting. But the new sidebar, and the ease with which you can operate Tab Groups, has seriously made me consider switching to Safari. It’s surprisingly useful to have bookmarks, tab groups, and my reading list all in one place. If all the Chrome extensions I currently use make it over there, I’ll probably do it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qwz6ZWtl78JzSglvvF6IjXqYjxM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989963/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_5.15.53_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="faVKTv"&gt;Continuity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Hirq8y"&gt;When I asked Apple if there was any unifying theme or goal behind the big dump of features that is macOS Monterey, the company told me it was meant to further the journey Big Sur began of unifying macOS and iOS. Monterey has a few additions that are clearly meant to do that, though the biggest one isn’t ready yet. Universal Control will allow you to use an iPad as a secondary screen to your Mac, so you can drag / drop files between the two devices and operate them with a single mouse and keyboard. This has been one of the most anticipated Monterey features since the software was announced, but it’s still nowhere in sight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fxAyVU"&gt;A few other iOS staples have made their way onto macOS Monterey. One is Focus, which allows you to filter notifications based on the task you’re doing. Within Focus preferences, accessible from the Control Center, you can create various Focus profiles for work, gaming, and other scenarios; for each profile, you’ll essentially whitelist applications or contacts that are allowed to send you notifications when that profile is on. You can schedule Focus to turn on automatically at various times, in various locations, or with the opening of various apps, and you can allow people and apps to choose to notify you anyway if something is urgent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="wbP1LW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge guide to macOS","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21281530/macos-mac-imac-user-guide-how-to-os-tips"},{"title":"Apple macOS 11 Big Sur review: a long time coming","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21564490/macos-big-sur-review-apple-macbook-pro-air-mac-ipad-m1"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="t9AIsE"&gt;This is a feature I really wish I’d had in college — it would’ve been great for turning off social media while writing papers and such. Employed me finds it mostly useful for shutting up Slack after work hours (though you could already do that within the app itself). Switching to Focus in macOS can also switch it on across your iOS devices. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QFdml7GZ791cQIXVPPM4iCAfwH0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989971/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_5.17.40_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KTRbbe"&gt;Another thing I’ve found surprisingly handy: Shortcuts. Yes, Siri Shortcuts are a thing on Macs now. I barely use these on my iPhone, but I’ve actually found a few of them handy on my MacBook because you can stick them on the menu bar for quick access. In particular, “Split Screen Two Apps” and “Start My Next Meeting” were convenient to have up there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TfmJ4A"&gt;Odds and ends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Q2oDhp"&gt;Various other apps have gotten updates here and there. There’s a new tab called “Shared With You” in Photos, News, Safari, Apple TV, and Apple Podcasts, which displays media that you’ve recently received in Messages. This feature sounds potentially useful but didn’t actually work for me — nothing was showing up in my Shared With You tabs unless I pinned it. Apple is still trying to figure out what’s going on but tells me it’s not an issue they’ve seen before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="vYJ6P1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;iOS staples have made their way onto macOS Monterey&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FZ9cPU"&gt;Speaking of Messages, if you text someone multiple photos, they’re now displayed as a collage or a stack, depending on how many you send. Sure. It’s cute. The app also displays a new button next to the photos you receive, which you can click to quickly save those photos to your device. Again, sure. It’s now slightly easier to save photos (though it wasn’t that hard before). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="Wtn1h2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10848592"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="T61d0j"&gt;You can now tag your Notes, which is such a no-brainer I’m surprised it took Apple this long to implement it. Just type a hashtag followed by a word anywhere in the note in question, and it’ll show up as a tag in a “Tag Browser” on the left sidebar. Useful! I will use these. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPgeSs"&gt;Elsewhere, Apple seems to be trying to push Notes towards a similar vein to Google Docs. There are a number of new features that smooth out the process of collaborating on Notes in iCloud. You can now type an @ to get a friend’s attention within a Note and can see a summary of updates to shared Notes in a new Activity View. These things I’m not sure about — I already use Docs for the purpose Notes is moving towards here, and the former is still much more full-featured, not to mention more widely accessible outside of Apple’s ecosystem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cdrK5k"&gt;Maps, finally, has received what Apple says is its largest update yet. The main thing you’ll notice is that zooming all the way out reveals a cute interactive globe floating in space. You can click and drag to spin it around, and there are little details for mountains, rainforests, and such. When I say cute, I mean cute — it’s somewhat cartoonish and not like using Google Earth. But it’s neat to play around with, and I’ve had fun dropping pins in random places. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wym9hn"&gt;More pragmatically, city layouts have gotten more useful. Zoom in on San Francisco, and you’ll see icons over the Golden Gate Bridge, Alcatraz, Fisherman’s Wharf, Oracle Park, etc. Click those icons, and little cards pop up with basically all the information you might need about these destinations: hours, accessibility information, phone numbers, addresses, etc. I have actually started using Maps to plan trips instead of Google Maps because of these cards — I much prefer the card layout to having the information pop up in the sidebar like it does on Google. It takes up less space on the screen and doesn’t move everything else around when you open it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of Apple maps viewing Manhattan, with Grand Central Terminal’s information card selected." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hV-g8rXlmkH_0f28Y-E7sisSVLQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22989991/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_5.22.27_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neat!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Kydzj7"&gt;Should you upgrade?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Ozx1H9"&gt;Sure, with the caveat that waiting a few weeks to download this stuff is always the safest course of action. For what it’s worth, Apple seems to have ironed out most of the bugs I saw in early betas, and it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/5/22765759/apple-macos-monterey-t2-security-brick-bug"&gt;just released a patch&lt;/a&gt; to fix some upgrade headaches with older Macs. It’s also worth bearing in mind that two of the most anticipated parts of this operating system — SharePlay and Universal Control — aren’t ready yet. Other folks who are particularly cautious about bugs may want to sift through the new features and figure out which ones will benefit their lives. There may be some, and there may not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fm1SuQ"&gt;Here’s what those features are for me: Portrait Mode, Safari Tab Groups, Shortcuts, Notes tags, and the new cards in Maps. None of these things have changed the way I observe or interact with macOS, but they’re all handy things that not all competitors have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of the Notes app in macOS Monterey. The not reads “Here is a new note, #newnote. That was easy.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/86sAZRm9X8k_GkUe6-YC7Ggu92I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22990000/Screen_Shot_2021_11_05_at_5.24.49_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sure, why not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4bN2c6"&gt;They are, I will note, also all things that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683681/ios-15-ipados-review-iphone-ipad-apple"&gt;also exist in iOS&lt;/a&gt;. In my review of macOS Big Sur, I noted that many of the port-overs from iOS weren’t as beneficial on a non-touchscreen laptop as they were on a phone. macOS Monterey is a more incremental step ahead, which is to be expected the year after a major redesign. But I think Apple has also done a better job this year of pinpointing the sorts of iOS features that make sense to have on a Mac. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MiKJDy"&gt;With that said, macOS Monterey isn’t finished (despite a rather lengthy beta period), and I think there are still plenty of people who will upgrade and find little to no change to their macOS experience. That may be the case until SharePlay and Universal Control are ready to take the stage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="LclBBY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10848602"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22765988/apple-macos-12-monterey-review-macbook-pro-air-imac-m1"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22765988/apple-macos-12-monterey-review-macbook-pro-air-imac-m1</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T10:27:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T10:27:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Security software company McAfee acquired for $14 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration, a McAfee Corp. logo is seen on a smartphone screen" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LX0JRNLHmgNTkLTvvX4lrnXafp4=/0x0:3888x2592/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70111764/1236429078.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;McAfee has been acquired for $14 billion | Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H64vK4"&gt;Security software company McAfee is going private via a buyout from an investor group in a deal valued at more than $14 billion, the company &lt;a href="https://ir.mcafee.com/news-releases/news-release-details/mcafee-be-acquired-investor-group-over-14-billion"&gt;announced Monday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; first &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-05/mcafee-said-in-talks-to-go-private-via-deal-with-advent-permira?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; last week that a likely deal was imminent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VjFnA0"&gt;McAfee was founded in 1987 by John McAfee and became known for its computer antivirus software. McAfee, the founder, left McAfee, the company, in 1994, and the company was &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/08/20/technology/20chip.html"&gt;acquired by Intel in 2010&lt;/a&gt; for $7.68 billion. In 2014, Intel announced it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/1/6/5282618/intel-phases-out-mcafee-brand-name-distancing-itself-from"&gt;phasing out the McAfee brand&lt;/a&gt; name for the security software and rebranding it as “Intel Security.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iJqZr3"&gt;Last October, the company returned to the public stock market. McAfee said in the announcement that it will continue as a “pure-play consumer cybersecurity” company after &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mcafee.com%2Fenterprise%2Fen-us%2Fabout%2Fnewsroom%2Fpress-releases%2F2021%2F20210727-01.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F8%2F22769910%2Fmcafee-private-investor-group-acquisition-software" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;selling its Enterprise business&lt;/a&gt; to private equity firm Symphony Technology Group for &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/mcafee-sells-its-enterprise-business-to-private-equity-group-as-it-focuses-on-consumer-security/"&gt;$4 billion&lt;/a&gt; in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OTpqXJ"&gt;The company said the deal announced Monday to sell to the investor group, which includes Advent International Corp., Permira Advisers, and Crosspoint Capital Partners, is expected to close in the first half of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BATHki"&gt;John McAfee had led a troubled life after departing the company; in 2012, he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/12/5/3734178/mcafee-arrest-murder-investigation"&gt;fled to Guatemala&lt;/a&gt; as authorities in Belize sought to question him in connection &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/11/12/3636412/john-mcafee-questioning-murder-investigation-belize"&gt;with a neighbor’s murder&lt;/a&gt;. In March, he was &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdny/pr/john-david-mcafee-and-executive-adviser-his-cryptocurrency-team-indicted-manhattan"&gt;charged with securities fraud&lt;/a&gt; over a “pump and dump” cryptocurrency scheme, where authorities said he and his bodyguard persuaded their Twitter followers to invest in certain coins, then sold their holdings in the currencies when the prices went up. McAfee was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547643/john-mcafee-dead-prison-spain-us-extradition"&gt;found dead in a prison cell in Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; in June, not long after Spain had approved extraditing him to the US to face &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315494/john-mcafee-fraud-securities-scheme-charges-cryptocurrency"&gt;tax fraud charges&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HHmXnc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769910/mcafee-private-investor-group-acquisition-software"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769910/mcafee-private-investor-group-acquisition-software</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T10:21:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T10:21:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Forza Horizon 5 is the best road trip ever</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0YSbCaSuiegGmc1WbZoXB4bFtdQ=/600x0:3840x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70111744/ForzaHorizon5_Launch_Preview_03_16x9_WM.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;And the best Forza Horizon yet&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="CcIqTi"&gt;If you’re an arcade racing game purist, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/15/17125348/burnout-paradise-remastered-ps4-xbox-interview"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Burnout Paradise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has a lot to answer for. By taking the classic series open-world, Criterion essentially obsoleted the concept of traditional racers — here are your cars, here are your tracks, learn to drive the former to perfect the latter — at least in the eyes of major publishers. Ever since, virtually all big-budget arcade racing games have been made in the shadow of &lt;em&gt;Paradise&lt;/em&gt;, with most tracks consisting of lines drawn across vast, explorable maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b4akMA"&gt;As someone who is personally not very happy about this turn of events, I have to admit that Microsoft’s &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/em&gt; series has been a pretty spectacular product of it all. With each entry in the series, developer Playground Games has delivered relentlessly entertaining open-world racing in vividly rendered settings. &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;, the latest release, relocates to Mexico and turns out to be the best &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/em&gt; yet — as well as one of the best games of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X3wa5x"&gt;Despite the name and the hundreds of accurately modeled real-world cars, &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/em&gt; has little in common with Turn 10 Studios’ &lt;em&gt;Forza Motorsport&lt;/em&gt; series, which is more of a serious racing simulator. While &lt;em&gt;Horizon&lt;/em&gt; isn’t exactly a &lt;em&gt;Ridge Racer&lt;/em&gt;-style arcade game, it’s certainly on the more accessible side of things. The physics feel somewhat grounded in reality, and you’ll notice big differences in how various cars handle, but the driving model is very forgiving, and it’s easy for anyone to pick up and play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="O6rlrD"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U3mEOHvSUyw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JhRcFe"&gt;The previous game in the series, &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 4&lt;/em&gt;, was personally appealing to me because of its UK setting, which I found to be a convincing rendering of where I grew up. But I found the game hard to get into because of the way it handled its open-world design, throwing an overwhelming array of cars and quests at you. Every time I opened the game after a week or two away, I’d have no idea what to do — the overwrought UI gave me option paralysis. It felt more like &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed&lt;/em&gt; on wheels than an arcade racer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JWiUAU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t change the basic structure, and there’s still a huge amount of stuff dotting the Mexican map. But it does do a better job of easing you into its mountain of content. You’re able to choose which specific types of events to unlock as you progress, so, for example, I preferred to focus on closed-track road races early on before delving into cross-country rallies. I feel like if I stopped playing the game and came back to it weeks later, I’d have a much better sense of what I’d been doing and where would be best for me to spend the next couple of hours. In turn, that makes me feel better about simply driving around the landscape in search of whatever esoteric quest I might come across. Unlike with &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, I’ve never felt like I’m wasting my time in &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;, as I always have more of a sense of what I could be working toward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="vIVo6t"&gt;&lt;q&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; does do a better job of easing you into its mountain of content&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cy7nYe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/em&gt;’s premise — a “festival” that descends on a loosely recreated real-world locale and takes it over with various racing events of dubious legality — remains as absurd as ever, with entirely superfluous “story” sequences peppered throughout. I have personally never been to Mexico, but I have a feeling most of the locals wouldn’t take too kindly to visitors causing wanton destruction while bombing around the streets in a Dodge Viper listening to Dua Lipa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s8hI6p"&gt;On the other hand, &lt;em&gt;Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;’s depiction of Mexico is only likely to drive interest in international tourism once such things are broadly possible again. This is a beautiful game that shows off the country’s diverse landscape in spectacular fashion, from lush forests to active volcanoes. Its predecessor made the most of the UK’s landscape, but it’s hard to escape the feeling that Mexico is a more appealing setting for a game like this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3YMcau"&gt;I don’t think I can overstate the extent to which &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; looks entirely out of control on the Xbox Series X. This is easily one of the most technically impressive games I have ever seen, with hugely improved lighting and stunning detail in the landscapes. You can run it at 60 frames per second on Xbox Series consoles, or there’s a 30fps mode that further boosts the graphical features; I personally find it hard to play racing games at 30fps, but each mode delivers a convincing presentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1jUB9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; is also an impressive test case for Microsoft’s cross-generational hardware strategy. I played the game for several hours on my Xbox One X, and it doesn’t feel compromised compared to anything else on the console. It’s still a better-looking game than &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, and it looks more or less the same as the Series X version’s 60fps mode — just running at half the frame rate. The One X is generally a machine designed for 4K/30fps games, and that’s what you get here with &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;. Would the Series X game have looked even better if it didn’t have to run on Xbox One consoles? Maybe, but it’s hard to complain about the performance on either platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9azOeouXgQBgz-I02cY49rRxRqE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22995273/ForzaHorizon5_Launch_Preview_06_16x9_WM.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BwMoic"&gt;That said, &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; has come in a little hot. During the review period and early access launch, I’ve noticed quite a few issues on various hardware, from graphical glitches to AI opponents that disappear completely. Server access has been spotty, and the PC version was almost unplayable for me due to constant controller disconnection errors. These will hopefully get ironed out, but I wouldn’t be happy about the server problems in particular if I’d paid $100 for the premium version of the game that includes early access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="7kUhzs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Forza Horizon 5 is the perfect portable Xbox game","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22762183/forza-horizon-5-perfect-portable-xbox-game-series-x-s-pc-steam"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A8JCSG"&gt;I wouldn’t normally spend as much time on the technical elements of a game when reviewing it, but I think it’s more relevant with &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; than most others. Last night, I fired up &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 3&lt;/em&gt; for a couple of hours, which I previously thought of as my favorite game in the series. Two things immediately struck me: it doesn’t look anywhere near as good as I remembered it, and it’s also almost exactly the same game as &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;, right down to the near-identical UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fF2P7m"&gt;Beyond its slight but welcome tweaks to the unlocking system, &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; makes hardly any progress on its predecessors in terms of game design. It really is as if the previous couple of games just got airlifted to Mexico and received an extreme technical glow-up. And honestly, I’m fine with that. The setting is everything in &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/em&gt; — it’s what dictates and defines the endless firehose of races and championships and quests, not to mention the future expansions that have already been confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="INrEpS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; is just another &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/em&gt;, yes, but it’s a beautiful one with an incredible setting, and that’s enough to make it the best in the series. If you have any interest whatsoever in driving fast cars fast, I highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QZH2eJ"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Forza Horizon 5 &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is available tomorrow on Xbox consoles, PC, and Xbox Game Pass for both platforms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22769985/forza-horizon-5-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22769985/forza-horizon-5-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge Holiday Gift Guide 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6pzjooxh36jGOlDFDP1r99AQaws=/0x0:2500x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70111588/VRG_Illo_4859_GG_Main_lede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Richard Parry&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Shop our curated guide for everyone in your life&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="SxVkbR"&gt;Finding the perfect gift for everyone special in your life can be, frankly, a nightmare. Some people are easy to shop for, but others in your family or social spheres might be less forthcoming about their desires. You could do the leg work of asking what might make them a happy camper over the holidays, but who has time for that? That’s a rhetorical question. No one has time for that, except for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WhSfEV"&gt;Our team of writers at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; huddled for weeks to come up with the definitive list of gift ideas that you’ll find below. There are gifts for gamers, aspiring podcast hosts, parents, board game connoisseurs, musicians, and much more. Given that we cover tech primarily, you know we’ve got you covered for all of this year’s desirable gadgets. But our team is also comprised of cooks, campers, photographers, fitness enthusiasts, and more, so expect a varied and inspired selection of gift ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rPO7rd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge’s Guide to Black Friday 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="pChznl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10842009"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T09:35:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T09:35:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s early Black Friday deals on games and consoles kick off November 21st</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ykzben2yN8aOyP3FXzVopn-nsOQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70111479/jbareham_180301_2346_nintendo_switch_0014.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pwlpf2"&gt;Nintendo has shared the slate of early &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;Black Friday&lt;/a&gt; deals it’ll offer starting on Sunday, November 21st. Like last year, the main attraction is the standard Nintendo Switch console that includes &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 8 Deluxe &lt;/em&gt;and a three-month individual membership to Nintendo Switch Online. It all costs $299.99. Nintendo didn’t share whether the Switch console included is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/12/20802539/nintendo-switch-v2-new-updated-battery-console-how-to-buy"&gt;the V2 model&lt;/a&gt; with improved battery life, but l&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/22/21564016/nintendo-switch-black-friday-mario-kart-8-online-bundle-best-buy-deal"&gt;ast year’s Black Friday promotion&lt;/a&gt; included the V2. Still, we’ve reached out to Nintendo for confirmation. We’ll also be on the lookout for which retailers will offer this holiday bundle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zr5KG5"&gt;Several games will receive $20 discounts, including ones that don’t commonly see such a big price drop. Those include &lt;em&gt;Xenoblade Chronicles: Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Astral Chain&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Paper Mario: The Origami King&lt;/em&gt;. In addition to those, several other must-haves are being knocked down to $40 (usually $60).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VDJbdv"&gt;Here’s the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="s551V2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tRrUiL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Super Mario Bros. U Deluxe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DASe5n"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Splatoon 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iBEu4I"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario Maker 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lDBXRt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kirby Star Allies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zvsOof"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Link’s Awakening&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rfZYqB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fire Emblem: Three Houses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dd0jD5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astral Chain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="dZXTGz"&gt;(Keep an eye out in case the digital versions of the games above are the same price as the physical version. If that’s the case, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-128GB-MicroSDXC-Memory-Adapter/dp/B08GY8NHF2/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;you might need a bigger microSD card&lt;/a&gt; to store more games on.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pVcW2P"&gt;You can also get big discounts on more interactive experiences for Switch, including &lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt; for just $55 (usually $80) and &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart Live: Home Circuit&lt;/em&gt; for $60 (usually $100). These are the biggest discounts yet for either of these titles. Keep in mind that all of these deals will end on the following Saturday, November 27th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="5WjekK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best early Black Friday deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="A4vsCV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769909/nintendo-black-friday-deals-2021-switch-ring-fit-adventure-mario-kart-console-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769909/nintendo-black-friday-deals-2021-switch-ring-fit-adventure-mario-kart-console-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T08:23:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T08:23:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney Plus is upgrading Marvel movies to IMAX aspect ratio</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NYgdE9SUS24S1Snuf5lT5Al7rSA=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70111209/IEDS003_Content_EAR_Assets_1920x1080_V4.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Lne3ft"&gt;Disney and IMAX have announced a collaboration that will see several Marvel movies presented in IMAX’s Expanded Aspect Ratio format on Disney Plus. 13 MCU movies in total will be upgraded to IMAX Enhanced on November 12th, including &lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings&lt;/em&gt;, which is making its debut on the service that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gjbTMM"&gt;While IMAX traditionally uses a squarer 1.43:1 format, Expanded Aspect Ratio is 1.90:1, which is relatively close to the 16:9 ratio of TVs. Marvel movies are generally presented in wider, letterboxed aspect ratios, but many of them feature some 1.90:1 sequences captured with IMAX-certified cameras for a taller picture in IMAX theaters. &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Endgame, &lt;/em&gt;meanwhile, were shot entirely in the format.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gr9Jts6vJYfK-XeyYmFwcMWv2jE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22987907/bwimax.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8ERLp6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt;, for example, has 22 minutes of IMAX Expanded Aspect Ratio footage, so those scenes will fill up more of your TV screen when you watch them on Disney Plus. In other words, the black bars will be smaller. The IMAX Enhanced designation will eventually involve more features, like DTS surround sound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NkgLpE"&gt;Here’s the full list of MCU movies that will be certified as IMAX Enhanced on November 12th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="d4Fmzk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ant-Man and the Wasp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PJVhyN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z7aTFE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rZ2ds7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Panther&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VKqNNM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yyf7bC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Captain America: Civil War&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FaPLJt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Kn3adO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BMTv5U"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HdBflR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YaXxKX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wLpcW3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BnFuLG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thor: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22764957/marvel-disney-plus-imax-expanded-aspect-ratio"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22764957/marvel-disney-plus-imax-expanded-aspect-ratio</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T06:02:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T06:02:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk, world’s richest edgelord, responds to billionaire tax with another stupid tweet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/opYNus1fbpwECLr24oTgx7GGQXI=/219x97:792x479/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70110857/elon_musk_edge_lord.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elon Musk responds to US Senator Ron Wyden on his plans to tax billionaires. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ocKwEC"&gt;Is it fair that the world’s richest people &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/08/richest-25-americans-jeff-bezos-elon-musk-tax"&gt;pay so little in tax&lt;/a&gt;? That in a time of &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2020/jan/22/wealth-gap-widening-for-more-than-70-per-cent-of-global-population-researchers-find"&gt;extreme inequality&lt;/a&gt;, those that have so much contribute so little in proportion to their vast wealth? These are the questions motivating US Democratic Senator Ron Wyden, who’s been calling for new taxes on billionaires. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NiCIZi"&gt;Is it fair that the democracy I live in might have some demands of me? How can I prove that I’m super edgy and totally unfazed by the prospect of paying more tax? These are the questions apparently motivating Elon Musk, who replied to a tweet from Wyden by asking why the senator looks like he’s just orgasmed in his profile picture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sAhjPG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Why does ur pp look like u just came?&lt;/p&gt;— Lorde Edge (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1457497438474981384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TV3LKW"&gt;Musk’s crude tweet caps a particularly interesting weekend for the world’s richest man, who  didn’t seem to get the answer he wanted when polling the internet on the issue of wealth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XPA9Pt"&gt;On Saturday, Musk asked his 63 million Twitter followers whether or not he should sell 10 percent of his Tesla stock. The question is important, because without selling stock, Musk isn’t actually taxed on the main source of his vast fortune (he owns around 17 percent of Tesla stock, currently worth around $200 billion). This is the situation that Wyden and other politicians wanted to change with a plan to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-the-billionaires-income-tax-would-work-1163532520"&gt;annually tax&lt;/a&gt; unsold assets like stocks belonging to the United States’ wealthiest citizens — around 700 billionaires (though Wyden’s proposals have &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/38770267-8fed-49a9-a85a-1b9cc2e45d60"&gt;already been rejected&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BGlu8O"&gt;As Musk put it in a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1457067398712942592"&gt;separate tweet&lt;/a&gt;: “I do not take a cash salary or bonus from anywhere. I only have stock, thus the only way for me to pay taxes personally is to sell stock.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1FutP8"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I will abide by the results of this poll, whichever way it goes&lt;/p&gt;— Lorde Edge (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1457066048944066565?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l6tAGM"&gt;Musk’s Twitter followers were clear, though: Elon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768364/elon-musk-poll-twitter-tesla-10-percent-billionaires-capital-gains-tax"&gt;&lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; sell his stock&lt;/a&gt;, with 57.9 percent of 3.5 million participants voting “yes” on the poll. In other words: Musk should be paying more in tax than he does already. (Interestingly, due to how Musk’s Tesla stock options are structured, he’s likely due a &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/08/business/elon-musk-twitter-poll.html"&gt;sizable tax bill&lt;/a&gt; regardless of the outcome of any Twitter poll.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kRpoxE"&gt;Musk, who &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1457066048944066565"&gt;promised&lt;/a&gt; to “abide by the results of this poll, whichever way it goes,” hasn’t commented directly on the poll’s outcome. Instead, he chose to fire off his tweet to Wyden after the senator pointed out that “whether or not the world’s wealthiest man pays any taxes at all shouldn’t depend on the results of a Twitter poll.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oAdUsV"&gt;It was this shocking suggestion — that questions of great public import, like billionaires’ tax rates, might be settled &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of Musk’s Twitter feed — that apparently proved too much for Elon to bear. Presumably, though, he’s too busy preparing the necessary paperwork to follow through on his promise and sell his stock to come up with a more articulate reply.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769731/elon-musk-billionaire-tax-stock-sell-off-ron-wyden-tweet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769731/elon-musk-billionaire-tax-stock-sell-off-ron-wyden-tweet</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T04:18:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T04:18:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Metal Gear games are temporarily disappearing from digital stores </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YvbxV_0BM9d4WWMAaRtZjPTqlc4=/0x60:1440x1020/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70110721/mgs2_screenshot_06.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Screenshot: Metal Gear Solid 2&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8np3SJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metal Gear Solid 2: Sons of Liberty&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater&lt;/em&gt; are disappearing from digital storefronts today, while Konami renews the licenses for the “historical archive footage” they contain, &lt;a href="https://www.konami.com/mg/jp/info/874/"&gt;their publisher has announced&lt;/a&gt;. Although the removals are temporary, Konami’s statement doesn’t give a timeline for when the games might return to affected storefronts. “We sincerely ask for your patience and understanding as we work towards making these products available for purchase once again,” the publisher said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EBFQjh"&gt;The removals affect various digital re-releases of the two games, which originally came out in 2001 and 2004. These include the PS3, Xbox 360, PlayStation Vita, and Nvidia Shield TV remasters of both games, the Nintendo 3DS version of &lt;em&gt;MGS3&lt;/em&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/25/21455139/metal-gear-solid-games-classics-pc-gog"&gt;GOG re-release of &lt;em&gt;MGS2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The games’ &lt;em&gt;HD Collection&lt;/em&gt; is also disappearing from the PlayStation Now streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RJHH5C"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We sincerely ask for your patience and understanding as we work towards making these products available for purchase once again”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oev8H2"&gt;While Konami hasn’t provided details on which historical footage is the problem, both &lt;em&gt;Metal Gear Solid 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt; use real-world footage in lengthy cutscenes to weave their stories together with 20th century historical events. This footage plays a significant role in establishing the atmosphere of both games, so it’s reassuring that Konami is going down the route of renewing licenses for the footage rather than attempting to strip it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gEdX35"&gt;Other games hit by similar licensing issues haven’t been so lucky. In 2012 &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2012/11/16/3652910/grand-theft-auto-vice-city-pulled-from-digital-pc-stores-due-to"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: Vice City &lt;/em&gt;was pulled from digital stores on PC&lt;/a&gt; over music licensing issues, and when it returned there were reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.cinemablend.com/games/GTA-Vice-City-Back-Steam-Nearly-10-Songs-Removed-50206.html"&gt;10 songs missing from its soundtrack&lt;/a&gt;. It was a similar story with the 2010 re-release of &lt;em&gt;Crazy Taxi&lt;/em&gt; on PS3 and Xbox 360, which &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2010/11/crazy-taxi-on-psn-xbla-when-the-music-stops/"&gt;lacked the music and real-world brands&lt;/a&gt; of the original.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769724/metal-gear-solid-2-3-sons-of-liberty-snake-eater-licensing-issues-digital-storefronts-removal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769724/metal-gear-solid-2-3-sons-of-liberty-snake-eater-licensing-issues-digital-storefronts-removal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
