<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-02T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Asus is going all-in on OLED laptops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A user uses the ProArt Studiobook 16 OLED, drawing on the touchpad with a stylus and operating the Asus Dial. The laptop sits on a small circular table with scattered pens to its left." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d_OdFkojGYAuNHjTnQQd4Rs2wJE=/0x0:1731x1154/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69808612/ProArt_Studiobook_16___Pro_16_OLED_H5600_W5600_Unbeatable_combination_of_CPU___GPU_power.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the new ProArt Studiobook 16 OLED.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lUxdpU"&gt;Asus has announced the ProArt StudioBook 16 OLED and the ProArt StudioBook 16 Pro OLED, two of the first 16-inch laptops to include 4K OLED HDR displays. Per Asus, the displays will cover 100 percent of the DCI-P3 color gamut and deliver a 1,000,000:1 contrast ratio (neither of which is uncommon among 4K OLED panels). The laptops target creative professionals who work in “color-critical” applications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXhRJP"&gt;The two devices come with an interesting new peripheral called the Asus Dial, a physical wheel on the left side of the keyboard deck. Users can map this controller to adjust various parameters in Adobe apps, which Asus says include After Effects, Photoshop, Photoshop Lightroom Classic, and Premiere Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="saEBG1"&gt;The StudioBook 16 and StudioBook 16 Pro will be available in North America in Q4, starting at $1,999.99 and $2,499.99, respectively. The difference between the two models is largely the chips. The Pro can come with an AMD Ryzen 5000 H-Series mobile processor or an Intel Xeon processor as well as an Nvidia RTX A2000 or A5000 GPU; the regular StudioBook can come with a Ryzen 5000 H-series or Intel Core i7 chip, and an Nvidia GeForce RTX 3070 or RTX 3060 GPUs. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The VivoBook Pro 14X on a white background, open. The screen displays a multicolor pastel background with the Asus VivoBook OLED on the right side." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OOVFmB1c24uamy8tcPxiIUVPCk4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22820800/VivoBook_Pro_14X___16X_OLED_M7600_DialPad.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here’s the VivoBook Pro 14X.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zR7k7j"&gt;Asus’ budget-oriented VivoBook line has also been outfitted with OLED screens, and some will have a digital version of the Asus Dial built into the touchpad. The 14-inch, 15-inch, and 16-inch models will start as low as $749.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LsRFp1"&gt;A new creator-oriented ZenBook Pro Duo 15 OLED is also coming in Q4 ($2,799.99), featuring Asus’ signature secondary touchscreen on the keyboard deck; a non-Duo version with just a single screen will also be available starting at $1,469.99. The Duo includes Intel processors up to a Core i9 and an RTX 3070 GPU; the standard model has Ryzen 5000 processors and an Nvidia RTX 3050 Ti GPU. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7OAKDZ"&gt;Even Asus’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22239215/asus-expertbook-b9450-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;ExpertBook business laptops&lt;/a&gt;, known for being mind-blowingly light, are getting OLED panels. The new ExpertBook B5 OLED and convertible B5 Flip OLED are both powered by 11th Gen Intel processors, with models starting at $1,299.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Y9pxn"&gt;Asus made a splash in the ultraportable market last year with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22538867/asus-zenbook-13-oled-review-amd-ryzen-specs-features-price"&gt;ZenBook 13 OLED&lt;/a&gt;, delivering a display technology that was once a luxury affair for &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202106AM030000001"&gt;as low as $800&lt;/a&gt;. After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242005/samsung-display-oled-laptop-production-90hz-14-inch"&gt;Samsung announced plans&lt;/a&gt; to mass-produce laptop-sized OLED panels this year, it was only a matter of time before we started seeing them implemented across smaller and more affordable models on a large scale. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22652549/asus-proart-studiobook-16-pro-oled-vivobook-expertbook"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22652549/asus-proart-studiobook-16-pro-oled-vivobook-expertbook</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Asus’s new Zenbook 14X is the latest thin and light laptop with an OLED screen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Asus Zenbook 14X facing away from the camera, angled to the right, half open, on a white background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MBZ2T4WQRXJkPYGrvIy9a290FiE=/0x334:2000x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69808604/Zenbook_14X_OLED_UX5400_Product_photo_Pine_Grey_Thin_and_light.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the Asus Zenbook 14X.&lt;/em&gt; | Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VLBXqs"&gt;Asus’s Zenbooks are known for being quite lightweight and quite affordable. But the company is adding another calling card to the line: OLED display technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LPGg5A"&gt;The new 14-inch Zenbook 14X OLED will be available with either a 4K OLED HDR display or a 2.8K OLED 90Hz display. Given those resolutions, either should be a significant step up in picture quality from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22538867/asus-zenbook-13-oled-review-amd-ryzen-specs-features-price"&gt;Zenbook 13 OLED&lt;/a&gt;, the ultraportable OLED model Asus released earlier this year. That device has an FHD OLED display (which was still quite vivid and bright in our testing). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qUgPpb"&gt;The Zenbook 14X OLED will cover 100 percent of the DCI-P3 color gamut and a 0.2ms response time. Asus claims it will emit “70 percent less harmful blue light than normal LCD”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uzGZa9"&gt;Screen aside, the 14X weighs 3.09 pounds and is 0.67 inches thick — decently portable, though there are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22239215/asus-expertbook-b9450-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;thinner and lighter 14-inchers out there&lt;/a&gt;. It can be configured with 11th-Gen Intel processors up to a Core i7, as well as 16GB of memory and 1TB of storage. Port selection includes Thunderbolt 4, HDMI 2.0, USB 3.2 Gen 2 Type-A, and a microSD reader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XiD5Lu"&gt;That all sounds good, but the big question mark is battery life. A high-resolution screen in a thin and light laptop can sometimes be a recipe for disaster there, as we’ve seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/6/21206151/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-review-android-laptop"&gt;time and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22528646/dell-xps-13-oled-2021-review-screen-specs-price"&gt;time again&lt;/a&gt;. The Zenbook 13 OLED lasted over 11 hours in our testing, which is excellent, but that screen has many fewer pixels to power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2sicLy"&gt;The Zenbook 14X OLED starts at $1,399.99 — a lot more than the Zenbook 13 OLED, which starts at $799. That’s not necessarily surprising, given the 14-incher’s larger and higher-resolution screen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus Zenbook Flip 14 OLED open facing the camera with the number pad illuminated. The screen displays a multicolored flower background with the Asus Zenbook OLED logo on the right side." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ssunf59CR7dkOYVw30ZwjLtDUhM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22821323/Zenbook_14_Flip_OLED_UP5401_Product_photo_4K_OLED_panel.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here’s the convertible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7IgVO4"&gt;There’s a convertible version of the 14X coming as well — the Zenbook 14 Flip OLED. That model has the same resolution options, and its touch display supports a “4096-pressure-level stylus”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J8lLwt"&gt;The new release follows &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242005/samsung-display-oled-laptop-production-90hz-14-inch"&gt;Samsung’s announcement in January&lt;/a&gt; that the company would start mass-producing 14-inch 90Hz OLED panels this year. The new Zenbook may be the first of many 14-inch OLED notebooks to hit shelves in the next few months; Samsung did not release a list of partners at the time of its announcement. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22652934/asus-zenbook-14x-oled-laptop-ultraportable-notebook-samsung-screen-display"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22652934/asus-zenbook-14x-oled-laptop-ultraportable-notebook-samsung-screen-display</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T11:41:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T11:41:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>TV streaming service Locast suspends service after court ruling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Locast NYC" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1aBSxiVLTUdlgDoaVNz617DmIfM=/0x21:1231x842/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69808484/Locast_nyc.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="02u16J"&gt;Locast has announced that it is suspending its TV streaming service starting today, following a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652988/broadcaster-victory-locast-abc-nbc-fox-cbs"&gt;court ruling earlier this week&lt;/a&gt; in a lawsuit from ABC, CBS, Fox, and NBC, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/31/20748677/locast-streaming-tv-lawsuit-abc-cbs-fox-nbc"&gt;jointly sued the nonprofit service&lt;/a&gt; shortly after it launched. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jTl5Mn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Broadcasters secure a win in their fight against scrappy TV streamer Locast","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652988/broadcaster-victory-locast-abc-nbc-fox-cbs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="zxXUE0"&gt;“As a non-profit, Locast was designed from the very beginning to operate in accordance with the strict letter of the law, but in response to the court’s recent rulings, with which we respectfully disagree, we are hereby suspending operations, effective immediately,” an email to Locast users sent out this morning reads. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w_XJy8yI3FE-inmk-6XHBeCGR9o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22822622/IMG_3197.PNG"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XDrvb2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18236704/locast-review-streaming-free-local-programming-tv"&gt;Locast was launched in 2019&lt;/a&gt; as an internet-based alternative to over-the-air television, rebroadcasting local, free over-the-air signals over the internet to users in those areas. Unlike Aereo, a similar service that was shut down after a lawsuit ruled it was violating copyright by rebroadcasting over-the-air networks online, Locast relied on a loophole, using its status as a nonprofit to retransmit broadcasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="euN6qJ"&gt;Locast didn’t technically charge a fee, although it frequently interrupted its free streams to request that users sign up for recurring $5 donations to keep the service running. But ABC, CBS, Fox, and NBC sued anyway, and it seems that the court has sided with the broadcasters, ruling earlier this week that Locast’s requests for donations exceeded “the actual and reasonable costs of maintaining and operating the service” and that it therefore didn’t meet the exception provided by copyright law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kyx3aS"&gt;Locast first responded by announcing on Wednesday evening it would simply remove the donation requests. “This means that anyone located in a market we serve who signs up for Locast will get the service without interruption, regardless of whether or not they donate,” the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="618lID"&gt;Today’s email, however, seems to have reversed that plan, with the service shutting down entirely. Locast has yet to announce what its plans for the future are or if the service will be returning in some form at a later date. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654047/locast-tv-streaming-over-the-air-court-ruling-shutdown"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654047/locast-tv-streaming-over-the-air-court-ruling-shutdown</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T11:14:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T11:14:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Moonfall is a disaster movie about the Moon falling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A0RiIe3Z-VBoZVDCe1ENE8QcA7w=/214x0:886x448/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69808346/Screen_Shot_2021_09_02_at_10.58.58_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OYykqu"&gt;You pretty much always know what to expect from a Roland Emmerich movie: namely, that a good chunk of the planet is going to be destroyed. The director of films like &lt;em&gt;2012&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Day After Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; is now taking that to its logical extreme with &lt;em&gt;Moonfall&lt;/em&gt;, a movie about the Moon... falling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SAgWCi"&gt;According to the synopsis, the movie is set when “a mysterious force knocks the Moon from its orbit around Earth and sends it hurtling on a collision course with life as we know it.” It stars Halle Berry as a NASA exec who seems to know how to stop it, but the only people who believe her are a former astronaut (Patrick Wilson) and a conspiracy theorist (John Bradley). “These unlikely heroes will mount an impossible last-ditch mission into space, leaving behind everyone they love, only to find out that our Moon is not what we think it is,” the description reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZNOMxS"&gt;Really, &lt;em&gt;Moonfall&lt;/em&gt; sounds like what would happen if you mashed a Hollywood disaster movie with &lt;em&gt;Destiny&lt;/em&gt; lore — which is to say, it sounds like a lot of fun. It’s expected to come to theaters on February 4th, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654021/moonfall-trailer-date-halle-berry-roland-emmerich"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654021/moonfall-trailer-date-halle-berry-roland-emmerich</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T10:59:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T10:59:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>FTC bans spyware app SpyFone, orders it to delete illegally harvested data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9xeRhYSV6GvSCjh_KN_vbeCpTCs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69808228/acastro_190204_1777_privacy_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The FTC has voted to ban SpyFone | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="y46sHr"&gt;On Wednesday, the Federal Trade Commission &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2021/09/ftc-bans-spyfone-and-ceo-from-surveillance-business"&gt;announced it had banned&lt;/a&gt; spyware maker SpyFone and its CEO Scott Zuckerman from the surveillance business. The commission called SpyFone a “stalkerware app company” that allegedly harvested and shared data about people’s movements, phone use, and online activity via a hidden device hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KWB70J"&gt;“The company’s apps sold real-time access to their secret surveillance, allowing stalkers and domestic abusers to stealthily track the potential targets of their violence,” the FTC said in a statement. “SpyFone’s lack of basic security also exposed device owners to hackers, identity thieves, and other cyber threats.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JxsbVg"&gt;In addition to the ban, the FTC ordered SpyFone to delete illegally harvested data and notify device owners when the app had been installed without their knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6qiiTm"&gt;“We must be clear eyed about the variety of threats that surveillance businesses pose,” FTC chair Lina Khan &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/linakhanFTC/status/1433435163707547649?s=20"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in a statement. “The FTC will be vigilant in its data security and privacy enforcement and will seek to vigorously protect the public from these dangers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H5GMRm"&gt;Stalkwerware apps, which are banned by app stores, can be used to track a user’s movements and online activities without their knowledge, sometimes marketed as ways to for “catching a cheating spouse” or, more subtly, to keep tabs on employees or children, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/07/coalition-against-stalkerware-expands-membership#breadcrumb:~:text=Stalkerware%20is%20the%20class%20of%20apps,that%20they%20are%20not%20being%20monitored."&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (EFF). Such apps can be used to perpetuate harassment and abuse, according to the &lt;a href="https://stopstalkerware.org/"&gt;Coalition Against Stalkerware&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WL1Lcr"&gt;SpyFone ran at a phone’s root level for several of its functions, the FTC said, including monitoring email and video chats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Incoq8"&gt;The app and its CEO are banned from “offering, promoting, selling, or advertising any surveillance app, service, or business,” according to the FTC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YzVren"&gt;The EFF praised the FTC’s order. “With the FTC now turning its focus to this industry, victims of stalkerware can begin to find solace in the fact that regulators are beginning to take their concerns seriously,” the foundation’s leadership wrote in &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/09/victory-federal-trade-commission-bans-stalkerware-company-conducting-business"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CqUnYT"&gt;The FTC board voted 5-0 to accept the consent order with the company. SpyFone, which is now doing business as Support King, did not admit or deny the FTC’s allegations, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/documents/cases/192_3003_spyfone_agreement_and_order_without_signatures_0.pdf"&gt;consent order agreement &lt;/a&gt;(pdf). Commissioner Rohit Chopra issued a separate &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/public-statements/2021/09/statement-commissioner-rohit-chopra-matter-spyfone"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;, saying the proposed order “in no way releases or absolves” the company or the CEO from potential criminal liability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rn6E2f"&gt;“While this action was worthwhile, I am concerned that the FTC will be unable to meaningfully crack down on the underworld of stalking apps using our civil enforcement authorities,” Chopra wrote. “I hope that federal and state enforcers examine the applicability of criminal laws, including the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act, the Wiretap Act, and other criminal laws, to combat illegal surveillance, including the use of stalkerware.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DswrE4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ARzIHm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653859/ftc-bans-spyware-app-spyfone-delete-data-stalkerware"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653859/ftc-bans-spyware-app-spyfone-delete-data-stalkerware</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T10:28:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T10:28:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Red Notice’s first trailer is full of explosions, car chases, art heists, and Ryan Reynolds quips</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6kcRfqafcnQjZC_GkJr4IMR7LEc=/326x51:1294x696/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69808080/RN_FirstLook_V220210707_4521_1pex5jr.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Frank Masi/NETFLIX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ToBATd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T6l3mM7AWew"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Notice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;Netflix’s next big action movie swing, has gotten its first trailer, showing off the fast (and dare I say, &lt;em&gt;furious&lt;/em&gt;) antics of Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson. He plays the FBI’s top profiler as he hunts down the world’s two most wanted criminals — played by Ryan Reynolds and Gal Gadot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3XBIRa"&gt;Based on the trailer, it seems Johnson’s Agent John Hartley actually catches Reynolds’ character, Nolan Booth — dubbed “the world’s greatest art thief” — fairly early on, forcing the two to partner up in order to catch Gadot’s character, “The Bishop.” She’s described as “the world’s most wanted art thief,” which is apparently a different thing than being the world’s greatest art thief. This is also, broadly, the plot of &lt;em&gt;Hobbs &amp;amp; Shaw,&lt;/em&gt; a movie that Johnson and Reynolds both were actually in. Gadot is also a &lt;em&gt;Fast&lt;/em&gt; franchise alum, which seems fitting. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nvOaiJO8s1lmT_t7P8Jt447yvbI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22822434/unnamed.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="j8OsEo"&gt;The film is named after &lt;a href="https://www.interpol.int/en/How-we-work/Notices/Red-Notices"&gt;Interpol’s actually real Red Notices&lt;/a&gt;, which are slightly less interesting international wanted notices that — in what I assume are almost all cases — do not actually allow for The Rock to relentlessly chase you around the globe in daring action sequences. The second does seem like a more entertaining concept for a movie, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2P9mfj"&gt;As one might expect from a big-budget heist film, &lt;em&gt;Red Notice&lt;/em&gt; will also feature considerable amounts of globe-trotting action, black tie dinner parties, rooftop chases, car chases, and endless amounts of lighthearted quipping (particularly where Reynolds is concerned). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOgzkK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Notice&lt;/em&gt; is also part of Netflix’s push toward building out its original blockbuster-level films (and maybe franchises). And by putting Johnson, Gadot, and Reynolds — three of Hollywood’s biggest stars — into a single action movie, there’s a good chance that it might be Netflix’s next big hit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYE3lu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Notice&lt;/em&gt; will stream on Netflix on November 12th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653894/red-notice-first-trailer-art-heist-actors-date-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653894/red-notice-first-trailer-art-heist-actors-date-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T10:05:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T10:05:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s new Big Brain Academy is like Mario Party with brainteasers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pj48Y0XPB7VtH4I0jzNqSaSsZrM=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69808019/bigbrain.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XCFFjJ"&gt;Nintendo sneakily announced &lt;em&gt;Big Brain Academy: Brain vs. Brain&lt;/em&gt;, a new educational puzzle game for the Switch that sees the revival of a franchise that previously appeared on the DS handheld (and later ported to &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/big-brain-academy-wii-u/"&gt;Wii U’s Virtual Console&lt;/a&gt;). It’ll release on December 3rd, 2021 &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/big-brain-academy-brain-vs-brain-switch/"&gt;for $29.99&lt;/a&gt;, and in it you’ll race through puzzle mini games and challenges to flex your smarts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MtB9qI"&gt;In addition to single player modes, the game will support couch multiplayer and online play. Nintendo is even implementing a ghost data system, so you can test your skills against people who have gotten higher scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BjsY20"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BigBrainAcademy?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#BigBrainAcademy&lt;/a&gt;: Brain vs. Brain is coming to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NintendoSwitch?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NintendoSwitch&lt;/a&gt; on 12/03! Flex your brainpower or engage in a battle of brains with your family and friends!   &lt;a href="https://t.co/lVavwzxbzd"&gt;pic.twitter.com/lVavwzxbzd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1433414764219207683?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QMB00v"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Big Brain Academy&lt;/em&gt; actually looks like a fun game to play with family, as it lets each player experience the game at their preferred difficulty level. Really, it’s just nice to see these kinds of casual games continue to release on the Switch. Along with titles like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/29/18522564/picross-s3-review-puzzle-games-nintendo-switch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picross&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21280837/nintendo-switch-clubhouse-games-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clubhouse Games&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20917908/nintendo-switch-ring-fit-adventure-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/16/21292655/nintendo-jump-rope-challenge-free-exercise-game-no-equipment-switch-eshop"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jump Rope Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and others, Nintendo keeps proving that the Switch is a console fit for unique experiences, too, not just core games.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653863/nintendo-big-brain-academy-vs-switch-multiplayer-release-date-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653863/nintendo-big-brain-academy-vs-switch-multiplayer-release-date-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fujifilm just announced its cheapest medium format camera yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IkPlWpojhBtkgP5MoEK_jp1fn2s=/0x101:2407x1706/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69807968/fujifuji.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Fujifilm&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4Jzkho"&gt;Today is Fujifilm’s September X Summit event, and the company has announced a slew of new hardware including several cameras and lenses for both the GFX and X systems. Leading the way is the new GFX 50S II, the company’s latest medium format camera. More importantly, at $3,999 body-only, it’s Fujifilm’s cheapest way into the GFX system yet. For comparison, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251933/fujifilm-gfx-100s-102-megapixel-medium-format-price-specs-date"&gt;the GFX 100S&lt;/a&gt; costs $5,999 and the GFX 50S still goes for $5,499. So dropping under $4,000 could mean big things for the lineup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNKTG8"&gt;The GFX 50S II has a 51.4-megapixel sensor that’s 1.7x larger than what you’d get in a full-frame camera, 5-axis in-body image stabilization good for 6.5 stops, improved autofocus (compared to the 50S), and a body that’s the same size as the GFX 100S. At 1.98 pounds, that’s rather compact for all the advanced photography power it wields. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3AF0jV"&gt;With the inclusion of IBIS, Fujifilm says the GFX 50S II “presents new opportunities in the way conventional medium format digital cameras are used” since you’ve got more leeway to shoot with it handheld instead of mostly keeping it mounted to a tripod. However, one tradeoff with this sensor is that it depends on contrast-detection autofocus instead of the more capable phase-detect approach on the GFX 100S and many other Fujifilm cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bL-63r3i3H_iDXGCwkKhMamuUJU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22822258/600022316_PT13_Image_GFX50S_II_top_GF35_70.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Fujifilm&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The GFX 50S II body is largely identical to the GFX 100S.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="niwH5a"&gt;Since the body style closely matches the GFX 100S, the same is true of the camera’s dials and controls, which are basically identical between the two. Carried over is the DSLR-style PASM dial, as well as a 1.8-inch monochrome display on the top plate that can be used for other settings and to display your chosen parameters. The main 3.2-inch LCD tilts in three directions for high- and low-angle shooting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwWmmp"&gt;The GFX 50S II offers 19 of Fujifilm’s film simulations, including the “nostalgic neg” that debuted on the GFX 100S, and a “Pixel Shift Multi Shot” mode that combines 16 RAW images into an ultra-high-res 200MP DNG file. Fujifilm will also sell the camera as a kit with the GF 35-70mm f/4.5-5.6 WR lens for $4,499. It’s expected to be available in late October.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T87ybg3oYi0uYIDEO2L9U4Qfh_Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22822256/16759615_PT10_Image_X_T30ii_left_diagonal_15_45_black.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Fujifilm&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The X-T30 II is an extremely similar camera to its predecessor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KaqMi8"&gt;Fujifilm is also introducing the new X-T30 II, which is a very modest update over the original that mostly brings the benefit of updated firmware and software features. It also gains additional memory (for improved performance) and a higher-resolution 1.68-million-dot LCD compared to the 1.04M-dot X-T30. It still uses the same 26.4-megapixel X-Trans CMOS sensor — and no, it doesn’t toss in IBIS or anything unexpected. Again, the most important upgrade is that the X-T30 II will be brought up to speed on firmware and film simulations. Fujifilm didn’t even bother issuing a standalone press release for this camera. The X-T30 II will be sold sans battery charger for $899 body-only. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kGWKhz"&gt;As for the company’s latest glass, the new lenses include the aforementioned GF 35-70mm f/4.5-5.6 WR, which Fujifilm describes as “the perfect gateway” into the detail, depth of field, and other benefits of its medium format cameras. It’s coming in November for $999.95. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ToJjVmoK7ff9qq3hsdy8kUR1Z1g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22822274/16719201_PT11_Image_XF33mmF1.4_left_diagonal_X_T4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Fujinon XF33mm f/1.4 lens shown on an X-T4 body.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6S6ZwF"&gt;But the X Series also has some exciting lens additions: Fujifilm has announced two new f/1.4 primes. The XF33mm R LM WR has a weather-resistant build, and the company says it “ushers in a new era of optical brilliance and performance for X Series cameras and lenses.” Since it’s equivalent to 50mm in the 35mm film format, Fujifilm thinks this is a perfect all-around lens. The 15-element lens measures 2.89 inches and weighs 13 ounches. It’s coming in October for $799.95. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G8Un2D"&gt;Not to be left out is the XF23mm R LM WR: this weather-resistant lens is being positioned as “suited to discerning street, wedding, editorial, and documentary photographers.” It has now has a closer minimum focus distance of 19 centimeters, as well. Curiously, Fujifilm says this one is “designed to support anticipated future camera sensors that offer further enhanced resolution.” Specifically, it can resolve sensors up to 40 megapixels. It’ll be available in November for $899.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653712/fujifilm-gfx50sii-xt30ii-xf33-xf23-announced-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653712/fujifilm-gfx50sii-xt30ii-xf33-xf23-announced-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T09:22:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T09:22:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp fined $267 million for breaching EU privacy law</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pM8MD0DIYB8vNYDereRZpI7NiDE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69807796/acastro_210119_1777_whatsapp_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rbTyQB"&gt;Facebook-owned WhatsApp has been fined €225 million ($267 million) for breaking the European Union’s data privacy rules. &lt;a href="https://www.dataprotection.ie/en/news-media/press-releases/data-protection-commission-announces-decision-whatsapp-inquiry"&gt;Ireland’s Data Protection Commission&lt;/a&gt; (DPC) announced the decision in an &lt;a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/system/files/2021-09/edpb_bindingdecision_202101_ie_sa_whatsapp_redacted_en.pdf"&gt;89-page summary&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), noting that WhatsApp did not properly inform EU citizens how it handles their personal data, including how it shares that information with its parent company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJynjX"&gt;WhatsApp has been ordered to make updates to its already lengthy &lt;a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/legal/updates/privacy-policy/?lang=en"&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; and change how it notifies users about sharing their data. This will bring it into compliance with Europe’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which governs how tech companies gather and use data in the EU. GDPR came into effect in May of 2018, and WhatsApp was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/25/17393766/facebook-google-gdpr-lawsuit-max-schrems-europe"&gt;one of the first companies&lt;/a&gt; to be hit with privacy lawsuits under the regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6MQpq5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Everything you need to know about GDPR","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/28/17172548/gdpr-compliance-requirements-privacy-notice"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="xcxVR7"&gt;A WhatsApp spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company will appeal the decision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rNlSjN"&gt;“WhatsApp is committed to providing a secure and private service. We have worked to ensure the information we provide is transparent and comprehensive and will continue to do so,” the spokesperson said. “We disagree with the decision today regarding the transparency we provided to people in 2018 and the penalties are entirely disproportionate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qfi9Wd"&gt;The decision by the DPC began with an investigation in 2018 and is the second-largest fine levied under GDPR regulations. In July this year, Amazon was fined a record $887 million for breaching the EU privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653747/whatsapp-fine-amount-europe-gdpr-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22653747/whatsapp-fine-amount-europe-gdpr-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-02T09:22:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-02T09:22:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best budget laptop of 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: HP Envy x360 13" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VrLlEr12ymqvrvZXaKwFhmZDmjk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69807794/mchin_200705_4086_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’ve got the best cheap laptop for you, no matter your budget.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The best cheap laptops for video editing, gaming, and more&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="3v5Ons"&gt;If you’re shopping for the best cheap laptop of 2021, the question to ask is: what’s most important, and what are you willing to sacrifice? Even the best cheap laptops aren’t perfect in every area — they have some strengths but cut corners to achieve their price tags. You can almost certainly find a budget laptop with a touchscreen, a premium-looking chassis, an HDMI port, a backlit keyboard, or stylus support, but you may need to consider which of those features you want the most, and which you can go without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zqLems"&gt;Our pick for the best cheap laptop of 2021 is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21319378/hp-envy-x360-2020-amd-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Envy x360 13&lt;/a&gt;. We feel that the Envy has build quality, performance, and battery life that surpass those of many premium laptops. But we’ve tested dozens of systems in the sub-$800 range, and we’ve got a number of additional models on this list from Lenovo, Acer, Samsung, HP, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jVG16P"&gt;Our other picks for the best cheap laptop of 2021 include the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21262694/lenovo-chromebook-duet-review-tablet-chromebook-chrome-os-price"&gt;Lenovo Chromebook Duet&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22451261/acer-chromebook-spin-713-2021-review"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt;. Many of these laptops also appear on our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21369381/best-student-laptops-school-high-college"&gt;best student laptop&lt;/a&gt; lists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sPoJxi"&gt;Many of our picks for the best cheap laptop of 2021 are currently Chromebooks. We believe that Chromebooks are, in many cases, the best-value option for shoppers seeking a laptop under $500 and tend to offer better specs, features, and build quality than most Windows laptops at that price point. We hope to add more Windows laptops under $500 to this page in the future and are keeping a close eye on those releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="4mn8ET"&gt;Best Cheap Laptops 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="7TNgC3"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: HP Envy x360 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hsUCwGNgpPr89jhL19Qz7czbcIc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20069602/mchin_200705_4086_0001.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photography by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP Envy x360 13 is the best cheap laptop of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oTToOm"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21319378/hp-envy-x360-2020-amd-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Envy x360 13&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rE8ByG"&gt;The best cheap laptop of 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="r62WQ4"&gt;HP’s Envy x360 13, &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeBestCheapLaptop090121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2FConfigureView%3FurlLangId%3D%26catalogId%3D10051%26langId%3D-1%26storeId%3D10151%26catEntryId%3D3074457345619562324%26quantity%3D1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently available for $699&lt;/a&gt;, is the best budget laptop you can buy under $800. With a high-quality and sturdy convertible build, it looks like a device that should cost twice its price. It has plenty of other great features as well, including a really excellent keyboard and a bright, colorful screen. It’s also exceptional on the inside. Thanks to its AMD Ryzen processor, the system delivers all-day battery life and very smooth performance — it can even handle some light gaming. (Intel options are available as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ox216u"&gt;We have some minor complaints about the Envy, of course. The screen is 16:9, which is a cramped aspect ratio for multitasking. Our test unit had a somewhat limited port selection (notably, missing Thunderbolt and HDMI support) and came with some bloatware preinstalled. But none of these are deal-breakers at the Envy’s price point. Overall, budget shoppers will want for very little with this machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Lfy32d"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10730286"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="WtXCCS"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: Lenovo Chromebook Duet" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sqrhaerF8C3afzjqOmP51SG-8wI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19978536/mchin_200512_4018_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lenovo Chromebook Duet is one of the best Chromebooks you can buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="O7mXrt"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21262694/lenovo-chromebook-duet-review-tablet-chromebook-chrome-os-price"&gt;Lenovo Chromebook Duet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="N7xEV5"&gt;The best laptop under $500&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hyeIry"&gt;If you’re looking for an absurdly cheap Chromebook that absolutely gets the job done, you should definitely be looking at the $219 Lenovo Chromebook Duet. The Duet is a 10-inch aluminum alloy Chrome OS tablet that comes with a kickstand and keyboard cover. It looks sturdy and classy, and it can easily function as either a tablet or a PC. But you’re not compromising &lt;em&gt;too &lt;/em&gt;much on performance for this device’s tiny size; as long as you’re not running dozens of tabs and apps, you should be fine. And we got over 11 hours of battery life in our testing, making it one of the longest-lasting Chromebooks we’ve seen in the past year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHlVCe"&gt;The main thing to know about the Chromebook Duet is that the screen is quite small — just 10.1 inches. That’s a fine size for a young student (especially with the touch capability) and for an adult’s secondary device for note-taking, Netflixing, and the like, but it’s not an ideal size for a primary work device unless you’re fine with quite a bit of squinting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aB9GyO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10730298"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ScvLyD"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: Acer Chromebook Spin 713" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1sG7NaRy6OP-4keVOTxJQ2YnRg8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22539424/mchin_20190815_4597_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Acer Chromebook Spin 713 is the clamshell Chromebook to buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SoHxJX"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21355769/acer-chromebook-spin-713-review-best-chromebook-to-buy"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="aOmcws"&gt;The best budget laptop with Chrome OS &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="N34v09"&gt;If you’d prefer a more traditional Chromebook with a clamshell form factor, the $699 Acer Chromebook Spin 713 is an affordable option that’s all-around excellent. It has a gorgeous 3:2 display that delivers a sharp picture and bright, vibrant colors with plenty of vertical space. The screen alone would make the Chromebook Spin 713 a standout, but it has a number of other strengths as well, including a great keyboard, all-day battery life, and a comprehensive port selection, including an HDMI, in addition to USB-C, USB-A, and a microSD slot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="N5isRn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10730313"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="83mqXY"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: Asus Chromebook Detachable CM3" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K1zNh5YWec5wp4VCQnyX4ZX-DGM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22646167/mchin_20190829_4618_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus Chromebook Detachable CM3 is the best cheap laptop with a built-in stylus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SSaLnR"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22526743/asus-chromebook-detachable-cm3-review-tablet-chromebook-chrome-os-price"&gt;Asus Chromebook Detachable CM3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IOuDKK"&gt;The best cheap laptop with a stylus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="iQA7Ph"&gt;If you like the Duet’s size and detachable form factor but are willing to spend on something a bit more upscale, you may find the Asus Chromebook Detachable CM3 to be a better choice. Like the Duet, the CM3 is a 10.5-inch 16:10 Chrome OS tablet with a fabric cover, kickstand, and detachable screen. But the CM3’s kickstand folds multiple ways: you can crease it lengthwise to stand the tablet up like a laptop or fold it the short way and stand the tablet up horizontally. Plus, it comes with a built-in USI stylus and roomy keys with a surprising amount of travel. Battery life was also quite impressive: we averaged close to 13 hours of continuous work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUYikQ"&gt;Where the CM3 lags a bit behind the Duet (and other cheap laptops you may try) is the power. Its MediaTek processor can be a bit sluggish compared to more pricier offerings. But the CM3 still offers a surprising number of perks for its sub-$400 price and makes a great student driver or secondary device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AlaXDH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10639759"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VBkIar"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: HP Pavilion Aero 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3mZoRLqwnC66HhxPhjJER8ewwB4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22785988/mchin_191108_47150009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP Pavilion Aero 13 is a 13-inch powerhouse that weighs almost nothing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VO4h4j"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22632318/hp-pavilion-aero-13-2021-amd-review"&gt;HP Pavilion Aero 13&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lYrZ3f"&gt;The best thin-and-light laptop under $1000&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="o8zBHM"&gt;If you’re looking for a budget Windows laptop that’s thinner and lighter than the Envy x360 while delivering similar category-topping performance, the $669 HP Pavilion Aero 13 is a good choice for you. It has a powerful eight-core Ryzen processor, which is one of the fastest processors for thin and light laptops that you can get. Not only does it perform well, but it’s also unbelievably light at just 2.1 pounds, and it comes with a blindingly bright 16:10 screen. It’s a standout in battery life, too — I averaged almost 11 hours of continuous work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DOWROI"&gt;HP did have to cut a few corners to achieve those benefits at this price point. The audio on our model wasn’t great, and the device shipped with some cheap bloatware installed. But the Pavilion Aero 13 is excellent in almost every other way, and it won’t disappoint if you’re looking for a functional, cheap Windows PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5ppnov"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10730332"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="bYyo2Q"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uAsoWZ0lsulyjGcUDGn9-euXFkY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22333696/akrales_210226_4438_0118.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 is the reddest Chromebook you can buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UcXjY2"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22301481/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-review"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Ucqsb1"&gt;An affordable laptop with a bold look&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="pT23AG"&gt;If you’re looking for an affordable Chromebook that stands out from the crowd, the $549 Galaxy Chromebook 2 should be on your list. It comes in a bold “fiesta red” color (as well as a regular gray, if you prefer to blend in). It’s a touchscreen convertible with stylus support (though the stylus isn’t included). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QIDME"&gt;On top of the design, the Galaxy Chromebook 2 includes an excellent QLED panel, which is one of the best displays we’ve ever seen on a Chromebook. You also get a solid keyboard, decent battery life (we averaged 7 hours and 21 minutes of continuous work), and a port selection that includes two USB-C ports, a microSD slot, and a headphone jack. It’s easily one of the best Chromebooks you can buy and one of the best cheap laptops as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fuAuGb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10698797"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="O9X0Vl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: Microsoft Surface Go 2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/35fxOxuusBrGJD8DhRUP9qa9UI0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19947636/microsoft_surface_go_2_DSC00140_dbohn.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Microsoft Surface Go 2 is one of the best cheap laptops of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wWYRLK"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21259805/microsoft-surface-go-2-review-windows-tablet-speed-intel-processor-price"&gt;Surface Go 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="w7TWDY"&gt;The best cheap laptop for Surface fans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="9t4Ji3"&gt;The $399 Surface Go 2 is a 10.5-inch tablet that’s about the size of a regular iPad. You’ll have to buy the keyboard cover separately, but the overall package is still quite affordable if you’re buying a lower-priced model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hPLGr"&gt;You can configure the Surface Go 2 with a Pentium Gold or Core m3 processor. Those aren’t the fanciest or most powerful processors, but the system should still be adequate for your streaming and browsing needs, especially if you only need it to do one task at a time. It can run any Windows app, it’s easy to carry around, and it makes a solid secondary computer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zwycZg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10730365"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="fGPx7P"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: Acer Swift 3" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1QBNYWhrZZb9CIlYM5OavCjRHyw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21786687/mchin_181113_4146_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Acer Swift 3 is one of the best college laptops you can buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cIbAld"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21377208/acer-swift-3-review-2020-14-inch-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Acer Swift 3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nxYz9i"&gt;The best budget laptop for students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="DeUYiZ"&gt;Many of the best cheap laptops might be good choices for high school and college students, but the Acer Swift 3’s exceptionally durable build makes it an excellent choice for backpack-battering and dining hall spills. Its 14-inch screen also gives you more room for homework multitasking than some of the 13-inch machines here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GVxnSd"&gt;But the highlight of the Swift 3 is its Ryzen 4000 processors. We tested a model with a Ryzen 7 4700U, which did an excellent job handling our daily multitasking workload, and delivered seven-hour battery life as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YWSkuR"&gt;On the outside, the Swift 3 isn’t the thinnest or most beautiful laptop you can buy, but it’s a solid performer in most areas. It has all kinds of ports, including USB-C, USB-A, and an HDMI. The backlit keyboard has a nice click to it and has a reliable integrated fingerprint reader as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XUPL4K"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10351151"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="H3Jm5p"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Cheap Laptop 2021: Lenovo Yoga C740" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4kRdC1NMAi2vFVZ2UX_r7zJ9lYs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19768316/awhite_20200304_3921_0087.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Avery White for The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lenovo Yoga C740 is a sturdy aluminum laptop for any use case.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="m9IrEq"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/11/21174917/lenovo-yoga-c740-review-laptop-specs-features-price-2-in-1-convertible"&gt;Lenovo Yoga C740&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="TA1Mem"&gt;A cheap laptop with standout build&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HqEdaD"&gt;The Yoga C740 is as straightforward as a laptop can get. It has a sturdy aluminum build and perfectly fine 10th Gen Intel processors. We were pleasantly surprised by the device’s audio — the upward-firing speakers on the sides of the keyboard deliver a nice surround-sound experience. The keyboard and touchpad are both quite comfortable to use. There’s not much to complain about and not much to enthusiastically praise — if you’re looking for a sub-$800 Windows laptop with a well-made aluminum chassis and a sturdy frame, you’re looking for the Yoga. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VGHm6c"&gt;The C740 is a year old now, but that means you can get it at very affordable prices. We’re looking forward to reviewing its successor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/18/21373719/lenovo-yoga-7i-6-convertible-laptops-intel-amd-processors-windows"&gt;Yoga 7i&lt;/a&gt;, shortly in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="miOdsi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10730374"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22652565/best-cheap-laptops"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22652565/best-cheap-laptops</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
