<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-14T11:01:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T11:01:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T11:01:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Russia’s FSB says it has taken down REvil hacker group at US request</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Hacker (STOCK)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QXFL5uohYJNwkZ3GS04VJMVL1RI=/3x0:1097x729/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70388599/hacker-stock1_2040.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nQYPPO"&gt;Russia’s domestic security service, the FSB, has &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/russia-arrests-dismantles-revil-hacking-group-us-request-report-2022-01-14/"&gt;arrested numerous members of the REvil hacking group&lt;/a&gt; at the request of the US government, the FSB said on Friday. The move, which marks an unusual degree of cooperation between Russian and US agencies, comes amid increasingly aggressive Russian military activity on the Ukrainian border and tense diplomacy as the United States attempts to prevent armed conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1jXZn"&gt;Reporting by the Russian &lt;em&gt;Interfax&lt;/em&gt; news agency claimed that the FSB &lt;a href="https://www.interfax.ru/russia/815466"&gt;seized 426 million rubles&lt;/a&gt; ($5.6 million) in a raid against 14 members of the group, along with more than $600,000 worth of cryptocurrency and 20 luxury cars. The FSB told &lt;em&gt;Interfax&lt;/em&gt; that it was acting at the request of US authorities and had informed them of the results of the operation. The operation effectively dismantled REvil as an entity, the FSB said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1MzfNS"&gt;The Biden administration has long &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/10/13/politics/white-house-ransomware-meeting/index.html"&gt;called on Russia to do more&lt;/a&gt; to crack down on ransomware gangs operating within the country, though with limited success until now. Analysts have tied Russian groups to extensive ransomware operations in Europe and the US, often without interference from local law enforcement. With no extradition treaty in place, the Russian government has been &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/11/russia-and-nearby-states-are-origin-of-most-ransomware-says-uk-cyber-chief"&gt;accused of sheltering cybercriminals&lt;/a&gt; provided they do not attack domestic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ulrtqD"&gt;US agencies have intensified their pursuit of REvil after the FBI linked it to the hack that shut down the Colonial Pipeline in May 2021. REvil was also behind a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463621/jbs-cyberattack-russia-largest-meat-supplier"&gt;cyberattack against meat supplier JBS&lt;/a&gt;, also in May 2021, which shut down the company’s meat processing plants across the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ealgdI"&gt;One alleged member of REvil was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22770701/revil-ransomware-arrest-kaseya-crypto-europol-cybersecurity"&gt;arrested by Polish authorities&lt;/a&gt; in November 2021 after being indicted by the US. According to reporting in &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, a source close to the case said that the FSB would not hand over REvil group members with Russian citizenship to the United States after the latest arrests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vTAFiC"&gt;The US Department of Justice had not responded to a request for comment by time of publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gKHSPX"&gt;The news of the operation against REvil comes on the same day that the government of Ukraine suffered a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883400/ukraine-government-websites-cyber-attack-russia"&gt;major cyber attack&lt;/a&gt;. Many government websites were disabled Friday morning, with spokespeople for both the Ukrainian government and the EU pointing the finger toward Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xlW5IK"&gt;As the US continues to negotiate with Russia over its military activities on the Ukraine border, the FSB’s actions could be an offering linked to the talks, said Nina Jankowicz, a global fellow at the Wilson Center and specialist in Russian affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aveygx"&gt;“The FSB’s takedown of REvil might be Russia trying to throw the US a bone after negotiations on the mounting tensions on Ukraine’s border this week,” Jankowicz said. “But it doesn’t mean much when the rubber hits the road — Russia still has over 100,000 troops on the border and this morning, Ukraine’s government experienced a massive cyberattack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="odd2MH"&gt;Though the Ukraine cyberattack has not yet been attributed to Russia, Jankowicz said, the mode of operation was similar to attacks carried out in advance of conflict in Georgia in 2008 and the annexation of the Crimean peninsula in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883675/russia-fsb-revil-hacker-group-ransomware-us-request-fbi-doj"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883675/russia-fsb-revil-hacker-group-ransomware-us-request-fbi-doj</id>
    <author>
      <name>Corin Faife</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Clean energy tech needs to be designed for recycling, experts say  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Wind energy" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dBOu-No5hJvUkNqUS303y_j3qZU=/0x124:5020x3471/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70388572/1237396065.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Patrick Pleul/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JeXA0B"&gt;Companies like Apple and Samsung aren’t the only ones making high-tech devices that are hard to take apart and recycle. So are the manufacturers of critical clean energy technologies like solar panels, wind turbines, and electric vehicle (EV) batteries — and unlike the consumer tech industry, which is &lt;a href="https://grist.org/technology/apple-finally-admits-its-products-are-difficult-to-repair/"&gt;slowly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://grist.org/accountability/bowing-to-investors-microsoft-will-make-its-devices-easier-to-fix/"&gt;starting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787336/apple-right-to-repair-self-service-diy-reason-microsoft"&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22832895/dell-luna-sustainable-laptop-concept-repairability-recyclable-environment"&gt;reverse&lt;/a&gt; some of its unsustainable design practices, there isn’t much being done about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ecafo"&gt;Batteries, solar panels, and wind turbines are all essential tools for combating climate change. However, these technologies take considerable energy and resources to make, and the best way to ensure we can keep making more of them sustainably is to recycle those resources at end of life. But today, clean energy recycling is limited by design choices that hinder disassembly, including the widespread use of ultra-strong adhesives. That could change, experts say, if the companies manufacturing supersized batteries for EVs and rare earth magnets for wind turbines shifted toward new adhesives that can be “de-bonded” using light, heat, magnetic fields, and more, or toward glue-free designs.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RSfdHp"&gt;“Design for recycling hasn’t really come to that market yet,” says &lt;a href="https://www2.le.ac.uk/departments/chemistry/people/academic-staff/andrew_p_abbott"&gt;Andy Abbott&lt;/a&gt;, a professor of chemistry at the University of Leicester who recently co-authored a &lt;a href="https://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlepdf/2021/gc/d1gc03306a"&gt;review paper&lt;/a&gt; on de-bondable adhesives and their potential use in clean energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvil54"&gt;Instead, Abbott says, manufacturers tend to “overengineer” their products for safety and durability. Take EV batteries, which are composed of anywhere from dozens to thousands of individual, hermetically-sealed cells glued together inside modules and packs. While the heavy use of adhesives helps ensure the batteries don’t fall apart on the road, it can make them incredibly difficult to take apart in order to &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/a-recycling-renegade-is-out-of-prison-and-ready-to-tack-1840417556"&gt;repurpose individual cells&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nationalgeographic.com%2Fenvironment%2Farticle%2Felectric-vehicles-take-off-recycling-ev-batteries&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22882287%2Fclean-energy-tech-design-recycling" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recycle critical metals&lt;/a&gt; like lithium, cobalt, and nickel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="icRKiM"&gt;“At the moment, because everything is bonded together, lots of batteries end up getting shredded,” study co-author &lt;a href="https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/staff/profiles/physics/harper-gavin.aspx"&gt;Gavin Harper&lt;/a&gt;, an EV battery recycling expert at the University of Birmingham in the UK, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The material is mixed together, which makes subsequent steps in the recycling process more complicated.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lbyeAM"&gt;Solar panels and wind turbines are also designed for durability in ways that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/29/22857157/solar-recycling-new-better-method"&gt;make recycling challenging&lt;/a&gt;. Most solar panels are composed of silicon cells coated in layers of polymer sealants that bind the cells to weatherproof glass and plastic covers. While this electronic sandwich design means the panels can spend decades on a rooftop exposed to the elements, the adhesives and sealants used throughout the panel make it hard to separate the components cleanly at end of life. The rare earth magnets inside wind turbine generators, meanwhile, are coated in resins and glues that can create significant contamination for anyone looking to reclaim and reuse the material. A single wind turbine can contain &lt;a href="https://ewi.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/2-Major-Industrial-Uses-S.pdf"&gt;hundreds of pounds&lt;/a&gt; of rare earth elements, and demand for these metals is &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-019-0252-z"&gt;set to skyrocket&lt;/a&gt; as the world builds more EVs and more turbines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LljPPz"&gt;Abbott says manufacturers are just starting to wake up to the fact that recovering the critical materials inside clean energy technologies is important for shoring up long-term supplies — and that new design approaches are needed to facilitate that. “Really only in the last 18 months or so, that conversation has started to raise its head,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F5dF3f"&gt;Abbott and Harper’s new paper lays out a number of potential paths toward a more recyclable clean tech sector. While solar manufactures are unlikely to eliminate adhesives any time soon, the authors suggest manufacturers could move toward adhesives and sealant materials that can be unstuck using chemicals, magnetic fields, or even a high-frequency sonic pulse. For wind turbine magnets, an adhesive that loses its stickiness in the presence of a strong magnetic field won’t work, but one that could be melted away using heat, or de-bonded when exposed to ultraviolet light, might be viable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YwlWsR"&gt;Designs that use fewer adhesives could help improve EV battery recycling immensely. If batteries were easier to take apart down to the individual cells, Harper says it could make it easier to recover critical materials inside the cathode, including lithium, which is rarely recycled today. And at least one company is already commercializing an adhesive-free battery design: In 2020, Chinese battery manufacturer BYD announced a new “&lt;a href="https://www.automotiveworld.com/news-releases/byd-blade-battery-set-to-revolutionise-ev-market/"&gt;Blade Battery&lt;/a&gt;,” which features long, skinny cells that &lt;a href="https://www.dcbel.energy/2021/08/23/next-gen-batteries-leading-the-green-energy-charge/"&gt;clip into the main battery pack&lt;/a&gt; without the use of glue. “In terms of disassembly, it’s trivial,” Abbott says. “The cells just clip out.”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KnUuOS"&gt;For EV battery makers who don’t want to ditch glue-based designs, there are “a huge number of methods out there” that could lead to a more de-bondable adhesive, says Jenny Baker, a battery storage expert at Swansea University in the UK. The challenge, in her view, will be developing adhesives that can be unstuck quickly, in a process that can be done on an industrial scale.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ibEWJ5"&gt;“The thing is now to take some of the science and try and move it into the engineering side so that we can get it ready for really large-scale recycling because we know there’s going to be a lot of these batteries coming through,” Baker says. Based on &lt;a href="https://iea.blob.core.windows.net/assets/24d5dfbb-a77a-4647-abcc-667867207f74/TheRoleofCriticalMineralsinCleanEnergyTransitions.pdf"&gt;projected growth&lt;/a&gt; in EV and energy storage markets, Harper &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nationalgeographic.com%2Fenvironment%2Farticle%2Felectric-vehicles-take-off-recycling-ev-batteries&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22882287%2Fclean-energy-tech-design-recycling" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;has estimated&lt;/a&gt; that by 2040, there could be about 8 million metric tons of battery waste in need of recycling around the world. A &lt;a href="https://www.irena.org/-/media/Files/IRENA/Agency/Publication/2016/IRENA_IEAPVPS_End-of-Life_Solar_PV_Panels_2016.pdf"&gt;similar amount of solar e-waste&lt;/a&gt; could flood recycling plants by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ylCPjd"&gt;To convince manufacturers (and consumers) to adopt more recycling-friendly adhesives and adhesive-free designs, Baker says they will need assurances that the alternatives don’t compromise product durability or lifespan, which in the clean tech sector is often measured in decades. She suspects that many new designs will have to be “road tested” in products with a shorter lifespan where premature failure is “less of a risk.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3MKF04"&gt;That could include consumer technology markets, where sustainability-oriented companies like Framework and Fairphone are already rolling out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22587205/framework-laptop-review"&gt;modular&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fairphone.com%2Fen%2F2020%2F01%2F17%2Fgoing-against-the-grain-to-design-a-sustainable-phone%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22882287%2Fclean-energy-tech-design-recycling" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;adhesive-free&lt;/a&gt; laptops and phones intended to be taken apart easily. Even industry titans like Apple and Dell have recently announced &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/behind-the-hype-of-apples-plan-to-end-mining-1833045476"&gt;ambitious goals&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22832895/dell-luna-sustainable-laptop-concept-repairability-recyclable-environment"&gt;product concepts&lt;/a&gt; focused on recyclability. Abbott has already had preliminary talks with a phone manufacturer about glues that can de-bond a screen much more easily, although he says the company hasn’t yet embraced the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnC72m"&gt;Ultimately, manufacturers may be forced to overcome their reluctance to tweak product designs for recycling if policymakers start to mandate it or if the world faces shortages of the metals and minerals needed to build these technologies. As the clean energy transition causes &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/the-role-of-critical-minerals-in-clean-energy-transitions/mineral-requirements-for-clean-energy-transitions"&gt;demand for high-tech metals to spike&lt;/a&gt;, Baker says that companies are going to have to start getting more creative about where they source from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Dn6Cm"&gt;“If you can get [a resource] but it’s a really high price, that’s bad, but you can pass the price onto the consumer,” Baker says. “If you can’t get it at all, you have no business.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22882287/clean-energy-tech-design-recycling"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22882287/clean-energy-tech-design-recycling</id>
    <author>
      <name>Maddie Stone</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T10:57:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T10:57:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: Wordle’s App Store clones, FTC’s Meta lawsuit moves forward, and PC’s big year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Image of a Wordle puzzle with “clone” in the answer field." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/425Wj8t0zT1jvV6S6-SUF_obVB0=/0x105:1125x855/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70388487/IMG_3651.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C3th0l"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where we discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UC37hI"&gt;This week on&lt;em&gt; The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;, Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Russell Brandom start the show with news of federal judge James Boasberg allowing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878808/ftc-meta-facebook-lawsuit-ruling-revised-complaint-discovery"&gt;FTC to proceed with an antitrust lawsuit against Meta&lt;/a&gt;. The crew explains why the case can go forward after a dismissal last year and what can happen next. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPlsY9"&gt;The next topic of discussion focuses on the viral success of the web-based puzzle game &lt;em&gt;Wordle&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878752/wordle-app-store-review-copies-advertisements-in-app-purchase"&gt;the race to clone it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt; walks you through the drama, resulting in a bunch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22879295/wordle-clones-app-store-removal-online-backlash-copycats"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wordle&lt;/em&gt; clones being removed from Apple’s App Store&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="la4Ys4"&gt;Later in the show,&lt;em&gt; Verge&lt;/em&gt; deputy editor Dan Seifert stops by for this week’s gadget talk. On the docket: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2022/1/11/22878850/canon-printer-ink-toner-break-drm-chip-shortage-fake"&gt;Canon printers abandoning their DRM toner&lt;/a&gt; (for now), reports of the PC market experiencing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225356/pc-sales-shipments-2020-growth-idc-canalys-remote-work"&gt;first big growth&lt;/a&gt; in a decade, and the takeaways from this year’s CES. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="D9sOyd"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP4363369809&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q8jgdn"&gt;There’s a whole lot more discussed in this week’s show — like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881813/white-house-tech-summit-apple-google-meta-amazon-open-source-security"&gt;White House hosting a tech summit&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22881882/android-12-google-pixel-6-pro-bugs-oneplus-oxygenos-12-samsung-one-ui-4-update"&gt;bugginess of Android 12&lt;/a&gt;, and, of course, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22876067/google-apple-ios-android-imessages-bullying-lockheimer"&gt;RCS discourse&lt;/a&gt; — so listen here or in your preferred podcast player for the full discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kq2XoW"&gt;Here’s a full list of stories discussed in this week’s show:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ElifFT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880467/white-house-covid-coronavirus-testing-website-order-rapid-tests"&gt;White House to launch COVID test-ordering site ‘by this weekend,’ reports say&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OTb8zJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881813/white-house-tech-summit-apple-google-meta-amazon-open-source-security"&gt;White House hosts tech summit to discuss open-source security after Log4j&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GTVcU6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882176/google-government-action-protect-open-source-software-funding-security"&gt;Google calls for new government action to protect open-source software projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bM4PAh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878808/ftc-meta-facebook-lawsuit-ruling-revised-complaint-discovery"&gt;Judge says the FTC’s Meta monopoly lawsuit can go forward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XKubHj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22879623/meta-facebook-antitrust-problems-ftc-vr-virtual-reality"&gt;Meta’s real antitrust problems are only beginning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7VP3uJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882110/tldr-act-lori-trahan-lujan-cassidy-facebook-twitter-terms-of-service-agreement"&gt;Want the ‘TLDR’ on a site’s terms of service? There’s a bill for that&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="n8NTdS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22876791/apple-app-store-developers-earnings-launch-services-subscriptions"&gt;Apple says App Store developers have earned more than $260 billion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yOuwsI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878752/wordle-app-store-review-copies-advertisements-in-app-purchase"&gt;The App Store clones are here to profit off Wordle’s success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZRO8wS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22879295/wordle-clones-app-store-removal-online-backlash-copycats"&gt;The Wordle clones have disappeared from the App Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cuD4aB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880353/wordle-copycat-creator-apology-word-game-app-store-apple"&gt;Wordle copycat creator apologizes for ripping off the popular free word game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uSmPzQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22881995/wordle-emoji-results-auto-generated-tell-a-story"&gt;The real beauty of Wordle is how its emoji results tell a story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zvHVyQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22881053/ampme-apple-app-store-scams-recurring-subscription"&gt;Alleged Apple App Store scammer AmpMe lowers prices and says it’ll investigate its ‘consultants’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TGlBxF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877304/google-lockheimer-accuse-apple-imessage-holding-back-rcs-text-sms"&gt;Google exec says Apple is ‘holding back’ customers who text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PdY69h"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22876067/google-apple-ios-android-imessages-bullying-lockheimer"&gt;Google says Apple ‘should not benefit from bullying’ created by iMessage lock-in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mpt8dK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2022/1/11/22878850/canon-printer-ink-toner-break-drm-chip-shortage-fake"&gt;It fills me with glee that Canon printers now think Canon’s own toner is fake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kqr9IM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878673/apple-polishing-cloth-in-stock-online"&gt;Apple’s $19 polishing cloth is back in stock online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="G19DkS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/8/22872969/ford-f-150-lightning-electric-pickup-resale-ban-dealerships-year-scalping-shortages"&gt;Ford doesn’t want the F-150 Lightning’s launch to be plagued by scalpers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wsryFa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881646/tesla-cybertruck-production-date-2022-removed-website"&gt;Tesla removes 2022 production date from Cybertruck website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="csF5Pa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881569/pc-sales-shipments-2021-growth-idc-gartner-pandemic-demand"&gt;The PC market just had another big year thanks to pandemic demand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pRM7uN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881576/tsmc-capital-investment-2022-chip-manufacturer-demand-increase"&gt;TSMC earmarks record $44 billion for chip manufacturing expansion in 2022&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Sz7Cxa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22872486/hp-president-alex-cho-hp-business-consumer-laptops"&gt;The pandemic has blurred the lines between laptop categories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0pi1uQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878181/sony-xperia-5-iii-us-price-release-date-specs-features"&gt;Sony Xperia 5 III now shipping in the US, almost nine months after initial announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fFl6hE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880057/nvidia-shield-android-11-update-set-top-box-streaming"&gt;The Nvidia Shield is getting Android 11 and other upgrades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fqjk0H"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880062/ps4-manufacturing-sony-ps5-shortage-xbox-one"&gt;Sony says it’s still making new PS4s, but most stores aren’t selling them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kDDbQp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22881882/android-12-google-pixel-6-pro-bugs-oneplus-oxygenos-12-samsung-one-ui-4-update"&gt;Google’s Android 12 update has been the rockiest one in years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rEyt48"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/8/22872969/ford-f-150-lightning-electric-pickup-resale-ban-dealerships-year-scalping-shortages"&gt;Ford doesn’t want the F-150 Lightning’s launch to be plagued by scalpers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="M6UDV3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879994/wear-os-lefties-smartwatches-fossil-google"&gt;Wear OS will work better for lefties... eventually&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rcbNnD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881646/tesla-cybertruck-production-date-2022-removed-website"&gt;Tesla removes 2022 production date from Cybertruck website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6LFcVm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880695/gm-general-motors-carbravo-online-used-car-marketplace-website"&gt;GM is creating an online used car marketplace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="d0CD5U"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/2022/1/12/22878353/buy-nothing-groups-facebook-app"&gt;Buy Nothing exploded on Facebook — now it wants a platform on its own&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="KAXAZ0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Gn36b8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883590/vergecast-podcast-481-wordle-clones-ftc-antitrust-lawsuit-proceeds-pc-market-growth"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883590/vergecast-podcast-481-wordle-clones-ftc-antitrust-lawsuit-proceeds-pc-market-growth</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>These are the video game studios leading the charge for a four-day workweek</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qxIOECSVVEYMDiUqf7Tn7NP0EOU=/0x125:3000x2125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70388343/gute_fabrik_office.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An illustration of Die Gute Fabrik’s studio space.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Some game companies are spearheading the idea that employees should work less rather than more&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="gqJrQW"&gt;In January 2020, &lt;a href="http://stanleyparable.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Stanley Parable: Ultra Deluxe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the follow-up to 2011’s critically acclaimed first-person explorer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/10/17/4848072/free-will-is-overrated-the-stanley-parable"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Stanley Parable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, had already been delayed. In this situation, most bosses in the video game industry would consider crunch, industry parlance for predatory, often unpaid overtime. But William Pugh and his team at Berlin-based studio Crows Crows Crows implemented a solution that goes against conventional industry wisdom. Producer Alicia Contestabile raised the idea of a four-day week in 2019, and then, a few months later, office manager Filo Franke and artist and co-founder Dominik Johann revived it. “At this point, the question was really, ‘How do we keep going?’” Pugh recalls over a Discord call. “And we were basically Iike, ‘Okay, let’s just go to a four-day week.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYZH5W"&gt;Prior to switching to a four-day week, &lt;a href="https://crowscrowscrows.com/"&gt;Crows Crows Crows&lt;/a&gt; was a regular nine-to-five, Monday-to-Friday organization; before that, it had been fully remote and operated a flexible working structure, paying employees for a certain number of hours per month because many of them were juggling multiple projects and clients. Pugh, a twenty-something with a background in theater who was only 19 when &lt;em&gt;The Stanley Parable&lt;/em&gt; became an indie smash hit, admits this initial transition to in-office work was tough. “I found going in five days a week straight up stressful,” he recalls. “I didn’t have a good work-life balance.” Pugh had &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/nov/04/microsoft-japan-four-day-work-week-productivity"&gt;read&lt;/a&gt; about Microsoft Japan’s trialing of a four-day week, which suggested that workers were not only happier but more productive. So he and the rest of the team at Crows Crows Crows, which has six full-time employees, made the leap because, as he puts it, “there was no real reason not to.” Contracts were rewritten — the same pay for four days’ work instead of five. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SArdSK"&gt;For years, stories about labor and workplace culture have made headlines in the video game industry for all the wrong reasons. &lt;a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/pc/-ea-spouse-weblog-raises-issues-on-game-development-quality-of-life"&gt;Erin Hoffman&lt;/a&gt; lifted the lid on EA’s grim working hours in the early noughties, and since then, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494499/cyberpunk-2077-development-crunch-time-cd-projekt-red"&gt;crunch&lt;/a&gt; has remained &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/20/17130056/telltale-games-developer-layoffs-toxic-video-game-industry"&gt;endemic within the industry&lt;/a&gt;, despite &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160412021002208#_blank"&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; of overwork’s harmful impacts on health and work quality. According to the latest &lt;a href="https://igda-website.s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/18113901/IGDA-DSS-2021_SummaryReport_2021.pdf"&gt;IGDA developer satisfaction survey&lt;/a&gt;, crunch has only intensified since the pandemic began. Crows Crows Crows, alongside a growing number of independent studios — &lt;a href="https://gutefabrik.com/die-gute-fabriks-4-day-week/"&gt;Die Gute Fabrik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-09-09-young-horses-implements-four-day-weeks"&gt;Young Horses&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/culture/q-a-kitfox-games-co-founder-tanya-x-short-breaks-down-the-four-day-week"&gt;Kitfox Games&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-11-03-armor-games-shares-four-day-workweek-findings"&gt;Armor Games&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.ko-opmode.com/"&gt;Ko_Op Mode&lt;/a&gt; — plus, most eye-catchingly, &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; maker &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714604/eidos-montreal-sherbrooke-four-day-week-game-development"&gt;Eidos-Montreal&lt;/a&gt; and its subsidiary Eidos-Sherbrooke are pushing back against such ingrained approaches to work. For all intents and purposes, these studios are putting people before product and profit. It is, says Pugh, about ensuring colleagues have space for their lives beyond the office — to “treat themselves with compassion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8XMarlx91obEQVxsC3FMSAAZYqA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167223/The_Stanley_Parable___Screenshot_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Stanley Parable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="v78q4h"&gt;By Pugh’s own admission, Crows Crows Crows, maker of decidedly experimental titles, is a “loose, chaotic kind of institution.” With such a focus on boundary-pushing work, he acknowledges it’s fallen into the trap of “valuing the product more than people.” The four-day week is a means of counteracting this, not least for Pugh’s own wellbeing as much as his colleagues. He mentions a mental health crisis that forced him to take time off and describes the four-day week as “literally life-saving.” With Fridays free, it allows Pugh to schedule therapy more easily, not having to tack it onto the start or end of a workday, which can leave him even more exhausted. While Pugh doesn’t have hard data on productivity, he feels work is more consistent across a four-day week. More than that, he says, “it just makes people happier.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TKVojb"&gt;Pugh’s anecdotal experience reflects scientific research. In Iceland, a trial run by Reykjavik City Council, which included over 2,500 workers (1 percent of Iceland’s working population), &lt;a href="https://en.alda.is/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ICELAND_4DW.pdf"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that workers felt “less stressed and at risk of burnout” while their “work-life balance improved” after adopting a shorter working week. Importantly, workers also reported having “more time to spend with their families, do hobbies, and complete household chores.” According to researchers, productivity remained the same or improved, despite the reduction in hours from 40 to 35 or 36. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LKii5xHsDJeHoH6WfKQsRzT_at4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23168582/1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Crows Crows Crows&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The team at Crows Crows Crows.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Op5NyX"&gt;Where Pugh confesses that his management style at Crows Crows Crows is hands-off (“I’m not gonna put the thumbscrews in if I notice somebody clocking in on the Friday,” he says), Hannah Nicklin, lead of Copenhagen-based studio Die Gute Fabrik (German for “The Good Factory”), has devised a more &lt;a href="https://gutefabrik.com/die-gute-fabriks-4-day-week/"&gt;rigorous approach&lt;/a&gt; to the four-day week. She’s taken steps to make her 15-person team’s use of time more efficient, including working with other studios that might have already solved technical or design problems. (Nicklin, for example, prefers to pay to an external source for two hours’ worth of consultation rather than an employee for a week of research on precisely the same issue.) The company’s creative producer Ben Wilson has devised meeting templates for various aspects of production, taking care to ensure everyone is fully prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dB8rxm"&gt;“A lot of it is actually about project management,” explains Nicklin over Zoom, “so that’s it’s never like, ‘Oh, what’s this meeting for?’ We’re not just here to shout over one another for two hours while the quiet people in our team just sit there. It’s about working out what the best solutions are for us and our workforce.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dyJxu8"&gt;Nicklin, even more than Pugh, has an unconventional CV for a game studio boss — she also has a background in theater, has done stints in community arts, and is a longstanding labor activist. The phrase she repeats is “dignity of work,” a nod to both the political philosopher &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/09/contributive-justice-and-dignity-work/615919/"&gt;Michael J. Sandel&lt;/a&gt; and the late anthropologist &lt;a href="https://www.atlasofplaces.com/essays/on-the-phenomenon-of-bullshit-jobs/"&gt;David Graeber&lt;/a&gt;. In Nicklin’s view, respecting people’s time at their place of work is one part of this, and so is the four-day week itself. The other big initiative she’s introduced is a flat pay structure, which means she’s paid exactly the same as someone with a less senior role who’s been at the studio a similar amount of time. Where women, people of color, and other marginalized groups might undervalue themselves or indeed lack experience (or the bandwidth) for negotiation, this is an attempt to ensure fairer pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BbmhCw"&gt;Nicklin acknowledges such changes would have been impossible without the support of her directors, who have bought into her workplace vision. “[Dignity of work] means empowering people and actively making space in the recruitment process and practice for a diverse workforce,” she continues. “There are people not thinking about that, who just think about the video game itself and don’t really care about who they burn through to get that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LiCx7sLzBaCQl2SKKm_ysKFlobE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167231/ss_2639e2a47c9e80542afffda93555358a7d9aad6b.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bugsnax.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9LmCoz"&gt;Burning through staff is a major criticism frequently leveled at blockbuster game development. According to &lt;a href="https://learning.linkedin.com/blog/engaging-your-workforce/see-the-industries-with-the-highest-turnover%E2%80%94and-why-it-s-so-hi"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, the turnover rate in the games is around 15.5 percent, higher than any other tech sector, while burnout, exhaustion, and declining mental health are widely accepted as part and parcel of working for major game companies such as &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bungie-report-battle-soul-work-culture-harassment-crunch"&gt;Bungie&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/inside-rockstar-games-culture-of-crunch-1829936466"&gt;Rockstar&lt;/a&gt;. For Pugh, this is what happens when you have a passionate workforce who has had formative experiences with the games such capitalist organizations produce. “If your dream is to make games, then why wouldn’t you want to sacrifice to do that?” he says. “But so often, it’s just people sacrificing to make nicer rock textures or optimizing particle effects.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VuggJS"&gt;For AAA developers, dignity of work is even harder to come by. Over the past decade, roles have been atomized in organizations whose scale now resembles gigantic factories. Eidos-Montreal and Eidos-Sherbrooke moving to a four-day week is arguably the first step in reimagining worker wellbeing in the corporate mainstream of an industry that has too long treated it with contempt. (Both Quebec-based studios are under the corporate umbrella of Square Enix, which publishes everything from &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt;.) During the pandemic, both studios operated a policy of up to four hours “rest-time” on a Friday, which, according to one employee who spoke to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; anonymously over Zoom, was a means of “compensation” for the pandemic and the mental health toll it took. Then, on a company-wide Zoom meeting in fall 2021, Eidos-Montreal head David Anfossi announced the winding down of the “rest-time” program, replaced by the full four-day workweek. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WscsE3"&gt;“It was kind of a rollercoaster,” reveals the Eidos employee. “We knew there was some talk of it because there were people looking at the research behind the whole thing, so it wasn’t a total surprise. But going from, ‘We’re looking into this,’ to, ‘We’re actively starting this,’ happened way faster than I thought it would.” Like Nicklin’s initiatives at Die Gute Fabrik, the Eidos studios are implementing smarter work structures, including certain hours of the week where meetings can’t be hosted and “focus time” designed to foster more productive working. These are ultimately measures intended to facilitate less “context switching” during the workday. “The changes make a lot of sense,” they say, “and should have just been done anyway.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Boyfriend Dungeon" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ikA7yNduoJk03nyriXXYPbHhOJY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19585855/ss_9b01ee46580e814aa6ef43d431746b3ed85300c8.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boyfriend Dungeon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NJWV7X"&gt;Despite the Eidos studios making the transition, it’s with independent companies that the four-day week is gaining the greatest traction. However, even those who have made the switch remain cautious about its long-term feasibility. Kitfox Games made the change in June 2021 during the lead-up to the launch of its dating simulation dungeon-crawler &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/22633028/boyfriend-dungeon-review-kitfox-games"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Boyfriend Dungeon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but the idea had been tossed around a few years earlier. At that stage, however, in the depths of development, co-founder Tanya Short felt it was simply “too risky” to add an “unknown percentage of inefficiency” to the studio’s work. “We’re probably not losing 20 percent. Lots of people aren’t super productive on Friday,” says Short. “But maybe they’re somewhat productive for the beginning of the day. Perhaps we’re losing 10 percent productivity or even 5 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9YaiB"&gt;As co-founder of Kitfox Games, Short’s acutely aware of the pressures on independent video game studios and describes moving to the four-day week in terms of another “constraint” on their output. “On the one hand, it’s not that unusual a feeling to think, ‘Okay, this is just a new difficulty I have to operate under and a new consideration when I greenlight a product,” Short explains. “On the other hand, some part of me does wonder if I’m being irresponsible — if I’ll have to do layoffs or if I’m making these games too expensive to be maintainable. I guess we’ll find out in a few years whether this constraint was the straw that broke the camel’s back or if it was just another way for us to make games in a way that lets us also lead a good life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8jKjoP"&gt;What hasn’t happened is any kind of pushback from the funders of these studios. Short describes Kitfox’s situation as enviable in the sense that the company only accepts funding from sources that trust it knows how best to make its games. “We don’t allow external scrutiny of our processes,” she says. Crows Crows Crows is self-financed, and Young Horses, developer of charming adventure game &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/21551529/bugsnax-review-playstation-4-5-xbox-one-series-x-pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bugsnax&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has cultivated an impressive level of financial independence, reliant on funding from Sony in only a “conservative way,” according to Kevin Geisler, COO and programmer at the company. For more precarious studios without the proven track record of these organizations, the four-day week may simply be less feasible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rIhY2h44m8DBy5mIUoEg1wsx12k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23168584/1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alicia Contestabile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alicia Contestabile.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wgO4Kn"&gt;Still, this hasn’t stopped Contestabile, former producer at Crows Crows Crows, from implementing a four-day week at the as-yet-unnamed studio she’s in the process of setting up. Because it’s embedded into the company’s work structures from the very start, “it’s not like we’re losing a day,” she explains over email. That said, Contestabile envisages challenges related to the four-day week as production deepens but, conversely, a team that’s better placed to weather such difficulties — one “more resilient and well-rested.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2f99cB"&gt;For Contestabile, the four-day week isn’t just an opportunity to foster a healthier work culture — one that’s “fundamentally anti-racist, feminist, and LGBTQ+ friendly” — it’s also a way of making a meaningful contribution to the climate crisis. According to a recent &lt;a href="https://6a142ff6-85bd-4a7b-bb3b-476b07b8f08d.usrfiles.com/ugd/6a142f_5061c06b240e4776bf31dfac2543746b.pdf"&gt;UK report&lt;/a&gt;, moving to a four-day week can shrink carbon emissions, both by reducing energy use in the workplace and slashing transport emissions in the mornings and evenings. The report also found that giving people an extra day off meant they took part in more “low-carbon” activities, including rest, exercise, and seeing family. Eidos-Montreal and Eidos-Sherbrooke are already doing so at the scale of approximately 500 employees, and if more companies made the transition to a four-day week, it would represent genuine progress in reducing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21243285/video-games-climate-crisis-impact-xbox-playstation-developers"&gt;environmental impact&lt;/a&gt; of an industry reliant on electricity-intensive PCs and laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XvNjEJ"&gt;Like everything else, the pandemic has fundamentally reoriented the experience and expectations of work for many. It’s hardly a coincidence that the majority of studios that have transitioned to a four-day week have done so during it. But this is also another development in the longer-running story of labor in the video game industry, one that picked up even greater steam in 2021. The year was defined by worker &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598410/activision-blizzard-employee-walk-out-protest-sexism-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;walkouts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826129/activision-blizzard-employees-create-strike-fund-while-taking-steps-toward-unionization"&gt;strikes&lt;/a&gt;, and, momentously, the first North American video game union, &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22834924/vodeo-games-first-video-game-union-north-america-code-cwa"&gt;Vodeo Workers United&lt;/a&gt;. These were actions initiated by those attempting to secure greater dignity of work for both themselves and their co-workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Elka2W"&gt;“We have a lot of privilege as video game workers,” concludes Contestabile, “and I hope we all use that to make positive changes not only in our own workplaces but in our local communities and with sustainability in mind.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22882669/video-game-studios-four-day-workweek"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22882669/video-game-studios-four-day-workweek</id>
    <author>
      <name>Lewis Gordon</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>EV startup Bollinger ‘indefinitely’ delays its rugged electric trucks to focus on delivery vans</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nh8AhElyK-ZmA46ztcqsZBP_ni4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70387927/sokane_170711_1870_0014.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uWueQJ"&gt;Bollinger, a Michigan-based startup, announced today that it was postponing its plans to manufacture electric trucks in order to focus on commercial delivery vans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHTM0W"&gt;Bollinger burst onto the scene several years ago with a pair of rugged, box-like electric truck prototypes: the four-door B1 (which is shaped like a Jeep Wrangler) and the B2 (which is longer and has a pickup bed). It’s the latest EV startup to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22846960/electric-vehicles-car-companies-promises-ship-dates"&gt;run into speed bumps&lt;/a&gt; as it attempts to build a complicated vehicle manufacturing business from scratch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IqOKC0"&gt;Bollinger has already delayed both vehicles, so their postponement may not come as a huge shock to close watchers. The trucks were originally scheduled to go into production in 2020, but that date was moved to late 2021, with the expectation of making several thousand by early 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KaPKLZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s the latest EV startup to run into speed bumps&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fv07gp"&gt;Now, the vehicles will be “postponed indefinitely” as the company shifts focus to an electric delivery van, Bollinger CEO Robert Bollinger said in a statement. The company will refund deposits for those customers who previously put money down to reserve the B1 and B2 trucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i1R98r"&gt;“The B1 and B2 are postponed indefinitely, in order to concentrate on commercial development,” he said. “As these trucks are dear to my heart, I’d never say never. If our continued development in commercial allows us to someday return, there’d be no one happier than me. But there’s no timeline for that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Xd9sL"&gt;The Deliver-E electric van, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/28/21405451/bollinger-electric-delivery-van-production-price-specs"&gt;which was announced in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, is slated to be built on a variable vehicle platform that allows for multiple battery sizes, such as 70 kWh, 105 kWh, 140 kWh, 175 kWh, and 210 kWh. This will mean customers will have a variety of range options, prices, and wheelbase sizes to choose from. The front-wheel-drive platform will be engineered to fit Classes 2B, 3, 4, and 5. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HyTeWj0lW4skUtIodMh9aH-HoSU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23166646/Bollinger_Motors_Electric_Platform_front_3.4.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZcPd7L"&gt;Bollinger declined to affirm a starting date for the van’s production, noting that the company is still on the hunt for a manufacturing partner. “The Deliver-E van was our interpretation of the kind of body that could be put on our electric platforms,” he said. “We never intended on building that body ourselves, but we are in talks with upfitter partners now that manufacture truck and van bodies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Ex7YD"&gt;If it eventually graduates from concept to production, the Deliver-E will have a lot of competition. General Motors is already &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/5/22867087/walmart-brightdrop-electric-delivery-van-gm-fedex"&gt;shipping electric vans&lt;/a&gt; under its BrightDrop brand to customers like FedEx and Walmart. Mercedes-Benz has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/10/21173373/mercedes-benz-evito-electric-van-specs-photos"&gt;multiple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/5/18251084/mercedes-benz-eqv-electric-van-geneva-motor-show-2019"&gt;models&lt;/a&gt; on the road, and Ford plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21559954/ford-e-transit-electric-delivery-cargo-van-price-specs-range"&gt;go into production&lt;/a&gt; this year on its electrified E-Transit van.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpCx9Y"&gt;Amazon, which has a fleet of tens of thousands of combustion-engine vans making up its massive delivery operation, has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20873947/amazon-electric-delivery-van-rivian-jeff-bezos-order"&gt;ordered 100,000 electric vans from EV startup Rivian&lt;/a&gt; (which it is also heavily invested in) and is planning on buying EVs from Stellantis as well. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22881883/bollinger-electric-truck-postpone-delivery-van"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22881883/bollinger-electric-truck-postpone-delivery-van</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T09:51:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T09:51:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Build a speedy USB-C drive with this discounted M.2 SSD enclosure</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pxCGRUJ1PYdB4bbdpmDEhxoNIX0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70387892/akrales_190430_3393_0021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ve got yourself a small weekend project.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q2O9Pp"&gt;In most cases, people purchase M.2 NVMe drives to stick into their desktop PCs or laptops for more of that good, fast storage. But there are some other, more practical applications that don’t require opening up your hardware. You can get one of these fast SSDs, then stick it into a small enclosure, and suddenly you’ve made yourself a convenient and speedy portable USB-C drive that’ll cost you as little as $93 with today’s deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YHLnR9"&gt;If that sounds like something you’d like to add to your tech repertoire, Sabrent’s tool-free USB-C Gen 3.2 enclosure &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08RVC6F9Y?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;is down to just $22.94&lt;/a&gt; (usually $40) at Amazon. Adding an M.2 drive to it is simple, just pop the top off and follow the instructions for carefully guiding the drive into the slot. Then, you fasten it into place to keep it from moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HmXvr7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10977806"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="J6H4W0"&gt;(Note: the M.2 SSD enclosure featured in the lead image above is available &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Plugable-Tool-free-Enclosure-Thunderbolt-Compatible/dp/B07N48N5GR/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;here at Amazon for $40&lt;/a&gt;, down from its normal $50 price.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mWbOEj"&gt;You can stick a SATA or NVMe (the latter being much faster) SSD in this enclosure, and it supports up to the 2280 form factor, which is the most popular size (it can house 2242- and 2260-sized M.2 drives, alternatively). Its USB 3.2 support allows for up to 10Gbps transfer speeds, though its speed will ultimately be determined by what kind of drive you stick inside of it. An affordable and relatively speedy option to put inside of this enclosure also comes from Sabrent. Its 1TB Rocket Q SSD costs $89.99 right now (usually $111) at Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="S0jH4A"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10977796" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Samsung 980" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YlcfbsH-cdg4lFx9HkgyMn7QpUM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22339485/samsung980hero.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hLb4jW"&gt;If you are hoping to get a Samsung SSD within this price range, its 1TB 980 NVMe SSD is $109.99 — down from $139.99 — at Best Buy. This model should be sufficient for a lot of people’s needs, though it’s not the fastest NVMe drive out there, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22307402/samsung-980-nvme-ssd-dram-pcie-3-speed-price"&gt;as it lacks DRAM&lt;/a&gt;, which is relied upon by your PC to map the contents within the drive to make it faster at serving up your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FS88as"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10977801" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NaOwH5"&gt;For a slightly speedier Samsung SSD that does feature DRAM, check out its 970 Evo Plus with 500GB of storage that costs $69.99 at Best Buy, down from its usual price of $95. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vD3Wdj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9567584" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="6yc6G5"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="AirPods 3 review: new shape, new fit|104501" data-volume-uuid="1a50839d4" data-volume-id="104501" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-406" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="T3GBzg"&gt;For something completely different, check out Amazon’s stellar sale price on the latest (third-gen) AirPods. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQL3NWT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;They’re back down to $139.99&lt;/a&gt; (originally $179), matching the great price that was popular with readers during Black Friday and Cyber Monday. For those not in the know, these retain a similar design to the AirPods Pro but have some key differences. Notably, they don’t have silicon ear tips for a better fit, nor do they support active noise cancellation. Though, while similar to the original AirPods in terms of how they fit in the ear canal, our review Chris Welch says that Apple amped up the sound quality in this generation, among other new additions. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J5KdKa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10744075"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="a0sDqF"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Govee Immersion LED backlight soccer demonstration|102877" data-volume-uuid="ca6c25c63" data-volume-id="102877" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-718" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ooypnS"&gt;If you’re looking for an affordable way to add some ambient lighting around your TV that changes color in response to what’s happening on the display, check out this deal at Amazon. Govee’s Immersion backlights that support TVs between 55 and 65 inches are $63.09 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Govee-Immersion-Backlights-Ambient-Assistant/dp/B08LVPWQQP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;when you check the coupon box on this page&lt;/a&gt;. Originally, this product costs $83.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QV3716"&gt;The Immersion kit includes a long LED light strip that goes behind your TV, along with a camera that needs to be mounted atop your TV (this is how its lights can match what is showing on your TV). The lights can be controlled through Govee’s app or via your voice with Amazon Alexa or Google Assistant. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22566408/govee-immersion-ambilight-tv-backlight-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TWqnin"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10681491"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TFjh4Z"&gt;Other deals to set you right this Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="xPkQnI"&gt;We recently covered this Amazon deal on Elgato’s Cam Link 4K, which makes it easier to link up your DSLR or mirrorless camera to a PC and supports up to 4K resolution playback at 30 frames per second (or 1080p / 60fps). Normally $129.99, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elgato-Cam-Link-Broadcast-Camcorder/dp/B07K3FN5MR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elgato-Cam-Link-Broadcast-Camcorder/dp/B07K3FN5MR?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$106.49. &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ERg5eY"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elgato-Cam-Link-Broadcast-Camcorder/dp/B07K3FN5MR?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Am&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?ascsubtag=3365db24753b11eca25a0675b876cbfa0INT&amp;amp;rh=n%3A23718262011"&gt;azon has several must-own Nintendo Switch games selling for great prices&lt;/a&gt;. You can check them all out right here, and note that they’re digital versions, so you’ll just need to ensure that you have enough storage on your console or the microSD card you may have. If you need more storage, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GY8NHF2/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sandisk’s 256GB microSD card costs $29.79 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="7nCViN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bJw1Ky"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/14/22883518/portable-usb-c-ssd-enclosure-apple-airpods-third-latest-gen-tv-backlighting-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/14/22883518/portable-usb-c-ssd-enclosure-apple-airpods-third-latest-gen-tv-backlighting-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T09:44:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T09:44:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Final Fantasy XIV sales to resume January 25th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w8pU0fSd8i7J2wQYoBcBdaebKYk=/300x0:1920x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70387794/2022_01_12_16_44_38_Greenshot.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1ilOEy"&gt;Your case of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV&lt;/em&gt; FOMO is nearing its end. Last night, game director Naoki Yoshida wrote on the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV&lt;/em&gt; website that Square Enix &lt;a href="https://na.finalfantasyxiv.com/lodestone/topics/detail/9a6bed5c06ae511c363ece5ead0a98a3986554a2"&gt;will resume digital sales&lt;/a&gt; of the popular MMO on January 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aoYJLT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV&lt;/em&gt; grew so popular with the launch of its latest expansion &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22877031/final-fantasy-xiv-endwalker-review-square-enix-pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Endwalker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the queues to log into game servers were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822793/final-fantasy-14-endwalker-early-access-server-queues"&gt;thousands of people long and took hours to get through&lt;/a&gt;. Servers were so congested that in December, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839415/final-fantasy-14-sales-suspended-servers-over-capacity-digital-physical"&gt;Square Enix suspended the sale of digital versions of the game&lt;/a&gt;. As more players progress through the content, levels of server congestion are finally starting to even out, permitting sales of the game to resume. Yoshida also acknowledged that &lt;em&gt;FFXIV&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/the-critically-acclaimed-mmorpg"&gt;meme-able free trial&lt;/a&gt; offering will remain unavailable for now but will return in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tHXwYA"&gt;Yoshida’s update also included information about the addition of a new Oceanian data center which will give Australian and New Zealand players, who traditionally played on Japanese servers or suffered high ping to connect to American ones, more choices on where to play. In his announcement, Yoshida said the new data center will go live January 25th, and to encourage players to move there, Square Enix will waive the typical $18 world transfer fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8A2CN7"&gt;In addition to a new data center, existing ones in Europe, Japan, and North America are getting expansions. Previously, Square Enix cited &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822825/final-fantasy-xiv-14-endwalker-global-chip-shortage-server-queue"&gt;the global chip shortage&lt;/a&gt; as the reason they could not deploy more servers to assist with congestion. Yesterday’s announcement included a roadmap for when these expansions are to take place with the first phase beginning in summer of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s87iuv"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DQ2fT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6TMySx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PARbZt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883544/final-fantasy-14-date-digital-sales-server-expansion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883544/final-fantasy-14-date-digital-sales-server-expansion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T09:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How God of War’s impressive PC port came to life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mPd8uBTR14dqz6vLOsF6tSMwpEo=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70387599/Announce_Screenshot_05_copy.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Mouse and keyboard, meet boy and Kratos&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="4Sxtsh"&gt;Lately Sony has been increasingly open to putting previously PlayStation-exclusive games on PC, and today’s release of &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; is the most notable yet. One of Sony’s premier franchises since the original game was released for the PS2 in 2005, all subsequent titles — a 2007 spinoff for mobile phones aside — have been locked to PlayStation hardware. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/12/17223854/god-of-war-review-ps4"&gt;Santa Monica Studio’s 2018 &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most acclaimed games for the PS4, and now it’s available to a new audience for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pq1rx1"&gt;I’ve spent some time with the PC version and found it to be impressively well-tailored to the platform, which is not always a given. I spoke with Santa Monica’s senior manager of technical production Matt DeWald and lead UX designer and accessibility lead Mila Pavlin to find out more about the process of bringing &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; to PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6gqTm4"&gt;“It was about two years ago that we decided to look into whether it was possible,” DeWald says. “So the idea came down of like, Okay, let’s let’s think about whether we could do a PC [port] — we have a custom engine, we haven’t actually released a PC game, let’s get it up and running and just see what are the issues that we’re going to have and how much work is this going to actually take.” Santa Monica tasked Jetpack Interactive, a studio in Vancouver that had already been working on other internal collaborations, with figuring out the scope of the project, and ultimately it got approved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vZNtm6"&gt;“They’re integrated into the team, so they’re not really a typical port house where we offload something and throw it over the fence,” DeWald says of Jetpack. “They’re working out of our code bases, they’re on our Teams channels and they’re communicating with our team, they’re part of our standups.” Four engineers at Jetpack handled primary development of the port, with DeWald serving as producer and other Santa Monica members like Pavlin making additional contributions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="g5Z9zW"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u9wM2Zdeloc?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JHvxlu"&gt;“[PC players] want it to feel like it was built for the PC rather than being a port,” says Pavlin, who worked on the project’s UX and controls. “So a lot of the work that we did early on was about hitting those points on the graphic quality, making sure that the graphics quality were up to standards and that it was responsive on the PC platform and then making sure that the controls were customizable and felt good in the native configuration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u3ubL0"&gt;I can’t speak to how &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; will run on everyone’s PC, of course — and as a hypothetical, DeWald wouldn’t be drawn on how it’ll perform on the Steam Deck — but my experience with the game on a five-year-old machine has been positive. There are a lot of graphical options and performance has been more or less in line with what I’d expect; I average about 50 frames per second on a 1440p ultrawide monitor with G-Sync, and that’s using a Skylake Core i5 processor and a GTX 1080 with a mixture of settings. Each visual option can be run in “original” mode, which basically gives you PS4-level quality, and you can crank them up or down from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="N3s45g"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“[PC players] want it to feel like it was built for the PC rather than being a port.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xaAeKs"&gt;While you might not immediately think of it as a good fit given its heritage as a console-based action game, &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; on PC can be played with mouse and keyboard controls, and the scheme is surprisingly well thought out. Actions like aiming and throwing Kratos’ axe, for example, feel more natural if you’re used to playing FPS games with a mouse. Pavlin points out that the commands aren’t mapped one to one from the list of controller actions — for example, on the PS4 you jump with the same context-sensitive button that’s used to interact with the environment, but on PC the jump command is handled separately by the space bar, like most other PC games. There are also options like auto-sprint, which can be more comfortable for many players. Personally, I would still lean toward using a controller, but I’ve finished the game on the PS4 so I’m already used to it. For newcomers who only play on PC, the mouse and keyboard scheme is a thoughtful addition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6vNBPm"&gt;“I found it very comfortable to use because I’m used to that from my other games — I play a lot of PC games,” Pavlin says. “It feels like a very native and fun way to play the game. It kind of changes up the whole way that you approach combat. I found that I was able to target very easily using the mouse because the precision was so good that I was able to do things like get headshots and make sure that I’m, you know, knocking out the legs of the dragon and doing those precision shots that maybe with a controller I would find a little bit more difficult or have to use an aim assist for. So I do think that there’s advantages to it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NIwaO7"&gt;Another strong addition to the PC version is support for 21:9 ultrawide monitors (as well as the taller 16:10). This is more interesting for &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; than it might be for other titles because of the game’s signature one-shot technique, where the camera essentially never cuts from the beginning to the end of the game. I wondered whether expanding the field of view presented any challenges in terms of revealing things that maybe weren’t intended to be on-screen originally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3sAoQ0"&gt;“[The ultrawide support] revealed all the little hacks and cheats we were using to kind of move people into position or have somebody come on from off-screen,” DeWald says. “They might not be fully animated. So that was a manual process that required just kind of going through the entire game.” Cutscenes, too, sometimes had to be reframed to better fit the expanded content that’s being rendered by the engine in real time. The results are impressive — I never felt like anything looked out of place, and Kratos’ AI-controlled son Atreus follows along with you just as convincingly as he did on a 16:9 TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kvdlod"&gt;Unfortunately, though, you’ll need to run the game at ultrawide resolution if you want a wider field of view, because there isn’t a conventional FoV slider. DeWald says it introduced bugs that the team didn’t have time to fix, with the game basing certain logic on what’s on- or off-screen at a given moment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M1v_6azjWFFgar-YWriP16DtquI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23168563/Announce_Screenshot_08_copy.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hxMCoP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t originally designed as a PC game, and the experience of going back and making it feel native to a platform has prompted Santa Monica Studio to reexamine its workflow. “Moving into the PC space really got us to think, not just about PC releases, but also our entire pipeline,” Pavlin says. “So looking at how we make things more adjustable and customizable from the get-go with the way that we’re building our code base and our assets. If we know that we’re going to have a large range of formats that we’re going to move into or we know that we’re going to need to have control customization, the programmers actually need to know that very early on in a project so that they can build the code base in a way that’s more flexible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QeBgwq"&gt;That will also allow Santa Monica Studio to help make its games more accessible, with Pavlin citing the example of how the way &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; was initially only designed with hard-coded PS4 controls in mind caused a lot of work for the team to rethink its inputs on PC. “This is very important not just for PC ports, but also you’re moving forward with accessibility and making sure that you are supporting additional control functions, controller customization, or keyboard customization. And in future projects, we’ve learned those key lessons here that we can take into actually designing our games better for them to be more flexible for the future, to make it easier on everyone going forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Atqsd3"&gt;Santa Monica Studio is currently developing &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;’s sequel, &lt;em&gt;God of War: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt;, which is set to be released on the PS4 and PS5 this year. There’s no word on whether it’ll ever make it to the PC, but Pavlin’s comments suggest that &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt;’s PC port could have a positive impact on even the console versions of &lt;em&gt;Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt;. For now, it’s simply the best way to play the game and well worth checking out whether you’re a new or returning player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ZGZHH"&gt;&lt;small&gt;God of War &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is out on Steam and the Epic Games Store today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22883541/god-of-war-pc-port-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22883541/god-of-war-pc-port-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Bill Gates’ climate fund looks to funnel billions into carbon removal, green hydrogen, and more </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BELGIUM-EU-SUMMIT" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u6GLcM63S-an-gZdmDgZyEcAJ30=/0x0:2952x1968/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70387499/1052366986.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Founder of Microsoft and chairman of Breakthrough Energy Ventures, to establish the Breakthrough Energy Europe investment fund, Bill Gates looks on during a press conference at the EU headquarters in Brussels on October 17, 2018. | Photo by JOHN THYS/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KexSfk"&gt;Bill Gates’ climate investment fund is moving forward with plans to funnel billions of dollars into emerging green technologies. This week, the fund, Breakthrough Energy, put out a Request for Proposals for projects in &lt;a href="https://www.breakthroughenergy.org/articles/announcing-catalyst-eu-rfp"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt; through Breakthrough Energy’s Catalyst program. It comes after the Catalyst program released its first RFP for similar projects in &lt;a href="https://www.breakthroughenergy.org/articles/announcing-catalyst-rfp"&gt;the US&lt;/a&gt; last month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ByXa6K"&gt;The Catalyst program, launched last June with the aim of enabling&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;a zero-carbon economy through public-private partnerships&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;says it has fundraised $1.5 billion over the past six months and hopes to raise $3 billion by the middle of next year. It plans to use that money to boost four different kinds of technologies: green hydrogen fuels, sustainable aviation fuels, energy storage, and tech that captures carbon dioxide in the air. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o2v6O8"&gt;Back in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621636/bill-gates-fund-climate-change-tech"&gt;August&lt;/a&gt;, Gates said that the Catalyst program would funnel $1.5 billion over three years into joint projects with the US Department of Energy if Congress passed a bipartisan infrastructure bill. That public-private partnership could trigger&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;up to $15 billion in investments in the US, Catalyst &lt;a href="https://www.breakthroughenergy.org/articles/doe-partnership-announcement"&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Z5ICtS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We feel very confident the the US has projects that would represent more than a billion and a half dollars of investment”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yO95hN"&gt;Biden signed that bill into &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/bipartisan-infrastructure-law/"&gt;law&lt;/a&gt; in November, unlocking $1.2 trillion in investments — including tens of billions of dollars to promote electric vehicles, update airports, makeover the power grid, build out “&lt;a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2021-12/FECM%20Infrastructure%20Factsheet.pdf"&gt;hubs&lt;/a&gt;” for clean hydrogen, and direct air capture and &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=justine+calma+pipelines+co2&amp;amp;rlz=1C5GCEM_enUS895US895&amp;amp;oq=justine+calma+pipelines+co2&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j33i160.3928j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8"&gt;pipelines for captured carbon&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="99py5M"&gt;Now, Breakthrough Energy Catalyst says it’s poised to follow through on its funding pledge. The amount it ultimately gives, however, will depend on how promising the projects are. It plans to dole out funds for the first group of technologies over the next five years or so. “We feel very confident that the US has projects that would represent more than a billion and a half dollars of investment from Catalyst, but I don’t want to say they definitely will until we start evaluating those,” Breakthrough Energy managing director Jonah Goldman tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We’re not going to just give a billion and a half — these are serious, rigorous project evaluation processes that have to go on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6DaZIn"&gt;The projects that Catalyst ultimately selects in Europe might also be eligible for additional funds from the European Commission and European Investment Bank. Altogether, Breakthrough Energy hopes that the public-private partnership can mobilize $1 billion USD for European projects between 2022 and 2027. The fund also has plans to release an RFP for the UK this year, followed by funding opportunities for other parts of the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HUXBlx"&gt;“Critical for all these climate technologies is to get the costs down and to be able to scale them up to a pretty gigantic level,” Gates told &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/bill-gates-pledges-1-5-billion-for-infrastructure-bills-new-climate-projects-11628769601?redirect=amp#click=https://t.co/Dfa8tXxdVM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="APEhNR"&gt;Technology that removes CO2 from the air, called direct air capture, is a potent example of how much investment is needed. Today, this technology is in a very early stage and is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22663597/largest-direct-air-capture-plant-c02-climeworks-iceland"&gt;very expensive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Microsoft, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254483/microsoft-climate-change-pledge-update-carbon-dioxide-removal"&gt;pledged in 2020 &lt;/a&gt;to reduce and draw down more carbon dioxide than the company emits by the end of the decade, might have faced a bill of $9.6 billion to remove the company’s 2020 emissions. To help bring costs down and make good on its commitment, Microsoft also launched a $1 billion Climate Innovation Fund. But far more investment will be needed for the tech to become cheap and widely available.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The other technologies that Gates’ Catalyst Program focuses on will similarly need a lot of help to get off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kkK9D3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22882648/bill-gates-climate-fund-breakthrough-energy-rfp-europe-us"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22882648/bill-gates-climate-fund-breakthrough-energy-rfp-europe-us</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T08:46:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T08:46:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Jack Dorsey’s Block is working to decentralize Bitcoin mining</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Bitcoin Conference Draws Cryptocurrency Fans To Miami" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SBtxAbmqdGMjG78Cul5Dk2dPqF8=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70387359/1321753348.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JflC7D"&gt;Block, the payment company formerly known as Square, is working on building an “open Bitcoin mining system,” its &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1481745463401500676"&gt;CEO Jack Dorsey has announced&lt;/a&gt;. In a thread, Block’s general manager for hardware &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TempletonThomas/status/1481728144071561221"&gt;Thomas Templeton outlined&lt;/a&gt; the company’s goals for the system, which is for it to be easily available, reliable, performant, and relatively power efficient compared to its hashrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZPgPO"&gt;The overall aim is to make mining more decentralized, in turn making the overall Bitcoin network more resilient. As the cryptocurrency’s value has increased, and it’s become more challenging to mine without economies of scale, there have been fears that the network has become &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-01-31/bitcoin-s-network-operations-are-controlled-by-five-companies?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;centralized on too small a group of miners&lt;/a&gt;. Making mining more decentralized is “a long-term need for a future that is fully decentralized and permissionless,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TempletonThomas/status/1481728134001033217"&gt;Templeton says&lt;/a&gt;. But the plans could be controversial given &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwin-6uTqbH1AhWilFwKHaEpBDYQFnoECAoQAw&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2Finteractive%2F2021%2F09%2F03%2Fclimate%2Fbitcoin-carbon-footprint-electricity.html&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1Cqd9-TaGQ4SKrj6VzzHCj"&gt;how energy intensive&lt;/a&gt; mining Bitcoin tends to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wP3dSy"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We want to make mining more distributed and efficient in every way, from buying, to set up, to maintenance, to mining. We’re interested because mining goes far beyond creating new bitcoin. We see it as a long-term need for a future that is fully decentralized and permissionless.&lt;/p&gt;— Thomas Templeton (@TempletonThomas) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TempletonThomas/status/1481728134001033217?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 13, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1tx2Y4"&gt;According to Templeton, Block is open to building its own ASIC (a custom chip optimized for a single purpose — in this case mining Bitcoin), but that the team will also include software designers. The aim is to build a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TempletonThomas/status/1481728144071561221"&gt;high performance integrated system that’s also open-source&lt;/a&gt;. Dorsey has previously said he wants Bitcoin mining to be “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1449110250058096640"&gt;as easy as plugging a rig into a power source&lt;/a&gt;,” and that he sees value in a mining system that’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1449110247776342018"&gt;vertically integrated&lt;/a&gt; across hardware and software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2y9slK"&gt;As well as its mining system, in July last year Block (then Square) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/8/22569309/square-hardware-wallet-bitcoin-jack-dorsey"&gt;announced it was building a Bitcoin hardware wallet&lt;/a&gt; with the aim of making “Bitcoin custody more mainstream.” Square also previously allowed its customers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/14/17689156/square-cash-expands-bitcoin-support-to-all-50-us-states"&gt;buy and sell Bitcoin using its Cash App&lt;/a&gt;. Dorsey has long been an avid supporter of Bitcoin, and his Twitter bio continues to simply be “#Bitcoin.” He earlier talked about his desire for Block to build a Bitcoin mining system &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1449110239442345995"&gt;in October&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883500/jack-dorsey-block-bitcoin-mining-system-open-source-mainstream"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883500/jack-dorsey-block-bitcoin-mining-system-open-source-mainstream</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
