<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-17T21:20:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T21:20:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T21:20:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon is in talks to buy MGM for $9 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="MGM Logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wegblktq-oWrF2eqz4NAKJbeeSk=/0x43:1024x726/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69302360/mgm-logo.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SHv5gJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;James Bond&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rocky&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Robocop&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Legally Blonde&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Vikings&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MGM_Holdings#Content_libraries"&gt;a historic catalog&lt;/a&gt; of films dating back many decades, an array of production and distribution companies, and the content network Epix — these are the things that Amazon might own if it buys storied film giant MGM for billions of dollars in the very near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y7ZW6h"&gt;Amazon has reportedly offered $9 billion for the company, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/amazon-mgm-acquisition-talks-9-billion-1234975168/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, following &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/amazon-pondering-deal-to-buy-mgm?"&gt;a scoop from &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; earlier in the day that suggested a range of $7-10 billion for a potential deal, and &lt;em&gt;Variety &lt;/em&gt;suggests that $9 billion was &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; the amount that MGM was reportedly hoping to get. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IzrCGA"&gt;Between those factors, the fact that MGM has been up for sale since December 2020, and the jealousy that comes with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439964/at-t-warnermedia-discovery-merger-spin-off"&gt;sudden impending existence of a new media giant earlier today as AT&amp;amp;T spins off WarnerMedia and combines it with Discovery&lt;/a&gt;, it wouldn’t be very surprising if Amazon and MGM made a deal. &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; was slightly less bullish in its report today, though, writing that “The status of Amazon’s discussions with MGM is unclear and it’s possible no deal will result.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tc4EHb"&gt;In December, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2020/dec/22/hollywood-giant-mgm-puts-itself-up-for-sale-at-5bn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that MGM has a library of 4,000 films and 17,000 hours of TV. James Bond in particular is &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_highest-grossing_films#Highest-grossing_franchises_and_film_series"&gt;one of the most valuable film franchises ever made&lt;/a&gt; — a list that’s only growing smaller as the Disney umbrella and Marvel Cinematic Universe swallow as many rivals as it can. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D92P09"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441330/amazon-mgm-offer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441330/amazon-mgm-offer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T21:02:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T21:02:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Kindle deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VfQnBwLbLIeiZEVOPMuNUumuNok=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67715739/akrales_190723_3560_0016.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MyfWR7"&gt;When it comes to finding a device to use to read your ebooks, you have a few options to choose from. You can always buy a tablet or simply use your smartphone, but those devices are multipurpose and can be used for a ton of things, like surfing the web or doom-scrolling through Twitter. If you are looking for something to strictly read books, e-readers, while a niche piece of tech, are designed to store all of your books in a virtual library with no other functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pDKHVT"&gt;Amazon has dominated the space for years with its Kindle products. Right now, there are three Kindle models you can choose from, each with pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JRHBaM"&gt;Below, we’ve listed each of the current Kindles available for purchase. Sometimes, there isn’t a deal for one or, in some instances, all of the products. In that case, we’ve mentioned the most recent sale price so you know when is a good time to buy the e-reader at a discounted rate. But most of the time, there’s some deal going on. Whether you’re looking for a new model or to grab a bundle that includes a few extras, these are the best Kindle deals right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jqPttv"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/4/10/18302177/amazon-kindle-base-model-low-resolution-screen-backlight-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle (10th Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="mXAcFi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10363966"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hfprjz"&gt;This is Amazon’s most affordable e-reader, usually costing $90. Released in 2019, this base Kindle model includes a front light, comes in one storage configuration of 8GB, and comes with or without ad support. Despite including the same 167ppi resolution as its predecessors, this model has slightly higher contrast than earlier models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pIAlEv"&gt;Right now, you can buy &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07978J597?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a 10th-gen Kindle with lockscreen ads&lt;/a&gt; for $90, which is its usual price. If you want &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VZV5VB?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=1ccac7c6dd4bb605e9b24952e83a00de&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one without ads&lt;/a&gt;, you can grab it for the usual price of $110. Both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VT322X?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VZV5VB?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;models&lt;/a&gt; also have a promotion where you can receive three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTnhuW"&gt;If you want to save some money on additional accessories for the e-reader, Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Essentials-including-Amazon-Printed-Adapter/dp/B08C6NDPFM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Essentials Bundle&lt;/a&gt; is $120 ($15 off its usual price); it includes one of three printed covers and a power adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RkX3DN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ze80m8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/10/7/20902588/kindle-kids-edition-amazon-bundle-young-e-reader-case-replacement-program-freetime"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Kids Edition (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JypT34"&gt;The entry-level Kindle and Oasis models were not the only ones that received a refresh in 2019, Amazon also announced and released a Kindle Kids Edition Bundle, which provides age-appropriate content for younger readers who prefer digital books for $110 ($20 more than the base Kindle). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6LlYfl"&gt;The Kindle Kids Edition consists of five items: the device, a case, a two-year extended replacement guarantee (in the event the device breaks), and one year of Amazon’s FreeTime Unlimited service. The latter is the biggest selling point of the device aside from the kid-friendly patterns, as it allows parents to grant their kids access to a digital library of kid-friendly books like &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Hobbit &lt;/em&gt;at no additional cost. You can grab one for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07NMY72SC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its normal price of $110&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N7AYlh"&gt;Right now, Amazon is also offering the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Essentials-including-Protector-Adapter/dp/B07XW24MVK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Kids Edition Essentials Bundle, which is $128&lt;/a&gt; and includes all of the things previously mentioned above, plus a screen protector and power adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3DEvBp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552664"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="t6m9om"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18065960/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2018-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Paperwhite (Fourth Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="P1C5xu"&gt;Amazon released the fourth-generation Kindle Paperwhite in 2018. Starting at $130, the Paperwhite comes in three different configurations: 8GB Wi-Fi, 32GB Wi-Fi, and a second 32GB model that drops the ads from the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qneu65"&gt;The Paperwhite features a six-inch, pin-sharp backlit display, which is the main reason to get one over the base Kindle. The 2018 model added a few useful features normally found on Amazon’s flagship reader, the Oasis, such as water resistance and Audible audiobook support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UaH6Zy"&gt;No deals are currently available, but if you want to buy one in the near future, the Kindle Paperwhite is on sale for the price it usually tends to sell for; you can buy an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PQ96B6B?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB Kindle Paperwhite with ad support&lt;/a&gt; for $130 or for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PTCW9G7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$150 without ads&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more space, Amazon is selling the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PP49ZDW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB Paperwhite with ads for $160&lt;/a&gt;; if you want an ad-free model, you can buy &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PT96B3T?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this configuration for $180&lt;/a&gt;. Just like the base Kindle, Amazon currently running a promotion where you can grab the e-reader plus three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Emeowb"&gt;Amazon also discounted its Kindle Paperwhite Essentials Bundle, which includes either an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HL49FCK/ref=mako_bundletwister_mt1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB e-reader bundle for $170&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HKT4M5K/ref=mako_bundletwister_mt1?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$200 if you buy the 32GB&lt;/a&gt; (with ads). If you’re a fan of Suzanne Collins’ Hunger Games trilogy, Amazon also offers a bundle that includes a Kindle Paperwhite, a power adapter, and a Mockingjay-emblazoned cover. It’s currently available in two ad-supported configurations and colors: an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NMH2F7?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB version for $160&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NM77FC?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB variant for $190&lt;/a&gt;, both of which save you $20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vOUHwk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552401"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="X5jbTU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707619/amazon-kindle-oasis-2019-e-reader-review-price-specs-features-display"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Oasis (Third Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IByP4u"&gt;The Kindle Oasis is the most expensive of the lineup, starting at $250. The device comes in two storage configurations, 8GB or 32GB, and like the other models, you can get the product with or without ads on the lockscreen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AvXZM"&gt;The Kindle Oasis 2019 model looks very similar to its previous model. It still maintains its waterproof, seven-inch, 300ppi E Ink display and supports Audible audiobooks by connecting to Bluetooth. Yet, the biggest change to the Kindle Oasis 2019 is that it can adjust the color temperature to a yellow-toned display, making it easier to read at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxP7sb"&gt;In the past, we have seen the Kindle Oasis go down to as low as $200 if you get the 32GB model, which is the lowest it has ever been for that configuration to date. While there are currently no deals on just the Oasis itself, you can grab one of the many configurations plus three free months of Kindle Unlimited for the normal price starting at $250. The ad-supported &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VHV8D7P?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB Oasis&lt;/a&gt; is $250 and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VDMJJLG?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one without ads is $270&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more storage, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VCMJSLB?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB version is $280 with ads&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VGTRMFS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$300 without&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuGlPY"&gt;Amazon is currently offering an Essentials Bundle for $30 off its normal list price. You can get either the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RNPKRKW/ref=mako_bundletwister_cg1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB, ad-support configuration for $290&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RSTQZ9M/ref=mako_bundletwister_cg1?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB variant for $320&lt;/a&gt;, both of which come with a leather cover, a power adapter, and three months of Kindle Unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hPPu8s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552599"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T20:46:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T20:46:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple HomePod and HomePod mini can’t play lossless Apple Music, either</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uXp9y9T3Sq1JLdxDiA3OqH9LwiY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69302215/dseifert_201107_4281_0009.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wpQZWb"&gt;Today, we learned that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440788/apple-airpods-max-lossless-music-explainer-spatial-audio"&gt;Apple’s ultra-premium $550 AirPods Max headphones aren’t ready for the new lossless audio catalog&lt;/a&gt; coming to Apple Music next month — and they’re not alone. Apple confirms to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that the HomePod and HomePod mini won’t support lossless audio, either. (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/05/17/homepod-wont-support-lossless-audio/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; confirmed the same thing with sources&lt;/a&gt; earlier this afternoon.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="brjFbG"&gt;The good news is that the HomePod and HomePod mini will indeed support the company’s new &lt;em&gt;spacial&lt;/em&gt; audio experiences, which are supposed to provide more immersive audio than a standard stereo or virtual surround mix — we were fairly intrigued &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;trying spacial audio on the AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s also coming to Apple Music next month in a bigger way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z13Cjy"&gt;And, Apple says, it’s not like any of these devices will fail to play back lossless tracks completely. They simply won’t be playing them at lossless quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kNasQp"&gt;Still, it seems like one more reason that Apple should really strongly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434783/apple-homepod-stock-problems-discontinued-sale"&gt;consider having a fire sale for the original HomePod&lt;/a&gt;, which is somehow still available for a increasingly hard-to-justify $300 months after officially being discontinued. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441305/lossless-apple-music-homepod-homepod-mini"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441305/lossless-apple-music-homepod-homepod-mini</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T20:41:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T20:41:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s Phil Schiller gives Epic iPhone testimony</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple Trial With Epic Threatens To Reveal App Store’s Commission Bounty" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0gRFHHDFdCsbRL8vZvs0WOukzLk=/0x0:2738x1825/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69302193/1232892504.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;What does ‘locked in’ mean, though?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="cbiQUK"&gt;We’ve gotten through the expert witnesses of &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt;, and as a reward, Phil Schiller — currently an “Apple Fellow,” whatever that is, and previously the senior vice president of worldwide marketing — took the stand like a twinkly App Store St. Nick. To hear him tell it, Apple is a wonderful partner to developers, selflessly improving dev tools and responding to their needs. At times the testimony feels like a prolonged ad for iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="167QOY"&gt;The goal of the testimony is to paint the App Store as a part of the iPhone that can’t be removed or replaced by a competing alternative. To this end, we heard in exhaustive detail about the improvements made to the iPhone that benefit the developers in the App Store. The chips. The Retina display. The accelerometer. The wireless upgrades. It’s practically an Apple event on the stand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IlcpDk"&gt;Among the exhaustive list, Schiller identified Metal, one of the developer tools Apple created. (Metal is a play on “close to the metal,” or writing code that’s close to the computer’s guts.) Apple’s counsel says the lawyer version of “roll tape!” and we’re treated to a 20 second clip of Tim Sweeney on stage at WWDC, praising Metal as a wonderful tool that will allow developers like Epic Games to create the next generation of improvements. Solid burn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="YVz0CV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Schiller’s testimony spends some quality time back in 2007&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pRIZcI"&gt;The overall impression I get from the list of improvements is, essentially, that &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; absolutely could not have launched on the first generation of iPhones — the hardware and chips couldn’t have handled the game. That is true! Also: &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;didn’t exist yet, so that’s a pretty good reason it couldn’t have been on those early iPhones. But there is another reason a time-traveling &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; couldn’t have launched on the first iPhones in 2007: the App Store didn’t exist yet, either. This particular fact is somewhat inconvenient for Apple’s argument that the iPhone and the App Store are inseparable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pKRVeo"&gt;Schiller’s testimony spends some quality time back in 2007, to explain the origin of the App Store. When the iPhone launched, the only apps on it were Apple’s own; all other apps were web apps. In response, there was a spate of “jailbreaking” — essentially, hacking the iPhone so you could put your own apps on it. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; was the genesis of the App Store: Apple realizing that people were going to put their own apps on the iPhone no matter what it did. If it wanted control of the process, it was going to have to create an official route. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOIOKP"&gt;From the jump, security was going to be a concern, Schiller said. After all, the point of the phone was that you could &lt;em&gt;carry it around&lt;/em&gt; — which involved collecting location data. So iOS was built from the ground up with this in mind, Schiller says. (This line of testimony is a rebuttal to Epic’s argument that MacOS allows side-loading, and it is therefore anticompetitive that iOS does not.) To put a stop to the jailbreaking, Apple did something unusual: rather than showing the world a finished product, it announced it was &lt;em&gt;working on something&lt;/em&gt;. That something was the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="dpS1zb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Look, “locked in” has an accepted meaning, and it’s not a very friendly one&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ey5O2Q"&gt;The Steve Jobs line that Epic has touted — ”We don’t intend to make money off the App Store” — comes from these early days. At the time of this announcement, Apple didn’t know if it would make money, Schiller testified. He also suggests that the line was not a promise that Apple would &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;make money. The App Store was a “huge” risk, Schiller said. “We’re taking our hot new product and putting something we’ve never done before on it, and we have no apps yet! So we have no idea how this is going to do.” This is credible. What is less convincing is Schiller’s attempt to redefine what it means to “lock customers into our ecosystem,” a phrase that comes from a Jobs email entered into evidence earlier in the trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lX3kF0"&gt;Look, “locked in” has an accepted meaning, and it’s not a very friendly one: prisoners, for example, are locked in. Schiller gives this the old college try anyhow, telling the court that the idea behind “locked in” was just to make services more attractive, so that customers wouldn’t want to leave. Later in the email, Jobs talks about making the ecosystem even more “sticky,” which is less menacing, but — glue traps are sticky. So are flystrips. When was the last time that being stuck to something was positive for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4b3Eox"&gt;But hey, Schiller’s a marketer. He was Apple’s marketing guy for &lt;em&gt;actual decades&lt;/em&gt;! Always be closing, baby. And so if it at times seemed like he presented Apple as though it were a selfless do-gooder, responding to devs’ requests for in-app payments — which was a then-nascent business — by building capability for that into the store, well, that’s his job. Still, presenting one of the most ruthlessly efficient cash machines in tech as a helpful friend of small developers is kind of like painting a whale shark orange and calling it a goldfish who feeds other goldfish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i9PVvV"&gt;Despite Schiller’s friendly demeanor, some of his testimony is a stretch. For instance, he says he doesn’t see mobile as a duopoly. He lists Samsung, Microsoft, Google, and Amazon as competition. The Amazon Fire phone was discontinued in 2015, as was the Windows Phone. Perhaps they haunt his dreams, but they certainly don’t haunt the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="VbCnf0"&gt;But Schiller mostly does what he needs to do for Apple — as I suppose he has for 30-odd years. He’s cheerful, pleasant to listen to, and at times, very convincing. The question in this case, though, is if marketing to a judge is as easy as marketing to Apple customers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441304/apple-phil-schiller-epic-iphone-testimony-app-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441304/apple-phil-schiller-epic-iphone-testimony-app-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T20:17:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T20:17:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oculus’ latest Quest update lets you record gameplay and yourself at the same time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Oculus Live Overlay" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qx2j4P7bOpiv5Rz3lbJiNRL73EQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69300645/oculusliveoverlay.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Oculus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PO5Lxs"&gt;Oculus will soon roll out its v29 software for Quest and Quest 2 headsets, and this one adds more features and functionality to the lineup. The most exciting one is a new Live Overlay casting feature that will give you an easy way to capture a view of you using VR superimposed over the content displayed in first-person within your headset. Any VR app that supports casting and recording will work with this feature, according to Oculus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uUoflT"&gt;All you’ll need is at least an iPhone XS or newer, a Quest headset, and the Oculus app for iOS updated to a new version that’s coming to “a subset of users.” Then you turn on the feature and have someone aim the camera at you (or aim it at yourself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TzQWF1"&gt;If this sounds familiar, you might be thinking of &lt;a href="https://creator.oculus.com/mrc/"&gt;Oculus’ Mixed Reality Creator Tool&lt;/a&gt; (MRC) for Quest and Rift S. That app requires a capable PC, including a rig with 16GB of RAM, a decent graphics card, your own 1080p webcam, a 5GHz Wi-Fi router, and — of course — your own green screen. The big difference according to Oculus is that the Mixed Reality Capture Tool “synchronizes the person perfectly with VR, whereas Live Overlay places the user over a first-person casting view.” So, while mixed reality &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nRywAihJ2jM"&gt;shows you actually doing cool things in virtual environments&lt;/a&gt;, Live Overlay appears to show what you see through the headset with you standing in the same frame, like the image above illustrates. Still, it’s impressive if you’re a creator who wants to show off gameplay and themselves in the same clip with minimal effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X239Dy"&gt;In other casting news, Oculus is allowing you to capture what you’re saying into your headset’s built-in microphone during casting sessions or when you’re recording a video clip. It’s also extending multi-user support and the app sharing feature to owners of the original Quest, so multiple people can share games on a single headset. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289577/facebook-rolling-out-multi-user-support-oculus-quest-2"&gt;These features were originally limited to the Quest 2&lt;/a&gt;, but Oculus is making good on its pledge to bring them to the Quest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Oculus files app" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IepGoo1U9sDFI_bY0nFAkTrx9lA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22520891/oculusfilemanager.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4REj2I"&gt;There’s a Files app coming with this update, and it’ll be located within your app library. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Fsee-yourself-in-vr-with-live-overlay-plus-new-infinite-office-features-and-more-in-latest-oculus-update%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oculus says in its blog post&lt;/a&gt; that you’ll be able to download and upload media files “to and from your favorite websites” through the browser built into the headset. In other words, it should be a lot easier to upload content to social media sites other than Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S5LvsE"&gt;The last couple of additions include an Infinite Office update that lets iOS users (using an iPhone 7 and newer, with Android support coming soon) see lock screen notifications from within a Quest headset. Oculus is also adding a shortcut for its Passthrough command to the user interface in the Quick Settings menu, giving you an alternative method of triggering it instead of physically double-tapping the side of your headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0SmwFs"&gt;Lastly, Oculus will begin showing ads for VR experiences within the mobile app with the intent to broaden discovery for both developers looking for an audience and users to find new content. This could be useful for smaller developers who have built quality experiences but don’t have the awareness of more popular apps. That said, if you’re a curious Quest owner looking for new experiences, I suggest checking out SideQuest on PC or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22395923/sidequest-android-app-sideload-oculus-quest-2-virtual-reality-apps-games-experiences"&gt;from an Android phone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4iCgsa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Capcom’s Resident Evil 4 VR remake launches this year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396528/capcom-resident-evil-4-oculus-quest-2-remake-trailer-footage-launch-date"},{"title":"All about Oculus’ new, more expressive avatars","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398060/oculus-new-avatars-editor-features-vr-virtual-reality-facebook-quest-rift"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="gDgrCc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: The new Live Overlay mode is not a full mixed-reality mode where you can film someone moving around inside a VR environment from the outside; it primarily shows a first-person view. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440683/oculus-v29-live-overlay-mixed-reality-capture-mic-files-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440683/oculus-v29-live-overlay-mixed-reality-capture-mic-files-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T19:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T19:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>London’s electric scooter trials will kick off on June 7th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Storm Alex Batters The South Of England" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KREyRNEUAXCqRLJYyXMBeoZi2Fs=/0x0:4188x2792/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69301865/1278013956.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electric scooters have become a common sight on London’s roads, even while their use has remained illegal.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Leon Neal/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="btxLkZ"&gt;London’s long-awaited electric scooter trials will begin next month on June 7th, the city’s transport authority and local councils announced today. Three scooter companies have been selected to offer rentals for up to 12 months as part of the pilot program: Dott, Lime, and Tier. Privately owned electric scooters will continue to be illegal to ride on streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LCUUE8"&gt;The selected companies will initially offer scooters to rent across six boroughs and local authorities in London: Ealing, Hammersmith and Fulham, Kensington and Chelsea, Richmond upon Thames, the City of London, and Canary Wharf. While rentals will not be available in Tower Hamlets, Londoners will be able to ride their rented scooters through the borough. Lambeth and Southwark boroughs are also seeking to participate in the trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jI4iWg"&gt;This might sound like a long list of areas, but it’s just a fraction of the 32 boroughs that make up the UK’s capital. London’s transport authority Transport for London (TfL) says more areas are expected to join the trial as it progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="A3h8iK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The trials will only cover a small portion of the city&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KZuVWD"&gt;While rented electric scooters have become a common sight across many cities around the world, the UK has been much slower to embrace the new form of transport. Until recently, electric scooters were completely illegal to ride on British streets. It was only in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21307974/uk-electric-scooter-rentals-legal-public-roads-micro-mobility"&gt;July last year&lt;/a&gt; that the situation started to change, with the government allowing trials of electric scooter rentals. But outside of the pilot programs, privately owned electric scooters are still illegal to ride on public roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KP1OU7"&gt;TfL’s announcement specifically cites the pandemic as a key reason for the importance of the new method of transport. Rather than having people flock to cars as a way of avoiding crowded buses and trains, authorities want electric scooters to offer an environmentally friendly and socially distanced way of getting around. “We’re doing all we can to support London’s safe and sustainable recovery from the coronavirus pandemic and it’s clear that e-scooters could act as an innovative, greener alternative to car trips,” said TfL’s electric scooter trial lead Helen Sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mcy2cc"&gt;Each electric scooter rental company will have to comply with a host of safety requirements to offer rentals in the city. Speeds will be capped at 12.5 miles per hour (reducing to eight miles per hour in specified “go-slow” areas), and scooters will be required to have always-on front and rear lights. They’re also required to have “audible warning systems” that riders can operate without taking their hands off the handlebars. The scooters will also be equipped with geofencing to ensure that they’re correctly parked in designated locations, and operators will have to collect them if they’re not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XCQny8"&gt;Scooters can be ridden on roads and cycle paths but not on sidewalks. When the government announced the start of the trials last year, it said riders would have to be over the age of 16 and have at least a provisional car, motorcycle, or moped license to ride. We’ve reached out to TfL to clarify whether these requirements will apply to the London trials. Riders will also need to take an “e-learning safety course” before hiring their first scooter in the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vctCy5"&gt;London will be far from the first city in the UK to have launched its electric scooter trials. &lt;a href="https://mindthezag.com/places/where-are-the-uks-e-scooter-trials/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zag &lt;/em&gt;has compiled a list&lt;/a&gt; of over 50 trials that have been launched across the country over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hswD65"&gt;&lt;q&gt;London is the latest UK city to announce a trial&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XTI0FN"&gt;Despite technically being illegal to use on public streets, privately owned electric scooters have become an increasingly common sight in London. National retailers &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.halfords.com%2Fscooters%2Felectric-scooters%2F%3Fcm_mmc%3DGoogle-_-KZ%2520-%2520Kids%2520Scooters%2520-%2520Own%2520Brand-_-Electric%2520Scooters%2520Exact-_-ad%26source%3Dppc%26_%2524ja%3Dtsid%3A35522%257Ccid%3A9696423349%257Cagid%3A96673753582%257Ctid%3Akwd-440281686218%257Ccrid%3A427046351899%257Cnw%3Ag%257Crnd%3A17179386706488057195%257Cdvc%3Ac%257Cadp%3A%257Cmt%3Ae%257Cloc%3A9045992%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwqIiFBhAHEiwANg9szmYVfaHPyq6JDYzbIUbfUev_aoZ_RTpvdFwpCEK-YIlA16vnObSx8xoC27gQAvD_BwE&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F17%2F22440320%2Flondon-electric-scooter-rental-trial-dott-lime-tier" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;like Halfords&lt;/a&gt; sell a range of models, although Halfords’ website carries a warning that they’re only legal on private property with the owner’s permission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bBp41A"&gt;The three scooter operators chosen for London’s trials already offer rentals in other cities around the world. Dott offers rentals across 16 cities in Europe, while Tier serves 100 cities across 12 countries. As well as offering electric scooter rentals in other cities, Lime has previously offered electric bike rentals in London. Notably absent from the list is Bird, which has offered electric scooter rentals on private property in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/6/18067670/bird-electric-scooters-uk-london-pilot-launch-european-expansion"&gt;London’s Olympic Park&lt;/a&gt;. London has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21335611/paris-electric-scooter-competition-lime-tier-dott-bird"&gt;joined Paris&lt;/a&gt; in deciding against allowing the company to operate on its streets, even after it announced a massive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22332624/bird-europe-investment-scooter-expansion-new-hires"&gt;$150 million European expansion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Cx9GC"&gt;As well as setting their own pricing, individual scooter operators are offering some unique features. Tier, for example, is installing charging pods in local businesses across the city and will give users free rides if they exchange their scooters’ drained battery for a fully charged one at a charging station. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u60Xn6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNMDvU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440320/london-electric-scooter-rental-trial-dott-lime-tier"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440320/london-electric-scooter-rental-trial-dott-lime-tier</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T18:22:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T18:22:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fox is making a blockchain animated series with Rick and Morty creator Dan Harmon to sell you NFTs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kh_SQ-qyc-RKJBiWLwPRYOobqgQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69301717/acastro_210329_1777_nft_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PsTsrk"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fox.com/krapopolis/"&gt;Fox has announced&lt;/a&gt; its upcoming animated comedy &lt;em&gt;Krapopolis, &lt;/em&gt;from &lt;em&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/em&gt; creator Dan Harmon, will be “the first-ever animated series curated entirely on the Blockchain.” The company plans to try to generate buzz for the show with its own brand-new NFT company dubbed Blockchain Creative Labs, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/dan-harmon-blockchain-nft-crypto-series-fox-1234954403/"&gt;THR reports&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZdCdpm"&gt;Fox Entertainment CEO Charlie Collier told advertisers during its upfronts presentation on Monday that “as an advertiser-focused, artist-first and animation-obsessed company, Fox is going to take advertisers into the world of Blockchain-powered tokens, including NFTs.” It will launch a dedicated marketplace for &lt;em&gt;Krapopolis&lt;/em&gt;, a show set in mythical ancient Greece “centered on a flawed family of humans, gods, and monsters that tries to run one of the world’s first cities without killing each other.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="EoCpCN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VfrI0E"&gt;The marketplace will “curate and sell digital goods ranging from NFTs of one-of-a-kind character and background art and GIFs, as well as tokens that provide exclusive social experiences to engage and reward super fans,” according to Fox. Characters and artwork from the show will become NFT collectibles — because why let the internet GIF your show for free when you can sell them GIFs as NFTs? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zflZ6Q"&gt;NFTs of some well-known memes have proven lucrative for their creators, including &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/bad-luck-brian-meme-nft-crypto-art-blockchain-ethereum-foundation-2021-3"&gt;Bad Luck Brian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/grumpycat/grumpy-cat-5467"&gt;Grumpy Cat&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/keyboardcat/play-him-off-keyboard-cat-5553"&gt;Keyboard Cat&lt;/a&gt;. The image of Disaster Girl, whose real name is Zoe Roth, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410070/disaster-girl-popular-meme-nft-500000-dollars"&gt;went for $500,000&lt;/a&gt;, and Nyan Cat’s creator Chris Torres sold &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/22/business/nft-nba-top-shot-crypto.html"&gt;that meme for nearly $600,000&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4iw8vd"&gt;A whole show that will produce NFT-ready content is a new twist on the idea, however, and counts on &lt;em&gt;Krapopolis&lt;/em&gt; becoming popular enough to attract bidders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zlbAdi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"NFTs, explained","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="mTF4cX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441078/fox-blockchain-animated-series-dan-harmon-nft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441078/fox-blockchain-animated-series-dan-harmon-nft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T17:45:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T17:45:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is teasing a big Wear OS update for smartwatches tomorrow at I/O</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Fossil Gen 5 with LTE smartwatch" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lqyZHnqBfYotUc-pRzfO6BgRGn4=/0x2:7952x5303/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69301515/FSL3748731_SP21_AD_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Fossil&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ohIG8n"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WearOSbyGoogle/status/1394357382747144194?s=20"&gt;new tweet&lt;/a&gt; from the official Wear OS Twitter account is teasing an update &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371782/google-io-2021-date-announcement-virtual-online-event-date-android"&gt;tomorrow at I/O 2021&lt;/a&gt; to Google’s frequently forgotten smartwatch operating system. Google has even suggested that the developer conference will feature an entirely new version of Wear OS on the I/O Adventure page, the “virtual sandbox” for trying the products Google will announce at the conference, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/05/17/brand-new-wear-version-google-i-o/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google &lt;/em&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zldiUh"&gt;Wear OS has been on a long and bumpy journey up until this point — with new features, but not the dramatic rethinking of the platform that it may need. In the last year, Google has added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423707/google-wear-os-gboard-swipe-type"&gt;a new keyboard&lt;/a&gt;, support for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22328909/google-third-party-developers-tiles-wear-os"&gt;third-party Tiles&lt;/a&gt; (Wear OS’s answer to glanceable widget-like information), and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366514/google-wear-os-fall-update-smartwatch-faster-apps-weather-pairing"&gt;improvements to performance&lt;/a&gt;. But the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/28/17912358/wear-os-2-1-smartwatches-software-update"&gt;last major design change&lt;/a&gt; to Wear OS — other than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/1/18525335/google-wear-os-tiles-widgets-new-feature-announced"&gt;the addition of Tiles&lt;/a&gt; — came in 2018. If anything, Google’s tease is a welcome sign of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ktzQgu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The time has come for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GoogleIO&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Join us tomorrow for a look at what’s new on Wear OS. &lt;a href="https://t.co/ylGiIevTc4"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ylGiIevTc4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Wear OS by Google (@WearOSbyGoogle) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WearOSbyGoogle/status/1394357382747144194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="u3S2S8"&gt;Both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/17/18187026/google-fossil-group-smartwatch-sale-40-million-wear-os-android"&gt;Google’s acquisition of Fossil’s smartwatch tech&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20943993/google-fitbit-acquisition-smartwatch-wearable-fitness-nest-htc-hardware-software"&gt;its plans to acquire Fitbit&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, reignited the hope that it would also acquire a renewed interest in wearables as a concept. The process of absorbing Fitbit in particular was drawn out for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21347798/eu-google-fitbit-acquisition-investigation-rumors"&gt;health data privacy concerns&lt;/a&gt; that came with it, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22188428/google-fitbit-acquisition-completed-approved"&gt;the deal was ultimately approved in 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aNJT7x"&gt;In the meantime, Google’s other wearable partners kept the platform on life support. Fossil’s watches — like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/28/20835364/fossil-wear-os-smartwatch-android-gen-5-review-price-specs-features"&gt;the 2019 Gen 5&lt;/a&gt; and 2021 Gen 5 LTE — were frequently limited by the subpar performance of Qualcomm’s smartwatch processors. Mobvoi took a different approach with its 2021 TicWatch Pro 3, by skinning Wear OS, layering in an extra display, and filling the watch with a suite of custom apps, but still ran into some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/7/22314135/ticwatch-pro-3-fossil-gen-5-lte-review-smartwatch-wear-os"&gt;inherently Wear OS-type issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8tEk3o"&gt;But back to the hope on the horizon: Google is teasing a new Wear OS version, and there are rumors of some hardware to back that up — Samsung is reportedly dropping its Tizen OS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439989/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-wear-os-tizen-switch"&gt;in exchange for using Google’s software&lt;/a&gt; on its next smartwatches. With a big powerful new partner, a wearable team of its own, and the possibility of Android 12’s rumored &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/16/22438065/new-leaks-ahead-google-io-android-12-big-changes"&gt;new visual design&lt;/a&gt; coming to Wear OS, it suddenly seems like Google might have a plan for your wrist. We’ll have to watch this week to see how promising that plan actually is.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440834/google-wear-os-update-io-2021-smartwatch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440834/google-wear-os-update-io-2021-smartwatch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T17:15:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T17:15:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hugo Barra is leaving Facebook </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Mark Zuckerberg Addresses F8 Facebook Developer Conference" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O0NfCB29zgujgdz27DD2UCEOJ1c=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69301316/953502230.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OkN4JM"&gt;Facebook’s vice president of AR and VR Hugo Barra is leaving the company, he announced (where else) &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/hbarra76/posts/10157618478316612"&gt;on Facebook Monday&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xfMh6v"&gt;“Today is my last day at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/facebookrealitylabs/?__cft__%5B0%5D=AZX2UjmeNgpyMfjeRfjrmWG0FmYcWpqLoUAq4Q_UN1yNAKjw8-Wxj8BHgwCPA2Zupfzuawfl6sVU_ISkvkxBPTJbg5aH79f5Cfo1YzZueKATci6RIi5fpMt79ybbqiVTIHIKja3PD7xMNdRtEpdJjnfD&amp;amp;__tn__=kK-R"&gt;Facebook Reality Labs&lt;/a&gt;, after 4 years working on projects that have been more exciting and more challenging than anything I’ve encountered in my career, with some of the brightest minds and kindest people I’ve ever had the pleasure to meet,” Barra wrote in the post. He said he planned to “explore the healthcare technology space,” so he could apply what he had learned in consumer tech to solve problems in health care. “I believe society is still poorly equipped with the tools people need to really understand our health and gain control over our health outcomes,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3WVBs4"&gt;After serving as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/8/28/4669960/android-vp-hugo-barra-reportedly-leaving-google-for-chinese"&gt;Google’s vice president of Android product management and then several years at Xiaomi&lt;/a&gt;, Barra joined Facebook in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/9/18563171/facebook-oculus-ar-vr-head-hugo-barra-stepping-down-new-role-jason-rubin-eric-tseng"&gt;2017 to run its Oculus VR team&lt;/a&gt;. In 2019, he moved to his current role, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hbarra/status/1126534172816728064"&gt;tasked with&lt;/a&gt; “building a global AR/VR partner ecosystem” based in New York City, which eventually became part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/14/18141524/facebook-building-8-reality-labs-ar-vr-portal-skunkworks-hardware-division"&gt;Facebook Reality Labs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tv10mK"&gt;Barra is leaving Facebook before the company launches its first pair of consumer “smart glasses,” which it said last year would be a branded Ray-Ban product. He touted the project on Twitter last September and mentioned the launch in his farewell note (but didn’t provide details about a release date other than “this year”). &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hbarra/status/1306279147778568194?s=20"&gt;Barra said development of the smart glasses&lt;/a&gt; became “his main focus at Facebook.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Nv3EYa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Beyond thrilled to finally share a sneak peek of our Facebook partnership with Ray-Ban! Our first smart glasses will launch next year, and that’s just the beginning… The future will be a classic and it's coming in 2021   &lt;a href="https://t.co/l9992ZQGoy"&gt;pic.twitter.com/l9992ZQGoy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Hugo Barra (@hbarra) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hbarra/status/1306278791669579776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 16, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="syhSIk"&gt;But after announcing in September that the smart glasses were coming sometime in 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/02/facebook-lowers-expectations-for-its-upcoming-ray-ban-smart-glasses.html"&gt;Facebook tried to temper expectations&lt;/a&gt; about the smart glasses; in March, CFO David Wehner said at a conference that the glasses wouldn’t be close to the technology Facebook eventually hopes to achieve in AR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3qkI1n"&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg thanked Barra for his work in a comment on Barra’s Facebook post: “Thanks for everything you’ve done to help build the next computing platform and the whole ecosystem around it,” Zuckerberg wrote. “I’ve learned so much working with you, and I’m excited to see what you build next.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BQ57dD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6xuLyr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440857/hugo-barra-leaving-facebook-ar-vr-oculus-google-xiaomi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440857/hugo-barra-leaving-facebook-ar-vr-oculus-google-xiaomi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-17T17:12:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-17T17:12:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>EV startup Canoo under SEC investigation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xQRigcZvoI3umu9FPQXUjWD6g1Q=/224x193:1535x1067/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69301279/Canoo_PickupTruck_ExteriorSnow_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Canoo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qv92fq"&gt;The Securities and Exchange Commission has opened an investigation into newly public electric vehicle startup Canoo, CEO Tony Aquila shared on a conference call on Monday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GwoI7w"&gt;The probe is broad, though the startup said in a &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/1750153/000155837021007431/goev-20210331x10q.htm"&gt;regulatory filing&lt;/a&gt; that the SEC has characterized it as a “fact-finding inquiry,” and that the agency has not yet concluded whether anyone violated the law. It covers Canoo’s merger with a special purpose acquisition company (or SPAC), plus its “operations, business model, revenues, revenue strategy, customer agreements, earnings and other related topics, along with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397356/canoo-cofounder-ulrich-kranz-resign-new-ceo-tony-aquila"&gt;the recent departures of certain of the Company’s officers&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Uy3fm"&gt;Canoo says it plans to provide all requested material and fully cooperate. Aquila declined to take any questions about the probe on the call, which was the startup’s second as a public company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vuFg4c"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Canoo says it will cooperate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JIWmfT"&gt;Canoo is one of a number of electric vehicle startups that went public by merging with a SPAC over the last year. These mergers provided a different path for these startups to go public than a traditional IPO. But since these mergers are regulated differently, it wound up giving startups more leeway in regards to their business projections. In April, the SEC said it would &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/09/sec-is-scrutinizing-spac-projections-seeks-clearer-disclosures.html"&gt;start taking a closer look at this discrepancy&lt;/a&gt; to make sure that investors weren’t being misled. Canoo received its notice from the SEC on April 29th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="88197m"&gt;A number of other newly-public EV startups are facing pressure from the SEC and various regulators. Lordstown Motors &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336751/lordstown-motors-sec-inquiry-review-hindenburg-investigation-orders"&gt;disclosed in March that the SEC is investigating&lt;/a&gt; whether the electric pickup truck startup misled investors. Hydrogen trucking startup Nikola also faces investigations from the SEC and the &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/11/10/nikola-discloses-grand-jury-subpoenas-from-doj.html"&gt;Department of Justice&lt;/a&gt; after being caught lying to investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="owidSY"&gt;Aquila stressed on the call that Canoo has been overly conservative with its projections to date, and also said the startup will be careful when reporting total deposits for its vehicles versus binding orders. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440287/canoo-electric-van-price-deposit-pickup-truck"&gt;startup began taking deposits&lt;/a&gt; for its electric van, pickup truck, and delivery vehicle earlier Monday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qCGdPO"&gt;Aquila came in as an investor last year around the beginning of the SPAC merger process, and quickly became Canoo’s executive chairman. He has since reoriented the startup’s business to be more focused on commercial vehicle sales. Aquila recently took over as CEO &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397356/canoo-cofounder-ulrich-kranz-resign-new-ceo-tony-aquila"&gt;after co-founder and former BMW executive Ulrich Kranz resigned&lt;/a&gt;. Kranz was the latest in a recent rash of departures from the startup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="etVmQG"&gt;On Canoo’s first quarterly investor call in March, Aquila announced that Canoo was pivoting away from providing engineering services to other companies, effectively killing a deal with Hyundai. He also obliquely referenced how some of the Canoo’s previous leadership made what he felt were “premature” statements about potential partnerships, though the startup was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sokane1/status/1376710472263696384"&gt;still promoting the Hyundai deal&lt;/a&gt; in January after he took over as chairman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gfmzqH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441025/canoo-sec-investigation-spac-merger-projections"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22441025/canoo-sec-investigation-spac-merger-projections</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
