<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-21T10:07:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:07:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:07:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro are available refurbished for 45 percent off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xq1PmTsFLqaQPVE1ypbttjwo35w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162616/bfarsace_210114_4372_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OpjJdW"&gt;At Best Buy, you can get a refurbished set of the Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro truly wireless earbuds &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738397414024596357#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $110 today in the silver colorway&lt;/a&gt;. This model released just a few months ago alongside the Samsung Galaxy S21, and at most retailers they still sell for their original $200 price. The lowest price we’ve seen recently for a new set is $165, and that’s bound to happen again at some point. But if you’re all about saving money, this refurbished deal can’t be beat. The Galaxy Buds Pro provide the “best sound quality yet for Samsung earbuds,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to audio expert and &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;reviewer Chris Welch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kBLnKJ"&gt;These come with a charging case, a USB cable, and three pairs of ear tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jFuQO6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10401237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="QnXS2i"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_FJFnm9PCfY?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Zrbuj"&gt;Oculus is set to announce some VR games later today, April 21st, and we expect it to share more on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22386496/resident-evil-4-vr-remake-oculus-quest-2-announced" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;that exciting VR port of &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. To celebrate the big day, Oculus is reducing the cost of several hit games for Quest headsets. In the mix are some solid games that I can personally recommend, like &lt;em&gt;In Death: Unchained&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;I Expect You To Die&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Room VR: A Dark Matter&lt;/em&gt;. Check out the sale here. If you’re new to VR and don’t mind throwing down $100 for a mix of some classic experiences bundled together, I’ll provide that link below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="whFwtj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10457990"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="M9Uei6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="CQEGom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/21/22395450/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-earbuds-refurbished-vr-game-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/21/22395450/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-earbuds-refurbished-vr-game-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Inside the glass fibers connecting our wireless world</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GgBgBWKLbyVdgbxP8ahQaIQJTfY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162418/adiaconis_untitled_20210419_0197_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TSzjiy"&gt;All modern means of communication rely on glass, from the Gorilla Glass on our phones to the infotainment screens in our cars. Most of the time, the glass is right in front of us, but when it comes to the internet — whether it’s 5G, Starlink satellites, or Wi-Fi — it’s easy to miss the 750,000 miles of fiber optic cables currently running under our oceans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QJzJpZ"&gt;These tiny strands of glass carry our photos, emails, and video chats from our phones to data centers to friends and family all across the world. It’s through these hair-thin strands of fiber that we are able to instantly communicate to almost anyone, anywhere, and it all relies on a 5,000-year-old technology: glass.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cwmHS6Zy5oFKfFikMOTfBb1iQ6E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459251/adiaconis_untitled_20210419_0197_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alix Diaconis / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A telecommunications-grade strand of single-core, optical fiber.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MlYr8T"&gt;Very little has changed in the way we use glass throughout its long history. It has always been a transparent and durable material through which light passes. And since light can travel quickly and at high frequencies while carrying loads of encoded information, a cable made of near-perfect glass is a secure medium to send all of our communications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yDegkJ"&gt;When I began researching materials that were shaping our future, Gorilla Glass was the obvious choice. But my path quickly turned to fiber and the urgent need to not only improve data transmission speeds but also provide all of humanity with internet access. Tune into our video to learn more about how these tiny strands of glass create the backbone for present and future of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22393952/glass-fiber-internet-cable-wifi-speed-5g-explainer-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22393952/glass-fiber-internet-cable-wifi-speed-5g-explainer-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Becca Farsace</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s AirTags don’t have a built-in keychain loop, and we have some thoughts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fsh9JcBTVaabDsfJuV2nAvrMoWk=/77x0:904x551/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162411/airtagaccessories.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CwaDy4"&gt;Apple’s new AirTag trackers are finally here after years of rumors. The $29 trackers work with Apple’s Find My network, utilizing both Bluetooth and UWB technology to help owners track anything from their keys to their bags. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XzvFVZ"&gt;But the design of the new trackers is somewhat controversial: unlike most Bluetooth trackers, Apple’s iteration doesn’t include a built-in key ring loop. The subsequent debate has shattered the tranquility of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s newsroom over whether Apple’s somewhat Spartan design is brilliant or bogus. Well, at least between two of the most genteel &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers, Jon Porter and Chaim Gartenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/492kammhY61DFUGcSC-yVmeGOFs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22458151/keychain.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artist’s rendering of an AirTag design featuring a keychain hole punch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qh75iy"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Porter, reporter&lt;/strong&gt;: Debate me, coward&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9KMiTJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim Gartenberg, news editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Gladly! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvGf9T"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Let’s start with a point that we’ll definitely both agree on: it’s a relief to see the AirTags’ battery is user-replaceable. It sounds like such a basic point, but considering Apple’s track record with its AirPods, Magic Mouse, iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, MacBook line, Magic Keyboard — wait does anything else Apple makes have replaceable batteries? — it wasn’t a guarantee. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/8/20901686/tile-tracker-mate-pro-slim-sticker-release-date-news-features"&gt;Tile’s keychain-focused Mate and Pro trackers&lt;/a&gt; have removable batteries, but its Sticker (which has a very similar form factor to the AirTag) doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HWw9NV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Brilliant or bogus?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DOebJ1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: I will grant you that easily accessible, user-replaceable batteries are always a good thing. And on a whole, the overall aesthetics of the AirTags are nice, with a two-tone shiny white plastic / chrome back that’s vaguely reminiscent of the old iPods to me. But the overly sleek Apple design highlights the biggest issue I have here: there’s no built-in loop or hole to attach a key ring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P8Ur5Y"&gt;The AirTag is a product that’s designed to track your keys, and yet it offers no way to actually attach itself to those keys out of the box, something that’s practically table stakes from Tile, Chipolo, and virtually every other Bluetooth tracker from the last decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TKNaTC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: I hear you, but I think Apple’s approach is better. It means it can sell just one version of the AirTag to track whatever item you want, rather than selling different devices whether you want to track your keys, or your bike, or your jacket. Just buy an AirTag and buy whatever accessory you need to attach it. And for what it’s worth, I really like the design of the little holder accessory they’re selling to attach the AirTag to a set of keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xhwlMC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: That little &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMHJ23ZM%2FA%2Fairtag-leather-key-ring%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;keychain accessory costs $35&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;em&gt;more than an entire AirTag&lt;/em&gt;. Even Apple’s cheapest AirTag case, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMK0W3ZM%2FA%2Fairtag-loop%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the $30 plastic loop&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn’t look like it’ll even be useful for attaching to keys. This is just Apple’s typical accessory tax, forced onto customers because of an intentional choice of aesthetic form over useful function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PNKKxo"&gt;And don’t get me started on the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMX862AM%2FA%2Fairtag-herm%25C3%25A8s-bag-charm%3Ffnode%3D6a69955a8a6ddce99e189acb007fb66a7a8f18e4729ee64e7b785b8e88b5246abab8110b9e5c815b2e8e74d5f263e66b2a7a391fb4c93d7f7a32238c65c707863e916aaeeebaa11b59a86351ea8281e57db77af4fcc7609d12ec0601e21a15603b9023598629f037ffbe58f82b035223&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hermès accessories&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VOt7rznNzumaSTrrkX8AFrjBc6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22458169/Screen_Shot_2021_04_20_at_5.57.30_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nmRXJl"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Okay fine, I’m not going to argue that the $349 Hermès key ring isn’t incredibly stupid, and it would be nice if the leather key ring actually included an AirTag at that price. The setup is too expensive, period, and hopefully third-party accessory manufacturers will step in to fill the demand for cheap keychain holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="girWDS"&gt;But more importantly, I think separating the tech bit from the holder bit makes sense for an accessory that’s going to have to withstand so much abuse on a daily basis. Keys can be sharp, and they beat up anything that shares a pocket with them, so I’d prefer it if that thing that gets beaten up is a holder rather than the core piece of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t773Ho"&gt;Look at a Tile key fob tracker that’s been used for a couple of years, and it looks grimy as hell. I wouldn’t be surprised if some people end up replacing the whole device when the battery runs out, just so they can get a shiny new tracker. But when your AirTag keychain inevitably starts looking worse for wear, you just replace the holder rather than the tracker itself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Co3luD8e5pkvGFCzcC1RfxhbWE4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22457308/yJBAy1w.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hywvlC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: These are all valid points, but you’re ignoring the fact that &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Faccessories%2Fall%2Fairtag&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22394644%2Fapple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;these accessories and protective cases&lt;/a&gt; could all exist in &lt;em&gt;addition&lt;/em&gt; to including a cutout to directly attach a key ring. There’s already a similar cottage industry of accessories for Tile’s trackers for those who want them, and with the marketing power of Apple behind it, there’s no reason to think that AirTags wouldn’t have eclipsed that level of interest from accessory makers, even if it did have a cutout for a key ring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NM8Yi5"&gt;It’s not that cases are bad — Apple’s leather option does look great and is almost definitely a more robust option than my hypothetical cutout. But it’d be nice to give customers the choice, instead of just forcing them into an option that requires spending more money right from the start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="D24Qfh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are all the AirTag accessories we know about ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394331/apple-airtag-release-launch-accessory-roundup-nomad-belkin"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PwfbZF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: At a certain point, though, you’re running up against physical limitations, and Apple has to pick its battles. I’m already seeing some of our esteemed colleagues in Slack complaining about how thick these trackers are, which I’d wager is because Apple prioritized building in a removable battery. Adding a loop with enough space for a key chain to go through adds yet more bulk. You have to draw the line somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lSBjAD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: Fair enough. So, Jon, are you buying an AirTag tracker? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="naEYZZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Honestly, I’m going to wait to see how the third-party accessories work out. If I can get a half-decent leather keychain holder for the equivalent of $20 or so, then I think it makes a lot of sense spending $50 all-in with the tracker itself. Yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pfzgre"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaim&lt;/strong&gt;: I might buy one to stick in my luggage at some point, but I generally don’t lose my keys enough to need to invest in a tracker for them (famous last words, potentially). Especially not at the $65 price tag that Apple is asking for a full key ring setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iYatkG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LMETVs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394644/apple-airtag-built-in-keychain-loop-design-price-accessories-debate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T09:57:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T09:57:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>EU outlines wide-ranging AI regulation, but leaves the door open for police surveillance</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8d6PbeA0DAaP0h_LXbRsK4PHHMY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162373/acastro_181017_1777_brain_ai_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i5YqCS"&gt;The European Union has &lt;a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/library/proposal-regulation-european-approach-artificial-intelligence"&gt;published a new framework&lt;/a&gt; to regulate the use of artificial intelligence across the bloc’s 27 member states. The proposal, which will take years to implement into law and will be subject to many tweaks and amendments during this time, nevertheless constitutes the most ambitious AI regulations seen globally to date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VyCCa1"&gt;The regulations cover a wide range of applications, from software in self-driving cars to algorithms used to vet job candidates, and arrive at a time when countries around the world are struggling with the ethical ramifications of artificial intelligence. Similar to the EU’s data privacy law, GDPR, the regulation gives the bloc the ability to fine companies that infringe its rules up to 6 percent of their global revenues, though such punishments are extremely rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FKmwgt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s our first ever legal framework on artificial intelligence.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4TqWkn"&gt;“It is a landmark proposal of this Commission. It’s our first ever legal framework on artificial intelligence,” said European Commissioner Margrethe Vestager during a press conference. “Today we aim to make Europe world-class in the development of secure, trustworthy, and human-centered artificial intelligence. And, of course, the use of it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i481DH"&gt;Civil rights groups are wary about some aspects of the proposal. One of the most important components is a ban on four specific AI use cases throughout the EU. These bans are intended to protect citizens from applications that infringe on their rights, but critics say some prohibitions are too vaguely worded to actually stop harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SA1Pka"&gt;One such prohibition is a ban on the use of real-time “remote biometric identification systems in publicly accessible spaces for the purpose of law enforcement,” which would include facial recognition. The regulation adds, though, that there are numerous exceptions to this prohibition, including letting police use such systems to find the “perpetrator or suspect” of any criminal act that carries a minimum three-year sentence. Using technology like facial recognition in these cases would need to be approved by judiciaries or similar bodies, but this would still give law enforcement an extremely broad scope to deploy AI surveillance as and when they want.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Video surveillance of a premises" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2gUSVGrwLT3kxTqKE07XMys9A3g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459274/1232158944.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Alexandra Schuler / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The proposal leaves significant room for law enforcement use of facial recognition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JJsUwx"&gt;“There are just too many exceptions and they are quite arbitrary,” Alexandra Geese, a German Green MEP, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;regarding the regulation. “I don’t see the point of saying ‘we don’t want biometric recognition’ and then granting continuous exceptions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fXeuRg"&gt;Sarah Chander, a senior policy advisor for digital rights group EDRi, agreed and said the proposal only offered “a veneer of fundamental rights protection.” Chander told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that banning mass biometric surveillance outright was “the only way to safeguard democracy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="dFOkXg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There are just too many exceptions and they are quite arbitrary.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LOEtb1"&gt;An earlier &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383301/eu-ai-regulation-draft-leak-surveillance-social-credit"&gt;leaked version of the proposal&lt;/a&gt; did feature a much stricter ban on AI for mass surveillance, but this was evidently watered down. As Geese told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;: “It looks like the Commission said, ‘Look we want to ban this thing,’ and then the safety authorities of the member states, the ministers of the interior, stepped in and said ‘No way.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AS2X2A"&gt;The fact that the ban mentions only “real-time” biometric identification also constitutes a substantial loophole. It seems to suggest that using facial recognition software after any target images have been captured is allowed. That would clear the way for European police to use services like the controversial Clearview AI, which has seen &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/clearview-ai-fbi-ice-global-law-enforcement"&gt;rapid uptake in the US&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UId00z"&gt;Other prohibited applications of AI include the use of the technology to create social credit scores, to cause physical or physiological harm to people, and to manipulate people’s behavior using subliminal cues. “We prohibit them altogether because we simply consider them to be unacceptable,” said Vestager of these use cases during the press conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pRlXXc"&gt;All other AI applications are sorted into three groups of stratified risk. The bottom category includes common, low-risk applications like spam filters, for which regulation will likely not change at all. Above those are “limited-risk” uses cases like chatbot used to buy tickets or find out information, which will require a little more oversight. And above those are high-risk uses of AI, which are “the main focus of the framework,” as Vestager said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pyeoV2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;AI systems like chatbots would be required to identify themselves to users&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B5cxsY"&gt;The high-risk applications are those which affect material aspects of people’s lives, like algorithms used to assess someone’s credit score or whether they can get a loan, as well as AI tools that control critical machinery like autonomous vehicles and medical devices. Their deployment and development will be overseen by various regulatory mechanisms — in some cases, based on existing national regulators like those devoted to digital privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="deYAdd"&gt;“Those AI systems will be subject to a set of five strict obligations because they will potentially have a huge impact on our lives,” said Vestager at the conference. These requirements include the mandatory use of “high-quality” training data to avoid bias, the implementation of “human oversight” into each system, and the creation of detailed documentation that explains how the software works to both regulators and users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74PLsx"&gt;Another notable aspect is compulsory transparency obligations for AI systems that interact with humans, like chatbots, and for AI-generated content, like deepfakes. “The aim is to make it crystal clear that as users we are interacting with a machine,” said Vestager.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Robot helps with control - “Please wear a mask”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2glOF9e6VvIcBIv5Y1EM5epTCdg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459269/1229663756.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Marcel Kusch / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;AI systems would have to identify themselves as such to users. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="anzuYu"&gt;In addition to these new regulations, all AI systems classified as high-risk will also have to be indexed in a new EU-wide database. Daniel Leufer, a Europe policy analyst at Access Now, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that this was an unexpected and welcome addition to the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXZ2aQ"&gt;“It’s a really good measure, because one of the issues we have is just not knowing when a system is in use,” said Leufer. “For example, with ClearView AI we rely on investigative journalism and leaks to find out if anyone’s using it.” A database would provide “basic transparency about what systems are in use... enabling us to do our job.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZF1th"&gt;Digital rights groups said there were additional problems beyond the loopholes involving biometric identification. A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22381370/automatic-gender-recognition-sexual-orientation-facial-ai-analysis-ban-campaign"&gt;hoped-for ban&lt;/a&gt; on the use of AI to automatically identify gender and sexual orientation was absent, for example, while algorithms used for predictive policing, which are frequently found to be affected by &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/07/17/1005396/predictive-policing-algorithms-racist-dismantled-machine-learning-bias-criminal-justice"&gt;racial bias&lt;/a&gt;, will not have strong oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o2n5AF"&gt;“These are supposedly high risk [AI applications], but in terms of enforcement are self-assessment,” says Chander. “This allows companies who profit from the development of these systems to decide whether or not they conform with the law. It’s astounding.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lpQPSu"&gt;Despite such objections, many will see the EU as following through on a promise to create a “third way” between the US and China on AI policy. As Vestager noted at the press conference, the bloc wishes to distinguish itself with fair and ethical applications of AI, and this proposal is still the biggest step toward regulation in line with those values. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5wAjDy"&gt;“I’m a little bit suspicious,” Geese said, “but I’m very happy that the EU is trying to be a global standard setter.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393785/eu-ai-regulation-proposal-social-credit-ban-biometric-surveillance-exceptions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393785/eu-ai-regulation-proposal-social-credit-ban-biometric-surveillance-exceptions</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T09:17:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T09:17:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the M1-powered iPad Pro compares to other iPad models</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kk2fuz1qoN65Gtr9IWma5nu9h8U=/3x0:977x649/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69162095/ipad_pro_2021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPad Pro 2021&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oYWndI"&gt;Apple has announced the next generation of its iPad Pro line. But most of the biggest changes for Apple’s flagship tablet are largely on the inside. The latest iPad Pros feature a new eight-core M1 processor; the same chip featured in the most recent model refreshes for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;newly announced iMac&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rIw2yY"&gt;Like last year, the iPad Pro comes in two sizes: 11 inches and 12.9 inches. The 12.9-inch model this year also includes a new Mini-LED screen, which Apple is branding as a “Liquid Retina XDR” display. The iPad Pro 2021 refreshes also include support for Thunderbolt 3 and USB 4, in addition to 5G connectivity. Both iPad Pros also feature a new 12-megapixel ultrawide camera that can automatically track you during video calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7V3r5T"&gt;Of course, specs don’t always tell how much has changed between model refreshes. And it can be easy to presume, at first glance, that not much has changed — especially if you own a 2020 iPad Pro. If you want to see how both iPad Pro models with the M1 chip compare to the other three iPads Apple currently sells, along with the 2020 Pro models, take a look at the chart below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xwiUSk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10457124"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="NDuhGp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to preorder the new iPad Pro with the M1 processor","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394227/apple-ipad-pro-2021-how-where-to-buy-preorder-link"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22394384/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-comparison"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22394384/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-comparison</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cadillac’s Lyriq EV will start at $59,990</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E98bZgyRJK8qXhwvbOyZ6uzy4ZQ=/0x148:1780x1335/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69161957/MY23LYRIQ_HERO_FRONT_3_4_BLACK_ROOF_FINAL.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Cadillac&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LgBpMP"&gt;Cadillac has announced that its first electric car, the Lyriq, will start at $59,990 before tax, license, and dealer fees. The luxury brand of General Motors also said the electric SUV will be available for reservations starting in September ahead of the start of production in the first quarter of 2022. The Lyriq SUV will officially go on sale shortly after that in the first half of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PaeoGK"&gt;The Lyriq got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21357717/cadillac-lyriq-gm-ev-suv-touchscreen-size-specs-release-date"&gt;a proper debut last August&lt;/a&gt;, but that was technically still just a show car. The photos Cadillac showed off Wednesday as it announced pricing are of the final production version. You’d be forgiven if you didn’t notice the difference; even Cadillac says that there have only been minor changes since then, like the addition of an extra seat and cupholder, smaller wheels, and a slight difference in the door design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BP3MXi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Only small changes from the version that debuted last year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j6a4nC"&gt;Cadillac also released a more complete spec sheet, though there aren’t any big changes here either. The Lyriq is slated to get “more than” 300 miles of range out of a 12-module, 100kWh version of GM’s new flexible Ultium EV battery pack. The SUV will be powered, for now at least, by just one electric motor capable of generating 255kW of power (around 340 horsepower). And owners will be able to charge it quickly when they drain the pack. The Lyriq can charge at up to 190kW at public fast charging stations or up to 19.2kW at home (with the right equipment), which adds around 52 miles of range per hour. Oh, and the Lyriq weighs an astonishing 5,610 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nSygls"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10457025"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qA7qQa"&gt;The Lyriq is not only Cadillac’s first EV, but it’s going to be a showcase for a lot of the automaker’s other leading technologies. It will, of course, have Super Cruise, which is the hands-free driver assistance system that started at Cadillac but is now spreading to other GM vehicles. The Lyriq also features a massive 33-inch display that stretches from the left of the driver all the way to the middle of the dashboard. There’s an active noise cancellation system to dampen road noise, LED headlamps, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K2D77a"&gt;The $59,990 starting price isn’t cheap, but Cadillac is clearly trying to make the Lyriq as enticing to EV-wary buyers as possible. The real question will be how quickly that price tag escalates start picking trim levels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HxPh5N"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394483/cadillac-lyriq-electric-suv-price-specs-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22394483/cadillac-lyriq-electric-suv-price-specs-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T08:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T08:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Tamagotchi Pix has a built-in camera for taking pictures with your pet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p1rouh0FKIFPB_WhL1S6AqeKPq0=/59x0:1942x1255/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69161878/Tamagotchi_Pix.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;image: Bandai&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PPmRF3"&gt;Today, Bandai is announcing the Tamagotchi Pix: a combination of its classic Tamagotchi pet-rearing toy line with a new built-in camera for taking pictures with your digital pet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AR12k8"&gt;The Pix is shaped like a hatching egg, with the top part of the “broken shell” working as a shutter button. Using the camera, you can insert yourself (and friends) into photos with your Tamagotchi, with appropriately cute photo frames. We’ve reached out to Bandai for more information about the camera quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ppWDt"&gt;Photos taken with the Pix are stored locally, and any photos you take will appear in a feed that documents your time with your pet. Bandai frames this as a sort of on-device social media, but because the Pix can’t connect to Wi-Fi and sharing photos is limited, it’s not actually social. Presale for the Tamagotchi Pix starts today for $59.99.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-2h6kqUEZQu9px6dEWAEhWPMEk8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22454749/Screen_Shot_2021_04_19_at_9.36.03_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bandai&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Tamagotchi Pix’s top shell works as a shutter button when you’re taking photos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="g2u8i5"&gt;Past Tamagotchi, like &lt;a href="https://tamagotchi.fandom.com/wiki/Tamagotchi_On"&gt;the Tamagotchi On&lt;/a&gt;, have used Bluetooth to connect to other devices, but the Pix is taking a less high-tech approach. If you want to share images with other Pix-carrying friends, they can take a picture of a “Tama Code.” Bandai says these codes contain the entirety of what you are sharing, so you can basically exchange pictures via QR codes. Bandai also plans to award Tama Codes for in-game items if you play games on tamagotchi.com starting in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUGOGq"&gt;Besides the camera features, Tamagotchi Pix also has new touch-based buttons in place of the usual physical ones, and several new gameplay mechanics. Have you ever wanted to influence your Tamagotchi’s future employment status off-world? Apparently, how you raise your Tamagotchi and decorate its room will now affect its future profession and what other eggs you can raise after your first Tamagotchi grows up. Tamagotchi can also engage in new activities like painting, cooking, and ordering food for delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C6VRTE"&gt;The Tamagotchi Pix captures a little bit of the feeling of &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;’s augmented reality camera. It’s not as robust — you’re just pasting your pet on a photo rather than finding them moving out in the world — but some of that AR magic is there. Obsessively documenting your pet’s life in photos might re-create some of that parent-child bond, but I think what’s more powerful is the basic feeling the Pix’s little AR photos could conjure: that you exist in the same space as your Tamagotchi and that, in some way, it’s real — even if it’s confined to a plastic egg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8I9Kb"&gt;The Tamagotchi Pix comes in four different colored “shells”: “floral” (pink), “sky” (purple), “ocean” (blue), and “nature” (green). Pink and purple are available for presale today, and blue and green are “coming soon,” according to Bandai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePTQXh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29nSSN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22386339/tamagotchi-pix-pet-egg-camera-toy-ar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22386339/tamagotchi-pix-pet-egg-camera-toy-ar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Asian activists are tracking the surge in hate crimes as police reporting falls short</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-TiurNLcHkKKsYwxbXt6CLaKtUU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69161634/GettyImages_1309488530.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;People demonstrate at the ‘Stop Asian Hate March and Rally’ in Koreatown on March 27, 2021 in Los Angeles, California. March 27 is the #StopAsianHate National Day of Action against anti-Asian violence. On March 16th, eight people were killed at three Atlanta-area spas, six of whom were Asian women, in an attack that sent fear through the Asian community amid a rise in anti-Asian hate crimes.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Mario Tama/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;With new tools and new technology, groups like Project 1907 want to fix hate crime statistics&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="m6VTkb"&gt;Julia Mah’s* eyes were still adjusting to the morning light when she woke up one Saturday and reached for her phone. A message from her aunt jolted her out of bed. Mah’s 79-year-old grandmother had been attacked at a bus stop in Vancouver’s Chinatown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AizJdR"&gt;Her grandmother was on her way home after a doctor’s appointment when she noticed a woman shouting racial slurs, Mah says. “She got really close to my grandmother, so my grandma ran.” The woman caught up and started beating the shocked senior with her bag. A year earlier, the Chinese elder had told her family that she was less afraid about getting COVID-19 than she was about getting randomly attacked downtown. Now, that’s exactly what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="dXYgTb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Nobody got involved”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QtY9r4"&gt;“The most frustrating part for me is that there were other people around — it was broad daylight,” Mah says. “Nobody got involved... no one went and checked on my grandmother.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gu7N3N"&gt;Mah believes what happened was a hate crime, one of thousands that go unreported every year. But her grandmother, who Mah says has seldom left home since the March attack, didn’t see it that way. She kept the incident secret for days before mentioning it to a relative, and she remains reluctant to share details about the attack, which curdled family efforts to collect information and file an official report with police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dd3X8b"&gt;For the older generation, Mah says, being perceived as a victim is culturally perceived as a “sign of weakness or vulnerability.” But for some activists, the problems with relying on police run deeper. Aided by new tech and social media, they’re launching their own projects to collect data on the real scope of the violence, hoping to push institutions that have overlooked and undercounted the issue for generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30eGjz"&gt;Doris*, a Vancouver-based community organizer, experienced her own run-in with anti-Asian harassment last year. She reported the racist, sexually explicit comments from a passerby to police — but they told her the incident didn’t meet their threshold for recording because it wasn’t a crime. In response, Doris and a group of others created &lt;a href="https://www.project1907.org/"&gt;Project 1907&lt;/a&gt;: a grassroots organization that is using technology to help “diasporic Asians to understand our histories, explore our identities, examine our privileges and reclaim our power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="skUZVi"&gt;Project 1907’s founders named the group after Vancouver’s 1907 anti-immigration race riots to both educate and put their advocacy work into a historical context. Among other initiatives, the organization operates its hate incident reporting tool — a Google form that’s available in Chinese, Japanese, Korean, and Vietnamese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="BKzHIp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;43 percent of reported incidents happened in a public space&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EmPGwb"&gt;More than 600 people have used Project 1907’s form to report anti-Asian racism since the onset of the pandemic. Two-thirds of respondents reported verbal harassment, and one-third reported assault, including elongated coughing and spitting. Women are disproportionately impacted, and 43 percent of incidents were reported to have taken place in a public space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UsQKZP"&gt;The job of the police is to fight crime, Doris said. “All the incidents that are reported to them are viewed from a criminal viewpoint, first and foremost.” Not everyone feels safe reporting a hate crime to police. For some undocumented workers and sex workers, the risks of engaging police can outweigh the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JdhfO5"&gt;“The police are not structured to fight racism,” Doris says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jc4rmr"&gt;The rarity of hate crime charges, despite recurrent stories of hate-motivated incidents, has stoked, in many people, an unfulfilled sense of justice. &lt;a href="https://ca.finance.yahoo.com/finance/news/minority-groups-call-city-strengthen-173258904.html"&gt;Some groups&lt;/a&gt; want to see police hate crime units expanded as a way to improve incident reporting. But others, including Project 1907, are wary that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22359080/anti-asian-racism-attacks-surveillance-policing"&gt;more surveillance&lt;/a&gt; and policing will create additional harm for marginalized communities. This paradox has spurred groups to launch &lt;a href="https://www.covidracism.ca/report"&gt;community-based surveys&lt;/a&gt; to record incidents that would otherwise be undocumented during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="erQT4S"&gt;&lt;q&gt;police-reported hate crime statistics only offer a partial view of what’s happening&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z7GzA0"&gt;For Asian communities, the shift is happening alongside a real rise in street attacks, which has led to some alarming official hate crime statistics. In February, the Vancouver Police Department released statistics noting a &lt;a href="https://vancouverpoliceboard.ca/police/policeboard/agenda/2021/0218/5-1-2102P01-Year-end-2020-KPI-Report.pdf"&gt;717 percent jump&lt;/a&gt; in anti-Asian hate crime incidents since 2019. New York City recorded an &lt;a href="https://www.csusb.edu/sites/default/files/FACT%20SHEET-%20Anti-Asian%20Hate%202020%20rev%203.21.21.pdf"&gt;833 percent&lt;/a&gt; increase over the same period. In Los Angeles, police tracked a 114 percent rise, and in San Jose, anti-Asian hate crimes increased 150 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lSZTM"&gt;But these police-reported statistics only offer a partial view of what’s happening. According to a Canadian &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gc.ca/eng/rp-pr/csj-sjc/crime/wd95_11-dt95_11/p2.html"&gt;federal government report&lt;/a&gt;, it’s estimated that only one in ten hate-motivated crimes are reported to the criminal justice system. Government data suggests hate crimes — ones motivated by a bias against someone’s “&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/hatecrimes/learn-about-hate-crimes"&gt;race, color, religion, national origin, sexual orientation, gender, gender identity, or disability&lt;/a&gt;” — get more attention in America, but the US Department of Justice still estimates only &lt;a href="https://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/hcv0415.pdf"&gt;46 percent&lt;/a&gt; of incidents were reported between 2011 and 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wYQxaC"&gt;Larger groups such as &lt;a href="https://stopaapihate.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Stop-AAPI-Hate-National-Report-210316.pdf"&gt;Stop AAPI Hate&lt;/a&gt;, a San Francisco-based nonprofit organization, are collecting even more reports of hate incidents against Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders than Project 1907. Their victimization survey recorded 3,795 hate incidents between March 2020 and February 2021 and found “women report hate incidents 2.3 times more than men.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qunDI2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The police are not structured to fight racism”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7vPkMw"&gt;Brian Levin, director of the Center for the Study of Hate and Extremism at California State University, San Bernardino, explains that a problem with crime data collection from law enforcement is that it’s “very uneven” across the United States. That’s because not all police agencies are set up to track hate crimes. It’s typically big cities that have large police departments with specialized units that are able to track hate crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WLkQpC"&gt;Definitions of a hate crime can also vary from state to state. For example, Arkansas, South Carolina, and Wyoming do not have any hate crime laws and their entries into the national data repository are zeros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lgH6Zq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d48cb4d61091100011eded9/t/5f5ab2bad55ac978cdd858f9/1599779524716/Barriers+to+reporting+hate+crimes_final.pdf"&gt;Systemic barriers&lt;/a&gt;, such as language accessibility, may prevent people from coming forward in the first place. Trust and confidence are long-standing issues to contend with as well. Discrimination and suspicion from officers at the intake level, revealing bias and inadequate training, can dissuade or stop victims from filing official reports. The seriousness of a crime and a victim’s access to legal and financial resources can also impact how a hate crime gets reported and recorded by police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vMan4"&gt;While the recent jump in hate crime statistics reflects a real growth in attacks, it may also reflect a new willingness to designate attacks as hate crimes, attacks that would have otherwise gone unreported. But while the current system produces only limited information, Levin says it’s better than nothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MAMEsw"&gt;“Even if you have 18,000 rain buckets and thermometers, and 16,000 are kicked over, but you’re getting reports across the country from over 2,000 — which is kind of what we got — that tells you something,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hLrkTr"&gt;The “broken thermometers” idea also explains why data on the increase in attacks has been so difficult to pin down. The biggest spikes came from &lt;a href="https://www.csusb.edu/sites/default/files/FACT%20SHEET-%20Anti-Asian%20Hate%202020%20rev%203.21.21.pdf"&gt;a study that tracked incidents in America’s largest cities&lt;/a&gt;, dense coastal areas with sizable Asian populations. As Levin notes, they’re places that “perhaps had some noteworthy difficulties with COVID,” but they’re also places with organized communities that can push for more robust reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="c8kCbh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Do they understand that, in the eyes of the law, that’s something different?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Xk4xMV"&gt;The number of reported anti-Asian hate crimes had been decreasing for more than 20 years before Donald Trump became president. Now, that trend seems to have reversed. “We’ve seen a lot of this stuff rising and falling with respect to politics,” Levin says. Internet invective and the stigmatizing “China virus” language, laundered by the president and his associates, seem to have made anti-immigrant sentiments in America that much worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysZZDX"&gt;Barbara Perry, a criminology and justice professor at Ontario Tech University and leading expert in the study of hate crimes and extremism, says clear definitions play an important role in fighting hate-motivated incidents. If someone is assaulted, it matters if a racial slur is used because it suggests there is a bias motivation. “Do they understand that, in the eyes of the law, that’s something different? Does that make it more important to them? Does it make it more meaningful to them?” Perry says. “Does it mean to them that I was just in the wrong place at the wrong time?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yHIkpj"&gt;Hate crime charges are rare in both the US and Canada because the legal definitions are narrow and the victim and law perspectives are always subjective. The cases are complex. But new laws and updated definitions won’t necessarily change the biases that fuel hate crimes. Activists hope new data, collected from victimization surveys, will do just that by making the invisible visible and connecting the trends to history.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="hV6uBs"&gt;“Just because we have more numbers and data to talk about now doesn’t mean it just started existing,” Doris says. “We’re starting to hear people find a voice, where they feel confident in actually talking about their experience of anti-Asian racism through their lifetime, not just the one incident at the grocery store two weeks ago. These aren’t isolated incidents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FAokiq"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Names marked with an asterisk are aliases, granted in response to a reasonable fear of harassment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393622/asian-hate-crime-reporting-community-group-statistics"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393622/asian-hate-crime-reporting-community-group-statistics</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zi-Ann Lum</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T06:20:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T06:20:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>FBI used facial recognition to identify a Capitol rioter from his girlfriend’s Instagram posts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qyZST6sbqbCc1L8CKExeuVZWzD0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69161461/acastro_180730_1777_facial_recognition_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UyERdM"&gt;The FBI says it used facial recognition technology to track down and arrest an individual suspected of taking part in the US Capitol riots earlier this year. The case, which was &lt;a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/facial-recognition-capitol-defendants_n_607f34c0e4b0df3610c17614?ri18n=true"&gt;first reported by &lt;em&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is notable for the FBI’s acknowledgement that it used facial recognition not just to confirm a suspect’s identity, but to discover it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dnB3od"&gt;According to an &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20665075-41f45c66-98d7-46c3-b08e-ae4b81a1f8c1"&gt;affidavit&lt;/a&gt; shared online by the &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;, federal agents tracked down an individual named Stephen Chase Randolph using crowdsourced images from the riots (including those shared on Twitter by a group known as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SeditionHunters"&gt;SeditionHunters&lt;/a&gt;). They searched these pictures on the web using “an open source facial recognition tool, known to provide reliable results,” and this led to a public Instagram page apparently belonging to Randolph’s girlfriend which contained “numerous images” of the suspect.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PWPDaeeJSIqwDqhh_SPv3wpuVUM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459136/Screen_Shot_2021_04_21_at_11.06.08_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20665075-41f45c66-98d7-46c3-b08e-ae4b81a1f8c1" target="_blank"&gt;FBI Affidavit&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/facial-recognition-capitol-defendants_n_607f34c0e4b0df3610c17614?ri18n=true" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;FBI agents found an Instagram page apparently belonging to Randolph’s girlfriend using “open source facial recognition.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TLD9TN"&gt;Pictures on the account showed Randolph wearing the same items of clothing as in stills captured at the Capitol. These included a grey knitted hat with the Carhartt logo embroidered in white on the front. This hat was key for tracking Randolph’s activities across multiple videos and images, leading to SeditionHunters dubbing him #GrayCarharttHat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pI2zlH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The SUBJECT then continued to assault two other USCP officers”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8n2Fe3"&gt;The FBI affidavit says Randolph was seen assaulting multiple US Capitol Police officers. “In the process of pushing the barricades to the ground, the SUBJECT and others knocked over a USCP Officer [...] causing [her] head to hit the stairs behind her, resulting in loss of consciousness,” says the report. “The SUBJECT then continued to assault two other USCP officers by physically pushing, shoving, grabbing, and generally resisting the officers and interfering with their official duties of protecting the closed and restricted US Capitol grounds.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FhxEi8"&gt;After finding Randolph’s girlfriend’s Instagram account, federal agents found Facebook accounts apparently belonging to his family members, revealing Randolph’s full name. They then cross-referenced his identity with state driving license records and surveilled him at his home and workplace, where he was spotted still wearing the same Carhartt hat.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NpAVi8jJSz27OJYZ8RvZN1_DRK4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459138/Screen_Shot_2021_04_21_at_11.07.41_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20665075-41f45c66-98d7-46c3-b08e-ae4b81a1f8c1" target="_blank"&gt;FBI Affidavit&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/facial-recognition-capitol-defendants_n_607f34c0e4b0df3610c17614?ri18n=true" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The FBI tracked down Randolph to his workplace, where he was interviewed by undercover agents. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="H06gVf"&gt;To confirm Randolph’s participation in the riots, two undercover FBI agents approached him at his work on April 13. They struck up a conversation with Randolph in which he admitted to attending the riots, saying “I was in it” and “It was fucking fun.” Randolph also said he’d seen a female police officer being pushed over by the barricades, and suggested that the officer had suffered a concussion because she’d curled up into the fetal position. Randolph was arrested in Kentucky a week after this interview took place, says &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYvElq"&gt;The case shows how the FBI is using facial recognition and crowdsourced images to track down those who participated in the January 6 riots. Such tools are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21295301/philadelphia-protester-arson-identified-social-media-etsy-instagram-linkedin"&gt;not always necessary&lt;/a&gt; to find suspects, but their use appears to be becoming increasingly common. A report from &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/clearview-ai-local-police-facial-recognition"&gt;earlier this month&lt;/a&gt; revealed that some 1,803 publicly funded agencies, including local and state police, tested controversial facial recognition service Clearview AI prior to February 2020. The technology has only become more widely known since.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395323/fbi-facial-recognition-us-capital-riots-tracked-down-suspect"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395323/fbi-facial-recognition-us-capital-riots-tracked-down-suspect</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-21T06:06:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T06:06:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>Any video conferencing app can use the iPad Pro’s fancy zoom and pan camera</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WzipxLaS7ueC_Y9xzx7EXXkc9IQ=/0x26:600x426/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69161443/Center_stage_ipad.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new iPad Pro’s front-facing camera can digitally pan and tilt to track video conference participants.&lt;/em&gt; | Video: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mFm6sw"&gt;Apple has confirmed that the digital pan and zoom feature of the new M1 iPad Pro’s front-facing camera can work with any video conferencing app, not just FaceTime. That opens the door for popular apps like Zoom and Microsoft Teams to make remote work and e-learning blend more seamlessly into the realities of pandemic life — a hybrid lifestyle that’s likely to continue even after the outbreak subsides. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BHdkaS"&gt;Center Stage, as Apple brands it, keeps video conferencing participants properly framed even as they move about a room by combining machine learning with a fixed 12-megapixel sensor touting an ultra-wide 122‑degree field of view. We’ve seen similar tracking on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/18/20871173/facebook-portal-camera-price-release-date-availability"&gt;Portal TV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22297810/amazon-echo-show-10-2021-review"&gt;Echo Show 10&lt;/a&gt;, and even the Xbox Kinect accessory. But those are niche devices compared to the iPad, which saw sales surge last year as students and remote workers snapped the tablets up in droves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QDTFsN"&gt;“Center Stage works with FaceTime and other video conferencing apps,” says Apple on the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fipad-pro%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F21%2F22395325%2Fipad-pro-pan-zoom-video-conferencing-microsoft-teams" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iPad Pro landing page&lt;/a&gt;. Apple missed its chance to scale FaceTime to compete with the likes of Zoom and Teams by reneging on its promise to make it an industry standard in favor of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375128/apple-imessage-android-ecosystem-lock-in-epic-games-filings-app-store-dispute"&gt;ecosytem lock-in&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m2tpdGV2oDI6nPCbtkc4DhWyros=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22459122/lcimg_b1916176_0880_4bb5_9b1c_bfaee6cd2f4d.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ultra-wide front-facing camera is still located at the “top” of the new iPad Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UQG24u"&gt;Apple demonstrated Center Stage with two participants, both of whom are recognized and framed appropriately as they move about a kitchen, on a FaceTime call with a third. It’s a good demo; the COVID-19 pandemic has blended work and life so hard that it’s now fairly common to see people making dinner during a Zoom meeting across international time zones, or a kid asking for a parent’s help during a Teams school lesson. Tech like Center Stage can help further infuse this sense of humanity into our otherwise stoic professional and educational pursuits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuwYuF"&gt;Unfortunately, the position of the front-facing camera, unchanged on the new M1 iPad Pro, makes participants appear to be staring off to the side when used with a keyboard dock, as is common for business and school uses. And &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;iPadOS creates other frustrations&lt;/a&gt; for video conferences. Hopefully the iPad Pro is just a start and we’ll see ultra-wide Center Stage cameras coming to the much maligned, but better positioned, MacBook webcams soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395325/ipad-pro-pan-zoom-video-conferencing-microsoft-teams"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395325/ipad-pro-pan-zoom-video-conferencing-microsoft-teams</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
