<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-25T13:36:20-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T13:36:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T13:36:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook will let researchers study how advertisers targeted users with political ads prior to Election Day</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sXZoPKn_krFttL0XsFkwmr_GAZg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68718016/mdoying_180411_2400_0043still.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michele Doying / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ob6dTN"&gt;Facebook is aiming to improve transparency around political advertising on its platform by opening up more data to independent researchers, including targeting information on more than 1.3 million ads that ran in the three months prior to the US election on November 3rd of last year. Researchers interested in studying the ads can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/28/18201361/facebook-political-ad-transparency-tools-blocked-user-data-privacy"&gt;apply for access to the Facebook Open Research and Transparency (FORT) platform here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MVlX8f"&gt;The move is significant because Facebook has long resisted willfully allowing access to data around political advertising, often citing user privacy. The company has gone so far as to even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/28/18201361/facebook-political-ad-transparency-tools-blocked-user-data-privacy"&gt;disable third-party web plugins&lt;/a&gt;, like ProPublica’s Facebook Political Ad Collector tool, that collect such data without Facebook’s express consent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="04O4iW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook wants to help researchers better understand how its products are used for political ads&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MXwQtn"&gt;Numerous research groups around the globe have spent years now studying Facebook’s impact on everything from democratic elections to news dissemination, but sometimes without full access to all the desired data. Only last year, after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/6/18531060/facebook-data-researchers-social-science-one-first-studies"&gt;partnering with Harvard University’s Social Science One&lt;/a&gt; (the group overseeing applications for the new political ad targeting initiative), did Facebook better formalize the process of granting anonymized user data for research studies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lVDAnL"&gt;In the past, Facebook has made some crucial political ad information in its Ad Library available to the public, including the amount spent on certain ads and demographic information about who saw those ads. But now the company says it wants to do more to improve transparency, specifically around how advertisers target certain subsets of users with political advertising. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XdfZum"&gt;“We created this tool to enable academic researchers to study the impact of Facebook’s products on elections, and included measures to protect people’s privacy and keep the platform secure,” reads a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/28/18201361/facebook-political-ad-transparency-tools-blocked-user-data-privacy"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Sarah Clark Schiff, a Facebook product manager, published on Monday. “By making the targeting criteria, such as location and interests, selected by advertisers running social issue, electoral or political ads available for analysis and reporting, we hope to help people better understand the practices used to reach potential voters on Facebook.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cofSLB"&gt;Schiff says Facebook is open to partnering with academics to “further understanding of the impact of digital advertising on the US 2020 elections.” The company will also be retaining its &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ads/library/?active_status=all&amp;amp;ad_type=political_and_issue_ads&amp;amp;country=US&amp;amp;sort_data%5Bdirection%5D=desc&amp;amp;sort_data%5Bmode%5D=relevancy_monthly_grouped"&gt;US 2020 Election Spend Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, but it will be moved to its &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/actions/preparing-for-elections-on-facebook/"&gt;Elections page&lt;/a&gt;, where it will still be available for download. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wByqHN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248806/facebook-us-2020-election-data-research-political-ad-targeting"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248806/facebook-us-2020-election-data-research-political-ad-targeting</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T13:00:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T13:00:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this story about how r/WallStreetBets triggered a huge rise in GameStop’s stock price</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A man wearing a face mask leaves Game Stop with the new..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pxMisllxPUz5f44fsDdbnkjdFrE=/0x74:4427x3025/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68717808/1229823860.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Aimee Dilger/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uzeQ7N"&gt;The market, like Soylent Green, is made of people. That’s never more clear than when there’s something bonkers happening — like what’s happened with video game retailer GameStop’s stock since last September. Back then, it was trading at around $6.68; by this morning, however, it was trading at $146.97. (Since that astounding high, it fell to $61.13 as of 12:26PM EST.) What happened? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J6U83H"&gt;For that, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-25/how-wallstreetbets-pushed-gamestop-shares-to-the-moon"&gt;check out this wild story from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which reported exactly how the subreddit &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/"&gt;r/WallStreetBets&lt;/a&gt; grabbed hold of a huge opportunity — found, naturally, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244900/game-stop-stock-halted-trading-volatility"&gt;in the mass shorting of GameStop stock&lt;/a&gt;. As writer Brandon Kochkodin explains, the stage for the rise was set in 2019, when two important things happened. “One was Michael Burry — of &lt;em&gt;Big Short&lt;/em&gt; fame and the veritable &lt;a href="http://csinvesting.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Michael-Burry-Case-Studies.pdf"&gt;spirit animal&lt;/a&gt; for internet stock gurus hoping to hit the big time — saying he was &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1649339/000156761919004198/xslForm13F_X01/form13fInfoTable.xml"&gt;long&lt;/a&gt; the shares through his fund &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/quote/1298866D:US"&gt;Scion Asset Management&lt;/a&gt;,” writes Kochkodin. “Second was the surfacing of an idea, first in jest, that eventually evolved into the blueprint for the crowd-sourced short squeeze that has blown up in January. Could GameStop fall so far as to make a takeover possible — by WallStreetBets itself?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bmMbO7"&gt;The rest of the story involves ballsy moves from a cadre of retail investors with, as they say over on r/WallStreetBets, “diamond hands.” These Reddit users managed to move the needle — to change the stock price — with their distinct brand of semi-disciplined investing. The whole thing is worth a read, as Kochkodin deftly explains the market conditions that led to at least one person becoming a millionaire (at least on paper).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248775/gamestop-stock-price-rise-bloomberg-wallstreetbets-subreddit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248775/gamestop-stock-price-rise-bloomberg-wallstreetbets-subreddit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T12:37:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T12:37:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s new 1.1 update introduces a game-breaking bug</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q2kglE-JlozGJdNXjZIOgrs_eOc=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68717653/foW7FiHncAEnBbTu6d7KKA.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xksLTj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;’s big new 1.1 patch has introduced a game-breaking bug. &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-01-25-cyberpunk-2077-players-report-1-1-patch-adds-game-breaking-bug"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the “Down on the Street” quest appears to be broken for some players. The quest includes a holocall that’s supposed to trigger progress through the main part of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;’s storyline. Unfortunately, some players are reporting that the call remains silent, and it blocks progress of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F3GIO7"&gt;Developer CD Projekt Red has &lt;a href="https://support.cdprojektred.com/en/cyberpunk/pc/gameplay/issue/1895/quest-down-on-the-street-takemura-holocall"&gt;published a workaround&lt;/a&gt; for the issue, but it requires players to have an earlier save of the game to try to get the holocall to work correctly. Here are the steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="zjoTxy"&gt;Load a gamesave before Takemura and V leave Wakako’s office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="klYjRg"&gt;Finish the conversation with Takemura outside the office right away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kMmb8u"&gt;Right after the finished conversation and when the quest was updated, skip 23h&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s8S2d7"&gt;See if the holocall triggers and the dialogue with Takemura starts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p id="PyqK6m"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; has been plagued by bugs since its release on December 10th, and CD Projekt Red has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189893/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-hotfix-bugs"&gt;three&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22198029/cyberpunk-2077-106-update-patch-corrupted-save-file-crashes"&gt;hotfixes&lt;/a&gt; to try to fix some of the early problems. Thankfully, most of the bugs and issues haven’t been game-breaking like the one players have discovered this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lYtKXP"&gt;This &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22239765/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-bug-fixes"&gt;new 1.1 update&lt;/a&gt; was supposed to be the first big patch to introduce stability improvements, not game-breaking bugs. CD Projekt Red is &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/37298/our-commitment"&gt;also planning&lt;/a&gt; another major 1.2 patch that is supposed to be a “larger, more significant update” that will arrive “in the weeks after” this latest 1.1 patch. It’s not yet clear if there will be a quick hotfix to resolve this latest issue, though.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248682/cyberpunk-2077-update-bug-workaround-cd-projekt-red"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248682/cyberpunk-2077-update-bug-workaround-cd-projekt-red</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T11:31:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T11:31:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>This 7-Eleven store got a gaming makeover, and I want to spend the night</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6DXXuUYAYcUZagQ5kEVv9G-bwKc=/0x347:5200x3814/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68717234/NoEDDl9A.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: 7-Eleven&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZYMn7I"&gt;If you reside in Dallas County, Texas, you have a chance to spend the night in what I think is the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.airbnb.com%2Frooms%2F47815323%3Fsource_impression_id%3Dp3_1611589174_xurABtavTnYYPw2u%26guests%3D1%26adults%3D1%23availability-calendar&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Ftldr%2F22248396%2F7-eleven-airbnb-gaming-evolution-store-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ultimate gamer’s paradise&lt;/a&gt;: a 7-Eleven complete with snacks, a Slurpee machine, and the hard-to-find PS5 available to use during your stay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lsvxoe"&gt;Starting February 1st, residents who are 18 years or older will have the chance to spend $11 for one night in the utopia for gamers before it opens to the public. However, the rules are a bit strict as two gamers from &lt;strong&gt;the same household&lt;/strong&gt; who book the experience through Airbnb’s website will have the chance to spend the night. Only two dates are available: February 26th and February 28th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SDF5il"&gt;During their stay, two lucky guests will have access to the store, which has a futuristic gaming aesthetic, and it is truly #gamingroomgoals. There’s a game pod that includes a big-screen TV, some comfy-looking furniture, and did I mention there was a PS5, too? Not only that, but guests will also have access to an exclusive one-hour streaming session on Twitch with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Temperrr?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor"&gt;FaZe Temperrr&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zIr8al"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Guests will also have access to an exclusive one-hour streaming session on Twitch with FaZe Temperrr&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1UUjgp"&gt;Guests will have access to drinks and snacks available inside the store, including an all-you-can-drink Slurpee machine, tacos from the Laredo Taco Company, and all the Doritos and Mtn Dew you can drink. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtmWKx"&gt;As a gamer, I was deeply upset that I am ineligible to try to book a night at this 7-Eleven store due to living in Maryland. I mean, I have a PS5, sure, but do you know how many brain freezes I could have achieved with access to an all-you-can-drink Slurpee machine? There are endless opportunities for fun to be had in just one night. But don’t take my word for it; check out the pictures and see for yourself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jHDJz9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10301778"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sXokRy"&gt;This is not the first time limited-time stays were available through Airbnb. In September, the company allowed residents in LA County to spend the night in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/9/15/21438810/airbnb-fresh-prince-of-bel-air-mansion"&gt;the same mansion featured in &lt;em&gt;The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;In August, Deschutes County, Oregon residents could have a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/17/21372440/blockbuster-video-store-airbnb-location-price-movies-booking"&gt;‘90s-themed sleepover at the last remaining Blockbuster&lt;/a&gt; video store, and in 2019, you could stay at the &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/travel/barbie-malibu-dreamhouse-listed-airbnb-60-night-n1068231"&gt;Barbie Malibu Dreamhouse for just $60 a night&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22248396/7-eleven-airbnb-gaming-evolution-store-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22248396/7-eleven-airbnb-gaming-evolution-store-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T10:32:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T10:32:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple faces yet another lawsuit over throttling iPhones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a3nt9kNdn25Rhi3ZkCv7y2VgOJk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68716942/acastro_170731_1777_0002_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OF3kxJ"&gt;A consumer advocacy group in Europe has filed the latest lawsuit against Apple saying the company intentionally throttled older iPhones in Italy. First reported by &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/apple-hit-with-another-european-class-action-over-throttled-iphones/?tpcc=ECTW2020"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the potential class-action lawsuit seeks €60 million (roughly $73 million) in compensation — or about €60 per device — for owners of iPhone 6, 6 Plus, 6S, and 6S Plus models sold in Italy between 2014 and 2020. Euroconsumers, an umbrella advocacy organization in the EU that includes Italy’s Altroconsumo, says the €60 compensation is the average amount consumers paid to replace their devices’ batteries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QpCdG1"&gt;“When consumers buy Apple iPhones, they expect sustainable quality products. Unfortunately, that is not what happened with the iPhone 6 series” Els Bruggeman, head of policy and enforcement at Euroconsumers, said in a statement. “Not only were consumers defrauded, and did they have to face frustration and financial harm, from an environmental point of view it is also utterly irresponsible.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PPl1GT"&gt;Euroconsumers filed two similar lawsuits in December on behalf of member orgs Test-Achats in Belgium and OCU in Spain. The group said &lt;a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/iapmw8ie3ije/4zMgaeXbZ5sZEqwiSNyVck/dea9914bb631761645b034b120ec7f9f/Euroconsumers_Class_Action_Apple_-_Italy_.pdf"&gt;in a press release&lt;/a&gt; that it plans a fourth lawsuit in Portugal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="va2i0t"&gt;“We have never — and would never — do anything to intentionally shorten the life of any Apple product, or degrade the user experience to drive customer upgrades,” an Apple spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Our goal has always been to create products that our customers love, and making iPhones last as long as possible is an important part of that.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vKW3C"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161271/apple-settlement-500-million-throttling-batterygate-class-action-lawsuit"&gt;Apple agreed to a $500 million settlement&lt;/a&gt; in the US last March, after it admitted &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/20/16800058/apple-iphone-slow-fix-battery-life-capacity"&gt;slowing down older iPhones&lt;/a&gt;. It compensated consumers who bought an iPhone 6 or 7, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/21/16806582/apple-battery-slowdown-science"&gt;were throttled to preserve battery life&lt;/a&gt;. The case grew out of the tech giant’s “Batterygate” controversy, when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/28/16827248/apple-iphone-battery-replacement-price-slow-down-apology"&gt;iPhone users discovered in 2017&lt;/a&gt; that iOS limited processor speeds as iPhone batteries aged. Apple didn’t reveal to consumers that the feature — meant to address problems with phones’ performance — existed. Users said if they had known about the slowdown feature they would have simply replaced the battery rather than buying an all-new phone, as many did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4xgwRv"&gt;The company &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/11/18/apple-fine-battery/"&gt;agreed to a second settlement&lt;/a&gt; in November — this time, with 34 US states —for an additional $113 million. The state attorneys general said Apple “fully understood” that by concealing the intentional slowing down of older phones, the company could profit from people buying new phones rather than replacing the batteries. Apple did not admit to any of the allegations in that settlement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gbRVAT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 25th, 10:45AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Adds comment from Apple spokesperson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jgAxZd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vkCOjt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248408/apple-class-action-suit-throttling-iphone-europe"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248408/apple-class-action-suit-throttling-iphone-europe</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T10:13:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T10:13:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify now hosts audiobook recordings from YouTuber David Dobrik and actress Hilary Swank</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BlI2tL3-fc5P8XGCGP9och8azZI=/72x0:857x523/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68716805/Audiobooks_Pilot_H_2021_1611357123_928x523.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="c5DmVZ"&gt;Spotify isn’t limiting its audio ambitions to podcasts and music. Today the company announced it’s furthering its audiobook experiments with the release of nine new audiobooks available exclusively in the app. As first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/spotify-tests-audiobooks-with-frankenstein-jane-eyre-and-other-literary-classics-exclusive?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, among the works, which are all part of the public domain, are David Dobrik narrating Mary Shelley’s &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;; Forest Whitaker reading Frederick Douglass’ memoir &lt;em&gt;Narrative of the Life of Frederick Douglass, an American Slave&lt;/em&gt;; and Hilary Swank narrating Kate Chopin’s&lt;em&gt; The Awakening&lt;/em&gt;. It’s also releasing an accompanying audio series called &lt;em&gt;Sitting with the Classics on Spotify, &lt;/em&gt;a show in which Harvard professor Glenda Carpio explains the stories’ histories and narratives for a modern listenership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DuAEFd"&gt;Although this is Spotify’s biggest effort in audiobooks to date, it’s not its first attempt. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21247804/harry-potter-daniel-radcliffe-reading-philosophers-stone-spotify-video"&gt;first partnered with J.K. Rowling’s Wizarding World&lt;/a&gt; to release &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher’s Stone &lt;/em&gt;in audio form&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;The chapters, which came out weekly, featured celebrities like Daniel Radcliffe, Dakota Fanning, Claudia Kim, and David Beckham. (The show no longer appears to be listed in Spotify, but we’ve reached out for clarification and will update if we hear back.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wk9wB2"&gt;The decision to pursue audiobooks is interesting, especially given the fact that the company is starting out with public domain works, meaning Spotify doesn’t have to pay to license them. It’s a lower-risk investment for the company, which it might need given that some analysts &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/15/spotifys-big-bet-on-podcasts-is-failing-citi-says.html"&gt;are starting to advise&lt;/a&gt; clients to sell their stock because they don’t see podcasting efforts yielding high returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9IpU3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248393/spotify-audiobook-exclusive-recordings-david-dobrick-hilary-swank"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248393/spotify-audiobook-exclusive-recordings-david-dobrick-hilary-swank</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>To all the streaming services you’ve never heard of before </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HPIOVgINobfQ-vfmX7NkgVfTVtA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68716677/acastro_210119_4370_streamingQuiz_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ncJToZ"&gt;The competition for streaming services is playing out in the same way the tech industry has over the past decade: a small handful of big names, backed by a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="exmJ7i"&gt;But for every Netflix, Amazon Prime, Disney Plus, and Hulu, there are a dozen smaller, more obscure streaming services — many of which you’ve likely never heard of. In fact, let’s see if you can tell the difference between the names of real streaming platforms and ones we’ve made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="AavcLD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22008812#"&gt;Take the quiz on The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="JFiJjy"&gt;
&lt;p id="ENk6pL"&gt;For every household streamer — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/streaming-wars"&gt;Netflix, Hulu, Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt; — there are a dozen that few users would likely recognize. How many people can explain what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21153029/comcast-xumo-acquisition-streaming-wars-tv-film-viant-myspace"&gt;Xumo,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21184294/fox-tubi-acquisition-streaming-wars-news-sports-xumi-comcast-pluto-viacomcbs"&gt;Tubi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/20/21228486/fandango-vudu-streaming-purchase-walmart-comcast-nbcuniversal-amazon-itunes"&gt;Vudu&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21552590/viacomcbs-streaming-paramount-plus-earnings-q3-license-pluto-tv-competition"&gt;Pluto TV&lt;/a&gt; are? How about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21352648/tv-shows-streaming-options-fatigue-netflix-hbo-max-hulu-amazon-prime"&gt;Acorn TV&lt;/a&gt;, Ovid, and Popcornflix?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PUZKv"&gt;But all of these obscure services may play a vital role in how the streaming business looks in the future — or at least media conglomerates believe that enough to spend hundreds of millions to billions to acquire them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Sz56n"&gt;Crunchyroll, a streamer dedicated exclusively to anime, has more than &lt;a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/anime-news/2020/07/28/crunchyroll-crosses-three-million-subscribers"&gt;3 million paying customers&lt;/a&gt;. Shudder, which is dedicated to horror and thriller content, &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/09/shudder-hits-1m-subscribers-as-key-part-of-amc-networks-targeted-streaming-approach-1234582104/"&gt;passed 1 million paying subscribers&lt;/a&gt; last year. BritBox, which is focused on British TV, also passed the 1 million paying subscriber &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/press-release/pr-prnewswire/4f1b9c818dd5d200242696096c37e6be"&gt;mark last year&lt;/a&gt;, doubling its North American customer base in just 14 months, according to the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3hdRt8"&gt;But these numbers aren’t exactly meaningful in a world where Netflix &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238877/netflix-200-million-subscribers-q4-earnings-bridgerton-emily-paris-cobra-kai-queens-gambit"&gt;boasts 203 million global subscribers&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, some companies see owning a portfolio of these smaller streamers as a way to compete indirectly with larger platforms. Crunchyroll was owned by WarnerMedia (which also owns HBO Max) until recently, when it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166585/sony-buy-anime-streaming-service-crunchyroll-at-t-funimation"&gt;sold to Sony for $1.175 billion&lt;/a&gt;. (The sale has not closed yet at the time of this writing.) Shudder is owned by AMC Networks, and BritBox is co-owned by BBC and ITV. They’ve become niche plays for sizable audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Deeo1h"&gt;&lt;q&gt;potential growth is key — not every niche streamer has it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5O6hqn"&gt;If Netflix and Amazon Prime Video want a massive, general audience, their bet is that people will pay for more specific genres of stuff (or endure ads) to watch. Want nothing but wrestling content? WWE &lt;a href="https://www.wwe.com/wwenetwork"&gt;has a streamer.&lt;/a&gt; The Criterion Channel &lt;a href="https://www.criterionchannel.com/"&gt;indulges cinephiles&lt;/a&gt;, while Boomerang hosts &lt;a href="https://www.boomerang.com/"&gt;nothing but old-school cartoons&lt;/a&gt;. The idea is that there’s a specific streamer for everyone, and executives operate under the assumption that there’s just enough of a hungry audience to turn those niche interests into recurring revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Rnmt7"&gt;“What we’ve seen over the years is that there has always been a home for content that caters to a particular area of interest,” Alden Budill, head of global partnerships and content strategy at Crunchyroll, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Our user base craves community inclusion in one place, and we really think that we have an opportunity to be that place.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RlRvgL"&gt;Crunchyroll was started in 2006 by a group of Berkeley grads as a place to host anime clips and provide a place for anime fans to congregate. It caught on quick. The more lucrative anime’s budding viewership in the United States became, the more attention it drew from larger organizations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Rt456"&gt;By 2017, Crunchyroll had more &lt;a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/anime-news/2017/02/09-1/crunchyroll-surpasses-over-one-million-paid-subscribers-details-daily-giveaways-to-celebrate"&gt;than 1 million paying subscribers&lt;/a&gt;. In 2018, AT&amp;amp;T bought &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/att_otter_media.html"&gt;all of Otter Media&lt;/a&gt;, including Crunchyroll, and rolled it into its new WarnerMedia division. The platform gained more than 2 million paid subscribers in that time, reiterating to WarnerMedia executives that anime was a massive potential growth area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bzOUen"&gt;That potential growth is key — not every niche streamer has it. When AT&amp;amp;T acquired Otter Media alongside its Time Warner acquisition in 2018, the telecom giant shuttered a number of niche streamers. Korean drama streaming service &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/asian-america/dramafever-korean-drama-streaming-service-shutting-down-n921221"&gt;DramaFever was shuttered&lt;/a&gt;, as was the &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2018/digital/news/filmstruck-shutdown-warnermedia-turner-1202998364/"&gt;art house-focused FilmStruck&lt;/a&gt;, with most of its library moved over to HBO Max. If the goal of streamers is to bring in and keep subscribers, finding niche genres of content that have ample opportunities to grow is crucial. Anime is a well-established and popular form of entertainment that Crunchyroll proved can continue to build an audience. It’s less clear if a service dedicated to K-dramas can do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="EA0Kl3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s what fans want. It’s how you get it.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vCT7lL"&gt;“Whether it’s a 24/7 cable channel that’s dedicated to cooking, a mobile app that is dedicated to Pac 12 Sports scores, or a streaming service that is dedicated to anime, I wholeheartedly believe that there will continue to be an appetite for and a format for that kind of focused, deep dive-type of experience,” Budill says. “It’s what fans want. It’s how you get it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6SDwg"&gt;Figuring out the formula for a niche streamer or advertisement-supported platform’s worth comes down to its purpose. Fox bought Tubi (an ad-supported, free movie streaming service) for nearly $500 million because it wanted a streamer to carry its titles in an effort to &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/business/story/2020-03-17/fox-acquires-tubi-for-440-million"&gt;grow its audience&lt;/a&gt;, alongside other licensed series and films, while selling better targeted advertising compared to its cable division. AMC &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/amc-networks-finalizes-65m-deal-acquire-robert-johnson-s-rlj-entertainment-1130611"&gt;effectively bought Acorn TV&lt;/a&gt; (a subscription service that carries British television shows and films) for $65 million because its CEO, Josh Sapan, believes it can grow to &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/do-niche-streamers-fit-a-sea-services-1253172"&gt;more than 10 million subscribers&lt;/a&gt;. WarnerMedia sold Crunchyroll to Sony likely because executives believe licensing certain titles is the more cost-effective way of providing anime to HBO Max subscribers without having to pay for the entire operation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f0mArk"&gt;Certain bets on niche streamers are working. Crunchyroll, Shudder, BritBox, Acorn TV, and WWE Network are finding their audiences and continuously hitting subscriber milestones. But as more giant companies try to find ways to pivot to streaming, either launching their own or acquiring services with already impressive followings, is there still a place for niche &lt;em&gt;independent&lt;/em&gt; streamers? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0LYMI2"&gt;One example of continued independent perseverance in the face of an industry swept up by consolidation is Mubi. The European-based streamer has remained independent over the last 13 years, finding success by leaning into areas that gigantic entertainment streamers don’t. While Netflix spends about $90 per subscriber on content (the streamer notably has annual content budgets north of $15 billion, and in 2020, it would have reached $18.5 billion if not for the pandemic), Mubi spends about $18 per customer, according to Mubi CEO Efe Cakarel. Mubi can exist with a smaller subscriber base because it offers a smaller library — just 30 movies at any given time. Not having a massive selection suddenly becomes its appeal; Mubi is tightly curated, rather than being an ocean of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cfFbWZ"&gt;“In a world where Netflix really won the game, in order to survive in a world where Netflix exists — and now Amazon, Apple, and Disney — you need a very clear differentiation,” Cakarel said while &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BMoAMr4QtMA"&gt;speaking at &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; Disrupt in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. “As a young startup, this is a very difficult industry to crack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="JicApN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;streaming services are a dime and dozen, and many of them won’t survive&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="SXxeWM"&gt;Mubi isn’t the only streamer leaning into catering to a smaller, specific audience to stay afloat and succeed. Kweli TV is a streaming service dedicated to carrying films by and about Black people. In August 2020, CEO DeShuna Spencer &lt;a href="https://melanmag.com/2020/08/22/can-your-demographic-afford-this-kweli-tv-founder-talks-to-melan/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Melan Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it grew from 2,000 to 35,000 paid subscribers in under two years. Like Mubi, Kweli TV offers exclusives and a curated library built around directors. FloSports has more than 500,000 subscribers (avid fans of cycling, rowing, and other non-major sports) across its 25 channels, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-08/niche-sports-streaming-service-expands-while-giants-retrench"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SeeUL"&gt;People subscribe to the platform to watch specific things, a different experience than signing up for Netflix to peruse a huge catalog. The best way to compete with the giants is by simply finding the places where they are too big to compete. Still, streaming services are a dime and dozen, and many of them won’t survive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fEeWZU"&gt;Like many stories out of Silicon Valley over the last several years, it’s David versus Goliath — or at least, David gets acquired by Goliath. Smaller companies doing clever things for an engaged audience are being swallowed up by bigger conglomerates. AT&amp;amp;T did the same thing with Otter Media and Crunchyroll before selling it off to Sony Pictures, whose executives also saw a way it could fit into the greater Sony ecosystem. AMC bought Acorn TV, Fox bought Tubi, Comcast bought Xumo and purchased Vudu from Walmart, ViacomCBS bought Pluto TV, and Sony Pictures bought a Christian streaming service called Pure Flix. This morning, NBCUniversal’s announced its service, Peacock, would be the new “exclusive home” for WWE Network content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="13cgUI"&gt;One study from August 2020 found that nearly half of US households &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/08/more-than-half-of-u-s-households-now-subscribe-to-multiple-streaming-services-study-1203025747/"&gt;subscribe to three or four&lt;/a&gt; video streaming entertainment platforms, which means there’s space in the market for niche streaming platforms to find their footing with smaller, specific libraries for smaller, specific audiences — but only if they don’t get swallowed up by media conglomerates first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKTBT8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: Comcast, which owns NBCUniversal, is also an investor in Vox Media, &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt;’s parent company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22244771/streaming-services-niche-crunchyroll-ovid-acorn-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22244771/streaming-services-niche-crunchyroll-ovid-acorn-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T09:58:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T09:58:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony’s flagship noise-canceling headphones are back down to their lowest price yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VJkKec_L_7ss0zTbcD00koez2IA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68716660/IMG_0625-1.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7JPGMM"&gt;If you’ve found yourself wanting some peace and quiet, whether it’s from the upstairs neighbor’s kid stomping around above you or just to silence other distractions, today’s marquee deal has your name written all over it. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356313/sony-1000xm4-noise-canceling-headphones-review-price-specs-features"&gt;The Sony WH-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt; are $72 off at Amazon, Best Buy, and other retailers — matching the lowest price yet that we’ve seen happen a few times now. We first saw this price drop occur during Prime Day last October, and it went on to become one of the most popular deals of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qns6lF"&gt;This model is almost identical to the previous generation (WH-1000XM3), with its similarly sublime audio quality and noise cancellation effect. What’s new in this set, though, is a sensor that automatically pauses music when you remove them, then resumes when you put them back on. It also has improved voice quality and, perhaps the biggest improvement, support for two simultaneous Bluetooth connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zfHhCr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9523565"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/djB1tHiowpxGPPVMQZXkRGJw7J0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22257893/aukey_usbc.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Aukey&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ePoDWf"&gt;Apple’s USB-C 20W wall adapter costs $19, but you don’t have to pay that much to get the fastest-possible charging speeds for your iPhone. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0828WB2VR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Aukey’s 20W USB-C wall charger is $7.69&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon (usually $13) right now. You’ll need your own USB-C cord (either one that ends in USB-C if you own an iPad Pro or the latest iPad Air, or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07H256MBK/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;USB-C to Lightning&lt;/a&gt; for all iPhones). Of course, this is also a nice, affordable option that’s suitable for any USB-C device, be it an Android phone or a Nintendo Switch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Transformers and Back to the Future mash-up" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PAliezXWynDimqOFFBjt6Eq8i_g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22258519/transformersbacktothefuture.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Hasbro Inc.&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vBndl6"&gt;Lastly, we wanted to point out that you can preorder this Transformers / Back to the Future mash-up collectible at GameStop. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-collectibles%2Fcollectibles%2Ffigures%2Fproducts%2Ftransformers-collaborative-back-to-the-future-mash-up-gigawatt-back-to-the-future-35-edition-figure%2F216733.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It’s $21 right now&lt;/a&gt; (usually $30). My colleague Sean Hollister snagged one from the first batch when it released, and he says it’s a well-designed figure. This batch is set to release in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="veeito"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/25/22248350/sony-wh1000xm4-wireless-headphones-usb-c-charger-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/25/22248350/sony-wh1000xm4-wireless-headphones-usb-c-charger-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T09:49:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T09:49:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>AMC Theatres staves off bankruptcy just in time for studios to delay their films all over again</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Entertainment &amp;amp;amp; Tourism Industries In New York City Struggle Under Pandemic Restrictions" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/29wNHsGcpQchZ5K7pz_1atCnNS0=/0x0:6192x4128/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68716610/1284144321.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Alexi Rosenfeld/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jMrpgf"&gt;AMC Theatres has raised nearly $1 billion in funding since December 14th, staving off bankruptcy for several more months, the company announced today. The announcement comes just days after several major studios, including Paramount, Sony, and Disney’s Fox, all &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22243496/bond-uncharted-ghostbusters-movie-delays"&gt;delayed many of their films&lt;/a&gt; to the latter half of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYUXP1"&gt;In total, AMC raised $917 million, &lt;a href="https://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0001411579/28598a3b-69d6-4e3e-8858-2bfa385c3268.html"&gt;according to public documents&lt;/a&gt;. More than half of that capital arrives in the form of equity that comes with selling 164.7 million new common shares. AMC raised another $411 million in incremental debt that is scheduled to be paid off by mid-2023, according to the filing. As such, AMC Theatres executives now believe they have a new “financial runway” that extends “deep into 2021.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xHBR6i"&gt;“This means that any talk of an imminent bankruptcy for AMC is completely off the table,” AMC CEO Adam Aron said in a press release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xkfkJR"&gt;How long that runway will actually last if nothing changes isn’t crystal clear, but public documents filed by the company say that “in the absence of any increase in attendance levels” and assuming that AMC will still have to pay its leases without any additional cash raised, “our existing liquidity would extend our operations through to July 2021.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ep7EIv"&gt;Still, having a deep runway is good news for AMC Theatres executives, who will likely watch as more films are delayed into the latter half of 2021. Films like &lt;em&gt;Morbius&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Ghostbusters: Afterlife&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; No Time To Die&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Uncharted&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and more have seen their release dates relegated to October 2021 and beyond, with &lt;em&gt;Uncharted &lt;/em&gt;moving in 2022. Industry insiders predict that other major films slated for the first half of 2021 — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21437889/black-widow-delayed-release-date-marvel-cinematic-universe-disney-streaming-mulan"&gt;&lt;em&gt;F9 &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example — will also likely move. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k6Ungw"&gt;Studios looking to hit the magical $1 billion box office revenue number likely see no upside to releasing movies in a market where theaters are either entirely closed or operating at a limited capacity. AMC Theatres currently has 438 of its 593 theaters in the US open as of January 21st, according to public documents. Theaters that remain closed, however, exist in some of the United States’ most important major markets, including New York City and Los Angeles. As such, AMC Theatres reported an overall attendance decline of 92.3 percent compared to 2019, according to public documents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3GcCaj"&gt;Other films that studios are less positive will come with a guaranteed return on investment are being sold off; Netflix just acquired &lt;em&gt;The Mitchells vs. The Machines&lt;/em&gt;, an animated film formerly called &lt;em&gt;Connected &lt;/em&gt;that’s directed by Phil Lord and Chris Miller, from Sony. While the theater chains and studios struggle to figure out when they can start ushering people into theater seats to watch films, streamers like Netflix continue to thrive as people try to find new things to watch while being forced to remain home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ICpS0D"&gt;Since everything is up in the air — that’s according to AMC executives — the actual runway of time that the additional cash raised will buy the company is dependent on “future attendance levels.” Future attendance levels are based on a couple of different criteria, including: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WSGEUX"&gt;vaccination rollout around the world, but especially in the United States&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mS9j5W"&gt;government orders regarding restrictions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DOAb7C"&gt;consumer behavior in a post-pandemic world &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="k0U8Mf"&gt;Cities like Paris, Toronto, and London have set heavier lockdown restrictions as COVID-19 cases rise, meaning that nonessential outings like going to the movies simply aren’t possible. In the United States, cities like Los Angeles and New York City have prevented movie theaters from opening since the pandemic began and, as cases rise, may continue to prevent nonessential gatherings. If a large portion of the population is vaccinated by summer, things may change, but it’s unclear if the United States will hit those goals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PCKnHE"&gt;Then there’s consumer behavior. This is an element of post-pandemic life that studios like Disney have warned their own shareholders about. Will people feel comfortable sitting in packed theaters with strangers again, hearing people sneeze and cough, especially during the winter months? Disney executives told shareholders they can’t predict that, but it’s something that AMC Theatres executives are also likely thinking about as they try to wrangle more cash from shareholders to stay afloat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EjQEq8"&gt;For now, however, AMC has a future in front of it — at least for a little while longer. Like everything these days, it’s all dependent on what happens next. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248335/amc-bankruptcy-debt-movies-delay-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248335/amc-bankruptcy-debt-movies-delay-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-25T09:37:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-25T09:37:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V9cZCU"&gt;Apple AirPods are among the most popular headphones on the market. They’re compact, easy to pair with your devices, and offer reliable connectivity, which can sometimes be a problem with truly wireless earphones. So there’s a chance that you might be looking for a deal on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR97R2"&gt;Surprisingly, they’re no stranger to the occasional price cut. There are often discounts on even the more expensive AirPods Pro, which offers noise cancellation and better sound than the standard second-generation model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;We’ll run through all three of the current models below, including the standard AirPods, the more expensive AirPods that include a wireless charging case, and finally, the AirPods Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZuVjFm"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple AirPods 2 review: even more wireless|63428" data-volume-uuid="c798b260f" data-volume-id="63428" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-896" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VFDHZw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="R1mQdI"&gt;These are Apple’s entry-level wireless earbuds. They are a reliable pair of wireless earbuds with a one-size-fits-most design. The AirPods usually retail for $160, which is not a bad price, but this model frequently gets discounted.  You can currently find Apple’s most affordable AirPods for $129 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441%3Fwmlspartner%3Dwlpa%26selectedSellerId%3D433%26%26adid%3D22222222227281354149%26wl0%3D%26wl1%3Dg%26wl2%3Dc%26wl3%3D339987579106%26wl4%3Dpla-667825192756%26wl5%3D9008008%26wl6%3D%26wl7%3D%26wl8%3D%26wl9%3Dpla%26wl10%3D111830562%26wl11%3Donline%26wl12%3D604342441%26veh%3Dsem%26gclid%3DCjwKCAiAoOz-BRBdEiwAyuvA61H2BRTbBBeDsoekxoiD1iyavhCvjOe-rc1VRE8KROBAR83M_YmAIBoC31kQAvD_BwE&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or for $130 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1730426167398815626" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yHjw-MSSOE9krvMa6cC9qYmHU9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993019/akrales_190327_3315_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PK1JRu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods (with wireless charging case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;The AirPods with wireless charging case are identical in every way to the standard AirPods, save for one: their charging case can be charged on a Qi wireless pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYNUWv"&gt;You’ll need to provide your own wireless charging pad to take advantage of this feature (if you have no use for it, just get the more affordable option above), but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2017/10/27/16554680/best-wireless-charger-qi-ravpower-samsung-anker-mophie"&gt;even the best ones are fairly inexpensive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="glqkTs"&gt;Most of the time you can find this version for less than Apple’s sticker price of $199, but keep a lookout for deals that bring the price down to $160 or below. Currently, the lowest price is $130 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F482532021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; or you can get them for $160 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=4781ccd9dac6fb8bf9e60c657cd3fbba&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1730426265427578073" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/979838/2092?sharedid=verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OGXtAu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Uv43TD"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="AirPods Pro review: the perfect earbuds for the iPhone|73652" data-volume-uuid="c840e1e11" data-volume-id="73652" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-211" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s9Ofwq"&gt;Apple’s high-end truly wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, have better sound quality than the other models described above, include noise cancellation, and now support Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. We think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;they’re the best wireless earbuds that iPhone owners&lt;/a&gt; can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaMGwU"&gt;The AirPods Pro are frequently available for less than their $249 retail price, and in fact, sometimes drop down to $200 and lower. Right now, if you don’t mind buying refurbished, they are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1730154636955201273" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$200 at Best Buy (Geek Squad Certified)&lt;/a&gt;. If you want a new pair, both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4/ref=as_li_ss_tl?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; are offering these flagship earbuds for the same $200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdTSzD"&gt;If those deals sell out, you can get them for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html%2FDFF%2Fd10-v21-t1-x995659%2FSID%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21302051%2Fbest-apple-airpods-deals#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$220 at B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1730426359423842282" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$235 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to get an Apple Care Plus protection plan for your wireless earbuds, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1570785-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html%2FDFF%2Fd10-v21-t1-x1050461&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21302051%2Fbest-apple-airpods-deals#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H is selling a bundle that includes both for $280&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TuBiVT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FDsE87"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c9yAKy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
