<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-03T17:13:20-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T17:13:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T17:13:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung tells Texas it wants to create 1,800 jobs with a $17 billion factory in Austin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bFCWVqYcfrRqy8s4GTOBE1bfF7Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68906140/acastro_190503_1777_samsung_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FvzK76"&gt;Samsung has submitted paperwork to Texas officials, requesting a billion dollars in tax incentives to make Austin the future home of the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22243994/samsung-chipmaking-texas-plant-3nm-10-billion-report"&gt;$17 billion chip factory&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-03/samsung-details-plans-for-17-billion-chip-facility-in-u-s?utm_content=tech&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;cmpid%3D=socialflow-twitter-tech&amp;amp;utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;noted by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and reported last month by &lt;a href="https://www.statesman.com/story/business/2021/02/04/samsung-austin-expansion-chip-plant-seeks-1-billion-taxpayer-incentives/4309503001/"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Austin American-Statesman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://assets.comptroller.texas.gov/ch313/1554/1554-manor-samsung-app.pdf"&gt;In the documents&lt;/a&gt;, which were filed in January, the company says it plans on bringing 1,800 permanent jobs to the factory over the first 10 years, with an average starting salary around $66K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pDrkFB"&gt;In return, Samsung is &lt;a href="https://www.statesman.com/story/business/2021/02/04/samsung-austin-expansion-chip-plant-seeks-1-billion-taxpayer-incentives/4309503001/"&gt;asking for a break on its property taxes&lt;/a&gt;: it’s looking for a 100 percent break on its payments to Travis County for 20 years, which the company estimates would save it roughly $718 million, and a 50 percent break on the taxes to the City of Austin for five years, with an estimated $87 million. It also wants the state to subsidize its property tax payments to the school district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7MndPp"&gt;It seems like Samsung is still trying to decide where to put the factory: in the documents, the company calls the project “highly competitive,” and says that “[d]ue to the higher tax cost of operating in Texas, the appraised value limitation is a determining factor. Without the appraised value limitation award, the company would likely locate the project in Arizona, New York or Korea.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zlN5Rw"&gt;If Samsung chooses Austin, it would be expanding its existing plant there — the company already has a chip-making fab in the city, which has been there since 1997. The factory currently employs around 10,000 people, and the &lt;em&gt;Austin American-Statesman&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.statesman.com/story/business/2021/02/04/samsung-austin-expansion-chip-plant-seeks-1-billion-taxpayer-incentives/4309503001/"&gt;notes that&lt;/a&gt; Samsung has recently bought 257.7 acres of land near its existing factory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h9ZIyW"&gt;Looking for incentives from cities and states is nothing new, but Samsung is asking for quite a lot, especially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/14/21323977/austin-tesla-tax-breaks-travis-county-cybertruck-factory-incentives"&gt;compared to Tesla&lt;/a&gt;, which is also building a factory in Austin: the car manufacturer only got around $60 million in tax rebates from the county and school district. The two planned factories aren’t directly comparable due to differences in cost, employment numbers and salaries, and more, but Samsung’s still looking for an order of magnitude more than Tesla received. It could be that Samsung used the billion-dollar figure as an opening negotiation, but any deals being worked on don’t yet seem to be public.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311825/samsung-texas-austin-chip-factory-expansion-choice-jobs-tax-incentives"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311825/samsung-texas-austin-chip-factory-expansion-choice-jobs-tax-incentives</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T16:29:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T16:29:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Losing YouTube on the old Apple TV underscores how far ahead competitors are</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vgNgIDxQvifYJQMBBbMX2HPZt3s=/0x0:1037x691/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68905907/appletv.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ktv7q8"&gt;The YouTube app on older Apple TV models has officially been discontinued as of today. If you have a third-generation device (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/3/14/2870779/apple-tv-review-2012"&gt;the 2012-era model&lt;/a&gt; that predated the modern tvOS-based set-top boxes), you’ll only be able to stream YouTube through an iOS device using AirPlay starting today, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/03/03/older-apple-tv-will-require-airplay-for-youtube-video-playback-starting-next-month/"&gt;as noted by &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vbm3Xl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22265965/apple-tv-3rd-gen-youtube-native-onboard-support-airplay"&gt;While the news&lt;/a&gt; has been known for a while, the change highlights a key issue with the Apple TV ecosystem. Namely, that it’s been nearly three and a half years since Apple has last updated its streaming box hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9YzIXC"&gt;If you own the old model with the now defunct YouTube app, your only Apple-made option is the Apple TV 4K, released in September 2017. That’s particularly problematic, given that the Apple TV 4K still starts at $179 (with a pricier 64GB model that offers double the storage for $199), despite being released years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xL6HP2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best streaming device to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21375098/best-streaming-device"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="131UHf"&gt;That’s in stark comparison to competitors like Amazon, Google, and Roku, which have released newer streaming products that offer the same (if not better) features than Apple’s outdated box at far lower prices. Roku’s flagship streaming box, the Roku Ultra, costs $99 — nearly half the price of the entry-level Apple TV 4K — while supporting 4K, HDR, Dolby Vision, and Apple’s own AirPlay 2 streaming. The $50 Streaming Stick Plus offers 4K and HDR (without Dolby Vision) for those looking to save even more money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AzpZWk"&gt;Amazon’s Fire TV Cube costs $119.99 and offers similar high-end streaming specs, while also doubling as a full-fledged Echo speaker. Like Roku, Amazon also has its cheaper $50 Fire TV Stick 4K, which offers the full gamut of streaming support (Dolby Vision, Dolby Atmos, HDR10+, and HDR10) without the added Alexa speaker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e4oWWs"&gt;And of course, there’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21495609/google-chromecast-2020-review-streaming-remote-control"&gt;Google’s latest Chromecast&lt;/a&gt;, which costs just $50, offers excellent content curation, supports 4K, HDR, Dolby Atmos, and Dolby Vision, and remains &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s best choice for a streaming stick in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Khq9Gq"&gt;With more and more apps starting to end support for Apple’s older streaming boxes (CBS All Access has already announced that it’ll be enacting a similar change when Paramount Plus launches), the problem of the Apple TV’s outdated hardware and pricing are only going to continue to grow. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311881/apple-tv-2012-youtube-discontinued-app-replacement-google-roku-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311881/apple-tv-2012-youtube-discontinued-app-replacement-google-roku-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T16:10:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T16:10:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple now lets you automatically transfer your iCloud Photo Library to Google Photos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-O7yIeZOplUwpIsFuP79ABD7WEs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68905811/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="B6Vb1x"&gt;Apple has added a service that lets you automatically transfer photos, videos, and albums from your iCloud Photo Library to Google Photos (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/03/03/apple-transfer-icloud-photos-google-photos/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The feature has &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208514"&gt;a support document outlining the procedure&lt;/a&gt;, which simply entails going to &lt;a href="https://privacy.apple.com/"&gt;privacy.apple.com&lt;/a&gt;, logging in, and going through the “transfer a copy of your data” process. Apple says the transfer will take between three days to a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OlPxfA"&gt;Some things won’t transfer: Apple says shared albums, smart albums, photo stream content, live photos, some metadata, and media that isn’t stored in your iCloud Photo Library won’t come along for the ride. The part about Live Photos is especially eyebrow-raising. &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT207310"&gt;iPhones take Live Photos by default&lt;/a&gt;, and Apple doesn’t make it clear if the entire picture will be left behind, or just the video clip surrounding it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mk15DTxUNHvZ7V2VrURoGN8T2rg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22343247/Screen_Shot_2021_03_03_at_12.23.03_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Mitchell Clark / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MKDR7D"&gt;For what it’s worth, the transfer tool tells me 10,793 of my photos will be transferred, which is the exact number of pictures in my library. Given that over 2,500 of those are Live, it would seem Apple is planning on transferring them, but we did reach out to clarify. At the time of writing, we haven't heard back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AOq2XL"&gt;Apple says the feature won’t remove anything from your iCloud Photo Library; it will simply make a copy of it, so you’ll still need to manually delete things if you no longer want them stored in iCloud. Additionally, the feature is currently only available to people in Australia, Canada, the European Union, Iceland, Liechtenstein, New Zealand, Norway, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SHmI7k"&gt;If you’re looking to make the jump from iPhone to Android or just want to use Google Photos, this tool should provide an easy way to quickly transfer all of your photos to the service without having to reupload them yourself. A few clicks, and your photos will be on their way to their new home. Just make sure &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560810/google-photos-unlimited-cap-free-uploads-15gb-ending"&gt;you have enough Google storage space&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311990/apple-icloud-photo-google-transfer-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311990/apple-icloud-photo-google-transfer-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T16:04:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T16:04:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Great apes receive COVID-19 vaccine at San Diego Zoo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A photo outside the San Diego Zoo on a sunny day. The sign for the zoo has its name in big green letters. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MrZ31n9flVto500UZcU1d4r4SZo=/0x0:5760x3840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68905789/1218313654.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The San Diego Zoo.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Daniel Knighton/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N26I4F"&gt;Several great apes at the San Diego Zoo received two doses each of a COVID-19 vaccine in February, &lt;a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/article/first-great-apes-at-us-zoo-receive-coronavirus-vaccine-made-for-animals"&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Geographic&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. The lucky recipients are four orangutans and five bonobos, who were distracted with treats as they got their shots. One of the orangutans is Karen, the &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1994-08-28-mn-32264-story.html"&gt;first ape to undergo open-heart surgery&lt;/a&gt; in 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8lowd"&gt;Ape vaccination is a welcome development at the San Diego Zoo, where a troop of eight gorillas &lt;a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/article/gorillas-san-diego-zoo-positive-coronavirus"&gt;tested positive for COVID-19 in January&lt;/a&gt;. The sick gorillas were symptomatic but &lt;a href="https://zoo.sandiegozoo.org/pressroom/news-releases/guests-can-once-again-visit-gorilla-troop-san-diego-zoo-safari-park"&gt;have now recovered&lt;/a&gt;, according to the zoo. They’ll likely join their orangutan and bonobo compatriots in vaccination later in the spring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F5sG1x"&gt;The vaccine the apes received is not one of the vaccines that have been authorized for humans. It was developed by a veterinary pharmaceutical company after the first recorded case of COVID-19 in a dog in February 2020. In addition to dogs and gorillas, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/4/21549737/denmark-cull-mink-coronavirus-outbreak-mutation"&gt;minks&lt;/a&gt;, domestic cats, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/6/21211217/pets-cats-tigers-bronx-zoo-covid-19-coronavirus"&gt;big cats&lt;/a&gt; have also been infected by the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xs9UTG"&gt;After the vaccine was confirmed to be safe and effective for dogs and cats, Nadine Lamberski, chief conservation and wildlife health officer at the San Diego Zoo, decided to start vaccinating the apes, &lt;em&gt;National Geographic&lt;/em&gt; reports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ixYuGO"&gt;Lamberski says it’s common to give vaccines to species that are different from the ones they were tested on because they’re developed for specific pathogens, not specific species. The apes haven’t had any adverse reactions, and they’re being tested for antibodies to see if the vaccine is working. Lamberski’s team will continue collecting and sharing data about the vaccine’s effectiveness as more apes are vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311984/great-apes-covid-19-vaccine-san-diego-zoo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311984/great-apes-covid-19-vaccine-san-diego-zoo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T16:01:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T16:01:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sinking City developer uses DMCA request to get its own game removed from Steam</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sdR7NUUVg5fGL43glfdsIQ3I2H0=/138x0:1625x991/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68905771/sc5qqo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Frogwares&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Z0YbvM"&gt;Valve has removed &lt;em&gt;The Sinking City&lt;/em&gt; from its digital storefront Steam after the company received a Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) request from the game’s developer Frogwares, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/epdw7p/the-sinking-city-developer-uses-dmca-to-remove-its-own-game-from-steam"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. Frogwares claims that the game’s original publisher, Nacon, hacked and pirated the game and republished it on Steam without the studio’s knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVZp4F"&gt;A Valve spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;Vice &lt;/em&gt;on Tuesday evening that the company was able to collect “extremely strong evidence to indicate this version of the game was pirated,” and that the version of &lt;em&gt;The Sinking City&lt;/em&gt; published on its digital storefront “contains content that Nacon has absolutely no rights to — namely &lt;em&gt;The Merciful Madness&lt;/em&gt; DLC.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LB93Pd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sinking City&lt;/em&gt;’s PC version is still purchasable as a self-published title&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vO0hPB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sinking City&lt;/em&gt; initially launched in 2019, but Frogwares announced last year it would &lt;a href="https://frogwares.com/the-sinking-city-is-being-delisted-heres-why/"&gt;pull the game from stores&lt;/a&gt;, citing back payment that Nacon owed the studio. Nacon &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-03-03-the-sinking-city-dev-dmcas-its-own-game-to-force-it-off-steam"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Eurogame&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; that it accused the developer of “playing the victim” and said it had paid the studio more than €10 million to date. In &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/26/22303653/the-sinking-city-steam-frogwares-nacon-pc"&gt;late February&lt;/a&gt;, Nacon put the game back on Steam, which Frogwares says was actually a pirated version of the game that was unassociated with the studio (and which has since been removed following the DMCA request).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PlPSOh"&gt;Currently, &lt;em&gt;The Sinking City&lt;/em&gt;’s Steam page does appear in a &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=the+sinking+city&amp;amp;oq=The+Sinking+City&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.0i131i355i433j46i131i433j0i131i433j69i59j0i131i433l2j69i60j69i61.895j0j7&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8"&gt;web browser search&lt;/a&gt;, but clicking on it redirects you to the homepage for the web version of Steam. &lt;em&gt;The Sinking City&lt;/em&gt;'s PC version is still purchasable as a self-published title from Frogwares through other storefronts, such as &lt;a href="https://www.origin.com/usa/en-us/search?searchString=the%2520sinking%2520city"&gt;Origin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311871/sinking-city-valve-steam-dmca-pirated-frogwares-nacon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311871/sinking-city-valve-steam-dmca-pirated-frogwares-nacon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T15:31:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T15:31:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Motorola Moto G Stylus (2021) review: the write stuff</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Your best bet for a budget phone with a stylus&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="eyIWAy"&gt;Calling the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motorola.com%2Fus%2Fsmartphones-moto-g-stylus-gen-2%2Fp&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22311690%2Fmotorola-moto-g-stylus-2021-review-price-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2021 Motorola Moto G Stylus&lt;/a&gt; the best budget stylus phone feels a bit like a backhanded compliment. There’s more or less just one other contender for that title, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22301223/lg-stylo-6-review"&gt;the LG Stylo 6&lt;/a&gt;, which is too underpowered to recommend. But the G Stylus doesn’t just win by default; it’s actually a well-rounded and capable phone for under $300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MrJn6O"&gt;It offers a big 6.8-inch 1080p screen, a generous 128GB of built-in storage, and a Snapdragon 678 processor with 4GB of RAM. Motorola &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22218732/motorola-moto-g-stylus-power-play-2021-one-5g-ace-specs-price-release-date-budget"&gt;introduced it earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; with a $299 MSRP, though it’s now selling for $279 from the manufacturer and other retailers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ERktRf"&gt;Other highlights include a 48-megapixel main camera accompanied by ultrawide and macro rear cameras, a 4,000mAh battery, a “water-repellant” design, and a fingerprint sensor embedded in the recessed power button. It’s a well-rounded set of features for a budget device, even without considering the G Stylus’ headline feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1CMXfG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10372411"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xMwyscYsaBk45_Mxu3BlvMy9hSc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22336738/ajohnson_210228_4453_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G Stylus includes apps for note-taking, doodling, and coloring.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="A24AIo"&gt;Moto G Stylus (2021) stylus features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Jio0dS"&gt;The main selling point is definitely the G Stylus’ stylus, so let’s cover that first. Like the Stylo 6, the G Stylus includes a built-in capacitive stylus tucked into the bottom-right corner of the device. Popping it out brings up a quick menu of shortcuts to stylus-friendly apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="twmfhO"&gt;There’s a note-taking app and a shortcut to take and annotate a screenshot. You can also jot down a quick note without unlocking the screen. It’s a basic set of features — nothing too advanced like what the Galaxy Note series offers — but with a couple of neat bonuses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GbZ0AIeUWlcJoEYrQ0CqKKtx11s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22343035/Screenshot_20210301_163539_resized.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;With AI, the phone can recognize what you’re trying to draw and turn it into a coloring book template.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i26b5z"&gt;First, messaging apps support handwriting-to-text conversion. This is a Gboard setting you can enable on any Android device, but it’s available by default on the G Stylus. Pressing the “globe” icon to the left of the spacebar opens up the handwriting panel. Write your message, and watch it appear in the text line above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BEE9d9"&gt;The Moto G Stylus’ other trick is the ability to create cinemagraphs, still images with a moving element. To create one, you’ll basically take a short video clip, holding the camera still. Then you use the stylus to draw on the areas of the scene with motion. The rest will remain frozen as a still image. You don’t necessarily need a stylus for this, but the added precision is helpful. Results can be saved as an MP4 or a GIF. The app does a decent job of stabilizing a handheld image for a more convincing final product, though the resulting clip is fairly low-res. Still, it’s fun to play with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x2wzF4"&gt;While the LG Stylo 6’s stylus features felt a little more fun and creativity-focused, the Moto G is a little more no-nonsense. Sure, there’s a coloring book app that does a neat trick of using AI to identify a rudimentary sketch of a cat and turn it into a template for your digital “crayons.” But where’s the animated GIF creator? Or an app that records as you sketch so you can text your friends and show off your mad doodling skills? These things exist in third-party apps, no doubt. But the native feature set feels, for better or worse, a little more grown-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jy_YBGfEcsjz-eNJ2sdY4-5mBxg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22336740/ajohnson_210228_4453_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto G Stylus features a big 6.8-inch screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NH82aJ"&gt;Moto G Stylus (2021) screen and performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="nyPqnf"&gt;The Stylus’ screen is nothing fancy — standard 60Hz refresh rate LCD — but it’s a decently bright and large 6.8-inch 1080p display. The phone itself is, naturally, also large and on the heavier side, but the slightly rounded edges of its back panel make it more comfortable to hold than its dimensions suggest. It looks a little ridiculous peeking out of the top of a yoga pants pocket, but this stylus-packing device was never meant to be ultra pocketable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8GsK6T"&gt;The G Stylus uses a Snapdragon 678 processor with 4GB of RAM, and this combination feels more than adequate for day-to-day tasks. Apps load quickly, and jumping between them feels snappy. There are some occasional hiccups and slight slowdowns when scrolling through media-rich apps like Twitter, but nothing that feels too frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Y8eANu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I had no problem getting through a full day with plenty of battery life left to spare&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="spyXqe"&gt;Battery life is also good — not outstanding but thoroughly sufficient. Motorola claims the Stylus will get two days to a single charge, which feels like a little bit of a stretch in my experience. More importantly, I had no problem getting through a full day, including two-plus hours of screen time, with plenty of battery life left to spare. Motorola includes a 10W charger, which it calls “Turbo Power” when it’s connected. Charging speeds are more average than “Turbo”: 10 minutes of charge got me an extra 10 percent, and it took about 40 minutes total to bring an 80 percent battery up to full charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p3Sirp"&gt;The Moto G Stylus ships with Android 10 and is expected to get an update to Android 11. Motorola doesn’t say exactly when, but G Stylus owners can keep an eye on the &lt;a href="https://motorola-global-portal.custhelp.com/app/software-upgrade/g_id/1949"&gt;company’s software update page&lt;/a&gt; for more information. Motorola’s budget device support isn’t great; the phone will get just two years of security updates, ending in January 2023. Samsung &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;recently announced&lt;/a&gt; that even its budget A-series Galaxy phones will now be guaranteed four years of security updates. Hopefully, that’s a policy more manufacturers like Motorola will consider adopting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F3eiDKGk5p3t3cGZ7uL5br-M_hs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22336741/ajohnson_210228_4453_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Stylus includes standard wide, ultrawide, and macro rear cameras.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DkYomP"&gt;Moto G Stylus (2021) camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="dk909J"&gt;The triple camera on the G Stylus is the same found on the $400-ish &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22255202/motorola-one-5g-ace-review"&gt;Motorola One 5G Ace&lt;/a&gt;, with the addition of a dedicated depth sensor. To recap, that includes a 48-megapixel f/1.7 main camera that produces 12-megapixel images, an 8-megapixel f/2.2 ultrawide, and a 2-megapixel macro camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DV5N2C"&gt;There are no surprises here. Like the Ace, the G Stylus is capable of good-quality images in bright light, particularly from the main camera. Downsampling from 48 megapixels to 12 allows it to capture plenty of detail, but if you look close, you’ll see some crunchy-looking sharpening. Colors are reproduced well, without looking overly saturated. As an exception, the camera seems to boost saturation and warmth when it identifies a subject as food. The results are more appetizing, if a little unnatural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y0nxv7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10372367"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NNoFvO"&gt;Unfortunately, the ultrawide camera is less good. Even photos taken in bright light show smeary details and some ugly noise. A photo I took of a city street has an unusual purple tint, while a photo from the main camera in the same spot looks much better. This is all evident even at smaller image sizes for social sharing, which is unfortunate. The macro camera is bad, but the selfie camera is a little sharper and better than expected from a budget phone. Win some, lose some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iP1sSz"&gt;While the camera system on the Ace was a bit of a letdown, it feels about right on the less expensive Moto G Stylus. You won’t find an amazing night mode or top-notch picture quality here, but for a sub-$300 phone, it does the job just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0JIEeXAt6iw_y6wEeLjcPgr3duc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22336739/ajohnson_210228_4453_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G Stylus is a well-rounded budget device, even if you don’t care about its pen-focused features.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="qbxBxO"&gt;The Moto G Stylus is a well-rounded budget phone that also happens to have a stylus. Of Motorola’s 2021 budget devices that I’ve tested so far, this one offers the best balance of features and cost-saving measures. It has a big display, stylus features, good battery life, and solid everyday performance. The cameras, though flawed, are good enough to get by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="NvcBBw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This is the obvious choice for someone looking for a budget stylus phone&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K8UcUv"&gt;This is the obvious choice for someone looking for a budget stylus phone, but I hesitate to recommend it to everyone else. The $299 OnePlus Nord N10 5G offers a faster refresh rate screen, a better camera, and slightly better performance for nearly the same price. If you can afford to spend a bit more, the $349 Google Pixel 4A will offer better software support and a great camera. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="X1RZZp"&gt;If you’re a stylus devotee or even just strongly stylus-curious, the Moto G Stylus is a good choice. But if you’re ambivalent toward the stylus, you might be better off with one of these other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TxCUMy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="YD0Ath"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10372352"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22311690/motorola-moto-g-stylus-2021-review-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22311690/motorola-moto-g-stylus-2021-review-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T15:18:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T15:18:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>San Diego Comic-Con, E3, and Anime Expo cancel geek gatherings for the second year in a row</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nGqeAOe2wA9Nu4_RJp2WNVBJTfc=/3x0:1017x676/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68893583/sdcc_stock31_1020.0.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H4J9Zo"&gt;San Diego Comic-Con &lt;a href="https://www.comic-con.org/cci"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; this year’s show will not go on, at least not in person, and the 2021 Anime Expo has &lt;a href="https://www.anime-expo.org/2021/03/03/anime-expo-2021/"&gt;now officially canceled&lt;/a&gt; its physical event as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cp58dC"&gt;That’s the second time in 50 years — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/17/21225299/san-diego-comic-con-canceled-dates-july-2021-refunds"&gt;the first was last year&lt;/a&gt; — that Comic-Con has been canceled due to the COVID-19 pandemic. There’ll still be a virtual event from July 23rd to the 25th, and organizers are planning a three-day in-person convention tentatively set for November, but they’re clear that the full shebang has been postponed until 2022 — and offering refunds and rollovers as appropriate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uQNN3a"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/YftNZhDuk5"&gt;pic.twitter.com/YftNZhDuk5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— San Diego Comic-Con (@Comic_Con) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Comic_Con/status/1366478468091965440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B7jJid"&gt;They’re not the only California geek gatherings that aren’t going to happen: the Los Angeles Department of Convention and Tourism &lt;a href="https://ens.lacity.org/lacc/laccdcagendas/lacclaccdcagendas250148287_03032021.pdf"&gt;has filed documents (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; that show that the biggest US video game show — E3, aka the Electronic Entertainment Expo — has also ditched its in-person gathering (via &lt;a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/e3-2021-as-live-event-cancelled-going-forward-as-digital-working-on-broadcast-options-at-la-live-lacc.385877/#post-59678096"&gt;ResetEra&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/e3-2021s-live-show-has-been-cancelled-according-to-la-t-1846373286"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O9X-pFh7WobSNCNfssIvNvlVRyM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22337636/e3_anime_expo.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LODzQy"&gt;E3 typically draws upwards of 60,000 attendees while Anime Expo can attract over 100,000, so they’re big losses for tourism that the city will be seriously discussing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4j2KW"&gt;Mind you, the Entertainment Software Association that runs E3 already hinted that it would be “transforming” its showcase, so a virtual event wouldn’t be much of a surprise. Anime Expo held &lt;a href="https://www.anime-expo.org/2020/07/14/anime-expo-lite-livestream-event-draws-500000-views-around-world-celebrate-japanese-pop-culture/"&gt;a successful virtual event last year&lt;/a&gt; that drew 500,000 viewers dubbed Anime Expo Lite, and organizers will try that once more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MhlI3B"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We will not have a physical event for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AX2021?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AX2021&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AnimeExpoLite?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AnimeExpoLite&lt;/a&gt; will return on July 4th weekend.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Read the update on our website → &lt;a href="https://t.co/MQdTt7oUtT"&gt;https://t.co/MQdTt7oUtT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/FGvgZVzMhZ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/FGvgZVzMhZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Anime Expo (@AnimeExpo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AnimeExpo/status/1367203282872004609?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Dm3wlC"&gt;E3 has not technically confirmed that their events won’t be happening in-person yet, but the city would know. An ESA spokesperson would only reaffirm that they’re “transforming” E3, and that “we’ll have official details very soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6LUkeF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 3rd, 3:17PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anime Expo has now confirmed its in-person event has been canceled, for the second year in a row. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307929/sdcc-e3-anime-expo-cancel-in-person-virtual-events"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307929/sdcc-e3-anime-expo-cancel-in-person-virtual-events</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T14:15:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T14:15:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Arizona advances bill forcing Apple and Google to allow Fortnite-style alternative payment options</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TWEgfW8HMIiY9WkmROupVEYvJps=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68905040/bfarsace_201106_4269_001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4YCz23"&gt;The Arizona House of Representatives just passed landmark app store legislation in a 31-29 vote on Wednesday that could have far-reaching consequences for Apple and Google and their respective mobile operating systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kwGZtT"&gt;The legislation, a &lt;a href="https://www.azleg.gov/legtext/55leg/1R/proposed/H.2005COBB.pdf"&gt;sweeping amendment to Arizona’s existing HB2005&lt;/a&gt;, prevents app store operators from forcing a developer based in the state to use a preferred payment system, putting up a significant roadblock to Apple and Google’s ability to collect commissions on in-app purchases and app sales. It will now head to the state senate, where it must pass before its sent to Arizona Gov. Doug Ducey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wDD94Y"&gt;The amendment specifically prohibits stores exceeding 1 million downloads from requiring “a developer that is domiciled in this state to use a particular in-application payments system as the exclusive mode of accretive payments from a user.” It also covers users living in Arizona from having to pay for apps using exclusive payment systems, though it’s not immediately clear if that means developers outside Arizona can avoid paying commission to Apple and Google when they sell something to a state resident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IPkq8S"&gt;The bill specifically exempts game consoles “and other special-purpose devices that are connected to the internet,” and it also bars companies like Apple and Google from retaliating against developers who choose to use third-party payment systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yZst2P"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The bill opens the door to alternative payment systems on iOS&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Bo2fXl"&gt;The amendment narrowly passed the Arizona House Appropriations Committee last week in a 7-6 vote, which sent it to the floor of the state’s House of Representatives for a full vote on Wednesday. Notable opponents of the bill have been Arizona Democrats, who’ve argued that state legislatures shouldn’t get involved in ongoing legal matters between companies, in reference to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367923/fortnite-apple-app-store-epic-games-need-to-know"&gt;ongoing antitrust lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; between Apple and Google and companies like &lt;em&gt;Forntite &lt;/em&gt;maker Epic Games. There was also concern the bill would interfere with interstate commerce and raise unconstitutionality claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQuEBI"&gt;The bill opens the door to developers using third-party payment systems, thereby allowing them to bypass the industry standard 30 percent cut Apple and Google have collected for years. It’s not clear how the tech companies will respond, as the bill could have significant effects on their businesses in the state of Arizona while also putting pressure on them to change the rules for all developers everywhere. Both Apple and Google declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e6jqkl"&gt;“Today, Arizona put a marker down and became the first state in the nation to advance a digital market that is free and fair,” said the Coalition for App Fairness (CAF), the industry group composed of Epic, Tinder parent company company Match Group, and Spotify that is responsible for helping draft the bill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ySd8Ae"&gt;“The Coalition for App Fairness is pleased to see the House passage of HB 2005, which will encourage business innovation in Arizona and protect consumer choice. While this is cause for celebration, it is only a first step toward achieving a truly level playing field for all,” the statement goes on to say. “We look forward to working with the Arizona State Senate to move a solution forward that builds on this momentum to provide consumer freedom, lower costs, and increase developers’ ability to thrive and innovate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oco2KR"&gt;The bill has attracted intense lobbying from Apple and Google. According to a &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/Policy/apple-google-lobbyists-arizona-bill"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;Protocol &lt;/em&gt;published earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, Apple tapped lobbyist Rod Diridon and also hired Kirk Adams, the former chief of staff to Arizona’s governor, to help make its case to the House of Representatives. Apple also joined the Arizona Chamber of Commerce and pushed the body to begin combating the bill, &lt;em&gt;Protocol &lt;/em&gt;reported. “We went through a very difficult weekend where Apple and Google hired probably almost every lobbyist in town,” Arizona State Rep. Regina Cobb, a Republican and the primary sponsor of the bill, told&lt;em&gt; Protocol&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ULD3Hv"&gt;In testimony in front of the House, Apple’s chief compliance officer, Kyle Andeer, made the case that the App Store provides value to developers that warrant its commission. “The commission has been described by some special interests as a ‘payment processing fee’—as if Apple is just swiping a credit card. That’s terribly misleading. Apple provides developers an enormous amount of value — both the store to distribute their apps around the world and the studio to create them. That is what the commission reflects,” Andeer said in written testimony. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sd59ZZ"&gt;“Yet this bill tells Apple that it cannot use its own check-out lane (and collect a commission) in the store we built,” he goes on. “This would allow billion-dollar developers to take all of the App Store’s value for free — even if they’re selling digital goods, even if they’re making millions or even billions of dollars doing it. The bill is a government mandate that Apple give away the App Store.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZcWRtn"&gt;“Apple and Google have a monopoly on how you download apps to your phone. Because of that, for any app that offers digital services like games or music, you have to pay through Apple or Google’s monopolistic payment processing system,” Cobb wrote in an &lt;a href="https://azcapitoltimes.com/news/2021/02/19/its-time-to-free-ourselves-from-big-tech-monopoly/"&gt;op-ed for the &lt;em&gt;Arizona Capitol Times&lt;/em&gt; last month&lt;/a&gt;. “You have to use their system and their payment processor, and then they tax you for it. Small app developers have to absorb the cost and struggle to survive or pass the tax onto their consumers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="4X4AfZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple and Google have a monopoly on how you download apps to your phone.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kxcyR5"&gt;The sentiment is one shared by vocal critics of Apple and Google, like Basecamp co-founder David Heinemeier Hansson. He has submitted testimony for two bills — this one in Arizona and another in North Dakota — in support of legislation to break up what he sees as monopolies on software distribution, and he’s waged an impassioned campaign against Apple in particular since last summer, when the iPhone maker &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21298552/apple-hey-email-app-approval-rules-basecamp-launch"&gt;engaged in a dispute with Basecamp&lt;/a&gt; over its new Hey email application. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4XrU4T"&gt;“Apple operates a tollbooth on the only road to distribution of mobile software for the dominant iPhone platform. And this doesn’t just hurt app developers, but consumers as well. When Apple tried to shake down our company for the 30% cut of revenues, they explicitly encouraged us simply to pass on the cost to consumers. And that’s exactly what other developers have done,” Hansson wrote in testimony to the Arizona House Appropriations Committee last week. He added that the bill “would not only provide immediate relief to Arizona developers and consumers, it would instantly make the state the most desirable place on earth to start a new software company.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lvANiS"&gt;The bill is one of many — including ones in Georgia, Hawaii, and Minnesota, as well as one that already failed in the North Dakota state senate — making their way through local legislatures. The multistate push can be drawn back to a national lobbying effort from the CAF. The industry group consists of not only Epic, Match, and Spotify, but also dozens of other companies dissatisfied with the rules imposed by Apple’s App Store and the Google Play Store. Epic is also engaged in an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367923/fortnite-apple-app-store-epic-games-need-to-know"&gt;ongoing antitrust lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against both Apple and Google over the removal of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;last summer, a dispute that sits at the heart of the ongoing app store debate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3CIISd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The bills are part of a multistate lobbying effort from the Coalition for App Fairness&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OBPaKu"&gt;The CAF, which worked alongside Match to approach Cobb for HB2005, has been hiring lobbyists around the country to approach representatives with draft bills that would make it easier for developers to bypass rules thought to be ironclad within the mobile app world. Specifically for Apple, these bills are targeting rules dictating that iOS users and the platform’s developers only buy, sell, and distribute software through the App Store. (Google allows alternative app stores on Android, though it does present security warnings and other obstacles to users who download and use them.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNk0wf"&gt;Additionally, these bills are taking aim at rules saying app makers must use the preferred payment systems of Apple and Google, as kind of backup defense in the event alternative app stores remain off the table. It’s those terms, written into developer agreements the companies make app makers sign to distribute software through the stores, that allow both companies to take anywhere from 15 to 30 percent of all revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ir14ht"&gt;The Arizona bill follows a similar, though broader and potentially more disruptive bill in North Dakota that last month &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286234/apple-app-store-north-dakota-bill-sb-2333-failed-vote"&gt;failed to pass the state’s senate&lt;/a&gt;. The North Dakota bill would have forced Apple and Google to allow alternative app stores onto iOS and Android, in addition to allowing developers to use alternative payment systems. The North Dakota bill, which failed in an 11-36 vote, would have also barred companies from retaliating against developers that opted to use alternative app stores or payment systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sj1Erq"&gt;Apple similarly lobbied hard against the North Dakota bill, with Apple’s chief privacy engineer, Erik Neuenschwander, testifying that the bill “threatens to destroy iPhone as you know it.” He further argued that it would “undermine the privacy, security, safety, and performance that’s built into iPhone by design,” &lt;a href="https://bismarcktribune.com/news/local/govt-and-politics/north-dakota-senate-bill-targets-monopolistic-app-stores/article_dc491c88-97e0-54cd-beb2-5a26044cb97c.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bismarck Tribune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “Simply put, we work hard to keep bad apps out of the App Store; (the bill) could require us to let them in.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kdVDxR"&gt;Central to all of these bills and the fierce lobbying efforts surrounding them from both sides is a debate threatening one of the most lucrative pillars of Apple’s (and to a lesser extent Google’s) business: Should app store owners be able to set the rules for what kind of software is allowed onto mobile phones, and should those rules also force developers into paying commissions for accessing the platform? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hBdiGX"&gt;Just a few years ago, that Apple and other companies would take 30 percent of all revenue was considered a settled matter. While some companies, like Netflix and Spotify, complained vigorously about unfair treatment, Apple’s iron grip on the App Store, and by extension the iPhone, felt inexorable. It was simply how mobile app distribution worked — unless you were a large company like Amazon, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21348108/apple-amazon-prime-video-app-store-special-treatment-fee-subscriptions"&gt;cut special deals with Apple&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="w8Xx9F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple already has an incredible advantage over any company that dares compete with them.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WCuqfA"&gt;But growing resentment from developers large and small, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301453/antitrust-facebook-google-amazon-apple-reform-cicilline-buck"&gt;an upswell in regulatory fervor in Washington&lt;/a&gt;, and growing consumer hostility toward Big Tech have created an unprecedented movement hoping to rein in Silicon Valley’s most powerful corporations. Square in the sights of all these parties is the App Store — specifically the 30 percent cut, or “Apple tax” as it has come to be known, and the payment system requirements that help enforce it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iUSoVB"&gt;Apple has already made some concessions in its relationship to developers in response to rising antitrust pressure. Most prominently, the company announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21572302/apple-app-store-small-business-program-commission-cut-15-percent-reduction"&gt;new small business program late last year&lt;/a&gt; allowing developers making less than $1 million in annual revenue to lower the App Store cut they pay to Apple from 30 percent to 15 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLbUvg"&gt;But those concessions are far from stopping Apple’s critics, nor the lobbying efforts of its most committed opponents, from pushing for more. “Apple already has an incredible advantage over any company that dares compete with them, and soon that might well be most of the economy,” Hansson wrote in the conclusion of his HB2005 testimony. “Giving us at least a fighting chance by enforcing a choice in payment processing is the right thing to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f6B1z3"&gt;Following the bill’s passing, Hansson said his company Basecamp was fully prepared to relocate to Arizona to take advantage of the perks. “This means everything,” he wrote on Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Wljdkv"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We are going to prepare app updates for both Android and iOS that give Arizonans the right to signup for service using our normal payment processing setup. Then start the conversation with lawyers on what it’ll take to relocate Basecamp to Arizona. This means everything.&lt;/p&gt;— DHH (@dhh) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dhh/status/1367197326041903106?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wKT1ur"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 2nd, 2:44PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added additional comment from David Heinemeier Hansson regarding his company’s response to the successful HB2005 vote. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mQddZP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 2nd, 3PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Noted that Apple declined to comment. Included public testimony from Apple’s chief compliance officer Kyle Andeer. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WHJO9y"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 2nd, 3:31PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Noted that Google declined to comment. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22309284/arizona-app-store-bill-2005-apple-30-percent-cut-bypass-legislation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22309284/arizona-app-store-bill-2005-apple-30-percent-cut-bypass-legislation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T14:14:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T14:14:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ford delays thousands of Mustang Mach-E SUV deliveries</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SCAcK4FoUDdqkwEuuNa_lixIzmM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68905028/sokane_210125_4386_1985.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RW1lNv"&gt;Ford has finally shed some light on the scale of the delays it’s experiencing in rolling out its first mass-market electric car, the Mustang Mach-E SUV. After the company announced on Wednesday that it shipped 3,739 Mustang Mach-Es in February — the first full month of deliveries — it told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in a statement that some 4,500 customers will have to wait longer than expected to receive the electric SUV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XbdWpw"&gt;The automaker didn’t say specifically what’s causing the delay, just that it’s holding back the electric Mustangs “as part of our commitment to deliver a quality vehicle to customers.” Ford previously said in January &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/16/22234668/ford-delays-deliveries-mustang-mach-e-quality-checks"&gt;it was delaying the delivery of “several hundred” of them for quality checks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5eptiC"&gt;To help make up for the delay, Ford is giving affected customers an extra 250kWh of free charging at stations that are in the company’s FordPass Charging Network. (Buyers of the Mustang Mach-E were already getting 250kWh free as a promotion.) Ford also says it “will cover the first month’s payment” — up to $1,000 — “for approximately 250 customers experiencing extended delays receiving their Mustang Mach-E.” News of these accommodations &lt;a href="https://www.macheclub.com/threads/ford-is-giving-1000-off-mach-es-250-kwh-free-charging-to-customers-with-delivery-delays.2461/"&gt;first bubbled up in a Mach-E forum on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nRzJzH"&gt;Ford’s not alone in experiencing trouble with the launch of an EV. Earlier this week, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; first reported that Volvo &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307866/volvo-xc40-recharge-delay-software-update-on-call-ota"&gt;is holding a number of XC40 Recharge SUVs at US ports&lt;/a&gt; in order to ship a software update before the electric vehicles get to customers. Volkswagen also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/11/21288572/volkswagen-id3-ev-delay-software-vw-herbert-diess"&gt;ran into trouble during the launch of its ID 3 mass-market EV last year&lt;/a&gt; because of a software issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nVFxm4"&gt;Ford also had &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-10-21/ford-botches-explorer-launch-putting-ceo-back-on-the-hot-seat"&gt;trouble rolling out a new version of the Explorer in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, which led to a &lt;a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/business/autos/2020/02/07/botched-launch-of-explorer-leads-to-shakeup-at-ford/"&gt;shakeup&lt;/a&gt; in the company’s executive ranks that was a precursor to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/4/21353950/ford-ceo-jim-hackett-retiring-replaced-restructuring"&gt;Jim Farley replacing Jim Hackett as CEO&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311594/ford-mustang-mach-e-delays-quality-free-charging-cash-back"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311594/ford-mustang-mach-e-delays-quality-free-charging-cash-back</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T13:29:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T13:29:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>New COVID-19 reporting tool is another patch for the US’s rickety health data system</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Coronavirus testing in Wisconsin" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q8VFRSDabwG-quFwambWW-UzBIg=/0x157:2400x1757/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68904643/1283618423.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Antigen tests run at a university in Wisconsin | Photo by David Joles/Star Tribune via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;But the CDC system doesn’t fix the foundational issue &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="0UceMV"&gt;It was taking staff all day to wrangle rapid test results at assisted living facilities like Via Elegante in Tucson, Arizona. The facility doesn’t normally run medical tests, but this year, it turned into a makeshift lab. Starting in August, staffers were doing hundreds of COVID-19 tests a week in the hopes of preventing a catastrophic outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l3P2Cg"&gt;The tests they use are fast; they only take about 15 minutes to report if someone is positive or negative for the coronavirus. But counting the results and reporting them to the state and local health departments was a long, arduous process each day, says Zach Briefer, the chief financial officer for the facilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cyMqN5"&gt;COVID-19 is a reportable disease, so public health officials have to be told about every new case. But Via Elegante and other places like it aren’t directly connected to the public health system. Instead, for months, they had to use makeshift systems: Google Forms, faxes, manual spreadsheets, the mail. “We had to put in everyone’s info, one at a time,” Briefer says. “At the height, we were doing around 400 tests a week.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="oPByjA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“At the height, we were doing around 400 tests a week.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QnTcdi"&gt;Eager for a way to make that process easier, Via Elegante signed on as the first pilot site for a new rapid test reporting system built by the United States Digital Service (USDS) and Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). The tool, called SimpleReport, was designed to streamline the flow of data between nontraditional testing sites and public health officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aYfOsb"&gt;“Currently, in our state, they’d have to input every single test result into a Google Form,” says Kat Davis, a member of the COVID-19 Response Team at Arizona’s Pima County Health Department. “It took all their time. For them, this is a huge time saver — they just hit submit and the reporting is complete.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B59SIb"&gt;SimpleReport is being used at around 100 sites, and the team behind the program hopes to continue to scale it up around the country over the next few months. It fills a gap, but it’s more of a bandage than a long-term fix. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O2Vm5S"&gt;The time-consuming reporting delays that SimpleReport was designed to solve are a symptom of a more fundamental problem. There are &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/09/24/how-fix-public-health-weaknesses-before-next-pandemic-hits/"&gt;huge holes&lt;/a&gt; in the US public health infrastructure. The rickety, outdated systems were &lt;a href="https://www.hcinnovationgroup.com/policy-value-based-care/public-health/article/21147049/pandemic-reveals-public-health-data-infrastructure-shortcomings"&gt;unprepared&lt;/a&gt; to share and analyze data during an emergency, and those inadequacies are one reason the COVID-19 pandemic was so devastating in the United States. They’re not beyond repair, but it’s a hard task in the middle of an emergency. Many of the solutions spun up during the pandemic have failed: a program built to streamline the COVID-19 vaccine rollout was &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/01/30/1017086/cdc-44-million-vaccine-data-vams-problems/"&gt;abandoned&lt;/a&gt; by many states after it proved chaotic and overly complicated. A new hospital data system was &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/07/31/897429054/covid-19-hospital-data-system-that-bypasses-cdc-plagued-by-delays-inaccuracies"&gt;error-ridden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="cUeph3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are huge holes in the US public health infrastructure&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GYP3iM"&gt;“It’s like building an airplane while you’re flying it, so it doesn’t surprise me that there have been a lot of whiffs here,” says Jeff Engel, senior adviser for COVID-19 with the Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dWniC6"&gt;SimpleReport is still new, and early users say it’s much better than the systems they were using before. But experts caution that even if it succeeds in its goal of linking nontraditional testing sites to health departments for COVID-19 testing, there’s still a lot of work to be done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CvllTQ"&gt;“This is an area where I don’t think we’re anywhere near mission accomplished,” says Julia Adler-Milstein, a health IT expert and researcher at the University of California, San Francisco. “The fear is that you find an easy workaround, and then you lose motivation to keep trying to improve. I hope that, even if this works, it won’t be the final end state.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A billboard advertises a rapid COVID-19 test site. Florida..." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rmTkfTllEajlZZQJyReB8_hJe7Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342748/1230021804.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Paul Hennessy / SOPA Images / LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="lsiLsY"&gt;
&lt;p id="xvibQK"&gt;Rapid COVID-19 testing is a key tool in reducing the spread of disease, especially in settings like long-term care facilities where people have to be tested regularly. Most rapid COVID-19 tests used in the United States today are antigen tests. The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) authorized the first of these tests &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/9/21253105/fda-covid-19-antigen-test-coronavirus"&gt;in May&lt;/a&gt;, and they started to become more widely used through the late summer and fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JaY75j"&gt;They’re appealing because they’re fast, cheap, and show results on the spot without having to be sent to a lab. Instead of looking for bits of the coronavirus’s genetic material, they look for the tiny proteins on the surface of the virus. They can be less accurate than gene-based tests, but they also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21420195/covid-19-test-infectious-viral-load-antigen-pcr"&gt;may be&lt;/a&gt; more likely to catch cases of COVID-19 when someone has a high level of virus floating around in their nose and throat (which is when they’re likely the most contagious). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8lLl4Y"&gt;There are lots of different kinds of tests on the market, including disposable cards and computer-sized machines, both of which can analyze samples on the spot. The result appears on the card or is displayed on the machine, usually in around 15 minutes. They’re easy for places like long-term care facilities to set up and use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="icueEq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GWavsN"&gt;Because they’re done outside of typical lab environments, it’s harder for state and federal health authorities to collect data from these tests. Commercial laboratories and state health labs have a direct line to health agencies and can easily pass along COVID-19 test results. Places like long-term care facilities, schools, and pop-ups in parking lots can’t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8yaUrn"&gt;The limited digital connections many places where people get health care (like long-term care facilities) have with hospitals and health departments is a constant challenge, even outside of a pandemic. Health records don’t seamlessly follow patients from place to place, leaving facilities to sort out medications and advice from multiple doctors for a single patient. When connections &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; put in place, patients are &lt;a href="https://www.leadingage.org/cast/case-studies/cast-case-study-healthmedx"&gt;less likely to cycle in and out&lt;/a&gt; of hospitals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="KGRfJE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Inefficiencies can be deadly&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="N8rlFx"&gt;During an emergency like COVID-19, those inefficiencies can be deadly. Without a clear path from long-term care facilities to health departments, it can take days for officials to get word of positive tests. That can delay contact tracing — and make it harder to stamp out an outbreak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aHDD64"&gt;Transmitting test results was anything but straightforward for facilities with limited experience communicating with health departments. “Reporting the results to the local health department or the state health department was a complete mystery to these sites,” says Engel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GbbuDZ"&gt;That created data gaps: in September, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21439951/covid-19-antigen-tests-states-not-reporting-results"&gt;half of states&lt;/a&gt; said their antigen test results were probably underreported. The problem persisted &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/virus-outbreak-us-news-public-health-86cb213b701c8c1e03f98083058369a4"&gt;through the fall&lt;/a&gt;. Like Via Elegante, many assisted living facilities were using makeshift online forms or sending off physical copies of test results to their local health departments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfWFg1"&gt;“We saw a lot of duplicate entries, with people handwriting the same thing on two different forms; we saw people faxing a lot of information,” Amy Gleason, an expert with the USDS who worked on SimpleReport, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E25ici"&gt;Those problems came to light last spring and summer, as the USDS spent time visiting health departments and hospitals in a handful of states to figure out what their biggest challenges were during the pandemic. By early fall, they recommended that the CDC should focus on creating a streamlined way for nontraditional testing sites to manage rapid testing and report results. SimpleReport came out of that process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DYB15JtGYxYcc1wERPV_YXrfWoE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342680/SimpleReport_View.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: USDS&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A mock SimpleReport window.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OVrLYF"&gt;The program lets staffers at a testing site pull up a digital card with places for a patient’s name, symptom survey, the date of their last test, and test timer. A facility can process multiple tests at once and has the option to change the test date. Both of those features came out of conversations with long-term care facilities about their workflows, says USDS’s Alicia Beckett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hSgEGY"&gt;“Our first version of the prototype only let you look at and manage one test at a time,” she says. They also adjusted the system to sync the in-progress tests between devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wqZvvb"&gt;Before starting with SimpleReport, Via Elegante staffers had to report COVID-19 test results in three different places: a Google Form for the state, an Excel list for the county, and internally for the facility’s own records. When they started using the program in early December, they were able to cut out those redundancies. They phased out internal records and the county list quickly, Briefer says. The Arizona Department of Health Services asked for a more extensive validation process before it felt comfortable that the data from the new workflow matched the data coming in through the Google Form. But eventually, Via Elegante was able to drop the Google Form as well. The Arizona Department of Health Services did not respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hYFBf"&gt;Having a single reporting system has slashed the administrative work from around three minutes to seconds per test, Briefer says. For hundreds of tests a week, that adds up. “That has really allowed us to do our real jobs,” he says. “It’s a lot easier and everyone is a lot less stressed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="SyfBaW"&gt;
&lt;p id="5lk26O"&gt;SimpleReport’s 100 sites are spread across eight states. The team is in discussions with a handful of other states as well. In Florida, they’re working with mobile testing sites and urgent cares; in a few other places, they’re talking with colleges and universities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AhrnAh"&gt;The program will get up and running more quickly going forward, now that the USDS team has gone through the initial pilot phase. Other states aren’t asking for the same extensive data validation as the Arizona Department of Health Services. USDS is building onboarding videos and support programs for new sites. “We can’t have the same high-touch, hands-on process we did with the first site for the 100th site,” Beckett says. “But we’re working on making sure that it’s as easy as possible for folks to do themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="People collect swab samples from their mouths at a walk-up..." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P-hEAFFgFAT4xcAb8If6Im9a9p0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342705/1229965852.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Paul Hennessy / SOPA Images / LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A mobile testing site in Florida.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NMgPJA"&gt;Engel, the adviser with the Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists, says he’ll be watching closely as the program starts to scale. “We offered our help, because the projects they were doing were helpful, but we were concerned that they wouldn’t be sustainable, or scalable,” he told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We’re still trying to work that out.” He doesn’t want to see a situation with a handful of one-off tech solutions that fade off without maintenance, and he says he’s concerned that sites will struggle to implement SimpleReport without the hands-on support of the pilot sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lki5Rh"&gt;Right now, USDS has a user guide and email address for questions, Beckett says. Eventually, it’ll route questions through a general Department of Health and Human Services help desk. The CDC is funding SimpleReport’s development, and it’s assumed responsibility for the program’s long-term sustainability. It’s also an open-source program, she says. “If anybody else wanted to maintain it and add to it, they could.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="CjEzM1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Many places testing, treating, or vaccinating patients aren’t well-connected to the public health infrastructure&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tQ2tG1"&gt;Even if SimpleReport does prove to be a good solution for test reporting, it doesn’t solve the underlying issue: many places testing, treating, or vaccinating patients aren’t well-connected to the public health infrastructure. If they were, facilities like Via Elegante wouldn’t need a new pandemic-specific tool. They would have a direct pipeline to health departments already. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FWCeTc"&gt;Instead, during an emergency like the COVID-19 pandemic, groups like USDS come in and develop makeshift solutions. “We keep developing these stovepipe systems that are doomed to failure,” Engel says. “Our data systems are in bad need of upgrading.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="maNxI7"&gt;Something like SimpleReport is a reasonable place to start, says health IT expert Adler-Milstein. There’s so much to do, and taking the problem one case at a time makes sense — it just can’t be the place to stop. Connecting long-term care facilities with the rest of the system would make it more efficient to care for patients and build a stronger foundation for future emergencies when fast communication saves lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="DsvGRU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’m pretty confident that there will be improvements.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z6tcNf"&gt;Adler-Milstein says she’s hopeful the pandemic highlighted the need for better connectivity, and that next time, our systems will be more prepared. “How much we’ll advance remains to be seen — but will we have advanced? I’m pretty confident that there will be improvements,” she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6i48Kf"&gt;Even as that momentum ticks forward, places like long-term care facilities will still need ways to report test results to health departments. The emergency phase of the COVID-19 pandemic will likely fade out over the summer, and millions of people are getting vaccinated each week. But the virus isn’t going away completely and could still be a threat to the most vulnerable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="zV2faG"&gt;Briefer says Via Elegante will be running regular COVID-19 tests — and using SimpleReport — for at least another year. Most residents and around half of the staff have had their first doses of the COVID-19 vaccine, but testing programs will stay in place. “From where we stand, we aren’t changing anything,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fG8FaI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22311478/rapid-covid-test-data-cdc-nursing-home-usds-arizona"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22311478/rapid-covid-test-data-cdc-nursing-home-usds-arizona</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
