<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-31T12:00:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T12:00:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T12:00:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Chrome beta makes it easy to jump between search results</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8AW3Xtmz5gFQcv6yAf_mWZzQ6r8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69798640/acastro_180416_1777_chrome_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RQSUgF"&gt;Google is announcing some new experiments available in the latest Chrome beta intended to make it easier to find things on the web and share interesting text. If you want to jump onto the Chrome beta to give these features a shot, download it &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/beta/"&gt;here for your computer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.chrome.beta&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US"&gt;here for your Android device&lt;/a&gt;. (Though as with all betas, exercise caution, as things may not work perfectly.) And I’m going to mention enabling flags throughout — to do so, enter chrome://flags into your address bar, which is where you can turn on Chrome’s many available experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IvMeuR"&gt;One cool new experiment in Chrome on Android lets you see some search results under the address bar after you’ve already navigated to a page. This one is best understood by watching this GIF:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZvdG2yinEVOZWYpi20vYaHNE5Ns=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22817208/Continuous_Search_Mobile.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OGsYZT"&gt;Although you can’t see full URLs in this additional bar, it seems like it could be a useful way to jump to another site without having having to go back to the full search results. You can try this experiment by turning on the #continuous-search flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LdEuDn"&gt;Another feature in testing lets you make a stylized image of text on websites, which could be useful to spruce up text you want to share with your friends or on social media. (The feature also seems ripe for some ridiculous memes.) This one is available on Android phones and tablets if you flip on the #webnotes-stylize. You can get an idea of how it works in the GIF below:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y_W5rEfjgqJDKIHNiup5daJoni8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22817224/Webnotes_Mobile.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fYuWU6"&gt;Another new feature adds cards to the New Tab page that makes it easier to jump back to sites you visited previously. In a blog post, Google gives examples of cards for recipe pages, a shopping cart, or documents on Google Drive. If you want to try this out, enable the #ntp-modules flag on a computer. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dCAv4W2M0DBQrw4lNnGRNzQiuy8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22817222/Docs_Module_Desktop.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what a card pointing you to previously visited Google Workspace documents looks like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rQpSvW"&gt;Because these are experiments, there’s always the chance that they don’t have all of the bugs ironed out just yet, and Google may decide not to move them past the experiment phase. But they could be previews of features to come, and if you want to try them early, check them out in the Chrome beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PVE5iD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650300/google-chrome-beta-experiments-android-desktop-new-tab-page-text-search"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650300/google-chrome-beta-experiments-android-desktop-new-tab-page-text-search</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Moment’s new video-coloring app Grain will let you take handcrafted presets to other apps </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gkFzLvUouOGyEtDhngfRZIvvxZc=/326x0:3770x2296/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69798634/grain_press_color_2.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Moment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VScVpG"&gt;Moment &lt;a href="https://apps.shopmoment.com/grain"&gt;is launching another video-focused app&lt;/a&gt; for iPhone and iPad Tuesday that lets you edit and color footage as well as create video presets or “looks” for use on social media or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21147761/moment-rtro-video-app-retro-filters-stories-ios-iphone"&gt;Moment’s other video app, Rtro&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LJ9Q30"&gt;The app is called Grain, and based on my experience with it in beta form, it seems to offer a lot of video settings to get lost in. Grain breaks its editing options into three categories: color, effects, and overlays. Color has a variety of preset filters to start with, like LoFi, 35mm, or Blockbuster, which you can then further customize with adjustments to color temperature, brightness, or saturation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IY0oSC"&gt;Effects and overlay presets work similarly. You can add film grain, light bleeds, blurs, VHS effects, faux film stocks and fine-tune them with granular controls. Grain also offers gestures to add or remove filters, but I quickly forgot they were an option.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f5_vQw8PzbC4WV8cyO8t4-YbNu8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22808038/Grain_App_WebRes399.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Moment&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grain offers granular control over individual effects, including more professional-grade tools like color wheels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tQy84I"&gt;As someone who is at best an amateur videographer, the amount of control you can have over an individual video clip can be daunting. Luckily, Grain is designed for as much or as little experimentation as you want. You can produce something interesting just by selecting a color filter and a video effect without diving into menus for fine-tuning. (Though you could arguably just as easily do too much that way.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cFlcCyTWnffTwqAogCsm4AIdDGI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22808040/Image__2_.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshots of my own disastrous attempt at coloring a clip of my dog.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="k2sRtL"&gt;Video presets you create can be saved for later use or exported as a LUT (Lookup Table) for use in professional desktop software like Adobe Premiere Pro. Grain can also send your presets to Moment’s other video app, Rtro, if you prefer your modified presets to the filters Moment sells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yYi2xo"&gt;The catch with Grain is that to get all of the features, you have to be willing to pay. Grain charges $4.99 per month, $29.99 per year, or a one-time payment of $69.99 to unlock advanced color editing tools, unlimited video length, and the ability to export LUTs and overlays. Otherwise, you’re stuck with the basics, and the novel ability to send filters to Rtro. Moment also plans to bundle subscriptions to Grain and Rtro for $6.99 per month or $39.99 per year if you like both apps enough to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zfv2R5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Moment made a retro video app for iPhones ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21147761/moment-rtro-video-app-retro-filters-stories-ios-iphone"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XCDZTR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22643623/grain-video-coloring-app-moment-luts-presets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22643623/grain-video-coloring-app-moment-luts-presets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Strava’s live location tracking service is now free</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dQbVGs98V8dAotbqstyyQ6_y5hU=/0x99:1280x952/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69798593/run_640px.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Athletes can now share their live location using the free version of the Strava app.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Strava&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fRj258"&gt;Today Strava is making Beacon, its live location-sharing service for athletes, available to everyone, whether you pay for the popular cycle and run-tracking app or not. Beacon sharing from the Strava app was previously only available via subscription, which currently costs $59.99 annually or $5.00 per month. The change follows a massive privacy push by Strava introduced earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IkmaZ0"&gt;Beacon sharing can be used for safety and fun. The feature lets you share your live location with up to three people who can track your progress until you finish. They receive a text message with a unique URL that opens in a mobile browser to show your activity in real time (updated every 15 seconds). This can be a life-saving feature for bikers or runners who find themselves in trouble on a secluded road or trail (safety!) while enabling some serendipitous rendezvousing for any friends who might want to you join you mid-course (fun!). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xfULgosf9GsT_mYkGTI7hdrAJTM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22816682/qksbOPqa.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Strava&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of a shared Beacon in Strava app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3G1Crz"&gt;There is one caveat. Strava says that Beacon sharing from connected devices like the Apple Watch and Garmin bike computers will remain a paid feature due to the complexity of supporting such integrations. Only Beacon sharing from the Strava app on your phone is free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="F3lFxc"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dDqHmeePBEY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eWPvZ3"&gt;The free Beacon service follows a major overhaul of Strava’s user privacy options a few weeks ago. These include new “privacy zone” features that give users more control over the accuracy and visibility of their GPS tracking maps beyond just their home, and activity-related features to hide data like heart rate and pace on a per-user basis. &lt;a href="https://www.dcrainmaker.com/2021/08/strava-new-privacy-zone-features-options.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;DC Rainmaker&lt;/em&gt; breaks it all down&lt;/a&gt; in the video above for anyone interested in the details.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649880/strava-beacon-live-location-tracking-map-data-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649880/strava-beacon-live-location-tracking-map-data-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T11:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Late nights, high scores, and blanket forts: the challenges of testing music and fitness games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nQaYRfkXComlAfU3sbcMfwbTJTA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69798415/akrales_191008_3706_0141.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;For games like Just Dance and EA Sports Active, QA is a tricky process&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="WKF7ND"&gt;“I hopped into the lounge, with myself, and was baffled to see that this dumb idea actually worked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lytqWE"&gt;One day during the testing of &lt;em&gt;Dance Central VR&lt;/em&gt; in the Harmonix office, Robbie Russell was struggling with a very particular problem. They were running a multiplayer check of a social hub feature where up to four players can hang out in a private visual space and take part in dances, play mini-games, or just chat. But everyone else in quality assurance (QA) was busy at the time. So Russell came up with a workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WBeya0"&gt;“You can’t just log someone in and then take the headset off because eventually it’ll time out,” they say. “So me, in my infinite dumbassery, put two headsets on, one Oculus Quest and one Oculus Rift, and strapped two sets of controllers to my wrist. The Rift controllers had holes big enough that I could slip my hands through them and wear them like very stupid bracelets while the Quest controllers fit in my hand normally. That became my go-to way to check multiplayer stuff for the rest of the project.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tfO9gy"&gt;Finding ways to cheat video game features and mechanics is not uncommon in QA. Testers are expected to dive into each corner of the experience in a thorough manner, often multiple times, to ensure that everything is working as intended. DIY solutions and shortcuts are bound to happen to optimize time. When it comes to QA testing for music and fitness games, however, these hacks aren’t just a way to save time — they’re a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TI5VrM"&gt;The physical component of these genres, all the way from &lt;em&gt;Dance Dance Revolution&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20917908/nintendo-switch-ring-fit-adventure-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has always made them unique. Breaking a sweat with a drum kit in &lt;em&gt;Rock Band&lt;/em&gt; or strapping a Joy-Con around your leg to go for a jog in Nintendo’s fitness RPG are not experiences you find in most games. But while players can pause or take breaks at any time, testers have to juggle these activities on a 9-5 routine. All of a sudden, the prospect of doing hundreds of jumping jacks or dancing to “What Does The Fox Say” a dozen times per day isn’t as enticing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The singer Usher performs as he introduc" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/01B4rnnRAHN1VwnSmUAwnxcxUMA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22814813/145716442.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Robyn Beck / AFP / GettyImages&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usher during the reveal of Dance Central 3 in 2012.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Wk55ET"&gt;The development of &lt;em&gt;EA Sports Active 2&lt;/em&gt; is a prime example of this complexity and differences from traditional testing. The first in the series was released as a Wii exclusive in May 2009, offering body workouts that required wearing a strappable pouch to hold the Nunchuck controller, alongside a resistance band depending on the exercise. Its sequel, released in November 2010, was multiplatform. This meant that PlayStation 3 players used Move controllers, while Xbox 360 players had the just-released Kinect scanning their full body instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HqhofS"&gt;A contract QA tester with Volt Media Consulting working at EA Vancouver at the time, who we’ll be calling Kyle upon his request for anonymity, recalls the project as a nightmare. “It was kinda like one of those Benny Hill sketches where everyone is running around,” he says over a Discord call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="arxZmx"&gt;QA was divided into three groups, one per platform, and Kyle was part of the Xbox 360 team. For both him and his co-workers, this meant learning the ins and outs of Kinect’s first iteration. There was no training manual available. Aside from the availability of an engineer (who was also learning on the fly) to verify whether certain bugs came from the game or the Kinect itself, understanding how the hardware worked came purely from trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="VG841b"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It was kinda like one of those Benny Hill sketches where everyone is running around.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3WJgI7"&gt;Due to the sensor-tracking nature of the device, the entire office floor had to be adapted. Testers taped off and fragmented the room into triangle-shaped spaces after finding out exactly where the limits of the Kinect’s sensor started and ended, marking the perfect spot — an imaginary box that doesn’t exist for anyone except the hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UqZEa0"&gt;Everyone was sharing desks to avoid moving their own all the time — as that would ruin the invisible spot — while being extra careful during walks around the office to prevent being read in somebody else’s triangle. Even jackets hanging on the walls had to be carefully placed. But the worst moments were when the device couldn’t read people at all, whether that was because they were using dark colors or wearing baggy clothes like a hoodie. Figuring out what to wear at work became part of the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EYdlk1"&gt;“The Kinect used infrared,” Kyle continues. “In the summer, when it can get over [80 degrees Fahrenheit] in Vancouver, the air conditioner ran through the entire building. If you by chance had one of the massive air vents in your triangle with cold air blowing on you, you would lose your body being read.” Since the Kinect could only read a person by their body temperature, the team had to make covers or lids to block the air conditioning vents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XIMjv5"&gt;According to interviews with eight current and former QA workers in AAA studios and outsource companies, not all offices offered the proper accommodation to cover the basic needs of this kind of testing. Elements such as showers, proper ventilation, hydration at hand, and sound-proof spaces varied greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpf4TE"&gt;An anonymous source who worked on &lt;em&gt;Just Dance&lt;/em&gt; for Ubisoft Reflections says the office was well-equipped, including showers and gym mats to dance on. There were around 10 testers on &lt;em&gt;Just Dance 4&lt;/em&gt;, with more at other Ubisoft studios due to co-development. “We had a lot of space and the way they’d set up the consoles and PCs made it easy to test and input bugs quickly,” they add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwFRZd"&gt;While working on &lt;em&gt;Xbox Fitness&lt;/em&gt; at an outsource studio, one former QA recalls the company commissioning a purpose-built gym to be constructed above a kitchen and bathroom stalls, providing ventilation and preventing noise disturbances. In addition, the team was also able to expense appropriate clothing after requesting a budget for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Milan Games Week 2019" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hunJu3eH7zrUpVypFnTHuFbd7HY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22814826/1177459865.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Emanuele Cremaschi / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="bfvpcO"&gt;The inclusion of properly equipped, separated spaces for QA that work on these types of games is crucial. Not just to keep singing or loud noises at a minimum, but also to divide such different work environments. When daily tasks demand physical activity in the way these tests do, it becomes the equivalent of putting an office and a gym under the same roof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HXf3yN"&gt;A former QA on &lt;em&gt;Rock Band 4&lt;/em&gt; and the expansion &lt;em&gt;Rock Band Rivals&lt;/em&gt;, as part of the outsourcing studio Keywords, originally worked in a noise-proof room located within the main floor. The company later had it torn down to expand the space, so QA (composed of around 16 testers) was relocated with everybody else. “I tested mainly drums and vocals which is an obvious distraction for everybody,” they mention. “Couldn’t do much about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5lNTn"&gt;At the Harmonix office, Russell (who is currently a senior QA at Proletariat working on &lt;em&gt;Spellbreak&lt;/em&gt;) adds that there was a dedicated room for drum testing in &lt;em&gt;Rock Band&lt;/em&gt;, and meeting rooms would often be booked entirely to do full-band runs when needed. But for the most part, people would “always hear somebody clacking away at a guitar or quietly humming at their desk to test vocal pitches.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="H5W4Xd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You’re gonna get sweaty eventually”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GsbgRi"&gt;There was plenty of room for QA to do their jobs safely as well as hydration available. Sadly, aside from a member-exclusive gym in the building (which was free for salaried employees), there were no office showers available. This is similar to how amenities worked in EA Vancouver. According to Kyle, there were showers and lockers available in the gym, but only full-time employees had access to it. The &lt;em&gt;EA Sports Active 2&lt;/em&gt; QA team, due to how chaotic the project was, was granted this privilege. But this wasn’t the norm for contractors. “It was kind of encouraged among the team to take breaks and not overexert yourself,” Russell explains. “But it’s rapid physical activity, you’re gonna get sweaty eventually.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wXwCcP"&gt;Caelyn Sandel, &lt;em&gt;Caves of Qud&lt;/em&gt; developer and former QA at Harmonix, recalls the encouragement for “everyone to bathe regularly” from the team leads. “I’m not saying it never got ripe, but it wasn’t a persistent issue.” That being said, Sandel recalls a specific day that stood out from the rest. “One time the HVAC system had some kind of crisis and that smelled so bad that we all evacuated and went to Flour Bakery. That was a fun day except for the horrible stink.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3WB7Wy"&gt;The lack of widely available showers isn’t unique to Harmonix or EA. During a CEDEC 2020 presentation reported by &lt;a href="https://www.famitsu.com/news/202009/04205252.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Famitsu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and translated by PushDustin on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PushDustIn/status/1301880802553155586"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, it was mentioned that the &lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt; office only had one, so the testing team would have to wait sometimes. (Nintendo declined our request for comment.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XL4l7E"&gt;The intensity of the required effort from testers, even as they all juggle far more ordinary QA tasks in between (inputting bugs, working on tickets on platforms such as JIRA, maintaining databases, and so on), can lead to a myriad of results. Not all QAs are professional drummers, dancers, or fitness trainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WPo8g4"&gt;Two of the developers recall how the constant movement and exercising helped them to get in better shape, one case being the result of the studio hiring professional dancers who had teaching experience and would lead testers through stretches and better practices. For others, the training activity during the day job was a compliment to already established exercising / health habits, while a few opted to not change theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kM3qJD"&gt;While pretty much everyone I spoke to mentioned ways in which they could get away with reducing the physical workload, it’s important to note that tests that involved completionist achievements or high difficulties would usually require traditional testing. Without the possibility of workarounds, some tests could only be done by someone who excelled at the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uwSzZ7"&gt;These logistics are part of daily planning. For a studio like Harmonix, this meant making sure there were enough working instruments for particular tests, knowing who in the office had a reliable vibrato to test out certain exploits on vocals, and, ultimately, recognizing whether there was someone who had the required level of skill to test specific bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LDMMke"&gt;Some cases could be bypassed by just playing in lower difficulties, but the full spectrum had to be tested at some point to avoid inaccurate results. Drum testing a fake plastic kit might not seem like much — yet, as Russell points out, playing it at a decent skill level “is a huge burden and often caused a lot of issues.” If the two people who were good enough at them to play on the expert difficulty weren’t in the office, then those bugs had to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKfrYf"&gt;In most cases, testers were able to take breaks throughout the day without objection from leads or management, sometimes outside of settled company breaks as well. EA, for example, offered two 15-minute breaks across mornings and evenings, on top of the lunch hour. Everyone would usually be understanding, allowing QA to trade tasks between them and, once again, encouraging them to find ways to cheat exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="r7JC4j"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ks5LRAadl7M?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="9GGYtI"&gt;Based on those I interviewed, studios and managers mostly had the right intentions in terms of setting healthy boundaries. But in practice, issues often took place. Testers who suffered any kind of injury outside of work still had to put up with physical testing, although there was a push to focus more on administrative work during the recovery periods. Scenarios like this, however, are inevitable — even in safe and accommodating environments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bdnw6C"&gt;Two particular cases stood out during interviews. An anonymous QA who worked on the Nintendo DS game &lt;em&gt;New International Track &amp;amp; Field&lt;/em&gt; says that while there weren’t any set breaks, the team didn’t need to put 100 percent effort in, except for high-end tasks or multiplayer tests. The latter would get “a bit too competitive” when the producers would ask the team to take part in a game mode that involved playing every event back to back. Producers would claim the testers wouldn’t be able to beat them, staking “free morning Starbucks on the challenge” as an incentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AcyKcA"&gt;A similar scenario took place in EA for &lt;em&gt;EA Sports Active 2&lt;/em&gt; by a POC (point of contact). Back in the day, they acted as a contact intermediary for managers or developers to get and spread work orders to employees. While our source is unsure whether this came as an order, he recalls a voluntary incentive for testers: whoever lost the most weight under a certain period of time would receive a prize. The reward was a one-month gym pass or a punch card that could be used for a gym or yoga class, one-on-one training, or even a consultation with a chiropractor, all activities that were already available for full-time employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="s4jRAT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We were up late and kind of delirious, fueling ourselves on stress and whiskey.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2tomXA"&gt;On social media, it’s common to see people joking around how QA testers who work on these games must be in excellent shape, but the reality is far more difficult to parse. Office preparations and day-to-day responsibilities play a big role, but so do each person’s capabilities and health conditions. In most cases, the aforementioned problems do nothing but strengthen or add upon the issues already in place that testers have to deal with across the video game industry as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iudOxf"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-interactives-qa-staff-allege-poor-treatment-low-pay-and-mismanaged-layoffs"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on Paradox Interactive, one tester mentions how the team “often got overlooked and it was very, very obvious that QA was lowest down on the hierarchical ladder.” During an interview with &lt;a href="https://egmnow.com/what-its-really-like-to-be-a-qa-tester/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;EGM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; a contractor who worked on &lt;em&gt;Titanfall 2&lt;/em&gt; paints a similar picture to the clear and enforced distinction between salaried employees and contractors, as the latter are often subject to lower pay and lack of benefits. In that same report, another source calls working QA for VR projects a “horrific job.” Both &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/01/05/video-game-internships/"&gt;internships and contract work&lt;/a&gt; are especially common with young developers, offering a foot in the industry in exchange for deplorable conditions. In many cases, QA is considered a stepping stone instead of receiving the same recognition as any other role in game development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UJrKuZ"&gt;Sandel considers her time at Harmonix a “weird employment experience,” as she was kept as a contractor (alongside the professional dancers hired for &lt;em&gt;Dance Central 2&lt;/em&gt;) for two years with “no benefits and low pay.” She mentions it was a different world after getting hired full-time for &lt;em&gt;Dance Central 3&lt;/em&gt;. “Harmonix’s healthcare coverage is the best in the industry by a country mile. I’m still kicking myself for only transitioning after I stopped working there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DhGv6H"&gt;For many testers, one of the things that made these challenging conditions more tolerable was the camaraderie that emerged from working with a small team on intense projects. “I have this really strong positive memory from close to the end of &lt;em&gt;Dance Central’s&lt;/em&gt; production,” Sandel says, “trying to record the filter data for individual moves over and over because the first scoring system was a mess. We were up late and kind of delirious, fueling ourselves on stress and whiskey. We crunched a lot for the first game and I definitely sort of fell for the exhilaration of it, which was helped by how personable and fun to be around the team members were. Thankfully, crunch eased up a bit on subsequent projects, but we did still crunch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JznmlH"&gt;The former Ubisoft QA recalls their time working on the &lt;em&gt;Just Dance&lt;/em&gt; series with “a massive wave of nostalgia” as they “genuinely had so much fun on that project.” They fondly remember one specific contraption called “Sweaty Betty,” which involved strapping a controller to a desk fan to test the scoring during &lt;em&gt;Just Dance 3&lt;/em&gt;’s development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Um6RQO"&gt;But the series’s tight schedule often resulted in late nights. “It’s difficult for me to critically analyze exactly why there was so much overtime on that project since I was so new to the industry at the time, but &lt;em&gt;Just Dance&lt;/em&gt; was usually featured at E3 too so there was a lot of work to get that ready for the reveal.” The source adds that at that point in time in their career, they were “extremely stoked to be in the industry, so I kind of expected it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mqik8r"&gt;According to Kyle, in order to avoid overtime, the team was split into day and night shifts. During the last few months of development, EA put budget aside to offer employees working late nights “10 to 15 dollars” toward the campus’s own restaurant for dinner. A second Volt Media contractor recalls taking part in the so-called “graveyard shifts.” During the last month or two of the project, some shifts would go from 8AM to 8PM, while the other half of the team worked 8PM to 8AM. The source did about five nights a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ExoGmIgy4P0xMGtO6h1kS9pn80=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19285520/akrales_191008_3706_0168.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="z8DE7S"&gt;While most of the stories from the developers I spoke to happened years ago, it’s worth noting that the issues surrounding QA &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/inside-rockstar-games-culture-of-crunch-1829936466"&gt;continue&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2019-06-26-stories-of-crunch-contempt-for-qa-at-treyarch"&gt;to this&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22622396/activision-blizzard-toxic-culture-qa-customer-service-report"&gt;day&lt;/a&gt;. Music and fitness games have their own particular challenges when the work conditions aren’t suitable for the physical task at hand. But at the very least, this also opens the door to inventive solutions. As absurd and anecdotal as they may sound, they’re often a lifesaver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pYEQno"&gt;During a graveyard shift, the second EA contractor recalls one time when the team was asked to test the Kinect in low-light situations. Since the project was one of the first games for the hardware, the UX was uncharted territory. This, of course, led to its own array of experimental testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="s4vqeE"&gt;“For a lot of us, around 5AM, when your last two brain cells have decided they’ve had enough, that’s when the real ingenuity kicks in,” the source concludes. “To ensure the game would pick up the user’s motions in a low-light environment, some of us ended up using a combination of cubicle walls and blankets to build tunnels that we would modify to allow more or less light in to see how the game responded. It’s the only time in my life I’ve been paid to build blanket forts.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22648429/music-fitness-games-testing-qa-just-dance-central"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22648429/music-fitness-games-testing-qa-just-dance-central</id>
    <author>
      <name>Diego Arguello</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T11:23:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T11:23:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>The makers of the GorillaPod made a MagSafe tripod mount</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Joby GripTight tripod mount" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r_NSg1BizLHuuko7dtawyAsKDP4=/1x0:3939x2625/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69798383/griptightmount.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Joby&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CF95F3"&gt;Joby has released a MagSafe mount for tripods that should simplify the process of attaching an iPhone 12 and any future iPhone models that support MagSafe. The new GripTight mount allows for quick attachment, letting the mount hold on to your phone either by just its MagSafe magnet or with a more secure option that tightly grips the edges of your phone like Joby’s previous smartphone mounts. With the latter use case, people may not know that you’re partially connected to the GripTight mount with MagSafe, but at least you’ll know it in your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p8d4i2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fjoby.com%2Fus-en%2Fgriptight-mount-for-magsafe-jb01752-bww%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F31%2F22650174%2Fjoby-gorillapod-tripod-wall-mount-magnet-magsafe" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;This new mount is available now for $23.97 from Joby’s site&lt;/a&gt;, and it works on the company’s line of flexible GorillaPod tripods as well as any other tripods that support the industry standard 1/4-20-inch thread. The clamp can rotate 360 degrees so that you can switch between portrait and landscape shooting modes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Joby GripTight wall mount" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gH_htMQ-oB-ZKGQirrfXPWbbtr0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22817056/griptightwallmount.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Joby&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="g5HH5B"&gt;Additionally, the company announced &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fjoby.com%2Fus-en%2Fgriptight-wall-mount-for-magsafe-jb01754-bww%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F31%2F22650174%2Fjoby-gorillapod-tripod-wall-mount-magnet-magsafe" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the GripTight MagSafe wall mount that costs $14.97&lt;/a&gt;. One side sticks to your iPhone 12 via the MagSafe magnet, while the other side has a sticky surface that lets it fasten to flat nonporous surfaces, like glass. Joby says you can restore its stickiness by rinsing it with water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yu9Zzj"&gt;Support for MagSafe as a means to charge phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"&gt;hasn’t really picked up in a huge way&lt;/a&gt;, but at least more accessory makers like Joby and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608012/otterbox-magsafe-compatible-gaming-clip-xbox-controller-price-iphone-12-mini-pro-max"&gt;OtterBox&lt;/a&gt; have devised ways to take advantage of the magnet within each of Apple’s latest iPhones. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650174/joby-gorillapod-tripod-wall-mount-magnet-magsafe"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650174/joby-gorillapod-tripod-wall-mount-magnet-magsafe</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>EA’s return to college football starts with a special event in Madden</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/miB78g1z6FGjBwxNJPJtd6WBhrY=/600x0:3840x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69798262/M22_CollegeSSKO_Landry_16x9_Watermarked.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jarvis Landry in an LSU uniform in &lt;/em&gt;Madden NFL 22&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: EA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1SWJrn"&gt;While we still don’t know exactly when EA’s upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262471/ea-sports-college-football-video-game-ncaa-players"&gt;college football video game will be released&lt;/a&gt;, fans will be able to play college ball soon for a limited time thanks to a special “Campus Legends” event coming to &lt;em&gt;Madden NFL 22’s&lt;/em&gt; arcade-y Superstar KO mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X6Zvcl"&gt;The event, which begins Tuesday and runs until September 27th, will let you play as one of 10 schools: Clemson University, Louisiana State University, Michigan State University, University of Florida, University of Miami, University of Nebraska, University of Oklahoma, University of Oregon (UO), University of Southern California, and University of Texas. The teams will also feature alumni as players — for example, UO graduate Justin Herbert, who is currently the quarterback of the Los Angeles Chargers, will be on UO’s roster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wyFW4y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Go Ducks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="V4JyBQ"&gt;The Campus Legends event seems like it could be a fun way to play some virtual college football while we wait for more news of EA’s full-fledged college football title, which will be will be EA’s first following the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/9/26/4774646/ea-wont-be-releasing-a-college-football-game-in-2014-after-all"&gt;cancellation of the &lt;em&gt;NCAA Football&lt;/em&gt; franchise in 2013&lt;/a&gt;. The new game will “include the rights to more than 100 institutions featuring the logos, stadiums, uniforms, gameday traditions and more that fans have come to know and love,” &lt;a href="https://news.ea.com/press-releases/press-releases-details/2021/Electronic-Arts--CLC-to-Bring-Back-College-Football-Video-Games/default.aspx"&gt;according to a press release&lt;/a&gt;, though as of right now, student-athlete names, images, and likenesses won’t be used. EA has promised that it will share more information about upcoming game as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EASPORTSCollege/status/1356727357638344705"&gt;“development progresses in the next couple of years.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649132/ea-madden-nfl-22-college-football-superstar-ko-campus-legends-event-mode"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649132/ea-madden-nfl-22-college-football-superstar-ko-campus-legends-event-mode</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T09:36:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T09:36:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>DC FanDome returns in October</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Batman" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JpFcLYQOpBGMEqBm_STjXn32DFU=/573x0:2598x1350/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69797731/rev_1_TBM_TRL_003_High_Res_JPEG.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Warner Bros. Pictures / DC Comics&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o5F2Mt"&gt;Last year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/22/21397238/fandome-dc-zack-snyder-justice-league-batman-robert-pattinson-black-adam-gotham-knights"&gt;DC had an impressive showing at its virtual FanDome event&lt;/a&gt;, and today the company revealed it’s doing it again very soon. &lt;a href="https://www.dccomics.com/blog/2021/08/31/welcome-back-to-dc-fandome"&gt;FanDome will return on October 16th&lt;/a&gt;, and will feature updates, trailers, and reveals covering what looks to be a big range of projects across film, television, comics, and video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mQa8od"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"DC’s FanDome set the new gold standard for virtual events ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21399490/dcs-fandome-virtual-event-convention-digital-batman-justice-league-film-gaming"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mw4rOL"&gt;That includes: “an exclusive new trailer” for the Robert Pattinson-led &lt;em&gt;The Batman&lt;/em&gt;; looks at movies &lt;em&gt;Black Adam&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom&lt;/em&gt;; more details on upcoming seasons of &lt;em&gt;Harley Quinn&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Batwoman&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Superman &amp;amp; Lois&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Sweet Tooth&lt;/em&gt;; reveals for games &lt;em&gt;Gotham Knights &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League; &lt;/em&gt;and a whole bunch of comic news, including the next chapter of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/25/22399355/batman-fortnite-zero-point-comic-book"&gt;the&lt;em&gt; Fortnite / Batman &lt;/em&gt;crossover&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u8BZfQ"&gt;You’ll be able to watch the event live on October 16th starting at 10AM PT across a number of platforms, including Twitch, YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter. DC also says that a kid-friendly version will be airing on the same day.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650092/dc-fandome-2021-date-batman-gotham-knights-sandman-fortnite"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650092/dc-fandome-2021-date-batman-gotham-knights-sandman-fortnite</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T09:17:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T09:17:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android 101: how to download or share a Google Photos album</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E3UsQhzC18VGm8Yykan99Q5_Xsk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69797629/jbareham_181010_2989_0323.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8uJELD"&gt;One thing Google really wants you to do is, well, stay in Google — because the more you do things the Google way, the more data the company can monetize. The result is that while it is possible to pull your emails, photos, and other material outside of the Googleverse, it’s just a little bit more difficult. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nGohqg"&gt;For example, let’s say you want to show an album of family photos that are stored on Google Photos to your favorite grandparent. If they’re reasonably Google-savvy, it’s not a problem at all — you just share the album with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="K22LrC"&gt;Share a Photos album on the web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="hAlk7g"&gt;Click on “Albums” in the left menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WoNU87"&gt;Hover the cursor over the album you want to share, and click on the three dots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zvZNgS"&gt;Click on “Share album.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="photos share album" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9OLMTQdvHJ7_Dm93WuZ4d5Oi-ng=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16311128/Screen_Shot_2019_05_31_at_10.57.55_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;All you have to do is click on “Share album.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vXyR1H"&gt;Another way to go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="CkrZue"&gt;Click on “Albums” in the left menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vLW7oK"&gt;Select the album you want to share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Xq2MWj"&gt;Click on the “Share” icon in the upper-right corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="woEVvC"&gt;Share an album using the mobile Photos app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Lmxo99"&gt;Tap on “Library” at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kAjowC"&gt;Select the album you want to share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="54QWMZ"&gt;Select “Share.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="6cYQCW"&gt;However, let’s say your grandparents want to download copies of the photos to email to a friend or to upload to a non-Google app. Then things get slightly more complicated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="b8ssds"&gt;Download a Photos album on the web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="1e6YuQ"&gt;Actually, &lt;em&gt;complicated&lt;/em&gt; may be the wrong word. It’s not difficult to download an album; you just have to know where to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="1Py3Hy"&gt;Click on “Albums” in the left menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Bc9RzB"&gt;Open the album you want to share, either by clicking on the album in the main section or selecting the album name in the left-hand column&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2TX0Dt"&gt;Click on the three dots in the upper-right corner and select “Download all.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="drUDLD"&gt;Google will then download a zip file containing the photos from your album.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="google photos download album" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TOCC9ANDr-QSM-tung0WdlwvPUU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16311140/Screen_Shot_2019_05_31_at_11.01.12_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s not difficult to download albums from the web. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="aSqEoS"&gt;You can also download multiple albums (or all your albums) by using Google Takeout, which lets you export data being held in your Google Account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="T2IjXW"&gt;Go to the “&lt;a href="https://takeout.google.com/u/1/?hl=en&amp;amp;utm_source=google-account"&gt;Download your data&lt;/a&gt;” page of your account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0RJf3d"&gt;Click on “Deselect all” (because this page automatically checks off every Google service you use).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="k1U65E"&gt;Page down to Google Photos and select it by clicking in the check box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9Xj4cc"&gt;Click on the button that says “All photo albums included.” Again, click on “Deselect all” and then check the boxes of those albums you do want to download. (Of course, if you want download all your albums, then just keep it the way it is.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lzezNv"&gt;Click on “Multiple formats” for information about how your photos will be downloaded. For example, the actual photos will be downloaded in the same format that they were uploaded, while metadata will be downloaded as JSON files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3flbgU"&gt;Scroll down and click on “Next step.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="91NQKP"&gt;You can then choose how you’ll receive your albums. You can receive the file via an email link or have it send to Dropbox, Drive, OneDrive, or Box. You can also choose if you want this to be a one-time download, whether you want it as a ZIP or TGZ file, and what the maximum size of the file should be. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ghzngc"&gt;Click on “Create export.” Be aware that it may take a while for you to receive your export — According to Google, it could take hours or days (although when I tried it with a single album, it took about a minute). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YopUrf"&gt;You will receive an email informing you of the successful download and offering you a link to download your files, or if you choose to send them to a cloud storage service, to where they were sent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="Apzgjq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:6360927"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xOd3d2"&gt;Download an album using the mobile Photos app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="rc3xlX"&gt;The answer to this is very simple: you can’t. There are, however, a couple of workarounds that you can use. For example, you can use Google Takeout using your mobile device’s browser and follow the steps listed above. You can also share the photos within the album to email or Google Drive, and then download them from there. This second method is pretty awkward, but it does work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLmOSR"&gt;Here’s how you share to email or Drive. (The photos shown are from a Pixel 3 XL running Android 12 beta, but the process should be the same for most Android phones and iPhones.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="8Pa3sy"&gt;In the Photos app, select “Library” from the bottom of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cxwqeZ"&gt;Look for the “Albums” heading, and then tap on the album you want to download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8Zzuoe"&gt;Press and hold onto the first photo until you see a check in the box in the upper-left corner of the photo. Then drag your finger down until all the photos in the album are checked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="E96nM5"&gt;Tap on the “share” icon on the top right of the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="h0tvTV"&gt;From here, you can either email the photos to yourself (an oldie but goodie) or save them to your favorite online storage service and download them from there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can find your albums by using the “Library” tab." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ypkVJfOAz72GrUO5YEMip02iDeM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22814837/Screenshot_20210830_112656.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find your albums by using the “Library” tab.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="After you’ve checked the photos you want, share them however you like." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wp0iyfF0VauRbMvY_8Y7DLeB1F8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22814838/Screenshot_20210830_112820__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;After you’ve checked the photos you want, share them however you like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mIPdVZ"&gt;As more people work using their phones rather than on laptops or other larger systems, the inability to do certain tasks on a mobile device — for example, download an album — is going to become, to say the least, irritating. Hopefully, Google will take note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jY8JZB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 30th, 2021, 11:50AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on June 4th, 2019, and has been updated to account for changes in the Google Photos interface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MvYDil"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22643429/android-how-to-download-share-google-photos-album"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22643429/android-how-to-download-share-google-photos-album</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T09:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T09:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Bose announces QuietComfort 45 noise-canceling headphones with 24-hour battery life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LaiLmsdMbnyp0UQ7pDDU1ditjtA=/185x0:1805x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69797621/0E8312A7_8138_4D4F_8D03_340251AB52EF.5.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Bose&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IDPZaz"&gt;After they first surfaced in July &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583264/bose-quietcomfort-45-headphones-qc45-fcc-filing-leak"&gt;in an FCC filing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22628896/bose-quietcomfort-qc-45-headphones-leak-features"&gt;again earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;, Bose is today introducing the &lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-11556694?sid=verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bose.com%2Fen_us%2Fproducts%2Fheadphones%2Fnoise_cancelling_headphones%2Fquietcomfort-headphones-45.html%23v%3Dqc45_black" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;QuietComfort 45 headphones&lt;/a&gt;. Priced at $329.95 and going on sale September 23rd, the QC45 headphones will offer improved active noise cancellation, a transparency / ambient sound feature that Bose calls “Aware Mode,” upgraded voice call performance, and longer battery life that can now hit 24 hours on a charge. Bose is making a big deal about this product release, claiming that it’s “updating the headphone that redefined headphones.” &lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-11556694?sid=verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bose.com%2Fen_us%2Fproducts%2Fheadphones%2Fnoise_cancelling_headphones%2Fquietcomfort-headphones-45.html%23v%3Dqc45_black" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Preorders begin today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KI2QiX"&gt;Available in black or “smoke white,” they look quite similar to their QC35 II predecessors, with a design that’s much more plasticky than Bose’s other premium headphones, the Noise Canceling Headphones 700. But that means, like before, these can be folded up for easy storage in a bag or the included carrying case. Bose says it has refined the design in subtle ways: according to the company, “pleats and puckers have been removed from soft materials, and gaps between components have been replaced with smooth transitions.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2tsPCQKeLRKfUYtqRjXWl8O_eLE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22816616/QC45_up_close.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bose&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Controls are the same as on the QC35 IIs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wwhPGl"&gt;The controls are largely the same, with four buttons on the right earcup and one on the left for toggling between noise canceling and transparency modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="utk9l2"&gt;Speaking of which, Bose claims the noise cancellation on the QC45s does a better job than the QC35 II headphones when it comes to eliminating mid-range frequencies, which are “those typically found in commuter trains, busy office spaces, and cafes.” Whereas the Noise Canceling Headphones 700 allow you to customize the amount of noise cancellation applied, the QC45s will offer just two modes: quiet and aware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jL3eNY"&gt;The QC45s also step up in terms of microphone performance. Bose has included a beam form array for improved voice isolation on calls, and there’s also “a rejection array” that is meant to prevent distracting nearby sounds from being picked up and coming through to whoever you’re speaking with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GWXH1v"&gt;Battery life is rated at up to 24 hours of straight playback. And yes, the QC45s have a USB-C jack. Bose says a full top-off takes two and a half hours, but you can get three hours of playback with a brief 15-minute charge. Like their predecessors and the NCH700 (which remain for sale), the QuietComfort 45 headphones support multipoint pairing for two connections at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cqHhCY"&gt;The QC35 IIs will be discontinued and replaced by the QC45s, but you might still be able to find Bose’s older pair until existing inventory at retailers is depleted. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22648407/bose-qc45-noise-canceling-headphones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22648407/bose-qc45-noise-canceling-headphones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-31T09:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-31T09:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Philips Hue bulbs are discounted in the lead up to Labor Day</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R3vJKoffF5qGEIip7f4lbqb77CI=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69797568/Philips_Hue_E26_smart_bulbs_press_image.5.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Now through September 12th, you can buy three Philips Hue bulbs for the price of two.  | Image: Philips&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lQJKuv"&gt;The upcoming Labor Day holiday signals the end of summer and the ramp-up of everything from the school year to new gadget season. While you can expect to get plenty of Labor Day-related deals from us coming very shortly, Philips has gotten a bit of a head start with their “Summer of Hue” savings promo, so you’re not stuck with having a single shade of lighting after Labor Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AAhEvs"&gt;Right now, Philips is offering three &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1750589459180759559#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;white and color smart bulbs &lt;/a&gt;for the price of two, shaving $35 off the cost of some of the most popular smart home lights through September 12th. The vibrant E26 Hue bulbs allow for funky lighting while offering a full spectrum of 16 million colors, as well the flexibility to stretch from a warm white to daylight-balanced cool white with up to 800 lumens of brightness. As the fall months come around, it can be refreshing to have color temperature options at your disposal to try and keep your mental state up, or at the very least to have adjustable smart timers for when the daytime hours get shorter. This is a great way to get into the Philips Hue ecosystem — the E26 bulbs can work with a Hue Bridge or without one via Bluetooth — or build up the stock of lights already set up in your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="sLBJMs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Philips Hue gets a sleeker new app rebuilt ‘from the ground up’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22465734/philips-hue-app-update-rebuilt-grid-view"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="mwF6P4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10649409"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TuGrn6"&gt;The world of gaming-focused accessories is flush with excessive RGB lighting, over-engineered aesthetics, and hard-edged design lines. If you’re looking for more subdued styling that doesn’t sacrifice performance, however, there’s the Logitech G Pro wireless mouse. The excellent peripheral has all the tenets of a gaming mouse, including a lightweight build and customizable DPI sensitivity, but with a look that could pass in either an esports tournament or an office. Its functionality extends a bit further, too, by allowing fully ambidextrous control, with a symmetrical design and swappable side button layouts. Normally $130, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07GCKQD77?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; currently has the Logitech G Pro for $85, its cheapest price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EAyinz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10726674"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W7Rzyk"&gt;The Studio Buds are a recent release from Apple-owned Beats, one that offers some unique features that separate it from the bevy of AirPods on the market. First off, the bold-colored Beats utilize a USB-C charging port as opposed to Lightning, making them more accessible and useful for Android users. They also support various Android features and offer active noise cancellation, which, while not as strong as the competition, still renders them a great pair of true wireless earbuds for working out or traveling. Amazon currently has the stylish &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B096SSCV5K/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;red model for $130&lt;/a&gt; ($20 off), which is a historical low for pair of earbuds that just launched in June. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22532970/beats-studio-buds-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Speyns"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10693512"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D7zmHR"&gt;If you’re looking for another deal on true wireless earbuds, the Jabra Elite 75t are &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07X9VG6ZJ?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;more than 33 percent off at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the price down to $100. These earbuds are a great alternative for multi-device users, or those who want some low-end punch while listening to tunes. They’re not as new as the aforementioned pair of Beats, but upon review, our colleague and seasoned headphone aficionado Chris Welch called them the best AirPods alternative. Considering the current price, the Jabra Elite 75t are a formidable competitor to standard AirPods and will make life a little easier if you’re someone who prefers to avoid Apple’s ecosystem. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21066947/jabra-elite-75t-review-wireless-earbuds-airpods-alternative" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lfqwzf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386608"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kyuIx1"&gt;The original Apple Pencil became the butt of many jokes across the tech space when everyone saw how it charged — we &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/12/8/9872746/apple-bad-hardware-design-iphone-case-pencil-magic-mouse" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;weren’t a fan&lt;/a&gt;, either. Thankfully, unlike the first-gen model, the latest Apple Pencil charges when magnetically attached to your iPad. It also supports gestures and is compatible with both the iPad Pro and the latest iPad Air. If you took advantage of our still-active &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/30/22648127/ipad-air-apple-gigabyte-aero-15-sony-wh1000xm3-headphones-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;deal from yesterday on the iPad Air&lt;/a&gt;, then this is your stylus of choice. For a limited time, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07K1WWBJK/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; is knocking $30 off the second-gen Apple Pencil, bringing it back down to its lowest price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="56WqB4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10500002"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZlbQ6Z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="81k7rK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/31/22648480/philips-hue-bulbs-labor-day-beats-studio-buds-jabra-elite-75t-apple-pencil-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/31/22648480/philips-hue-bulbs-labor-day-beats-studio-buds-jabra-elite-75t-apple-pencil-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
