<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-23T12:50:06-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:50:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:50:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Most dermatology algorithms don’t have transparent data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Dermatology Symptomatology, Woman" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/90L8Tnq97pXAnwhZIEyk64JZ3rs=/1x0:5100x3399/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898652/481684305.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by: BSIP/Universal Images Group via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7tyC2v"&gt;Most algorithms designed to help people identify skin problems don’t let experts see the datasets they were developed with and don’t share information on the skin tone or ethnicity of the patients in those datasets, according to &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2784295"&gt;a new review&lt;/a&gt;. That could make it hard for people to evaluate the programs before using them and to understand if they might not work as well for certain groups of people, the authors argue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Cf0qs"&gt;These types of tools use pictures of skin conditions to teach a system to recognize those same conditions in new images. Someone could upload a picture of a rash or mole, and the tool would be able to tell what type of rash or mole it was. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AUxOOF"&gt;The paper, published in &lt;em&gt;JAMA Dermatology&lt;/em&gt;, analyzed 70 studies that either developed a new&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;deep learning model or tested an existing algorithm on a new set of data. Taken together, the models were developed or tested using over 1 million images of skin problems. Only a quarter of those images were available for experts or the public to review, the analysis found. Fourteen of the studies included information about the ethnicity or race of the patients in their data, and only seven described their skin types. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="42RGse"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I highly suspect that these datasets are not diverse, but there is no way to know”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2IxUWF"&gt;The rest did not share the demographic breakdown of their patients. “I highly suspect that these datasets are not diverse, but there is no way to know,” study author Roxana Daneshjou, a clinical scholar in dermatology at Stanford University, said on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RoxanaDaneshjou/status/1440813771820208130"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7NdZrg"&gt;The analysis also checked if the models that aimed to identify skin cancer&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;were trained on images where the cancer was confirmed with a skin sample sent to a lab — the “gold standard” to make sure that diagnosis was correct. Of the studies included, 56 claimed to identify those conditions, but only&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;36 of those met the gold standard. The ones that did not could be less accurate, the authors say. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P3E5MV"&gt;The review included &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-020-0842-3"&gt;an algorithm&lt;/a&gt; from Google, which developed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451361/google-skin-condition-dermatology-symptom-checker"&gt;a tool&lt;/a&gt; designed to help people identify skin conditions. The company plans to make a pilot version of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22440754/google-health-ai-skin-condition-model-dermatology"&gt;web tool&lt;/a&gt;, which lets people upload pictures of a skin problem and get a list of possible conditions, later this year. According to the analysis, the Google paper includes skin type and an ethnicity breakdown but did not make the data or model used publicly available. It also didn’t use the gold standard methods for assessing a few types of skin cancers, including melanoma and basal cell carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OswpqJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Medical algorithms are only as good as the data they were developed with&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z0UNUk"&gt;Medical algorithms are only as good as the data they were developed with, and may not be as effective if they’re used in situations different from the ones on which they were trained. That’s why experts argue that data, or descriptions of that data, should be freely available: “the data that are used to train and test a model can determine its applicability and generalizability. Therefore, a clear understanding of data set characteristics ... is critical,” the authors wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pmn8QX"&gt;Lack of transparency is a consistent problem with medical algorithms. Most AI products cleared by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) don’t report important information about the data they were developed with, according to a February 2021 &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/02/03/fda-clearances-artificial-intelligence-data/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stat News&lt;/em&gt; investigation&lt;/a&gt;. The FDA told &lt;em&gt;Stat News&lt;/em&gt; that its new “action plan” for AI pushes for more transparency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M8zvPa"&gt;The limitations don’t mean most dermatology algorithms are useless, wrote Philipp Tschandl, a researcher at the Medical University of Vienna, wrote in an accompanying editorial. Physicians also aren’t perfect and have their own biases or knowledge gaps that can skew their interpretation of a skin problem. “We know this and still manage to practice medicine well,” he wrote. “We need to find ways through explainability, smart checks, and risk mitigations to allow algorithms to work safely and in an equitable manner within the field of medicine.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22689562/dermatology-algorithm-transparency-google-skin-cancer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22689562/dermatology-algorithm-transparency-google-skin-cancer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Unagi reveals ‘The Eleven,’ an electric scooter that plays music, avoids potholes, and looks incredible</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eps3GG-wBBl1PFmPpfOYAzCkssc=/338x0:2764x1617/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898507/ModelElevenGroup.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2kYxMm"&gt;Unagi, maker of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dgz-OJdfhhU"&gt;Iggy Pop’s favorite electric scooters&lt;/a&gt;, is releasing its second model called “The Eleven.” (Yes, it’s a &lt;em&gt;Spinal Tap&lt;/em&gt; reference.) As such, the company is taking everything that was cool and stylish about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/17/18080142/unagi-electric-scooter-kickstarter-price-specs"&gt;Model One scooters&lt;/a&gt;, and dialing it up to, well, eleven. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nWkiPw"&gt;The number of new, high-tech features on this scooter is truly impressive: swappable batteries, motion-detector alarm system, camera-based advanced driver assistance, and front and rear suspension to help cushion those potholes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2WUc77"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“a full on urban assault vehicle”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AaOZ9J"&gt;The Eleven is meant to be the company’s new flagship vehicle. “It’s an industrial work of art, the smartest scooter on the planet, and a full on urban assault vehicle,” Unagi CEO David Hyman told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zpteG5"&gt;The Eleven looks fantastic, too. That’s thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/8/6/5930539/the-makers-mark-yves-behar-fuseproject-profile"&gt;famed Swiss designer Yves Béhar&lt;/a&gt;, who made his mark designing iconic objects for Jawbone, Herman Miller, General Electric, and Puma, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/8/6/5975203/yves-behars-most-iconic-designs"&gt;among many others&lt;/a&gt;. According to Hyman, Béhar “took over” Unagi’s industrial design team after investing a chunk of money in the company. (Unagi has raised $23 million in venture capital funding in the past year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="A61AtO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10769282"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9KvOpM"&gt;Along with a “rock star team of renegades across material science, electrical engineering, and client application development,” Béhar designed the Eleven using a new material from Switzerland called “long carbon,” Hyman said. It’s a type of carbon composite that includes other materials like nylon, which allowed Unagi’s design team to formulate the shape of the scooter using injection molding rather than carbon wrapping. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1viSl7"&gt;The Eleven is almost entirely made of long carbon, including the handlebars, stem, platform, and even some of the innards. It allows for a unique, full-suspension design, while keeping the overall weight light and portable. “The advantage of that is that you can get very complex shapes that you can’t do with a traditional carbon fiber,” Hyman added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="alnjsf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Compared to the Model One, the Eleven has a host of new, high-tech features&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pDGapi"&gt;Compared to the Model One, the Eleven has a host of new, high-tech features. A multi-lens camera installed in the stem beneath the handlebars feeds visual data to an onboard computer, enabling the scooter to alert the rider about upcoming obstacles in the road like car doors or potholes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEk4WN"&gt;Hyman likens it to a vehicle’s advanced driver assist system (ADAS), like Tesla’s Autopilot. The feature won’t come standard on the scooter and will likely “add a few hundred bucks to the retail price,” he said. But in a few years, Hyman predicted that Unagi’s scooters will have the ability to slow down or stop autonomously to avoid crashes, a technology that is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252156/spin-scooter-remote-control-tortoise-segway"&gt;already being put to use by other scooter companies&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QvsmNx"&gt;“Our scooter knows the difference between a human being, a stop sign, a traffic light, or any kind of impeding danger that’s coming into the periphery,” he said. “So if somebody swings a car door open in a bike lane, you’re going to get a very loud warning over the audio system along with a visual warning.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="h0SDfN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10769321"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NHlHrK"&gt;Those warnings take the form of a ring system in the scooter’s main display that also helps with navigational directions. Customers can put a destination into the Unagi app, which connects to Google Maps through an API, and get turn-by-turn audio and visual directions while they ride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y4R8lX"&gt;“You never have to look at your phone,” Hyman said. “It’s all done with Google Voice over the audio system at a visual display. You don’t have to take your eyes off the road.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TqDrFD"&gt;Hyman also described the Eleven’s audio system as “very pumping loud,” so it can be heard on a city street. Customers can also play music via a Bluetooth connection, which is sure to be a popular feature with Unagi’s various &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/en/news-release/2019/10/01/1923644/0/en/Unagi-Scooters-scores-3-15-million-to-bring-transportation-freedom-to-everyone.html"&gt;celebrity and influencer customers&lt;/a&gt;, like Kendrick Lamar, Chance the Rapper, Khalid, Halsey, Steve Aoki, and Billie Eilish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="es2tfB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Be the Forrest Gump of scooters,” he said, “and ride ride across America.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ldUHPz"&gt;There are five different riding modes, with a top speed of 19mph (30kph). The entire scooter only weighs 32lbs (14.5kg), and the battery provides a maximum range of 15 miles on a single charge. Much like the Model One, the Eleven will run on a dual-motor system, with each motor delivering 250W of power for a total of 1,100W for the entire ride. The battery, which has 67.7W of capacity, is removable, meaning a customer can bring extra with them and never have to worry about range anxiety, Hyman said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="naCI2Z"&gt;“Be the Forrest Gump of scooters,” he said, “and ride ride across America.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Witk4T"&gt;Hyman is turning to crowdfunding site Indiegogo to raise money for the scooter’s production, which is an interesting move for a company that has successfully raised a lot of money from venture capital firms. “Tooling on this scooter is very expensive,” he noted. “So we don’t mind getting some cash upfront to offset the tooling costs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jRIP9i"&gt;Unagi plans on offering discounts to early adopters. And the company traces its roots to a Kickstarter campaign in 2018. “We could have done it with preorders on our site,” Hyman said. “But you know, this company was born on crowdfunding. That’s how we started. We’re believers in it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kgX3VR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Unagi is expanding its electric scooter subscription service to more cities","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334608/unagi-electric-scooter-subscription-expansion-cities-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="IYzyyG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fkDDlS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689633/unagi-electric-scooter-eleven-yves-behar-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689633/unagi-electric-scooter-eleven-yves-behar-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:25:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:25:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Halo-themed Xbox Series X and PS5 are now available through Walmart (update: to be rescheduled)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t6etFJjv5JSjBEKdsBpJGRqCC-Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898014/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vBOobq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 12:25PM ET, September 23rd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Walmart’s console restock didn’t get off to a good start. Pages weren’t loading for most people, it seems, and the retailer updated its site with a header saying “Console event to be rescheduled”. We’ll update this post again once we know when the event will happen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29Au4E"&gt;Walmart is hosting a big console restock event today, September 23rd, at 12PM ET / 9AM PT.  It’s going to have the PS5 consoles, along with the standard Xbox Series X and the limited edition &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;-themed Series X. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wbMpfd"&gt;In case you’re after that &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-themed console, &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X-Halo-Infinite-Limited-Edition-Bundle%2F288604110" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;try your luck at getting one through this link&lt;/a&gt;. Spec-wise, it’s no different than the standard model, but it has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641632/microsoft-xbox-series-x-halo-console-elite-2-controller"&gt;a more alluring design&lt;/a&gt;, both on the console and the included wireless controller. Two things to note: it’s $549.99, costing $50 more than the regular Series X. Another thing is that you won’t receive this until the game launches on November 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6F44Hm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10718933"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Mfv5Ml"&gt;Or, you can try to &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X%2F141335186&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;get the $499.99 Xbox Series X console&lt;/a&gt;, which has a Blu-ray disc drive, around 800GB of useable (but expandable) storage, and includes a wireless controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1LmOSa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444130"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9RkL9X"&gt;Getting an Xbox? Consider these add-ons:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="feA9TT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-Wireless-Headset-for-Xbox-Series-X-S-Xbox-One-and-Windows-10-Devices%2F466809446&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Wireless Headset for $98&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QsDNIA"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass%23join&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F23%2F22648984%2Fps5-xbox-series-x-halo-walmart-restock-time" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Game Pass Ultimate is $1 for the first month for new subscribers&lt;/a&gt; ($15 per month otherwise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7DdcY6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dxbox%2Bcontroller&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Wireless controller for $60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="HhIaF6"&gt;For people who are eager to get a PlayStation 5, Walmart has both editions of the console available today. &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Video-Game-Console%2F994712501&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You’ll be able to get the $499.99 version&lt;/a&gt; that has a built-in Blu-ray disc drive and a DualSense controller. &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Digital-Edition-Video-Game-Consoles%2F979738052&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It’s also going to sell the digital version&lt;/a&gt; that lacks a disc drive for $399.99. Both consoles have around 660GB of useable storage, but they’re expandable via their NVMe M.2 slot. If you just plan on playing PS4 games, you can use a cheaper external USB hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VwRWZA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10384391"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="twDYRJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ak8TVg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The PS5 SSD buying guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22602046/best-ps5-playstation-5-m2-ssd-compatible-drives"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="mO7e2e"&gt;Getting a PS5? Check out these games and accessories:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="pe0i85"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDeathloop-Arkane-Lyon-Bethesda-Softworks-PlayStation-5%2F495171229&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deathloop &lt;/em&gt;for PS5 costs $60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hTDuHB"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDemon-Souls-PlayStation-5%2F741555735%3Fathbdg%3DL1300&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; costs $50&lt;/a&gt; (normally $70)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2QCYqD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Ddualsense&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pick up an extra DualSense controller for $69&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LesDLb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPS5-PULSE-3D-Wireless-Headset%2F667802535%3Fathbdg%3DL1200&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony’s Pulse 3D Audio wireless headset costs $99&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="VzMYhI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hVX4te"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KUqIxG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22648984/ps5-xbox-series-x-halo-walmart-restock-time"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22648984/ps5-xbox-series-x-halo-walmart-restock-time</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:14:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:14:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s new Galaxy Watch 4 is $20 off and comes with a free wireless charger today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The regular Galaxy Watch 4 has a touch-sensitive bezel, which is fiddly." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aotX4LF0nKdqEAnXgoVj3-BjHr0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898410/dbohn_210816_4717_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 runs Watch OS 3.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CKg29I"&gt;Today only, the new Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 is not only discounted to its best price to date, but the smartwatch also comes with a free dual wireless charging pad. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-Smart-Bluetooth/dp/B099Y7SPHC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon has the combo on sale for $230&lt;/a&gt;, which is $20 cheaper than the watch would normally sell for on its own. The deal encompasses all available colorways, as well as the larger &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Galaxy-Watch-Smart-Bluetooth/dp/B099YPLVZ3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;44mm version for $260&lt;/a&gt; if you prefer a bigger watch. The wireless charging pad you get with it fast charges both the watch and a phone, and it would normally sell for $60 on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mmxGIt"&gt;The Galaxy Watch 4 launched just over one month ago, and it’s the first device to run the new Wear OS 3 platform that Google and Samsung collaborated on. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22629459/galaxy-watch-4-classic-review-bixby-google-wearos"&gt;In our review&lt;/a&gt;, we found that even with the software promises of Wear OS 3, it still very much feels like Samsung’s world and is best paired with a Galaxy phone. It’s a very capable smartwatch with snappy performance and expansive health tracking. With today’s deal, the Galaxy Watch 4 becomes an even better value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ufm4sT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10768955"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LBGZVj"&gt;If you’d like a pair of Samsung earbuds to accompany your new smartwatch, &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836602-13527013?sid=vergedailydeals092321&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fsamsung-galaxy-buds2-true-wireless-anc-earbuds-4" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Galaxy Buds 2 are $35 off at Woot&lt;/a&gt;. These are the latest wireless earbuds from Samsung, and even though they just released in August, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/18/22630394/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-earbuds-woot-chromebook-2-airpods-max-apple-deal-sale-amazon"&gt;they have seen some sales from Woot before&lt;/a&gt;. Now, they have dropped an additional $10, hitting a new best-ever price of $115. You even have your choice of colors: graphite, white, olive, and lavender. The only thing to keep in mind is that these have a 90-day warranty from Woot as opposed to a one-year warranty direct from Samsung. Though, there is no better price anywhere else for this great pair of active noise-canceling earbuds. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0fWuXJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10707231"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Qqg2C"&gt;If you saw Amazon’s recent announcement of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22684801/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-features-price-release-date"&gt;new Kindle Paperwhite&lt;/a&gt;, you know that in addition to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22685873/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-preorder-buy-how-to-price-release-date"&gt;preordering the upcoming model&lt;/a&gt;, you can look forward to discounts on the outgoing one. Sure enough, today, the 10th-generation ad-supported Kindle Paperwhite has hit a new all-time low price of just $80 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Waterproof-Storage-Special/dp/B07V3GSG2Y/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-kindle-paperwhite-waterproof-ad-supported-10th-generation%2F-%2FA-75574430%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailydeals092321"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. The new 11th-gen model will be bringing several improvements, but it also has a higher price of $140. Compared to this freshly discounted price for the 10th-gen model, let’s just say sometimes it pays to be a late adopter. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18065960/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2018-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cxzNHP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10695294"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ojhUTR"&gt;Apple users, if you saw the Samsung deal at the top of our roundup and like the sound of a dual wireless charger for your watch and phone, we’ve got you covered. &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/vergedailydeals092321/https://www.verizon.com/products/apple-magsafe-duo-charger-wireless-qi/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon is discounting the Apple MagSafe Duo wireless charger&lt;/a&gt;, dropping the price from $129 to a much more palatable $96.74. We &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/9/21557152/apples-magsafe-duo-charger-wireless-iphone-12"&gt;haven’t exactly loved the MagSafe Duo&lt;/a&gt; here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, though a big part of that is due to its high price. Getting a nice deal on it is surely more worthwhile if you value owning the only dual wireless charging solution that can charge your iPhone and Apple Watch at the fastest rate they can achieve — plus, it rarely goes on sale. The MagSafe Duo also gets some style points for folding up nice and small to be a little more travel or hotel-stay friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TkwA9U"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386180"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p5ygZR"&gt;The Oculus Quest 2 has become a fan-favorite for people &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22379859/vr-virtual-reality-fitness-work-out-supernatural-chris-milk-interview"&gt;getting into exercising at home&lt;/a&gt;, as well as general VR gaming without the need for an expensive PC setup. Some households may have a tougher time sharing one headset, so the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=vergedailydeal092321&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fquest-2%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy-two-get-$100-off deal that Oculus is currently running&lt;/a&gt; could be just what a couple or family needs. If you add two Quest 2 headsets to your cart on the Oculus website, the discounted price will automatically be applied, totaling $498 for two of the 128GB models or $698 for two of the 256GB. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v3Vid1"&gt;What better way to get in shape or immerse yourself in interactive virtual worlds than to do it alongside your loved one or friend while competitively destroying each and every one of their high scores? Mercy is for the weak. (Disclaimer: The Verge Deals is not responsible for marital or relationship advice.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lcDVYz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10459857"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WjJhGv"&gt;A few more deals worth checking out:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="DYIpsv"&gt;The Asus TUF Gaming 17.3” laptop we &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/22/22684883/samsung-odyssey-g9-ssd-apple-pencil-echo-show-acer-chromebook-deal-sale"&gt;featured yesterday&lt;/a&gt; is still on sale for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752787261366758437" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$800 from Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cAB7JG"&gt;The charcoal Peak Design Everyday Messenger 13” Version 2 bag is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1411870-REG%2Fpeak_design_bs_13_bl_2_the_everyday_messenger_13.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F9%2F23%2F22689418%2Fsamsung-galaxy-watch-4-kindle-paperwhite-galaxy-buds-2-apple-magsafe-duo-oculus-quest-2-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$120 (45% off) at B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt; for today only. This popular bag will most likely sell out at that price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="w3HtG2"&gt;The Amazon Fire TV Stick 4K is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fire-TV-Stick-4K-with-Alexa-Voice-Remote/dp" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$35 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. Not its cheapest price ever, but a consistently good one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BLKyhY"&gt;Razer’s Blackwidow V3 Mini 65 percent mechanical keyboard just released in the summer and is now &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0935HWL1Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$150 on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, a discount of $30.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PwYnT4"&gt;The OnePlus Buds Pro in white or black are $20 off with discount code &lt;strong&gt;BUDSPRO20&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://onepluscom.pxf.io/c/482924/916678/12532?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.com%2Fproduct%2Foneplus-buds-pro&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailydeals092321" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;direct from OnePlus&lt;/a&gt;, bringing their price down to $130. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637548/oneplus-buds-pro-review-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="nHLCum"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/23/22689418/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-kindle-paperwhite-galaxy-buds-2-apple-magsafe-duo-oculus-quest-2-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/23/22689418/samsung-galaxy-watch-4-kindle-paperwhite-galaxy-buds-2-apple-magsafe-duo-oculus-quest-2-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android adds facial gesture controls and handwriting recognition accessibility features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YhSAR5NLr-vSqy9nVE9ClpNFHzM=/0x0:834x556/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898307/ezgif.com_gif_maker__1_.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gNVQfw"&gt;Google’s raft of &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-features-fall-2021/"&gt;new features coming to Android this fall&lt;/a&gt; includes some interesting new accessibility features. There are new facial gesture controls designed for people with motor impairments, as well as a new handwriting recognition feature for Lookout, a Google app that uses a phone’s camera to help people with low vision or blindness. There are also improvements coming for Google Assistant, Digital Wellbeing, Nearby Share, and Google’s Android keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kKsO1o"&gt;There are two parts to Android’s facial gesture controls. Camera Switches (which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626754/android-accessibility-face-gesture-controls"&gt;previously been spotted&lt;/a&gt; in Android 12’s beta) sits within Android’s existing Accessibility Suite and lets you use gestures like opening your mouth or raising your eyebrows to activate various commands. The second part is Project Activate, a standalone app that’s designed to help people communicate. Here, facial gestures can be set to trigger actions like playing audio or sending a text message.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/209OPL1Vbo4o5aBuQJQ181vUoaQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22871770/ezgif.com_gif_maker__1_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Using facial gestures to control a weather app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yje8II"&gt;Meanwhile, Google says Lookout’s handwriting recognition will be able to read out Latin-based languages and is accessible from its Documents mode. Euro and Indian Rupees are also being added to the app’s Currency mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30D3kL"&gt;Beyond accessibility, Gboard is also seeing improvements. Most interesting is that on all devices running Android 11 and up, Google’s Android keyboard will be able to use Smart Compose to finish sentences, similar to what’s already possible in specific services like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/20/20973917/google-docs-smart-compose-feature-g-suite-update"&gt;Google Docs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/10/17340224/google-gmail-how-to-use-smart-compose-io-2018"&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt;. This feature has previously been exclusive to Pixel phones. Copying and pasting is also being updated to automatically separate out separate contact information and details like phone numbers and email addresses when they’re copied in a single chunk of text. Finally, Gboard will also proactively suggest sharing a screenshot if you immediately switch to a messaging app after taking one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAJhp7"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379419/android-digital-wellbeing-heads-up-walking-google-pixel-4a"&gt;“Heads Up” Digital Wellbeing feature&lt;/a&gt;, which reminds people to stop looking down at their phones while they’re walking, is expanding from just Pixels to all Android phones, while asking Google Assistant to “open my reminders” now offers a one-stop-shop for managing all reminders added to the voice assistant. Nearby Share is also being updated to offer new visibility settings, letting you control who can see your device and send files. It’s a real grab bag of features that should offer something for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xsr0Pz"&gt;Google isn’t offering exact release dates for any of these features, and there’s no mention of whether any of them will be exclusive to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661647/android-12-final-beta-5-pixel-5a-stability-ui-changes-preview"&gt;upcoming Android 12&lt;/a&gt;. So expect most of them to gradually roll out over the course of this fall, which is generally considered to run until the start of December.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689349/android-facial-gesture-controls-handwriting-recognition-accessibility-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689349/android-facial-gesture-controls-handwriting-recognition-accessibility-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Honda will use Google’s embedded Android Automotive in its cars starting in 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Honda e Prototype" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bsHiATzJEHPEFIqd0QIKtSxgDv8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898246/geneva_honda_eprototype_vladsavov29.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vlad Savov / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Mn0CN3"&gt;Google nabbed another big automaker in its quest to become the default operating system for cars. Honda will soon begin rolling out vehicles with Google’s embedded Android Automotive OS, which includes Google’s voice-activated Assistant, Google Maps, and other automotive-approved Android apps as the default infotainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2fw9P7"&gt;The first Honda vehicles with embedded Android will start rolling out in 2022. The Japanese automaker wouldn’t say which models it expects to get the new infotainment systems first. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nJko9m"&gt;“We will collaborate with Google to better integrate Google in-vehicle services in our vehicles including the ability to more-easily use features like Google Assistant, Google Maps functionality and other in-vehicle apps offered through Google Play,” a Honda spokesperson said in an email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Gqrald"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Honda wouldn’t say which models it expects to get the new infotainment systems first&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Uut7ru"&gt;To be clear, Android Automotive is distinct from Android Auto. The former is the car’s default infotainment system, controlling everything from music to navigation to heating and air conditioning, while the latter is projected from a smartphone onto the car’s dashboard display and serves as a competitor to Apple’s CarPlay. Google also had a number of announcements regarding Android Auto (that you can read about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22453578"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xdBDsA"&gt;There are only two cars available today with embedded Android Automotive: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21365032/polestar-2-hands-on-first-drive-electric-android-automotive-photos-range"&gt;Polestar 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195499/volvo-xc40-recharge-ev-suv-first-drive-specs-price"&gt;Volvo XC40 Recharge&lt;/a&gt;. But Google has made deals with a number of other automakers, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260176/ford-google-android-infotainment-os-2023"&gt;Ford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/5/20851021/general-motors-android-auto-google-infotainment"&gt;General Motors&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/18/17873502/google-android-os-cars-renault-nissan-mitsubishi-alliance"&gt;Renault-Nissan-Mitsubishi Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, that will result in millions of future vehicles released with default Android operating systems. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9GchADo27AuvRadCIJQEPOscnN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22872025/Cars_with_Google_built_in.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7aky4h"&gt;The news that Honda is joining the Android Automotive party won’t come as a complete surprise, given that the automaker’s current operating system has been Android-based for years. Honda was also part of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/1/6/5279116/google-open-automotive-alliance-android-car-announcement"&gt;Google-led Open Automotive Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, along with Audi, Hyundai, and chipmaker Nvidia, which focused on the integration of Android into in-car infotainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ndb0MI"&gt;But it can also be a slippery slope. Initially, car companies seemed to want &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/13/14268252/apple-carplay-google-android-auto-vs-carmakers"&gt;to keep big tech companies at arm’s length&lt;/a&gt; to prevent them from tapping into the lucrative customer data streams flowing in and out of their vehicles. But Honda figures that by letting Google under the hood, it can probably sell more cars to customers who would prefer a more smartphone-like in-car experience than the OS software currently provided by the automaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xIUljj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;a new dashboard for Google Assistant driving mode&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688309/honda-google-android-auto-assistant-driving-mode-gas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688309/honda-google-android-auto-assistant-driving-mode-gas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google TV mercifully launches mobile remote for Android users </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EEQZGjpH3Jm6UdWZBpkoSGF0mG8=/0x180:1080x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898245/AFS_01A_VirtualRemote_IJ_Realistic_1x1_Frame_11.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OYv7u7"&gt;A new Google TV feature will allow users to use their Android mobile devices as remotes for those moments when your streaming box’s wand disappears without a trace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2oPlbW"&gt;Android mobile remote support for Google TV arrives today after the company initially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;announced the feature&lt;/a&gt; during Google I/O back in May. (A spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;the tool will only be available for Android at this time and did not have anything further to share about future iOS support.) &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yhGxyRTYteCRB7TF49dt9vRv7GQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22871153/1._Android_TV_Remote.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xOkujC"&gt;Support for a mobile remote should be a tremendous help to those of us constantly losing our wands beneath mountains of blankets and pillows, but it should also streamline processes for things like entering long or complicated passwords, search terms, and titles to films and series. Google said that beyond just Google TV, support would extend to other Android TV OS devices as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8VdmwZ"&gt;The remote tool can be accessed two ways: either by adding the r&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/android/answer/9083864?hl=en"&gt;emote tile to quick settings&lt;/a&gt; from an Android device or through the Google TV app (which Google said will be launching in 14 new countries in the coming weeks). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688867/google-tv-mobile-remote-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688867/google-tv-mobile-remote-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Photos’ nude-friendly folders coming to all Android phones soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QdyiNMpg6RzB3GugrUVBiTqaqhk=/75x0:1176x734/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898244/Screen_Shot_2021_05_18_at_10.46.16_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The feature lets you hide photos and videos behind a passcode or biometric security.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LsKomr"&gt;Google Photos’ Locked Folder feature, which lets you hide sensitive photos and videos from your main library and secure them in a passcode- or biometric-protected folder, is coming to all devices running Android 6 and above. The feature was released exclusively on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524661/google-photos-locked-folder-private-videos-available-pixel"&gt;newer Pixel phones in June&lt;/a&gt;. Google hasn’t provided an exact date for when the feature is releasing more widely, noting only that it’s “rolling out soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fcKveF"&gt;When it announced the feature onstage &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442416/google-photos-locked-folder-private-hidden-pictures"&gt;at Google I/O in May&lt;/a&gt;, Google gave the wholesome example of the feature being used by parents hiding photos of a newly purchased puppy from their children. But I think it’s fair to say that most people are going to have very different photos stored in their Locked Folder. I don’t know about you, but in all the times I’ve had to wrench my phone out of someone’s hand to stop them scrolling through my photos, it’s never been because of a puppy picture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="85pinM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;With Locked Folder in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/googlephotos?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@googlephotos&lt;/a&gt;, you can add photos to a passcode protected space and they won’t show up as you scroll through Photos or other apps on your phone. Locked Folder is launching first on Google Pixel, and more Android devices throughout the year. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GoogleIO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/yGNoQ8vLdq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/yGNoQ8vLdq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Google (@Google) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1394710047213633536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Iu3G3B"&gt;You set up a Locked Folder by going to Library &amp;gt; Utilities &amp;gt; Locked Folder in the Google Photos app. Then, existing photos can be manually moved to the folder. The Pixel camera app is able to save new shots directly into the folder when taken, but it’s unclear whether this feature will also be available for other Android camera apps. Note that any images saved in a Locked Folder won’t be backed up to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VHT9xn"&gt;The wide launch of Locked Folders was announced as part of a host of new features &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-features-fall-2021/"&gt;coming to Android this fall&lt;/a&gt;. Other new features include the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22452908"&gt;use Android phones as remotes&lt;/a&gt; for Google TV and Android TV OS devices, as well as new Android Auto and accessibility features.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689322/google-photos-locked-folder-passcode-protected-sensitive-images"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689322/google-photos-locked-folder-passcode-protected-sensitive-images</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s how to watch the latest Nintendo Direct</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LfhYbPAIK72pJ9Yp7w6XNyjW_3o=/0x0:2160x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898251/switch_oled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Switch with an OLED screen.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FdZr6Z"&gt;Nintendo is hosting one of its Direct streams later today, September 23rd, where it will showcase Switch games launching this winter. Though, that doesn’t mean there won’t be some news on games coming out later in 2022. There’s also a possibility that Nintendo might show off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/16/22677624/nintendo-new-controller-fcc-wireless"&gt;the mysterious device that recently popped up in FCC filings&lt;/a&gt;. We think it’s a controller, but given that the company makes so many strange devices, ranging from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20917908/nintendo-switch-ring-fit-adventure-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; exercise ring to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/18/17253574/nintendo-labo-review-switch-learning-diy"&gt;Labo&lt;/a&gt; and modern &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22535212/nintendo-the-legend-of-zelda-ii-links-awakening-game-watch-handheld-release-date"&gt;Game &amp;amp; Watch&lt;/a&gt; handhelds, who’s to say what’s in store?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4HYu2"&gt;Parts of the presentation will likely be focused on what’s coming in the immediate future, which for Nintendo includes its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22569208/nintendo-switch-oled-model-hands-on-screen"&gt;new Switch console that has an OLED screen&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22536783/metroid-dread-yoshio-sakamoto-nintendo-switch-e3-2021"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metroid Dread&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Both launch on October 8th, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yx9AOW"&gt;As usual, we’re going to give you the details to help you tune into the latest Nintendo Direct when it’s live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yDafRT"&gt;When is the next Nintendo Direct?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VHDo3O"&gt;It’s happening later today, September 23rd, starting at 6PM ET / 3PM PT. Nintendo says that the presentation will last for “roughly 40 minutes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xgrZS2"&gt;Where can I watch the Nintendo Direct?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mpsw2j"&gt;You can check out the Direct on &lt;a href="http://youtube.com/nintendo"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://twitch.tv/nintendo"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkYDAM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689427/nintendo-direct-date-time-watch-how-to-switch-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689427/nintendo-direct-date-time-watch-how-to-switch-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android Auto is getting a new look to make futzing with your car less distracting</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cfYuxHTya5QHq2n3yJuIEJUwIn8=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898253/Sequence_02.00_01_09_21.Still007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ndb0MI"&gt;Google announced a few updates to Android Auto, including a new dashboard for Google Assistant driving mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZHDZnR"&gt;Earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633755/google-android-auto-for-phone-screens-shutting-down-android-12-google-assistant-driving-mode"&gt;Google shut down the standalone “Android Auto for Phone Screens”&lt;/a&gt; app with Android 12. Instead, Android phone owners are now recommended to use the Google Assistant driving mode available within Google Maps or the native Android Auto interface available in select cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNIxGq"&gt;For Android customers with older cars who use their phones for navigation and other functions, Google Assistant driving mode now includes “glanceable, tappable cards” with music, text messages, and other frequently used apps collected all in one place. Customers will be able to use voice commands like “Hey Google, let’s drive” to open the new driving mode dashboard, reducing the need to futz with your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9WtGRo"&gt;Google says this is designed to ensure drivers keep their eyes on the road and not on their phones. Drivers can also have their incoming text messages read out loud to them using voice control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/odU8xoJo7wek9bD5knPWRpn9qX8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22871992/Assistant_driving_mode_800px.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ffqojA"&gt;There are also new updates to Android Auto, which mirrors your smartphone’s display on your car’s infotainment screen. Drivers can select which apps they want to see when they first plug their phone into their car (or when it connects via Bluetooth). This also is designed to cut down on driver distraction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ZF1uP"&gt;Distraction is a major problem for drivers, especially as infotainment systems become flashier and more complicated. A recent &lt;a href="https://trid.trb.org/view/1694794#:~:text=Self%2Dreported%20data%20suggested%20that,Android%20Auto%20and%20Apple%20CarPlay."&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that drivers selecting music with Apple CarPlay or Android Auto had slower reaction times than those who were high from smoking pot. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18117046/android-auto-new-features-updates-music-playback-messaging-safer-less-distraction"&gt;Google has been trying to work its way through this problem&lt;/a&gt; for several years now, but they have yet to arrive at a definitive solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cbPVZm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Distraction is a major problem for drivers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JrYHkM"&gt;When their car is safely parked, Android Auto customers can play games from GameSnacks right on their car’s display. For those who don’t recognize the name, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/14/21137737/gamesnacks-google-html5-games-area-120-bad-internet-connection-budget-phones"&gt;GameSnacks is Google’s series of HTML5-based browser games&lt;/a&gt; that are meant to be easy to load and play on nearly any device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e7G6B3"&gt;Lastly, Google announced that Android Auto users will soon be able to use Google Pay to pay for gas. After pulling into a gas station, drivers need only select their pump number on the screen and Google Pay will do the rest. (Of course, they’ll still need to get out of the car and pump their gas; Google hasn’t figured out how to automate that yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v75aFz"&gt;Automakers have been building payment options into their cars for years now. For example, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/18/17248282/chevrolet-shell-in-car-payment-gas"&gt;Chevrolet has a deal with Shell&lt;/a&gt; that lets drivers pay for gas from their vehicle’s infotainment screen. But this feature has yet to go mainstream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHiztD"&gt;The new Google Pay feature will be available at 32,500 gas stations in the US starting with Exxon and Mobil stations, with Shell, Conoco, Phillips 66, and 76 stations coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yk1npz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fERA7G"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689537/android-auto-google-assistant-driving-mode-dashboard-distraction"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689537/android-auto-google-assistant-driving-mode-dashboard-distraction</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
