<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-07T11:07:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T11:07:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T11:07:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Bungie celebrates its 30th Anniversary in Destiny 2 with off-brand Halo gear</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QwG-w7IB3RcrvNu27kCUwUNQtks=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239813/2021_30th_Press_Kit_Large_Gear_08.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="obF5tQ"&gt;A lot is happening in the world of &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; today. Bungie is celebrating its 30th Anniversary inside &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt;, with a big content drop that includes &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-like guns. A trailer for &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt;’s new Bungie 30th Anniversary pack shows off a Magnum-like sidearm in &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt;, alongside a Battle Rifle-like pulse rifle in the looter shooter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mg6sym"&gt;Both guns appear to look and feel like the original &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; weapons, but there’s no mention of an official crossover with Microsoft anywhere. It doesn’t appear that Bungie secured the official rights from Microsoft to put the actual &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; guns it originally created in &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; and has instead done a good job at producing replicas that nod to the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FgiAih"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Bungie just revealed a Halo-like Battle Rifle and Magnum are coming to Destiny 2 today, to celebrate 30 years of Bungie   &lt;a href="https://t.co/xkSUwpTtPZ"&gt;https://t.co/xkSUwpTtPZ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/4fdaR7yrMr"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4fdaR7yrMr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1468236173646737422?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vBg9Hi"&gt;“Reunite with an Exotic Sidearm that you may recognize from adventures long ago,” reads a &lt;a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/Direct/Anniversary?ciid=50638"&gt;description on Bungie’s website&lt;/a&gt; for the Magnum-like gun. “It led you to glory then and it will do so again.” The exotic sidearm is called Forerunner, and the Battle Rifle-like weapon is named BxR-55 Battler. There’s even armor for the Titan that includes a Needler-style shoulder pad, and armor for the warlock that features the &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; ring. The &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-like loot doesn’t even require Destiny 2 players to own the 30th Anniversary pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tw7o5K"&gt;The 30th Anniversary pack also includes a new six-person activity (which is separately free to all players) with armor and weapons, the grasp of avarice dungeon, and the return of the infamous Gjallarhorn rocket launcher. Bungie is also bringing back classic weapons like the Matador 64, Eyasluna, and 1000-Yard Stare, which can be earned with the 30th Anniversary pack, alongside some heavy changes to the player-vs-player sandbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ft7wsW"&gt;If that’s not enough nostalgia for Bungie’s classic games, there’s even a Myth Claymore (&lt;em&gt;Myth&lt;/em&gt;) and Marathon (&lt;em&gt;Marathon&lt;/em&gt;) armor ornament set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KzSPQS4eRkj5kih3ZSHBeGyJwcg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23070058/2021_30th_Press_Kit_Large_Gear_16.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bungie&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Destiny 2’s new exotic sidearm looks like Halo’s Magnum.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QXo07d4JaHVAPuQQ5GjJkDMJO2U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23070108/2021_30th_Press_Kit_Large_NPC_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bungie&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new space horse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TcUpoZ"&gt;There’s even a space horse, an NPC that will be housed inside the giant loot cave where players will earn some of today’s new weapons and armor. The mystical space horse was first spotted in &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2 &lt;/em&gt;during Season of the Drifter, and it has some links to the Nine, a mysterious faction inside &lt;em&gt;Destiny’s &lt;/em&gt;universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iw5DAq"&gt;Combined with some great-looking armor, cosmetics, and ornaments, it feels like &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2 &lt;/em&gt;is getting a big injection of content midway through a season that leads to the next big expansion: &lt;em&gt;The Witch Queen&lt;/em&gt;. The game’s biggest expansion in years, &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2: The Witch Queen&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639582/destiny-2-the-witch-queen-expansion-release-date-gjallarhorn"&gt;will launch on February 22nd&lt;/a&gt;. It will see players finally face Savathûn, and continue the story of the sci-fi space series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Bk9co"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witch Queen&lt;/em&gt; expansion will also feature a new location, Savathûn’s Throne World, alongside important changes to existing subclasses, campaign content, weapons, armor, and a new raid. The 30th Anniversary pack should hopefully hold players over until February, in what’s an unusually long season for &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822240/bungie-30th-anniversary-destiny-2-halo-guns-armor-gear"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822240/bungie-30th-anniversary-destiny-2-halo-guns-armor-gear</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Discord’s new Premium Memberships let creators monetize servers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D3sfgjAj-V2HnOoo2-Si6oKhZow=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239712/acastro_200318_1777_discord_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2m7f91"&gt;Discord is starting to test a new Premium Memberships feature that will allow creators to monetize their servers. An initial pilot is going live today with around 10 creators who will pave the way for Discord’s 150 million monthly active users to pay to access a range of channels or servers and support creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FLqIkq"&gt;Premium Memberships offer what a number of creators have already been experimenting with: a way to offer more content or access to community members. Discord communities will be able to create tiered perks, view analytics on member engagement, and lock channels or even entire servers to paying subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/27PZsyf0pFGkRdTb2zrC7pXgdmU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069823/Home.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Discord&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discord’s new Premium Memberships include tiers for community servers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="stRGLM"&gt;“We see Discord becoming a home for more creators and communities through products like Premium Memberships,” explains Sumeet Vaidya, director of engineering at Discord, in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “By providing tools that let community creators earn money, more of them will run healthy engaged communities for longer periods of time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cqg2M"&gt;While Discord already has a number of integrations with Patreon, YouTube, Twitch, and other services that let subscribers on other platforms get special perks or privileges in Discord servers, Premium Memberships will be fully native to Discord. That means Discord also sets the terms of payments directly, and it has picked a 90 / 10 split with creators, allowing Discord communities to keep 90 percent of all revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qetlgv"&gt;“We want to make sure that creators are able to make as much money as possible, while also making sure that if creators are successful Discord is also making some money which makes sure Discord is successful too,” says Vaidya. “This was the most favorable split we could think of, to make sure both parties are invested in the long run.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qlmFaJhF2-ClS6HxO2he2vl8cns=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069825/Basic_Info.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Discord&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creators will be able to set different membership levels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_I8MeSwn9T3PLQYRcFXWYtn-JSA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069826/Welcome_Modal.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Discord&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A welcome message for Discord Premium Memberships.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6eunEW"&gt;So what do you get if you opt for a Premium Membership to a Discord server? That’s really up to creators, and it’s something Discord is looking to its communities to help shape these memberships during this trial phase. There are already journalists, professional map makers, and other communities monetizing their Discord servers, with many using the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22356682/discord-stage-channels-clubhouse-like-feature-voice"&gt;Clubhouse-like Stage Channels audio features&lt;/a&gt; to provide a small and more intimate community or exclusive perks for subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="chpQLn"&gt;It’s clear Discord saw this emerging trend and wanted to make it a lot more streamlined, native to its platform, and easier for everyone involved. While you might associate Discord subscriber-only channels with Twitch streamers or Patreon subscriptions, Discord is working with a diverse set of communities to test Premium Memberships and make them accessible for both creators and Discord users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MBoAw1"&gt;Premium Membership channels will have a small blue star next to them, and if you try to access them, you’ll be offered the tiers of access that creators have set. In the coming weeks you might see Discord community servers testing this new feature, and it’s something that will expand to more communities next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="05dzTW"&gt;“This is one of our most-requested features from creators,” reveals Vaidya. “While it’s something that many creators already do through third parties, this is the first time they’ll be able to do it natively on Discord.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822042/discord-premium-memberships-creators-monetize-servers-feature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822042/discord-premium-memberships-creators-monetize-servers-feature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T10:42:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T10:42:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge’s favorite guilty pleasures</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hVQyZyHsNgrL9DbfoLZwZceztd4=/0x200:1200x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239637/ember_cup_with_phone.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Ember Technologies&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aeNrDm"&gt;We all have stuff that we’ve bought ourselves — or asked others to buy for us — that makes us happy, even if we suspect our friends may not understand why it’s so great. It could be a $100-plus coffee cup that keeps your liquid at the exact right temperature. Or a video game that you’ve been playing for years. Or a hair styler that is way expensive but would make you look fabulous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0tqkN"&gt;We asked the staff of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; what some of their guilty pleasures are, and the braver among us volunteered some answers. Here they are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zIwJem"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.geappliances.com/appliance/GE-Profile-Opal-2-0-Nugget-Ice-Maker-with-Side-Tank-XPIO13SCSS"&gt;GE Opal 2.0 ice machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Maut8q"&gt;I’m hesitant to call it a “guilty” pleasure because I have used this $550 (or more) GE Opal 2.0 ice machine every day for nearly a full year and not once have I felt guilt about spending such an obscene amount of cash on a kitchen gadget that does exactly one thing. But the GE Opal gives me the “good” ice, alternatively known as “nugget” or “Sonic” ice. Besides being crucial for authentic Tiki drinks, this ice just feels like it classes up every drink it touches. I stopped buying iced coffee elsewhere because mine always just came out fancier — and seemingly tastier. Juice feels luxurious poured over these chewy little ice nugs. Sodas sparkle when faced with so much surface area. Even a glass of water feels like it’s more expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mSLWHb"&gt;The GE Opal costs $550 if you’re lucky (it goes on sale often) but usually retails for $579 to $679. It comes with Bluetooth and an atrocious app I closed immediately after opening. It’s noisy — the churn of ice being made is providing a background rhythm even as I type this. But every day I use this machine I feel a little trill of joy — so it might not be a guilty pleasure for me, but depending on your love of beverages, mileage will vary. &lt;em&gt;—Alex Cranz, managing editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6qQY6d"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905059"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="1dbMgX"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JmsFpY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drinkspindrift.com/drinks/orange-mango-sparkling-water/"&gt;Spindrift sparkling water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="AkhYmk"&gt;I’m obsessed with the orange mango flavor of Spindrift sparkling water. It tastes kind of like orange soda but without all of the sugar, and I find it extremely refreshing. If I think about it too much, sparkling water feels like a waste of money. But every week when I go to the grocery store, a case of the delicious Spindrift just happens to end up in my cart. &lt;em&gt;—Jay Peters, news writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nWf1yB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905143"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Rsp0Kv"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="dTPZVH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://nerf.hasbro.com/en-us/product/nerf-halo-bulldog-sg-dart-blaster-pump-action-rotating-10-dart-drum-tactical-rails-10-nerf-darts-skin-unlock-code:1025C4C0-4F78-41BD-AAC4-4AA5B3ED58BC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;Nerf Bulldog SG Dart Blaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gY3lTR"&gt;Don’t let the gray hairs, mortgage, spouse, and two cats fool you — I am a child. A recent example is my impulsive purchase of two &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/NERF-Pump-Action-Rotating-Tactical-Official/dp/B08SMQLYJW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;Nerf Bulldog SG Dart Blasters&lt;/a&gt; from a lightning deal during the Black Friday / Cyber Monday weekend. I usually refrain from buying into the hype cycle of new game releases, but I have been getting back into &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; in a big way since the multiplayer beta launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4JlfjR"&gt;As for the Nerf, the pump-action loading and included in-game weapon skin hooked me. I got one for myself and one for my brother-in-law, ensuring I have a partner in crime. We immediately tested them on each other — they do sting a bit — before turning our aim to my wife’s Christmas decorations (that poor snowman). Then we hopped into some multiplayer matches, giggling as we hunted down shotguns just to see our cool digital Nerf guns. Now I want the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/NERF-NER-Halo-MA40/dp/B08486XL7R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MA40 assault rifle&lt;/a&gt; to go with it, so I can start every match in &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; with another silly, guilty pleasure purchase straight from IRL. &lt;em&gt;—Antonio G. Di Benedetto, commerce writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yrbY7a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905435"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="nQSjD9"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="29evVB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dyson.com%2Fhair-care%2Fhair-stylers%2Fairwrap%2Fcomplete-nickel-fuchsia&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22820219%2Fguilty-pleasures-ice-halo-dyson-sims" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dyson Airwrap Complete styler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ApCJtT"&gt;I’ve attended a few weddings in the “Before Times” where I had to style my hair with a curling iron like a grown-up, and not default to my usual ponytail. I watched countless YouTube videos and practiced a bunch, but each attempt was anxiety-inducing. After all, there is no Control-Alt-Z or edit button to undo the wrong curl, especially when you’re working with a hot piece of equipment and under time pressures. In those anxious moments, the $550 Dyson Airwrap styler doesn’t seem like &lt;em&gt;such &lt;/em&gt;a ridiculous splurge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yMjQ6H"&gt;The Airwrap styler uses Dyson’s vacuum technology to create a vortex that automatically wraps your hair around the styling barrel or brush. This eliminates the confusion over which direction to twist the barrel (which is half the battle) and makes it easier to style the hair at the back of your head. My guilty pleasure just involves checking in on this product’s price (no change or even more expensive) and availability (mostly sold out) every now and then. While I can’t guarantee I will use this tool regularly enough to justify its cost, at least I would have no excuse for turning up in a ponytail again.  &lt;em&gt;—Gloria Sin, reviewer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uFyMWh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905921"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="NAHPbJ"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FafVHk"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22277238/dji-mini-2-drone-review-price-specs-features"&gt;DJI Mini 2 drone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="u2giDX"&gt;I am a drone pilot. That’s what I tell myself every time I purchase a new drone. And maybe six times a year, it’s vaguely true. I love flying and I love drones, but I definitely did not need to purchase the $449 DJI Mini 2. When I sold my DJI Mavic Pro, just a couple years after buying that one to upgrade a Phantom 3 Pro I never used, I told myself I would wait. Of course I didn’t listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3xltw"&gt;Like I told my friend Vjeran Pavic, who is an &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; photographer and videographer and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/vjeran-pavic"&gt;reviews drones like a pro&lt;/a&gt;, I feel kind of naked without one now. Who knows when there might be something amazing happening in my neighborhood and I can just toss a drone up in the air for a look? (Never mind that I’ll undoubtedly have to spend half an hour recharging batteries and possibly updating firmware and databases first.) I &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; clocked those kids launching illegal fireworks in my neighborhood this summer, and it reminded me of fond memories reading &lt;em&gt;Harriet the Spy&lt;/em&gt; growing up. I’m not sure if it was that, or flying through the fireworks that really made me smile. Either way, the drone is now back in the drawer where it’s been sitting for months. While it’s hard to explain why, I’m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; glad it’s there. —&lt;em&gt;Sean Hollister, senior reports editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NIVH2S"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215854"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="3xhz0A"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HWKyDC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ea.com/games/the-sims/the-sims-4/buy"&gt;Sims 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6VR9Y"&gt;Look, there’s an evergreen joke about people who like &lt;em&gt;The Sims&lt;/em&gt; but only pick it up every few months to aggressively play it for about a week before forgetting it exists again. I am not one of those people. I am a very avid &lt;em&gt;Sims 4&lt;/em&gt; player and I refuse to hide that any longer. I create intricate storylines for all of my characters and I challenge myself to become a better virtual interior decorator with each new house I build. It helps that new features have recently been added like Scenarios, predetermined sticky situations your Sims can find themselves in, and Kits, which add small batches of new items without needing to buy a full expansion pack (although, I do already own plenty of the expansion packs). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CrhWou"&gt;I discovered the first version of the game in the early 2000s at my babysitter’s house as a child, and I’ve been a lost cause ever since. I’ve followed the series through most of the iterations on multiple consoles. This means I can confidently say that The Sims 2 on the PC is still the best version of the game. I also follow TikTok creators who create Sims content to share in the gallery, like &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@thatsimschick?"&gt;ThatSimsChick&lt;/a&gt;, who builds beautiful homes and styles them with the eye of a professional. Perhaps one day I’ll be good enough to share my own creations (and abominations) in the gallery, too. Until then, I’m gonna keep logging an embarrassing amount of hours of gameplay a week. — &lt;em&gt;Kaitlin Hatton, senior e-commerce social media manager&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="h3W9XF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905993"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="pTSl8O"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="R7vYdY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ember.com/products/ember-mug-2?variant=30843977859157"&gt;Ember Mug 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Q6fZQn"&gt;As a number of my colleagues likely remember, just a few weeks ago in our team Slack channel, I vociferously criticized buying a $100-plus coffee mug that did nothing other than keep your coffee (or tea, or hot cocoa, or whatever liquid you like to drink hot) at the exact temperature you set it to. Perhaps this was a case of a schoolyard bully negging the kid they have a crush on to hide their true feelings, because I’ve been coveting one of those fancy Ember mugs for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kcT2XC"&gt;And when Best Buy put its &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9N7v1IqHE" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;exclusive blue color of the Ember Mug V2&lt;/a&gt; on sale for Black Friday, I finally bit. Reader, this mug is fantastic. It keeps my coffee hot no matter how long I take to consume it, I never have to bother with microwaving a room temperature mug, and I can even tweak its settings depending on what I’m drinking out of it (coffee in the morning, tea in the afternoon, usually). I even get the joy of occasionally updating the firmware on my coffee mug, a sentence that would have made no sense to anyone just a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rce7yH"&gt;To be clear, this is a completely frivolous product that nobody actually needs. It makes a mildly annoying thing slightly less annoying and its drawbacks (cost, can’t put it in the dishwasher, did I mention the cost?) probably outweigh those benefits for most people. It’s a little embarrassing how much I like it, which is why it’s a perfect guilty pleasure. I enjoy it, I feel a little awkward about it, and I’d like to never speak of it again. — &lt;em&gt;Dan Seifert, deputy editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UkmZKD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10906039"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="taTD7V"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="BF9Na6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monteverdepens.com/engage/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Monteverde Engage Ink Ball pen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="l5TEw3"&gt;I have a close friend who for years tried to convert me to pen collecting. But while I loved the fountain pens she bought me for birthdays, I was constantly inking up my fingers and smearing the pages, and I just couldn’t get the hang of writing with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3z6DRb"&gt;Then she bought me the Monteverde One Touch Engage pen, which uses fountain pen ink in a roller-ball format — in other words, it uses ink like a fountain pen but writes like a ballpoint. At first, I was doubtful: it was larger than most pens I used and felt a little awkward in my hand. But it definitely grew on me; when I use it, the ink flows so smoothly and beautifully that I feel like another Jane Austen, sitting at a desk and penning some clever 19th-century prose. You can fill the pen with ink from a bottle or use disposable cartridges. (I use the latter; refilling pens was something I also never got the hang of.) The model my friend gave me has rose-gold accents and a stylus on the top so I can also use it with a touch device. The current model lacks the stylus but is, I’m sure, still a cool pen.&lt;em&gt; — Barbara Krasnoff, reviews editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PNxisS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10906136"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="X2v9qi"&gt;
&lt;aside id="3svLK6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Other Verge Favorites","url":"https://www.theverge.com/favorites"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22820219/guilty-pleasures-ice-halo-dyson-sims"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22820219/guilty-pleasures-ice-halo-dyson-sims</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T10:41:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T10:41:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter acquires messaging platform Quill to make DMs suck less</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HaCJK38A8qTLOn0UrLJ_FmqI0Dw=/420x62:1188x574/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239635/quill_and_twitter.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Twitter is acquiring Quill | Quill&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I1I4Tu"&gt;Twitter has acquired Slack-like messaging app Quill with an eye toward improving messaging services, including direct messages, the company announced Tuesday. In a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nickcald/status/1468221428268863489?s=20"&gt;tweet thread announcing the deal&lt;/a&gt;, Nick Caldwell, general manager for core tech at Twitter, described Quill as a “fresher, more deliberate way to communicate. We’re bringing their experience and creativity to Twitter as we work to make messaging tools like DMs a more useful &amp;amp; expressive way people can have conversations on the service.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CKeEIJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ludwig?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ludwig&lt;/a&gt; and his talented team built Quill as a fresher, more deliberate way to communicate. We’re bringing their experience and creativity to Twitter as we work to make messaging tools like DMs a more useful &amp;amp; expressive way people can have conversations on the service.&lt;/p&gt;— Nick Caldwell   (@nickcald) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nickcald/status/1468221428268863489?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8cwZJr"&gt;Quill will shut down, but its team will join Twitter’s Experience org. Terms of the deal were not disclosed. A &lt;a href="https://quill.chat/updates/2021-12-07-quill-twitter/"&gt;farewell blog post&lt;/a&gt; on Quill’s updates site provided instructions for users who want to export their team message histories, which will be available until 1PM PT on December 11th. At that point, Quill will be turning off its servers and deleting all data. Active customers will be issued full refunds, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="arBTmL"&gt;“Together with Twitter, we will continue to pursue our original goal — to make online communication more thoughtful, and more effective, for everyone,” the blog post reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v7aLrs"&gt;Quill made its &lt;a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/quill-7"&gt;official launch&lt;/a&gt; in February, &lt;a href="https://quill.chat/"&gt;billing itself&lt;/a&gt; as “messaging for people that focus.” It was founded by Ludwig Pettersson, former creative director of payments processing platform Stripe. Pettersson will be joining Twitter’s Conversations team under Oji Udezue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Wbq20"&gt;The platform was built for work conversations but with controls over some of the features that make Slack a distracting time suck. Its structured channels allowed for more focused conversations than the traditional reverse chron chat thread, and message threads could be split and moved into separate conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kXPIfa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MlZ5oK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ma3k5h"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822184/twitter-quill-messaging-platform-dms-slack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822184/twitter-quill-messaging-platform-dms-slack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T10:16:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T10:16:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon Echo devices still available for Black Friday Prices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Amazon Echo Show (second generation)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dk0UFqYauf6s7hpqR5vgPxlN3lo=/0x84:2000x1417/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239553/Echo_Show__Entertainment.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Echo Show devices are still available for their lowest prices ever. | Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KAh4dg"&gt;Black Friday has come and gone, but many awesome deals are still sticking around. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J8FFJ8H?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9vIoa0cLs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; are still offering the second-gen Echo Show 5 for $44.99, the lowest price we’ve seen for this smart device. And while not quite the same price we saw on Cyber Monday, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Echo-Show-8-2nd-Gen-2021-release/dp/B084DCJKSL?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Echo Show 8 is also available for a sizeable $40 discount&lt;/a&gt;, taking the price of this smart screen down to just $94.99. Both of these second-generation smart displays are similar in form and function, with the Echo Show 8 featuring a slightly larger screen and a more powerful, 13MP camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AJoABq"&gt;Dan Seifert reviewed both the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22529891/amazon-echo-show-5-2nd-gen-alexa-smart-display-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Echo Show 5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22521948/amazon-echo-show-8-2nd-gen-2021-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Show 8&lt;/a&gt; for us when they launched this past summer. He concluded that the Echo Show 5 remains a solid option, even though the iterative updates weren’t that impressive. However, he concluded that the second-gen Echo Show 8 remains the best Alexa smart display, despite spotty video calling software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CGjFPc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10873822"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="NHNs7t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10889414"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZDeSXc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s new Echo Show 15 is meant to hang on your wall","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22693503/amazon-echo-show-15-smart-display-wall-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Amazon’s Echo Show 15 goes up for preorder, shipping December 9th","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786975/amazon-echo-show-15-release-date-preorder-smart-display-alexa"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="mPFdUk"&gt;The latest MacBook Air with the vaunted M1 CPU is still available for $899.99 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08N5KWB9H?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9uVs7jC5c" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. While not quite the same deal we saw on Black Friday, $100 off for a machine of this caliber is nothing to scoff at. This 13-inch laptop features 8GB of RAM and a 256GB storage capacity, but the 512GB version is also available for $1,100, taking $150 off the regular price. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In our review&lt;/a&gt;, Dieter Bohn mentioned the excellent battery life and performance of this keystone piece of Apple hardware, even though its webcam left something to be desired. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dvlEvr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cxLRKn"&gt;The Beats Studio 3 are still available for their lowest price at Best Buy. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9oXmObe6Y" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Currently $169.99, this sale takes almost $200 off the original MSRP&lt;/a&gt;. This price is only available for the black and grey colorways, but considering black goes with everything, this shouldn’t be a huge issue. These collapsible, over-ear headphones are designed with Apple users in mind, featuring an Apple W1 chip for seamless Bluetooth connectivity and power efficiency. Rechargeable over micro-USB, the Studio 3 can last up to 22 hours on a single charge and feature built-in noise cancellation. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/25/16542656/beats-studio-3-wireless-headphones-review-noise-canceling" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Read our review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ODXAf6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10869141"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CKa1fP"&gt;The Logitech G502 Lightspeed is available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07L4BM851?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1739789224930594992" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, matching its all-time low price of $99.99. This massive mouse hit this price originally at the beginning of November and fluctuated for a while but is resting comfortably at its lowest price ever. This iteration of the G502 comes equipped with the 25k DPI Hero sensor, six programmable buttons, inserts for adjustable weight, and is compatible with Logitech’s wireless charging Powerplay system. The G502 sports solid battery life on its own, capable of lasting up to 60 hours on a single charge. But, if you invest in the Powerplay mouse pad, you can keep the G502 topped off indefinitely without ever having to worry about battery life again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GoiiLD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9550529"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="GFrv8r"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wired or wireless gaming mouse you can buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21252193/best-gaming-mouse"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="3hdLcB"&gt;The massive K95 RGB Platinum keyboard from Corsair is currently available from &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9qRDjiluJ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Corsair-Platinum-Mechanical-Keyboard-Backlit/dp/B082GR814B?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for a slightly better price than were available on Black Friday. Down to just $145.99, this price takes $54 off the regular MSRP and is a remarkable value for this versatile, full-sized keyboard. The K95 Platinum was Corsair’s flagship model until the release of the K100 but remains an amazing entry in this line of gaming Keyboards. Equipped with Cherry MX Silver switches, dedicated macro and media playback keys, the K95 is still one of Corsair’s best keyboards to date. The XT built on the original legacy of the K95 by adding PBT keycaps that resist wear and add a slightly textured finish. Overall, this is an excellent gaming keyboard to have in your armory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gJ4oTm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9740232"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="0Tnu0W"&gt;A few more deals to keep an eye on&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="SRDMG0"&gt;Save $20 on the portable &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9sBexnv1I" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bose Soundlink Micro Bluetooth speaker at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, bringing it down to $99.99, matching the all-time lowest price for this lightweight and powerful speaker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NZ5QBz"&gt;If you’re looking to build out your &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; collection, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9sBIyK5RV" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently, if you buy three Magic boosters or starter kits, you can get a fourth one free at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wr8i1A"&gt;Can’t get enough of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;? GameStop is offering a Master Chief-themed Razer peripherals bundle. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=VergeDeals120621&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fgaming-accessories%2Fkeyboards%2Fpc%2Fproducts%2Fhalo-infinite-pc-accessories-bundle%2FB307085A.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;This $299.99 collection includes the wired DeathAdderV2 mouse, BlackWidow V3 keyboard, and Goliathus mouse mat&lt;/a&gt; — a $340 value when purchased separately. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="fPJsb8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/7/22820347/amazon-echo-apple-macbook-logitech-corsair-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/7/22820347/amazon-echo-apple-macbook-logitech-corsair-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T10:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T10:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>From a meme to $47 million: ConstitutionDAO, crypto, and the future of crowdfunding</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/16kwoq8B6Z1Av_JqJdasl5cVlKU=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239543/VRG_ILLO_Decoder_Jonah_Erlich_s.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The real Constitution is the friends we made along the way&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="IWNuVT"&gt;Jonah Erlich is one of the core members of a group called ConstitutionDAO, a group that raised money to try to buy one of the original copies of the United States Constitution at an auction held by the high-end auction house Sotheby’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zyYFmU"&gt;Raising money on the internet is a pretty familiar idea — there are crowdfunding campaigns for everything from new products to movies to scientific research to politics. But most of the crowdfunding we’re used to happens through a central service: Kickstarter, or GoFundMe, or Indiegogo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bNbTTa"&gt;But the DAO in ConstitutionDAO stands for decentralized autonomous organization. Jonah and around 30 other people formed the DAO and then offered people around the world the ability to donate to it using the Ethereum blockchain. In exchange, they’d get the right to vote on what to do with this copy of the Constitution and what the organization should do in the future. And this attempt to raise money was extremely successful: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787993/constitutiondao-crypto-buy-us-constitution-copy-sothebys-ethereum"&gt;ConstitutionDAO raised something like $47 million&lt;/a&gt; and verified enough funds with Sotheby’s to participate in the auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XdnJQY"&gt;I asked Jonah to come on and explain how ConstitutionDAO got started, what happened with the auction, what the actual plan to handle one of the only remaining copies of the Constitution was if they’d won, and what happens to all the money now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wFAAr6"&gt;There’s a lot to this story that hasn’t really been told yet — and I think it’s a really useful look at the tension between the promise of crypto technologies, like smart contracts and DAOs, and the reality of getting a bunch of people together to do... well, anything. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9brmBD"&gt;The biggest question I had was why did they need this technology to achieve their goal. I think that’s the big question for a lot of crypto right now, and I really appreciated Jonah coming on the show to talk it over with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WwfwXF"&gt;Okay, Jonah Erlich from ConstitutionDAO. Here we go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2jHO0V"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP9374168078" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UaDBJL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This transcript has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="puRlsV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3wrTlU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonah Erlich, you are a software engineer and you are one of the core contributors to the ConstitutionDAO. Welcome to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decoder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SrkvgI"&gt;Thanks, Nilay. Glad to be here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8rJwN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So from what I understand of your project, you wanted to buy the Constitution. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSoVGh"&gt;What started as a joke on Twitter led to being a very real bid in an auction to buy a copy of the US Constitution. It was a really great experience to see and flex the power of the internet in just a week of trying to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tMRQ51"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a lot to talk about with what happened with the bid, how the auction process actually went, what you plan to do with the money you have raised so far. You raised roughly $47 million — although that’s in Ethereum, so that number is moving all the time — but I want to start with the very basics. DAO stands for decentralized autonomous organization, but what is a DAO?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uv3pmW"&gt;The definition of a DAO is a group of people that come together around a shared community and a shared resource. The most fun description I’ve heard is that a DAO is a group chat with a bank account. Essentially, what a DAO lets you do is have this very lightweight organizational structure to be able to move around assets and interact with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c4cdaT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We spend a lot of time on this show talking about organizational structures: very few are actually lightweight in the end. If you have a group chat with a bank account, how do you decide how to spend the money in that bank account?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JTtTT0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If DeFi is speedrunning the history of finance, then DAO is speedrunning the history of organizational structures.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FadjOm"&gt;It depends on the DAO. DAO structures are really in their infancy today. What most of them do is it’s a voting process. Essentially, everyone who holds the token for a DAO will be able to vote. They’ll suggest a proposal: let’s say we want to buy the Constitution, as an example. All the token holders get a vote. There are more complicated and interesting mechanisms being worked on in the DAO world right now. One of the jokes in the crypto world is that if DeFi (decentralized finance) is speedrunning the history of finance, then DAO is speedrunning the history of organizational structures. Because DAOs are so new, most of them operate on this very simple structure of direct democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mjDF7Q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I had contributed to ConstitutionDAO, what was I actually buying?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kmXXSY"&gt;A donation to ConstitutionDAO means that — if we were to have succeeded at our bid — we would’ve been granted governance rights over the documents of the US Constitution. We were trying to bid and win one of the remaining 13 copies of this document. At that point, the DAO would have voted on what to do with it. For example, we had museums lined up that were going to give proposals on how their museum should be the one to store and display this document. The DAO would also be able to vote on what text should be displayed alongside this copy of the Constitution. What message do we want to share with the world? Say the DAO won a copy of the Constitution, and we displayed it in a museum. We probably would have funds left over to give to a community that is really excited about doing things. The token holders would set the future direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qkakrb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I read on the website that when someone contributed, what they were fundamentally buying was a governance token. The token was called $PEOPLE, which is very funny — buying $PEOPLE has a dark connotation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jb1Egz"&gt;Yeah. It was a dark side. This was something we moved very, very quickly on. We were actually planning on rebranding the token to a name that was a little more positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fjiwB6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How were you going to rebrand it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mbphhF"&gt;It was going to be $WTP — We the People. That was the leading idea. We really want this DAO to be a positive thing, so we really listened to the community when members said they were uncomfortable with the name of the PEOPLE token. That was something that was chosen very quickly, and we wanted to adapt to what the community wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c4yx2V"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When someone buys tokens named $PEOPLE or $WTP, do they get one vote per token?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="j7INpH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9545330"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2LG79d"&gt;We had not figured out the governance model. In the rush to be able to buy this document, there were a lot of details that we were going to figure out after we had won. We were actually discussing different governance models had we won. One of the big concerns is that some of the large holders in the crypto world — we call these whales — would have outsized control over what happens with the documents. Our big message is: this is a movement for the people. This is the people’s document, so we want to have it controlled by the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ilvKv"&gt;We were looking at different mechanisms. We were looking at the direct democracy voting: one token, one vote. We were also looking at one vote per wallet, which isn’t an exact proxy for one person, but it’s pretty close. Quadratic voting is another mechanism in which voting power is actually diminished when a person has more tokens: you don’t have a hundred extra votes for every hundred extra tokens, but rather a smaller amount of votes as that number of tokens increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hLZ5e5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you say DAO is speedrunning the history of organizational structure, you’re describing speedrunning the history of democracy: setting up a voting system and figuring out how those votes will be representative of a group of people. However, a group of people has to make those decisions; not exactly democratic. How is that working for ConstitutionDAO?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="liwt7H"&gt;There’s a good concept called progressive decentralization: it’s really hard to actually start something fully decentralized, so you have to start with an initial team that builds something, who then brings it to decentralization. Our plan with ConstitutionDAO [was] that, once we win this auction, we’re going as fast as we can to becoming fully decentralized to the greatest extent possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="umhnEp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of what I hear about with blockchain projects is trust and verification. What is the mechanism of accountability for that process? If I buy into this project, you have promised to decentralize it as fast as possible. What makes you do that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TlwO15"&gt;Everyone who was involved with this project was very public. The signers on our [multisignature wallet] were very public. We worked with an excellent nonprofit called &lt;a href="https://endaoment.org/"&gt;Endaoment&lt;/a&gt; who helps with on-chain giving to take custody of the documents and do our bid on behalf of Sotheby’s. The personal reputations of people who are trusted within the crypto community were on the line, getting us to this point of decentralization. That’s really what we were leaning on for the beginning of this process. What happens with a lot of new technologies is unfortunately you can’t do things perfectly the first time. We’re still very, very early with the capabilities of DAOs and the capabilities of crypto. We wanted to be able to move as fast as possible and get things done while keeping that promise that we are going to get there. I felt very confident that had we won the document, we’d be getting there very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mt0SGM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reason I’m pushing on it is because I hear from the crypto community that you don’t have to trust people: the software will do it for you in some way. We can build mechanisms of accountability that are automated, transparent, or verifiable — all without some central control. In reality, quite often you have to trust a bunch of people to do what they say they are going to do. Did you perceive that tension as you were racing through this project?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9UL6pd"&gt;You are 100 percent right. There was trust you had to put into the ConstitutionDAO core team. Initially we had what’s called a multi-sig — basically a smart contract that would hold the funds that were controlled by 13 different signers. Seven of them had to sign to move the funds. Initially, for their safety, those signers were anonymous, because it was a lot of money and we were concerned about their personal safety. But we heard from the community: “Hey, we’re not okay with this.” Many people didn’t want to contribute because of the anonymity, so we asked the signers to volunteer to let us know if they are comfortable sharing who [they] are so we could put them on our website. Everyone decided to volunteer. It was definitely an iterative learning process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fKSEWf"&gt;The trust aspect is something that we definitely want to minimize in the long run, and I think what’s really interesting here is how to connect the physical world with the crypto world with these trust assumptions. How do you make sure the physical document is actually governed according to the will of the token holders? One of the ideas that we explored was moving the DAO into a 501(c)(3) where the bylaws would require signers to act in accordance to the will of the token holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q0VnYV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The will of the token holders expressed through a voting scheme that you had not determined yet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vXhODl"&gt;Yes. There’s great tooling out there, but we had not officially determined anything yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="irqOrX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have to trust a bunch of people — some of whom I believe you knew personally — and in the end, voting just implies a level of politics, why do you need a decentralized worldwide computer network to manage that? Really, you’re just buying shares of a thing that provide you some governance rights. That describes every corporation in America.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IvaU4C"&gt;The way that I like to think about this is in terms of two primary types of agreements that we’re used to in the world. One is the agreements between people and society. These are laws along the lines of prohibiting theft or avoiding taxes. You’re not doing something bad to one specific person — although some of those do have individual parties — but rather it’s enforcing societal rules as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GGCBqj"&gt;The other part of that is agreements between individuals and agreements between entities. I think this creates a much lighterweight framework for arbitration for agreements between individuals, so we can put as much as possible into the code as opposed into legal documents. When it’s in code, it’s a lot easier to actually simulate what happens. It’s a lot more difficult to interpret that in a way that was not intended. You can put in those spots where you want human interpretability, but it creates a much more lightweight, efficient system for agreements between people. That’s why it’s really important that it’s on this decentralized structure, because it allows us to move a lot faster and more efficiently in that sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ebY9Q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Put this into practice for me: I went to law school. I spent years of my life learning contract law, though I’m not sure I learned anything that I retained to this day. Contract law is a very well-established body of law, with hundreds of years of doctrine behind agreements between people. What exactly can you put into code that automates contract law?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CSGo70"&gt;There are lots of things that are already running today. I think ConstitutionDAO, once we had gotten the document and the token holders had voting power, was part of that, I think with a lot of this—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ns3Q5C"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But why do you need a decentralized network of computers to manage something proposing some text for a museum display of the Constitution? Why is that impossible on a centralized computer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gagcRA"&gt;Centralized computers don’t have the same guarantees that you do on a blockchain. For example, you can directly read and audit the code of what the agreement is that you are interacting with, where that’s much more difficult with a centralized service. That’s not important for something big, like a highly regulated financial institution. It makes it a lot easier for an upstart to come in and to create a new service where someone can audit the code and say, “Hey, this does exactly what it does.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jRV5ws"&gt;Obviously we can’t expect individuals of all sorts to be auditing code. Most people don’t know how to read code, but there’s a very strong cottage industry of smart contract auditors growing in this space and doing a better job of understanding what the best practices are and what outcomes we want from these smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hxtBzZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are smart contract auditors just lawyers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mCNTgP"&gt;No, they’re software engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSXzlq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okay. Again, my history is a very analog version of this, which is: I write you a contract. I send that contract to you. You should not sign that contract unless your lawyer reads it. Should I wait to sign a smart contract until my smart contract auditor reads it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TjaUSG"&gt;Either your smart contract auditor or firm that you trust. Actually, I have a really great example for you of a smart contract that you might find interesting: a very common thing in the tech world for a tech employee is vesting — you join a company, you get stock options, and there’s a one-year cliff. What you can do is essentially put that vesting into a smart contract. What’s really interesting about that is you can actually see the funds. They are sitting in that contract. You can pull them at any time, so it’s not that you’re getting your equity a month at a time, but rather you’re able to pull that at any time, every block. It’s almost a continuous stream of pulling out this equity from the contract and it’s significantly lighterweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsqYzZ"&gt;I’ve read some of these vesting contracts and they’re 200-300 lines of code. At the end of the day, that’s pretty light. If you’re reusing the same one over and over again, you can verify that this is the same vesting contract that Google used for 100,000 people — you would know that this is something secure that you can probably trust as opposed to the repetitiveness of legal documents. For example, when I’m reading my lease for my apartment in New York, I have the New York fire safety code in there. It’s unclear what I actually need to read here. In software, there’s this idea of modularity, where I can just say, “Alright. I know that there’s this fire safety code module in here and I can move on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ywIntj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think a lot of lawyers would say the same things about how they read contracts. There’s a lot of crossover between the ways lawyers work and ways software engineers work. There’s a great Larry Lessig essay from ages ago called “&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harvardmagazine.com/2000/01/code-is-law-html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code is Law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,” which is—&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6mTMmx"&gt;The thing I want to push back on though: with software, you can choose your own interface. With a legal document you don’t have that optionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Gxjmy"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of this makes sense for financial instruments and payment rails. With this project, you were trying to do something far more subjective: deciding which museum gets the Constitution. I’m still unclear why that needs to operate on a decentralized computer network, as opposed to a model in which a bunch of people you trust have issued you some shares in their organization that provides you governance over those people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FDia67"&gt;I see. Part of this was just the speed at which we were moving. We wouldn’t have been able to do this via traditional mechanisms in terms of payment processing. We had some very, very large payments come in. We had a donation of $4.5 million that came in overnight. Most payment processes are not going to handle that in a span of 15 seconds in the way that a blockchain will, so that was a big part of using a decentralized system. It’s also significantly more difficult to get those voting rights into place using traditional systems. It’s not something that’s very common outside of the financial world, and this is not a financial instrument — this is donation and control over a document. That’s why this technology was necessary because it gave us the ability to have that governance rights without the heavy-handedness of going through a lot of different, really important processes. It also guaranteed that the holders that were voting were who they said they were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qxkH5I"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think that makes sense, but at that point, the second half of the puzzle wasn’t assembled yet. The tokens had not actually conferred any articulated rights or voting structure. I’m curious why people were buying into a thing that they didn’t know what they were quite getting yet, but before we get too far down the road talking about donations and voting structure inside the DAO, I wanted to talk about how the ConstitutionDAO started. There are 30 core contributing members to ConstitutionDAO. How did this all start?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="eol4kX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It started as a meme.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PYX2TT"&gt;Like all great things on the internet, it started as a meme. There was an article about the Sotheby’s auction for a copy of the US Constitution, and some crypto people were making jokes of, “Oh, what if a bunch of crypto people got together and bought the Constitution?” Those jokes turned into being a little bit more serious, and there was then a Zoom call where half the people came in joking and the other half came in dead serious. And by the end of the Zoom call, it was decided, “Alright. We’re actually going to go after this thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0r4KNi"&gt;There’s precedent for crypto groups betting on auctions — PleasrDAO, for example, did a $4 million buy of a Wu-Tang Clan album — so we thought, “Alright. This is a significantly bigger number.” At the time we thought $20 million, but it’s in the realm of possibility. That’s when we started planning and organizing. We formed a Discord and a website. We started talking to museums and vendors. Literally seven days later, we had a representative at Sotheby’s bidding with an almost $50 million war chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sVbYdU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was your role in this organization?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uv4rX6"&gt;A lot of this was super vague and we were moving very fast. What I ended up specializing in was newbie onboarding: how do we teach people who are new to crypto how to get involved with this safely? We also had open Discord rooms where we were helping people troubleshoot. I also contributed a bit to marketing and some things strategically. What we found was that people were very flexible about moving all over the place to where they were needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HEWAXt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s funny. Newbie onboarding is why you’re on the show now, that’s me. I appreciate the expertise. When you’re talking to vendors, you obviously need banking partners. You have this partner called Endaoment — and it’s a great name; it’s “dao’’ in the middle, instead of “dow.” It’s perfect. That’s a lot of people trying to do a lot of things all at once. How did it actually come together? Did you not know that it was going to come together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqwwpH"&gt;We really didn’t know until the end. There were a lot of things happening, up in the air, and a lot of uncertainty. As we raised more money, our legitimacy became greater and greater with different institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aVUoWQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is very much an American story. The story of the United States of America is if you have more money, your legitimacy increases.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pBV6v3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The story of the United States of America is if you have more money, your legitimacy increases.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UtJe2B"&gt;Right. I think a lot of people got really curious. One of the most rewarding parts of this experience was the number of museums that we’re speaking to that now want to learn more. They saw us raise $40 to $50 million depending on the Ethereum price. They had said, “We take six months to raise this amount of money. Let’s talk: how do you do this?” Obviously, there were some very specific dynamics that were happening here, but they are very curious now about DAOs, about collective ownership, and all the different things that we explored with this organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bQhIuc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Were you more interested in the copy of the Constitution or the technology and the organizational speed run?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q2rB6p"&gt;I was interested in both parts of it. What really interested me was the story — there were so many people that were interested in this project for different reasons, and I’d encourage you to actually look at our fundraising site. We used a platform called Juicebox. People could leave messages of why they were contributing, and they wrote some really beautiful, heartfelt things: talking about how they were descendants of slaves and they were really excited to now own this document, despite some of the horrible things that were in it. Immigrants wrote in, as did parents who were excited to share this with their children one day. The different emotional stories that this project evoked in people was really the thing that pulled me in. I’m also very curious about the technology, but that’s the secondary factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="amBMUV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is interesting. During the swirl of activity in the seven days leading up to the auction, the auction itself, and the very rapid aftermath, we heard almost exclusively about the technology. We heard that this project had proven X, Y, and Z about crypto going mainstream, regarding DAOs. What I found very challenging was I heard very little about the Constitution. There’s only 13 copies of this thing floating around, and it seemed like the object was a meme. Like all internet jokes, there was an element of it which was just a troll. Did you think that was going to flip when you actually had to govern this copy of the Constitution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DMfYd9"&gt;I want to push back on that it was just a troll. I think there was legitimate excitement and curiosity around owning this document. A big part of the narrative was around the technology because it’s such a new thing. The technology is something that’s very misunderstood and people are still trying to wrap their heads around it, but all great technology exists for one reason: to enable people. That’s why I would say the people and their stories are what drove me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vRjhYH"&gt;But you’re right — the technology was really important because it drove the narrative. “Hey, these crazy crypto people are going to buy a copy of the US Constitution. What’s a DAO? Why are they raising ‘on chain’? What does ‘on chain’ mean?” Those two factors combined are what drove that narrative. The technology, yes, was a big part of it, but again — technology just enables humans to do better things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dtn0o3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The flip side of this is that people are spending money. I watched your education video on how to contribute. You recommended that people add $100 or $200 to what they’re willing to contribute just to pay for the gas fees, which are the transaction fees in the Ethereum network. That is real money for quite a lot of people in this country. Quite a lot have contributed, but the back half of the project really wasn’t plotted out. What do you think the next steps would have been after raising the money and winning the auction at Sotheby’s? What was supposed to happen after all that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7CzTnu"&gt;We had this idea of doing a 501(c)(3). None of it was hammered into stone, but the concrete plan was Endaoment was going to custody the document until we had a legal structure together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mG9r6o"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is my real question: your organization spends the money and you were just going to give it to another organization. That is a very complicated contractual relationship, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6h4ZYr"&gt;Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PhyINq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Were you going to write a contract with Endaoment to say, “We’re giving you custody of this document”? Were there lawyers on either side of that relationship?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dB1c5Q"&gt;This is — as we’ve discussed — a very highly experimental technology. This is something that we’ve done in a very lightweight fashion because it’s so new. This is something we’ve done in a very trustful way. Endaoment is very well-known within the crypto community, and I’m sure they wouldn’t want to risk their reputation on doing something negative. That’s the structure that drove this. In the future, I would love to see better legal structures that enable this sort of project. One of the biggest lessons of ConstitutionDAO is that the technology is so close, but we’re not fully ready yet. There’s a lot of rough edges that need to be sanded for this to have gone so much easier in two to five to 10 years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V4zcM0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sure, but is this a technology question? That’s what I keep coming back to. I understand it with payment rails and financialization, which right now basically operate on computers owned by banks. Let’s decentralize those computers — I can get from here to there. You have one of the 13 remaining  copies of the founding document of the country and you haven’t planned out what to do next. Technology doesn’t help you solve that problem, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UsPRb3"&gt;Right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IJTFhP"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Someone has to take it and store it and not ruin it. You have to make sure that happens the minute you take possession of the document. Who was going to do that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpNZBn"&gt;It’s both a technology question and a regulatory question. We had some partners that were ready to actually take physical custody of the documents. Sotheby’s was willing to hold it for an additional 30 days. One of the reasons we didn’t bid our full amount is because we knew we needed money for things along the lines of custodying the document, as well as paying fees and taxes. It’s both a question of regulation and technology as we figure out those structures. There are so many great organizations right now working with regulators to make this a lot easier. I’d say that’s one of the things that makes crypto different from a lot of the rest of the tech industry. There are organizations like Coin Center, the Blockchain Association, that are working very hard to get regulators to understand. A lot of this isn’t trying to convince regulators to let everything run buckwild and free, but rather, “Hey, let’s think very thoughtfully about what a really good policy framework looks like to keep the United States competitive while also keeping investors safe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qXuBzJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait — how do we get to regulators from what were you going to do with the Constitution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2qqj1g"&gt;So what I was saying is, it’s a problem of both technology and regulation, and trying to tie those two things together so we can figure out how an on-chain entity can hold onto a physical document from a very concrete—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PeWgrN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What part of that is regulated?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gbFlvL"&gt;There is not a clear vehicle for a DAO to interact with a real-world entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YXrB7c"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you raised a bunch of money in this DAO. Did you start an LLC? Forming one costs like $50.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C1RnJ8"&gt;Yeah. We had an LLC essentially as a backup if the relationship with Endaoment didn’t work out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yeyaCA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okay. So the DAO had the money, and it held the money on the blockchain in Ethereum. Were you going to transfer the money to Endaoment? Were you just going to give it to them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yR3pIG"&gt;We had the money in an FTX account that Sotheby’s used to verify proof of funds and Endaoment would bid on our behalf—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6xL6Gy"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That was the win-win. I’ll give you that one. Sotheby’s verified the money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EptWfK"&gt;Thank you. I appreciate that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hCDWaZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is a big deal; I don’t think Sotheby’s has done that before. I’m just curious about the actual steps: you had the money, and then you made the bid. If you had won the bid, what would have happened to the money next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j0AYWJ"&gt;It would go either from FTX directly to Sotheby’s or to Sotheby’s via Endaoment. I was not directly involved with that process. As I said, I was more involved on the newbie onboarding and the marketing side, so I don’t have an actual concrete answer there, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32Npwf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reason I’m asking so explicitly is that if I were a prospective investor thinking about giving this project money, “What happens next?” would be the question I would want the answer to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UxGoru"&gt;Totally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tLeKmh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who would have gotten the Constitution in the end? It seems like that part was not actually baked. You’re just the third party that I just have to trust. There is no software contract or standard legal contract that I can look at that says we’re going to transfer $47 million to Sotheby’s. And then, somehow, this middle organization — whose governance relationship to ConstitutionDAO is unclear — is going to get the Constitution, and then something else will happen. To me, that’s all just lawyer stuff: converting an LLC to a 501(c)(3), handing the document back. Did you have a budget for lawyers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1e60qU"&gt;Yeah, that was part of our budget, and you’re right — there was a lot of trust baked in here, but we were very transparent from the beginning that this is a very trustful process. This is not something that, at the point where we started, was fully decentralized. The core team was working as fast as we could towards progressive decentralization. We were very transparent with those trust assumptions from the start. People felt they could trust us, and they came along for the journey. We are really grateful for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gomtnv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You said when you started that about half the people thought it was a joke, and half the people were dead serious. Some people suggested burning the Constitution symbolically. What were the internal politics of this core group as this week went on?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="50Qw1h"&gt;There was plenty of internal politics. The thing I think was most interesting was the pace at which we moved and how that really bred trust, and how the fast pace meant that people really had to choose. If I’m committing to this project, who has control here? Who has the decision-making power? A lot of that was very often unclear. One thing that would very frequently happen is we would have a vote in our Discord, and you’d have maybe an hour in the core team to get your voice in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ed4r2p"&gt;Some of these were very big decisions. A lot of it was being in a very high-trust environment. There were a lot of newcomers that people didn’t know, but pretty much everyone had at least one person they had known previously, so it was this very loose network of people that were vaguely aware of each other that came together. The internal politics were mostly disagreements on direction. There was nothing actually truly political in the way that you get in a company, because everyone was so mission-driven and knew we just needed to get things done really fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ONKAUF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I just keep coming back to, the point of blockchain technology is to decentralize trust — to build trustless systems. A lot of our conversation has come back to how this was a high-trust environment between people, so I’m just trying to explore that tension.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LXOcc9"&gt;I think this goes back to the fact of the speed-run DAO infrastructure. We did use some great trustless technology like Juicebox, which led us through the fundraising. People were able to look at the Juicebox contracts, see how they worked. That part was really important to us. That was done in a contract. It wasn’t just a multi-sig for the fundraising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rCduR5"&gt;There are a couple of other features that were really important, but this goes back to the fact that we’re still early. This technology is still so new. People like to compare it to the early era of the internet in the 1990s. I think that’s pretty accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ALa90C"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you think software would actually change the politics of an organization? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MPwtm0"&gt;That’s a very broad question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Te5ui6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to make decisions. You’re voting in Discord. That changes the valence and speed of decision-making, I’m sure. For example, a DAO could work like a direct democracy, one token per vote — just the simplest framework to think about. You’re still going to get blocks of token holders politicking other blocks of token holders. You’re still going to get &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt7660850/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Succession&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-style investor meetings where you vote for leadership. How does this software actually change any of that outcome? Or are we just speedrunning to that outcome?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2kM6iH"&gt;For looking at the software, it’s actually better to look at more established DAOs because there’s some really interesting, innovative things that people are working on. There’s a DAO called Index Co-op that makes index funds: you can buy, for example, the DeFi Pulse Index, which has 20 different DeFi tokens. This organization is fully a DAO. The votes on which products to release, who manages the products, funds for marketing — all that sort of thing is managed on-chain. What they’re finding is that more complicated organizational structures are needed to be able to keep pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lHLk9u"&gt;A really interesting discussion in their forums recently led to an organizational change where Index Co-op now has what they call Wise Owls: council members who are dedicated to stepping in when there’s a lack of clarity and either figuring out a way to solve a problem, or bringing it to the person who can solve that problem. The thing that makes this really clear, and what’s really interesting with this software, is you can essentially define the hard capabilities of someone in an organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kcmKig"&gt;Can they call a certain function on a smart contract? Do they have control over a certain amount of funds in the treasury? Some of these more cutting-edge, more developed DAOs are much more interesting case studies for looking at this because they’ve been actively working on this for — in the example of Index Co-op — over a year with people working full-time on that project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EdHMZC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I find the whole thing fascinating, but at the end of the day, ConstitutionDAO is the one who raised all the money and got all of the attention. To me, that is the gap where I’m looking at the stats. For 5 percent of your donors, this project was their very first transaction with a [cryptocurrency] wallet. Almost half of your donors had under 40 transactions with a wallet. You brought a lot of people into the fold. That’s a lot of people trusting you with their money. What happens now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mm8ThA"&gt;You’re right. It’s a lot of people trusting us with their money. That’s why there were two things that were really important here: the first was transparency. We were upfront with everything that was going on throughout the process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PjHsj9"&gt;The second important thing was refunds. It’s a big reason that we chose the smart contract that we did for the fundraiser because it had that built-in refund functionality. We did exactly what we said we were going to do. We were going to raise money. We were going to bid in the auction. Had we lost, which we did, we were going to offer refunds. The refunds are available for people to claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shiMF1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s talk about the auction real quick, and then let’s get back to the refunds. You raised $47 million. Your max bid for the auction was $43 million. Sotheby’s had to verify that number for your max bid, and then they told you to hold some in reserve for taxes, fees, storage, and all of that. That’s how you got to $43 million. When did you know that $43 million was the max?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5OjPjl"&gt;It was very, very shortly before. We did our proof of funds about three hours before the auction. We were hoping to be able to continue fundraising throughout those last few hours, but totally understand that we had to go through the process of making sure that they could verify we had the money. This was something very new for Sotheby’s, and we’re really grateful that they chose to partner with us and work with us to verify these funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mm2nQD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ConstitutionDAO didn’t win. A famous billionaire investor who runs Citadel named Ken Griffin won the auction. He came in at $43.2 million, which is not that much more than what ConstitutionDAO raised. I imagine that’s quite frustrating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJTRXp"&gt;It is frustrating, but that’s the way the world is. If we can’t win based on our own merits, then I think we just need to work harder to build a stronger ecosystem. I see this as a moment of inspiration. I want to congratulate Ken. He has some really great plans to display the document to make it so people are able to see it and engage with it. I hope that after this, Ken also takes the opportunity to engage a little bit more deeply with what we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fhMper"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ken, if you’re listening — and I’m sure he is — reach out to Jonah. What was it like for you watching the auction?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wCY3zf"&gt;A group of us actually ended up getting together in New York to watch the auction together. It was exhilarating. Internally, we knew the name of the person who was bidding on our behalf, but obviously, we were not able to release that until after the results of the auction. During the auction, when the number was creeping up, I felt like I was going to puke. If we won, I might have cried. It was a very intense experience, especially after this crazy week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LcDNgM"&gt;One of the coolest parts was meeting a ton of people in person that I knew from the internet, which was such a fun experience. Even though we lost, people were sad for a little bit, but there was so much hope about what we accomplished. We got DAOs on some of the largest news publications in the world and taught people about this technology. We got all of these new people to actually try this. That’s a big part of new technology, especially with crypto: people often understand it better when they actually try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R6PrQB"&gt;One thing I like to think about as a student of the history of technology is the ways in which people adopt new tech — often, it’s because they have to. If you think about email, for example, a lot of people’s attitudes in the ’90s were basically, “Why would I use email? This is ridiculous.” Fast forward to the present, and it’s, “I’m going to get fired if I don’t use email because I’m not capable of doing my job.” By no means is ConstitutionDAO a project that everyone needs to participate in, but it’s a start that piques people’s curiosity. It gets more people asking, “What could I do with this thing?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2sJca2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think you introduced more people to crypto and DAOs or more people to the Constitution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dLNOX5"&gt;Definitely more people to crypto and DAOs. I think a lot of people knew what the Constitution was, and I think their interest was piqued because they were already familiar with the Constitution. I think people also really liked the Nick Cage memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E6JISv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They were very good. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4lTbnp"&gt;Oh, yeah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bTHxS4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There was a lot of confusion at the end of the auction. You knew the identity of the person bidding on ConstitutionDAO’s behalf, but the public didn’t. We had no idea who the bidders represented. Immediately, the Twitter space was full of cheering: “We won.” Where did that disconnect come from?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uIT9tZ"&gt;We don’t know exactly how that happened. Everyone on the core team was told not to post on social media until the official results were out. The people associated with that space were not affiliated with our team. This is some classic social media confusion that was happening there. It was really unfortunate because I saw some of the memes when people thought we’d won. There was so much joy, and it really felt like a bummer to get that official statement out. I think there’s a lot to still be optimistic and excited about. Unfortunately, people who are not affiliated with the team are going to do what they do on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dx1VOW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When did you find out? Since you knew who was bidding, did you know immediately?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aWXGDv"&gt;Yeah, we knew right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XMRn7Y"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the plan to release that information?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4QHLu"&gt;We were waiting for a final confirmation from Sotheby’s, and then we had an official statement that we released on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="70gFGd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have refunded about 55 percent of the money after some initial confusion about refunds. The whole project was going to get wound down, and refunds were going to happen in some way, but then there was some outcry, and you’ve changed that process. How are refunds working now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tvHhTp"&gt;Just to clarify here, we actually didn’t change it. We were exploring another avenue that we decided not to approach. And we went back to the original plan just because we felt like that was the simplest and safest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gWAfV3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me the difference between the two.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UEdRtp"&gt;We explored a few options, and actually hadn’t fully settled on one. The plan that we had was, essentially, redepositing the funds back into the contract on Juicebox. Then people were able to withdraw their refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RKKHsJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is what’s happening now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BOIeXM"&gt;Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xHvp0Q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the other plan that you explored that you decided against?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oCeKm0"&gt;The other options aren’t really worth getting into the details, but we essentially decided that all of them had sufficient technical risk. With technical risk comes the risk that we lose people’s money, and that is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LINJwe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the challenges now is that people have paid $100 in gas fees to donate $100. Now they might have to pay $100 in gas fees to get their $100 back. Some people have already paid more to get their money back than they put in. Isn’t this one of the core challenges of this entire project — that the transaction fees actually outweigh everything else that it has accomplished?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7bR7Fu"&gt;This is a really important criticism. The fee issue is something we were transparent with from the start. We were telling people, “Hey, the gas fee is part of it. There is this transaction fee, and another  transaction fee for refunds.” People were aware of that. It’s part of any new technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mPsmkA"&gt;It reminds me of a story that’s very near to my heart about &lt;a href="https://iwataasks.nintendo.com/interviews/#/ds/pokemon/0/2"&gt;Nintendo’s Satoru Iwata&lt;/a&gt;. Iwata was developing the &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Gold&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Silver&lt;/em&gt; games. &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Gold&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Silver&lt;/em&gt; had two different broad areas to explore. The cartridges they used at that time were very constrained in terms of storage. In the software world, there’s a legendary story of Iwata basically figuring out a way to do compression that fit both of these regions into that cartridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7InfV3"&gt;That’s the era we’re in right now with crypto. We still haven’t gotten all of the scalability and all of the bandwidth figured out yet. Right now, we’re still in those early days of trying to pack in as much as we can at the lowest fee cost. That’s part of technology. A lot of things start off as a slightly worse experience than the technology of the day. But as the tech improves over time, it becomes significantly better. Another example of this I bet we’ll also see in the upcoming years is self-driving cars — worse than a human now, but eventually I hope to never drive a car again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ej8bSC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m with you. We talk a lot about self-driving cars on the show, but you’re in the here and now. The idea that technology will get better with time does not solve the problem of someone who was in love with the idea of buying the Constitution is now out $200 in fees because they gave you 50 bucks. How do you solve the problem for that person?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yXhRus"&gt;That’s why there was transparency from the start. It’s unfortunate. I wish there could have been lower fees. There are scaling solutions, but they didn’t have the contract with that refund feature, which was really important to us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T2mNHc"&gt;We felt like we needed to be super transparent from the start, especially when we were just targeting people that are what we call crypto-native. They understand that fees are part of it. For those that weren’t crypto-native, that’s why we wanted to make it very clear in our education that there will be fees that are part of using the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cYSOk1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You refunded about 55 percent of the money. We have all the great stats about the people who contributed for the first time or close to their first time. Were the same first-time wallets requesting refunds? Is the 45 percent of funds left over from your first-time donors? That, to me, would be very telling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UZvPgC"&gt;I wish I had those stats for you. The dashboard that we had for who contributed how was a community-built dashboard. That’s one of the really cool things about this technology: someone who’s totally unaffiliated was actually just able to pull the blockchain data and make this dashboard on what’s going on. I’m sure it wasn’t as exciting for that person to do the refund dashboard. They did a little bit, but didn’t put details on who and how much per wallet and that sort of thing. There was an overall refund dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fUW059"&gt;So we don’t have that data, unfortunately, but I do think the fact that it wasn’t even someone on our team, it wasn’t someone affiliated — there’s just a third party that wanted access to this data. Because it was publicly on the blockchain, they could share it with us and with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="et2LV7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But doesn’t this issue sort of implicate everything we’ve been talking about? This is all about trust, transparency, and accountability. In the mad scramble of things to do, building dashboards is always the lowest level of priority. I understand that, but at some point, knowing who your donors are and taking care of the newest ones should have risen up that priority chain, right? Did you think, “We should go figure out who the people we introduce to crypto were, to make sure they feel taken care of, because that is the big victory of this project right now”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MRQLzb"&gt;That’s why we’ve still been active in the Discord, providing support to people who are trying to figure out how to do this. The dashboard would be great, I agree, but I’d rather engage with people directly who are asking me — both individually and direct messages and in the general Discord — “Hey, I’m struggling to do this. Can you help?” Or, “I’m not sure if the fund’s transferred out. Can you check?” It’s nice to have a dashboard that we can share with other people, but I would much rather work with those individuals to actually get them those refunds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TxigMQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forty-five percent of the money is sitting there. That number has trailed off, at least when I looked at the dashboard right before we started recording. It seems like you hit 55 percent refunds and that number has just stayed there for several days. Why do you think that is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="um2wxH"&gt;I think part of it is the gas fees, as we were talking about. Part of it is people not paying attention as much. A lot of people in the crypto world move very fast and they miss things — mostly people who are crypto natives. They’ve got 50 different things that they’re paying attention to at once. I expect that, over time, the number will continue tapering off, but there’s a lot of people in crypto who are just throwing bets everywhere and seeing what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="skwmrD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$20 million of “let’s see what happens” money in the bank right now, or on the chain?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WqI0GD"&gt;To clarify, I think the gas fees are a big part of it. I don’t think their attitude is “let’s see what happens,” but rather they’re not paying attention or haven’t made the time to do it yet. It’s very exciting. You want to jump right in when there’s excitement around donating to buy a copy of the Constitution but claiming a refund is not as fun, so I think people are in less of a rush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5hqd3q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A classic business model is to make people claim their refunds. I don’t think that’s what you’re doing, but—&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5wQ8n9"&gt;No. We don’t have access to those funds either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0HGMGX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you going to do if, five years from now,  there is still money in the wallet? The price of Ethereum moves quite a bit. Five years from now, if that 45 percent of ConstitutionDAO’s money is still there, it could be worth $50 million again. What’s the plan?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tuHhos"&gt;Those refunds will be available indefinitely. The smart contract is on the chain and it can’t be modified, so someone could come back 20 years from now and say, “Oh, I realized I still had funds here. I want to pull them out.” I expect a lot of the tooling to get better. One thing that’s really popular nowadays is those apps that tell you how many subscriptions you’re subscribing to that you don’t know about. We’re going to start to see that with a lot of blockchain-based things, because people are going to realize they have money in nooks and crannies all over the place that weren’t worth a lot when they first put it in there. Then, way down the line, you realize, “Oh, I should really go grab this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Okj1x0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A secondary market for the $PEOPLE token has already developed. That seems very strange because this secondary market is not related to an ongoing organization. What do you make of that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9cuKS"&gt;When we were choosing which platform we were going to use, there were a series of tradeoffs we had to make. We really wanted to optimize for refunds. Part of that was choosing Juicebox — it has the token and you can claim the token even if we don’t win the auction. That was not something that we had advised people to do. We were telling people just to claim their refunds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OMiCAv"&gt;With the blockchain, you can’t really stop people. It is nothing that’s affiliated with the team anymore and we’re sunsetting the project. It’s something that exists out there, but not something we’ve been endorsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="33M6Fv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have a sense of why people are building a secondary market for this token?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="31X5MT"&gt;People like the memes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kbHC7x"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You think that’s it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hVVCm0"&gt;Yeah. People like the memes; they like to have fun. I think that one thing that I’ve learned from exploring the crypto world is that it’s very hard to rationalize a lot of the different momentums — things that happen with memes and with the memetic transfer of information. I think if people are having fun and they’re doing their thing, then I don’t try to interpret it too deeply, because I’m just going to break my brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="govatd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is where I want to end it. We’ve discussed a lot of really big ideas here. I think it is fundamentally cool that people tried to raise a lot of money to buy a copy of the Constitution. At the end of the day, though, the internet has always been good at firing a bazooka of money at things.  You can go back to the ice bucket challenge. When people fired a bazooka of money at the ALS Association, they were not necessarily ready for it. You hoped they would do good things with it and that they actually invested in that research — and &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.als.org/stories-news/ice-bucket-challenge-dramatically-accelerated-fight-against-als"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thankfully, in this case, they did&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kKoLxJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The layer on top of this dynamic is financializing that bazooka of internet money in extremely surprising ways — ways that move with a momentum that breaks my brain, too. Do you think that’s good? Now there is a secondary market of a token that was meant to govern the physical copy of a Constitution but now it’s just playing in the wreckage of this project. Something about that doesn’t seem great — it actually cuts against your goals. I’m wondering if you think about that tension.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tWnioh"&gt;It’s a really good philosophical question and a very good concrete question. My belief is that people will do what they can, and they are going to be curious and they’re going to try things. I think it’s our job as a society to figure out what we want to come out of that — and what things we don’t want to come out of that. It is interesting to be pushing the boundaries; I’m not talking about this case specifically, but with how we can repackage and organize information and value and governance and all those mechanisms. It’s going to take some time to figure out what the right thing is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DIv1hG"&gt;That’s one thing I’ve actually really appreciated about the way that the US government is approaching crypto regulation, compared to some other governments. The US government is giving the industry some space to breathe. They’re saying, “Alright, let’s watch what’s happening in the depths here. We’ll try to understand this more limited group of people who know they’re getting into a very highly risky asset class. What are we going to learn from this smaller group?” I do want to emphasize again that what we were doing was a donation for governance — voting on the future of this document. How can we make this document something that’s governed by the people? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpqwFg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You introduced a lot of people to these concepts for the first time. Now some of them have taken their refunds, some of them are waiting on gas fees, and some of them are just happy to have participated. What do you think the takeaway for that group of people should be? Is it that they can spend money on cool meme things with a community attached? Or should they be more interested in this project as a new instrument of fundamentally corporate governance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wTOuow"&gt;I think it’s the latter. What things do you want to happen in the world and how do you make that happen? Is this the right tool set? There’s been a proliferation already of really interesting DAOs that are doing lots of exciting projects. A few examples: there’s a DAO that’s now working on prison reform. There’s another that’s working on how to create more public scientific research. There’s one that’s acquired another document: anti-slavery documents from US history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w39ZMf"&gt;We’re already starting to see the effects of this. In the long term, we’re going to see more DAOs for people who are trying to accomplish goals that don’t fit in the structure of a company or a nonprofit, but more of a community collective. We’re going to see lots of people take the lessons from what we did and build better tooling and better best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gKqx0R"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s end where you started: the interface between the crypto world and the DAO community world and the real world is not yet built out. I understand why it is happening in financial institutions first. That is all just computer stuff. Literally, we just had an Excel influencer on the show: most of that industry is people using Excel or computers to do things. You can automate and reconstitute those contracts on decentralized databases right away.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SNSlgb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you are talking about prison reform — that is bodies in the world. That is not computer work. What do you think are the next steps between DAOs coming together to form governance collectives and impacting the real world? What is the next most important step?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UKP6AZ"&gt;There’s a few things that a DAO can actually do today. The thing we need to bridge the gap with is figuring out what a smart contract can actually control, because that’s the source of a DAO’s power. For a lot of DAOs today, the majority of what they do is just sending treasury funds; $20 million to start a crypto lobbying group. That is a real world example from Uniswap, a decentralized exchange that had a vote to start this crypto lobbying group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zr51Ed"&gt;However, I think that over time we can build out more functionality for the powers of DAOs — both from the voting power, what the actual token holders can vote on, but also elected representatives who the DAO gives very specific, concrete and auditable powers to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cKA372"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I feel like I could go another hour on this. I really want to know if the lobbyist now gets to pick what steak restaurant they take elected officials to. Can the DAO vote on that? That would be really interesting, but you’ve given us so much time. What is next for you? What is next for the core members of the ConstitutionDAO group?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oqot4z"&gt;ConstitutionDAO is finishing, shutting down official activities, refunds are going. Everyone’s dispersing to different projects. I have a day job as a software engineer at a very different — but I would say just as exciting — part of the tech industry. People are working on what they’ve been working on, but I expect we’ll see more from this group in the future. It was really incredible. I’d say one of the best parts of this experience is I made some new friends. It’s really fun when you can call up people you know from the internet and say, “Hey, do you want to go hang out? Do you want to go grab a coffee?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7NKhno"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s great. Jonah, thank you so much for coming on &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decoder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. I pushed you a little bit. Thank you for engaging. I really appreciate it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="uHA38e"&gt;Nilay, thank you for having me. This has been a great experience and glad to be on this journey of understanding crypto with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VIJVxi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Decoder with Nilay Patel","description":"A podcast from The Verge about big ideas and other problems.","label":"Subscribe now!","url":"https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/decoder-with-nilay-patel/id1011668648?i=1000496212371"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22820563/constitution-meme-47-million-crypto-crowdfunding-blockchain-ethereum-constitution"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22820563/constitution-meme-47-million-crypto-crowdfunding-blockchain-ethereum-constitution</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T10:10:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T10:10:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Now you can listen to recorded Twitter Spaces on iOS, Android, and the web</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UxlnzQu1lm4f73JdRQSFN7wt4-w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239539/acastro_170726_1777_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZXqSj3"&gt;Twitter is now letting all users across iOS, Android, and web listen to recordings of Spaces, which can come in handy for listeners who are late to a live broadcast. This comes after Clubhouse &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702034/clubhouse-recording-in-app-clip-tool-update"&gt;rolled out recordings for its audio-only chatrooms&lt;/a&gt; in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HHAIMN"&gt;Twitter is also giving “some” hosts the ability to record Spaces on iOS and Android. Previously, only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750341/twitter-spaces-recording-feature-sharing-option"&gt;iOS users could listen to and record Spaces&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ht6EC8"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Some updates on recorded Spaces:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;▪️ The option to record a Space is available for some hosts on both iOS and Android.&lt;br&gt;▪️ The option to listen to a recording of a Space is available for everyone on iOS, Android, and now web!&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1467986249852063748?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="evB0cU"&gt;Hosts can start recording a Space by toggling on the “Record Space” option. When recording is enabled, a (REC) icon will appear for the host and participants — listeners will see the icon, too, although they won’t be displayed in the recording. After the Space ends, hosts can see how many people were in the Space and tweet out a link to the recording. Hosts can choose the time that the Space starts playing as well, allowing hosts to edit out any silence at the beginning of the recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="esTnrn"&gt;On &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/spaces-hosting"&gt;Twitter’s help center&lt;/a&gt;, the platform notes that recordings will be publicly available when a recording-enabled Space ends. The only way to make a recording private is to delete it. Keep in mind that Twitter holds onto recordings for 30 to 120 days to check for rule violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zrp5v7"&gt;Twitter has been continually expanding its audio-only chatrooms since the feature’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22187490/twitter-spaces-test-voice-chat-rooms"&gt;launch in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. In September, Twitter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691761/twitter-adds-spaces-topics-limited-android"&gt;started letting hosts add up to three Topics to their Spaces&lt;/a&gt;, such as Music, Gaming, and Entertainment, giving listeners the ability to find Spaces that align with their interests. It also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/27/22644283/twitter-ticketed-spaces-live-audio-test"&gt;started launching Ticketed Spaces on iOS&lt;/a&gt; for hosts to charge listeners for entry and later began offering a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724450/twitter-spaces-accelerator-spark-clubhouse-creators"&gt;Spaces accelerator program&lt;/a&gt; that provides creators with resources to promote their Spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822078/twitter-spaces-recorded-ios-android-web"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822078/twitter-spaces-recorded-ios-android-web</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Mess Comes Home</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F3XUfEsaAbYOZOQDuWlIeO6mfwg=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239445/VERGE_LEAD.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDk8Qx"&gt;When Infosys announced construction on its &lt;a href="https://www.indystar.com/story/news/politics/2018/04/27/mike-pence-infosys-jobs-indianapolis-campus/556359002/"&gt;planned headquarters in Indianapolis&lt;/a&gt; in 2018, it was a coup for the Trump administration. Although few have heard of the company today, Infosys is an IT firm best known for outsourcing jobs from the US to India in the ’80s and ’90s, the same sort of company Trump targeted &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/02/us/politics/transcript-trump-immigration-speech.html"&gt;during his campaign&lt;/a&gt; and through &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/04/trumps-executive-order-wont-give-tech-clarity-h-1b-visas/"&gt;executive orders&lt;/a&gt; as president. Good American jobs were being moved overseas by firms like Infosys, according to Trump. Now, they would be bringing &lt;a href="https://www.indystar.com/story/money/2018/04/26/infosys-campus-jobs-indianapolis-mike-pence-eric-holcomb-joe-hogsett/550067002/"&gt;3,000&lt;/a&gt; jobs to Indiana and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/02/business/infosys-hire-10000-american-workers.html"&gt;10,000 jobs&lt;/a&gt; nationwide — well-paying tech jobs at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MwyCKK"&gt;For Infosys’ president, Ravi Kumar, the new headquarters was just one part of a larger project to revitalize the American dream. “The American dream is all about, ‘I could start anywhere, but I could be a CEO of a company or I could literally reach the top of the ladder as long as I have the capability and potential,’” Kumar told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. He outlined an ambitious plan to not just hire entry-level workers but &lt;a href="https://www.theweek.in/news/biz-tech/2018/04/27/infosys-announces-new-training-center-in-indianapolis-to-create-ik-additional-jobs.html"&gt;train them, too&lt;/a&gt;, in partnership with Indiana’s Purdue University, as well as colleges across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j2YSq8"&gt;One of Infosys’ many recruits was Josh, who joined the company at the height of the pandemic after graduating college. (The names of the Infosys employees quoted in this article have been changed to protect their anonymity, out of fear of retaliation.) But although Infosys hired Josh and paid for his salary, it’s difficult to say that Josh &lt;em&gt;worked&lt;/em&gt; for the company. Instead, he spent much of his time at Infosys on what the company referred to as the Bench. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SKmUwx"&gt;Infosys is a consulting firm and assigns employees to specific clients. When Infosys has more employees than it needs for its clients, those spare employees end up on the Bench, where they are, in effect, paid to do nothing. And as Infosys has ramped up its hiring of American workers, many of those workers found themselves getting paid to not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ebpP0d"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It feels like I am being wasted, I could be doing more, and I’m not”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="mCtkIe"&gt;At first, being on the Bench had its perks, particularly for Josh, who worked remotely due to the pandemic. “I ended up playing a lot of video games,” he said. But his time on the Bench began to wear on him for reasons he found difficult to describe to his family and friends. “It was really hard to explain to them why I felt like it was a bad thing,” Josh said. “They were just like… ‘Well, you’re getting paid to do nothing, how could that be bad? That sounds like a dream job.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEh2N4"&gt;Far from a dream job, Josh found his time on the Bench to be quite stressful. Infosys said that the company would place him on a client project, but Josh didn’t know when that would happen or whether the project would involve the software engineering skills he learned in college. “They don’t keep you up to date on a daily basis,” Josh said. “Sometimes, you can go for a week without hearing them, so you have no sense if any progress is being made toward getting you on a project.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2Hph7"&gt;Josh spent a total of six months on the Bench, during which he constantly checked his computer to see if he had been assigned a project. “While you’re on the Bench, your one job is to respond when people try and contact you,” Josh said. “Days can go by where there’s nothing coming from the laptop or the phone that you need to respond to, and yet you feel kind of chained to it. There’s a good chance that you could be called or sent an email that says you have an interview in four hours. That was what happened to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ryKElg"&gt;Josh was relatively lucky. He was eventually placed on a project, and although the work was what he described as “bottom-rung type of labor,” it was at least a software development project, meaning he got to stick with what he studied in college. Not everyone who worked at Infosys could say the same. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; interviewed 15 current and former Infosys workers, who all asked to remain anonymous due to fear of retaliation from their employers. The experiences they described were varied, in part due to opaque Infosys policies that were applied inconsistently for different employees. Some described moving across the country in search of assignments, while others were put on projects that were completely unrelated to the skillsets they had been hired for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xIs5vM"&gt;But one common experience for many Infosys employees is the Bench. And while the Bench might have benefits in the short term, the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AZpvJibVZSY"&gt;Infoscions&lt;/a&gt;, as the company’s employees are called, are keenly aware that spending too long on the Bench might damage their career prospects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="s6YFOQ"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TG4wBO"&gt;“Whether or not you like sitting around and doing nothing and collecting a paycheck, at some point, it’s going to end, and when that ends, somebody is going to ask you what you did during that period of employment,” Josh said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OQLYwC"&gt;By most accounts, Infosys’ pivot to hiring American workers has been a success. In 2020, Infosys announced that it had exceeded its initial goal and had &lt;a href="https://www.infosys.com/newsroom/press-releases/2020/american-jobs-commitment.html"&gt;hired 13,000 employees&lt;/a&gt; nationwide. Then, in the midst of a pandemic at the time, Infosys made a commitment to hiring an &lt;a href="https://www.infosys.com/newsroom/press-releases/2020/american-jobs-commitment.html"&gt;additional 12,000 employees&lt;/a&gt; to bring the total to 25,000. Unlike other tech companies, the hires weren’t experienced programmers but were typically recent college graduates or workers for whom Infosys would be their first tech job. “We strongly believed that we could train anybody who has the potential, aptitude, and the attitude,” Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cDb3A5"&gt;But for the new hires, many of whom had recently graduated from an education system that teaches young people to tie their self-worth to their job, it was hard to see Infosys as a reincarnation of the American dream. Entering the workplace but not working felt infantilizing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0En2K1"&gt;To Josh, working at Infosys felt “almost like I never really graduated.” Like the practice assignments he had done in school, his time on the Bench felt devoid of the responsibility he thought would come with a full-time job. “It does really mess with your sense of being an adult,” Josh said. “The money isn’t really the main part of it that felt weird to me. It’s just the lack of responsibility.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BveMLp"&gt;The Bench was taking an emotional, almost existential toll on him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mygfn0"&gt;“It feels like I am being wasted, I could be doing more, and I’m not,” Josh said. “That’s the part that feels bad. I want to do things, but I can’t.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XwwP1H"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f3CjsMLLdnyY8HENXLwezm5gBGk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067492/CHAIN_SPOT.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="9spM5B"&gt;Founded in &lt;a href="https://www.infosys.com/about/history.html"&gt;1981&lt;/a&gt; and headquartered in Bangalore, India, Infosys has become &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2005/04/03/magazine/its-a-flat-world-after-all.html"&gt;synonymous with globalization&lt;/a&gt;. The company allowed corporations in the US to employ lower-cost workers remotely, &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20080506084241/http://www.time.com/time/specials/2007/article/0,28804,1652689_1652372_1652367,00.html"&gt;pioneering &lt;/a&gt;a business model &lt;a href="https://story.californiasunday.com/infosys-india-tech/"&gt;known as&lt;/a&gt; the “global delivery model” or, more informally, “your mess for less.” The model split the tech industry in two: the more complex jobs would be done in the US by highly skilled and highly paid engineers, while the jobs companies didn’t care about went overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="40xeqU"&gt;The key to Infosys’ success in India was its ability to hire entry-level workers and train them for software engineering jobs. “Even today, no company has training like we have at Infosys,” said company founder Narayana Murthy in &lt;a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=8GstDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PT55&amp;amp;lpg=PT55&amp;amp;dq=%22Even+today,+no+company+has+training+like+we+had+at+Infosys.+We+take+people+through+eight+months+of+training.+We+have+the+world%27s+largest+training+facility%22&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=VkHzcYn8OU&amp;amp;sig=ACfU3U3VIzMcnotmt6G2cuAZHSJbQ-Tpmg&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiK1PzL3qbyAhUtn-AKHbXBDl4Q6AF6BAgCEAM#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22Even%20today%2C%20no%20company%20has%20training%20like%20we%20had%20at%20Infosys.%20We%20take%20people%20through%20eight%20months%20of%20training.%20We%20have%20the%20world's%20largest%20training%20facility%22&amp;amp;f=false"&gt;a history of innovation in India&lt;/a&gt;. “We have the world’s largest training facility; nobody else in the world has anything like this.” (Infosys’ record &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/saritharai/2014/01/08/indias-top-outsourcing-firm-tcs-building-worlds-largest-corporate-training-facility/?sh=6e79614032d3"&gt;has since been taken by TCS&lt;/a&gt;, a different Indian outsourcing company.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q04K2J"&gt;The emphasis on training made sense because many of the jobs companies were outsourcing were jobs that previously would have been given to entry-level employees. “One of the funny things is that we, as a country, essentially fueled the technology rise of India, of China, of Eastern Europe,” said Jacob Hsu, the CEO of the US-based staffing firm Catalyte who previously was the CEO of the international staffing firm Symbio. “A lot of that was driven because we sent a lot of the entry-level work overseas.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ao3JF"&gt;Another key to the model: salaries in India were much lower than they were in the United States. But wages in countries like India have been &lt;a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/rising-salaries-may-dent-it-rd-offshoring-to-india/articleshow/3337964.cms"&gt;gradually&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://supplychaindigital.com/supply-chain-2/india-no-longer-cheapest-outsourcing-location"&gt;increasing&lt;/a&gt;, and the math of the “labor arbitrage” that previously made moving to India a no-brainer is slowly making less and less sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T8bAUl"&gt;But even if labor costs no longer give offshoring the same advantages it had decades ago, the model of “your mess for less,” or of giving undesirable tasks to other companies, still holds sway in corporate America. It’s just that today, that mess for less can be done with American labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8TTHf2"&gt;Previously, Infosys preferred not to hire Americans at all. The company was a frequent sponsor of the H-1B visa, which allowed the company to bring its Indian employees to the US. The visa came with a number of conditions: companies needed to pay their employees a &lt;a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/h-1b-visas-and-prevailing-wage-levels/"&gt;prevailing wage&lt;/a&gt;, and employees needed to meet &lt;a href="https://www.uscis.gov/working-in-the-united-states/h-1b-specialty-occupations"&gt;minimum educational requirements&lt;/a&gt;. In 2020, Infosys’ 3,528 H-1B visas placed it second on the &lt;a href="https://www.epi.org/blog/the-h-1b-visa-program-remains-the-outsourcing-visa-more-than-half-of-the-top-30-h-1b-employers-were-outsourcing-firms/"&gt;list of the companies&lt;/a&gt; that had the most H-1B visas approved. The company in first place, Amazon, is an American tech company, but “more than half” of the top 30 H-1B sponsors were outsourcing firms that competed with Infosys, &lt;a href="https://www.epi.org/blog/the-h-1b-visa-program-remains-the-outsourcing-visa-more-than-half-of-the-top-30-h-1b-employers-were-outsourcing-firms/"&gt;according to one report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XSSw3c"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxiE1q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cJdJ4h"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We are continuing to do what we are doing in spite of the fact that there is a new administration in the US”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="ECfqdr"&gt;It’s unclear whether staffing firms like Infosys are using the H-1B visa for the reasons it was originally intended for. The H-1B visa was created in 1990 to “bring in high-skilled workers who could complement the skills of US workers,” said Julia Gelatt, a senior policy analyst at the Migration Policy Institute. “The sense at the time was that there were growing industries in the United States in areas that the US wanted to develop to be globally competitive, but there weren’t necessarily enough US workers who [were] qualified and ready to fill those jobs.” Whether the work that companies outsource to firms like Infosys is aligned with the original intention of the H-1B visa program is somewhat up for debate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i38ZZh"&gt;On one hand, the jobs often require college degrees and some technical knowledge; on the other, many of the Infosys employees interviewed by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; saw the positions as menial and certainly entry-level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nW19ZJ"&gt;Infosys has run into trouble with visa rules. In 2013, the company &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edtx/pr/indian-corporation-pays-record-amount-settle-allegations-systemic-visa-fraud-and-abuse"&gt;settled a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; with the US Department of Justice, which alleged that Infosys had obtained visas for its foreign workers through “systematic fraud,” specifically by bringing workers to the US under a B-1 visa instead of an H-1B visa. The distinction matters because while B-1 visa holders are allowed to enter the country and attend meetings, they &lt;a href="https://www.ice.gov/news/releases/indian-corporation-pays-record-34-million-fine-settle-allegations-systemic-visa-fraud"&gt;aren’t actually allowed to perform work&lt;/a&gt; in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ESWZPZ"&gt;But Infosys’ three-decade reliance on the H-1B visas came under siege during the Trump administration, which instituted &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/22/us/politics/trump-h1b-work-visas.html"&gt;new rules&lt;/a&gt; in 2020 targeting the visa program. And while those rules were &lt;a href="https://www.law360.com/articles/1422263/calif-federal-court-strikes-down-trump-era-h-1b-lottery-rule"&gt;struck down by the courts&lt;/a&gt;, the Trump administration did drag their feet when it came to approving new visas for Infosys and other competitors, a trend that &lt;a href="https://www.deccanherald.com/business/business-news/h1b-visa-approval-rates-for-infosys-staff-has-risen-significantly-says-coo-999323.html"&gt;only reversed&lt;/a&gt; when Biden took office. “There certainly was a lot more scrutiny being applied to H-1B applications, and that was particularly true of some of the outsourcing firms,” said Gelatt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B90JaQ"&gt;According to Infosys, the Trump era visa restrictions were tangential to the company’s expansion in the US. “We are continuing to do what we are doing in spite of the fact that there is a new administration in the US,” Kumar told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, Kumar said, the change was driven by Infosys’ clients, who wanted their contractors to be closer to home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XSSw3c"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cQvPMv"&gt;To meet their aggressive hiring goals, rather than hiring expensive experienced engineers, Infosys returned to their roots and invested in training. “Since 2017, we’ve been very aggressively growing as a company, so we need talent,” Kumar said. “The only way you can get talent is to build it if there is not enough available in the market.” The training isn’t cheap; Infosys spends $25,830 on every employee they hire from college, Kumar told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, which funds a formal two-month training program, as well as project-based training for an additional three months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o8XTkg"&gt;Once employees join the company, they then enter a corporate environment where moving up the ladder is not only allowed but encouraged. As an example, Kumar cited more lucrative consulting positions, which he said were often filled internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UlpCYk"&gt;This flexibility, according to Kumar, is part of what allows the outsourcing firm to embody the American dream. “If we want to create social upward mobility in jobs, we will have to create these reskilling bridges, so people can start at the bottom, but they can transition to high potential jobs,” Kumar said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VBtWO8"&gt;The very same flexibility, Infosys employees say, is part of what makes the company a challenging and, in some cases, disappointing place to work for. One employee, Stuart, was hired by the company to be a business analyst, and Infosys even paid him to attend a short-term training program to learn how to be one. “It was very hands-on. It was enjoyable,” Stuart said of the training. “I learned a lot. I felt excited to become a business analyst.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MD9jPG"&gt;But that enthusiasm faded when Stuart finished his training and was promptly put on the Bench. “Eventually, you see people bringing in a deck of cards to work,” Stuart said. “There’s no supervision; there’s nothing to do; there’s no projects to get on, but we’re required to be there.” So when a position finally opened up, Stuart took it, even though it wasn’t the business analyst role he had trained for. It was an IT support desk project, a position he described as “being a call center employee.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dxiE1q"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Uq1bqi"&gt;The project gave him steady work, but paradoxically, Stuart found that the new project made it harder to look for a job other than at Infosys. “I now have nominally two years of experience in IT, but I definitely don’t have two years of business analyst experience,” Stuart said. “People don’t view me as having enough experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WirhNX"&gt;Ultimately, Stuart and other Infosys employees questioned whether the flexibility Infosys offered was actually a good thing. “People sometimes talk about a job versus a career, and right now, I have a job,” Stuart said. “A career is: ‘I have a vision of this leads to that leads to that, and it’s something that I want to do for the next 40 years.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UpmX0L"&gt;For some, rather than revitalizing the American dream, Infosys might instead be strangling it. Kumar acknowledged that Infosys’ model of a career might look different from a career where workers could expect job stability but said that this shift was an inevitable consequence of technological innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JXKBd3"&gt;“We are out of this era where for the first 20-plus years, we went to school, and the next 50 years or so, we went to a corporate job, and we recycle everything we did in the first 20 years for the next 50 years,” Kumar told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “In the digital age, when skills are so short-lived, you should be on a lifelong learning continuum all your life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JLj1c5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N4KviRFYw4HbiySCb93HA713Nus=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069885/Divider_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="ZdxDb7"&gt;Infosys’ career flexibility assumes that Infosys’ employees can find work to do in the first place. But as Infosys has ramped up its hiring in the US, some of its employees have found themselves on the Bench for an extended period of time. They are, in effect, paid to do nothing while Infosys attempts to put them on a project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YcT1vh"&gt;Adding to the uncertainty around the Bench was a perceived lack of communication about how the Bench even worked. “It felt like none of us really had a good grasp on what was going on,” said Josh. “There wasn’t a whole lot of communication about it, and if we asked about it, then we didn’t really get very many details.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSVsyx"&gt;For those familiar with how consulting firms work, the Bench is not a new concept, and companies like Infosys report their efficiency metrics in their quarterly reports. “Our utilization rates are one of the highest in the industry,” Kumar said. He explained reasons why a worker might be on the Bench for an extended period of time but ultimately conceded: “In some ways, it’s our responsibility to get them on to projects.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yEEOCw"&gt;One employee described the Bench as a convenient way to get &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt; projects. George, who joined the company after graduating college, saw getting put on the Bench as “kind of awesome.” Unlike many other Infosys employees, George was quickly assigned to a project, but he found the work unpleasant. “They assign you completely menial, completely trivial stuff for you to do,” he said, describing assignments where he translated code from one programming language to another. “There’s not really much to learn.” One day, George decided not to show up to work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ATGqj4"&gt;“No one noticed for almost an entire month,” he said. “I was just at home literally doing nothing.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4bgklC"&gt;Eventually, the Infosys managers caught on and called George into the office to explain himself. After a contentious discussion about the importance of George’s job — “I was gone for an entire month, and nobody noticed at all, so you can’t really tell me what I was doing mattered,” he recalled saying — George asked them to put him on the Bench. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27mvro"&gt;“I heard stories of the Bench, and it was just a limbo place you could be in between assigned roles at Infosys where they paid you, and you didn’t have to do anything,” he said. “Honestly, it sounded wonderful. It sounded like what I was already doing for the past month.” The managers agreed and put him on the Bench, asking him not to show up to the office. George rode out his Bench time from home, which he did, for months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="T0Hr3a"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oJXXWQ"&gt;George used his free time to prepare for job interviews. He was eventually terminated by Infosys, but within a few months, he landed a position at “great company,” one where he could do meaningful work and that paid him enough for him to “achieve the lifestyle that I wanted, that I was told a software engineer was supposed to have.” But finding the time to prepare for these positions meant standing strong when Infosys asked him to relocate to client projects in different states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lrSmq"&gt;“I was in a unique position in that I was willing to put my foot down despite the threat of termination,” George said. “For others that I had met that were not willing to go that far, they were basically forced to go wherever.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TxqAHA"&gt;One of the unusual elements of a job at Infosys is that employees were sometimes encouraged to relocate to a different state if they are unable to be assigned to a project. In some cases, this encouragement can involve the threat of termination. According to an email obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, employees on the Bench were told that “[l]ocation preference requests cannot be guaranteed as described in your Employment letter” and that “[r]efusal to take assignments during Bench will be reviewed for appropriate disciplinary action up to and including termination.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aEMQZW"&gt;Although Infosys did not appear to have a consistent policy around terminating people for being on the Bench for too long, it is a real threat. In the same email, employees were told that “[y]our time on Bench will be tracked (also referred to as ‘Bench aging’) and therefore it is essential that you make efforts to find a billable position and come off Bench as soon as possible.” While not every employee interviewed by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; seemed to have been affected by Bench aging, two workers were fired for that very reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LICvpa"&gt;For some, Infosys’ flexibility around which office employees could work from was a positive. Infosys has various offices, or Hubs, all across the country. “I know of cases where we have hired, trained, moved them to Indianapolis, and then they come back and say, ‘OK, our parents live in Chicago, we want to go back and work out of Chicago,’” Kumar said. “So we are actually being very flexible.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dJBAnduw6Vip6E3BO78SzBksTD0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067494/HAND_SPOT.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="EYTmgk"&gt;But for others, that flexibility is just another aspect of the uncertainty and stress of trying to start a career at Infosys. David is one of the employees who switched locations during his tenure at Infosys, having relocated twice while working for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tH7mim"&gt;When David joined the company for what he thought was a software development position, he was first asked to relocate to a large city. At the time, he was enthusiastic about getting his start in software development, having “always liked technology.” But the first project he was assigned to had nothing to do with software development. It was a customer support job. Later that year, he was removed from the project, and David, like George, spent his time on the Bench at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QgdCuw"&gt;After a few months, David interviewed for a new project, this time in a more suburban location. David got the job, but it came with a catch: Infosys only gave him a week to move, a request David was “not happy with.” But despite the short timeframe, the opportunity to leave a city that “was definitely a bigger city than what I was used to” was enticing, he said. The suburbs offered a quieter lifestyle. (“I liked being able to go on hikes.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="521k7w"&gt;David made the move, which involved renting a U-Haul and breaking his lease. But when he got to the new location and arrived for his first day of work, no one was ready for him — or for the other new employees. “We just sat in the office during the day,” David said, describing how it took a week before he and the other new employees received the company-issued laptops they needed to start work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bs4V7V"&gt;He did eventually get put on a project at the second location, which this time involved development work. “I was so excited after a year of waiting for it to finally happen,” David said of the prospect of finally getting to gain experience in his chosen career. But that project was again short-lived, and he was dropped after a few months. “I was a little bummed out,” said David. “I was worried that maybe I wouldn’t get any real opportunity to work on development stuff at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EqRZxT"&gt;&lt;section class="ad"&gt;
    &lt;div class="ad__inner"&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="ad-placemarker-athena-mobile"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qyZadW"&gt;After a second time on the Bench, David was brought back on to the same client, but his experience was a bit different. Although he spent about a month developing a testing framework for the client, during the rest of the time, David didn’t have any other work to do. Sometimes, the more experienced Infosys employees would give him practice assignments designed to give him experience with a new technology. But mostly, he spent the rest of his time in the office trying to “look busy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EpS2D8"&gt;“They saw me sitting at my desk, reading something — sometimes it was code-related, sometimes it wasn’t. But unless they actually stopped for a few seconds to read over my shoulder, they wouldn’t know the difference,” David said. “I actually spent a lot of time researching hobbies that I wanted to get into.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWxQvo"&gt;David’s third and final stint on the Bench began unceremoniously: he tried to get to the client’s office only to find that his badge didn’t work. “We were on our way in to do more busy work as usual, and the badges wouldn’t let us swipe in anymore,” David said. But even then, he didn’t get fired. His time at Infosys ended when he finally landed a new job at a different firm that, unlike Infosys, gave him consistent software development work and allowed him to finally progress in his career as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yLR991"&gt;Now, David looks back at his time at Infosys with a mixture of bemusement and frustration. “I don’t think most people are going to complain about getting paid to do pretty much nothing,” he said. But at the same time, working at Infosys did delay his career for two years and, worse, gave him a nominal two years of experience that made it difficult for him to be considered entry-level. “It’s basically like Infosys was paying me less than I could have made to do next to nothing while also crippling my ability to get better jobs or better work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QxrQFp"&gt;Then there was the guilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iL6zxO"&gt;“Even though knowing that it was outside of my control, at the same time, I’m sitting there getting paid more than someone who is a housemaid... or who is a plumber, or who is a construction worker,” he said. “Thinking about it that way, it’s like, ‘Wow, I know this isn’t really in my control, but it still does feel a little bad to know that I’m living what some people would call the dream, getting paid for doing nothing.’”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N4KviRFYw4HbiySCb93HA713Nus=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069885/Divider_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="b8C015"&gt;As Infosys has expanded across the US, politicians have showered the company with tax breaks. In Indiana, Infosys’ planned headquarters granted it &lt;a href="https://subsidytracker.goodjobsfirst.org/subsidy-tracker/in-infosys"&gt;$101.8 million in subsidies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://subsidytracker.goodjobsfirst.org/prog.php?parent=&amp;amp;statesum=IN&amp;amp;fedsum=&amp;amp;major_industry_sum=&amp;amp;hq_id_sum=&amp;amp;company_op=starts&amp;amp;company=&amp;amp;major_industry%5B%5D=&amp;amp;hq_id=&amp;amp;free_text=&amp;amp;subsidy_level=&amp;amp;subsidy_op=%3E&amp;amp;subsidy=&amp;amp;face_loan_op=%3E&amp;amp;face_loan=&amp;amp;subsidy_type%5B%5D=&amp;amp;sub_year%5B%5D=&amp;amp;state=&amp;amp;federal="&gt;one of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.indystar.com/story/news/politics/2017/05/02/indiana-gives-infosys-largest-state-incentive-package-ever/101194224/"&gt;the largest&lt;/a&gt; incentive packages in the state’s history. And in Connecticut, a proposed smaller 1,000-person headquarters gained the company up to &lt;a href="https://ctmirror.org/2018/04/13/bond-commission-approves-14m-bring-infosys-1000-tech-jobs-hartford/"&gt;$14 million in subsidies&lt;/a&gt;, with the final amount conditional on hiring all 1,000 workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I1Nvqx"&gt;Other companies have taken notice. Tata Consultancy Services, an Infosys competitor also based in India, announced that it would &lt;a href="https://www.bloombergquint.com/business/tcs-to-recruit-10-000-staff-in-us-by-2022-2"&gt;hire 10,000 workers&lt;/a&gt; by 2022, having previously hired 21,500 workers between 2015 and 2020. But Infosys’ fiercest competition might come from American staffing firms, which see Infosys’ lifelong learning model as a way to adapt to the future of work. Some of those competitors are funded by Achieve Partners, which raised &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1772162/000177216219000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml"&gt;$80 million&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 for a “putting America back to work fund” to invest in staffing firms in industries with labor shortages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KxCWZL"&gt;Achieve Partners was founded by Ryan Craig, a venture capitalist who typically invests in education companies. But Craig had become &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/ryancraig/2021/05/28/lambada-school-the-forbidden-coding-bootcamp/"&gt;increasingly skeptical&lt;/a&gt; of models where students pay education companies directly, particularly in light of the rising costs of college tuition. “For at least the past decade it’s been clear that apprenticeships – earning while learning – are more powerful and lower risk pathways for socioeconomic mobility than the tuition-based colleges and universities,” Craig told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in a written statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FpsUCi"&gt;Achieve Partners was a way to bypass the higher education system entirely. According to investment documents reviewed by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Achieve Partners’ business model involves acquiring staffing firms and then adding a “last-mile training” component to the business, wherein the firm hires recent university graduates and trains them to specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="5wu6vn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Was Infosys terrible? Yes. Would I ever go back? Absolutely not.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="1jS6YS"&gt;The documents also show that their investments are expected to be profitable. Achieve Partners expects to make an average of $100,000 per worker, according to the documents, with a gross margin of 40 percent. The documents don’t say how long each worker will be employed by the staffing firms, but theoretically, with Achieve Partners taking a 40 percent cut, workers would be left with a salary of $60,000, less expenses (such as the cost of training) paid by the employer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EWHNF6"&gt;Dave DeSario, a director at Temp Worker Justice who reviewed the investment documents, described Achieve Partner’s 40 percent markup as “pretty typical in the industry.” DeSario added that companies typically keep their markup data private from their employees. “Workers have no right to know or to see what the markup is on their wages,” DeSario said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Gt3MR"&gt;As companies like Infosys have expanded across the US, they’ve been quick to portray themselves as job creators, in large part because of their willingness to hire and train entry-level talent. But critics caution there is little evidence that staffing firms actually create new jobs that wouldn’t exist otherwise because, by design, they make money by winning contracts to supply companies with workers. Presumably, if a company doesn’t sign a contract with a staffing firm, they would hire the employees themselves in-house, and the employees would have higher wages because there wouldn’t be a staffing firm to take a markup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uOLL0o"&gt;“There’s no evidence to suggest that giving state or federal money to temp agencies creates actual long-term, good jobs,” DeSario said, citing a &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/02690940600808230?needAccess=true&amp;amp;"&gt;2006 study on the topic&lt;/a&gt;. “All the evidence is actually to the contrary that when states or the federal government gives money to develop jobs through temp agencies, it only produces short-term jobs, which don’t have a positive impact for those workers, or it produces the very limited hiring of the top tier candidates who would have gotten hired anyway through other means.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Hd2iQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k_7ePhGIkiovgJtSRq-5WY5QLd0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067490/CARDS_SPOT.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="NQZioz"&gt;(For his part, Kumar said that comparisons between Infosys and other staffing firms were misguided. “We don’t do staffing or staff augmentation at all,” Kumar said. “We run projects and programs for large enterprises. A lot of our business is fixed price.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aF6ewk"&gt;At first glance, Infosys seems like an exception. For the Trump administration, Infosys’ hiring spree is a vindication of its protectionist policies targeting H-1B visas. And for local politicians, Infosys’ job numbers help justify the tax breaks foisted upon the company. The carrot and stick approach seems to have worked — no small thing for a country still recovering from a pandemic-driven recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4HFFuq"&gt;But for the Infosys employees, whether or not they were actually employed was a complicated question. For some, while the job was not ideal, it was a job nonetheless. “I would say a paying position is better than no pay, no position,” George said. “Was Infosys terrible? Yes. Would I ever go back? Absolutely not. But if I could do it all over again, and I was in the same situation, and I had absolutely nothing else going for me, it was better than nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dcbzil"&gt;And yet, although models like Infosys are supposed to help new workers get a foot in the door, it’s unclear if these sorts of contracting jobs are good environments to start a career. These models continue to proliferate because of the profitability of their markups, but if the companies can’t get their employees real-world experience, there’s a risk that employees may become stuck in less stable positions that don’t pay as well as permanent roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzTDGq"&gt;Ultimately, other Infosys employees found it difficult to see their position as a real job at all. “I have other friends who got actual jobs at Allstate or Caterpillar or stuff like that,” Josh said. “They’re actually doing things, and I’m just sitting here.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/c/22820291/tech-jobs-outsourcing-infosys-bench-paid-to-do-nothing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/c/22820291/tech-jobs-outsourcing-infosys-bench-paid-to-do-nothing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Rindlisbacher</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T09:56:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T09:56:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uncharted’s remastered Legacy of Thieves Collection is coming to PS5 on January 28th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RbmiSyXL7UqRQPXPqxD4AHu7eJ4=/245x0:2873x1752/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239425/Screen_Shot_2021_12_07_at_9.44.36_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LamB88"&gt;Sony has officially announced a release date for its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22661816/sony-playstation-showcase-uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-ps5-pc"&gt;remastered &lt;em&gt;Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for PlayStation 5: it’ll be out on Janaury 28th. That release date is only for the PS5 version, though. Sony still hasn’t put a date on the PC port beyond the same vague “2022” date it had originally announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qhcOFA"&gt;Sony also added that existing owners of either &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Uncharted: The Lost Legacy&lt;/em&gt;, or the digital two-pack PS4 bundle of both will be able to upgrade to the remastered &lt;em&gt;Legacy of Thieves Collection&lt;/em&gt; on PS5 for $10, rather than buying the new collection again for the full $49.99. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tee-XnRhlQCfVtNLS61zxha1ICQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069957/51728813547_009dd31431_h.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IjybOx"&gt;There are a few caveats with the new collection, though. Players who got a copy of &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt; for free through PlayStation Plus won’t be eligible for the free $10 upgrade. And the multiplayer modes from both titles included in the collection won’t be included in the new remasters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vQk3Hs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection&lt;/em&gt; will offer three different options for the PS5 port: Fidelity Mode, for 4K / 30fps gameplay; Performance Mode, which targets a 60fps frame rate; and Performance Plus Mode, which drops resolution down to 1080p but offers a 120fps frame rate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Y4wnr"&gt;The remastered collection will also leverage the PS5’s usual hardware improvements, including the DualSense controller’s haptic feedback and adaptive triggers, 3D audio, and faster load times thanks to the PS5’s speedy SSD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bpbLfn"&gt;Lastly, Sony is sweetening the pot for anyone who buys &lt;em&gt;Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection&lt;/em&gt; between now and February 3rd by offering a free movie ticket to see the upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738187/uncharted-movie-trailer-tom-holland-nathan-drake-mark-wahlberg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncharted&lt;/em&gt; film adaptation starring Tom Holland&lt;/a&gt;. The deal is good both for customers paying the full $50 price tag, as well as anyone taking advantage of the $10 upgrade, although it’s limited to the US, UK, Australia, and New Zealand. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822130/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-ps5-remaster-price-release-date-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822130/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-ps5-remaster-price-release-date-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-07T09:37:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-07T09:37:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sonos now supports Amazon Music’s Ultra HD and Dolby Atmos tracks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CSUW6QRJFpi9kk-ieFikmas7Zt0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70239360/acastro_180529_sonos_1777_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DPILlp"&gt;As it previously promised, Sonos is today rolling out support for Ultra HD and Dolby Atmos tracks from Amazon Music Unlimited. After downloading the latest system update for their Sonos speakers, Amazon Music subscribers will see new badges on the Now Playing screen that clearly identify the quality of whatever music you’re playing. Sonos already supported CD-quality HD tracks on Amazon Music, as it does for other services as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TfeZuH"&gt;These new badges will show either HD (lossless 16-bit stream), Ultra HD (lossless 24-bit stream), or Dolby Atmos. Sonos notes that for lossless music, the maximum sample rate supported is 48kHz. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GM2tXxsXHqydLT6rMCrSXgZr3x8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23069922/Screen_Shot_2021_12_07_at_9.21.07_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sonos&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll see badges on the Now Playing screen to indicate music quality.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6nHFmu"&gt;The company has also put together its own pretty thorough guide on &lt;a href="https://blog.sonos.com/en-us/hi-res-audio-guide"&gt;understanding high-resolution audio&lt;/a&gt;, saying that “while some aspects of what constitutes hi-res audio are clearly defined, some are not. And as the industry evolves, streaming services are applying their own terms to brand their higher-resolution tiers.” Give it a look if you’re new to lossless streaming, honestly — it’s quite good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x4ozYm"&gt;Dolby Atmos music is only supported on Sonos’ Atmos-enabled soundbars, the Arc and second-gen Beam. But Ultra HD tracks can be played across a much wider selection of Sonos devices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="jHgCEZ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/amp" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vZFqVb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/arc" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Arc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MW2rij"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/beam" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beam&lt;/a&gt; (both generations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="o1ua02"&gt;Connect (second generation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZkASr0"&gt;Connect:Amp (second generation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="l85FP2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/five" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Five&lt;/a&gt; and Play:5 (second generation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ItHRvm"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/move" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Move&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XF5GNL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/one" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1ZgbQE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/one-sl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;One SL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2jE6y9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/port" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Port&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fDGqtR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/roam" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Roam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Bbbkz8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/sub" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sub&lt;/a&gt; (all generations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vkao2U"&gt;Symfonisk Bookshelf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c2gQ9S"&gt;Symfonisk Table Lamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="HJFGsn"&gt;In its blog post / explainer, Sonos hints that it plans to enable hi-res audio for other streaming services — Apple Music, hopefully — in the future. I’ll again take this opportunity to point out that Spotify has yet to launch its long-awaited HiFi tier after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality"&gt;announcing it nearly 10 months ago&lt;/a&gt;. But there’s still time for the company to make good on its “later this year” promise, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822132/sonos-amazon-music-ultra-hd-dolby-atmos-music-now-available"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822132/sonos-amazon-music-ultra-hd-dolby-atmos-music-now-available</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
