<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-20T01:51:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-20T01:51:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-20T01:51:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Trump pardons convicted ex-Google engineer Anthony Levandowski</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Anthony Levandowski In Court For Bond Hearing After Being Charged With Stealing Google Trade Secrets" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j9ZGx_kUSbwk1Zaofz11W5N-Pak=/0x0:3587x2391/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68693341/1172284877.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9UnvaV"&gt;One of President Trump’s final acts in office is to pardon a former Google engineer who was convicted of stealing trade secrets. Anthony Levandowski worked for Google’s self-driving car division, now called Waymo, before leaving to found Otto, a self-driving truck company that was acquired by Uber. He was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/4/21354906/anthony-levandowski-waymo-uber-lawsuit-sentence-18-months-prison-lawsuit"&gt;sentenced&lt;/a&gt; to 18 months in prison in August, with judge William Alsup describing the incident as the “biggest trade secret crime I have ever seen.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LVD8zv"&gt;Levandowski was found to have downloaded thousands of files to his laptop before he left Google and entered into sale discussions. Uber ultimately fired him after Google sued, and Levandowski remains in a legal battle with the ride-hailing company, claiming it should be liable for the $179 million he was ordered to pay Google. In a separate suit, Levandowski has argued Uber owes him billions of dollars in lost value from the Otto deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Ywbap"&gt;Levandowski never began his sentence, as Alsup allowed it to be delayed indefinitely because of the COVID-19 pandemic. According to a &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/statement-press-secretary-regarding-executive-grants-clemency-012021/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; from the White House, Levandowski’s pardon was supported by figures from the tech industry including controversial billionaire investor Peter Thiel, fellow Founders Fund partner Trae Stephens, Palantir investor and advisor Michael Ovitz, and Oculus and Anduril founder Palmer Luckey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zhPO1v"&gt;Alongside Levandowski, Trump has pardoned 72 other individuals and commuted the prison sentences of 70 more. The list includes rappers Lil Wayne, who pled guilty to a firearms possession charge last year, and Kodak Black, who is currently in prison on weapons charges. Trump also granted a pardon to Steve Bannon, the former Breitbart News boss who served as chief strategist to Trump until his acrimonious departure in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/20/22240175/trump-pardons-anthony-levandowski-google-uber-waymo-trade-secrets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/20/22240175/trump-pardons-anthony-levandowski-google-uber-waymo-trade-secrets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T20:18:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T20:18:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk’s flamethrower was not a flamethrower, but that isn’t stopping police</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9_9n4_v4m-g450qb2-PLhw7wZE8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68692290/llopatto_180609_2658_0068.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by random stranger in the crowd&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FD3rzo"&gt;Mark Harris has put together &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/elon-musk-said-it-was-not-a-flamethrower/?tpcc=ECTW2020"&gt;an amazing report&lt;/a&gt; for TechCrunch on the legal troubles that have befallen buyers of the Boring Company’s flame-throwing device. Part of what makes it worth a read is that it digs up stories you may have not heard about yet: a police raid in London, an American doing time in an Italian prison, and how they’ve turned up in narcotics hauls alongside real guns and bags of cocaine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1RJ2qE"&gt;While the Not a Flamethrower name &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/10/17445838/boring-company-flamethrower-elon-musk-tweets-party"&gt;may actually be accurate&lt;/a&gt;, the story shows that when police the world over see you with a gun-shaped device, especially one that shoots flames, they may not join you in laughing about Elon’s zany project ideas. They may just end up arresting you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="E7okhT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s a toy they sell to children.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E7okhT"&gt;The biggest “what the heck” moment of the story for me was when a lawyer says of the Not a Flamethrower: “It’s a toy they sell to children.” Please, if you were one of the people who got this device — do not give it to a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uiueNt"&gt;While the product may be Boring, the article certainly is not, and you should definitely &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/elon-musk-said-it-was-not-a-flamethrower/?tpcc=ECTW2020"&gt;go give it a read&lt;/a&gt;. I promise you won’t get burned.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239773/police-interactions-with-not-a-flamethrower-elon-musk-boring-company"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239773/police-interactions-with-not-a-flamethrower-elon-musk-boring-company</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T20:00:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T20:00:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mojang is retiring the old Minecraft Dungeons launcher</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8HAUj73llPEwcDdRCsObD9WdN4M=/375x0:7625x4833/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68692176/Screenshot_Combat_HiRes.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="awck9Y"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minecraft Dungeons&lt;/em&gt;’ dedicated launcher on PC is being retired &lt;a href="https://help.minecraft.net/hc/en-us/articles/360053351331"&gt;in favor of a new “Unified Launcher”&lt;/a&gt; that lets you launch &lt;em&gt;Dungeons&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Minecraft: Java Edition &lt;/em&gt;from the same place,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reducing the number of places where you can play &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; on PC by one (via &lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/minecraft-unified-launcher-now-available-offers-access-minecraft-and-minecraft-dungeons-pc?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wmexperts+%28Windows+Central%29"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XErjdg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minecraft Dungeons&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270311/minecraft-dungeons-reviews-xbox-pc-switch-ps4"&gt;the hack-and-slash loot collecting cousin of &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that, until this change, had its own launcher unless it was purchased from the Microsoft Store. As of January 18th, the non-Microsoft Store version of &lt;em&gt;Dungeons&lt;/em&gt; on PC can only be launched from the new Unified Launcher (which itself is an update to the Java launcher). Mojang says the change shouldn’t affect save files and that either a Microsoft account (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21527647/minecraft-microsoft-account-mojang-java"&gt;soon to be required to play on PC&lt;/a&gt;) or a Mojang account can be used to log in to the launcher.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tODDe9zbSNKZzOkYv2OGwxA9u5w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22246238/UnifiedLauncher.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Mojang&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An account screen from the new unified Minecraft launcher.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="52VdNP"&gt; Here are the remaining ways and places you can play &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; on PC after the changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="DwS1Yz"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Minecraft Windows 10 Edition&lt;/em&gt; (sometimes just called &lt;em&gt;Minecraft &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;Minecraft: Bedrock Edition&lt;/em&gt;) is managed through the Microsoft Store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pb80oh"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Minecraft: Java Edition&lt;/em&gt; is managed through the Unified Launcher, but you can also play without updating, for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nY3qok"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Minecraft: Education Edition&lt;/em&gt; (the specialty version of the game for schools) is managed through its own launcher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="M7IbPj"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Minecraft Dungeons&lt;/em&gt; (a &lt;em&gt;Minecraft &lt;/em&gt;spin-off) is either managed in the Unified Launcher or the Microsoft Store if you’re using Xbox Game Pass for PC or you bought it from there. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="U8a9OP"&gt;Consolidating where you launch two &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; games doesn’t do much to help confusion over the many different types of &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;, but for any person who enjoyed playing both &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Dungeons&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Minecraft: Java Edition&lt;/em&gt;, it’s now a little bit more convenient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xw55XS"&gt;You can find out more information about the change and how to download the new launcher on &lt;a href="https://help.minecraft.net/hc/en-us/articles/360053351331"&gt;Mojang’s &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; Help Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h0DGZb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pnaGWa"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239451/minecraft-dungeons-java-edition-unified-launcher-microsoft-mojang"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239451/minecraft-dungeons-java-edition-unified-launcher-microsoft-mojang</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T19:10:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T19:10:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Storytelling incubator Wattpad is getting bought for over half a billion dollars</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4--JaeOqjDNoFWullF7axPog96M=/0x34:1440x994/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68691965/126866607_1781483032008933_7991615642394760692_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;After We Collided&lt;em&gt;, a sequel to a film adaptation that came from a Wattpad author.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: Aviron&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JDjztp"&gt;Last week, we told you how Wattpad has become a place where budding authors can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22215052/wattpad-authors-fanfiction-netflix-hulu-streaming-movies-romcom-teen-drama"&gt;sometimes turn their work into Hollywood film and TV&lt;/a&gt;, with Hulu, Netflix and others adapting Wattpad writers’ labors into titles like &lt;em&gt;The Kissing Booth, Light as a Feather &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;After We Collided&lt;/em&gt;. But it looks like Wattpad may no longer be trying to become an entertainment tastemaker all on its own — South Korean web company Naver is buying Wattpad for over $600 million, &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/webtoon-parent-naver-announces-approval-of-agreement-to-acquire-wattpad-301211308.html"&gt;the companies announced today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="teMxsS"&gt;While details are scarce, it seems like Naver already sees Wattpad as a natural pairing with one of its other brands — Webtoon, an online webtoon publishing portal that similarly allows artists to upload their own work and similarly spawns TV and anime adaptations.(Here’s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line_Webtoon#Adaptations"&gt;a handy list of those adaptations from Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0ZfAml"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A new chapter in our story is about to be written, and we're not writing it alone... We’re thrilled to announce our board has approved an agreement to be acquired by Naver, home of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/webtoonofficial?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@webtoonofficial&lt;/a&gt;! Read the exciting news → &lt;a href="https://t.co/xgwGtD4nVz"&gt;https://t.co/xgwGtD4nVz&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/fzoIJyTWrp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/fzoIJyTWrp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Wattpad (@wattpad) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wattpad/status/1351676903363645441?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wbp2I8"&gt;Wattpad’s press release explicitly mentions Webtoon, and &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/webtoon-parent-naver-announces-approval-of-agreement-to-acquire-wattpad-301211308.html"&gt;Webtoon was the one to issue a press release&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of its parent company Naver as well. Here’s how Webtoon describes the buyout:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Y73BlD"&gt;With the backing of Korean technology giant, NAVER, WEBTOON and Wattpad will collaborate to create a stronger and connected ecosystem across visual and textual storytelling content, with a combined reader base of over 160 million monthly users globally. WEBTOON’s innovative monetization model and Wattpad’s massive library of diverse stories will provide each prospective affiliate with new levers for growth, creating a stronger foundation to fund an aspiring generation of young, creative talent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="dUVU2I"&gt;However, Wattpad co-founder Allen Lau &lt;a href="https://betakit.com/wattpad-to-be-acquired-by-south-koreas-naver-corp/"&gt;tells &lt;em&gt;BetaKit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that his company will continue to operate independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ozQV9q"&gt;Naver is a popular search engine in South Korea, and competes with the likes of Google and Facebook in other ways too. The most notable is probably Line, a messaging app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/27/18760928/line-conference-2019-score-sticker-vision-mini-app-tokyo"&gt;whose associated services&lt;/a&gt; have helped make it the dominant social media company in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="enWT4v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How Wattpad went from fanfiction to Netflix hits","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22215052/wattpad-authors-fanfiction-netflix-hulu-streaming-movies-romcom-teen-drama"},{"title":"Wattpad is launching a publishing imprint called Wattpad Books","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/24/18195753/wattpad-books-launching-publishing-imprint-self"},{"title":"Digital publishing site Wattpad is partnering with Sony to adapt stories for Hollywood","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/18/18485603/wattpad-sony-pictures-first-look-deal-develop-original-programming-tv"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="cnONNs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 8:38PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added info from BetaKit about how Wattpad plans to operate independently. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239704/naver-buy-wattpad-600-million-aquisition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239704/naver-buy-wattpad-600-million-aquisition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T17:50:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T17:50:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Animal Crossing is getting an official makeup line</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Image of the Animal Crossing-inspired palettes " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6rT-LbS62LuLgVq5tQcRwVlsYqY=/0x36:1311x910/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68691534/AC_SIGNUP_DESKTOP.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: ColourPop&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IAWRkf"&gt;Nintendo &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1350148378659852288"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; that it’s collaborating with cosmetics brand ColourPop on a makeup collection inspired by &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;. The collection &lt;a href="https://www.allure.com/story/colourpop-cosmetics-animal-crossing-collection"&gt;looks to be relatively extensive&lt;/a&gt;, including four powder palettes that are themed after characters in the game. Obviously, Isabelle is fabulous enough that she doesn’t have to share with anyone and gets her own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="woaCZQ"&gt;ColourPop is no stranger to pop culture collaborations. It has lines inspired by Disney princesses, &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;, and even &lt;em&gt;Sailor Moon. &lt;/em&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; venture won’t even be the first collab it’s done with a gaming brand, as there’s also a Candy Land x ColourPop line. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TPkpUb"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Featuring fun shades inspired by the island paradise life, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ColourPopCo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ColourPopCo&lt;/a&gt; x Animal Crossing: New Horizons makeup collection adds some new hues to your look on 1/28! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ColourPopxAnimalCrossing?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ColourPopxAnimalCrossing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; ️: &lt;a href="https://t.co/KT70wQfwLu"&gt;https://t.co/KT70wQfwLu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/JvKvDAidkK"&gt;pic.twitter.com/JvKvDAidkK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1350148378659852288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xrj8gr"&gt;The collection shows that, even though the game has been out for 10 months at this point, the game still has some cultural significance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GbfOlh"&gt;The makeup collection will launch on January 28th. Hopefully it doesn’t have the stock issues that have been plaguing Nintendo recently (I have friends who have spent weeks trying to get an &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt;-themed switch), and we’ll all be able to wear our &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; makeup to our &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/4/15/21220911/animal-crossing-date-tinder-dating-app-trend-coronavirus"&gt;virtual &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; dates&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239450/animal-crossing-makeup-line-colourpop-collaboration"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239450/animal-crossing-makeup-line-colourpop-collaboration</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T17:35:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T17:35:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Goodbye and good riddance to the 16:9 aspect ratio</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lqa9yF70f-zjpIwuKZSF4qjt-l0=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68691466/HP_Elite_Folio_Front_Left_Forward.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The brand-new HP Elite Folio has a 3:2 display.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: HP&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fWm2S4"&gt;One of the biggest trends coming out of this year’s CES wasn’t something people will necessarily notice at first glance unless they look closely. After enduring years of cramped, “widescreen” laptop displays, it looks like we’re finally starting to say goodbye to the 16:9 aspect ratio. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E2UFdDdgN8dd4Pg1LlafEzciff0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22214848/Dell_Latitude__9420_3_view.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the new Dell Latitude 9420.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ENE2RC"&gt;An aspect ratio is the ratio of a display’s width to a display’s height (in that order). For example, a screen with a resolution of 500 x 500 would have an aspect ratio of 1:1. Think of it like simplifying a fraction: a 1080p screen has a resolution of 1920 x 1080, which divides down to 16:9. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K5Ls5D"&gt;The aspect ratios you’ll typically see on laptops are 16:9, 3:2, 16:10 (which, for whatever reason, is called 16:10 rather than 8:5), and (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22175087/lenovo-thinkpad-x1-fold-review"&gt;occasionally&lt;/a&gt;) 4:3. 16:9 is the most common option and also the one with the lowest amount of vertical space relative to its horizontal space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Acer Aspire 5 open from the front." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pO4D8o8uOcrjYm9Gei-840mU10o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029470/akrales_201110_4271_0078.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a 16:9 Acer Aspire 5.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Surface Book 3 is a powerful, portable desktop PC." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PuN2e3kfrkrkWQzUCTkmF09NNPE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19984309/dbohn_200516_4026_0022.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here’s a 3:2 Surface Book 3. See the difference?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5qBxPl"&gt;If you have a modern Windows laptop, there’s a good chance your screen is 16:9. If you have a gaming laptop, its panel is almost certainly 16:9. (It’s unusual to find high refresh-rate panels with other proportions.) There are some notable exceptions: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/23/21526702/microsoft-surface-pro-x-2020-review-arm-windows-10-apps-features-specs-price"&gt;Microsoft’s Surface products&lt;/a&gt; have been 3:2 for quite some time, while Dell’s last few &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21221003/dell-xps-13-2020-review-core-i7-specs-features-price"&gt;XPS 13&lt;/a&gt; models and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21244349/apple-new-13-inch-macbook-pro-vs-air-dell-xps-surface-2020-comparison"&gt;Apple’s MacBooks&lt;/a&gt; are already 16:10. But traditionally, Windows laptops like these have been few and far between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JuHBma"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/4/19/17027286/laptop-widescreen-aspect-ratio"&gt;16:9 screens are cramped&lt;/a&gt; — at least compared to other options. I usually can’t comfortably work in multiple windows side by side without zooming out or doing a ton of vertical scrolling, and when I’m multitasking in Chrome, the tabs get tiny very quickly. If you’re used to using a 16:9 screen and you try a 16:10 or 3:2 display of the same size, you probably won’t want to go back. You just have a lot more room, and it’s a much more efficient use of screen space. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1pZGuD"&gt;But this CES showed that 16:10 and 3:2 displays are inching closer to the mainstream. These are some of the biggest laptops announced at the show that are offering non-16:9 display options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="39re6I"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224455/hp-elite-folio-announced-arm-convertible-laptop-specs-ces-2021"&gt;HP Elite Folio (1920 x 1280, 3:2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="07ktib"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214058/dell-latitude-business-laptops-9420-automated-webcam-shutter-ces-2021"&gt;Dell Latitude 9420 2-in-1 (2560 x 1600, 16:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OxaP4y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226031/lenovo-thinkbook-plus-gen-2-e-ink-lid-display-ces-2021"&gt;Lenovo ThinkBook Plus Gen 2 (2560 x 1600, 16:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hLIe6T"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227013/lenovo-legion-7-slim-5-pro-gaming-laptops-amd-ryzen-5000-cpu-nvidia-rtx-gpu-ces-2021"&gt;Lenovo Legion 7 and Legion 5 Pro (2560 x 1600, 16:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MdS03s"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217915/lg-gram-17-2021-laptops-announced-specs-ces"&gt;LG Gram 17 and Gram 16 (2650 x 1600, 16:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TUI75s"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22217872/lenovo-ideapad-5-pro-laptop-amd-ryzen-ces-2021"&gt;Lenovo IdeaPad 5 Pro (2560 x 1600, 16:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qcZDy6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224757/lenovo-thinkpad-x1-titanium-yoga-carbon-business-laptops-intel"&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Titanium Yoga (2256 x 1504, 3:2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qSgW2X"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224757/lenovo-thinkpad-x1-titanium-yoga-carbon-business-laptops-intel"&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon Gen 9 and X1 Yoga Gen 6 (up to 3840 x 2400, 16:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Wrct2V"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22221393/lenovo-thinkpad-x12-detachable-convertible-laptop-price-release-date"&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad X12 Detachable (1920 x 1280, 3:2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZpKHuj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226223/asus-rog-flow-x13-zephyrus-duo-15-se-gaming-laptop"&gt;Asus ROG Flow X13 (up to 3840 x 2400, 16:10)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="unxhVO"&gt;That doesn’t mean there are no 16:9 displays left — plenty of laptops still use it, and probably will for the foreseeable future. And some of these devices, like the LG Grams, were 16:10 already. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PjbFCD"&gt;But it’s significant that a large number of the flagships we’ll be seeing in the first half of 2021 will be either 16:10 or 3:2. In fact, when you include &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/3/21418451/msi-summit-series-prestige-modern-announced-specs"&gt;MSI’s 16:10 Summit E13 Flip&lt;/a&gt; and Razer’s 16:10 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21549504/razer-book-13-laptop-intel-tiger-lake-screen-price"&gt;Razer Book 13&lt;/a&gt; (both of which were announced prior to CES), I can’t think of a mainstream consumer laptop company that isn’t now selling a non-16:9 flagship-level machine. It’s clear that companies across the board are moving toward laptops with taller aspect ratios, and I fully expect to see more of them in the years to come. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Detachable in laptop mode, angled to the left side." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yWkgMVux36XCxhC2Pz0FSV0hxfs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223432/03_Thinkpad_X12_Hero_Front_Facing_Right.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lenovo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the X1 Detachable (currently attached).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2Jg1Io"&gt;Again, this may seem like a boring change. But it will make a big difference in the lives of this year’s laptop buyers, particularly people shopping for a work-from-home device. I switched from a 16:9 laptop to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/16/16658466/microsoft-surface-book-2-review"&gt;3:2 Surface Book 2&lt;/a&gt; back in 2017, and it was one of the best purchasing decisions I’ve ever made. If you’re using a 16:9 screen now and are looking to upgrade this year, I encourage you to give one of these new devices a shot. You won’t want to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238671/16-9-aspect-ratio-hp-elite-folio-dell-latitude-lenovo-thinkbook-plus-legion-7"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238671/16-9-aspect-ratio-hp-elite-folio-dell-latitude-lenovo-thinkbook-plus-legion-7</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T17:09:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T17:09:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vrbo is blocking new Washington, DC reservations during inauguration week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pJdSuZSn_YDioOTYMYv4p5X0_TU=/0x0:1500x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68691308/Vrbo_logo_dark.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;vrbo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0AxJ2N"&gt;Vrbo has changed its stance on people making reservations in the Washington, DC area during the week of the inauguration. The company announced on January 19th, the day before the event, that it will block any new reservations through Friday, January 22nd. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/16/22234501/vrbo-cancel-reservations-washington-dc-inauguration-airbnb-capitol"&gt;Vrbo previously stated it was evaluating new bookings&lt;/a&gt; and that it would “take appropriate action in coordination with law enforcement” if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QW28dL"&gt;The news was tweeted by Expedia Group (which owns Vrbo) and from the official Vrbo Twitter account. It comes in light of DC officials encouraging people to &lt;a href="https://www.governor.virginia.gov/newsroom/all-releases/2021/january/headline-891291-en.html"&gt;stay home and participate in the inauguration virtually&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XXCZk3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Based on updated guidance provided by government officials regarding security threats, and as part of ongoing efforts to protect the safety of travelers, partners and communities, all new Vrbo reservations will be blocked in and around Washington, D.C. through Friday, 1/22.&lt;/p&gt;— Vrbo (@vrbo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vrbo/status/1351583247260672005?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PqmXRz"&gt;The company has slowly been changing its policies around inauguration rentals, after &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/katienotopoulos/vrbo-wont-cancel-inauguration-rentals"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed News&lt;/em&gt; reported that residents are concerned&lt;/a&gt; about extremists using the service to stay in DC. But while Vrbo stated that it was “encouraging hosts to cancel bookings,” it’s not blanket-canceling reservations. When asked if this was still the case after today’s block, the company responded that it would indeed not cancel all existing reservations, but it is “re-vetting [them], to help ensure public safety.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qTBi2v"&gt;In comparison, Airbnb not only blocked new reservations, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228798/airbnb-washington-dc-inauguration-reservations-blocked-cancelled"&gt;but it canceled existing ones as well&lt;/a&gt;. On January 6th, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ExpediaGroup/status/1351050004312559617"&gt;Vrbo stated&lt;/a&gt; that all new reservations would be subject to increased scrutiny and security, but it seems like we’ll just have to trust that those measures were effective, as the new ban seems like it’ll only affect people who are booking last minute. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KBJwBy"&gt;The home-sharing apps are not the only ones trying to avoid more violence in the nation’s capital ahead of tomorrow’s inauguration: Facebook has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233871/facebook-blocking-events-white-house-us-state-capitols-inauguration-day"&gt;shut down events near the White House&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221730/apple-removes-suspends-bans-parler-app-store"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22221648/google-suspends-bans-parler-play-store"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228675/amazon-parler-takedown-violent-threats-moderation-content-free-speech"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; have all worked to remove the distribution of Parler, an app that failed to moderate rioters during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/18/22236750/propublica-parler-capitol-riot-videos-timeline-resource"&gt;the attack on the Capitol building&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239269/vrbo-blocking-new-reservations-dc-inauguration"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239269/vrbo-blocking-new-reservations-dc-inauguration</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T17:05:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T17:05:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>COVID-19 cases in the Capitol are only the tip of the iceberg</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pro-Trump Protests over Electoral College Vote Certification" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RNp8isYVJzc9_RTlFLmvjVb2gDY=/1x0:2500x1666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68691289/1230480701.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Kent Nishimura / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Ripples from the Capitol riots could be spreading across the country &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="2wfHrJ"&gt;When &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/it-is-difficult-if-not-impossible-to-estimate-the-size-of-the-crowd-that-stormed-capitol-hill-152889"&gt;thousands&lt;/a&gt; of insurrectionists descended on Washington, DC, from all over the country in early January, it had the makings of a COVID-19 superspreader event: people packed in close quarters, chanting and cheering, all unmasked. United States lawmakers tested positive for the virus after the pro-Trump riots, and those cases could be only the tip of the iceberg. The surge of activity, which snubbed all public health guidelines, could lead to outbreaks in the city, in prisons and jails, and all around the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5LM08H"&gt;Finding out exactly how much damage the riots did, though, would be an enormous epidemiological challenge. Tracking superspreader events is difficult under the best of circumstances. When the event is populated by people who are unlikely to cooperate with officials and case counts are already sky-high, that task gets even harder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FHPs4v"&gt;“The whole US is a superspreader event right now,” says Andrew Noymer, an infectious disease epidemiologist at the University of California, Irvine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="xsEOs4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The whole US is a superspreader event right now.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WH3ZEs"&gt;Tracking the disease through the halls of Congress, where it touches public figures, is clearer: so far, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/01/13/us/congressional-members-with-coronavirus.html"&gt;six members&lt;/a&gt; of Congress reported positive test results after the riots when they were forced to pack into small rooms for safety. (A seventh tested positive &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/siladityaray/2021/01/07/kansas-rep-jake-laturner-tests-positive-for-covid-19-hours-after-house-vote/?sh=43b6aecf68f9"&gt;the day of&lt;/a&gt; the riots and was already infected while they were ongoing.) Three Democrats who have COVID-19 &lt;a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2021/01/could-the-capitol-riot-become-a-superspreader-event.html"&gt;explicitly blamed&lt;/a&gt; it on the close quarters and Republican colleagues who refused to wear masks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zMQVYz"&gt;Outside of the Capitol building, the disease was likely circulating as well. The far-right groups that gathered for the riots don’t take the pandemic seriously. “Part of the MAGA riot platform is a complete disavowal of science, of public health, and of the necessity of things like masks,” says Eric Reinhart, a researcher studying health and incarceration in the Department of Anthropology at Harvard University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BKftUa"&gt;Among the thousands who traveled to Washington, DC from all across the country, people gathered outside without masks, broke into the Capitol building without masks, and returned to hotels, where they &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WilliamTurton/status/1346980282243678209"&gt;sat unmasked&lt;/a&gt; in lobbies. They risked spreading COVID-19 among themselves but also to people they encountered through the city, including DC workers. When they returned back home, they also could have seeded new outbreaks in their own communities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Trump Supporters Hold “Stop The Steal” Rally In DC Amid Ratification Of Presidential Election" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a8bv_FxuslGmG7v8lFimkxNVfNU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22245953/1294942197.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tasos Katopodis / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gvefgj"&gt;COVID-19 is surging through the country, so everyone is at a higher risk of infection right now than they might have been at another point in the past year. But because of their behavior, the rioters may have been more likely to be infected and spread infection than the population at large, Reinhart says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xP6rv0"&gt;That’s one of the main differences between these riots and protests against police brutality over the summer (which were also not violent and were not trying to subvert the democratic process). Most people did not travel to participate in those protests, instead gathering where they lived, and the vast majority of protesters wore masks and were cautious about maintaining distance. The main risks of COVID-19 at protests against police brutality &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/3/21278340/protestors-coronavirus-spread-police-violence-health-racism"&gt;came from police officers&lt;/a&gt; who funneled protesters into tight quarters and arrested thousands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4yBCNp"&gt;“People were taken in paddy wagons or big vans with ten, 20 or 50 people,” Reinhart says. “Then they’re detained in bullpens in these jails, often with 20 or 30 people in a tight confined space.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3apmL9"&gt;By contrast, fewer than&lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/number-of-arrests-capitol-riot-compared-blm-protests-chart-2021-1"&gt; 100 people&lt;/a&gt; were arrested in or after leaving DC in connection with the Capitol riot. For legal and public safety reasons, more arrests were likely warranted, Reinhart says. But for public health, he was relieved to see such a low number. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Lf4ic6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Thank god they’re not throwing thousands of people into jails”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RsQnGX"&gt;“Thank god they’re not throwing thousands of people into jails in DC and Virginia right now, because that would be an absolute disaster, not just for those detained, but for everyone,” Reinhart says. COVID-19 spreads more quickly in the close quarters of a prison or jail than outside of it. When the virus takes hold in one of those facilities, it also cycles out to the surrounding community as guards arrive and go home each day and as people are brought in and released. In Illinois, people cycling in and out of Cook County Jail explained about 15 percent of COVID-19 cases in Chicago, Reinhart’s &lt;a href="https://www.healthaffairs.org/doi/full/10.1377/hlthaff.2020.00652?utm_campaign=covid19fasttrack&amp;amp;utm_medium=press&amp;amp;utm_content=reinhart&amp;amp;utm_source=mediaadvisory"&gt;research found&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8QxPUk"&gt;The small number of rioters arrested may have blunted that element of risk to public health after the riots. But hard-line Trump supporters like the ones seen at the Capitol &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/videos/politics/2020/09/14/trump-supporters-nevada-rally-coronavirus-jorge-rodriguez-sot-nr-vpx.cnn"&gt;tend to be anti-maskers&lt;/a&gt; and are less likely to follow public health guidelines than the general population. The chances that the few dozen rioters who were arrested had COVID-19 and brought it into a jail may be higher than the typical incarcerated person. Even with lower numbers, it’s reasonable to speculate the rioters could be a risk for jails and prisons, Reinhart says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MQBAi4"&gt;It could be weeks until epidemiologists are able to piece together the full ramifications of the Capitol riots on COVID-19 spread, if they do at all. It takes meticulous detective work to quantify the ripple effects of a gathering, Noymer says. There are two strategies researchers could use. One involves finding the genetic sequence of the virus that infected someone who got sick after the riots, they could follow it as it jumped from person to person. That’s how experts &lt;a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/early/2020/12/09/science.abe3261"&gt;tracked the spread&lt;/a&gt; of the virus from a conference in Boston last year, finding around 245,000 cases could be traced back to that single event. It’s unlikely to be a good strategy for the riots since it depends on people who were at the event coming forward and agreeing to participate in research. “Good luck getting these people to cooperate,” Noymer says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="xB7Dks"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Good luck getting these people to cooperate.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zLCqxG"&gt;Another strategy is measuring the changes in the number of cases in an area before and after an event, and modeling how much the event likely contributed to any change. That’s the basis for &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/sturgis-motorcycle-rally-superspreader-johns-hopkins-research-doubt/"&gt;a study analyzing&lt;/a&gt; the impact of an August motorcycle rally in Sturgis, South Dakota, on COVID-19 spread. The motorcycle rally happened when COVID-19 cases in the United States were far lower than they are now. Disentangling the reasons for infections and finding bumps in case numbers will be harder now after the Capitol riots when there are over 200,000 cases reported each day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="koCmRv"&gt;Neither method is perfect, and both rely on modeling and estimates. Coming up with numbers may be a helpful way to conceptualize the damage done by an event like the riots at the Capitol, but it’s not the only way to know something bad happened. The riots were clearly a significant event and based on every public health metric, likely spread COVID-19. Experts don’t need to quantify exactly how much it supercharged the spread of the virus in order to feel confident that it mattered and that it was dangerous. “We don’t need to try and put a number on it,” Noymer says. “It’s a fool’s errand.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pGKRE4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239408/capitol-riot-covid-cases-superspreader-arrests"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239408/capitol-riot-covid-cases-superspreader-arrests</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T16:57:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T16:57:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Why did The CW skyrocket to the top of the App Store?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MFujyjOpHruyccp-MYUN8fUpqbY=/94x0:1107x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68691224/batwoman.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The CW&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pg7V2m"&gt;Some people may have been surprised to see The CW’s app sitting atop the list of free apps available on iOS devices, passing YouTube, TikTok, Instagram, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C7pGqS"&gt;The CW noted in a statement that this is the third year in the row it reached the top of the charts during a premiere week, despite earlier data from SensorTower claiming it was the first time in three years. Screenshots provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;from The CW show the app hit the top of the app store every week, with the exception of 2020 because the premiere week was moved to 2021 due to production issues brought on by the pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IczeQu"&gt;For people without a cable subscription who want to watch &lt;em&gt;Riverdale, All American, Batwoman, &lt;/em&gt;and more, The CW’s free, ad-supported app is an easy option. On January 18th, the app saw approximately 36,000 installs in the US App Store and Google Play, according to SensorTower. That’s seven times as high as the week before it, a spokesperson for SensorTower added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i3NtJN"&gt;Like most things in the entertainment industry these days, some of the answers may lie in Netflix and streaming-at-large. After many of those shows air their season finales, they end up on Netflix about a week later — and having people discover series via the streamer has created a Netflix Effect, according to CW chairman Mark Pedowitz. Just last week, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/cw-boss-mark-pedowitz-unpacks-pandemics-anticipated-effect-on-pilot-season-1234885498/"&gt;Pedowitz told &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that its free, ad-supported CW streaming platform “has been enormously successful for us,” although he didn’t say exactly how many viewers the app was actually drawing. Pedowitz added that The CW has seen “great increases in &lt;em&gt;Batwoman, Nancy Drew, &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; Stargirl&lt;/em&gt; in terms of what we would have done in a rolling five [most recent five episodes of a season that aired on TV] for Netflix.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xmiRTM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Like most things in the entertainment industry these days, some of the answer may lie with Netflix and the pandemic&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DVleUn"&gt;A couple of important notes about The CW: it’s not a ratings juggernaut. Compared to other cable channels — and the big networks — The CW isn’t competing as a heavyweight contender week after week. In 2016, however, Netflix &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2016/tv/news/netflix-cw-streaming-licensing-deal-1201808624/"&gt;made a deal with The CW&lt;/a&gt; to carry a number of its shows. In international territories, those shows (like &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt;) were labeled Netflix originals. Pedowitz claimed in 2019 that having the Netflix deal “gave the chance for the CW to breathe.” By 2017, Pedowitz pointed to the Netflix deal for &lt;em&gt;Riverdale&lt;/em&gt;’s stronger second season start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QLt5Dl"&gt;“We came back so strong that second season, because of the binging that was going on the first,” Pedowitz &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2019/02/cw-president-netflix-black-lightning-in-the-dark-1202040374/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;IndieWire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “The key for us, when that happens, is to try to bring them back into the in-season, and remembering that it’s a CW show, and that they’re more than welcome and they can watch all the original episodes throughout the year.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="slSUaV"&gt;It’s the second part of that sentence that’s most important — “they can watch all the original episodes throughout the year.” SensorTower’s above data points to a number of downloads on January 18th, the day of &lt;em&gt;All American&lt;/em&gt;’s third season premiere. &lt;em&gt;All American &lt;/em&gt;is a series that seems (it’s impossible to know without actual viewership data from streamers) to have benefitted &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/blakemorgan/2019/02/19/what-is-the-netflix-effect/?sh=854c34f56409"&gt;from the Netflix Effect&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MxVxgY"&gt;The series, which follows a high school football star uprooting his life to move to a wealthier part of Los Angeles in order to play for a better team, saw an “explosion” of interest when the second season landed on Netflix, showrunner &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/krystieyandoli/all-american-netflix-trending-show"&gt;Nkechi Okoro Carroll told &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in May. Prior to it landing on Netflix, &lt;em&gt;All American &lt;/em&gt;was already seeing growth in linear ratings, &lt;a href="https://tvline.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tv-ratings-cw-midseason-2019-2020-1.png"&gt;according to Nielsen data&lt;/a&gt;, partially due to it following &lt;em&gt;Riverdale &lt;/em&gt;on TV and possibly finding an audience on Netflix. Following the show’s second season debut, it sat in Netflix’s Top 10 list in the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="TMsBKI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The key for us, when that happens, is to try to bring them back into the in-season.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xSIlWU"&gt;“It’s important to note that the CW is a vital part of their ecosystem,” Pedowitz &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2019/05/the-cw-boss-comment-end-netflix-output-deal-1202616278/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hSmkJ3"&gt;The third season didn’t premiere on Netflix, but it did put Pedowitz’s “Netflix Effect” theory to the test. Again, while it’s impossible to say for certain that people downloaded the app for one specific show without any data, the linear ratings do tell an interesting story. &lt;em&gt;All American&lt;/em&gt;’s third season premiere brought in four times The CW’s average since the fall season began in September 2020. &lt;em&gt;All American &lt;/em&gt;also saw a massive spike in data on January 18th, according to Google Trends. The show’s premiere far outpaced its first season, which Pedowitz has pointed to the Netflix Effect for other shows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mceUDS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;All American &lt;/em&gt;may not have driven swaths of people to download the app, but considering that &lt;em&gt;Batwoman &lt;/em&gt;premiered to expected ratings the night before and &lt;em&gt;Riverdale &lt;/em&gt;is returning tonight, it may have created the perfect cornucopia of series to drive people’s downloads — especially at a time when people are still stuck at home with nothing to do but watch TV. Now, many of these shows are heading to HBO Max instead of Netflix after their seasons are over. If that same streaming effect continues, there will be similar questions about whether &lt;em&gt;The Office &lt;/em&gt;will find the same type of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22216867/peacock-office-subscription-streaming-ad-free-premium-plus-netflix"&gt;viewership on Peacock&lt;/a&gt; as it did on Netflix. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tJK66I"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 19th, 5:29pm ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The story has been updated to include a statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WC7798"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 19th 6:34pm ET: The story has been updated to include additional data from The CW. A representative told &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Verge &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reached the top of the app store for a third year in a row, not for the first time in three years, as stated by SensorTower. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239170/cw-app-store-top-free-all-american-season-3-batwoman-riverdale-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239170/cw-app-store-top-free-all-american-season-3-batwoman-riverdale-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-19T16:17:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T16:17:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s latest ‘military grade’ rugged tablet arrives in the US starting at $489</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E8NX4nKcx-bUadNFsAh_ZO3A1hI=/459x0:5409x3300/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68690937/galaxy_tab_active3_front_dl1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Tab Active 3 is IP68 rated and, with the included case, can withstand a 1.5 meter drop. | Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MOmTPI"&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Tab Active 3, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/28/21459565/samsung-galaxy-tab-active-3-rugged-android-tablet-gloves-lte-wifi-6"&gt;announced globally in September&lt;/a&gt; of last year, is now available in the US starting at $489.99. It’s a rugged 8-inch Android tablet designed primarily for manufacturing, retail, and job sites, with an IP68 water- and dust-resistance rating. Samsung even says it passed tests against 23 environmental conditions, including vibrations and high altitude, to meet the MIL-STD-810 military-grade standard. An IP68 S Pen stylus is included in the box, as is a case that protects against drops up to 1.5 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AgmZgs"&gt;The Tab Active 3’s touchscreen is designed to be used even when wearing work gloves, though not “extremely heavy duty gloves or mittens.” It also offers three physical navigation buttons as well as two programmable buttons that can act as shortcuts to certain apps. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5-1x8-PKF90yHTvAlFPryX1WsVc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22245870/SM_T575_002_Back_Black.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Tab Active 3’s rear 13-megapixel camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NFEBFe"&gt;Its rear 13-megapixel and front-facing 5-megapixel cameras are optimized for scanning barcodes, and a removable 5,050mAh battery is included. While it will ship with Android 10, Samsung says an upgrade to Android 11 will follow. It will sell with either 64GB or 128GB of internal storage, expandable by microSD card slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W0sL6l"&gt;The Galaxy Tab Active 3 is available now from Samsung’s partner distributors and at &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/business/products/mobile/tablets/galaxy-tab-active/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung.com&lt;/a&gt;. It starts at $489.99 for a Wi-Fi-only version and $589.99 for the LTE model. Samsung says it will remain available for purchase for three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUnjak"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="anaJNf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0xRx5Z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSZ7Oj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238948/samsung-galaxy-tab-active-3-us-availability-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238948/samsung-galaxy-tab-active-3-us-availability-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
