<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-14T15:21:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T15:21:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T15:21:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>SiriusXM sued for failing to provide podcast transcripts for Deaf users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IF6NfIyjGB5vjDl8CBa0JWgvsNY=/1x0:535x356/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70271143/siriusxm.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;SiriusXM, along with its subsidiaries Stitcher and Pandora, are being sued by Deaf advocates | SiriusXM&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qGWTmM"&gt;SiriusXM is facing a lawsuit from the National Association for the Deaf (NAD) and the Disability Rights Advocates (DRA) for failing to provide captioning and transcripts for “the vast majority” of its podcasts. According to the complaint, SiriusXM and its subsidiaries Pandora and Stitcher are in violation of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) and New York state law for failing to make their podcast streams accessible for Deaf and hard-of-hearing users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Neo1lO"&gt;“Defendants’ failures to provide transcripts of their podcasts excludes deaf and hard-of-hearing persons from the critical sources of news, entertainment, educational programs, and popular culture that Defendants make available to their hearing customers, in violation of the Americans with Disabilities Act, the New York State Human Rights Law, and the New York City Human Rights Law,” the complaint states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lWqEp5"&gt;The lawsuit notes that the ADA requires companies providing services to the general public are expected to provide the services in a manner accessible to people with disabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tk36S7"&gt;The lawsuit does not name Spotify, producer of some of the most well-known podcasts, including &lt;em&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;/em&gt;. Spotify doesn’t yet provide a transcript for Rogan’s shows (although some third-party apps provide transcripts). In May, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441886/spotify-podcast-transcription-accessbility-app-update"&gt;Spotify announced it would begin auto-transcribing&lt;/a&gt; some of its original shows, with the aim of eventually enabling transcripts across all its podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJEzKE"&gt;“We can’t sue every bad podcast provider in a single lawsuit and had to start somewhere, but it is important to deaf and hard of hearing users that transcripts be provided across all podcast platforms,” Christina Brandt-Young of DRA said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s deeply concerning to us that even when the authors of podcasts make their transcripts available elsewhere (like some podcasts from the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;), SiriusXM, Stitcher, and Pandora don’t provide them through their services, making our clients work twice as hard to get the same information everyone else gets.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4qgFfo"&gt;She noted that transcripts are easy to provide, “and these are multimillion-dollar companies. It’s time for them to do the right thing and provide podcast transcripts on their websites and apps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yx89im"&gt;The lawsuit seeks unspecified compensatory damages and an injunction requiring the companies to provide transcripts for all their podcast content and to “affirmatively market the availability of transcripts to deaf and hard-of-hearing” people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q5pMZT"&gt;Sirius XM didn’t respond to requests for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6WOZ3U"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21154179-nad-vs-sirius-stitcher-and-pandora/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="NAD sues podcast providers (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834002/siriusxm-lawsuit-transcripts-deaf-users-ada-pandora-stitcher-podcast"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834002/siriusxm-lawsuit-transcripts-deaf-users-ada-pandora-stitcher-podcast</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T15:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Opal’s C1 offers DSLR-rivaling video quality in a small form factor</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Stellar design and performance, with more improvements to come&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="3bHgPq"&gt;Would you consider buying a $299.99 webcam? That’s the cost of Opal’s C1, which is now available to purchase on an invite-only basis. My guess is that many of you will say no. Others, who are on the never-ending quest to look good for all of those Zoom meetings, might have a list of questions in need of some &lt;em&gt;really &lt;/em&gt;convincing answers, and rightfully so. Like, why pay this much when there are so many other more economical options, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21281765/webcam-phone-tablet-android-ios-pc-mac-how-to"&gt;using your phone as a webcam&lt;/a&gt;? And why go with newcomer Opal over legacy brands like Logitech?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="evrRCw"&gt;Opal has good answers to those questions. But having a chance to try the webcam itself was more convincing than any answer I received. The C1 aims to — and mostly succeeds at — supplying DSLR-like image quality (complete with plenty of background separation or bokeh) for far less than a decent camera-turned-webcam might cost you, without all of the dongles and other hardships that sometimes come with the territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tFdZah"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10919482"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="713HTf"&gt;The C1 was designed by Kenny Sweet, who was responsible for the cute but misguided &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/27/17055618/google-clips-smart-camera-review"&gt;Google Clips camera&lt;/a&gt;, among many other popular tech products. That ID comes through here, but it almost looks like something that Essential might have whipped up. The C1 is available in either a white or black colorway, and its paint finish is matte with glossy speckles that only show themselves in certain lighting. I don’t want to gush too much, but it’s lovely to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Opal C1 camera" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zvJVzN-UmOm4ARx6UUQSKMP9tj0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067803/cfaulkner_141231_4911_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The C1 has a low-profile build that doesn’t stand out too much.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Opal C1 camera" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mWYhZUs37PuNJ0B_J7EeXIcSEO8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067801/cfaulkner_141231_4911_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The bottom has a rubberized grip, plus a tripod mount.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZQkqi4"&gt;The C1 has an indicator light that’ll let you know when the camera is in use. The front of the webcam also hosts stereo mics in its grille, with an extra noise-canceling microphone on its rear. Compared to my MacBook Pro’s built-in microphone, my voice is just as clear, but through the C1 it has a little more resonance and depth to it. When I was recording a sample, some home construction next door started, and while its noise cancellation effects weren’t great, it was capable of picking my voice out from all of the noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="jOBNzs"&gt;Here’s what the stereo microphones in the Opal C1 sound like:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;audio controls=""&gt;
  &lt;source src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23086976/opalc1mic.mp3" type="audio/mp3"&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23086976/opalc1mic.mp3"&gt;Here’s what the stereo microphones in the Opal C1 sounds like&lt;/a&gt;(opens a new window)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/source&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q7TtBJ"&gt;The backside looks like a heatsink you’d apply to an M.2 SSD inside your custom PC, and indeed, it’s partially used for dissipating heat (in addition to looking rad). It’s also where you’ll find its USB-C port. Opal’s webcam includes a sturdy mount that can hang onto a monitor or a MacBook lid, though the webcam itself can attach to any ¼-20 tripod mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QFQiFm"&gt;The C1 features the Sony IMX378 sensor (the same one &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/sony-imx378-comprehensive-breakdown-of-the-google-pixels-sensor-and-its-features/"&gt;used in Google’s first Pixel smartphone&lt;/a&gt; released in 2016) capable of up to 4K resolution at 30 frames per second behind an f/1.8 lens. It currently defaults to 1080p at 30 frames per second because Opal says 4K can crash videoconferencing apps. The higher resolution is there as an option, so owners can utilize it for streaming or recording if they want. I was initially bummed out that the C1 lacks the capability to record at 60 frames per second, but it nevertheless seemed to run more smoothly in video calls than other webcams that I had on hand, like Elgato’s $199.99 Facecam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wUwXpK"&gt;This is where Opal’s pitch for the C1 starts to sound more like a phone than your average webcam. Software has become the secret sauce responsible for driving many features in the best smartphone cameras. And like the top phone makers, Opal, too, is putting just as much (if not more) thought into the software side of the C1’s performance, not just the specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Opal C1 camera" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ow9cSGIh_68-FRNy9ca8fqZKNzs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067806/cfaulkner_141231_4911_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The automatic settings in the Opal app on macOS produced this warm, detailed image.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PM6zfo"&gt;The C1’s automatic settings excel at making me look far better in multiple lighting scenarios than any webcam I’ve tried so far. The out-of-the-box settings also produce a better image than even my &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/25/9201455/olympus-e-m10-mark-ii-hands-on-photos"&gt;Olympus E-M10 Mark II&lt;/a&gt; mirrorless camera. I bet it’d be a closer race if I labored over tweaking my camera’s numerous settings, which feels like an arcane skill that I sadly lack. That’s the big advantage of the C1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P9sN2g"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;readers who’ve used recent flagship phones probably know from experience that the power of software to enhance picture quality cannot be understated. But it’s not just software at play here. The C1 has an Intel Myriad X chip inside that helps to power the set of features presently found in the macOS app, which are a mix of what you’d expect to see for a webcam, along with some interesting additions (Windows support is coming in late 2022, though the C1 works as a plug-and-play device right now). The app itself is currently considered a beta and Opal says it plans to add more features in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Opal C1 camera" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H8Ztmw0ZEx-mCO8gnqVZ7CsVkCc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067805/cfaulkner_141231_4911_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can make your feed pixelated if you want.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Opal C1 camera" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r1CH7PwgJKBX4aY821zu3CwHN4U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067804/cfaulkner_141231_4911_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The included mount is very sturdy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6Kub7K"&gt;My work desk is positioned in such a way that I’m backlit by windows, which always presents a challenge for webcams and DSLRs alike to light me adequately and to make my skin look its natural color. Yet, I was happy leaving the task up to the C1 to figure out what was right because it reliably made me look good. But if you’d prefer to tweak, there are several settings in the macOS app that can be customized, including focus locking at a range of distances, brightness, exposure, saturation, contrast, vibrance, and white balance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uP8htT"&gt;Digging further into the app, the bokeh slider can add some simulated blur to your background. Despite some similar halo effects to what we usually see from portrait modes on phones, the end result could easily be confused for the real thing, particularly when it’s viewed through a streamed video call. Opal says its webcam has its own “graphic rendering pipeline that actually models the physics of how light enters a lens through a hexagonal lens – all to make a Bokeh effect that is far more convincing.” Basically, Opal figured out a software solution to this hardware problem, as many phone makers have, to defy what’s possible with these tiny lenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7oxTzt"&gt;The C1’s artificial blur is far more convincing than Zoom’s blurred background feature, but it doesn’t provide the same level of privacy that Zoom’s does — it’s still possible to make out what’s in the background behind you. It’s more akin to the Portrait Mode that Apple baked into the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22765988/apple-macos-12-monterey-review-macbook-pro-air-imac-m1"&gt;latest version of macOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ociYDq"&gt;Another optional feature that you can turn on is “Face Lock,” which follows your face’s movement, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;Apple’s Center Stage feature on iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. The “stickiness” of this feature is controlled by a slider in the app and at high settings it almost seems to predict your movements instead of reacting to them. It can look blurry and a little distracting on the high setting (you can see what that looks like in the video below), so I imagine most people will want to keep this setting on low to medium for a more smooth, subtle tracking effect. Another thing I liked during my time with the C1 is that any changes that I made to the camera’s settings were applied automatically, even when I was already using it in Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="mWRK0W"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.294%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://streamable.com/o/d9onuj" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VWkYyY"&gt;Many of these features aren’t novel in the realm of webcams, but the company has more ideas to take advantage of its Intel chip and software. One of the more ambitious ideas is gesture recognition. Opal intends to let users drop from video calls by signaling the peace sign or to zoom in on their picture by making a pinch gesture in front of the C1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8ns28"&gt;Additionally, the company is testing an update for release in the coming months that will use machine learning and neural networks on the Intel chip to improve how you look and sound. It aims to deliver a feature called Studio Sound that’ll push the voice quality through a neural net to enhance the level of depth and clarity to rival a dedicated podcast-grade microphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uefgwr"&gt;It also wants to be able to utilize the C1’s software and hardware to evaluate your behavior in calls, like grading you on how much eye contact you gave or how well you did at reducing filler words like “ums” and “uhs” in your speech. Opal didn’t attach a timeframe to these ideas, or comment on whether they’ll be opt-in features, but these would push the C1 far beyond what other webcams are attempting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Opal C1 camera" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/siwa5zrz0tBBaDoEx9FJItTRLMc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23067799/cfaulkner_141231_4911_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The design of the Opal C1 is one of my favorite things about it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A2wVZF"&gt;We’ll have to wait to see whether Opal delivers on any of these promises, but for now, it delivers on the goal of being a convincing stand-in for a DSLR. It’s far simpler to setup, use, and manage than my large camera or even a smartphone converted to work as a webcam. There are no batteries, space constraints, multiple cables and dongles, or driver woes to worry about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="lgQ3JZ"&gt;The C1’s biggest obstacle is its $299.99 price. But if you primarily work from home and value having a stellar picture in videoconferencing apps, this might be worth it to you — especially if you’ve tossed around the idea of investing in a pricey DSLR (or already did).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sb24o6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22834196/opal-c1-webcam-camera-dslr-video-quality-performance-review-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22834196/opal-c1-webcam-camera-dslr-video-quality-performance-review-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T14:55:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T14:55:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Pony.ai’s permit to test driverless vehicles in California is suspended after crash</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pony.ai Tests Self-driving Car In Guangzhou" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2Zx-T_wk-fzJ9XrCqfAH9d3XDDI=/73x0:2149x1384/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70270959/913385808.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Visual China Group via Getty Images/Visual China Group via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GYSD2M"&gt;Pony.ai, an autonomous vehicle startup based in Silicon Valley and Guangzhou, China, is temporarily unable to test driverless vehicles in California after a vehicle crash led the state’s Department of Motor Vehicles to suspend the company’s testing permit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xw9vBb"&gt;Pony.ai was one of the few companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/22/22449084/chinese-startup-pony-ai-autonomous-vehicles-california"&gt;approved to test fully autonomous vehicles&lt;/a&gt; without safety drivers behind the steering wheel on public roads in California. The DMV has only issued permits to seven other companies, including major operators like Waymo and Cruise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jZuHbt"&gt;But the permit was suspended — and Pony’s name removed from &lt;a href="https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/vehicle-industry-services/autonomous-vehicles/autonomous-vehicle-testing-permit-holders/"&gt;the DMV’s list of permit holders&lt;/a&gt; — after a reported vehicle collision in Fremont, California on October 28th, the agency said in a statement. Pony has 10 Hyundai Kona vehicles registered under its driverless testing permit. The company is still authorized to test vehicles with a safety driver behind the steering wheel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KpfWsZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pony’s AV “came into contact” with a center divider&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B2SW1s"&gt;The permit was suspended after the company &lt;a href="https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/file/pony-ai_102821-pdf/"&gt;reported a crash to the DMV&lt;/a&gt;. (All AV permit holders are required to file reports after a collision.) According to the report, Pony’s vehicle was in autonomous mode, turning right onto Fremont Boulevard from Cushing Parkway when it “came into contact” with a center divider containing a traffic sign. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4tqTcQ"&gt;“The Pony.ai AV suffered moderate damage to the front of the vehicle and the undercarriage,” the report states. “There were no injuries and no other vehicles involved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X991Zr"&gt;Fremont Police were called to the scene. Pony said that it later reached out to local authorities to “resolve all issues” related to the damaged street sign. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HvUwbJ"&gt;“The safety of the motoring public remains the California DMV’s top priority, and the department’s autonomous vehicle regulations provide a framework to facilitate the safe testing and deployment of this technology on California public roads,” the DMV said in a statement. “When there is an unreasonable risk to public safety, the DMV can immediately suspend or revoke permits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FtMuJc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This represents a hurdle to Pony’s commercial plans in the state&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yPOici"&gt;This represents a hurdle to Pony’s commercial plans in the state. Shortly after receiving its driverless testing permit in May, Pony.ai founder and CEO James Peng told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company was seeking approval to include those vehicles in its robotaxi service in California. “We are actually at the final stage of getting the approval for travelers,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pZZB8U"&gt;Pony.ai was valued at $3 billion after a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21152817/toyota-pony-ai-self-driving-car-investment-valuation-china-silicon-valley"&gt;$400 million investment from Toyota&lt;/a&gt; last year. The company has been testing autonomous vehicles in Beijing and Guangzhou since late 2018 as well as in Fremont and Irvine, California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYvTvA"&gt;In a statement, a spokesperson for Pony noted that the company’s autonomous vehicles have driven over 750,000 miles in California since 2017. Pony is also conducting its own investigation into the October collision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1VbIVo"&gt;“We are proud to have one of the industry’s best safety records,” the spokesperson said. “We look forward to a safe resolution to this incident.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834496/pony-ai-av-test-permit-suspend-california-dmv-crash"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834496/pony-ai-av-test-permit-suspend-california-dmv-crash</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T14:51:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T14:51:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite adds four new playlists — including Slayer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q99u20eCOpuzW3S8HbOcjfK68ig=/94x0:1107x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70259863/HaloInfinite_Inline3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wud1bO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 14th, 2:45PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The new playlists are now available. As noted in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/news/halo-infinite-playlist-challenge-update"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Waypoint&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, there are also five new playlist-specific challenges that let you earn XP based on performance and gameplay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U81KPe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;is getting Slayer, Free-For-All (FFA), Tactical Slayer (SWAT), and Fiesta playlists, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/halo/comments/re5kdv/playlist_update/"&gt;Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; from u/ske7ch343, otherwise known as 343 Industries’ community director Brian Jarrard (via &lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/halo-infinite-getting-new-playlists-dec-14"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Jarrard confirmed that the four playlists are coming to the game via an update on December 14th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="soJobQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Halo Infinite MP is getting four new playlists on December 14th: Slayer, Fiesta, FFA, and Tactical Slayer (SWAT)   &lt;a href="https://t.co/DeTJQEz5zy"&gt;https://t.co/DeTJQEz5zy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/hzTLFGA2De"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hzTLFGA2De&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1469748946906099715?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fKfwjO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816491/halo-infinite-multiplayer-deathmatch-slayer-dedicated-playlist"&gt;343 Industries previously&lt;/a&gt; said that Fiesta, SWAT, and FFA playlists would be coming to the game by the end of the year, while a Social Slayer playlist wouldn’t arrive until sometime in 2022. In his post, Jarrard acknowledges that developers promised a Social Slayer playlist with “a variety of new variants.” But since this wouldn’t get done before the holidays, 343 has decided to launch a basic Slayer playlist first, and will “look to bolster and expand with more variants” in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W8nkmo"&gt;Currently, you can’t choose your game mode. You’re forced to rotate between Capture The Flag (CTF), Slayer, Strongholds, and Oddball, which is obviously a pain if you prefer playing one game type. It’s also an annoyance if you’re tasked with completing a challenge that corresponds to a specific mode, however, 343 is addressing that complaint as well — Jarrard says that the December 14th update will remove “particularly frustrating” mode-specific challenges as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dFoFpn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The update will remove “particularly frustrating” mode-specific challenges&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Pc04Sr"&gt;The update will also lessen some requirements for challenges, make the weekly ultimate challenge “less intensive,” and will add challenges specifically for the upcoming playlists. 343 is also slowly trying to implement performance-based XP — something that the game currently doesn’t offer — by adding a challenge category that’s “based on accumulating player score.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OrsKaT"&gt;Right now, you’re only rewarded with XP for completing challenges, not for each game you play, which has been a major complaint among players who want to level up. Last month, 343 attempted to address battle pass progression issues by adding &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22788990/halo-infinite-battle-pass-progression-xp-changes"&gt;a “Play 1 Game” challenge&lt;/a&gt;, increasing the duration of XP boosts, and rewarding players with more XP for the first six matches they play in a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LNZlh5"&gt;In addition to these changes, Jarrard also noted that developers are working on fixing the “intermittent hiccups” that seem to affect Big Team Battle (BTB), and is also taking a look at ranked matchmaking after hearing reports of “potential anomalies.” Although &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; was officially released on December 8th, players are still waiting for the co-op story mode that’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791487/halo-infinite-campaign-co-op-season-2-may-2022-forge"&gt;set to become available in 2022&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a way to replay individual levels in the campaign, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22821522/halo-infinite-campaign-levels-replay-mission-select-343-industries-microsoft"&gt;which 343 says it will add&lt;/a&gt; but doesn’t have a set timeline for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hfsr8h"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Halo Infinite’s creators say your wildest stunts are part of the series’ DNA ","url":"http://theverge.com/2021/12/11/22827053/halo-infinite-developers-wild-stunts-series-dna"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Z8wWl2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829744/halo-infinite-playlists-slayer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22829744/halo-infinite-playlists-slayer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T14:45:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T14:45:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge Holiday Gift Guide 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6pzjooxh36jGOlDFDP1r99AQaws=/0x0:2500x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70111588/VRG_Illo_4859_GG_Main_lede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Richard Parry&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Shop our curated guide for everyone in your life&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="SxVkbR"&gt;Finding the perfect gift for everyone special in your life can be, frankly, a nightmare. Some people are easy to shop for, but others in your family or social spheres might be less forthcoming about their desires. You could do the leg work of asking what might make them a happy camper over the holidays, but who has time for that? That’s a rhetorical question. No one has time for that, especially with shipping deadlines looming and delivery dates slipping further and further into January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WhSfEV"&gt;Thankfully, our team of writers at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; huddled for weeks to come up with the definitive list of gift ideas that you’ll find below. There are gifts for gamers, aspiring podcast hosts, parents, board game connoisseurs, musicians, film buffs, and much more. Given that we cover tech primarily, you know we’ve got you covered for all of this year’s desirable gadgets. But our team is also comprised of cooks, campers, photographers, fitness enthusiasts, and more, so expect a varied and inspired selection of gift ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rPO7rd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge’s Favorite Holiday Gifts Under $50","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22748775/holiday-gift-guide-under-50-cheap-tech-gadgets-best-ideas"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide for Creators","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22746670/holiday-gift-ideas-2021-creators-content-artists-tech-gadgets-creative"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Home Tech Holiday Gift Guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22752612/smart-home-tech-holiday-gift-guide-2021-kitchen-lighting-speakers"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide for Moms","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759870/holiday-gift-ideas-mom-2021-unique-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Gaming and Entertainment Holiday Gift Guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22747287/gaming-entertainment-gift-guide-2021-nintendo-playstation-xbox-gadgets-accessories"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide for Kids","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759900/holiday-gift-ideas-kids-children-2021-unique-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The Verge’s Favorite Holiday Gifts Under $25","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22745314/holiday-gift-guide-under-25-cheap-tech-2021-best-ideas"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide for Dads","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22752556/holiday-gift-ideas-dad-2021-unique-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide for Working From Home","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22746680/work-from-home-remote-office-holiday-gift-guide-2021-supplies-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Fitness and Wellness Gift Guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22746889/fitness-wellness-holiday-gift-guide-2021-fitness-trackers-watches"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="AJCFg6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10875071"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="pChznl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10842009"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T14:45:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T14:45:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Adobe brings two more desktop tools to Photoshop on iPad</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gpApUXWY0MjymkbAmWE3Ov0u8aE=/59x0:1607x1032/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70270870/Screen_Shot_2021_12_14_at_2.32.32_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p8QGix"&gt;&lt;a href="https://helpx.adobe.com/photoshop/using/whats-new/mobile-2022-1.html"&gt;Adobe has updated Photoshop for the iPad&lt;/a&gt; with two crucial new tools — the smudge and sponge tools, which have been mainstays on the desktop version of the app but absent on mobile until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4fbG1H"&gt;The smudge tool (as the name suggests) is used to help blur and blend lines or colors together and comes with the usual settings for adjusting size and strength of the effect, along with a variety of modes (including normal, darken, lighten, hue, saturation, color, and luminosity). The sponge tool, on the other hand, works to help retouch images by saturating or desaturating color, allowing users to fine-tune how vibrant their images and art look. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-DjKsJrK9ogKA23FoYIW2adXEQs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23087711/Screen_Shot_2021_12_14_at_2.34.54_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="12RbGa"&gt;Additionally, Adobe also rolled out a &lt;a href="https://helpx.adobe.com/premiere-pro/using/whats-new.html"&gt;new update for Premiere Pro on desktop&lt;/a&gt;, adding key performance improvements for M1-powered Macs. With the new update, all M1 Macs now work with hardware-accelerated exports for DCI 4K and 8K HEVC formats, which Adobe says will result in “significantly faster performance.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M2H3C7"&gt;Additionally, Adobe is also offering hardware acceleration for ProRes videos on the M1 Max and M1 Pro chips in the latest MacBook Pro laptops, offering up to five times faster performance. Windows users with integrated Intel GPUs are also getting a boost, with improvements to video playback, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QJva5p"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834232/adobe-photoshop-ipad-smudge-sponge-tools-premiere-pro-m1-macs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834232/adobe-photoshop-ipad-smudge-sponge-tools-premiere-pro-m1-macs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T14:37:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T14:37:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Teams now has end-to-end encryption support for one-to-one calls</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iP94E9OJtG4thB9525Yo8OPc56s=/0x0:2640x1760/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70270756/microsoftteams.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Iho3we"&gt;Microsoft is rolling out end-to-end encryption (E2EE) support for Microsoft Teams. After announcing the feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308915/microsoft-teams-end-to-end-encryption-support-e2ee"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; and testing a public preview since October, Microsoft Teams is getting the added E2EE security support for all one-to-one calls. An update is rolling out to all Teams users today, giving IT admins the option to enable and control E2EE for one-to-one calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jBPgbe"&gt;“Multiple enterprise customers in the US and Europe across industries such as aerospace, manufacturing, telecommunications, and professional services are in the process of rolling out E2EE for Teams calls,” &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-teams-blog/end-to-end-encryption-for-one-to-one-microsoft-teams-calls-now/ba-p/3037697"&gt;explains John Gruszczyk&lt;/a&gt;, a technical product manager at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DFs2ohNDoKz4xEGNtiXvxVNLdCs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23087677/e2ee.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Teams shows that calls are fully encrypted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tw3Xhx"&gt;Microsoft Teams currently encrypts data in transit and at rest, allowing authorized services to decrypt content for data retention record purposes. Microsoft also uses SharePoint encryption to secure at-rest files and OneNote encryption for notes stored in Microsoft Teams. All chat content in Teams is also encrypted in transit and at rest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPPF2J"&gt;This new E2EE encryption will further secure one-to-one calls within Teams, but it does mean certain Teams features will be disabled if IT admins enable it. Recording, live caption / transcription, call transfer, call park, call merge, and features like transferring calls to another device or adding participants to create a group call will all be disabled in one-to-one calls that use E2EE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7UbTzg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834634/microsoft-teams-end-to-end-encryption-support-e2ee-available-now"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834634/microsoft-teams-end-to-end-encryption-support-e2ee-available-now</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T13:48:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T13:48:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Five former SpaceX employees speak out about harassment at the company</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vVdNvj-lkzDSRoxSK0XaBmhunus=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70270454/acastro_211214_4932_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Workers claim HR did not take their complaints seriously&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="N9PrIY"&gt;A group of former SpaceX employees are coming forward about their experience working at the commercial rocket company, claiming that there is a culture of sexual harassment in the workplace and that managers and the human resources department handled complaints poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ic8Win"&gt;The individuals are speaking out in light of an &lt;a href="https://www.lioness.co/post/at-spacex-we-re-told-we-can-change-the-world-just-don-t-try-to-stop-the-sexual-harassment"&gt;essay&lt;/a&gt; published by one former employee, Ashley Kosak, who left SpaceX in November. In her account, Kosak details multiple instances of being groped and feeling uncomfortable after fending off sexual advances by her male co-workers. Four additional people who spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; described their own troubling experiences at SpaceX or witnessing other women and nonbinary people being harassed. In three cases reviewed by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, SpaceX HR was made aware of the allegations and had inconsistent responses that the employees felt were inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WriqV0"&gt;“SpaceX as an organization values the mission over employee wellness to the extent that I never saw meaningful action taken against individuals who committed acts of sexual harassment,” one former employee said, adding that she felt SpaceX’s lack of action was driven by management’s desire to avoid work disruptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7LcSNK"&gt;Kosak decided to come forward publicly with her story in order to help others in the space industry realize that any harassment they might be experiencing should not be tolerated. “I think until someone finally says, ‘This is unacceptable,’ you find a way mentally to accept that it’s okay,” Kosak tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “I hope that this essay helps bring to light that a lot of behaviors that are happening out there are not okay.” The essay was published in Lioness, a platform for whistleblowers to report on workplace misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Agv1dd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The former employees also believe the company is reluctant to hold some men accountable for bad behavior&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rBaS6B"&gt;In the essay, Kosak, who worked as a build reliability engineer in Cape Canaveral, Florida, alleges that a colleague grabbed her butt when she first started at the company and describes another incident where she says a different colleague ran his hand over her chest during a team bonding event. She claims that multiple men from the company would DM her and make sexual advances toward her, sometimes calling her in the middle of the night. One colleague apparently even came over to her house and tried to touch her multiple times, despite her pleas to stay professional. Kosak says she reported all of these incidents to either her superiors or to HR, but people rarely followed up on her complaints and her alleged perpetrators suffered no repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y8Gb9u"&gt;Kosak also says she witnessed other women dealing with similar issues at SpaceX. “Some of the men who work at SpaceX hug women without consent, stare at women while they work, and interpret every social encounter as an opportunity to date (or hit on) women in the office,” Kosak wrote in the essay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1Myib"&gt;Though Kosak is the lone author on the essay, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with four additional people who used to work for SpaceX, all of whom claimed to have experienced similar types of treatment or witnessed other women and nonbinary people dealing with harassment at the company. These former employees agree that SpaceX is a bit of a “boys’ club,” as one former employee put it, and say they were part of a very small group of women and nonbinary people working at the company. That made them feel severely outnumbered. The former employees also believe the company is reluctant to hold some men accountable for bad behavior, especially if those men have put in a lot of time at SpaceX or have contributed great things to the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pO8jhx"&gt;One woman who used to work as an intern at SpaceX, Julia CrowleyFarenga, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/28/21405671/spacex-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-former-intern"&gt;filed a lawsuit against the company in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, alleging that a manager retaliated against her after she reported harassment from one of her other managers, ultimately blocking her from being hired at SpaceX when her internship ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qUTvGs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“All four of the women or nonbinary people in my room, separately, were harassed during our internships”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oBCRBu"&gt;Another woman, who asked to remain anonymous for fear of retribution, described an instance during her internship when a senior SpaceX technician repeatedly tried to open her locked door and enter her room in internship housing, while he was demonstrably  intoxicated. Another former SpaceX intern said a male co-worker made inappropriate comments about their appearance and saw others experience similar behavior. “All four of the women or nonbinary people in my room, separately, were harassed during our internships,” the individual tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “And that was a really upsetting experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2cWEvD"&gt;SpaceX did not respond to a request for comment about the allegations, nor did the company respond to a request for details about its sexual harassment policy. However this weekend, after Lioness reached out to the company about Kosak’s essay, Gwynne Shotwell, president and COO of SpaceX, sent a company-wide email to SpaceX employees, reminding them of the company’s “no A-hole” policy and that harassment will not be tolerated. She also encouraged people to report any harassment they might experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2GmahR"&gt;“Timely reporting of harassment is key to our maintaining SpaceX as a great place to work; we can’t fix what we don’t know,” Shotwell wrote in the email, a copy of which was obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; “&lt;/em&gt;If you are aware of, or experience any acts of harassment or discrimination, report it to your manager or any HR representative.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BCrfw"&gt;The email also claims that SpaceX will be taking a closer look at its HR practices moving forward. “We also know we can always do better,” Shotwell wrote in the email. “That is why HR has been soliciting feedback from groups across the company to ensure the process is effective. HR will also conduct an internal audit, followed by a third-party audit.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZN6QHDdwGAX712oFKWtzKnbibVk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23087464/acastro_211214_4932_0002.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="D1UNVI"&gt;In her essay, Kosak said she did meet with HR on a few occasions throughout her time with the company but says that no meaningful action was taken. She also says she presented HR with a proposed framework for addressing sexual harassment, one that told people how to report their harassment and the kinds of repercussions that employees who engage in inappropriate behavior might expect. However, there was never any meaningful follow-up on her proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UTd6Kb"&gt;Finally, in October, she decided to submit an “anonymous” tip to the company’s Ethics and Compliance tip line, addressed to Gwynne Shotwell. In her tip, a copy of which was provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, she detailed her frustrations with HR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="zV7uYC"&gt;I am reaching out to you because the HR department has done absolutely nothing to resolve these issues, and in cases where engineering leaders have come together to bring to HR the list of changes necessary, they forced us to [put] in over 10 hours of work updating their training.... then nothing happened. Then I got harassed. Then these people got promoted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="KaMUdg"&gt;The submission document for the tip was a Microsoft form, which ultimately revealed Kosak’s identity. Kosak says she then received a call from HR, confronting her about the allegations in the tip. During the call, which Kosak recorded and shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, representatives asked her if she was the one who submitted the tip or knew who submitted it. She was asked to come up with solutions for HR to implement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="NXDjo5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Women who have worked despite the many blockades on the path to joining this company get called ‘Too Ambitious’”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Avlbgl"&gt;Afterward, Kosak spoke with a supervisor who set her up with a meeting with Shotwell and the company’s head of HR, Brian Bjelde. During the meeting, Kosak says, Shotwell and Bjelde claimed to have never heard of her complaints and asked her to propose solutions for how to fix SpaceX’s harassment reporting process. She suggested conducting a third-party investigation, in an email obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J6pwCE"&gt;After that meeting, Kosak had a follow-up call with HR, during which she was asked to detail her allegations again, and again asked for ideas on how to fix the harassment reporting process. She suggested that there be some kind of matrix of repercussions for harassing behavior, which the HR representatives seemed  reluctant to implement, suggesting that this information was too private to discuss openly in the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ynoSK"&gt;It wasn’t the first time that Kosak had presented a plan to upper management. She had previously presented her own environmental plan to Elon Musk, detailing how to make SpaceX carbon neutral by 2030. Musk ultimately dismissed the idea, saying that SpaceX relies on some wind and solar energy, Kosak claims. Kosak also presented the Starlink team with an “environmental compliance initiative” that was deemed too ambitious by the people she presented it to, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NREmsX"&gt;“Men here are allowed to get promoted despite a clear disrespect for the requirements of their authority,” Kosak wrote in her original tip to Shotwell. “Women who have worked despite the many blockades on the path to joining this company get called ‘Too Ambitious’.” The day before Kosak’s essay was published, Musk tweeted that SpaceX plans to start an initiative to capture carbon dioxide out of the atmosphere and turn it into rocket fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gfvYQi"&gt;Due to the stress at work, Kosak took a leave of absence in November before quitting 10 days later. She received a phone call from HR during her leave and then two more after she left permanently. She did not answer the phone calls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="95Fm6o"&gt;Kosak’s experiences with HR are mirrored by the experiences of another former employee of SpaceX, the female intern who dealt with a technician trying to enter her locked room. One night, a bunch of drunk technicians showed up at the house she was staying in at Vandenberg Village, near one of SpaceX’s launch sites, according to the former intern. The house was internship housing provided by SpaceX. One drunk technician, she says, repeatedly tried to enter her room, asking her if she was naked because she had just gotten out of the shower. She then came downstairs, where she says the technician tried to hug her and made obscene comments about women and her appearance. She then says she hid behind her couch, too scared to go back to her room because she thought he might follow her up there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="hTGbxg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“if female employees are being negatively impacted, and if their work suffers, well, that’s too bad because this guy’s really good”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oKeKWs"&gt;The day after the incident, the former intern says that an HR manager reached out to her about what had happened. The HR manager, she says, had heard about the incident from another individual who was present. She says after the meeting with HR, the technician confronted the intern at work and told her he was just teasing her. He also told her he was worried that he might lose his job. Fearing that she would not be hired on a permanent basis for speaking out, she did not fully cooperate with the HR investigation, as she had to continue working with the technician. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCDhDe"&gt;Later, after leaving the launch site where her internship was based, she did report all the details to HR. The HR manager would not tell her what actions had been taken, citing confidentiality and the fact that she was previously uncooperative with their initial investigation. However, the HR representative said the company did make one change to internship housing guidelines, and that employees of different genders would not share bathrooms anymore. She ultimately did not receive a job offer, and the technician continued to work at SpaceX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1P6Isr"&gt;CrowleyFarenga, another former intern who filed a lawsuit against SpaceX which has since been resolved privately and dismissed, felt she was retaliated against even though she was reluctant to speak about her harassment. In her lawsuit, she alleged that her manager would comment that she was talking to too many men, even though she was one of very few women on the team, and that she should be careful about who she spoke to, lest people get the wrong impression about her. He would also apparently spend much more time with her during one-on-one meetings than her male colleagues. When she eventually reported his behavior, she was moved to another team but says she suddenly started receiving bad reviews. Ultimately, she learned that the person she reported the harassment to blocked her from getting hired after her internship ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bzzrJb"&gt;“What they care more about is work than work culture,” CrowleyFarenga says of SpaceX. “And if female employees are being negatively impacted, and if their work suffers, well, that’s too bad because this guy’s really good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S3ONeJ"&gt;The third former SpaceX intern who spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; says they did receive a response from HR after a co-worker made an inappropriate comment to them over email about their Halloween costume. However, they saw plenty of people dealing with inappropriate behavior from co-workers that went unaddressed. The former employee recounted the experience of another woman at SpaceX who shared a cubicle with a man who would joke about putting porn on their shared TV and who made uncomfortable abortion jokes. Another female roommate of the employee wound up switching to a different team because of a team member’s unwanted advances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dD3bKO"&gt;All of the former employees who spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; believe SpaceX’s failure to adequately address inappropriate behavior in the workplace stems from a larger problem with the company’s culture that devalues individual workers. All of them felt that culture comes from upper management, notably from SpaceX CEO Elon Musk. Kosak argues in the essay that Musk “uses engineers as a resource to be mined rather than a team to be led.” They all say burnout is high at the company, and that everyone is dedicated to the mission of exploring space. Any distractions from that mission are seen as something to eliminate, they argue, even if it’s an employee reporting harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6R6T17"&gt;Ultimately, they see it as a big factor in why women leave the field of aerospace, and why the field continues to be dominated by men. The former employees hope that by sharing their stories, they’ll encourage other women to speak up. Along with the publication of Kosak’s essay, Lioness is also auctioning an NFT, the proceeds of which will go toward bringing more workplace harassment stories in the space industry and other fields to light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="LoAyRx"&gt;But most of all, the employees hope that women will feel safe in the field of aerospace someday. “I want women in aerospace to be able to be happy in the field and stay for decades and decades and contribute just like men do without being pushed out by issues that don’t get responded to,” says CrowleyFarenga. “I want them to be able to reach their full potential, which is what’s not happening because of misbehavior from men.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LGF4KK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rq1j47"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22831380/spacex-employees-harassment-workplace-misconduct-elon-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22831380/spacex-employees-harassment-workplace-misconduct-elon-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T13:33:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T13:33:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is requiring masks again at all US retail stores</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mFTDMXcCnSWV9xPeXmYwluX9qjk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70270378/acastro_190530_1777_wwdc_2019_0001.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sOfkHh"&gt;Apple is again requiring customers to wear masks in all its US retail stores after it had &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1470808052186161155"&gt;reportedly rolled back the mandate for around half of its locations&lt;/a&gt;. In an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; the company said that “amid rising cases in many communities, we now require that all customers join our team members in wearing masks while visiting our stores.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JOqYlz"&gt;While employees have been required to wear masks throughout most of the pandemic, customers haven’t always had to, which has led to outbreaks at some Apple stores. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1470808052186161155"&gt;also reports&lt;/a&gt; that some locations will have occupancy limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="B5IAIK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple reportedly started dropping mask mandates for some stores in November&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g8jhBI"&gt;Apple’s current mask policy was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763958/apple-mask-requirements-retail-store-customers-coronavirus"&gt;reportedly enacted in early November&lt;/a&gt; when some retail stores dropped the requirement following increased vaccination rates and decreased infection rates. This cycle seems to be a repeat of what happened this summer — Apple &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-13/apple-s-u-s-stores-offices-to-start-dropping-mask-requirement?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;started relaxing mask requirements&lt;/a&gt; for some stores in June but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598686/apple-retail-stores-mask-mandate-requirement"&gt;brought them back&lt;/a&gt; at most locations in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kdyi7h"&gt;Apple is reinstating these requirements as the number of COVID infections in the US is again on the rise, even as booster shots start to become widely available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i65K1T"&gt;This change also comes after a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826604/apple-store-closed-southlake-texas-covid-19-outbreak-black-friday"&gt;widespread outbreak was reported at an Apple store&lt;/a&gt; in Southlake, Texas, earlier this month. &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/apple/apple-store-texas-closes-covid-outbreak-rcna8000"&gt;According to NBC News&lt;/a&gt;, 22 employees at the location tested positive for COVID following Black Friday, where some staff reported that customers (who were not required to wear masks) were packed into the store “shoulder to shoulder.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ljTxM"&gt;Apple also told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;: “We regularly monitor conditions and we will adjust our health measures in stores to support the wellbeing of customers and employees.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834419/apple-retail-store-mask-requirement-december-2021-omicron-covid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834419/apple-retail-store-mask-requirement-december-2021-omicron-covid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-14T13:27:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T13:27:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>It’s easier for hackers to jailbreak the PS4 than it is to buy a PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="ps4 stock playstation 4" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PXwrRHNWeSfTLn9gUTfY0nAVcso=/0x0:1024x683/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70270314/ps4.0.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xEj60u"&gt;Hackers have jailbroken the PS4 with a new kernel exploit, &lt;a href="https://wololo.net/2021/12/13/ps4-9-00-jailbreak-poobs4-released/"&gt;according to Wololo.net&lt;/a&gt;, a website that covers jailbreaking news, seemingly opening the door for people to run things like homebrew apps on Sony’s last-gen consoles. The jailbreak is called “pOOBs4.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66tX5x"&gt;It’s a major development, but it comes with a big catch: the jailbreak only works on PS4 firmware 9.00 or lower, according to one of the people involved with the jailbreak, SpecterDev, which isn’t the newest PS4 software available. If you’ve already updated to the &lt;a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/hardware/ps4/system-software/"&gt;latest firmware, 9.03&lt;/a&gt;, the jailbreak apparently won’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Q8g9s0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Seeing a bit of confusion on 9.03 - this will *not* work on 9.03, it's patched. Only 9.00 and below.&lt;/p&gt;— Specter (@SpecterDev) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpecterDev/status/1470302473189535747?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c1lthK"&gt;Here’s a video from SpecterDev showing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpecterDev/status/1470225946007556097"&gt;unofficial software running on the PS4&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EDwcP7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;9.  (awesome work by chendochap &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Znullptr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Znullptr&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href="https://t.co/ME12bLyu3C"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ME12bLyu3C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Specter (@SpecterDev) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpecterDev/status/1470225946007556097?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SRQYn4"&gt;The kernel exploit &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; affects PS5, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Znullptr/status/1470263207122161668"&gt;according to Znullptr, another person involved with the jailbreak&lt;/a&gt;, but don’t get your hopes up about being able to mod your PS5’s software anytime soon, if ever. Znullptr says a PS5 version of the jailbreak “is not ready or being released” because the lead developer doesn’t have a PS5. (And it might be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22775829/sony-ps5-supply-chip-shortage-forecast-cut"&gt;hard to get one of the elusive consoles for a while&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V3pxFZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Alright, was just a joke about caturday.&lt;br&gt;The exploit is legit, and as a bonus:&lt;br&gt;The kernel exploit affects Playstation5 as well!&lt;br&gt;(no, ps5 is not ready or being released, the lead developer does not currently have a ps5 console)&lt;/p&gt;— Z (@Znullptr) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Znullptr/status/1470263207122161668?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834264/ps4-ps5-jailbreak-playstation-poobs4"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834264/ps4-ps5-jailbreak-playstation-poobs4</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
