<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-05T10:21:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-05T10:21:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-05T10:21:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk reportedly plans to move to Texas</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Elon Musk Awarded With Axel Springer Award In Berlin" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nm-Y0LsGYapj9TAWrOlkjLab1p4=/0x19:5333x3574/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68462958/1229892934.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Britta Pedersen-Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eFSxTo"&gt;Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk is planning to move from California to Texas, a move that would potentially save him from a huge personal income tax bill, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/02/tesla-ceo-elon-musk-plans-to-move-to-texas-friends-and-associates-say.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A4q4qM"&gt;Musk announced in July that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/22/21334860/tesla-cybertruck-factory-austin-texas-location-model-y"&gt;Tesla was building its next US factory in Austin,&lt;/a&gt; where it will produce its Cybertruck, Model Y, Model 3, and Semi vehicles. The company received &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/14/21323977/austin-tesla-tax-breaks-travis-county-cybertruck-factory-incentives"&gt;tens of millions of dollars&lt;/a&gt; in local property tax breaks to build the plant on 2,100 acres east of Austin’s airport, over the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21300909/tesla-austin-cybertruck-gigafactory-elon-musk-tax-breaks"&gt;objections of some local residents&lt;/a&gt;. The factory is expected to begin delivering its first vehicles in 2021. Musk’s Boring Company already has operations in Austin, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/29/20889605/spacex-elon-musk-starship-rocket-update-pictures-mk1"&gt;SpaceX has a facility&lt;/a&gt; in Boca Chica, Texas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RqqtY0"&gt;Earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1256239554148724737"&gt;Musk tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that he was “selling almost all physical possessions. Will own no house.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TdEzEx"&gt;Musk &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21201651/tesla-fremont-factory-covid-19-coronavirus-shutdown-shelter-in-place"&gt;battled with officials in California&lt;/a&gt; in recent months over pandemic lockdown orders that temporarily shuttered Tesla’s Fremont plant. In May, Musk said he was going to move the automaker out of state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fVNyf5"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Frankly, this is the final straw. Tesla will now move its HQ and future programs to Texas/Nevada immediately. If we even retain Fremont manufacturing activity at all, it will be dependen on how Tesla is treated in the future. Tesla is the last carmaker left in CA.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1259162367285317633?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 9, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6r6hxP"&gt;In November, Tesla said employees at its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/20/21587781/tesla-workers-california-fremont-exempt-new-covid-19-order-newsom"&gt;Fremont plant were “essential workers”&lt;/a&gt; and exempt from California’s new statewide COVID-19 health orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S52fn4"&gt;If Musk does change his permanent address to Texas, he’d pay significantly less in taxes, as &lt;em&gt;CNBC &lt;/em&gt;notes. Musk stands to earn more than $50 billion in stock options, and would have to pay income taxes on the profits when he exercises them if he remained in California. Texas, however, has &lt;a href="https://statutes.capitol.texas.gov/Docs/CN/htm/CN.8.htm"&gt;no personal income tax&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eGfZYh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/5/22155743/elon-musk-moving-texas-tesla-spacex-california"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/5/22155743/elon-musk-moving-texas-tesla-spacex-california</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-05T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-05T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Preparation for a big COVID-19 vaccine rollout is underway </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Training At The Covid-19 Vaccination Clinic In Coventry" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2KDfg37tVICKwDmPoCZftxrsYP4=/0x184:4597x3249/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68462898/1229942180.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Medical personnel train for vaccine distribution in the UK.  | Photo by Steve Parsons - WPA Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dX1uMk"&gt;In the US, COVID-19 vaccines are just around the corner, leaving the entire country peering out the window in anticipation of their arrival. Officials and healthcare systems, already taxed by &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2020/12/the-worst-case-scenario-is-happening-hospitals-are-overwhelmed/617301/"&gt;skyrocketing case counts&lt;/a&gt; are making sure that everything is prepared when they show up. Here’s a few things still on their vaccine to-do lists: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rkwcrj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save the dates: &lt;/strong&gt;In the next few weeks, committees with the Food and Drug Administration will meet to decide whether or not to authorize vaccine candidates for Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna. The Pfizer vaccine is up first, with a meeting &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/advisory-committees/advisory-committee-calendar/vaccines-and-related-biological-products-advisory-committee-december-10-2020-meeting-announcement"&gt;scheduled for December 10th&lt;/a&gt;. Moderna’s &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-announces-advisory-committee-meeting-discuss-second-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;meeting will happen a week later, on December 17&lt;/a&gt;. The committee will meet to discuss the mountains of data from the clinical trials, and decide if they are safe and effective enough to be distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SADE3U"&gt;While the US is taking some time to do thorough background checks on the vaccines, others have expedited the process. This week, the UK authorized the Pfizer / BioNTech vaccine, &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/02/u-k-approves-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-putting-pressure-on-fda/"&gt;putting pressure on the US&lt;/a&gt; to do the same. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="yjopOK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F3TlO7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seating arrangements: &lt;/strong&gt;Once the FDA has decided which vaccines are invited to the party, states need to have a plan for their allotted doses. Friday, December 5 was the &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Health/wireStory/states-submit-vaccine-orders-coronavirus-death-toll-grows-74544381"&gt;deadline for states to place orders for the Pfizer / BioNTech vaccine&lt;/a&gt;. And earlier this week, a committee of the CDC met to finalize their recommendations as to who should get the vaccine first. The VIPs who are most likely to receive the vaccine first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21779433/covid-vaccine-priority-health-care-workers-long-term-care"&gt;are healthcare workers&lt;/a&gt; and people living and working in long-term care facilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wKx8qL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Menu planning: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/20/21587664/pfizer-moderna-covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine-two-doses-shots"&gt;As expected&lt;/a&gt;, the vaccine front runners are both two dose vaccines, and the vaccines have to be given weeks apart. This is a challenge for states who now have to make sure that everyone gets the right vaccine at the right time. They plan to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22153908/covid-vaccine-dose-tracking-digital-registry-fda"&gt;use digital databases&lt;/a&gt; to track who got which vaccine, and when they got their shot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTBTJb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing out the fridge(s): &lt;/strong&gt;These vaccines have to be kept very cold. They can both stay potent for a while at refrigerator-like temperatures, but for longer-term storage Pfizer / BioNTech’s &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/11/17/935563377/why-does-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-need-to-be-kept-colder-than-antarctica"&gt;needs to chill at minus 70 degrees Celsius&lt;/a&gt;. That has states clearing out cold storage and buying up dry ice anywhere they can as they prep for the vaccine’s arrival. In Maine, community college freezers may be pressed into service as the state starts vaccinating more people, the head of the Maine Center for Disease Control and Prevention &lt;a href="https://slate.com/technology/2020/12/maine-covid-vaccine-distribution-plan.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Slate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qzQw4l"&gt;There’s still a lot more to do before the first doses start trickling in. First on the priority list, there’s a surge of cases and hospitalizations that must be stopped. Then, transparent plans and communications need to set the tone for a vaccine campaign. The vaccines need to be delivered equitably, and researchers will have to keep a watchful eye on the long-term effects of the vaccines. But if all of those can be accomplished, and this hastily-planned vaccine effort can be pulled off, it will be a triumph. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1f3Ygs"&gt;Here’s what else is happening this week: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q1kdm0"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="AVg4JD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://zeynep.substack.com/p/small-data-big-implications"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small Data, Big Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;How dangerous is it to dine inside a restaurant right now? There’s still a dearth of data, but some fascinating studies are coming out, including a recent one from South Korea, broken down in this article by sociologist Zeynep Tufekci. Tufekci’s newsletter &lt;em&gt;Insight &lt;/em&gt;is worth a read — &lt;a href="https://zeynep.substack.com/p/the-pandemic-heroes-who-gave-us-the"&gt;another post this week&lt;/a&gt; highlights the efforts of Chinese researchers to sound the an early alarm on this virus.&lt;br&gt;(Zeynep Tufekci&lt;em&gt;/Insight&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5abKtM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/03/health/coronavirus-testing-labs-workers.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Nobody Sees Us’: Testing-Lab Workers Strain Under Demand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;In labs across the US, scientists and lab workers are reaching a breaking point as demand for tests continues to grow. &lt;br&gt;(Katherine J Wu/&lt;em&gt;The New York Times)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NuuSJJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22150189/covid-19-cdc-quarantine-guidelines-coronavirus"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why the CDC changed its Covid-19 quarantine guidelines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The CDC officially changed its guidelines for quarantine this week, shortening the time frame in certain scenarios. The reason why? It hopes more people will stick to a shorter quarantine schedule. Later in the week, the &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2020/12/04/cdc-mask-guidance-indoors/"&gt;agency urged ‘universal face mask use’&lt;/a&gt; for the first time in a &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/69/wr/mm6949e2.htm?s_cid=mm6949e2_w"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;(German Lopez/&lt;em&gt;Vox)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RHFOup"&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HQ9lPA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/02/how-society-can-make-the-most-of-covid-19-vaccines/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The COVID-19 vaccines are a marvel of science. Here’s how we can make the best use of them&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;If you want a &lt;em&gt;really &lt;/em&gt;deep dive into how experts think these vaccines should be used, this is an article for you. It lays out the challenges and opportunities facing us all in this next phase of the pandemic. &lt;br&gt;(Helen Branswell/&lt;em&gt;Stat)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gN2NCP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22153908/covid-vaccine-dose-tracking-digital-registry-fda"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multidose COVID-19 vaccines will test state tracking systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;States plan to keep tabs on who gets vaccinated and when they get their doses. Here’s how that will work. &lt;br&gt;(Nicole Wetsman/&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cx26K8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/03/cdc-advisory-panels-lone-dissenter-on-why-long-term-care-residents-shouldnt-receive-covid-19-vaccine-first/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CDC advisory panel’s lone dissenter on why long-term care residents shouldn’t receive COVID-19 vaccine first&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;This week, when a CDC advisory panel met to decide who they thought should be the first to receive vaccines, there was only one person who opposed the recommendation. Here’s why she cast a dissenting vote. &lt;br&gt;(Helen Branswell/&lt;em&gt;Stat)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8lS21"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22151016/hackers-phishing-coronavirus-vaccine-ibm-security"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hackers are targeting the COVID-19 vaccine supply chain, IBM finds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;There’s now evidence that phishing attacks are targeting the vaccine ‘cold chain’. Experts still aren’t sure what the end goal of the infiltration might be, or who is behind it. &lt;br&gt;(Monica Chin/&lt;em&gt;The Verge)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MFh8Le"&gt;Perspectives &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SfuEvG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/12/03/opinion/covid-19-vaccine-timeline.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find Your Place in the Vaccine Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;To put things in perspective, check out this infographic showing an approximation of where you are in the line for a vaccine. &lt;br&gt;(Stuart Thompson/&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="25LbB6"&gt;COVID doesn’t care how you vote, where you live or if you die. The fire burns all around us and we are dry grass, from sea to shining sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="7iIJWp"&gt;—Mark Morocco, a physician in Los Angeles &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/opinion/story/2020-11-23/medical-workers-angry-lame-coronavirus-excuses"&gt;writing in &lt;em&gt;The Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="S1Rr3R"&gt;For two hours that summer night, there were no sounds but soft piano and the gentle beep beep beep of the monitors. Klein thought about how he would feel if the person in the bed were his own father, and he squeezed his hand tighter. Around midnight, Klein watched as the man took one last, ragged breath and died.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="b2ifJ4"&gt;—Elaine Godfrey writes in her article “&lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2020/12/how-iowa-mishandled-coronavirus-pandemic/617252/"&gt;Iowa Is What Happens When Government Does Nothing&lt;/a&gt;” in &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SFOVQC"&gt;More than numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="y94GO9"&gt;To the more than 65,760,928 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qbnoli"&gt;To the families and friends of the 1,515,990 people who have died worldwide — 278,594 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M4cwFh"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZthsA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pvVtvF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/5/22153805/covid-19-vaccine-rollout-preparation-antivirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/5/22153805/covid-19-vaccine-rollout-preparation-antivirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mary Beth Griggs</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-05T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-05T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s Selena doesn’t have a lot of Selena</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XTbb8q6LxmP_vRfjyOcMHS2cLIo=/0x91:7452x5059/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68462913/Selena_102_Sc41_0055_R3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cesar Fuentes Cervantes / Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IZ2btE"&gt;There haven’t been many musicians like Selena Quintanilla: she was a Tejano superstar who managed to find major label mainstream success as one of the music industry’s first Latin artists to top the charts. Her dazzling career was cut tragically short when she was murdered by a fan in the spring of 1995, just before her 24th birthday. A 1997 film, &lt;em&gt;Selena&lt;/em&gt;, which starred Jennifer Lopez in the titular role, solidified her legend — anointing her as a pop culture saint and a bridge between cultures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GRGn1n"&gt;The real Selena Quintanilla, however, was a complex person with an interior life beyond her star persona and her tragic death. She’s a person whose life is worth diving deeper into, beyond the constraints of a two-hour Hollywood picture. In another world, Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;Selena: The Series&lt;/em&gt;, now streaming a nine-episode “Part 1,” might have been that. But the new series isn’t interested in any of this. It’s barely interested in Selena herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9zoiPk"&gt;After moving swiftly through her childhood with a premiere showing young Selena (Daniela Estrada) discovering music and her father Abraham’s (Ricardo Chavira) early attempts at getting his other children to form a band around her incredible talent, the Netflix series settles into her teen years — when her dream starts to become a reality. As a teenager, Selena’s (Christian Serratos) career begins in earnest, with her father managing the band she’s settled into with her siblings, Selena y Los Dinos. The series shows her navigating the difficulties of poverty and playing Tejano music while dealing with racism from Americans and skepticism from Mexicans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nta2Wz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Selena: The Series&lt;/em&gt; treads familiar ground for anyone who has seen the 1995 film or any story about making it in America as an immigrant. You start small, with an impossible belief in the opportunities this country can provide, and then, with perseverance and a little luck, you get your own slice of the American dream. You prove to the world that your culture is worth celebrating. The series hews very closely to these familiar beats, so much so that it’s less a story about Selena and more one about her father, Abraham. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0pneD"&gt;The show makes clear that it’s Abraham’s dashed dreams of having a band of his own that fuels his support of his daughter’s career, his controlling attitude that keeps the band focused but also suffocates his children. His pride and ambition are at the center of most of the show’s conflicts. Selena, for the most part, is just along for the ride. In later episodes, as her star rises, she bemoans the lack of a normal life as touring keeps her from socializing with friends and dating boys. (In fact, she gains the most agency when, late in this clutch of episodes, she decides to date someone against her father’s wishes.) But again: her father is there, giving her arc its friction, and sucking up all the oxygen in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6w6TM3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Selena: The Series&lt;/em&gt; isn’t interested in its subject as anything other than a symbol, a prayer candle to keep lit while the rest of the Quintanilla family gets proper narrative treatments. Selena’s sister Suzette (who also serves as an executive producer) begins the show afraid of receding into the background as Selena’s drummer but ends up inspiring fans in her own right. Her brother, A.B., gets significant screen time depicting how he grows as a songwriter and chafes under his father’s leadership. Despite being the ostensible focus of the series, Selena doesn’t get the same space. She’s mostly shown as cherubic: smiling, singing, and ultimately not saying very much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MUZXAA"&gt;In her &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; story about the ongoing exploitation of Selena Quintanilla, writer Alex Zaragoza criticizes &lt;em&gt;Selena: The Series&lt;/em&gt; as an extension of the nonstop merchandising of the star’s image and story that has ultimately flattened her identity and remade her into a bland symbol of Latinx success. “The fullness of her identity is in danger of becoming a faded carbon copy of its original self,” &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/5dp983/netflix-selena-the-series-latinx-exploitation"&gt;writes Zaragoza&lt;/a&gt;, noting that Serratos’ performance reflects this, reading as a performance based on Lopez’s film version of Selena and not the human being herself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BDdAwy"&gt;The result is a show that feels cheap. The feeling is magnified by a moment in the series’s ninth episode when Suzette makes an innocuous-seeming phone call to a fan to see if she’s willing to run the fan club. It’s a bit of dramatic irony that gives away the game: you know the woman at the other end of the line is going to say yes, just as you know that the show, should it return, will eventually show this particular fan shooting and killing Selena Quintanilla. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cvn6UJ"&gt;This is the Selena that &lt;em&gt;Selena: The Series&lt;/em&gt; is most interested in: the one you already know, the one forever frozen in time and infinitely marketable. If there’s a more complex Selena to discover in between, you won’t find her here.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22154137/netflix-selena-jennifer-lopez-merchandise"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22154137/netflix-selena-jennifer-lopez-merchandise</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Rivera</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-05T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-05T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>A cheap tablet is a great entertainment device</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Tab A7 is a good cheap tablet&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="waI69m"&gt;I’m here to tell you that cheap tablets are good. I’m not here to tell you that they are the future of computing or will replace your laptop for getting work done. But I will tell you they are great entertainment devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9KSiUT"&gt;The best way to experience a cheap tablet is to just install the apps you use for entertainment and relaxation: Kindle, Hulu, Prime Video, HBO Max, Pocket, whatever your vice of choice is. Don’t install or set up things like Twitter, Slack, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; app, email, or anything that’s going to take away from leisure time and suck you into work or the dreaded doomscroll. This is a tablet you buy to watch video and read things, not to try to replace your laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8Bfuq"&gt;I’ve been testing Samsung’s Galaxy Tab A7 for the past few months and found that it is an excellent example of a cheap tablet. At $229.99 (and often available for less), it’s much more affordable than an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451699/apple-ipad-2020-review-eighth-generation-bionic-processor-zoom"&gt;entry-level iPad&lt;/a&gt;, but it works just as well for watching video and reading books and articles. I’m not one to go around recommending Android tablets — an iPad is objectively better in almost every scenario — but the Tab A7 is surprisingly competent and priced right for its tertiary device status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="67kiX4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10201334"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q1TIc8"&gt;The bar for a tablet that is destined to be just a personal entertainment device is actually quite low. It needs an engaging screen with enough resolution so you won’t see individual pixels at a comfortable distance, speakers that aren’t muffled or crackly sounding, and battery life that will let you get through a few movies between charges since you likely won’t be plugging this thing in after every time you use it. It should also be thin and relatively light so you can hold it for long periods without getting tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="amU6qb"&gt;The Tab A7 exceeds all of those metrics. The 10.4-inch 1080p screen is vibrant and colorful, the battery easily goes for 10 hours or more of video, and the quad-speaker system sounds tremendous. It’s surprisingly thin, with a metal chassis that feels stiffer and nicer than the plastic-clad Amazon Fire tablets. There’s just enough bezel around the screen so I can comfortably handle it without worrying about errant touches, and it’s light enough so I can even hold it in one hand for reading. It even has a 3.5mm headphone jack for when you don’t want to disturb anyone else while watching the seventh episode of &lt;em&gt;The Boys&lt;/em&gt; in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ptFyJqGKeM-kK1VSFj_lYQ31YnE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22024669/dseifert_201107_4280_0007.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Tab A7’s display is great for watching movies and TV shows, and the four speakers put out surprisingly excellent sound.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BNn3Bd"&gt;Where the Tab A7 comes short won’t be a surprise, but none of its faults stop it from being a good entertainment device. Its low-midrange Qualcomm Snapdragon 662 processor and 3GB of RAM make it far from the fastest or snappiest device around — but that doesn’t matter when you’re using the video or ebook app of your choice. Its cameras suck, but on the other hand, if you do use it for a Zoom call, it’s way less awkward than an iPad, thanks to the correct placement of the front camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DKRJTC"&gt;Android doesn’t have nearly the breadth or depth of apps as the iPad, but it has all of the major streaming video services (save for Apple TV Plus) and all of the book-reading apps you could want. There’s only 32GB of storage in the base model, but it supports microSD card expansion, so it’s easy to add more. Finally, Tab A7 lacks any sort of fingerprint scanner or biometrics login, but since I just use it at home and don’t have any sensitive or work data on it, I’m comfortable disabling the secure screen lock to make it easier to get to binge-watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cvo3MXHmbZ37LvpUtH_M3I69A-Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22024672/dseifert_201107_4280_0004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Tab A7’s metal chassis is thin and stiff and nicer than the plastic you usually find at this price point.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2PO3SDZoTq1cVcmRbiHGSUcDEMQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22024670/dseifert_201107_4280_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yay for USB-C charging and quad speakers. (There are two on the other side.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r84yNt"&gt;Samsung isn’t pushing any productivity features here: it doesn’t come with a stylus, there’s no keyboard case available for it, and it doesn’t have Samsung’s DeX desktop software mode. It doesn’t even have Samsung’s dumber-than-average Bixby voice assistant. (The Google Assistant is available and works just like on any other device.) Instead of spending time and resources developing features most people won’t use, Samsung focused on what matters here: putting the best speakers and perhaps the best display you can get in a tablet at this price point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SkS4JD"&gt;And really, that’s all you could want from a tablet like this. It needs to look good, it needs to sound good, and it needs to have the apps with the content you want. The Tab A7 checks all of those boxes and no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="hgziOR"&gt;It’s the best anti-doomscrolling gadget you can get this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e4TbSd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="7mbkj0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10201371"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22150980/samsung-galaxy-tab-a7-tablet-review-price-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22150980/samsung-galaxy-tab-a7-tablet-review-price-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-04T21:02:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T21:02:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>The US government will let TikTok run out the clock and ‘overlook’ its own deadline</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZW8L8BkMGjO0i-9LYWeiBZCOEAA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68461504/acastro_200803_1777_tikTok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="okQe7F"&gt;The Trump administration won’t enforce its own deadline for ByteDance to sell or spin out video-sharing platform TikTok’s business in the US, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-05/tiktok-sale-deadline-is-put-on-hold-as-talks-with-u-s-continue"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8YXWtx"&gt;The latest deadline for that move, given by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/28/21723883/bytedance-extension-us-government-tiktok-sale-oracle-trump"&gt;on November 28th&lt;/a&gt;, was today, December 4th. An extension isn’t expected, though the current deadline will “be overlooked while the discussions continue” between the Trump administration and TikTok, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8QkZCx"&gt;CNN tech reporter Brian Fung is corroborating that the US won’t enforce its own deadline, with his sources amusingly suggesting that the &lt;em&gt;lack&lt;/em&gt; of a deadline is proof that the US is “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/b_fung/status/1335024625298919425"&gt;highly motivated&lt;/a&gt;” to complete talks about the sale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FhrJI8"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;US officials are “highly motivated” to complete the talks, the person said, and added that the lack of a new, specific deadline is indicative of that.&lt;/p&gt;— Brian Fung (@b_fung) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/b_fung/status/1335024625298919425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 5, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kueYVg"&gt;The Trump administration has repeatedly argued that TikTok and ByteDance are a national security risk, and the US Commerce Department issued an order to block downloads of TikTok &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/21445060/trump-tiktok-wechat-ban-us-apple-app-store-google-play-commerce-department"&gt;in September&lt;/a&gt;. But Trump then said that he approved of a bid by Oracle and Walmart “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/19/21437850/president-trump-approves-oracle-tiktok-partnership-bytedance-china-ban"&gt;in concept&lt;/a&gt;” to create a new US-based entity called TikTok Global, though it’s not clear how that would address concerns of security risks. That deal also requires final approval from China, which hasn’t come yet, either. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154801/us-government-tiktok-ban-deadline-bytedance-trump-administration-cfius"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154801/us-government-tiktok-ban-deadline-bytedance-trump-administration-cfius</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-04T21:01:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T21:01:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Fi is offering $100 to upgrade your 3G phone before it stops working</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-NdljImFs0d0G5zgAlypHSwcftE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68461500/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="60j1FS"&gt;Google Fi will stop activating non-VoLTE phones in January, and encourage customers with older phones to upgrade with a $100 credit provided they purchase a new phone from the Fi store and activate it before December 31st, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/12/04/google-fi-volte/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LfR1r4"&gt;Google’s hand is forced in the matter. Customers subscribe to Fi, but as an MVNO, Fi actually piggybacks on T-Mobile and US Cellular’s networks to provide coverage. Since T-Mobile has already announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21336397/t-mobile-require-support-volte-2021-5g-lte"&gt;its own plans to phase out support for non-VoLTE phones&lt;/a&gt; starting in January 2021, Fi has to as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="TzjZ75"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Requiring VoLTE all but assures 3G’s days are numbered&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NN5wBe"&gt;VoLTE stands for “Voice over LTE”, which is the handling of phone calls over LTE data rather than older 3G tech. VoLTE calls are typically clearer, with fewer drops in connection, though they’re completely unavailable to older phones that only use 3G radios and even some early LTE models as well. Google stopped activating 2G and 3G phones August 4th of this year &lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/faq/"&gt;according to the Fi FAQs&lt;/a&gt;, but requiring VoLTE all but assures 3G’s days are numbered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oOBEHY"&gt;There’s no hard date for the end of 3G service at Fi, but it is coming, and until Google makes an official announcement, your best bet is to look for when T-Mobile ends its coverage. T-Mobile gained a lot of sway over what Fi can offer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/1/21202726/tmobile-sprint-acquisition-ceo-finished-john-legere-steps-down"&gt;when it purchased Sprint&lt;/a&gt;, giving it control over both of the biggest networks Fi relied on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fxo3Gf"&gt;There’s actually a couple cheap options on the Fi store that could serve as a quick fix. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap"&gt;We like Google’s Pixel 4a&lt;/a&gt;, which normally sells for $349, but there’s also options that you could get &lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/phones/moto-g-power"&gt;for less than $100&lt;/a&gt; with Google’s current holiday promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CB5irS"&gt;Upgrading to better cell service is a long term good for the usability of phones, but it is an inconvenience to customers. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/7/17/17582370/verizon-stops-3g-activations-smartphone-network-shutdown"&gt;Verizon already made its change&lt;/a&gt; a while back, phasing out elements of 3G services in favor of LTE and 5G over time. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/22/21334221/att-customer-upgrade-email-3g-shutdown-2022"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21336397/t-mobile-require-support-volte-2021-5g-lte"&gt;T-Mobile’s&lt;/a&gt; plans are a bit more abrupt. There’s an intense focus on upgrading to 5G that seems to be motivating all of this, which is especially inconvenient because around 30 million Americans &lt;a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/3g-use-america-1067961/"&gt;still used 3G exclusively as of 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Unless customers are able to upgrade, they could be left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154364/google-fi-volte-tmobile-upgrade-end-support-clearer-calls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154364/google-fi-volte-tmobile-upgrade-end-support-clearer-calls</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-04T20:34:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T20:34:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hope you weren’t planning to watch Wonder Woman 1984 with an HBO Max free trial</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bv2vBOzjqyLkPn2CFbQGE0mKhJU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68461413/acastro_200602_1777_HBOMax_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9y7hGh"&gt;It may be time to pour one out for the streaming service trial. &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/hbo-max-kills-one-week-free-trial-before-wonder-woman-1984-hits-dec-25/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNET &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that HBO Max is no longer offering users a free week of watching its content, following both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/19/21296717/disney-plus-no-free-trial-streaming-hamilton-release-monthly-subscription"&gt;Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514661/netflix-free-trial-us-cancel-content-sampling-streaming"&gt;Netflix’s examples&lt;/a&gt; earlier in the year. This change, probably not coincidentally, comes just weeks before December 25th, when &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt; is set to launch on the service (as well as in theaters, but you should probably stay home). While it can’t compete with free, the $14.99 you’ll now have to pay to see the movie still compares favorably to the price of a theater ticket (and it’s a month of entertainment as opposed to two-ish hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6KnkmX"&gt;It’s not the first streaming service to nix a free trial before a big release: Disney Plus did it just a few weeks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/19/21296717/disney-plus-no-free-trial-streaming-hamilton-release-monthly-subscription"&gt;before it started streaming &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The logic is sound, if annoying: people want to watch the Big New Thing, and if you offered a free trial, they might just watch it and bounce. If they have to pay for it for a month, a lot will, and they might get hooked on something else while they’re looking around for other content to justify their month-long subscription. Or, if you’re HBO Max, they might see the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"&gt;absolute deluge of movies&lt;/a&gt; coming to the service next year and decide it’s worth keeping around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A promotional picture of Wonder Woman 1984" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ePKGrOkaB8tivzdSNnbsVOMze8g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19821876/wonder_woman.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Free trials don’t recoup a $200 million production budget.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="D6wmG7"&gt;So, if you were hoping to use the free trial to watch &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt;, it’s not an option anymore. Is it worth paying for a month of HBO Max? You’ll have to decide, though whether or not you’re willing to pay will probably be determined by how many of the other streaming services you pay for, because &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/streaming-wars"&gt;there sure are a lot of them&lt;/a&gt;. As for me, I’m just sad I have to cancel my plans of having an incredible week of free movie watching at the end of next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ceTPiH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Warner Bros. will release all of its new 2021 movies simultaneously on HBO Max","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="GgzxZT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154553/hbo-max-ditches-one-week-free-trial-ahead-of-wonder-woman-1984"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154553/hbo-max-ditches-one-week-free-trial-ahead-of-wonder-woman-1984</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-04T19:39:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T19:39:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple will replace your iPhone 11’s display for free if it has the glitchy touchscreen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D8PT62YDNXml7OSbonHaanfBhiA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68460383/akrales_190913_3628_0277.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="L3xLK2"&gt;If your iPhone 11 isn’t responding to touches, it might be eligible for a free fix from Apple. The company has launched a replacement program for iPhone 11 displays that stop responding to touches “due to an issue with the display module.” Apple says that “a small percentage of iPhone 11 displays” are affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DeMZH4"&gt;Devices affected by the issue were manufactured between November 2019 and May 2020, Apple said, meaning not every phone is affected. If you’re seeing the issue on your iPhone 11, you can check to see if your phone is eligible for the program by plugging its serial number into a box on &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/iphone-11-display-module-replacement-program"&gt;Apple’s website for the replacement program&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fPTNR6"&gt;If your phone is eligible for replacement, you can find one of Apple’s authorized service providers to help, make an appointment at an Apple retail store, or contact Apple support to arrange for a mail in. And Apple says that affected phones are covered for two years from the day you bought it, so if the issue comes up for you sometime in that two-year window, you’re still eligible for a free replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="bSBaRc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple iPhone 11 review: the phone most people should buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/17/20869456/apple-iphone-11-review-camera-price-budget-battery-screen-size-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22154507/apple-iphone-11-free-replacement-program-display-touchscreen-touch-module"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22154507/apple-iphone-11-free-replacement-program-display-touchscreen-touch-module</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-04T18:59:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T18:59:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple developers can now let you share free copies of your in-app purchases with your family  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mrPbwH8TGYX2Qt3aYbPktzsIRXU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68460226/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BJhO3f"&gt;If you’ve ever wished you could share an in-app purchase with your family, you may be in luck. Today, &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=4zbvn7u9"&gt;Apple announced&lt;/a&gt; that subscriptions and one-time in-app purchases can now be shared among families. If you buy a consumable item, like coins in a game, you’ll still be the only one who can use them, but if you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/suppliesapp/status/1334955683658280962?s=20"&gt;unlock an ad-free or pro version&lt;/a&gt; of an app it could be eligible for the new Family Sharing program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WNZyX6"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2020%2F06%2Fapple-introduces-macos-big-sur-with-a-beautiful-new-design%2F%23mn_p&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F4%2F22154178%2Fapple-family-sharing-allows-subscriptions-in-app-purchases#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announced this change back in June&lt;/a&gt; with Big Sur, but it’s finally letting developers flip the switch to allow subscriptions and purchases to be shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TGvyeg"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;App developer PSA: it is now possible to enable Family Sharing for IAPs and subscriptions, but you have to turn that on in App Store Connect. For subscriptions, it's under the duration… &lt;a href="https://t.co/Hj3NBRN3L0"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Hj3NBRN3L0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steve Harris (@steveharris) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/steveharris/status/1334615046090076162?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 3, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HXhaqh"&gt;Developers will need to flip that switch, though, as allowing Family Sharing of a subscription or purchase &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/steveharris/status/1334615046090076162"&gt;is a manual opt-in&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment, only one of my subscriptions, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/food_noms/status/1334683219405508614?s=20"&gt;calorie-tracking app FoodNoms&lt;/a&gt;, allows sharing its subscription, but other big names such as &lt;a href="https://blog.ulysses.app/family-sharing/"&gt;writing app Ulysses&lt;/a&gt; have also announced support for the feature. However, it does seem like the functionality is rolling out slowly. I asked my sister if she could access a subscription I had shared, and she couldn’t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="crBTtQ"&gt;If you’re the person who buys the subscriptions in the family, It’s easy to check which of them have the option to share by going to &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt;, then clicking on your name. From there, tap &lt;strong&gt;Subscriptions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Screenshot showing the Share New Subscriptions toggle" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FPjn4y0ldlk5BlutxoIWF5G5VYg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146161/Share_new_subscriptions_toggle.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ovBrVb"&gt;At the top of the screen, you’ll see a switch labeled Share New Subscriptions. Setting it to on will automatically give your family members access to any eligible in-app subscriptions that you sign up for. If you’re planning on signing up for any embarrassing subscriptions that you think might get shared with mom and dad, you may want to turn this off for the time being. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftboW0"&gt;Beneath that, you’ll see the list of your current subscriptions. Tapping on one will bring you to the Edit Subscription screen, where you’ll see a Share with Family switch if the developer has decided to allow it. Turning it on will give your family access to the subscription just as if they had bought it themselves!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Screenshot showing an Edit Subscription page on iPhone, with the new Share with Family toggle" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_i_VpA4YgzRGr4T7PkSX8Lbxb7E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146180/Share_with_family_subscription_toggle.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Share with Family toggle will show up on apps that support sharing. For me, it was off by default.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="887Sl4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/12/04/family-sharing-subscriptions-in-app-purchases/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; has reported&lt;/a&gt; that the process is different for sharing one-time in-app purchases. For example, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WorkingCopyApp/status/1334871247440769024?s=20"&gt;Working Copy’&lt;/a&gt;s Pro version unlock is done through an in-app payment. For a family member to be able to access it, they’ll have to go to the App Store, click on their account button in the upper right corner, go to &lt;strong&gt;Purchased&lt;/strong&gt;, and then select the family member that purchased the unlock. They’ll then have to download the app from that screen. Depending on how the app is set up, they may then need to click the Restore Purchases button. This process is way more involved, so I’d love to see some tweaks to it down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kwcujz"&gt;If your favorite app doesn’t support subscription sharing yet, it may be worth checking back in on the Subscription screen from time to time. There are reports of users &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/viticci/status/1334611244083507210"&gt;getting notifications&lt;/a&gt; when one of their subscriptions becomes eligible for Family Sharing, but I haven’t gotten any yet. Given that I’m currently not able to share my budgeting app subscription with my wife, I’ll certainly be checking the Subscription screen every once in a while to see if my favorite apps are adopting the model. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154178/apple-family-sharing-allows-subscriptions-in-app-purchases"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154178/apple-family-sharing-allows-subscriptions-in-app-purchases</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-04T17:40:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T17:40:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube and Peacock are now streaming 22 James Bond films for free</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Goldfinger" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JwGsKkDGB9VI1JB2YYtbLRyG9-k=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68459806/gfcomputer-goldfinger-lyrics-balloons-media-hdcaptures-red-106111.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Om8vWw"&gt;Maybe you’re feeling nostalgic for a classic James Bond film following &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/31/21543223/sean-connery-james-bond-dies"&gt;Sean Connery’s death in late October&lt;/a&gt;. Or perhaps you’re simply feeling a gap given that the next film, &lt;em&gt;No Time to Die&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21499362/james-bond-no-time-to-die-delay-april-2021"&gt;got pushed back to April 2021 or beyond&lt;/a&gt;. Either way, you can now binge a sizable selection of the James Bond collection completely for free (with ads) &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLwwhtOnMyjuyEeWvv6UX11aw3jFLFAxU1"&gt;from YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.peacocktv.com/watch/home/Free-Bond-Binge"&gt;Peacock&lt;/a&gt; (with a free account), and &lt;a href="https://pluto.tv/on-demand"&gt;PlutoTV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hBSYEA"&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: Comcast, which owns Peacock parent NBCUniversal, is also an investor in Vox Media, &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt;’s parent company.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pq0pop"&gt;Not every provider has every film, and a few aren’t on streaming services at all: you’ll need to rent &lt;em&gt;Skyfall&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Spectre&lt;/em&gt; if you care to watch those again. It’s also not clear how long these films will be free to stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tQOv81"&gt;But every Sean Connery, Roger Moore, Timothy Dalton, Pierce Brosnan, and George Lazenby Bond film is represented here for now, and the first couple of Daniel Craig flicks as well. I’ve bolded the ones you can find on YouTube that you can’t find on Peacock and vice versa. &lt;a href="https://pluto.tv/on-demand"&gt;PlutoTV has all of the below&lt;/a&gt;, save &lt;em&gt;Quantum of Solace&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fUtPoA"&gt;You can also find most of the films on Hulu and Amazon Prime this month, though you’d have to pay for those subscriptions, and Netflix has &lt;em&gt;Casino Royale&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Quantum of Solace&lt;/em&gt;, and three Pierce Brosnan flicks including &lt;em&gt;GoldenEye &lt;/em&gt;— newly relevant &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22150330/arecibo-observatory-collapse-drone-footage-video"&gt;now that the famed Arecibo Observatory, which gets destroyed in the film, has also collapsed in real life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="c1Uyva"&gt;YouTube, 20 films&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="YDFDzP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. No&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="W5iQqV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Russia with Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vSCMrB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goldfinger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9yAag2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thunderball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PpPufd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;You Only Live Twice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RHencQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Her Majesty’s Secret Service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="plGCrp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diamonds Are Forever&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9aioc6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never Say Never Again&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GTSPV9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Live and Let Die&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ezNO4e"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Man with the Golden Gun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0YqTLQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Spy who Loved Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dUQvht"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moonraker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ke47oK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Your Eyes Only&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f8fY4N"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Octopussy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LNrqTF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A View to a Kill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Pve7yA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Living Daylights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4yXsAM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Licence to Kill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="u5GE3d"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoldenEye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ygRbvP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tomorrow Never Dies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yNvR7z"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The World is Not Enough&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="VsSNEQ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLwwhtOnMyjuyEeWvv6UX11aw3jFLFAxU1" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ltTbUC"&gt;Peacock: 12 films&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="cZbQjh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Russia with Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hTC2OK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goldfinger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4Frzvu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;You Only Live Twice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7KDgt3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diamonds Are Forever&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UIYaaP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Man with the Golden Gun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="07njer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Octopussy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sEamQJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Licence to Kill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CvEEUn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoldenEye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9KyS7q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tomorrow Never Dies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="N1CgwG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The World is Not Enough&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oDflz5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casino Royale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="p0U7IF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantum of Solace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="kR2Ywi"&gt;I highly recommend &lt;em&gt;The Living Daylights&lt;/em&gt; with Timothy Dalton. It’s underrated, and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c14-nM8XXXA"&gt;its car chase scene&lt;/a&gt; has yet to be beat. Did I mention I got to see &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/my-afternoon-with-james-bonds-amazing-spy-vehicles-1729067561"&gt;a lot of the real Bond cars and took photos of them&lt;/a&gt; back in 2015?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="u2NcmG"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/c14-nM8XXXA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154044/james-bond-free-marathon-youtube-peacock-plutotv-hulu-amazon-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154044/james-bond-free-marathon-youtube-peacock-plutotv-hulu-amazon-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
