<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-04T09:13:59-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T09:13:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T09:13:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Watch Series 7 launches October 15th, preorders begin on Friday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VYJLsuxRPAJ9WlsPRgRLGPEsDnw=/0x47:1960x1354/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947813/Apple_watch_series7_availability_hero_10052021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Watch Series 7 includes a bigger display.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DEXMH2"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-watch-series-7-orders-start-friday-october-8/"&gt;is opening up preorders&lt;/a&gt; for its Apple Watch Series 7 on Friday, October 8th, with the devices set to ship on October 15th. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;first revealed the Watch Series 7 at an event last month&lt;/a&gt;, but the company simply said it would be available later this fall. Preorders for the Apple Watch Series 7 will now begin at 5AM PT / 8AM ET on Friday, October 8th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U4rsJI"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7 includes a display&lt;/a&gt; that goes virtually to the edge of the case, with more rounded corners and a softer design. The Series 7 now comes in 41mm and 45mm sizes, up 1mm from the Series 6. The bezels around the display are just 1.7mm, and the always-on mode is 70 percent brighter than the Series 6.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rh_93UzApG97WIOiYk9nH-h8KZA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22899644/Apple_watch_series7_availability_contour_face_10052021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s new Contour watchface for the Watch Series 7.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CqsEmC"&gt;Apple has also created a variety of new watchfaces to take advantage of the larger screens on the Apple Watch Series 7. An improved modular watchface lets you view activity ring details alongside the regular complications found on the regular modular watchface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCCHDc"&gt;The screen size is really the big change to the Apple Watch Series 7, alongside watchOS 8 improvements like better outdoor cycling support, fall support in workouts, and some Fitness Plus upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8NqShL"&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 will start at $399 and will be sold alongside the Watch Series 3 at $199. Preorders for the Apple Watch Series 7 start on October 8th, and devices will start shipping on October 15th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708611/apple-watch-7-release-date-price-preorder"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708611/apple-watch-7-release-date-price-preorder</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch the 2021 League of Legends World Championship</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="CHINA-ESPORT-GAMES-LEAGUE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7mVma0igVVIOLj3A5I2Nb1Ojou4=/0x0:5262x3508/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947751/1229376555.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by HECTOR RETAMAL/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5fUFRE"&gt;The 2021 &lt;em&gt;League of Legends &lt;/em&gt;World Championship (aka Worlds) kicks off tomorrow, October 5th, marking the beginning of a month-long tournament where 22 of the best &lt;em&gt;League of Legends teams&lt;/em&gt; will face off to take home the Summoner’s Cup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7r2Fmy"&gt;While Worlds is one of the biggest esports competitions on the planet, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; isn’t exactly the easiest game to start watching. This time of year is one of the best times to jump in, though, as you get to see the best teams at their peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJQSxf"&gt;If you want to learn more about the game — or are a longtime fan who just wants to know more about Worlds before it starts — we’ve put together this primer for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tIA5YU"&gt;What is Worlds?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="RoNnGJ"&gt;Worlds is the concluding tournament in the &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; esports year. Teams from around the globe have qualified for the event after having successful seasons in their local leagues. Think of it sort of like the Champions League in soccer; all year long, teams compete locally for the chance to face off against the best from other regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gXd3Ni"&gt;This year, Worlds takes place &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22649691/league-of-legends-world-championships-2021-europe"&gt;in Reykjavík, Iceland&lt;/a&gt;, at the Laugardalshöll indoor sporting arena. The location means that if you’re in the US, games might take place in the morning or early afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YeqOwM"&gt;No fans will be in attendance at the matches themselves due to COVID-19 restrictions. The event was originally going to take place in China, but &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; developer Riot Games had to move the location &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638914/league-of-legends-world-championships-2021-moved-china-europe"&gt;in the 11th hour&lt;/a&gt; due to travel restrictions and COVID protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6QtXXk"&gt;What are the rules?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="icqFIl"&gt;Here is a very basic explanation of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a strategy game pitting two teams of five “champions” against each other. Each champion is controlled by one player, and each has different abilities. The goal of a game is for one team to break into the other team’s base and destroy a giant crystal, called the Nexus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ND50h8"&gt;Players can’t just walk in and whack on their opponent’s Nexus from the beginning of the game, though. The bases are guarded by turrets that shoot powerful magic energy, auto-spawning soldier units that march toward the other team’s base, and, of course, the enemy team. Over the course of a game, which typically lasts about 30-45 minutes, players will level up, earn in-game money to buy items, skirmish against the enemy team, and, eventually, attack the Nexus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MRqxkq"&gt;I’m glossing over a lot of what happens in a typical &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; match, but that’s the gist of it. For a short video explainer with more detail, check out Riot’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l4bf7pjcYYw"&gt;introductory video&lt;/a&gt; made for last year’s tournament. For a slightly deeper dive, I recommend &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/esports/story/_/id/29915901/league-101-league-legends-beginner-guide"&gt;ESPN’s written article and video&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9XoYtY"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l4bf7pjcYYw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="T2238L"&gt;Who should I root for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mmRr2b"&gt;Like any sport, that’s not an easy question to answer. There are big dogs and underdogs, and you might decide to root for a team based on their name, their logo, or because you think one player is exciting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GLUBRW"&gt;If you want to root for a US team, there are three at Worlds this year, representing the League Championship Series (LCS): 100 Thieves, which &lt;a href="https://dotesports.com/league-of-legends/news/100-thieves-capture-2021-lcs-championship-become-fifth-team-ever-to-win-a-north-american-title"&gt;just won the 2021 LCS Championship&lt;/a&gt;, Team Liquid, a consistent powerhouse in the LCS, and Cloud9, one of the most storied teams in the league. (Cloud9 punched their ticket to Worlds by beating longtime rival TSM.) Europe is represented by &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; European Championship (LEC) teams MAD Lions, Rogue, and Fnatic. (Fnatic also earned their Worlds trip in dramatic fashion, beating one of its rivals, G2 Esports.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9g0g6a"&gt;They’ll be up against some tough competition, though. Last year’s champions, Korea’s Damwon Gaming, have qualified again, as has Korea’s T1, the home of perhaps the most famous League of Legends player of all time, &lt;a href="https://lol.fandom.com/wiki/Faker"&gt;Faker&lt;/a&gt;. The four teams from China’s &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; Pro League (LPL), including the 2019 world champions FunPlus Phoenix and LPL 2021 champions Edward Gaming, could prove to be formidable opponents as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O8J3Fl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dot Esports&lt;/em&gt; has a good rundown of &lt;a href="https://dotesports.com/league-of-legends/news/all-teams-qualified-worlds-2021"&gt;the 22 teams that have qualified for Worlds&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zwXV6M"&gt;Tournament Format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="f7yfrz"&gt;Play-Ins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="cTyyHF"&gt;Competition starts with Play-Ins, where 10 teams will compete for four spots in the Group Stage. The 10 teams will be split into two groups of five. Each team will play one match against the other teams in their group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYa4Db"&gt;The team with the best record in each group automatically moves on to the Group Stage. To determine who gets the final two Group Stage spots, the third- and fourth-place teams in each group will play against each other, and then, the winners of those matches will play the second-place teams in each Play-In group. Whoever wins advances to the Group Stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="STk4uG"&gt;Play-Ins kick off at 7AM ET on October 5th and will run through October 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="oDcNMS"&gt;Group Stage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="6qdK2B"&gt;The Group Stage pits the best teams in the world against each other in four groups of four. Three teams in each group have already been locked in, and one of each of the Play-In victors will be added to the groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Yxynx"&gt;Each team will play each other team in their group twice. The two teams with the best record in each group will move on to the Knockout Stage, which is the final stage of the tournament leading up to the championship match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LPX5mu"&gt;Groups go on for a bit longer than the Play-Ins. The first round of matches runs from October 11th through the 13th, while the second takes place from October 15th through the 18th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="RFsmi8"&gt;Knockout Stage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="uedOfA"&gt;Finally, there’s the Knockout Stage, where the top eight teams from Groups vie for the championship. In this stage, teams will compete in a single-elimination bracket, playing each other in best-of-five matchups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gu5UzW"&gt;The games take place over three weekends: a quarterfinals round set for October 22nd through 25th, a semifinals round scheduled for October 30th and 31st, and the finals match on November 6th to determine the world champion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q3ONFJ"&gt;If you don’t tune into anything else, consider checking out the Knockout Stage. The high caliber of teams that have advanced that far are almost always worth watching. That doesn’t mean there aren’t blowouts or mismatches — the champions in both &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/esports/story/_/id/25164094/invictus-gaming-sweeps-fnatic-3-0-win-league-legends-world-championship"&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/mikestubbs/2019/11/10/funplus-phoenix-win-the-league-of-legends-world-championship-in-a-3-0-stomp/"&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt; won in 3-0 sweeps — but you can expect to see some very exciting matchups during these three weekends of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eXzEp4"&gt;How to watch and schedule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="cVJJSS"&gt;You can watch games live on the &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/riotgames"&gt;Riot Games Twitch channel&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/lolesports"&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; esports YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;, and at &lt;a href="https://lolesports.com/"&gt;https://lolesports.com/&lt;/a&gt;. And if you want to see the full schedule, &lt;a href="https://lolesports.com/schedule?leagues=worlds"&gt;it’s right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HG75eU"&gt;And don’t miss out on the cool graphics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9alJv"&gt;Riot usually uses Worlds to put on a spectacular show that can be as interesting as the competition itself. The 2017 Worlds finals ceremony included &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/league-of-legends-world-finals-had-a-freaking-dragon-1820142112"&gt;a giant virtual dragon&lt;/a&gt;. 2019’s opening ceremony &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/11/20959206/league-of-legends-worlds-2019-opening-ceremony-holograms-holonet"&gt;featured holograms&lt;/a&gt;. And last year, Riot made an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/24/21529317/league-of-legends-world-championship-high-tech-stage-riot-mandalorian"&gt;astonishing mixed reality stage&lt;/a&gt;. Each year, Riot seems to do everything it can to top the last, so it surely has some impressive technological wizardry up its sleeve for the 2021 event.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22704180/league-of-legends-worlds-world-championship-2021-date-how-to-watch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22704180/league-of-legends-worlds-world-championship-2021-date-how-to-watch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T08:46:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T08:46:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>The very big eagle that escaped from the National Aviary in Pittsburgh is back home</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AC4-4nlfGeJaL5K95CU8tEj9ZUw=/0x81:940x708/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69942472/kodiak_the_stellers_sea_eagle.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Kodiak (Kody) the Steller’s sea eagle, who escaped the National Aviary in Pittsburgh September 29th | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/National_Aviary/status/1444319155843477508?s=20" target="_blank"&gt;National Aviary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HJJcYY"&gt;A Steller’s sea eagle named Kodiak &lt;a href="https://www.aviary.org/birds-habitats/kodiak-the-stellers-sea-eagle/"&gt;escaped from its enclosure&lt;/a&gt; at the National Aviary in Pittsburgh on September 25th, and thanks to the valiant efforts of the Aviary staff, was found and brought back to the Aviary on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5nAW7V"&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://www.aviary.org/birds-habitats/kodiak-the-stellers-sea-eagle/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; posted to the Aviary website at 8:15PM Sunday, a team of the Aviary’s animal care experts spotted Kodiak — Kody to his friends— in a suburb of Pittsburgh north of the Aviary. The Aviary team used “professional falconry techniques and equipment” to retrieve the bird and bring him home to the Aviary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MTe0Vx"&gt;Kody is a bird that would be difficult to miss: he’s large (although in Pittsburgh we probably wouldn’t call him “giant” because “Giant Eagle” is a grocery store chain here), with a yellow beak, white tail and white feathers on the tops of his wings. He’s bigger than a bald eagle, and has a wingspan of about six feet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OZVeai"&gt;The Steller’s sea eagle (&lt;em&gt;Haliaeetus pelagicus&lt;/em&gt;) typically weighs between 13 and 20 pounds, and stands about four feet tall. It has no natural predators, &lt;a href="https://www.aviary.org/birds-habitats/our-birds/?category=30"&gt;according to the Aviary&lt;/a&gt;, but Kody has lived in captivity for 15 of his 16 years, so he may be a little rusty on the whole hunting/prey thing. Steller’s sea eagles eat fish, and more fish, “scavenged mammals” (ew) and even other birds “when fish is in short supply.”  And in case you wondered, they’re named for German naturalist &lt;a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Georg-W-Steller"&gt;Georg W. Steller&lt;/a&gt;, who encountered the birds on a visit to Alaska in 1741.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JdvQfN"&gt;The Aviary posted frequent updates to social media and kept getting tantalizingly close to retrieving Kody, but he eluded them for more than a week. I was half-hoping Kody might make some kind of majestic appearance at the September 26th Steelers’ game since Heinz Field is not far from the Aviary, and the team was at home against the Bengals (we’re not going to talk about &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/nfl/story/_/id/32292626/cincinnati-bengals-wr-tyler-boyd-says-pittsburgh-steelers-gave-late-loss"&gt;that game&lt;/a&gt; today, though). Alas, he did not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mb6Kcc"&gt;On Thursday, the Aviary’s animal care experts camped out to monitor his roost in a high tree in the North Park area of the city, and they confirmed he was in good condition. They tried to entice him with some food, but he didn’t come down. But look at this handsome, handsome boi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aORnxj"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CUdOpqBty5r/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:16px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CUdOpqBty5r/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 19% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"&gt;&lt;svg width="50px" height="50px" viewbox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"&gt;&lt;g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding-top: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: auto;"&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CUdOpqBty5r/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by National Aviary (@national_aviary)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SRH2Wa"&gt;Many people— including me, before I moved to Pittsburgh a thousand years ago— don’t know what a hidden gem the National Aviary is, or, that it’s in Pittsburgh. &lt;a href="https://www.aviary.org/programs-encounters/animal-encounters/penguin-encounter/"&gt;Their penguins&lt;/a&gt; are usually the big celebrities (hi, this is &lt;a href="https://www.nhl.com/penguins"&gt;Pittsburgh&lt;/a&gt;), but they also have very cute— as well as very large—owls, eagles, flamingos, falcons, and canaries among other birds. You can sign up for educational “animal encounters” with many  of the birds— I recall visiting when my son was little; we sat in a large auditorium where some birds of prey were flying around, and we got like a popsicle stick with some food on it (I would prefer not to think about what the food actually was) and you’d hold it up until one of the birds swooped down to eat it. Extremely awesome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ocCzkI"&gt;The Aviary said on Sunday that a veterinary exam found Kody in “excellent” health, and added he was “enjoying healthy meals of fresh meat” while he rests up from his adventure. The Aviary thanked the community for its help locating their missing bird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SBleJ5"&gt;“The entire team at the National Aviary is extremely relieved to have Kody back, and would like to share our gratitude to the community of supporters who helped in these efforts.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="muZhhM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 4th 8:45AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Adds the news of Kodiak’s return to the Aviary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5xYIo4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/2/22706177/stellers-sea-eagle-escaped-national-aviary-pittsburgh"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/2/22706177/stellers-sea-eagle-escaped-national-aviary-pittsburgh</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T08:40:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T08:40:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>What is the metaverse, and do I have to care?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dhU0_aCImBg2_FKnLOLZFqzgTtA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947626/acastro_210929_4779_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;One part definition, one part aspiration, one part hype&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="gW5f3d"&gt;In recent months you may have heard about something called the metaverse. Maybe you’ve read that the metaverse is going to replace the internet. Maybe we’re all supposed to live there. Maybe Facebook (or Epic, or &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt;, or dozens of smaller companies) is trying to take it over. And maybe it’s got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;something to do with NFTs&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mj3MHU"&gt;Unlike a lot of things &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; covers, the metaverse is tough to explain for one reason: it doesn’t necessarily exist. It’s partly a dream for the future of the internet and partly a neat way to encapsulate some current trends in online infrastructure, including the growth of real-time 3D worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KLylpJ"&gt;But let’s get to the fun part. Will you start checking your Facebook feed in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; with a pair of augmented reality glasses? Will your friends invite you to cyber-brunch instead of normal brunch? Time to jack in and figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N8NCJS"&gt;So, the metaverse. That started as a science fiction thing, right?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="vrOHfx"&gt;Correct. Neal Stephenson famously coined the term “metaverse” in his 1992 novel &lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt;, where it referred to a 3D virtual world inhabited by avatars of real people. Lots of other science fiction media includes metaverse-like systems (some of them predating &lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt;). But Stephenson’s book remains one of the most common reference points for metaverse enthusiasts, along with Ernest Cline’s 2011 novel &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="k0gpso"&gt;Aren’t both those books set in horrible dystopias?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="G7Stai"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt;’s metaverse is an outgrowth of Stephenson’s satirical corporation-dominated future America, but it’s undeniably depicted as having a cool side. (The protagonist is a master hacker who gets in katana fights at a virtual nightclub. No amount of narrative self-awareness can fool readers into thinking that’s not supposed to be fun.) &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;’s virtual world is symbolically named the OASIS, and Cline portrays it as an almost utopian source of escapism in a horrible future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gXmWKG"&gt;On one hand, emulating the virtual worlds of &lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt; is less deliberately creepy than naming your tech initiative “Skynet” or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/7/17/5893221/soylent-survivor-one-month-living-on-lab-made-liquid-nourishment"&gt;your nutrient shake after Soylent Green&lt;/a&gt;. On the other hand, science fiction stories can conjure a vivid picture of “the metaverse” without illuminating how it should work or why it should exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oG9f3y"&gt;Then what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the real metaverse?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="aX31Tt"&gt;There’s no universally accepted definition of a real “metaverse,” except maybe that it’s a fancier successor to the internet. Silicon Valley metaverse proponents sometimes reference a description from venture capitalist Matthew Ball, author of the extensive &lt;a href="https://www.matthewball.vc/all/forwardtothemetaverseprimer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metaverse Primer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="mqcuf6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The Metaverse is an expansive network of persistent, real-time rendered 3D worlds and simulations that support continuity of identity, objects, history, payments, and entitlements, and can be experienced synchronously by an effectively unlimited number of users, each with an individual sense of presence.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="9G9Qd4"&gt;Facebook, arguably the tech company with the biggest stake in the metaverse, &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/building-the-metaverse-responsibly/"&gt;describes it more simply&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="P1KCWe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The ‘metaverse’ is a set of virtual spaces where you can create and explore with other people who aren’t in the same physical space as you.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="pjlBR8"&gt;There are also broader metaverse-related taxonomies like &lt;a href="https://www.raphkoster.com/2021/09/02/online-world-or-metaverse/"&gt;one from game designer Raph Koster&lt;/a&gt;, who draws a distinction between “online worlds,” “multiverses,” and “metaverses.” To Koster, online worlds are digital spaces — from rich 3D environments to text-based ones — focused on one main theme. Multiverses are “multiple different worlds connected in a network, which do not have a shared theme or ruleset,” including &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;’s OASIS. And a metaverse is “a multiverse which interoperates more with the real world,” incorporating things like augmented reality overlays, VR dressing rooms for real stores, and even apps like Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwttvu"&gt;If you want something a little snarkier and more impressionistic, you can &lt;a href="https://networkcultures.org/longform/2021/01/11/archeology-of-virtual-worlds/"&gt;cite digital scholar Janet Murray&lt;/a&gt; — who has described the modern metaverse ideal as “a magical Zoom meeting that has all the playful release of &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="avsBRS"&gt;But wait, now &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt; isn’t a metaverse and virtual worlds don’t have to be 3D? It sounds like some of these definitions conflict with each other.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xzzD2t"&gt;An astute observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zYxNRB"&gt;Look, I just read an article saying we were all going to live in the metaverse, and I want to know what that means.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="H15qAS"&gt;Right now, tech industry figures who talk about “the metaverse” are usually excited about digital platforms that include some of the following things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="yyQN8a"&gt;Feature sets that overlap with older web services or real-world activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dZzmhK"&gt;Real-time 3D computer graphics and personalized avatars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EXYh3y"&gt;A variety of person-to-person social interactions that are less competitive and goal-oriented than stereotypical games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="D7DTn4"&gt;Support for users creating their own virtual items and environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PoxubQ"&gt;Links with outside economic systems so people can profit from virtual goods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kJwUOJ"&gt;Designs that seem well-suited to virtual and augmented reality headsets, even if they usually support other hardware as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="OYh40l"&gt;But in most current discourse, “the metaverse” arguably isn’t a fixed set of attributes. It’s an aspirational term for a future digital world that feels more tangibly connected to our real lives and bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gxreBV"&gt;So is &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; a metaverse? Or &lt;em&gt;Facebook Horizon&lt;/em&gt;? Or is the metaverse all of them put together?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QqgXG8"&gt;People like Tim Sweeney (CEO of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; publisher Epic) and Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg often say they’re just building one piece of a larger interconnected metaverse, similar to an individual social network on the present-day internet. “The metaverse isn’t a single product one company can build alone. Just like the internet, the metaverse exists whether Facebook is there or not,” one recent Facebook statement reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="IB4O2A"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The metaverse is bigger than any one service, except when it’s convenient to call that service the metaverse&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Gg1617"&gt;But informally, “metaverse” is also used to describe a single platform that meets the criteria listed above. &lt;em&gt;Second Life&lt;/em&gt;, a virtual world that isn’t a traditional game, has been &lt;a href="https://www.economist.com/special-report/2006/09/28/living-a-second-life"&gt;frequently&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/computing/name-that-metaverse/"&gt;described&lt;/a&gt; as a metaverse. Sweeney has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417697/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-1"&gt;described &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s user experience&lt;/a&gt; as a metaverse because it’s a virtual 3D space that mixes gaming and non-gaming elements. &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt; CEO David Baszucki &lt;a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/roblox-metaverse"&gt;coyly notes that&lt;/a&gt; “some people refer to what we’re building as the Metaverse.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAczxp"&gt;If you like Koster’s “multiverse” definition, there are also arguably several standalone multiverses. Microsoft’s &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; gets less hype than &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt; these days, but it enables similar activities through modding. So do lower-profile services &lt;a href="https://medium.com/sandbox-game/what-is-the-sandbox-850de68d893e"&gt;like &lt;em&gt;The Sandbox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which incorporates a complex cryptocurrency-based economy as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xoZcbp"&gt;Why is the term “metaverse” even useful? “The internet” already covers mobile apps, websites, and all kinds of infrastructure services. Can’t we roll virtual worlds in there, too?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="0B0ZcO"&gt;Matthew Ball favors the term “metaverse” because it creates a clean break with the present-day internet. “Using the metaverse as a distinctive descriptor allows us to understand the enormity of that change and in turn, the opportunity for disruption,” he said in a phone interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s much harder to say ‘we’re late-cycle into the last thing and want to change it.’ But I think understanding this next wave of computing and the internet allows us to be more proactive than reactive and think about the future as we want it to be, rather than how to marginally affect the present.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3yjQS3"&gt;A more cynical spin is that “metaverse” lets companies dodge negative baggage associated with “the internet” in general and social media in particular. “As long as you can make technology seem fresh and new and cool, you can avoid regulation,” researcher Joan Donovan &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/09/24/facebook-washington-strategy-metaverse/?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=wp_main&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in a recent article about Facebook and the metaverse. “You can run defense on that for several years before the government can catch up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="du1tjI"&gt;There’s also one very simple reason: it sounds more futuristic than “internet” and gets investors and media people (like us!) excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="BUJsxJ"&gt;Didn’t we have a whole metaverse hype cycle around &lt;em&gt;Second Life&lt;/em&gt; in the ‘00s? What’s different now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NniiyK"&gt;It’s true: plenty of new “metaverse” phenomena aren’t really novel. People were becoming &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2006-04-30/my-virtual-life"&gt;digital land barons&lt;/a&gt; and selling virtual items in &lt;em&gt;Second Life&lt;/em&gt; nearly two decades ago. Schools and businesses have opened &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2007/01/07/education/edlife/07innovation.html"&gt;satellite campuses&lt;/a&gt; in that world and others. Social 3D spaces like CyberTown long predate &lt;em&gt;Second Life&lt;/em&gt;. Even before that, early virtual worlds popped up in the 1970s with text-based multiuser dungeons or MUDs. Many older worlds also inspired the kinds of utopian predictions we see around the metaverse today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XTOWqh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘Fortnite’ isn’t the first virtual world to inspire utopian predictions&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="94Twgq"&gt;One reason we might be experiencing the hype cycle again is that graphics technology and internet connectivity has significantly advanced since, say, &lt;em&gt;Second Life&lt;/em&gt;’s 2003 launch. Many video games operate under a “live service” model where the developers constantly update a game to encourage players to return, creating a more convincing illusion of a living, breathing, ever-changing world. Non-metaverse games like &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; make significant changes to gameplay years after release, treating the experience more like a virtual space than a static game. From there, a leap to in-game concerts and fashion shows doesn’t seem that far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lTV6zu"&gt;Virtual and augmented reality have gotten closer to consumer application, even if VR remains niche and AR nascent. &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/bulletins/quest-2-4-million-units"&gt;One estimate suggests&lt;/a&gt; Facebook has sold around 8 million Oculus Quest 2 headsets, and &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/60-apps-oculus-quest-2-million-revenue/"&gt;several dozen VR games&lt;/a&gt; have made over $1 million in sales. Those are tiny numbers compared to phone and console sales, but huge compared to the practically nonexistent home VR market 10 years ago. Apple is reportedly working on VR / AR headsets, and Chinese company Nreal has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21362407/nreal-light-ar-glasses-lg-uplus-samsung-galaxy-note-retail-launch-availability-price"&gt;successfully shipped&lt;/a&gt; full-fledged consumer AR sunglasses at a comparatively low price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XlTv7J"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pop culture is obsessed with cinematic universes, so why not have a virtual one?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eu68nL"&gt;Another possible reason is that modern pop culture is built on sprawling and highly intertextual media franchises owned by a few companies that promote their huge intellectual property catalogs as shared universes. That enthusiasm has translated into dreams of — as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22412899/epic-apple-trial-rules-investment-app-payment"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; editor Liz Lopatto describes it&lt;/a&gt; — “an online haven where superhero IP owned by different companies can finally kiss.” (This is the entire premise of &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z5kZ5q"&gt;And if you believe the metaverse shouldn’t be owned by a handful of companies, there are new technologies that could facilitate less centralized virtual worlds, like cryptocurrency and non-fungible tokens or NFTs. These metaverse visions overlap with &lt;a href="https://web3.foundation/"&gt;the concept of Web3&lt;/a&gt;, a term covering decentralized internet services where users retain more personal control over the data they put online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tlPOhV"&gt;Or maybe we’re in a global pandemic that’s kept billions of people away from casual real-world human contact for more than a year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zA7sPF"&gt;Or that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="adjWlm"&gt;People keep saying NFTs are part of the metaverse. Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="WRif0g"&gt;NFTs are complicated in their own right, and you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;read more about them here&lt;/a&gt;. Loosely, the thinking goes: NFTs are a way of recording who owns a specific virtual good, creating and transferring virtual goods is a big part of the metaverse, thus NFTs are a potentially useful financial architecture for the metaverse. Or in more practical terms: if you buy a virtual shirt in Metaverse Platform A, NFTs can create a permanent receipt and let you redeem the same shirt in Metaverse Platforms B to Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQNdiC"&gt;Lots of NFT designers are selling collectible avatars like CryptoPunks, Cool Cats, and Bored Apes, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22639353/cool-cats-bayc-generative-nft-profile-avatar"&gt;sometimes for astronomical sums&lt;/a&gt;. Right now these are mostly 2D art used as social media profile pictures. But we’re already seeing some crossover with “metaverse”-style services. The company Polygonal Mind, for instance, is building a system called CryptoAvatars that lets people buy 3D avatars as NFTs and then use them across multiple virtual worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CdNth0"&gt;Is using one avatar or item across different worlds as simple as it sounds?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="aA2xrN"&gt;On the contrary, people &lt;a href="https://www.raphkoster.com/2021/09/23/how-virtual-worlds-work-part-one/"&gt;like Raph Koster think&lt;/a&gt; it’s one of the metaverse’s toughest problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J7N4S4"&gt;There are a few ways designers support people “moving” items between worlds right now. One is to build all the worlds within a single platform like &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt;, where players can do things like accessorize an avatar with virtual gear and use it across different experiences. But this breaks down across worlds that are more technically and aesthetically different. Even leaving aside wonky problems like file format support, something as simple as a 3D hat model might look good on a Lego-like &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt; character but make no sense on a pixelated avatar from &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;. An item might have a particular ability in one world (like playing music) that another world doesn’t support at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="DZvLFM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘Snow Crash’ was right: avatars are tough&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="egTJj7"&gt;A second option is to manually create a different version of the same asset for every world. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; both feature Master Chief avatars, for instance, but with a design tailored to each game. (This is typically how media franchises kiss with the companies’ official blessing — Warner Bros. can’t just take a Bruce Wayne model from the &lt;em&gt;Batman: Arkham &lt;/em&gt;series and drop it in a &lt;em&gt;Lego Batman&lt;/em&gt; game.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fv3HfX"&gt;This method can look seamless to users, but it can be a lot of work for developers and not worth the payoff in all cases. Epic and Microsoft might both benefit by adding a popular character to a popular game, but does Microsoft really want to model its own version of every single &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; skin for &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;, just so players can use another company’s avatars in its world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="avvTGZ"&gt;A third option, available in the popular virtual world VRChat, is having players or third-party designers upload their own 3D models with a specific set of characteristics. But uploading a model demands more work and technical skill from users. (Arguably this is the closest analog to Stephenson’s Metaverse, where a good avatar requires either money or great computer skills.) Meanwhile, the developers cede some control over the aesthetic of their space. And if companies approach them with deals for licensed characters or items, they could find a world already populated by knockoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YAE7vQ"&gt;This could change in the future. Epic could try to implement a shared item library for its popular Unreal Engine, for example. New AI visual filters could tweak a single 3D model to match different world designs the way existing ones turn &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/wxewkz/how-to-turn-yourself-into-an-anime-character-with-one-click"&gt;selfies into anime&lt;/a&gt;. But any fix would require a level of coordination that we haven’t seen so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="75bfmV"&gt;Is the metaverse a kind of internet? Will it replace the internet?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bc0g1v"&gt;People are certainly talking about it that way! &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview"&gt;In an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Mark Zuckerberg described the metaverse as “an embodied internet,” basically an upgraded version of the internet where people can have “different experiences that you couldn’t necessarily do on a 2D app or webpage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5q7sqh"&gt;Tim Sweeney takes a similar line in &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/09/28/epic-fortnite-metaverse-facebook/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, imagining the metaverse as “a kind of online playground where users could join friends to play a multiplayer game like Epic’s ‘&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’ one moment, watch a movie via Netflix the next.” If you’re imagining a place where you can watch videos, play games with friends, and buy things, it’s going to end up looking a lot like the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="AHZMDR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The metaverse’s key promise is “presence”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zkixce"&gt;One of the metaverse’s key benefits is supposed to be “presence” — a sense that you’re physically engaging with places and people instead of watching them through a window. Gathering your co-workers around a virtual table in a service like Spatial and &lt;em&gt;Facebook Horizon&lt;/em&gt;, for instance, could feel more natural to some people than looking at a grid of Zoom thumbnails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EIJQmo"&gt;But many pieces seem as likely to supplement the internet as replace it. A virtual dressing room makes sense if you want to see how an outfit would look on you. It doesn’t necessarily require a whole virtual store, though, just an easy way to switch between flat and spatial experiences. A good comparison point might be the mobile internet, which saw a slew of app-based services supplement or even replace traditional websites — but hasn’t made desktop-based options obsolete, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v4qEqt"&gt;A text-heavy, non-real-time internet also has some noteworthy advantages. High-end computers, gaming consoles, and VR headsets that support detailed virtual environments can be expensive. People with mobility issues or slow internet connections might find moving an avatar around a real-time 3D world inconvenient. And people with low or no vision can use screen readers to access text on webpages, while navigating an environment based on images can be harder. Accessibility experts can help mitigate these issues, but there’s still a long way to go before they’re solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CiUi9K"&gt;Will the metaverse turn into just another form of advertising, like social media?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VRzUKY"&gt;People like Tim Sweeney say they don’t want it to. Sweeney &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/09/28/epic-fortnite-metaverse-facebook/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; that present-day social media&lt;/a&gt; has “trapped” companies and users in walled gardens and bombarded them with ads. &lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt; designers make money that’s not ad-driven by selling digital goods in their individual worlds and letting the company take a (&lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-08-20-roblox-exploiting-young-game-developers-new-investigation-reports"&gt;sometimes surprisingly large&lt;/a&gt;) cut. Proponents of new options like NFTs see them as a viable alternative to ad-supported systems, although NFTs have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change"&gt;potential negative side effects&lt;/a&gt; of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="vVKojl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Finally, a way to mingle with brands&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="24y7uy"&gt;But “advertising” is a slippery word. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, Sweeney’s version of a world beyond ads, is still packed absolutely full of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22242696/fortnite-predator-marketing-brands-cross-promotion"&gt;big pop culture franchises&lt;/a&gt; and brands building name recognition — in the same &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; interview, he imagined auto companies dropping models of their cars into the metaverse to let people test-drive them. With varying levels of skepticism, media coverage &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/09/28/epic-fortnite-metaverse-facebook/"&gt;refers to the metaverse&lt;/a&gt; as “an expansive, digitized communal space where users can mingle freely with brands” &lt;a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture-council/articles/nfts-3d-avatars-metaverse-music-entertainment-1231911/"&gt;or&lt;/a&gt; “a realm of culture and digital identity for brands to further discover their fullest potential.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="YezlOc"&gt;This might not come as a shock to fans of &lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt;, where brands have supplanted nations, or &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;, where pop culture franchises have all but conquered reality. Fortunately, if it doesn’t sound like much fun, there’s still time to help shape the future of the metaverse — assuming it actually arrives.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Yes, Siri is my favorite smart home controller and here’s why</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v1fKRWFS8SYv0MquROlM6mooZSA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947472/dseifert_201107_4281_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Hey Siri, turn my home on.”&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Speed, brevity, and an abject failure at fart jokes make Apple’s AI voice assistant the winner in my smart home&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="WPTvnX"&gt;I use a fairly simple metric to determine which artificially intelligent voice assistant is the best for controlling my smart home: Which one do I swear at the least? Apple’s Siri, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22468274"&gt;who turns 10 today&lt;/a&gt;, wins hands down. This is slightly to do with the fact it rarely spews useless information at me when it didn’t understand what I was asking (*cough* Google) and definitely because it never asks if I want to buy something (you know who you are). But mainly, it’s because as a smart home controller, Siri is seriously fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49IGjx"&gt;Siri, you say? That same Siri whose lagginess is legendary in its native iPhone home? Yes, that’s the one. Bring Siri into your home, put the power of an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22454960/apple-tv-4k-2021-review"&gt;Apple TV 4K&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/15/21517945/apple-homepod-mini-homekit-smart-home-system-gateway-price"&gt;HomePod&lt;/a&gt; (maxi or mini) behind it as a HomeKit hub, and the snappiness with which the AI does what you command will floor you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="26UCCw"&gt;A simple, “Hey Siri, Good Night” turns off all the smart lights in my home, locks the front and back doors, closes the garage door, pauses any music playing, lowers the shades, and sets the thermostat to my sleep temperature in around 6 seconds, give or take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sh1Q62"&gt;A quick “Hey Siri, lights on” directed at the kitchen HomePod Mini turns just those lights on in under a second. As a bonus, it has never once accidentally illuminated the whole house at 5AM, as some other voice assistants have unhelpfully done (I mentioned the swearing already, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zORgUx"&gt;A whispered “Good Morning” into my Apple Watch while pressing the digital crown, and my home springs gently back to life; turning on just the lights I need to get ready without waking up my partner and playing NPR quietly on the kitchen Mini, all before I’ve made it out of the bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="egleSZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Hey, Alexa. Hey Siri. Hey Google. Hey, can anybody hear me??&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z9Ac9k"&gt;Siri may lack some of the excellent qualities found on competing smart speakers.  It’s not the smartest AI — that goes to Google Assistant with its powerhouse backend. It’s not the most helpful — that goes to Alexa with its frequent (and frequently unsolicited) offers of assistance. But when all what you want to do is turn the lights on and instead your AI launches into a monologue about who invented the light switch, that’s when you say to yourself, “I wish my smart home controller was a little dumber.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qaodwa"&gt;While the smart home dream is one powered by artificial intelligence that uses context to anticipate your every need, we are a long way from that reality. Today, all you really need from your smart home voice control are listening skills and comprehension — we’re talking first grade here, not a master’s degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JdTZeY"&gt;To be helpful, voice control in the smart home just has to be easier and less obtrusive than pulling out a phone and opening an app, and more convenient than walking over to flip a switch. It’s a challenge and one that Apple is the closest to conquering — in my home at least. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="RBU0iX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I do wish Siri was more promiscuous&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sPRgrc"&gt;Yes, fart jokes are fun, and it’s great to have the world’s knowledge just a few words away — Siri is no good at either of those things. But Siri does hear me 100 percent of the time, even when the closest speaker is on the other side of the room, understands my smart home requests 95 percent of the time, and limits its chatty banter to the absolute minimum — “On it” or “Coming right up.” These are qualities I admire in a smart home controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B5Q26x"&gt;However, I do wish Siri was more promiscuous. There are a fair number of gadgets and gizmos in my admittedly out-of-the-norm smart home that can’t talk to Siri. This means I occasionally find a member of my household standing haplessly in the middle of the room saying, “Hey, Alexa. Hey Siri. Hey Google. Hey, can anybody hear me??”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojs8L5"&gt;It was also not a simple nor inexpensive process to set up my partly-Siri-powered smart home. (The nature of my job means I’m contractually obliged to run all four smart voice assistants at once — yes, I have Bixby in here too). Searching for Siri-compatible devices generally means choosing the “highest-priced” filter in the search results and closing your eyes when you hit that buy button. A few more budget-friendly offerings released over the last year from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523877/aqara-smart-home-review-m2-hub-homekit-alexa-google-assistant"&gt;Aqara&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.meross.com/home"&gt;Meross&lt;/a&gt; have made it a little easier on the wallet, but there are still a number of categories entirely missing or sparsely populated — such as robot vacuum cleaners, smart smoke alarms, and home security systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="QZyYA5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Searching for Siri-compatible devices generally means choosing the “highest-priced” filter in the search results&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bvXGH3"&gt;The coming promise of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430666/matter-project-chip-smart-home-partnership-apple-amazon-google-zigbee"&gt;Matter&lt;/a&gt; may fix this interoperability conundrum, which, to be fair, is not just Apple’s problem. But in the meantime, I’ve found that Siri Shortcuts offers a useful way around some of these limitations. &lt;a href="https://gotailwind.com/"&gt;Tailwind, my favorite garage door controller&lt;/a&gt;, didn’t have HomeKit support for a long time. It does now, but in the interim it offered a Shortcut to program in my own command to have Siri open and close the door. The same deal with my ceiling fans. &lt;a href="https://bondhome.io/product/bond-bridge/"&gt;The Bond Bridge&lt;/a&gt; (an RF device that can communicate with a ceiling fan remote control, not a scene from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/27/22252018/james-bond-no-time-to-die-hmd-global-nokia-phones-product-placement"&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Time to Die&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) can use Siri on your iPhone or Apple Watch to trigger Shortcuts to control my not smart, definitely not HomeKit-compatible fans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0QLWz"&gt;The downside of Shortcuts, however, is they only work on an iPhone or Apple Watch, and smart home control needs to be easily accessible to everyone in the house, whether they’ve bought into the Apple ecosystem or not. Until the advent of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review"&gt;HomePod Mini&lt;/a&gt;, the price to outfit a modest-sized home with on-demand Siri access was prohibitive, and even the HomePod Mini’s $99 per room is still steep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="GniVqK"&gt;In honor of Siri’s tenth birthday, it looks like the AI is inviting some friends to the party. A new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv"&gt;Siri-enabled accessories program&lt;/a&gt; allows non-Apple gadgets with speakers and microphones in them to relay requests to a HomePod. As of now, the Ecobee SmartThermostat is the only manufacturer to have committed to this. (Considering &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701965/amazon-fitbit-ecobee-basics-design-halo-view-smart-thermostat-clone-ripoff-regulators"&gt;Amazon just Sherlocked them with its new smart thermostat&lt;/a&gt; I wouldn’t blame Ecobee if it evicted Alexa entirely.) With more ways to talk to Siri in the home and more products that can be controlled by the smart assistant, I’m hoping my swear jar will be gathering cobwebs by Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9OMrqQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22704860/siri-best-smart-home-voice-assistant-editorial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22704860/siri-best-smart-home-voice-assistant-editorial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T07:07:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T07:07:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dyson’s next robot vacuum cleaner revealed in FCC filings with new design </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mndiPgqkNj0JdI8ClBl7UcYkBvQ=/0x5:1770x1185/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947409/new_dyson_fcc_filing.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The unnamed robovac has the same striking blue color as its predecessor, the Dyson 360 Heurist. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://fccid.io/QVHRB03001" target="_blank"&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt; / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Nt4ShT"&gt;Dyson’s last vacuum cleaner, the oddly-named &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/9/12/17850670/dyson-robot-vacuum-360-eye-heurist"&gt;360 Heurist&lt;/a&gt;, skipped a US release, &lt;a href="https://www.techradar.com/uk/news/first-look-dyson-360-heurist-robot-wants-to-be-the-smartest-vacuum-cleaner-ever"&gt;apparently because&lt;/a&gt; its design was ill-suited to the layout of American homes. But it looks like the company is planning to launch a new robovac in the US soon, after &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/QVHRB03001"&gt;filing details of an unannounced product&lt;/a&gt; with the FCC. Photos in the filing seem to show a new design that is wider and flatter than its predecessors, with a squared-off rear and bulkier charging base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="waDtrz"&gt;The unnamed robovac comes in the same striking nickel blue color as its predecessor, and has tank treads and a detachable dust bin, just like Dyson’s previous forays into this product category. It also looks like the device (labelled RB03) has the Heurist’s 360-degree camera with LED lighting ring. Those LEDs are important, as they ensure the device can navigate in the dark — handy if you want your robovac to clean when you’re out or asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CT2cWq"&gt;Branding on the device suggests it will also use Dyson’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dyson.co.uk%2Fvacuum-cleaners%2Fsticks%2Fdyson-hyperdymium-motor&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fcircuitbreaker%2F2021%2F10%2F4%2F22708470%2Fdyson-robot-vacuum-cleaner-us-fcc-filing" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new Hyperdymium motors&lt;/a&gt;. This is simply Dyson’s name for its latest brushless electric motors, which have appeared in its most recent stick vacuums. It also looks like you can remove part of the internal tubing (picture 4 below) that connects the bin to the brushes. That would be a neat upgrade, as the 360 Heurist had a &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/zDVl6EP42FY"&gt;tendency to clog&lt;/a&gt; when vacuuming piles of large debris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="i8MKj3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10788612"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VYCOid"&gt;The most interesting change for this product, though, is the new shape. Dyson’s previous vacuums, the 360 Eye and 360 Heurist, have been taller and narrower than rival products built by iRobot and the like. This allows them tighter cornering around items like chair legs, but stops them from vacuuming under some furniture. It’s hard to gauge the exact dimensions of this new product (despite the inclusion of rulers in pictures, the perspective is confusing), but it does seem to be wider and flatter than the Eye and Heurist. This would tally with Dyson’s past comments that the Heurist was not quite right for US homes. Allowing the vacuum to get under more items of furniture would certainly help with sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Clm7k9"&gt;There’s no guarantee of course that this product will end up in the US, but an FCC filing does obviously suggest that this is Dyson’s current ambition. We  expect to hear more about this product in the future. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/10/4/22708470/dyson-robot-vacuum-cleaner-us-fcc-filing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/10/4/22708470/dyson-robot-vacuum-cleaner-us-fcc-filing</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hey Siri, what happened?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/suDspLBgHdfFDtXFwilxVwt4Qxw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947342/acastro_211001_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;After a decade as Apple’s assistant, Siri still hasn’t figured out the job&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="XxOI1i"&gt;Ten years ago today, Apple’s digital assistant Siri was revealed with the promise that the iPhone maker had finally figured it all out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQlAfC"&gt;“For decades, technologists have teased us with this dream that you’re going to be able to talk to technology, and it’ll do things for us,” said Apple exec Phil Schiller, taking the stage at the launch of the iPhone 4s. “Haven’t we seen this before, over and over? But it never comes true.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cdxm20"&gt;The problem, said Schiller, was that voice interfaces were too reliant on simple syntax. &lt;em&gt;Call&lt;/em&gt; Mom. &lt;em&gt;Dial&lt;/em&gt; 555-2368. &lt;em&gt;Play&lt;/em&gt; Beethoven. “What we really want to do is just talk to our device,” he said, “and your device — in this case, your phone — will figure out what you mean and help you get what you want done.” He paused before bringing up the next slide, showing a familiar icon of a microphone cut-out in burnished aluminum. “That’s a feature on the iPhone 4s we call Siri.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YX13ru"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“What we really want to do is just talk to our device,” said Schiller&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lXFa7h"&gt;Described by Schiller as a “humble personal assistant,” Siri gave 2011’s iPhone a dose of star power during a difficult time for Apple. Just months before the phone’s unveiling, a relative unknown at the company, then-chief operating officer Tim Cook, had been named CEO. The day after Schiller’s presentation, Apple’s legendary co-founder Steve Jobs would die from pancreatic cancer. Analysts were cool on the company’s prospects but praised Siri as a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2011/oct/05/iphone-4s-icloud-analysts"&gt;potential game-changer&lt;/a&gt;. One called it “a powerful harbinger of the future use of mobile devices,” while another said it was “the beginning of a new user experience [for] all of Apple’s mobile and Mac products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="FOHUYM"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agzItTz35QQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R75LfJ"&gt;A decade later, the sheen has worn off Siri’s star. “It is such a letdown,” was how Schiller described the promise of voice interfaces past, and such a description could easily be applied to Apple’s contribution to the genre. Everyone who uses Siri has their own tales of frustration — times when they’ve been surprised not by the intelligence but the stupidity of Apple’s assistant, when it fails to carry out a simple command or mishears a clear instruction. And while voice interfaces have indeed become widespread, Apple, despite being first to market, no longer leads. Its “humble personal assistant” remains humble indeed: inferior to Google Assistant on mobile and outmaneuvered by Amazon’s Alexa in the home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L1AzJI"&gt;Looking back on a decade of development for Apple’s personal assistant, there’s one question that seems worth asking: hey Siri, what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="vLyruz"&gt;The wow factor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="khQMdg"&gt;Looking back to 2011, initial reactions to Siri were incredibly positive, with reviewers impressed by the feature’s responsiveness and accuracy. “The crazy thing about Siri is that it works — at least most of the time — better than you’d expect it to,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/apple/2011/10/12/2484524/iphone-4s-review"&gt;was &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s judgment&lt;/a&gt;; “It’s kind of like having the unpaid intern of my dreams at my beck and call,” &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2011/10/12/tech/mobile/review-siri-iphone-voice-wired/index.html"&gt;said &lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; “Siri saves time, fumbling and distraction, and profoundly changes the definition of ‘phone,’” &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/12/technology/personaltech/iphone-4s-conceals-sheer-magic-pogue.html?_r=1&amp;amp;ref=technology"&gt;said &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. All in all: Apple seemed to be living up to its promises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7TLsF1"&gt;But reading these reviews now, it’s clear Siri was graded on a curve. Its novelty and ambition invited generous appraisals, but when reviewers noted frustrations, they caveated that the software was only in beta and that any rough patches would surely be smoothed away in due time. A &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2011/10/iphone-4s-a-siri-ously-slick-speedy-smartphone/"&gt;detailed run-down of Siri in 2011 from &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; highlights problems familiar today, with the assistant dinged for mishearing instructions in loud spaces and mangling complex commands. An instruction to “Send a text to Jason, Clint, Sam, and Lee saying we’re having dinner at Silver Cloud” is interpreted with Siri texting Jason: “Clint Sam and Lee saying we’re having dinner at Silver Cloud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="MYZdcd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Siri was first on the scene, but soon was just part of the chorus&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q860Aj"&gt;Siri had a first-mover advantage, but it didn’t take long for rivals to emerge. Samsung introduced S Voice on the Galaxy S3 in 2012; that same year Google Now was launched for Android (replaced by Google Assistant in 2016); in 2014 Microsoft brought out Cortana for Windows Phone; and also that year, Amazon went its own way by introducing customers to Alexa on the Echo smart speaker. Speaking to your computer quickly became an expected feature not just on mobile devices, but a whole range of gadgets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="galXfv"&gt;Looking through reviews and comparisons of digital assistants in this period, two things stick out. The first is that people soon get bored of Siri. As reviewers tackle iPhones after the 4s, they often note incremental updates to the assistant but never dedicate much space to it its features. Partly, this seems just because the changes are so small (e.g., retrieving sports results in iOS 6; integrating Wikipedia in iOS 7; introducing ‘Hey, Siri’ in iOS 8), but also because the novelty has worn off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0N0ZfW"&gt;By the time we get to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/19/technology/iphone-reviews.html"&gt;reviews of the iPhone 8&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, Siri is mentioned in passing, if at all. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/19/16323570/apple-new-iphone-8-review-plus-2017"&gt;Our own review&lt;/a&gt; summarizes the assistant’s contribution in a single line: “Siri sounds a lot nicer as well, although it’s not any more capable than before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iPhone 4S Siri" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e36FE_zxFYAre8sm8lY_SbNQCE4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets/938847/iPhone_4S_Siri_1020.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Siri on the iPhone 4s impressed reviewers for its sheer novelty. But Apple never kept up the momentum. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SPA8NE"&gt;The second major trend is that once competitors did arrive, Apple’s advantage evaporated quickly. A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/5/24/3040552/siri-vs-s-voice-comparison-video"&gt;comparison of Siri and Samsung’s S Voice&lt;/a&gt; in 2012 notes that the latter already “offers a very good approximation” of Apple’s digital assistant, while a head-to-head test in 2014 shows that “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/10/9/6951813/google-now-crushes-siri-and-cortana"&gt;Google Now crushes Siri&lt;/a&gt;.” By 2017, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/19/15655558/google-assistant-vs-siri-iphone-ios-apple-locked-down-sandbox"&gt;noted that&lt;/a&gt; Siri “feels largely half-baked,” and a dissatisfaction with digital assistants in general had begun to creep in. We point out that these assistants can answer basic questions just fine but fail to reliably &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; things for the user — like booking cinema tickets or ordering food. At least, not without creating new problems of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lL13Qf"&gt;Looking back, it’s clear that Siri’s big problem is that it failed to maintain momentum. The basic roster of tasks that made Apple’s digital assistant so appealing in 2011 — setting alarms, taking notes, and so on — were never significantly expanded upon. The ability to answer trivia questions and retrieve sport scores is fun, but not as significant an upgrade as telling a computer to complete tasks using just your voice. Meanwhile, rivals replicated and then exceeded what Siri could do. They began to offer more reliable dictation, better language understanding, and integration with third-party skills. Siri just didn’t keep up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="lsd4sf"&gt;Trouble at the top&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="xLN0Rx"&gt;So, where did things go wrong? How did Apple lose its lead? The answer is complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TdKpJv"&gt;Many suggest Apple’s dedication to privacy means it can never keep up with rivals like Google whose business involves collecting users’ data because that data is incredibly useful when it comes to improving AI systems. I don’t buy this as a reason for Siri’s failure, though. First, because Apple’s love of user privacy is far from absolute. (In 2019, for example, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/jul/26/apple-contractors-regularly-hear-confidential-details-on-siri-recordings"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian &lt;/em&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; that “a small proportion” of Siri recordings were being passed to contractors for analysis, with a whistleblower claiming they overhead discussions “between doctors and patients, business deals, seemingly criminal dealings, sexual encounters and so on.”) And secondly, because Apple is a two-trillion-dollar company. If it wants to circumvent the messy problems of collecting user data, it can, simply by paying to generate this data. Yes, analyzing random Siri interactions is helpful, but there are other ways to achieve the same improvements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BJ0NiG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“When Steve died the day after Siri launched, they lost the vision”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wABLGp"&gt;A more convincing explanation is management dysfunction. In 2018, &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/the-seven-year-itch-how-apples-marriage-to-siri-turned-sour"&gt;published a damning report&lt;/a&gt; on the comings-and-goings at team Siri. It noted that there was deep-seated disagreement within the company about how Siri should work (is it a feature focused on search and retrieval, or an assistant that carries out complex tasks?). These disagreements stemmed back to Jobs’ original plans for Siri but had devolved into “petty turf battles and heated arguments” between rival factions. They were exacerbated by a lack of leadership and continuity in the Apple execs overseeing Siri. As one former employee told &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;: “When Steve died the day after Siri launched, they lost the vision [...] They didn’t have a big picture.” This tallies with the feature’s stalled development after its initial launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZANm6e"&gt;Other problems are rooted in Apple’s ideology of technology development. For example, &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;’s report claims that Apple exec Richard Williamson made the decision to only update Siri once a year, following the company’s cadence of new hardware and iOS updates. This seems to have slowed progress. (Williamson, who refuted this claim, left Apple in 2012 after spearheading the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/9/20/3363914/wrong-turn-apple-ios-6-maps-phone-5-buggy-complaints"&gt;disastrous Apple Maps launch&lt;/a&gt;. Scott Forstall, another executive involved in Siri and Apple Maps, &lt;a href="https://www.cultofmac.com/509277/today-in-apple-history-scott-forstall-forced-out-of-apple/"&gt;departed that same year&lt;/a&gt;. Read into that what you will.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oJvTNr"&gt;There’s also Apple’s walled garden approach, which means Siri has always worked well with iOS features but played badly with third-party services. While testing Siri in preparation for this story, I was consistently surprised by its failure to execute simple tasks on popular iOS apps. Siri can’t send a voice memo on WhatsApp; can’t post a story to Instagram; can’t record a run on RunKeeper; and can’t open up &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; crossword. Sure, some of the blame for this lack of interoperability lies with outside developers, but it’s also Apple’s job to encourage such functionality through toolkits and the like. The company certainly doesn’t lead by example, either. When I ask Siri for information I know is stored in iOS, like “show me photos from last August,” it just performs an image search for the phrase “last August.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k_CDKU4S2TXG2fNJS-ekOGHqWCM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22893700/Screen_Shot_2021_10_01_at_4.04.05_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not close, and no cigar: results when you ask Siri to “show me photos from last August.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WnyGFp"&gt;Instead, Apple uses Siri to herd people back to its own inferior apps like a shepherd directing sheep off a cliff-face. If I ask Siri for directions, it prompts me to reinstall Apple Maps (when I habitually use Google Maps and Citymapper). If I try to send an email to my boss, Siri tells me, “I’m sorry I can’t do that,” and then directs me to the App Store to download Apple’s default mail app (I use Outlook). And, here’s a sign of how slipshod Siri’s development is right now: when this happens, Siri sets up a search for “mobilemail” on the App Store. This, of course, isn’t the name of Apple’s mail app, but an ID used by iOS developers, and so it draws a blank when you search for it on the App Store. That’s the kind of broken functionality you get when a company isn’t thoroughly testing its own product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5L0wtM"&gt;This last point, though, highlights a problem particular not just to Apple’s assistant, but to voice interfaces more generally, and that is one of &lt;em&gt;expectations&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="belhu2"&gt;When Schiller introduced Siri in 2011, he stressed time and time again that Siri would understand users — that it knows what they are saying, just like a real person. This set the bar too high for Siri’s functionality. If you treat voice interfaces as if they have the same level of fluency and knowledge as a human being, you will always be disappointed. We speak, and they stumble. We guess what they’re capable of, and they disappoint. Usually because they don’t support the app or command we thought they would. Each failed interaction then teaches users: &lt;em&gt;don’t trust this feature&lt;/em&gt;. By comparison, screens and displays tell us clearly what we can and cannot do. They offer menus, directions, and buttons. A voice offers only itself and our projections of intelligence. For Siri, users have been guided by Apple’s flair for the theatrical. They expect too much, and Apple delivers too little. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="24pjSv"&gt;The future of voice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="UZ8jBr"&gt;Here’s a true story. I took a break just now from writing this article to make a cup of tea and remembered that I had a meeting in an hour’s time. Worried it might slip my mind, I did what I often do in these situations: I asked Siri to set a reminder. “Siri, remind me at ten to five that I have a call,” I said. “Okay,” said Siri, “Setting a reminder for tomorrow at five: you have a call.” I tried again. This time Siri created a reminder for ten o’clock in the evening. The third time, I paused mid-command, trying to think of a clearer way to word my query. Siri got tired of waiting and beeped at me: “What do you want me to remind you of?” And at that, I gave up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xfCE77"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple can’t afford to give up on Siri&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l1xMve"&gt;It’s true that Siri and its ilk are often disappointing, but they still tempt users because they hold great potential. Despite the problems associated with voice interfaces, the technology represents a genuine advance. I regularly use Siri for quick tasks, like taking notes, setting timers, and making searches. And when it works, it works seamlessly and unthinkingly. It’s a genuine time-saver. Siri can do much more, too, especially if you’re willing to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22704860/siri-best-smart-home-voice-assistant-editorial"&gt;dive into the world of Apple Shortcuts and smart home commands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWPvuM"&gt;As an accessibility tool, voice controls and dictation have opened up modern gadgets to many more users, and since Apple introduced Siri in 2011, the company has launched a number of products that rely heavily on voice. This is either because screen real estate is limited (the Apple Watch) or it’s nonexistent (the AirPods and HomePod). In years to come, we can expect Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654606/apple-ar-vr-headset-iphone-wireless-connection-stream-data"&gt;augmented reality glasses&lt;/a&gt; to be added to this list. With this in mind, Apple urgently needs to fix Siri — not ignore it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7tmRQiWXwOhvqxy7gSrUc-vv5eI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993026/akrales_190327_3315_0182.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;AirPods, HomePod, and Apple Watch — all products where Siri is helpful or essential. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lSIjso"&gt;If you want to be optimistic, then there are some signs the company is turning the ship around. AI, in general, has received much more attention from Apple in recent years. From poaching Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/3/17195076/google-ai-chief-john-giannandrea-joining-apple-machine-learning-siri"&gt;head of machine learning in 2018&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/13/16300464/apple-iphone-x-ai-neural-engine"&gt;designing its own AI processors&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21301511/apple-ai-machine-learning-features-wwdc-2020-convenience"&gt;regular launch of AI-enhanced features&lt;/a&gt;, the company is clearly paying more attention to the field. And, best of all, Siri itself has seen a few significant improvements, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522993/apple-siri-on-device-speech-recognition-no-internet-wwdc"&gt;on-device processing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523045/apple-wwdc-siri-third-party-devices-ecobee-watch-tvos-tv"&gt;availability on third-party hardware&lt;/a&gt; added this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Di1z2J"&gt;I’m still skeptical, though. For a start, even when it comes to basic commands, it often seems Siri is not just standing still but moving backward. With iOS 15, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/352142/ios-15-siri-third-party-app-integrations-deprecated.html"&gt;removed a decent chunk of Siri’s functionality&lt;/a&gt;, including tasks related to notes and photos, and third-party integrations like ride-hailing and payments. Other basic commands, like checking voicemail, also seem &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/29/users-complain-about-siri-no-longer-being-able-to-send-email-and-check-call-history/"&gt;to have recently disappeared&lt;/a&gt; (whether temporarily or not isn’t clear). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SdqcXC"&gt;The big problem, I think, is that Apple still doesn’t know what it wants Siri to be. Is the feature simply a way to control your phone with your voice — letting you navigate apps and find content? Or is it something more ambitious — an actual assistant capable of carrying out complex tasks on your behalf? Apple tends to present Siri as the latter in marketing materials, while users find its functionality limited to the former. As someone who reports on AI and machine learning, I think we’re still many, many years away from building computers that truly &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; us. Language is just too complex, too deeply rooted in human experience and culture, to be brute-forced by the sort of statistical models we’re throwing at the problem. And while, yes, there are lots of impressive new language systems out there, none of them are reliable enough to create a flawless digital assistant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="D5vLZ1"&gt;If Apple wants to salvage Siri, I think it needs to reset expectations and focus on core competencies instead. It’s interesting to compare Siri’s launch with that of its competitors. When Google introduced &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/snL88L1DQQ4"&gt;Google Assistant in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, for example, the focus was less on solving complex tasks and understanding users’ every whim, and more on making the company’s basic search functionality accessible in more places. It was a tighter focus that gave Google the space to surprise, rather than disappoint. (Though the company has certainly over-promised in later ads, too.) Siri, by comparison, surprised us all when it launched in 2011, but has since burned out that goodwill. Apple needs to re-focus on the basics rather than push into a future that doesn’t yet exist. It needs to start listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJPM0M"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22704233/siri-apple-digital-assistant-10-years-development-problems-why"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22704233/siri-apple-digital-assistant-10-years-development-problems-why</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T03:32:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T03:32:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple finally lets you report App Store scams</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MSLXmSgAgFbhRM3vT8eiqNXDfn8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947070/acastro_210831_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2QeKQk"&gt;One month ago, we laid out a list of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;eight obvious things Apple could do&lt;/a&gt; to prove it puts App Store users ahead of profits. Today I learned the company acted on at least one of these ideas: Apple will now let you directly report a scammy app from its listing in the App Store with a new-and-improved version of its “Report a Problem” button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G8UELa"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mazkewich/status/1444780501949194256"&gt;Richard Mazkewich&lt;/a&gt; and scam hunter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1444801938990657536"&gt;Kosta Eleftheriou&lt;/a&gt; point out on Twitter, the button has not only returned to individual app listings for the first time in years, it now includes a dedicated “Report a scam or fraud” option in the drop-down menu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OagmtA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;In a major reversal, Apple quietly added back the “Report a Problem” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AppStore?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@AppStore&lt;/a&gt; button in iOS 15: &lt;a href="https://t.co/UopiPDEV7e"&gt;pic.twitter.com/UopiPDEV7e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Kosta Eleftheriou (@keleftheriou) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/keleftheriou/status/1444814469184425988?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BuSUQB"&gt;Until iOS 15, the only way you could find this button was to scroll &lt;em&gt;all the way down to the bottom&lt;/em&gt; of the Apps or Games tab in the App Store, get kicked out to a website where you’d need to re-sign in. Then you could pick from “Report suspicious activity,” “Report a quality issue”, “Request a refund” or “Find my content.” None of the options offered a clear way to report a scam, and the “Report suspicious activity” would redirect you to Apple Support instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kV3tFU"&gt;To add insult to injury, Apple would only let you report “a quality issue” if you’d already paid money (and thus fallen for the scam). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dvpc1F"&gt;But now, it seems like every free app with in-app-purchases appears to offer the “Report a Problem” option. I checked a handful of apps I’ve never paid for (but could have) and they all displayed the button. You’ll still get kicked out to a website where you’ll need to sign in, but overall this seems like a step forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="7pUYa5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Is Apple actually hiring scam investigators?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aIfpkS"&gt;Of course, the big question is whether Apple will actually take action on those reports. Another thing we pointed out last month is that Apple only has 500 human app reviewers — compared to 15,000 content moderators at Facebook, 20,000 at Google, and, yes, 2,200 at Twitter (a company &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; from the most valuable and profitable in the world). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aabRXO"&gt;Intriguingly, there may be some movement on that front too: Eleftheriou pointed out to me that Apple began hiring &lt;a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:mi2lnsb96ikJ:https://jobs.apple.com/en-us/details/200284943/asi-investigator&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;strip=1&amp;amp;vwsrc=0"&gt;for an “ASI Investigator” position on September 8th&lt;/a&gt;. “ASI Investigators are accountable for investigating fraudulent apps and trends, as well as the developers involved,” part of the job posting read. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvTqX3"&gt;Shame that job posting no longer exists; it’s been taken down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R9LPlp"&gt;Perhaps, at the very least, Apple’s automated systems can use the new data to sound the alarm when a scam app crosses a predefined threshold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bJYUny"&gt;Apple definitely seems to be listening to the recent wave of anger around the App Store. In addition to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22667242/apple-app-store-major-policy-changes-history"&gt;a variety of small forced concessions&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of judicial and regulatory scrutiny, Apple just &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/29/rate-and-review-apple-iphone-built-in-apps/"&gt;started allowing users to review the company’s own apps that it bundles with every iPhone&lt;/a&gt;. Apple Podcasts, Weather, and even the built in Calculator app are all fair game for angry 1-star reviews. Immunity from user scrutiny may not be the most egregious advantage Apple has enjoyed in its own App Store, but it’s nice to see the company leveling the playing field even a little bit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uqRb8Q"&gt;Here are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;the other suggestions&lt;/a&gt; we had for Apple’s App Store, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22667242/apple-app-store-major-policy-changes-history"&gt;a brief history of significant policy changes&lt;/a&gt; that Apple’s made over the years. Yes, we’re keeping track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZZXZth"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The App Store is too big to change","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22645070/apple-app-store-policies-purchases-cut-fees-change-class-action"},{"title":"Sweetheart deals and plastic knives: all the best emails from the Apple vs. Epic trial","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22611236/epic-v-apple-emails-project-liberty-app-store-schiller-sweeney-cook-jobs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22705405/apple-report-a-problem-button-app-store-scams"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22705405/apple-report-a-problem-button-app-store-scams</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-04T03:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T03:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon Prime members can now send gifts with just a phone number or email address</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8dLXvTD1FaGABeSBtm_-SKzsy7A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69947040/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Amazon Prime members can now send gifts without having the recipient’s address. | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1rT0ri"&gt;Amazon is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b/node=23555099011#nav-top"&gt;launching&lt;/a&gt; a new gifting feature today that will allow subscribers to its Prime service to send gifts to others using only an email address or phone number — no address required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Q5zBt"&gt;Gift-givers have to be Amazon Prime members, the program is limited to the continental US, and it can only be used on mobile devices for the time being. And even though Amazon has built in some safeguards— the gift-giver never gets access to the recipient’s mailing address— this sounds like a bad idea that is ripe for abuse by scammers, stalkers, and those who take pleasure in the online harassment of others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yvf6b5"&gt;Here’s how the new feature works: Gift-giver wants to surprise recipient with a present but doesn’t know recipient’s mailing address. Gift-giver does, however, have either recipient’s email address or phone number. Gift-giver chooses the gift on his Amazon mobile app, selects the “add gift receipt for easy returns” options during check-out, and will see an option to “let the recipient provide their address.” The giver then adds the recipient’s email address or mobile number. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VxDoAg"&gt;At this point the gift-giver’s card isn’t charged, but a hold is put on their payment card for the amount of the purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bYh34W"&gt;Recipient then gets a notice —via either a text message or email— that there’s a present from gift-giver waiting for her.  Note that if recipient doesn’t have an Amazon account, they can create one at this point. The recipient has to have an Amazon account to accept the gift, but only the giver has to be a Prime member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CPfRF2"&gt;The recipient can click on the notice from Amazon to reveal what the gift-giver sent, then she can decide whether to decline the gift, accept the gift but convert it to an Amazon gift card—the gift giver won’t be notified— or, she can just accept the gift. If the recipient accepts the gift, the giver’s payment card is charged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8A4VIX"&gt;If the recipient ignores the gift notification entirely, it expires within a few days, and the gift-giver gets his money back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ctcIIz"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WbaD-dl83cg?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=95&amp;amp;start=95" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zjz2hz"&gt;I asked Amazon if there was a mechanism for its members to opt out of this new service; there is not. Amazon’s stance is that if the recipient doesn’t want the gift, they can just decline it, or ignore the notification. What’s to stop a troll/harasser/stalker from sending multiple gifts to a recipient just to spam them with notifications, when the giver knows the recipient won’t accept? Technically nothing, although the recipient could notify Amazon customer service, which will decide what action to take. Such behavior would appear to violate Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?ref_=help_search_1-2&amp;amp;nodeId=GLHXEX85MENUE4XF&amp;amp;qid=1633180599372&amp;amp;sr=1-2"&gt;community guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OUxuRu"&gt;Not everything Amazon sells is eligible for the new gifting feature, but “millions” of items are, the company said. The eligible items include products sold by Amazon and third-party sellers on its platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PhUYs5"&gt;This is a clever feature from Amazon that will theoretically drum up more members; remember, you can’t accept a gift through this process without an Amazon account. It’s well-timed, too; the holiday shopping season is approaching and we’re already hearing warnings about &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/germanys-christmas-king-gets-caught-up-in-shipping-chaos-11632475801"&gt;shipping delays&lt;/a&gt; and supply shortages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vPiZmX"&gt;But the idea of getting a gift from someone who doesn’t have your address is problematic; there may be a very good reason the recipient’s address isn’t known to the gift-giver. If someone spams your phone or your inbox with multiple gift alerts, even if you don’t accept them or decline them, it will be up to the recipient to notify Amazon of the problem. Theoretically, since Prime members register their names, addresses and a payment method with Amazon, they wouldn’t risk having their account revoked by sending fake gifts. This is hardly a foolproof method for preventing harassment, however. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i6d9JM"&gt;Amazon says it will roll out this feature over the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GLEPDL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22704909/amazon-prime-members-send-gifts-phone-number-email-address"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22704909/amazon-prime-members-send-gifts-phone-number-email-address</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-03T20:25:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-03T20:25:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook encourages hate speech for profit, says whistleblower</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_GB8DFDxs2V5EqaZTlvK8KyrDD0=/387x0:2388x1334/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69946435/7CF1506A_B241_40D9_9565_05E4C77C2DC7.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen appears on &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GjQkgB"&gt;The whistleblower behind the leak of &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;an enormous cache of Facebook documents&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Frances Haugen, &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/facebook-whistleblower-misinformation-public-60-minutes-2021-10-03/"&gt;went public on &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday, revealing more of the inner workings the most powerful social media platform in the world. Revealing her identity on national television, Haugen described a company so committed to product optimization that it embraced algorithms that amplify hate speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TNTay4"&gt;“It’s paying for its profits with our safety,” Haugen told &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; host Scott Pelley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4boPU"&gt;According to a since deleted LinkedIn profile Haugen was a product manager at Facebook assigned to the Civic Integrity group. She chose to leave the company in 2021 after the dissolving of the group. She said she didn’t “trust that they’re willing to invest what actually needs to be invested to keep Facebook from being dangerous.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5cFvGm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There was conflict... between what was good for the public and what was good for Facebook”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PV1Jdl"&gt;Consequently she leaked a cache of internal research to the Securities and Exchange Commission in the hopes of driving better regulation of the company. She noted that she had worked at a number of companies, including Google and Pinterest, but that “it was substantially worse at Facebook” due to the company’s desire to put its profits over the welfare of its users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NJrYKb"&gt;“There was conflict... between what was good for the public and what was good for Facebook,” Haugen told Pelley, “and Facebook chose over and over again to optimize for its own interests — like making more money.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XSIrpG"&gt;While the company repeatedly claims it is helping stop hate speech, at least on its own products, one internal Facebook document leaked by Haugen says, “We estimate that we may action as little as 3-5% of hate and ~0.6% of V&amp;amp;I [Violence and Incitement] on Facebook despite being the best in the world at it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ruHTer"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Misinformation, toxicity, and violent content are inordinately prevalent among reshares,” said an internal document&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="J4KuvT"&gt;Another document was even more blunt. “We have evidence from a variety of sources that hate speech, divisive political speech, and misinformation on Facebook and the family of apps are affecting societies around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZ4FXB"&gt;Haugen claims the root of the problem is the algorithims rolled out in 2018 that govern what you see on the platform. According to her they are meant to drive engagement and the company has found that the best engagement is the kind instilling fear and hate in users. “Its easier to inspire people to anger than it is to other emotions,” Hagen said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qfYOL5"&gt;At the time, Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/11/16881102/facebook-news-feed-changes-meaningful-interactions"&gt;presented the algorithm changes as positive&lt;/a&gt;. “We feel a responsibility to make sure our services aren’t just fun to use, but also good for people’s well-being.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BaTR4c"&gt;But according to the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s reporting on Haugen’s concerns, the result was a sharp turn towards anger and hate. “Misinformation, toxicity, and violent content are inordinately prevalent among reshares,” said one internal memo quoted by the Journal, assessing the effects of the change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ITqMKf"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; began publishing its findings from the cache under the name “The Facebook Files” in September. One report &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675130/facebook-instagram-teens-mental-health-damage-internal-research"&gt;alleging Facebook had research proving Instagram harmed teenage girls&lt;/a&gt; has since led to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696698/facebook-instagram-for-kids-mosseri-markey-blumenthal-blackburn-pause"&gt;Congressional&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22704308/finsta-instagram-facebook-privacy-kids-safety-richard-blumenthal-blackburn"&gt;hearing&lt;/a&gt;. Ahead of the hearing Facebook attempted to change the narrative &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22695629/facebook-says-instagram-is-not-toxic-for-teens-despite-damning-wsj-report"&gt;in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;, which reproduced two of the reports referred to in the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;’s reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="irvkLs"&gt;Ahead of the &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; report, Facebook attempted the same deflections in a different form. Facebook Vice President of Global Affair Nick Clegg appeared on CNN’s &lt;em&gt;Reliable Sources&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ReliableSources/status/1444730430461251585?s=20"&gt;to defend the company&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday afternoon, just hours before Haugen would appear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lsEpXw"&gt;“I think that’s ludicrous,” Clegg said of the allegation that social media was responsible for the January 6 riots. “I think it gives people false comfort to assume that there must be a technological, or technical, explanation for the issues of political polarization in the United States.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2bkYb9"&gt;Haugen ended the interview by calling for regulation of social networks more broadly, something Facebook itself &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/2/19/21142478/facebook-regulation-content-moderation-singapore-pakistan"&gt;has called for&lt;/a&gt; in more limited form. She is &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/facebook-whistleblower-testify-us-senate-hearing-next-week-lawmakers-say-2021-09-29/"&gt;scheduled to appear before a Senate Commerce&lt;/a&gt; panel on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/3/22707860/facebook-whistleblower-leaked-documents-files-regulation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/3/22707860/facebook-whistleblower-leaked-documents-files-regulation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
