<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-30T12:35:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T12:35:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T12:35:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite on the Nintendo Switch will look and run better after its latest update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LyXVznhHET_gLcYd0qQjVoheMZk=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69049175/fortnite_battle_royale_50_on_50_1920.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ztSGlO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; for the Nintendo Switch is getting a patch that will boost performance in portable and docked modes. &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/gpu-performance-and-resolution-boost-for-fortnite-on-nintendo-switch"&gt;Epic Games says&lt;/a&gt; the game will run with a more consistent frame rate across the board “with fewer hitches,” though it’s still not 60 frames per second. And while the game will still use dynamic resolution to make visual adjustments on the fly to keep things running as smoothly as possible, the target resolutions in handheld and docked modes have gotten upgrades, too, seeing a 38 percent boost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZQcKJ"&gt;In handheld mode, the game has gone from 1000 x 560 up to 1170 x 660, which is closer to the Switch display’s 720p resolution. In docked mode, it’ll go up to 1560 x 880 instead of topping out at 1390 x 780. That’s a little closer to native 1080p docked resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4hLuy3"&gt;What this means is that the game will look less blurry, a common problem that many third-party ports encounter. The team provided a quick visual sample comparing pre-patch and post-patch sharpness to let you see what it might look like in-game. It’s definitely a noticeable improvement, even if it’s minor. Anyone squeezing more juice out of the aging Switch hardware gets kudos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jFKQSq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10420122"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EnsGvu"&gt;Lastly, the team says the game will free up 140MB of storage on your console, marking a small reduction in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite’s&lt;/em&gt; file size. Companies seem to be prioritizing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356947/call-of-duty-activision-file-size-shrink-space-savings-warzone"&gt;these kinds of updates these days&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s great for people who are still installing games to the Switch’s internal storage (despite microSD cards being extremely affordable).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2ZO5wI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Fortnite’s dinosaur eggs have hatched, and now raptors roam the island","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357140/fortnite-primal-update-egg-hatch-dinosaur-raptor"},{"title":"How AI, not just hardware, could make a new Switch more powerful than ever","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22348095/nintendo-switch-nvidia-dlss-graphics-ai-explained"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358448/fortnite-nintendo-switch-update-resolution-increase-visual-quality"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358448/fortnite-nintendo-switch-update-resolution-increase-visual-quality</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T12:35:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T12:35:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to score a COVID-19 vaccine appointment</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_u2r1v0qpkmDCofvfzLEcU6WDG4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809161/acastro_201217_1777_vaccine_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DzZXIa"&gt;One of the most frustrating tasks for many of us these days is finding how and where to get an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. It can be a real exercise in exasperation: the websites are often difficult to navigate and prone to frequent crashes; in addition, after finding an open appointment slot and filling out multiple pages of questions, you are often told that the opening has disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Vp4Bt"&gt;In view of all this, we’ve tried to gather as much helpful information as we can about ways to research and snag vaccination appointments for yourself and others. We’ll update this as more information presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7JT5j0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Real-world evidence shows that the COVID-19 vaccines work","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358085/covid-vaccines-effective-real-world-infection-protection-cdc"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="JYv8ZW"&gt;Research the vaccination qualifications in your state&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jJJ2mU"&gt;To begin with, it’s a good idea to try to pin down if you or the person you are assisting is currently qualified for the COVID-19 vaccine. Find the vaccine information site (or sites) that is being run by your state and / or city. This will also help you figure out when you might be qualified if you aren’t already. If you can’t find it via a quick search, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/specials/plan-your-vaccine/"&gt;NBC News has created a simple website&lt;/a&gt; that lets you find out what the current situation is in your specific state. &lt;a href="https://www.goodrx.com/covid-19/where-to-get-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;Prescription company GoodRx&lt;/a&gt; offers similar information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N5dWHX"&gt;Find all the places that might offer appointments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XK1Cc0"&gt;There are, fortunately or unfortunately, many different sites where you can go to find out if you can get an appointment to be vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgvDmn"&gt;For example, here in New York City, we’ve had to navigate separate sites run by the city and the state. Various hospital systems also have their own sites, as do pharmacies such as Walgreens and CVS, which have recently begun offering appointments for vaccinations. It’s a lot to check — and it can be enormously confusing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="usTdFX"&gt;As a result, your first step is probably to check your state’s government health website (searching your state name and “COVID vaccine” will probably do it). If you’re an urban dweller, check for your city’s information site as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8ot2F"&gt;While most personal physicians do not have access to vaccines, your doctor may be able to tell you some of the places to check. Other resources include your local hospital system, your union (especially if your employment qualifies you for a vaccination), and, of course, friends and colleagues, many of whom have probably been doing their own searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WZ6Bfn"&gt;As you find resources and sites, make sure to bookmark them. I keep a folder on my bookmarks bar called “COVID” — you may want to name yours something more cheerful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8lP4_R3np2CX9crqTcg9Mq6I2Js=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13963741/IMG_1653.1419968302.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6uguNM"&gt;Have all your information ready&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1Dt0LZ"&gt;Many of us who have tried to register for vaccination appointments have gone through the experience of filling out several screens of information only to find that, by the time we got to the end, the appointment was gone. So it’s a good idea to have all your data — such as your name, age, address, insurance info, and the registration ID / password for the site — immediately at hand. The faster you can go through the registration process, the more likely you are to actually get an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tRD8jU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleague Cory Zapatka says that he highly recommends using a password manager if you have one. He created accounts with all the vaccination sites in his area, even if they didn’t have appointments available at the time, so that if / when the time came, he could just auto-fill and get in right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9bBlc"&gt;And if you do get an appointment, make sure you have the appropriate paperwork already handy — especially since available appointments can be last minute. Necessary paperwork could include proof of employment, proof of age, or proof of a qualifying condition. Since the last one may require a doctor’s note or other record, it’s a good idea to call your doctor now — or if you’ve got access to a doctor’s or hospital website, that may offer you access to the proof you need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dqUcf"&gt;One more thing: check to see if you’ve gotten all the email that has been sent to you by your vaccine supplier. At least one staff member of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; found a necessary consent form hiding in her spam folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wCK4vB"&gt;Watch for news of upcoming vaccination sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bDlWg4"&gt;Keep an eye on the news. More and more sites and hubs are being added as the US gears up for a stronger push. If you see a news item saying that a hub is about to open, find the site for the hub and keep checking — once it does open, the available slots will probably go quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rz172X"&gt;One thing that sometimes helps is to look for patterns in the appearance of new appointments. For example, when I heard that the pharmacy chain Walgreens was going to begin giving out vaccines in my area, I spent a couple of days going onto the site, and suddenly realized that there was a pattern: the company was only scheduling appointments two to four days in advance and was adding new appointments each day just after midnight. Once I understood the pattern, I was able to get appointments for a couple of friends and let others know about it as well. (Note: since vaccine supplies and scheduling methods can change on a dime, this particular strategy may no longer work by the time you read this.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FsRia6ki1VqiuNodQvjKHdK9-ek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299690/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_8.47.56_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gz26d4"&gt;Look for help online&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PgrwN8"&gt;There are a number of online resources popping up headed by developers and other technology-savvy folks who have taken the time and effort to try to make sense of this confusion. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/02/10/covid-vaccine-appointment-websites/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/09/nyregion/vaccine-website-appointment-nyc.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for some of these listings.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="bUR9PN"&gt;California&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="111Dwk"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.vaccinateca.com/"&gt;VaccinateCA&lt;/a&gt; checks pharmacies and hospitals for information about open appointments.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="h3AFk9"&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WLYqtL"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.macovidvaccines.com/"&gt;MA Covid Vaccine Appointments site&lt;/a&gt; offers lists of and links to sites with available appointments. A volunteer-run site, &lt;a href="https://vaccinatema.com/"&gt;Vaccinate MA&lt;/a&gt;, tries to improve on the state website with a map-based design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BeZogz"&gt;Another site, &lt;a href="https://macovidvaxhelp.com/"&gt;Massachusetts COVID Vaccination Help&lt;/a&gt;, uses volunteers to help eligible state residents book an appointment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="c9OpvY"&gt;New Jersey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="ZYJAS8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://vaccinatenj.com/"&gt;Vaccinate NJ&lt;/a&gt; also uses volunteers to try to help state residents find vaccine opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ijVYyv"&gt;New York&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Vhk2GI"&gt;An NYC site called &lt;a href="https://www.turbovax.info/"&gt;TurboVax&lt;/a&gt; pulls “the latest appointments from 45 city and state-run vaccine sites in the NYC area” and puts them on Twitter. Followers who set their Twitter notifications for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/turbovax"&gt;@turbovax&lt;/a&gt; can quickly find out about newly opened appointment slots. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c0AX5B"&gt;Another called &lt;a href="https://nycvaccinelist.com/"&gt;NYC Vaccine List&lt;/a&gt; uses a combination of scripts and checks by volunteers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22256167/covid-vaccine-website-nyc-appointment"&gt;scour various sites for openings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YhbTu2"&gt;A site called &lt;a href="https://vaxhelp.nyc/"&gt;vaxhelp.nyc&lt;/a&gt; takes you through step-by-step instructions on how to navigate the New York State-run vaccine site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DyhcNt"&gt;Pennsylvania&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="TFo3y1"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://vaccinatepa.org/"&gt;VaccinatePA&lt;/a&gt; uses a team of volunteers to call hospitals and pharmacies for information on where appointments are available, where you can get on a waitlist, and whom to contact.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vRg75P"&gt;Texas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ZJic26"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.covid19vaccinetx.com/"&gt;Covid 19 Vaccine TX&lt;/a&gt; is a crowdsourced resource for registering with local counties and finding locations where vaccines may be available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3D44TY"&gt;If you’re on Slack, you might want to check out &lt;a href="https://www.texasupdates.com/"&gt;Texas Vaccine Updates&lt;/a&gt;, where you can get alerts on availability at various venues and find discussions on topics like how to prove eligibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="NEM7f0"&gt;Washington&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="yR8waA"&gt;A volunteer group in the state of Washington has launched the &lt;a href="https://www.covidwa.com/"&gt;WA COVID Vaccine Finder&lt;/a&gt; as an aggregation resource for vaccination appointments.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hFMYTz"&gt;General resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="C1YLfR"&gt;There are several sites that aggregate the aggregators: &lt;a href="https://wherecanigetavaccine.com/"&gt;Where Can I Get A Vaccine?&lt;/a&gt; offers a list of sites available for various US states. &lt;a href="https://covidshotfinder.com/"&gt;COVIDShotFinder&lt;/a&gt; lets you select a state or county and look for the various vaccine resources available. &lt;a href="https://www.findashot.org/"&gt;Find A Shot&lt;/a&gt; also shows you possible openings depending on your state, and it has its own &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/findashot/id1556177037"&gt;iOS app&lt;/a&gt;. A site named &lt;a href="https://www.findvaccinenow.com/"&gt;Vaccine Now&lt;/a&gt; offers to find sources not only in the US, but in the UK, Germany, India, Pakistan, and the UAE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jTJTFG"&gt;The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), together with the Boston Children’s Hospital and other medical institutions, operates &lt;a href="https://vaccinefinder.org/"&gt;VaccineFinder&lt;/a&gt;, which was created to promote flu and other general vaccinations but is now dedicated to helping people find COVID vaccinations. VaccineFinder lets you search using your ZIP code and is singular in that it allows you to filter for the Moderna, Pfizer / BioNTech, and Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jdCWU8"&gt;One possible strategy is to use page-change-monitoring tools such as &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/blog/how-to-be-alerted-of-covid-19-vaccine-availability-in-your-local-pharmacy/"&gt;Visualping&lt;/a&gt; to generate alerts for when new appointments become available. These apps watch websites for you and send alerts to your email, text, or even Slack account when new information appears. They can be very useful (and allow you to take time for, say, lunch). But since these are, for the most part, business apps, you may need to pay for the privilege. For example, while &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/pricing"&gt;Visualping does have a free service&lt;/a&gt;, it is limited to pinging you once an hour up to 65 times a month, which may not be often enough if you’re trying to score an appointment.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nhHjOx"&gt;If you’re a developer and / or coder who wants to help, check out &lt;a href="https://www.usdigitalresponse.org/"&gt;US Digital Response&lt;/a&gt;, an independent organization which, according to its website, “connects experienced, pro-bono technologists with local government and non-profit organizations responding to crisis.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Reservation Of The Anticovid Vaccine For Over Eighty In Apulian Pharmacies" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4leCSmB_jTd6jhw7V_SvQQsfQ8Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299704/1231117569.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Davide Pischettola / NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are able, it’s a good idea to reach out and help those who may not be able to get appointments on their own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8mSy40"&gt;If you can, help others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Kz9AlN"&gt;One of the worst things about the distribution of the COVID-19 vaccines is that those who need it the most are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227531/covid-vaccine-website-appointments-accessible-seniors"&gt;often the least likely to be able to navigate the technology required to get an appointment&lt;/a&gt;: older people, differently abled people, or those who don’t have or can’t afford computers and / or internet connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W2VOR9"&gt;If you have the time and talent, reach out to anyone you know who may not be able to get an appointment on their own. This could be as simple as finding phone numbers they can call to try to schedule an appointment, going online and getting an appointment for them, or helping them get to and from the vaccination site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Evm4o5"&gt;You could also see if there are any groups that are organizing help. For example, a startup nonprofit called &lt;a href="https://www.brydgehealth.org/"&gt;Brydge Health&lt;/a&gt; tries to make connections between those who need help getting an appointment and volunteers who can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rm5plO"&gt;Look for leftover vaccine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="M5v0nn"&gt;While the vaccines can last for six months while they’re kept frozen, once thawed and refrigerated, the Pfizer vaccine will last five days while the Moderna vaccine will last for 30 days. As a result, when people don’t show up for their appointments, some centers will &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/22229169/leftover-vaccines-random-people-grocery-stores-pharmacies"&gt;offer vaccinations to those who may not immediately qualify&lt;/a&gt; rather than waste vaccines that would otherwise be rendered unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EI3933"&gt;However, running to a nearby pharmacy or vaccine hub in the hit-and-miss hopes that there will be some shots waiting at the end of the day isn’t the most effective way to be vaccinated. (Besides, getting hypothermia while waiting in the cold isn’t going to help.) At least one group is trying to ameliorate the situation: a pilot project called &lt;a href="https://vaxstandby.com/"&gt;Vaccination Standby&lt;/a&gt; says that it will monitor providers around the US for word of extra doses and text notifications to those whose zip codes are near the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAc3tM"&gt;There are also local organizations that are offering standby lists. For example, Buncombe County in North Carolina has a &lt;a href="https://www.buncombecounty.org/countycenter/news-detail.aspx?id=19137"&gt;vaccination waitlist and standby list&lt;/a&gt;, as does the &lt;a href="https://www.co.monroe.in.us/egov/documents/1611179705_09719.pdf"&gt;Monroe County Health Department&lt;/a&gt; in Indiana. Check your local government site to see if there’s one in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fg3eNk"&gt;Be persistent!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JTTPvK"&gt;Yes, it’s frustrating as hell, but keep at it. If a website crashes, try again. If you’re dropped from a phone call, call again (and have a game, video, or book ready to keep yourself occupied while you’re on hold). If you can’t find anything during working hours, try late at night or very early in the morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBXxUO"&gt;Persistence may be one of the most important aspects of getting an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. You may be tempted to give up, especially after hitting the “no appointments available” wall time and time again. But until vaccine production is ramped up enough to cover more of our population, and until distribution becomes more organized and easier to manage, simple stubbornness may be your best tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwiVs8"&gt;And hopefully this article, and all of the advice it contains, will soon be unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1QdqaC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 12th, 11:10AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include the WA Covid Vaccine Finder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rW1K6i"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 16th, 10:10AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include a mention of webpage change monitoring tools.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Jkqbm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 19th, 11AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include another Massachusetts site and two general vaccination finding sites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSy6ej"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 22nd, 10:40AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to add the Find A Shot site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K6N5Zp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 24th, 11:15AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to add the Massachusetts COVID Vaccination Help site and reorganize some entries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZCf2zL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 25th, 9:15AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add the VaccineFinder site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysE1ZQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 1st, 9:10AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add the VaccinatePA site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5QTZ9Z"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 8th, 9:15AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add the Texas Vaccine Updates Slack channel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P99rRE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 30th, 11:45AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to check links, add services, and correct outdated information.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwQk0g"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0F1RM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T12:29:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T12:29:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Real-world evidence shows that the COVID-19 vaccines work</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="New York Opens 14 Pop-Up Vaccination Sites Throughout State" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fO5w88qUpMva_wnxOF_Q1KLSbNs=/0x0:6240x4160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69049121/1309318485.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Spencer Platt / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aazvjm"&gt;Three months after the United States’ COVID-19 vaccination campaign began, researchers are starting to collect data showing that the vaccines are just as good in the real world as they were in the clinical trials testing them. Recent studies have consistently shown that the vaccines don’t just protect against symptoms — they reduce the risk that someone will get infected with the coronavirus, a signal that they’ll reduce the spread of the virus, not just prevent sickness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t6h3vW"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21569345/moderna-covid-19-vaccine-coronavirus-efficacy-announcement"&gt;Moderna&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573072/pfizer-vaccine-effective-authorization-fda-safe"&gt;Pfizer / BioNTech&lt;/a&gt; vaccines were both around 95 percent effective at protecting people against symptomatic COVID-19 in large trials. It was never guaranteed that they’d perform just as well when they were distributed to the general public. Despite the best efforts of researchers to closely mimic the real world in a clinical trial, they’re never quite the same. The types of people who volunteer for trials sometimes aren’t representative of the general population. Certain groups, like pregnant people, weren’t recruited for the trials. The dose administration was in a more controlled environment than mass vaccination sites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJUa0d"&gt;That’s why it’s so encouraging to see these vaccines do just as good a job protecting people outside of the clinical trials. This week, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention announced encouraging results from a study designed to check how well the COVID-19 vaccines could protect frontline workers against infections in a real-world setting. Just under 4,000 health care workers and first responders &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/70/wr/mm7013e3.htm?s_cid=mm7013e3_w#contribAff"&gt;swabbed themselves weekly&lt;/a&gt; over 13 weeks to check for the virus. In that group, which is regularly exposed to COVID-19 at work, two shots of the vaccines were 90 percent effective against infection. A single dose was also protective; it prevented 80 percent of infections. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mx3oHg6C39gd0artDq6gbLM_ANw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22408006/mm7013e3_COVIDVaccineFieldEffectiveness_IMAGE_29Mar21_v2_1200x675_medium.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fI3sg4"&gt;The CDC’s results build on other research that has had similarly good findings. The first real-world data on vaccines came from Israel, which had a fast start to its COVID-19 vaccination program. &lt;a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2101765?query=featured_home"&gt;One study&lt;/a&gt; from February compared around 600,000 people who had been vaccinated with the Pfizer / BioNTech shots to 600,000 people who had not been vaccinated. It found that it was 94 percent effective against symptomatic COVID-19 a week after the second dose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1YAdt5"&gt;In the United States, the first data came from people living in long-term care facilities and health care workers — who also happened to be the first people to get the vaccine in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tUwTpc"&gt;A close look at the long-term care facilities was especially important for researchers because the people living in them are elderly and very vulnerable to COVID-19. In addition, vaccines sometimes don’t work as well in older adults. So it was good news to see that just one dose of the Pfizer / BioNTech vaccine was &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/70/wr/mm7011e3.htm#contribAff"&gt;63 percent effective&lt;/a&gt; against infection — not just symptoms — of the coronavirus in two long-term care facilities in Connecticut, according to a CDC report from March. &lt;a href="https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2021.02.15.21251623v1.full.pdf"&gt;Another study&lt;/a&gt; found that the shots were also 88 percent effective against coronavirus infections in a group of Mayo Clinic patients vaccinated between December 2020 and early February 2021, presumably all long-term care facility residents and health care workers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LuIFUS"&gt;As vaccination campaigns around the world continue, researchers will keep collecting data and tracking their effectiveness in different groups. There are still unanswered questions — experts still want to know how the available vaccines &lt;a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/health-law-and-business/real-world-study-to-offer-look-at-how-covid-19-vaccines-stack-up"&gt;compare to each other&lt;/a&gt;, how long protection lasts, and how well they work in people who are &lt;a href="https://www.medpagetoday.com/infectiousdisease/covid19/91775"&gt;immunocompromised&lt;/a&gt;, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OCCvYP"&gt;But the studies we have so far are early signals that the COVID-19 vaccines are working, and working extremely well. That makes holding off the looming &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/peteraldhous/cdc-cases-warning-fourth-surge"&gt;fourth coronavirus surge&lt;/a&gt; in the United States even more important: the more people stay safe now, the more get the benefit of the lifesaving shots. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9BrrOu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z0IJIR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358085/covid-vaccines-effective-real-world-infection-protection-cdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358085/covid-vaccines-effective-real-world-infection-protection-cdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T12:15:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T12:15:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Game of Thrones is heading to Broadway with a new prequel play</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j_-y6TK5sJCNZN1eKyDkkx1lpQY=/0x0:2500x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69049046/ep01_sean_bean_04.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="14weUB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; has often been called out for its near-Shakespearean levels of intrigue and theatrical drama. So it’s not exactly a surprise that the next move for the franchise is to the stage: a new Broadway show based on George R.R. Martin’s popular fantasy series is now in the works, according to a new report &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/game-of-thrones-play-in-the-works-for-broadway-will-revive-iconic-characters-exclusive?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;from &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K3HLpm"&gt;The goal is to stage the &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; play starting in 2023, with plans for productions in New York City, London’s West End, and Australia. Dominic Cooke is set to direct, with Simon Painter and Tim Lawson on board as producers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Kwfviw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Coming in 2023&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Crc2Cf"&gt;The play is said to be a prequel set during &lt;a href="https://awoiaf.westeros.org/index.php/Tourney_at_Harrenhal"&gt;The Great Tourney at Harrenhal&lt;/a&gt;, 16 years before the events of Martin’s &lt;em&gt;A Song of Ice and Fire&lt;/em&gt; book series (and &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;, HBO’s blockbuster TV series adaptation). Fans will recognize that tournament as the start of the pivotal events in the lead-up to the books and show, which (mild spoilers) would eventually lead to Robert Baratheon’s rebellion and the overthrow of the Targaryen dynasty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xxBq8P"&gt;And while HBO isn’t involved in the production (at least for now), the as-yet-unnamed play would give fans a chance to revisit popular characters like Ned Stark, Jaime Lannister, Robert Baratheon, Oberyn Martell, Barristan Selmy, Arthur Dayne, and Prince Rhaegar Targaryen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w55OdV"&gt;“The seeds of war are often planted in times of peace,” Martin said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;THR&lt;/em&gt;. “Few in Westeros knew the carnage to come when highborn and smallfolk alike gathered at Harrenhal to watch the finest knights of the realm compete in a great tourney, during the Year of the False Spring. It is a tourney oft referred during HBO’s &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;, and in my novels, &lt;em&gt;A Song of Ice and Fire&lt;/em&gt; … and now, at last, we can tell the whole story... on the stage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FS2QvE"&gt;Martin is involved in the production and is working with playwright Duncan Macmillan on the story. That adds yet another item to his already crowded plate of projects, including serving as an executive producer on &lt;em&gt;House of the Dragon&lt;/em&gt; and at least two other TV shows and his new five-figure deal with HBO to develop new shows and films for HBO Max. Additionally, HBO is already working on at least five more &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; spinoffs, which will presumably see Martin’s involvement in some fashion. And of course, there’s his work on the &lt;em&gt;long-&lt;/em&gt;awaited final books in his &lt;em&gt;A Song of Ice and Fire &lt;/em&gt;series — &lt;em&gt;The Winds of Winter&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;A Dream of Spring&lt;/em&gt; — which Martin has been working on for nearly a decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HNRLzw"&gt;Martin’s series wouldn’t be the first major fantasy story to make the jump from page to screen to stage. The most obvious precedent is &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Cursed Child&lt;/em&gt;, the two-part Potter play that serves as a sequel to the popular series of books, with a story from author J.K. Rowling that continues the events of the series. That play, which opened in London in 2016, has since expanded with productions on Broadway in NYC and in Melbourne, with a planned run in Toronto set for 2022. &lt;em&gt;Cursed Child&lt;/em&gt; has also been a critical and commercial success, winning six Tony Awards in 2018 (including Best Play) and &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2019/01/broadway-harry-potter-to-kill-a-mockingbird-box-office-records-musicals-frozen-aladdin-1202527930/"&gt;bringing in record-setting revenues&lt;/a&gt; — despite a somewhat lukewarm reception by fans of the story itself. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358391/game-of-thrones-broadway-play-george-r-r-martin-theater-2023"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358391/game-of-thrones-broadway-play-george-r-r-martin-theater-2023</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T12:06:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T12:06:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>The loneliest polar bear has company in a warming world</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rjURzzCDnhePV0meNc0X9Bsr_bs=/0x0:5184x3456/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69048994/NORA9.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nora the polar bear.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Beth Nakamura /The Oregonian&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MLzAOK"&gt;In early November 2015, a polar bear cub named Nora was abandoned by her mother at the Columbus Zoo and Aquarium, leaving her fate in the hands of a team of veterinarians and zookeepers. &lt;em&gt;The Loneliest Polar Bear: A True Story of Survival and Peril on the Edge of a Warming World&lt;/em&gt; tells the story of the frantic effort to keep Nora alive and well, from the struggles of replicating polar bear milk to an hours-long surgery to fix a broken bone in her leg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sbBRJh"&gt;But the book, an expansion of author Kale Williams’ &lt;a href="https://projects.oregonlive.com/projectnora/1-3/series"&gt;2017 series about Nora&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;The Oregonian &lt;/em&gt;/ OregonLive, goes beyond the life of a single bear. It details the political battles over the existence of climate change, debates about the ethics of zoos, and the already disastrous effects of global warming on native Alaskan villages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aj2u62"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke to Williams about pulling all of these pieces together, writing about native communities, and the trouble of holding up one animal as a mascot for a complex problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wPsOOE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview has been lightly edited for length and clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VaES8TrTPQVViX8Hdi9AL4y03gw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22406406/9781984826336.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gULjVq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a lot of very riveting and emotional moments packed into this book. So my first question for you is, did you cry at all when you were writing it? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oikxmi"&gt;Absolutely, on more than one occasion. Do you want just the writing part or the reporting part? Do you want travel frustrations or just emotional destitution? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hzcu21"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about the emotional destitution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3HMHsd"&gt;I think probably one of the hardest parts, this was actually after the manuscript was finished, and we were sort of in the editing phase and starting fact-checks. But last year, and this was hard for lots of reasons other than just the book itself, but I had been reading so much about climate change and talking to so many people who had been affected by it, and then the pandemic had hit. And then the wildfires in Oregon just brought this blanket of smoke into Portland that seemed to stick around forever. And that was really, I think, the low point for me because it kind of just brought home all these different themes of, you know, there was so much science denial going on around the pandemic, and it was just so reminiscent of all the stuff that I had sort of been reading about for the book and that I researched and writing about. And then to have that with the smoke on top of it was really just, at a lot of times felt like it was too much to bear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vZ4oSF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The book covers the history of polar bears and their habitats, the difficulty of raising them in captivity, the history of climate studies, the precarity of native populations in Alaska — and that’s all within the first 50 or so pages. So was it tough to weave all these different threads together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iyD9br"&gt;It was, but I thought it was important to do so because I really wanted to place both humans and polar bears in their present situation by looking at how we got here, even on a geological timescale. We’ve all adapted to the world as it exists now, and we’ve been able to do so because it has changed on a geologic pace. But that is no longer the case. Obviously, the changes that we’re seeing now are much more rapid. So those adaptations that we’ve been able to do are not going to be enough for a lot longer. As the pace of change increases, then we are obviously going to need to adapt more quickly, which will be possible for some of us, those of us with means, but not possible for others, who aren’t able to escape wildfires in hotels or ice storms in shelters, or for polar bears who don’t have the advantage of being able to leave their habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3t7k73vupdlc-l9sUWsAvEZBbWg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22408014/NORA1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dave Killen / The Oregonian&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nora at the Oregon Zoo in 2017. Her father, Nanuq, was born near Wales, Alaska, where warming temperatures threaten the livelihoods of both polar bears and native people who depend on seasonal ice sheets for hunting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QJtFPT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s sort of a “come for the cute polar bear cub, stay for the climate and indigenous justice” vibe to the book. So are you hoping people will be reeled in by Nora and then have larger takeaways from it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O2TCg8"&gt;Yeah, it struck me that I was kind of doing the same thing that zoos do. You know, where obviously there’s a draw that these types of animals have, and you can sort of use that as a vehicle for another message, but I think her story remains central to the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L1Yij5"&gt;But I think, like I said before, I wanted to have this additional context of how people who live where polar bears do have learned to exist in the same type of harsh climate that seems inhospitable for those of us who live farther south. And you can’t really understand the problems that they’re facing without looking at the history of climate science and the rise of climate denial over the last 40 or 50 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DDyF25"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So this is your first book, your first time writing and being edited in such a large format. Were there any stories or interesting facts that didn’t make it into the book?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eP26rc"&gt;Oh, man, there definitely were because we cut probably 25,000 words from the first draft to the final manuscript. I think that maybe is one of the areas where my editor helped the most was writing about the indigenous community up there. [&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: one of the main settings of the book is the village of Wales, Alaska.&lt;/em&gt;] I had a lot more on their history in some of the earlier drafts, including this whole long story about the first missionaries that went to Wales and the schools that they set up and how one of them ended up getting murdered by a couple of teenagers in the village, mostly because he was a supreme asshole to all of the people that lived there and treated them all with great disdain, was horribly racist, had no respect for any of their culture or traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KsEb5e"&gt;That didn’t make it into the story. But I think that’s probably for the best. One of the things that I’ve been trying to pay close attention to is there’s a hashtag going around that was, I think it was like “OwnStories,” where people from these communities should be allowed to tell their own stories. And it’s not really my place to write the complete unabridged history of the village because there are lots of people who are more informed on that topic than I am. And for me to come in as an outsider and try to tell that story, it’s probably not my place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iBmuI2LQxzQ60vEp3uUfspihMsw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22406428/WALES1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dave Killen / The Oregonian&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An aerial view of Wales, Alaska, an Inupiat village.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FenUIY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You talk about polar bears being a really complicated mascot for climate change and also the trickiness of trying to figure out if an animal is happy. But there are also a lot of anecdotes about Nora’s caretakers connecting in a really emotional way with her. Do you think there are problems that come with ascribing human traits and feelings to animals?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PeMLqZ"&gt;I do, yeah. You know, obviously, anthropomorphizing has its drawbacks. I mean, we can project things onto animals that it’s impossible to know whether they’re actually experiencing. But I do think that there are plenty of ways to know whether an animal is doing well or not doing well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lFeebl"&gt;There are dangers to ascribing human emotions to animals. But I think it’s also dangerous to think of them as, you know, big bags of meat that don’t have any sort of emotion at all. I don’t think it’s possible for us to necessarily understand how they experience that emotion. But I think it would be dangerous to think that they have no emotions whatsoever because then you are free to not care how well they’re doing. And you can treat them however you want. And I don’t think that’s right, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4mlzpL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll be honest, when I looked at the cover of the book, I felt a little like, “Oh man, here we go” because when I was a kid, I definitely grew up in the era where it felt like every day at school, people were saying, “We have to save the polar bears,” to the point at which polar bears became sort of an empty signifier and just barely have any meaning anymore. Do you feel like through the process of writing this book, your feelings about the polar bear as a mascot or about conservation efforts or how we talk about climate change, did they change throughout the writing of this book?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JEOkj0"&gt;I don’t know if they changed, but I certainly became more aware of the problems of having any sort of poster child or figurehead or mascot for a problem that’s as complex and multifaceted as climate change. I mean, anytime you simplify something as big as the climate crisis into “We need to save the polar bears,” something is going to be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kLdqLx"&gt;There are 19 populations that are around the Arctic. And some of them are certainly declining, others are stable, some are growing, others they have no idea about. When you put the polar bear up there as “We need to save this animal,” when, in fact, some of these populations are growing, then people who want to argue in bad faith can come back and say, “What do you mean we need to save the polar bears? We’ve got populations that are trending upwards. This is why all of climate science is fake.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M6Kys7"&gt;When you have one mascot at the top of your flag, and everybody is supposed to rally around, it provides opportunities for people like that to come in and sort of cherry-pick and dismiss your whole argument. That being said, you know, if the polar bear is what it takes to inspire action in somebody, then I don’t really see the harm in that. It’s just a matter of trying to weigh those two things against each other.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357151/kale-williams-loneliest-polar-bear-climate-change-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357151/kale-williams-loneliest-polar-bear-climate-change-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Area 120 incubator releases a powerful AI document scanner for Android</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0LkIYK9iwh9IhIfXkNrntStG9VQ=/107x0:1292x790/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69048903/Screen_Shot_2021_03_30_at_9.01.49_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2GBHa9"&gt;Google’s Area 120, an internal incubator program for experimental projects, is releasing a new app today called Stack that borrows the technology underlying the search giant’s &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/document-ai"&gt;powerful DocAI enterprise tool&lt;/a&gt; for document analysis. The end result is a consumer document scanner app for Android that Google says vastly improves over your average mobile scanner by auto-categorizing documents into the titular stacks and enabling full text search through the contents of the documents and not just the title. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Bt1Ca"&gt;“I joined Google a couple of years ago when my education startup, Socratic, was acquired. At Socratic, we used Google’s computer vision and language understanding to make learning easier for high school students. I wondered if we could apply the same technologies to make organizing documents easier,” said Christopher Pedregal, the team lead on Stack, in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FpXSKY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Stack lets you search through the full text of scanned documents &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="muAoj3"&gt;Following the acquisition, Pedregal and his colleague Matthew Cowan joined Google’s Area 120, where they came up with an app that could use DocAI and its artificial intelligence technology to improve the process of scanning receipts, bills, and other important documents. The app uses Google’s biometric authentication on Android, so you can secure sensitive documents behind face or fingerprint scanning to unlock the software. It also automatically creates fields for scanned bills so you can fill in due dates and other important info. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B3GTMH"&gt;The app, like so many of Google’s experimental (and sometimes even not-so-experimental) efforts, is getting released in the hopes it catches on and not with any real concrete business model attached or a definite roadmap. Pedregal stresses that “it’s early days” for Stack, which means the app can “still get things wrong.” It also means it could, at a moment’s notice, get sent to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/26/20977968/google-graveyard-products-shut-down-dead-not-supported-discontinues-spring-cleaning"&gt;Google Graveyard&lt;/a&gt; — though, presumably, with the option to export your documents if that does happen at some point in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uAX5gh"&gt;That said, it seems like a powerful alternative to a normal document scanner, and few companies are better than Google at understanding text and recognizing images. So it’s certainly worth a shot if you’re in the market for a better way to organize your real-world paper. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358088/google-stack-ai-document-scanner-app-android-release-announce"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358088/google-stack-ai-document-scanner-app-android-release-announce</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T11:47:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T11:47:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to type special characters on a Windows PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KyFfDbSg1BrFhmUnbhFSkzciu-Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69029603/mchin_190527_4449_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nBtPSS"&gt;Here’s the situation: you’re typing a report for work, and you suddenly have to write the phrase “Jones née Berkowitz.” Or you are adding a phrase in Spanish and need to use the word “años.” How do you add the special characters to the letters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2JFT5W"&gt;Special characters (also known as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diacritic"&gt;diacritical marks&lt;/a&gt;) may be more common in certain languages, but there are plenty of circumstances in which English speakers may need to use them. But because they are so rare in English, native English speakers may not have learned how to add those marks to documents, emails, or other writings. It’s not difficult to add them to your Windows document, although it’s not quite as smooth an operation &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22347140/apple-mac-special-characters-how-to"&gt;as on a Mac&lt;/a&gt;, where all you have to do is hold the appropriate key down. (In fact, once upon a time, you would have had to look up the symbol character codes...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="F2UXCI"&gt;Use the touch keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="cK212s"&gt;The easiest way to add diacritical marks to a document is to enable the Windows touch keyboard. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/windows-10-tip-get-easy-access-to-symbols-emojis-and-other-special-characters/"&gt;Ed Bott from &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for first leading me to this method.) The touch keyboard automatically appears if you’re using a Windows tablet or if you’re using a PC in tablet mode. If you don’t have a touchscreen, you can use the keyboard icon that appears in the taskbar, on the right side near the date. Don’t see it? This is how you get it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="3mKSNx"&gt;Right-click on the taskbar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="guGqAk"&gt;Click on “Show touch keyboard button”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Click on “Show touch keyboard button.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zX5tGpTALETlEtcWIgb7syaRgx4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22397964/special1.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click on “Show touch keyboard button” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="isigzU"&gt;Now, when you want to use a special character:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MiArSp"&gt;Click on the touch keyboard icon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vkiOjM"&gt;The touch keyboard will appear. Long press (with your mouse button or, if you have a touchscreen, your finger) on the letter you want to use &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mxWCG7"&gt;You’ll now see several extra keys showing the ways you can type that letter with different symbols. Select the one you want, and it will appear on your document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YsM2S5"&gt;If you want to enter an emoji, click on the emoji key (on the left of the “space bar”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Select the special character you want, and it will appear on your document." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ianQf8kqWF7MLYr-Jkzt0fc99TM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22397970/special3.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Select the special character you want, and it will appear on your document.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3KuFuR"&gt;Use the emoji keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Ias5hY"&gt;Another keyboard that you can access and can let you easily add special characters to your text is Windows’ emoji keyboard. Yes, it is mainly for adding emojis to your text, but it’s got other uses as well. And it’s simple to use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="YHAmrI"&gt;Hold down the Windows key (the one with the Windows symbol on it) and hit the period key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yERfP0"&gt;The emoji keyboard will pop up, showing a variety of emojis. Click on the symbols tab on top (the third from the left).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The emoji keyboard also lets you access special characters." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0rwi7njzEZ8YaPRWp_OnJwmWVBg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22399994/emoji4.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The emoji keyboard also lets you access special characters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="RBvuoy"&gt;Use the menu on the bottom line to select the type of symbol you’re looking for (if you’re looking for characters to use within text, you’ll probably want to select this one: Ç). Then scroll down until you find the character you want.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="blWVk1"&gt;Use the character map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MX8CIZ"&gt;If you’d like to try a more old-fashioned method of adding special characters to Windows, you can use the character map, which is a less polished and more complicated version of the touch keyboard but offers a similar service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rCcyqh"&gt;To access it on your Windows 10 system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="QyOOxs"&gt;Type “character” in your search field and then select the Character Map app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2thjaB"&gt;You’ll get a pop-up map showing a bunch of special characters for a specific font. You can change the font by clicking on the drop-down font menu at the top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The character map lets you access a wide variety of special characters." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t7GknZWGbXmLDWNLFDoIqxsW84U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22397981/special4.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The character map lets you access a wide variety of special characters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4Xgqtz"&gt;Click on the letter(s) or special characters that you want to use in your document and then click on the “Select” button. They’ll appear in the “Characters to copy” field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XN5Maf"&gt;Once you’ve selected all the characters you want, click on the “Copy” button and then paste the character(s) into your document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="F8Ftnt"&gt;Use the Unicode value&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="cLBy3k"&gt;If you look at the lower right-hand corner of the character map after you’ve chosen a letter or special character, you’ll see the word “Keystroke” followed by “Alt” and a four-digit number. This number represents the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unicode"&gt;Unicode value&lt;/a&gt; of the symbol, and it’s the time-honored standard for adding characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SKmqL4"&gt;If you use a few special characters consistently, it can be faster to simply add the character you want using your keyboard. There are several ways to do this; here are two of the easiest (each of which has its limitations):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="dMoLKy"&gt;Press the Alt key and then type the four-digit Unicode value. For this to work, you need to have a separate number pad on your keyboard, and the NumLock key should be enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PrXVUY"&gt;If you’re working with Microsoft Word, WordPad, Outlook, or another Microsoft app, you can type in the Unicode value and then type Alt-X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Hnw0dE"&gt;You can also press the Control key plus a symbol, and then the letter you want to accent. For example, Ctrl+’ and “e” will result in “é” — assuming you’re in a Microsoft app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="fcd8Jh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 26th, 10:50AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to add a section on using the Unicode values and the emoji keyboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aOGU5g"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 30th, 11:15AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated to add another way to add special characters within Microsoft apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22351023/windows-pc-special-characters-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22351023/windows-pc-special-characters-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T11:45:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T11:45:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>League of Legends: Wild Rift makes one of the world’s biggest games more accessible</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0BGRXXZ0qifoUNmfn0FGnp0fEsE=/16x0:7984x5312/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69048792/Key_Visual.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BOemoG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most popular games in the world, and it has been for the better part of a decade. But it’s also incredibly intimidating: a 5 vs. 5 competitive experience with all kinds of complex rules and quirks. It’s not a game you pick up and understand right away. That’s part of what makes &lt;em&gt;Wild Rift&lt;/em&gt;, a new spinoff for mobile, so surprising. It takes the core of &lt;em&gt;League &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;packages it in a way that makes it much more approachable for newcomers. This is by far the best way to start playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7qz41s"&gt;First, it’s important to note that &lt;em&gt;Wild Rift&lt;/em&gt; isn’t a direct port of &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt;. Instead, it’s a new version designed specifically for mobile (and, at some point in the future, consoles). It still feels like &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt; in a lot of ways, but there are some key differences. The core is identical: it’s a team game where squads of five go up against each other with the goal of taking down the opposing team’s base. You still navigate a map made up of three lanes, with a jungle full of creatures to kill in between, and you have to choose between a variety of heroes with unique skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KpLT6p"&gt;But the changes, while seemingly small, are noticeable. For one thing, the map is smaller, so it’ll take less time to clear out lanes on your way to the enemy’s base. In my experience, matches last around 20 minutes in &lt;em&gt;Wild Rift&lt;/em&gt;, compared to &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt; on PC where they can stretch out past 45 minutes. It’s just about the ideal length for playing on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PeV6yAmfkvWU-Ec7HixYGwLWCik=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22407862/dcf4f32e_8ef3_4fb5_80ad_f109c533de45.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YPahhn"&gt;The addition of touchscreen controls is a big shift as well. Riot has replaced a mouse and keyboard with lots and lots of on-screen buttons. There’s a virtual joystick for movement — it’s serviceable, but like all virtual joysticks, it can be unresponsive at times — and buttons for all of your different attacks. There are also auto-attack buttons so you can focus on killing nearby minions or destroying towers, one for warping back to base, as well as a mini-map and pop-ups whenever you can buy a new item. It’s a lot, and the screen can get pretty cluttered on a phone. (It’s a bit better if you’re on a tablet; I played on an iPad Pro, and the UI had a lot more room to breathe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6OITiz"&gt;Surprisingly, though, aside from a few small issues, the controls have worked fine for me across a dozen or so matches. The joystick can get sticky, and it’s easy to accidentally start recalling yourself back to base, but other than that, I haven’t had any issues. So long as you aren’t planning to go pro, you should be fine. Riot seems to have found a nice balance between streamlined controls and giving you lots of information. The game also has fewer characters to choose from — around 60, compared to well over 100 in the PC version — simplifying yet another aspect of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jzN6gi"&gt;So basically, &lt;em&gt;Wild Rift &lt;/em&gt;is a slightly lightweight take on &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt;. But aside from the controls and smaller map, the thing that really makes it work is the onboarding. &lt;em&gt;Wild Rift&lt;/em&gt; has an excellent tutorial series that teaches you the basics — how positions work, why you might want to wander off to kill a dragon — and it even gives you some in-game rewards for completing it. You can also bring up a version of the in-game map at any point and refresh yourself on everything from how the monsters work to what a top laner is supposed to do. It’s still an incredibly complex game, and you won’t learn everything from the tutorial, but it does an excellent job of easing in new players by explaining the basics in simple terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Nl4jn"&gt;A mobile version of &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt; makes a lot of sense — so much so that it’s surprising it took so long. Most of the biggest online games are available on smartphones. Sometimes, like with &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/em&gt;, those games offer an identical experience across platforms. Others, like &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22345184/rocket-league-sideswipe-android-ios-announced"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and — now — &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, have opted for a mobile-specific spinoff. (That strategy worked out for &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350782/pubg-mobile-one-billion-downloads-tencent"&gt;which recently celebrated 1 billion downloads&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NLG8Cf"&gt;It may be a decade old, but &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt; is arguably as popular as it’s ever been, with multiple spinoffs and even a Netflix series in the works. &lt;em&gt;Wild Rift&lt;/em&gt; may be a bit late to the party, but it looks to be an important part of the game’s next decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jdmftB"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Wild Rift &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is currently in open beta on both &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/league-of-legends-wild-rift/id1480616990"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;iOS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.riotgames.league.wildrift&amp;amp;hl=en_CA&amp;amp;gl=US"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358213/league-of-legends-wild-rift-iphone-android-preview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358213/league-of-legends-wild-rift-iphone-android-preview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T11:35:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T11:35:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Snag a refurbished, waterproof Kindle Oasis for $100 at Woot (update: sold out)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l-BqAzxZY0UEFyaHmf5tTTkgh8s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69048214/akrales_190327_3174_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Cfs4g1"&gt;The refurbished Kindle Oasis has sold out at Woot after about an hour of this post being live. Unfortunately, refurbished versions of the current model are a little over twice the cost of the $100 version this post originally highlighted, but &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07L8W2S8C/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s an option if you need to buy today&lt;/a&gt;. One big perk is that the newer version has a display with an adjustable color temperature that might make reading a little easier on the eyes wherever you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9FOkE"&gt;Another solid deal happening at Woot is on the Beats Solo Pro wireless headphones that have active noise cancellation. We’re including them here today because they’ve dropped another $5 below the best price yet. You can get the light blue color for $145, while the others available are $150. These are Beats’ best on-ear headphones yet, though people who aren’t enmeshed in the Apple ecosystem might want to know upfront that they recharge via Lightning. If you have an iPhone or iPad, there’ll be no adjustment necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tOwYwy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625639"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="upHxe9"&gt;Apple’s latest MacBook Air equipped with its M1 processor is $50 off at Best Buy and Amazon. It’s not a huge price drop, but it’s less than what Apple is charging for the same model. This laptop has 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. For the price, you’ll get fantastic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Yg2xIT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4FaIO5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated 11:36AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The refurbished Kindle Oasis has sold out at Woot. Updated to reflect this, and to provide a link to the refurbished version of the current generation Oasis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nxAhkV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/30/22358166/amazon-kindle-oasis-beats-headphones-apple-macbook-air-m1-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/30/22358166/amazon-kindle-oasis-beats-headphones-apple-macbook-air-m1-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-30T11:29:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-30T11:29:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Adobe’s new $14.99 iPad subscription bundles Photoshop, Illustrator, Fresco, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1cPb6twTH06ncxwJfv8ueZJLqmQ=/497x0:1199x468/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69048662/ezgif.com_gif_maker__3_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Adobe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0t3urR"&gt;Adobe has launched a new bundle for iPad creators. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adobe.com%2Fcreativecloud%2Fmobile-design-bundle.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F30%2F22358304%2Fadobe-design-mobile-bundle-price-ipad-photoshop-illustrator-fresco" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Design Mobile Bundle&lt;/a&gt; is available for $14.99 a month or $149.99 a year, and it includes access to iOS Creative Cloud apps like Photoshop, Illustrator, Fresco, and Spark, as well as services like Adobe Fonts and 100GB of cloud storage. Unlike Adobe’s other bundles, this won’t get you access to its desktop apps. Adobe says the bundle saves you 50 percent compared to paying for each app separately and that “they all work with touch and Apple Pencil.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vnMg16"&gt;Adobe’s mobile apps have come on a lot in the last couple of years. Photoshop only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/4/20937111/adobe-photoshop-ipad-now-available-download-cloud-psd-workflow"&gt;arrived on the iPad&lt;/a&gt; back in 2019, lacking many of the features of its desktop counterpart. But over time, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/27/21336315/photoshop-ipad-refine-edge-brush-rotate-canvas-update"&gt;Adobe has continued to add features&lt;/a&gt;, including a new rotate canvas tool that’s soon &lt;a href="https://blog.adobe.com/en/publish/2021/03/30/everythings-coming-together-for-mobile-creativity.html#new-ways-to-create:~:text=Our%20work%20on%20mobile%20applications%20is,capability%20to%20Illustrator%20on%20the%20desktop."&gt;making its way to desktop Photoshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="V47tWP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Soon, you’ll be able to load your brushes onto Photoshop on the iPad”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bvjiXE"&gt;Adobe also says that support for Photoshop’s desktop brushes is coming soon to iPad. “Soon, you’ll be able to load your brushes onto Photoshop on the iPad, meaning that all the great brushes you’ve discovered or created on Photoshop on the desktop will be close at hand on the iPad as well,” the company writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zw0SHn"&gt;A monthly cost of $14.99 makes this one of the less expensive bundles Adobe offers, though you are limited to only accessing it via an iPad (and iPhone in the case of Fresco). Currently, you can subscribe to all of its apps for $52.99 a month. Meanwhile, if you only need Photoshop and Lightroom, there’s a bundle with 20GB of storage for $9.99 a month that works on both desktop and tablet. (A bundle with 1TB of storage costs $19.99 a month.)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358304/adobe-design-mobile-bundle-price-ipad-photoshop-illustrator-fresco"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358304/adobe-design-mobile-bundle-price-ipad-photoshop-illustrator-fresco</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
