<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-22T14:19:20-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T14:19:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T14:19:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s concert series returns with a Rocket League rave</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0frdLnmWV4o3Nxv51Zm-Ue8Q9Dw=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69007270/fortnite_llama_rama_kaskade_concert_1920x1080_27dc77beeff6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="F8Sb49"&gt;Epic Games is reviving its in-game &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;concert series with a virtual performance by electronic artist Kaskade&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;over the course of the March 26th weekend. The concert will take place inside &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s Party Royale game mode, and it will also feature tie-ins with &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;’s upcoming season, as the popular competitive car soccer game is developed by Epic-owned studio Psyonix. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UYnqEe"&gt;There’s a lot of, shall we say, corporate synergy going on here. Psyonix has a longstanding partnership with electronic music label Monstercat to bring leading producers of house, bass, and other genres into &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;’s in-game soundtrack. And Kaskade just last fall &lt;a href="https://edm.com/lifestyle/rocket-league-season-2-electronic-dance-music"&gt;released his Monstercat debut&lt;/a&gt;, an EP called &lt;em&gt;Reset&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oTDEtI"&gt;Now, Kaskade will be performing &lt;em&gt;Reset&lt;/em&gt; in its entirety within &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, while his performance will be followed up by the debut of the &lt;em&gt;Rocket League &lt;/em&gt;season’s new trailer. The producer and DJ will also apparently “drive &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; cars” around to various in-game stages and “arrive at the new Neon Fields for a festival-style performance.” Oh yeah, and the concert can also be viewed with friends from the social video app Houseparty, another of Epic’s acquisitions from the last few years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9QBMnx"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nWPzco67Bmo?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Yf6CvT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s concert series, which started in 2019 with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/21/18234980/fortnite-marshmello-concert-viewer-numbers"&gt;record-breaking in-game performance by electronic artist Marshmello&lt;/a&gt;, became a surprising hit during the early months of the COVID-19 pandemic as a way to experience the kind of live events that all but disappeared last year. Travis Scott’s &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;performance last April attracted &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21233946/travis-scott-fortnite-concert-astronomical-record-breaking-player-count"&gt;more than 12 million people&lt;/a&gt;, and the company’s Party Royale mode it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21241414/fortnite-party-royale-ltm-mode"&gt;launched around the same time&lt;/a&gt; has become an avenue for all sorts of in-game events and the kinds of cross-cultural spectacles that have transformed &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;into a kind of hybrid media destination. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KTlxSV"&gt;Epic has since expanded the technology setup that makes these live events possible with a new studio space in Los Angeles, which it began using for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21423004/fortnite-party-royale-concert-series-dominic-fike"&gt;three-week concert series in September&lt;/a&gt;. Now, it looks like the developer is ready to get back to hosting boundary-pushing live events with what sounds like a truly transmedia experience covering its many apps, games, and music connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sKKiG9"&gt;The Kaskade concert will run inside Party Royale on March 26th at 8PM ET, and then on March 27th at 9AM ET and 2PM ET. It will be part of the next&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/rev-up-for-the-next-llama-rama-earn-rewards-in-fortnite-and-rocket-league"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;Llama-rama” event&lt;/a&gt;, where players can earn in-game items and other rewards for playing both &lt;em&gt;Rocket League &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, starting March 25th and running until April 9th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j2K0pZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344853/fortnite-concert-series-rocket-league-kaskade-live-rave"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344853/fortnite-concert-series-rocket-league-kaskade-live-rave</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T13:54:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T13:54:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Jeep’s ‘Magneto’ electric Wrangler concept is a big tease</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OH2ISekpe7UgQWr0pdSAPc0rpCA=/0x27:3000x2027/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69007068/CN021_004JP5ui31njcmo9dtvpekb1b9b6816.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Stellantis&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="krRWdH"&gt;Jeep has unveiled a new electric vehicle with an X-Men-inspired name: the Wrangler Magneto. However, don’t get your hopes up for this being the electric Jeep Wrangler you might have been wishing for — the Magneto is just a concept car, so you probably won’t be able to buy one any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qCUEXN"&gt;The car’s design is based on the 2020 Jeep Wrangler Rubicon, but it has an electric motor that offers up to 273 pound-feet of torque and 285 horsepower, and it comes equipped with an 800-volt system spread across four battery packs, &lt;a href="https://media.stellantisnorthamerica.com/newsrelease.do?id=22607&amp;amp;mid=1"&gt;according to Jeep&lt;/a&gt;. The company didn’t share a range for how far the Magneto can go without needing a charge, though that’s not all too surprising given that this is a concept car. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UJf4h8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10406458"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3HjXen"&gt;The Magneto also, interestingly, comes equipped with a &lt;a href="https://www.thedrive.com/tech/39877/how-the-electric-jeep-wrangler-magneto-concept-works-with-a-manual-transmission"&gt;six-speed manual transmission&lt;/a&gt;. And while that might be surprising, since most electric cars have single-speed transmissions, the Magneto actually isn’t the first electric concept car to have a multi-gear transmission. Ford showed off a concept six-speed manual transmission all-electric Mustang, the Mustang Lithium, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/5/20950148/ford-electric-mustang-manual-prototype-stick-shift-lithium-sema-2019"&gt;back in November 2019&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AU57So"&gt;Jeep’s parent company Fiat Chrysler (which is now called Stellantis) has been slow to adopt EVs, and with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21525290/hummer-ev-electric-truck-gmc-price-specs-range"&gt;GMC’s Hummer EV&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/13/21563949/rivian-electric-truck-suv-price-r1t-r1s-hands-free"&gt;Rivian’s R1T pickup truck&lt;/a&gt; on the very near horizon, Stellantis could risk losing customers if it doesn’t offer an electric version of the Jeep, one of its most iconic cars. And while Stellantis has been making some &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/19/from-jeep-to-maserati-stellantis-to-rollout-10-new-ev-models-in-2021.html"&gt;bold promises&lt;/a&gt; about its plans for electric vehicles, the Magneto is lacking some substance to show that any sort of electric Wrangler is coming out anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qv0p4D"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344578/jeep-wrangler-magneto-concept-ev-manual-transmission-stellantis"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344578/jeep-wrangler-magneto-concept-ev-manual-transmission-stellantis</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T13:31:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T13:31:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max somehow beats Netflix and Disney Plus to custom profile photos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ss46JcwAKZIgOId3LZi20NmqjfI=/104x0:1979x1250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006956/Screen_Shot_2021_03_22_at_12.43.41_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: WarnerMedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oUotWp"&gt;I can’t imagine there are many people out there clamoring for the ability to create a custom profile image on their favorite video streaming service, but HBO Max wants you to know that it’s giving customers just that option starting today. Subscribers can now choose from a range of preselected avatars — featuring over 120 characters from HBO Max’s library of content — or upload their own photo. The presets come from shows like &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; The Sopranos&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Curb Your Enthusiasm&lt;/em&gt;, and many others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xDxJVi"&gt;Uploading a custom photo isn’t something you can do on Netflix, Disney Plus, Hulu, or most of the other video streaming apps. (Netflix used to let you link to a social media account and show an image from there, but this is no longer available.) And it could help HBO Max feel just that extra bit personalized to you and other people in your home. If you’ve got kids, maybe they’ll get a kick out of seeing themselves on the profile select screen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9SSMjM40TZ03HoplmAsOoilXxO0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22389057/maxavatars.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: WarnerMedia&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dHNw04"&gt;“This new feature, which launches today and rolls out across all supported partners by March 26th, allows users to express their identity through a creative lens and further connect with the stories and characters they love on the platform,” WarnerMedia said in a press release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NcTSUE"&gt;You’ll be able to pick an avatar or take / upload your own photo using the HBO Max mobile or tablet app. That image will then appear across HBO Max on all of your devices. A WarnerMedia spokesperson told me that “uploaded photos are encrypted and hard deleted once a user removes or changes their profile photo.” And if you’ve got parental controls enabled, a PIN is required before the profile image on a kid’s account can be changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hmJts5"&gt;I guess HBO Max gets the win on this one versus its streaming rivals — even if WarnerMedia took its sweet time on other, more important things &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21813364/wonder-woman-1984-4k-ultra-hd-dolby-vision-atmos-announced"&gt;like adding 4K support&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344759/hbo-max-custom-profile-image-avatar-now-available"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344759/hbo-max-custom-profile-image-avatar-now-available</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:53:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:53:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro: everything we know about the new phones coming on March 23rd</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LEMLXCseYvGioce_ob8iNEHrfYk=/93x0:2097x1336/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006765/Screen_Shot_2021_03_19_at_3.46.40_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The one place for OnePlus&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="T6FYA5"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22334396/oneplus-9-march-23rd-event-rumor-announcement-roundup-smartwatch-cameras"&gt;a week of previews&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter and in the press, OnePlus’ new flagship phones are set to be officially announced at an event on March 23rd at 10AM ET. Alongside them, we expect to hear about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338504/oneplus-9r-less-expensive-phone-confirmed-india-5g#comments"&gt;a budget option&lt;/a&gt; as well as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22339768/oneplus-watch-image-reveal-design-leak-smartwatch-wearable"&gt;new smartwatch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KnZkTx"&gt;OnePlus’ main focus with the 9 and 9 Pro seems to be the cameras, partnering with legendary camera maker Hasselblad for the phones. Whether it’ll help make the cameras excel or be more of a marketing gimmick is something that only testing will reveal, so we’ll post our reviews here when they’re live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OWbWp3"&gt;We’ll also post comparisons between the phones and their competitors, along with any other announcements OnePlus may make, so watch this space to see all of our coverage of the event — as well as all of the details OnePlus has already revealed.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22339187/oneplus-9-series-event-news-smartwatch-phones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22339187/oneplus-9-series-event-news-smartwatch-phones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:48:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:48:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fitbit adds Tile tracking feature to its Inspire 2 wearable </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gAIez-3ckEW8Peo2rzAzZuAwqBI=/0x79:2700x1879/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006741/fitbit_tile.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Tile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="G3uHiY"&gt;A new partnership between Fitbit and Tile will now let users of Fitbit’s Inspire 2 locate their devices with Tile’s Bluetooth tracking, the companies &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/fitbit-inspire-2-devices-now-findable-with-tile-301251281.html"&gt;announced Monday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F0qiO4"&gt;The free update is available starting Monday. Users will just have to update their device software in the Fitbit app to add Bluetooth tracking, then download and activate the Tile app. Once the Tile app is enabled, Inspire 2 users should be able to locate their misplaced device (it happens to the best of us) via its most recent location, or they can use Tile’s global crowdsourced network to try to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1lZmtY"&gt;Fitbit Inspire 2 users can also sign up for Tile Premium to get smart alerts and other premium content at a price of $2.99 per month or $29.99 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9FfRZi"&gt;It’s the first official partnership between Tile and a wearable device company (although Tile does count headphone manufacturers like Bose, Skullcandy, and Sennheiser &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thetileapp.com%2Fen-us%2Fpartners&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F22%2F22344359%2Ffitbit-adds-tile-tracking-feature-bluetooth-inspire-2-wearable" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;among its partners&lt;/a&gt;). The lost-item-tracking field is growing crowded as more companies develop products to compete with Tile. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22227621/samsung-galaxy-smarttag-price-release-date-tile-locator"&gt;Samsung unveiled its Galaxy SmartTag&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, and &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/01/04/kuo-airtags-ar-device-2021/"&gt;Apple’s AirTags&lt;/a&gt; have been expected for some time. Both are expected to have both Bluetooth and ultra-wideband (UWB) versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QG3i2g"&gt;Also starting Monday, &lt;a href="https://blog.fitbit.com/fitbit-charge-4-updates/"&gt;Fitbit’s Charge 4 devices&lt;/a&gt; will get an update that adds SpO2 blood oxygen saturation tracking, skin temperature tracking, and Fitbit’s health metrics dashboard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kmPT55"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344359/fitbit-adds-tile-tracking-feature-bluetooth-inspire-2-wearable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344359/fitbit-adds-tile-tracking-feature-bluetooth-inspire-2-wearable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:46:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:46:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>John Cleese has an NFT bridge to sell you for $69.3 million</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="John Cleese Brooklyn Bridge" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RX2HTeoawTyjcEPr8pHl0q-2dU0=/0x21:653x456/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006735/unnamed.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;John Cleese’s illustration of the Brooklyn Bridge, being sold as an NFT. | Image: John Cleese&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ah6puc"&gt;“The world has gone terminally insane,” Monty Python’s John Cleese told &lt;a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2021/03/nfts-are-driving-stunts-and-diving-into-the-culture-wars"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the topic of getting into NFTs. So naturally, the comic actor known for silly walks is now selling a ludicrously expensive NFT of his own: a Vonnegut-esque drawing of the Brooklyn Bridge made on an iPad Pro. &lt;a href="https://opensea.io/assets/0x9201a886740d193e315f1f1b2b193321d6701d07/1021"&gt;It’s listed on OpenSea&lt;/a&gt; and the auction ends in 10 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X2GMfB"&gt;Bidding started at $100 and has now made its way up to nearly $36,000. Cleese won’t let his masterpiece go for that cheap, though. Cleese said he wants $69.3 million for the piece, suggesting the illustration won’t sell unless someone bids at least that much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EIhFxB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hello! It is time you meet my alter ego "Unnamed Artist" I'm delighted to offer you the opportunity of a lifetime. I'm selling my 1st NFT. Though bidding starts at 100.00, you can “BUY IT NOW” for 69,346,250.50! &lt;a href="https://t.co/Vuyx4trvPE"&gt;https://t.co/Vuyx4trvPE&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/aC4oSVfGHF"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aC4oSVfGHF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— John Cleese (@JohnCleese) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JohnCleese/status/1372944852325789704?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OMwB4x"&gt;While many artists are making more money than ever by selling NFTs for their digital goods, Cleese wants to make a joke of it. NFTs, he argues to &lt;em&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/em&gt;, are “another investment vehicle for the uber-rich.” The auction price refers to digital artist &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325054/beeple-christies-nft-sale-cost-everydays-69-million"&gt;Beeple’s NFT sale at Christie’s, which fetched $69 million&lt;/a&gt; — the third highest-grossing sale from a living artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="zMmUFh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1ydEKw"&gt;Cleese continues by saying “technology is changing and moving so quickly that we can’t even see we’re standing in quicksand as we stare at a bunch of pixelated JPEGs, wondering what they might sell for next.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TUfSYX"&gt;Honestly, this sounds like a twisted Monty Python sketch that I want to see actualized. Right before you’re sucked into the sand, surrounded by screens with indiscernible JPEGs, look at the camera and say &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cCim90WO1-4"&gt;“It’s!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344556/john-cleese-monty-python-nft-brooklyn-bridge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344556/john-cleese-monty-python-nft-brooklyn-bridge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:42:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:42:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Razer Blade 15 Base review: losing its edge</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Some new specs aside, this laptop has changed very little since 2018&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="qI06Hc"&gt;Razer’s Blade 15 Base isn’t broken necessarily, but it could use a tune-up anyway. It’s emblematic of the company’s excellent design chops — stuck in a loop of flexing it in practically the same way as last year and the year before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KOoorX"&gt;The laptop’s all-aluminum build is still impressive to see and use. And yes, it has a webcam, unlike some of the gaming laptops we’ve reviewed recently. But the effect it gives off is getting stale, and Razer still hasn’t addressed all of the annoyances that have been present since this design debuted in 2018. It’s a magnet for fingerprints and smudges, and for a laptop that starts at $1,699.99, its lack of any biometric login method is baffling. You’ll need to type in your password or PIN every time you log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KDYTy6"&gt;It’s no longer as ahead of the pack in terms of design as Razer might hope. Some competing machines, like Asus Zephyrus G15 and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22248630/msi-gs66-stealth-2021-review-rtx-3080-nvidia-qhd-1440p-gaming-laptop"&gt;MSI GS66 Stealth&lt;/a&gt;, are thinner, lighter, and priced aggressively to take on the Blade, with the same (or more) features in tow. 2021 could be the year when other manufacturers catch up or overtake it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2rt9Sl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10376126"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9TzYqW"&gt;We’ll need to wait and see if Razer’s next steps for this laptop are more exciting than what the early 2021 model serves up, but at least some of the improved specs inside make it feel a little fresh. The $2,199 high-end “Base” configuration I’ve been testing features the Nvidia RTX 3070 graphics chip along with Razer’s first QHD screen in a laptop. Those are new specs for 2021, and Razer’s among the first to ship a machine featuring them both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Blade 15 Base " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yeByAYdWmgP0_OG8yiVZUfGEWSc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22336711/cfaulkner_210228_4451_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The design is gorgeous, and few manufacturers can match Razer’s all-aluminum chassis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wTXIek"&gt;A few weeks after this review originally published in early March 2021, Razer fixed a serious issue with the way this Blade 15 Base handled switching between running on the dedicated GPU or Nvidia Optimus, a technology that switches between integrated and dedicated graphics as needed for efficiency and performance. It was set to Optimus by default, but switching to using the RTX 3070 exclusively caused the screen to permanently go black without a way to recover — requiring a full system wipe. With the Nvidia driver version 461.92, the issue has been resolved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u7GEPo"&gt;This laptop performed as well as I expected for gaming, given its RTX 3070’s specific specs. The updated driver that fixes the display issue didn’t impact gaming performance in a noticeable way, and our 4K video export test didn’t fare any better than before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GG0F6N"&gt;Razer recently started to publicly disclose the detailed specs of its GPUs on its site (which can vary wildly at the manufacturer’s discretion), &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266921/nvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs"&gt;as Nvidia now requires&lt;/a&gt;. The RTX 3070 graphics chip in this configuration has a maximum power draw of 95W with a clock speed of 1,290MHz (boosting up to 1,410MHz). Unsurprisingly, given this laptop’s thin build, the GPU can’t run wild compared to the likes of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22244409/msi-gp66-leopard-gaming-laptop-review-price-specs-features"&gt;MSI’s GP66 Leopard&lt;/a&gt;. But that’s not to say it isn’t capable for gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Blade 15 Base " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q1jr2LGiI4qn_e9ME3UCwm6tgJc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22336710/cfaulkner_210228_4451_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The keyboard layout got an update last year, serving as one of the few visible tweaks Razer has made to this laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QJRpLr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2&lt;/em&gt; running at 1440p with ultra graphical settings enabled averaged 59 frames per second. &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt;, also running at its highest settings with ray-tracing shadows set to ultra, displayed an average of 46 frames per second. I wanted to easily test more games, but I, unfortunately, ran out of space on the 512GB SSD that’s included by default with the Blade 15 Base. Of course, I juggled things around to get more testing done, but this amount of storage is insulting in a $2,199 laptop. It’s a minor consolation that more NVMe M.2 storage can be added with its second open slot, but you’ll have to front that cost. Back to testing, the open-world game &lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn,&lt;/em&gt; with all of the graphical tricks set to ultra, ran at an average of 71 frames per second. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="2YLGJW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10376147"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ninOjL"&gt;The Blade 15 Base performs worse by a small margin when compared to the new Asus Zephyrus G15, which also features a QHD screen and a slightly more powerful RTX 3070 (same clock speed but with a higher 100W power ceiling). In real-world usage, you might notice Asus’ laptop doing a few extra frames per second better, like we did. Otherwise, performance should be similar. In short, it nearly meets the bar for smooth 60 frames per second gameplay at QHD resolution, and knocking down a graphical setting or two should get you there in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cgBMAR"&gt;Interestingly, both laptops make ponying up more money to get the RTX 3080 in a thin laptop next to pointless. These machines perform nearly as well with QHD gaming as the MSI GS66 Stealth that has a QHD screen with an RTX 3080 clocked at 1,245MHz and 95W and costs $2,599. Doing some research could really put some money back in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xb8S8D"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This RTX 3070 performs nearly as well with QHD gaming as the 3080&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4pbG9Z"&gt;Like my experience with MSI’s QHD screen, I’m surprised that Razer’s QHD 165Hz refresh rate panel is its first in a laptop because it’s a very good first effort. The viewing angles are generous, the colors are rich but accurate, and of course, the big pixel density boost looks fantastic. The jump from 1080p to 1440p is noticeable during everyday tasks like hanging out in a browser or playing games. Text pops with clarity, and watching content or playing games in the native QHD resolution makes for a better experience than a 1080p panel can provide. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22217171/gaming-laptops-qhd-screens-display-fast-refresh-rate"&gt;I think it’s worth paying a premium for&lt;/a&gt;, and the extra $200 cost Razer asks is on par with other manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5mvyzv"&gt;Installing Nvidia’s latest driver (at the time of publishing) made it possible to switch between Optimus and the dedicated graphics chip, but it didn’t make exporting 4K video via Premiere Pro any faster. Our Adobe Premiere Pro test sees how quickly a machine can export a five-minute, 33-second project from our Verge video team. On average, it took six minutes, 40 seconds, which is slow for the level of specs inside of this laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Blade 15 Base" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BcmqxK-iW0Gq9E3SRkEFQBisVD0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22336713/cfaulkner_210228_4451_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can customize the backlit keyboard to be as bright and colorful or dim as you please.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="FzDpLz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10376140"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="9KCCKi"&gt;If you’ve used any of Razer’s Blade laptops in the past few years, you’ve essentially used them all. If not, you’re in for a treat with its keyboard and trackpad, which are among the best around. The keyboard has backlit keys, and you can customize their color or lighting pattern to be as extravagant or subtle as you prefer. Razer fixed the &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tqi6q2kSdWQ3OKu2gPjeWRjLNPg=/0x0:2040x1360/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2040x1360):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19367231/akrales_191107_3772_0057.jpg"&gt;problematic arrangement of its directional keys&lt;/a&gt; starting with last year’s model, so the layout is just as ideal for my 9-to-5 workflow as it is for gaming. Unlike every other laptop Razer currently makes, this one doesn’t have a Windows Hello-enabled IR webcam or any other biometric login method. It’s a disappointing omission, but sadly, not a new one. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/21/17485494/razer-blade-15-review-gaming-laptop"&gt;Our review from June 2018&lt;/a&gt; criticized that year’s Blade 15 for the same thing, citing that the power button, which looks like (and should be) a fingerprint reader, isn’t one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NgBkmQ"&gt;The arrangement of ports should be suitable for most people, but it’s one of the key areas where this Base model differs from the more expensive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21499199/razer-blade-15-advanced-edition-gaming-laptop-2020-review"&gt;Blade 15 Advanced model&lt;/a&gt;. Both have a Thunderbolt 3 port and an HDMI 2.1 port (capable of up to 4K resolution at 120 frames per second) in common. Outside of that, Ethernet is exclusive to the Base configurations, while the Advanced models have a slew of exclusive ports and features, including a UHS-III full-sized SD card reader, a Windows Hello IR webcam, up to 20V charging via USB-C, along with Bluetooth 5.2 and Wi-Fi 6E. I’d happily trade an Ethernet port for an SD card reader in the Base, but getting one in a 15-inch Razer gaming laptop will bump the cost up to $2,499 at minimum — and you’ll lose the Ethernet port. The strategy of sectioning off ports based on the model cost is outdated and out of touch, given that this machine is nearly just as capable for creators and gamers as the Advanced model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="PwcRNt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;First-time Blade 15 buyers will adore this machine for several reasons&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vznjV6"&gt;The last thing I’ll touch on is the heating and cooling, which is something Razer has struggled a bit with past models. During gaming, this one gets toasty as well, but it doesn’t seem noticeably worse than before. It also didn’t cross my threshold of what I’d consider to be a loud laptop, even during intensive loads. Also, its 65Wh battery can last about six hours. That’s Razer’s claim for longevity, and my experience matches up with it when in battery saver mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3nRRdU"&gt;The Blade 15 is a competent, well-designed gaming laptop that first-time buyers will adore for many reasons. This particular configuration is noteworthy as the first Base with a luscious QHD display, and with it, the RTX 3070 performs well for both gaming and productivity. The lack of biometrics and an SD card reader might be bothersome for some, though, since the step-up Advanced model has both. Beyond that, it’s tough to give the Blade 15 Base a pass again when it’s getting easier to find &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"&gt;other similarly priced thin and light gaming laptops&lt;/a&gt; with just as many features and sleek designs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bFWUkC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="XuyRzR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 12:43PM ET, March 22nd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Nvidia’s graphics driver 461.92 fixed the display issue we experienced with the Blade 15 Base. The laptop can now switch between Optimus and the dedicated GPU without issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22315386/razer-blade-15-base-2021-review-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3070-qhd-screen-performance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22315386/razer-blade-15-base-2021-review-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3070-qhd-screen-performance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:01:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:01:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Our favorite things: gear, gadgets, and other stuff</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9_-_OPGsDKHCXstCcg0HgiZ-4Rc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006425/acastro_201105_4277_50guide_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We ask The Verge staff what they like to work with, play with, and cook with&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="cQDcJj"&gt;We all have our favorite stuff. It could be a laptop that you’ve used for several years or the snazzy new one that just arrived last week. It could be the headphones that deliver your favorite music and podcasts, the controller that helps you win your games, or the app that puts a weird background on your Zoom calls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DeeD2"&gt;Of course, we’re not just talking tech. We’re also talking about your favorite coffee maker, the TV shows that you binged through the pandemic, the hiking boots that have never given you a blister, and the immersion blender that your friend gave you for your birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OTJ1qT"&gt;We’ve talked to the people who work at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and asked them to tell us about their favorite stuff, whether it be for working at home, cooking, or playing. Some of these things may be what you already like to use; others may give you ideas of the kind of items you could use for yourself. Either way, we hope you enjoy reading about the things we use and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29ICxX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22344288/favorite-gadgets-tech-lgear-aptops-headphones-kitchen-recommendations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22344288/favorite-gadgets-tech-lgear-aptops-headphones-kitchen-recommendations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:00:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:00:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube is testing automatic product detection in videos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sf6qQvXKbhxDN66DLzy-UrMsfps=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006419/acastro_180403_1777_youtube_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r3Juxw"&gt;YouTube is always running experiments. One of its latest: testing an automated list of products detected in videos uploaded to the site. As of March 22nd this year, that test is being expanded to “people watching videos in the US,” according to &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/18138167?hl=en"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. (An early version of the feature was tested midway through last year, though that test was very small, reports &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/03/22/youtube-experiment-will-auto-detect-products-in-videos-and-provide-related-content-links/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nYPqi2"&gt;In one of its &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/18138167?hl=en"&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt;, a YouTube representative gave a little more detail about how this particular feature will be deployed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="azF21n"&gt;We are experimenting with a new feature that displays a list of products detected in some videos, as well as related products. The feature will appear in between the recommended videos, to viewers scrolling below the video player. The goal is to help people explore more videos and information about those products on YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="mPQyKH"&gt;Presumably, it’s a move intended to give Google its own piece of the incredibly lucrative affiliate link market, while also tying commerce directly to video uploads. These lists could function as a second recommendation algorithm, with YouTube serving videos that feature similar products. It would also put YouTube in the same shopping space as other social platforms (like &lt;a href="https://business.instagram.com/shopping"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;). Who knows! As with most experiments, it’s a little up in the air — at least until the results come in.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344553/youtube-shopping-recommendation-products-instagram"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344553/youtube-shopping-recommendation-products-instagram</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-22T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-22T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Creating WandaVision’s visual effects, from old-school sitcom gags to Vision’s CG face</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k9c_naY-UzWJO406HwF1j4aUbKo=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69006382/wandavision.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="11MGML"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; was an important moment for Disney. It was the company’s first attempt to expand its Marvel Cinematic Universe to its streaming service, &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt;, after over a decade focused on theatrical releases. And a big part of keeping that continuity was the visuals. &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; was a relatively strange show, with a storyline that spanned a few decades of sitcom history, and it had the aesthetics to match. But it managed to combine black-and-white &lt;em&gt;Bewitched&lt;/em&gt;-style visuals with classic, city-spanning MCU battles in a way that somehow felt natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Yhr9u"&gt;According to Tara DeMarco, a visual effects supervisor on the show, the approach to &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;’s special effects wasn’t any different because it was destined for living rooms. “The visual effects for Marvel features and streaming [shows] are treated very similarly in terms of the expectation for the quality. And really, we’re all in service of a story,” she tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s just that some of our stories are longer than others.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e8pMNY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315094/wandavision-finale-marvel-mcu-scarlet-witch-doctor-strange-captain"&gt;Now that the show has wrapped&lt;/a&gt;, I had the chance to talk to DeMarco about creating those classic sitcom effects, designing the ever-present Hex that surrounds the town of Westview, filming those big superhero battles, and, of course, Vision’s CG face. Here are some highlights from our chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G4tFpN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This story contains light spoilers for &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WandaVision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;’s first season.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Mc94uP"&gt;On the classic sitcom visual effects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="MoC02m"&gt;The early episodes were a collaboration between all the departments — but particularly, production design and special effects and visual effects — to determine what could be achieved with puppeteers in each set. And then special effects would go away and rig the different props that we might be given by props, and then we might do different wire works as elements and combine them later. We determined ahead of time that we would get as many practical puppeteered effects as we could, and visual effects would either combine them or enhance them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFhz5v"&gt;Puppeteered effects are used in television sometimes — you just don’t know. And it’s really a way of getting an object for someone to act against and to have something real in the scene that you can take and maybe then duplicate or create in CG in another way. But we often use wires to put objects in scenes. The difference is that we were paying homage to shows that had very specifically put wire gags in that the audience would know. So the plate that heals itself is a great tip of the hat to how they would’ve done it in the era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="EpDEkx"&gt;DeMarco also notes that, while the team did plenty of research on how effects were originally done on those shows, they had some help: Dan Sudick, head of the special visual effects department, grew up with a neighbor who worked as a puppeteer on &lt;em&gt;Bewitched&lt;/em&gt;. “We had an inside source,” DeMarco says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kOsW8s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10405789"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5CA6Jp"&gt;On the Hex that covers Westview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="N7xmUG"&gt;The Hex was really driven by the story point of each scene. So that first view of it, when Monica gets pulled in, where we see the sort of invisible wall and it’s a mystery, was meant to really unsettle the audience. And so we wanted it to be slightly invisible, slightly visible, unknown, and for it to affect her in an unknown way, but using the language of television. That was driven by [director] Matt Shakman and what he wanted the tone of the scene to be, in terms of what the audience should take away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rUS5HS"&gt;Each progression of the Hex was similar in that, in the next episode, we wanted to showcase that Wanda was angry that Hayward had flown a drone into her home. So at the end of the episode, we made it red, violently red, to showcase both her power and that it was meant to be a hard boundary. She wasn’t messing around. And then in the subsequent Hexes, it was really what is important to show about Wanda either keeping people out or letting them in, and rewriting objects to fit within her Westview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PJWAX4"&gt;And each time we worked on the Hex, we just made sure that it was clear that it was made of the cathodic lines of old tube TVs and pixelization and a lot of cool RGB chromatic aberration effects so that you could see the colors split into three like the old Trinitron logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1HuR2O"&gt;DeMarco adds that keeping the Hex largely a mystery, particularly for the first few episodes, was important. “The idea was to not show it off too much,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lKrJpa"&gt;On that huge battle in the last episode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="yyR4kZ"&gt;All of the big scenes we start with first script, and then boards if we have them, and then [pre-visualization]. So there’s an evolution to all of those scenes so that we have an idea of what the work will be. Once we’ve gotten through a pre-viz scene, and [director Matt Shakman] likes the pre-viz, then we would break down each scene and try to figure out which pieces we could capture with a human or with a set, to keep as much real as possible, and then the next phase is what could we augment in CG, or what could we start with a human and then maybe do a digital double take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jbwTeM"&gt;Our last resort is an all-CG scene. Because we wanted as much real and in-camera as we could keep, knowing that it had to be big MCU beats. So we did fly a lot of actors on wires. We flew Visions on wires in a library set, we flew witches on wires on a green screen set. But we tried to get the basic elements with practical pieces as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id="RiUXey"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10405797"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="zVGjMv"&gt;On Vision’s CG face&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Wvt0WQ"&gt;I am most proud of all of our Visions. I am actually loving the fact that, after [Disney Plus behind-the-scenes documentary &lt;em&gt;Assembled&lt;/em&gt; aired], people didn’t seem to realize he had a CG face. So the fact that we were able to execute Vision through so many eras and so many looks — dead, white, on the operating table in pieces, through all of his sitcom emotion — and no one questioned that, they were focusing on Vision and the performance of the character and not on the fact that he had a CG face. That gives me the warm fuzzies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="rx0NJC"&gt;
&lt;aside id="obEAAL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus","description":"$6.99 per month or $69.99 if you pay annually","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344250/wandavision-disney-plus-visual-effects-interview-tara-demarco"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22344250/wandavision-disney-plus-visual-effects-interview-tara-demarco</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
