<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-13T17:28:20-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T17:28:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T17:28:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Detroit man sues police for wrongfully arresting him based on facial recognition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Eej5qpe8qSL7BEn6DYq6kMh8edw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69121479/acastro_180730_1777_facial_recognition_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / Th&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lO3tqz"&gt;A man who was falsely accused of shoplifting has &lt;a href="https://www.aclu.org/press-releases/michigan-father-sues-detroit-police-department-wrongful-arrest-based-faulty-facial"&gt;sued the Detroit Police Department&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/24/technology/facial-recognition-arrest.html"&gt;arresting him&lt;/a&gt; based on an incorrect facial recognition match. The American Civil Liberties Union filed suit on behalf of Robert Williams, whom it calls the first US person wrongfully arrested based on facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gMBe1c"&gt;The Detroit Police Department arrested Williams in 2019 after examining security footage from a shoplifting incident. A detective used facial recognition technology on a grainy image from the video, and the system flagged Williams as a potential match based on a driver’s license photo. But as &lt;a href="https://www.aclumich.org/en/press-releases/farmington-hills-father-sues-detroit-police-department-wrongful-arrest-based-faulty"&gt;the lawsuit notes&lt;/a&gt;, facial recognition is frequently inaccurate, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/20/21031255/facial-recognition-algorithm-bias-gender-race-age-federal-nest-investigation-analysis-amazon"&gt;particularly with Black subjects&lt;/a&gt; and a low-quality picture. The department then produced a photo lineup that included Williams’ picture, showed it to a security guard who hadn’t actually witnessed the shoplifting incident, and obtained a warrant when that guard picked him from the lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xP1S7G"&gt;&lt;q&gt;At least three Black men have faced arrest after a bad match&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dUbB9I"&gt;Williams — who had been driving home from work during the incident — spent 30 hours in a detention center. The ACLU later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21301759/facial-recognition-detroit-police-wrongful-arrest-robert-williams-artificial-intelligence"&gt;filed a formal complaint&lt;/a&gt; on his behalf, and the prosecutor’s office apologized, saying he could have the case expunged from his records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gvvWFo"&gt;The ACLU claims Detroit police used facial recognition under circumstances that they should have known would produce unreliable results, then dishonestly failed to mention the system’s shortcomings — including a “woefully substandard” image and the known racial bias of recognition systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SHhzk"&gt;The department itself has acknowledged that Williams’ arrest was based on “sloppy investigative work” and other mistakes. But the complaint calls this incident part of a pattern, pointing to a second wrongful arrest involving a Black man misidentified by facial recognition tech. That man, Michael Oliver, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/bv8k8a/faulty-facial-recognition-led-to-his-arrestnow-hes-suing"&gt;sued the department&lt;/a&gt; last year. Outside Detroit, at least &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/29/technology/facial-recognition-misidentify-jail.html"&gt;one other Black man&lt;/a&gt; has sued for a wrongful arrest based on facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ya8as0"&gt;Thousands of law enforcement agencies have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21402978/clearview-ai-ceo-interview-2400-police-agencies-facial-recognition"&gt;allegedly used&lt;/a&gt; facial recognition tech to identify suspects. But a backlash has led several cities to ban the practice, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21288053/microsoft-facial-recognition-police-law-enforcement-pledge-regulation"&gt;Microsoft, IBM, and Amazon have pledged&lt;/a&gt; to keep their systems out of police hands.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382398/robert-williams-detroit-police-department-aclu-lawsuit-facial-recognition-wrongful-arrest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382398/robert-williams-detroit-police-department-aclu-lawsuit-facial-recognition-wrongful-arrest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T16:59:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T16:59:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Gigabyte is announcing three OLED gaming monitors with HDMI 2.1 and TV sizes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RYlkbRoBSfYHMDCnUQH950AdxJs=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69121351/AORUS_4K_Gaming_Monitors_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Gigabyte&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DFyVGn"&gt;Gigabyte has announced three new 4K OLED gaming monitors, which feature HDMI 2.1, the somewhat hard-to-find display connector that allows for high refresh rate gaming at 4K (&lt;a href="https://www.tweaktown.com/news/78707/aorus-fo48u-48-inch-4k-120hz-oled-gaming-monitor-with-hdmi-2-1-tech/index.html"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;TweakTown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Besides having some of the best tech available in TVs or monitors, all three have desk-dominating sizes. According to &lt;a href="https://videocardz.com/press-release/aorus-announces-32-43-and-48-inch-4k-gaming-monitors-with-hdmi-2-1"&gt;a press release posted by &lt;em&gt;VideoCardz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the monitors will also feature VESA’s HDR 1000 standard and come in three sizes: 32, 43, and a mind-boggling (for a gaming monitor anyway; we’ll get back to that) 48 inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wLJEa0"&gt;The 48-inch version is a little different, and it set off a firestorm of discussion at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, so let’s set it aside for just one moment. The 32- and 43-inch monitors, named the FI32U and the FV43U, respectively, will feature 144Hz panels. Gigabyte is also claiming that FI32U will have a 0.5ms response time, which looks to make it one of the faster 4K gaming monitors out there. While the FV43U has a slower 1ms response time, that’s probably something even the most eagle-eyed and competitive gamers would have issues noticing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z24FGI"&gt;The 48-inch model, dubbed the FO48U, is slightly different from the other two. Besides dropping the refresh rate from 144Hz to 120Hz, it’s also the size of a TV more at home in an entertainment center — specifically, the 48-inch model of LG’s CX OLED TVs, which shares many of the same specs as Gigabyte’s version, from the HDMI 2.1 inputs to the 120Hz refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="a6iIbN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If Gigabyte &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;going for a TV experience, what is it offering that LG doesn’t already have?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n3WiY5"&gt;So what’s going on here? Gigabyte is likely using the same OLED panels as LG. That makes it kind of hard to figure out why anyone would want to go with it over LG’s TV (especially since you could go out and buy LG’s version right now). And despite calling it a “monitor,” it doesn’t seem like Gigabyte expects many people to use this on a desk; its website specifically says it’s for “your gaming space or living room.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7dzcao"&gt;However, LG’s 48-inch TV has had great success in the last year as a monitor for people who apparently want to sit very close to the action. There’s no doubt it’d be immersive... at least, until you had to crane your neck to see the minimap or other HUD elements. But if Gigabyte &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;going for a TV experience, what is it offering that LG doesn’t already have? G-Sync and FreeSync? LG’s got it. Cheaper price due to potentially less processing power and smart features? Gigabyte hasn’t announced pricing, but we’re skeptical that it’ll end up being cheaper. (The LG retails for $1,500.) Gaming (er, sorry, “tactical”) features, such as “black equalizer,” which supposedly makes enemies easier to see? Okay, fair point. LG’s TV is intended for watching movies and playing games, while Gigabyte appears to be adding a few more gamer-focused features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SZBQ2"&gt;This isn’t to say there’s no reason for it to exist. Some people might prefer its aesthetic over LG’s (maybe it’ll even have RGB to really sell it). Or maybe Gigabyte will surprise us, and it’ll be cheaper. Until we know pricing, it’s hard to judge. Still, it seems like if it stands out, it won’t be for its uniqueness — which is a shame, really, given how the other models seem to be offering a set of features that is hard to find elsewhere. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382201/gigabyte-aorus-4k-gaming-monitor-tv-oled"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382201/gigabyte-aorus-4k-gaming-monitor-tv-oled</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T16:40:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T16:40:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>CS:GO has a years-old bug that can let a hacker take over your computer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EO_RV8qkswTZdQkNeWiA-42DHOU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69121208/acastro_300505_4008_pcGameHacks_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="auo56r"&gt;Hackers have found a new exploit in &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive&lt;/em&gt; that could allow a hacker to take control of your computer if you click on a Steam invite to play the popular first-person shooter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6nC1hh"&gt;The bug was discovered by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/the_secret_club"&gt;The Secret Club&lt;/a&gt;, a white hat hacking group, which found that the hackers can exploit the bug by using Steam’s invite system. Should a victim click on the link, a hacker could acquire private information from anyone who accepts it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QeIbiD"&gt;The exploit was &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rNQn%E2%80%949xR1Q"&gt;discovered in the Source game engine&lt;/a&gt;, which Valve developed and is used in several game Valve titles, including &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive&lt;/em&gt;. While some games that use the engine no longer have the bug, the exploit is still present in &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive &lt;/em&gt;as seen in the video below. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MMQt0R"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rNQn--9xR1Q?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GfaO4C"&gt;According to The Secret Club, one of its members and security researcher named &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/floesen_"&gt;Florian&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/the_secret_club/status/1380868759129296900?s=20"&gt;flagged the bug to Valve in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Florian &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/dyvgej/counter-strike-bug-allows-hackers-to-take-over-a-pc-with-a-steam-invite"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that he reached out to Valve about the bug via HackerOne, a bug bounty platform that the studio uses. Despite Valve classifying the bug as “critical,” Florian told &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; that the studio admitted it was “slow to respond” in threads regarding the bug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y68XX5"&gt;The revelation about this bug is concerning for &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive &lt;/em&gt;players. Although the game is almost 10 years old, it is still &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/stats/Steam-Game-and-Player-Statistics?l=t/"&gt;very popular on Steam&lt;/a&gt;. More recently, the game &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/6/18129666/counter-strike-go-danger-zone-battle-royale-mode-free-to-play-expansion"&gt;switched to a free-to-play model&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 and is one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/27/21238268/league-of-legends-csgo-esports-leagues-twitch-viewership"&gt;world’s biggest esports leagues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382243/counter-strike-global-offensive-game-engine-bug-take-over-pc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382243/counter-strike-global-offensive-game-engine-bug-take-over-pc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T14:59:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T14:59:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Anker is making a $130 webcam as part of its new expansion to home office gear</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BGQSIcCKm6tyCpMGxn-5fJxXhhg=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69120466/PowerConf_C300___02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Anker&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZEuXaG"&gt;Anker has &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/anker-launches-smart-ai-enabled-webcam-and-portable-noise-isolating-conference-speaker-301267988.html"&gt;announced a new webcam&lt;/a&gt; as part of its new AnkerWork line of home office gear. The new webcam, called the PowerConf C300, is a 1080p webcam with a “built-in AI chipset,” which Anker says “provides a high-quality image with accurate color reproduction and unparalleled low-light performance.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w5LL1z"&gt;The webcam offers three field-of-view options: 78 degrees, intended for closeups; 90 degrees; and 115 degrees, which offers a wider field of view. It also has dual stereo microphones that can pick up your voice. The PowerConf C300 is available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-AI-Powered-Noise-Cancelling-Microphones-Adjustable/dp/B08RNHCZ3K/ref=sr_1_3?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=anker+powerconf+c300&amp;amp;qid=1618338789&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2FAnker.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F13%2F22382179%2Fanker-webcam-ankerwork-powerconf-c300-s500-home-office-gear" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker.com&lt;/a&gt;, and “select retailers,” and it costs $129.99 in the US, €129.99 in Germany, and £119.00 in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Y7GMIj"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GV1HDVFQQiw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="afheyx"&gt;Anker also announced a new portable conference speaker, the PowerConf S500. Pricing and availability will be announced at a later date, the company said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gcSTTx"&gt;The news of Anker’s new webcam and speaker comes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22381422/microsoft-new-webcam-headsets-usb-c-speaker-features-price-specs-release-date"&gt;the same day that Microsoft &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; announced&lt;/a&gt; a speaker designed for conference calls and a webcam of its own. Webcams have been in high demand during the pandemic as people have used them while working from home, attending remote school, or even just to catch up with friends and family, and Microsoft and Anker’s new offerings give people more options to choose from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uzrzBS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The webcam is the gadget of the year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22173744/webcam-gadget-of-the-year-2020"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382179/anker-webcam-ankerwork-powerconf-c300-s500-home-office-gear"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382179/anker-webcam-ankerwork-powerconf-c300-s500-home-office-gear</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T14:51:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T14:51:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mobvoi’s TicWatch GTH has an Apple Watch look and a skin temperature sensor for $79.99</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bLwjUYMBfW6GpP7jy4K9jR67ocA=/0x557:3840x3117/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69120420/TicWatch_GTH_Right_facing.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Mobvoi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tVJFt8"&gt;Mobvoi is starting to sell the TicWatch GTH today, a $79.99 fitness wearable that features sensors for skin temperature and blood oxygen that are typically reserved for more expensive watches. Mobvoi has generally focused on Wear OS devices in the past, providing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/7/22314135/ticwatch-pro-3-fossil-gen-5-lte-review-smartwatch-wear-os"&gt;a variety&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/8/18217223/mobvoi-ticwatch-e2-s2-review-price-size-battery-release-date-smartwatch-wear-os"&gt;of options&lt;/a&gt; for Google’s troubled wearable operating system, but the TicWatch GTH seems more like a Fitbit competitor than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMbsP4"&gt;The TicWatch GTH has an Apple Watch-esque square body, a noticeably bezeled 1.55-inch screen, and only comes in “raven black.” Mobvoi claims the GTH’s 260mAh battery can last more than a week on one charge, “depending on usage,” and that the watch is also water-resistant up to 5ATM or 50 meters. Despite that, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mobvoi.com%2Fus%2Fpages%2Fticwatchgth&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F13%2F22381867%2Fmobvoi-ticwatch-gth-smartwatch-skin-temperature-blood-oxygen" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mobvoi’s website&lt;/a&gt; notes that the GTH is not safe for shower use. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ArT_8aBJiqEEKU7ybEz4hDEp1SA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22441461/TicWatch_GTH_Back.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Mobvoi&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TicWatch GTH has several sensors that appear on more expensive watches, like an SpO2 sensors and an electrodermal activity sensor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3l7QpG"&gt;For sensors, the GTH has the usual fitness tracker standbys like an accelerometer, gyroscope, and a heart rate monitor, but also a SpO2 sensor for measuring blood oxygen level and a skin temperature sensor for... well, measuring your skin temperature. Actual uses for skin temperature data vary, however. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21399307/fitbit-sense-versa-3-smartwatch-inspire-2-fitness-tracker-ecg-eda-stress"&gt;The Fitbit Sense&lt;/a&gt; advertised skin temperature sensing as an indicator for stress. In its announcement for the GTH, Mobvoi didn’t specify what skin temperature should be used for. But as a rule, we urge caution for any big claims a new sensor might come attached with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EuES45"&gt;That rule also applies to measuring blood oxygen saturation. There’s been a trend of including blood oxygen sensors in smartwatches, but the wrist is not actually the best place to measure saturation, and these smartwatches &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21438576/blood-oxygen-apple-watch-series-6-reliability"&gt;shouldn’t be thought of as medical devices&lt;/a&gt;. Knowing your blood oxygen level mostly seems useful for serious athletic training and not much else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pAn7IP"&gt;But even if they might not necessarily be useful, the fact that the TicWatch includes both SpO2 and skin temperature sensors for only $79.99 is notable. The GTH undercuts &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"&gt;the Apple Watch Series 6&lt;/a&gt; at $399, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21450123/fitbit-sense-review"&gt;the Fitbit Sense&lt;/a&gt; at $299.95, and even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21199567/fitbit-charge-4-tracker-gps-nfc-spotify-sp02-announcement-price"&gt;the Fitbit Charge 4&lt;/a&gt; at $169.95, while tracking a lot of the same things. The TicWatch GTH is stuck in Mobvoi’s Tic-based app world, but the company does offer a variety of features like stress management, sleep tracking, automatic workout detection, audio playback controls, and basic messaging notifications if you’re willing to invest in a potentially unfamiliar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vhzyDA"&gt;The TicWatch GTH is not particularly flashy, but its price might be enticing if you’re looking for an even more affordable entry into tracking than Fitbit’s entry-level watches. The TicWatch GTH is available today for $79.99 / €79.99 / £69.99 from Mobvoi’s site or Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381867/mobvoi-ticwatch-gth-smartwatch-skin-temperature-blood-oxygen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381867/mobvoi-ticwatch-gth-smartwatch-skin-temperature-blood-oxygen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T14:33:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T14:33:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pinterest will now let workers blow the whistle on harassment and discrimination, despite NDAs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rbSBaUeZa0oOqO--xfRjXLBqF1c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69120299/acastro_200902_1777_pinterest_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3lIChp"&gt;Pinterest has been battered with accusations of workplace discrimination for many months, and we’ve followed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/11/21429619/pinterest-workplace-discrimination-finance-team-unequal-culture-bias"&gt;a large portion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21369035/pinterest-virtual-walkout-protest-discrimination-slack-blind"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21755406/pinterest-shareholders-lawsuit-sue-toxic-work-culture-discrimination"&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22175043/pinterest-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-settlement-coo-francoise-brougher"&gt;saga&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178609/pinterest-wilmer-hale-workplace-culture-report-gender-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;That includes,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;most recently, how Ifeoma Ozoma, a former Pinterest employee who accused the company of trying to silence her, helped draft California’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272779/silenced-no-more-act-california-nda-employees-workplace-harassment"&gt;new Silenced No More Act&lt;/a&gt;. Today, Ozoma is &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/13/opinion/nda-work-discrimination.html"&gt;speaking out in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about why she believes nondisclosure agreements (NDAs) should not be allowed to keep whistleblowers in check — but Pinterest now says, effective immediately, it will stop making workers sign NDAs that prevent them from talking about such things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XjuF08"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/pinterest-silenced-no-more-act"&gt;That’s the news from &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Pinterest will “not require employees to sign agreements that would prevent them from talking about their personal experiences at Pinterest after they leave,” according to the company’s global head of communications. It sounds like NDAs for other forms of company secrets will continue on, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bz82Ue"&gt;Pinterest CEO Ben Silbermann also reportedly issued a staff memo this morning about the Silenced No More Act, where he came out in support of the bill. “Regardless of what happens in the legislature, whether the bill moves forward or not, we’re going to adopt the policies behind the proposed law,” he reportedly wrote, according to &lt;em&gt;Protocol. &lt;/em&gt;Silbermann was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21755406/pinterest-shareholders-lawsuit-sue-toxic-work-culture-discrimination"&gt;one of the executives sued in December&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly creating a toxic work environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UqkveN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Inside Pinterest, more tales of workplace discrimination","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/11/21429619/pinterest-workplace-discrimination-finance-team-unequal-culture-bias"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="c9Nell"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GYDePj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VKTO5y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382148/pinterest-silenced-no-more-act-sb331-discrimination-harassment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382148/pinterest-silenced-no-more-act-sb331-discrimination-harassment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T14:18:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T14:18:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the Johnson &amp; Johnson pause could move the needle on vaccine fears</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DwX3XuymUoy4jd3NY6ubGNwIJx8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69120209/acastro_210309_1777_vaccine_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bVRBe9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381469/covid-vaccine-pause-blood-clots-johnson-fda-cdc"&gt;Today’s announcement&lt;/a&gt; that federal officials have recommended pausing use of the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine might hurt efforts to encourage people to get vaccinated. But — critically — that doesn’t mean the federal officials shouldn’t have made the recommendation, says Melanie Kornides, an assistant professor at the University of Pennsylvania School of Nursing who studies why some people are hesitant to take vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ajnh35"&gt;“Some people are missing the message — they’re so worried about hesitancy, that they’re not seeing how important it is to address the safety, in order to make people feel less hesitant,” she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QSOrRd"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) recommended the pause while they investigate six reports of rare blood clots in people who received the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine. The specific illnesses were unusual: the patients had a rare type of blood clot in their brains &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; very low levels of platelets, a type of blood cell involved in clotting. Similar clotting disorders were seen in the AstraZeneca vaccine, which uses the same vaccine technology as Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson. This combination of clots and low platelets needs a different type of treatment than normal blood clots, and the federal agencies wanted time to look into the cases and tell doctors what symptoms to watch for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YxYTe6"&gt;“I think that they did the right thing,” Kornides says. “The worst possible thing that they could do would be — if they had a legitimate concern, which it seems like they did — to investigate it without announcing, which would make it seem like they were covering something up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hCzFBY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think that they did the right thing.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9adYov"&gt;Still, flagging a potential safety concern to the public could make some people more reluctant to get the vaccine, Kornides says. Even if it turns out the blood clots were not linked to the vaccine or that they were extremely rare, the pause might make people hold off on getting a vaccine. The biggest worry is for people who were already on the fence about the shots. Those people may now decide to wait longer to get their vaccine or be nudged toward turning one down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I7C3wV"&gt;The Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine was the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrewAltman/status/1376921970072154112"&gt;shot of choice&lt;/a&gt; for the group of people that was on the fence — it’s only one shot and had fewer common side effects. “It’s going to introduce new fears for those people,” Kornides says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hahtQQ"&gt;It’s a bad time to lose ground with that group: in some states, supply of the COVID-19 vaccine has already &lt;a href="https://www.hawaiinewsnow.com/2021/04/11/with-vaccine-supply-exceeding-demand-maui-health-officials-urge-residents-get-their-shots/"&gt;started to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.idahopress.com/eyeonboise/idaho-will-soon-have-more-covid-vaccine-supply-than-demand-official-says/article_e311f334-b555-5bd6-b321-ac4158f8a31f.html"&gt;exceed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cbs17.com/community/health/coronavirus/covid-19-vaccine-supply-could-soon-exceed-demand-gov-cooper-says/"&gt;demand&lt;/a&gt;. In those areas, health officials and doctors are trying to encourage people to get vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="koHPsD"&gt;Luckily, there are two other vaccines available (the Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna shots), and these safety issues have not been seen in the more than 100 million people who received them. People worried about the very rare blood clots could be convinced to get those instead. Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, highlighted that point during a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8coTfdqYv6c"&gt;White House press briefing today&lt;/a&gt;. “There have been no red flag signals from those,” said Fauci.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kBUoiB"&gt;From a messaging perspective, the pause could be communicated as a positive sign and an indication that the FDA is taking safety seriously. “They’re not hiding anything,” Kornides says. It shows that people can be confident that the system watches out for any problems, even rare ones. Fauci stressed in the press briefing that the investigation should be left to the health officials. “You want to make sure that safety is the important issue here,” he said. “We are totally aware that this is a very rare event. We want to get this worked out as quickly as we possibly can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UoKcp8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You want to make sure that safety is the important issue here.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CfYUk7"&gt;It’s a good message, even if there’s a chance it might not win out in the back-and-forth around the COVID-19 vaccine. People may still be afraid of potential risks even if they know officials are monitoring them, Kornides says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZU8Ves"&gt;But ultimately, a personal touch may be more effective than public messaging. It’s now even more important for doctors and health officials to hear each person’s individual concerns about the shots and tailor their conversations accordingly, Kornides says. If someone is worried about the blood clots, for example, a doctor can explain the rarity of the reaction or encourage them to take one of the other vaccine types. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JF2t7r"&gt;The FDA and CDC should continue to be transparent about the investigation, Kornides says. The risk of increasing hesitancy can’t be a reason for the FDA and CDC not to explain vaccine-related concerns. “They had to do this because this is the way that we monitor safety of vaccines,” she says. “Without doing this, you can’t say that it’s a transparent system.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381875/covid-vaccine-johnson-pause-fda-cdc-coronavirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381875/covid-vaccine-johnson-pause-fda-cdc-coronavirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T13:47:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T13:47:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>AMD now offers Ryzen 5000 processors with integrated GPUs, but you can’t buy them yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fc-ceqkOieoBa2Q8hL2GY4jx7Q4=/401x0:4720x2879/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69119979/AMD_Ryzen_5000_Series_Lidded_5.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hta9A8"&gt;AMD has announced a new version of its Ryzen 5000 desktop processors — &lt;a href="https://www.amd.com/en/processors/ryzen-with-graphics"&gt;the Ryzen 5000 G-Series&lt;/a&gt;, which (like AMD’s previous G-Series offerings) adds an integrated GPU to the company’s existing Ryzen processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="34zznH"&gt;The company is launching six new APUs today. There are three 65W chips for more powerful machines — an eight-core Ryzen 7 5700G model, a six-core Ryzen 5 5600G, and a quad-core Ryzen 3 5300G — along with a trio of 35W GE chips with slightly less power and thermal headroom. And like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/8/21506447/amd-zen-3-ryzen-5000-processors-gaming-cpu-price-release-date"&gt;their GPU-less counterparts&lt;/a&gt;, the new chips use AMD’s 7nm process and feature its Zen 3 architecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yPmJda"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10444349"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TlSP2o"&gt;The integrated GPUs here are nothing to write home about: they’re based on AMD’s legacy Vega platform instead of its newer RDNA / Navi process that’s used in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/3/17/22334662/amd-radeon-rx-6700-xt-review-gpu-graphics-card"&gt;its latest Radeon GPUs&lt;/a&gt;. But they do look capable enough for midrange gaming, particularly if you’re only interested in playing less demanding games like &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CkSfxh"&gt;To start, the new chips will only be available as part of pre-built OEM systems — similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/7/21/21331824/amd-7nm-ryzen-4000-desktop-chips-apu-processor-prebuilt-systems-intel"&gt;AMD’s Ryzen 4000 APUs&lt;/a&gt; — but the company promises that this time, it’ll be offering the chips directly to customers interested in using them in their own custom-made machines sometime later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMr8az"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382081/amd-ryzen-5000-processor-apu-gpu-cpu-chips-oem-prebuilt-graphics"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382081/amd-ryzen-5000-processor-apu-gpu-cpu-chips-oem-prebuilt-graphics</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T12:59:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T12:59:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix redesigns kids’ profiles to be more kid-friendly</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iVCHIWLRY9UxuSSYzdhv0caYh1k=/53x0:628x383/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69119642/New_Kids_Homepage_1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/netflix-gives-its-kids-profiles-a-visual-upgrade/" target="_blank"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oxMSq8"&gt;Netflix is redesigning its kids’ profiles to make them more visually appealing and more prominently display popular characters from kids’ shows. You can see the new look at the top of this post, which features a row of a kids’ most-watched shows right on the home screen with characters from the shows appearing on top of the title boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TA3Bqj"&gt;The decision to include characters was to help kids better recognize their favorite shows, Netflix says. “We wanted to represent a title in the way that kids most recognize it — through the characters,” Michelle Parsons, product manager for kids and family at Netflix, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/netflix-kids-profiles-character-favorites-row-1234950107/"&gt;said to &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “This is going to be like a kid walking into their own room, where they know where every Lego piece is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5me7SX"&gt;For a show to appear in the favorites row, a kid must watch it at least once, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/netflix-gives-its-kids-profiles-a-visual-upgrade/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;The shows that appear on the favorites row won’t just be Netflix-made — titles from Netflix’s full catalog can be featured. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12h2LW"&gt;The revamped profiles are rolling out now to Netflix’s TV apps, and Netflix will test the new look on phones and tablets in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381917/netflix-kids-profile-design-favorites-row-on-screen-characters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381917/netflix-kids-profile-design-favorites-row-on-screen-characters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T12:37:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T12:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Five things to consider before you sign up for T-Mobile Home Internet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1TZIzJqFNRIgNYCXWaFZO0zeUIU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69119429/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;T-Mobile’s 5G home internet may sound like a tempting alternative to Big Cable.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0MLEl6"&gt;After a long early life in a pilot program, T-Mobile’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22312155/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-wireless-broadband"&gt;5G home internet service&lt;/a&gt; has finally arrived. The bar for decent, reasonably priced internet service in the US is embarrassingly low, so T-Mobile’s terms might sound like a dream: $60 per month, no contract, no installation appointment, no equipment rental fees, and no data caps. It’s a service that’s very much in its early days, and &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/home/internet/t-mobiles-60-home-internet-service-six-weeks-later/"&gt;reviews so far&lt;/a&gt; note some inconsistencies in performance among other quirks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zgbpDM"&gt;Even taking all this into consideration, it may still sound well worth the potential risks if you’re shelling out close to twice that to Big Cable every month. But before you drop-kick your Comcast router into the river, there are a few things to be aware of if you’re thinking about switching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zaKGul"&gt;Eligibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MeoYKV"&gt;First, and most obviously, is that you may not be eligible for the service. Home Internet isn’t offered everywhere that has T-Mobile cellular phone service; the company is introducing it as local network capacity allows. And even where it’s offered, you might not necessarily be able to get it. To make sure that it can handle the added demands of home internet users, T-Mobile may limit the number of signups they’ll allow in your neighborhood or condo building, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wAxZwQ"&gt;Take a look at &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/where-can-you-get-t-mobiles-5g-home-internet-service-lets-go-to-the-map"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PCMag&lt;/em&gt;’s map&lt;/a&gt; for an easy visual of the areas where home internet is currently offered, but for the most precise information, you’ll of course want to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fisp%2Feligibility&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F13%2F22381885%2Ft-mobile-5g-home-internet-issues" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;check your home address with T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3AK7cs"&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IRBirI"&gt;Setting up wireless internet isn’t quite the plug-and-play experience you get with traditional wired service. You’ll be looking for the best spot in your home to place the Internet Gateway, as T-Mobile calls it. Signal strength may vary from room to room, and even within the same room you might find better signal near a particular window. An accompanying app takes you through the setup steps and lets you self-evaluate your tech comfort level at the beginning to provide an appropriate amount of guidance through the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="WC8zV0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;unlike traditional broadband, you might find a different spot in your home gives better service&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nepUqz"&gt;Reviewers and early testers have noticed that signal strength can also vary throughout the day, so keep an eye on your internet speeds. Be prepared to try moving the Gateway to other locations if you’re not getting performance you’re happy with when you need it — unlike traditional broadband, you might find that a different spot in your home gives you better service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hM81wx"&gt;Slowdowns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XTCRst"&gt;Home internet service is subject to the same “data prioritization” policies as most of the company’s cellular data plans, meaning customers might see their speeds temporarily drop during busy times for the network. On some plans, this is applied only after a certain data threshold is met, but that’s not the case for Home Internet — users are always subject to this kind of slowdown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="4uKY6j"&gt;&lt;q&gt;customers might see their speeds temporarily drop during busy times&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aFUL1R"&gt;That sounds like a dealbreaker, but T-Mobile executives that I spoke to said that customers are “unlikely” to experience this thanks to how the company is expanding the service. They say that Home Internet is only offered in places with adequate network capacity, and that signups in a particular area or building may be capped to avoid congestion. That’s reassuring but still something to take into account as a potential drawback if you need guaranteed speeds at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kDuKlS"&gt;Hulu + Live TV isn’t supported right now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gDoDBy"&gt;Tucked away in Home Internet’s fine print is a statement that it’s “not compatible with some live TV streaming services.” T-Mobile clarified this for us, saying that while YouTube TV and Netflix will work, Hulu’s live TV service doesn’t work right now due to a technical requirement. The company says it’s working with Hulu to resolve the problem. If Hulu is your main source for live TV, then it’s a good idea to wait until that’s squared away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="imZe3x"&gt;You can’t take it with you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="yWK4wZ"&gt;It might sound appealing to take your internet with you when you stay somewhere else, like a vacation home, but that’s not allowed according to the service’s terms. T-Mobile says that’s to make sure that the service is being used in areas with adequate network capacity. Similarly, you can’t take the SIM card out of your modem and pop it in your phone when you leave the house. T-Mobile’s not going to let you quit your cellphone plan that easily.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381885/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-issues"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381885/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-issues</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
