<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-11T12:05:32-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T12:05:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T12:05:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: Qualcomm president Cristiano Amon on the Snapdragon 888, the future of 5G, and Apple’s M1 chip </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l7PhLHw4O1Oqmj7OkcPxBgPsWsI=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68497371/Snapdragon_888_Mockup.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7diHWU"&gt;At first we thought this was going to be a slow news week. Now, it’s Friday and we have published two &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; episodes back-to-back to cover everything you need to know in the world of tech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LZ3Qby"&gt;To sum it up: We’ve got another &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/21438042/apple-max-studio-noise-canceling-headphones-price-date"&gt;new Apple product&lt;/a&gt; to talk about, an interview with the &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/company/about/leadership/cristiano-amon"&gt;president of Qualcomm&lt;/a&gt;, and a discussion on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;the antitrust lawsuits against Facebook&lt;/a&gt; put forward by the Federal Trade Commission and 48 state attorneys general. (I hope you understand now why we separated these into different episodes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uCN0bt"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/3guY6dNe1shpzEl8rEEIKi" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IvImhd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9NtMWS"&gt;In the first half of the first episode this week of &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast, &lt;/em&gt;Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, and Chris Welch discuss the announcement of Apple’s new noise-canceling headphones, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/21438042/apple-max-studio-noise-canceling-headphones-price-date"&gt;AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt;. Nilay was able to try them out for a brief period of time and gives &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166888/apple-airpods-max-design-comfort-price-features"&gt;his first impressions&lt;/a&gt; on the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ow005o"&gt;In the second half, Nilay and Dieter chat with Qualcomm president Cristiano Amon about Qualcomm’s new flagship processor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21672519/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-cpu-gpu-details-performance-ai-isp-photography-specs-release-date"&gt;the Snapdragon 888&lt;/a&gt;, the potential of 5G, and what he thinks about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;Apple’s new M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RZerHD"&gt;Here’s a little snippet from that conversation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fWe7sv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dieter Bohn: What lessons could Qualcomm and Microsoft take from what Apple did with the M1? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WBRqL8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristiano Amon: &lt;/strong&gt; One of the great things about the M1, the way we look at it, we’re super happy with that announcement. Very happy.  And kudos to Apple because it validates our belief. It basically validates our beliefs that, you know, that the mobile user is defining what they expect out of the PC experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jn7pZI"&gt;And when adding Apple to that conversation, you started to see that the ecosystem is moving. Great example: I believe it was probably this week, if not the week before that Adobe announced a bunch of applications, that are all ARM native. And once you make it ARM native, performance increases as you have now app compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9YgOT1"&gt;So that overall is a very good sign. The ecosystem is going to move and it showed that Microsoft and Qualcomm were in the right trajectory. It’s about battery life, it’s about connected, it’s about a whole different multimedia experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="wjRqEU"&gt;Even though an interview with the president of a dominant chip maker company was enough to call it a day, we also decided to put out a separate episode of &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast &lt;/em&gt;to explain some rather important tech policy news. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Czix8t"&gt;In our second episode, Nilay talks with &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;policy editor Russell Brandom, senior reporter Adi Robertson, and contributing editor Casey Newton about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;why the FTC and 48 state attorneys general are suing Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, what antitrust &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166978/facebook-ftc-antitrust-instagram-whatsapp-tiktok"&gt;remedies they are proposing&lt;/a&gt;, and how possible it is to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22165534/instagram-facebook-antitrust-ftc-lawsuit-monopoly-case-opportunity"&gt;separate Instagram from Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LJmKzg"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/3DhISuyAIf4WzhEmHE3eSY" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LfdxSS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tQxk7k"&gt;You can listen here or subscribe on your preferred podcast player to hear the full discussions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TeLQXX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169567/vergecast-podcast-433-interview-qualcomm-snapdragon-888-airpods-max-ftc-facebook"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169567/vergecast-podcast-433-interview-qualcomm-snapdragon-888-airpods-max-ftc-facebook</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:44:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:44:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Mandalorian takes a stand on the line between good and evil in its latest episode</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s94WegQEER94-45OPI1378dDKjc=/713x0:3128x1610/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68497169/HUC2_FF_003556.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Lucasfilm Ltd.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d6viZr"&gt;“Empire. New Republic. It’s all the same to these people,” comments Migs Mayfield (Bill Burr) in the latest episode of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/star-wars/2020/10/30/21517931/the-mandalorian-news-reviews-disney-plus-star-wars-baby-yoda"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K1Ovej"&gt;For a while, it seems that the show believes it, dressing Mando up in stormtrooper armor as he goes to desperate lengths to save Baby Yoda (neé Grogu) from Moff Gideon. In “The Believer,” it’s not an X-Wing swooping in triumphantly to save our heroes; it’s Imperial TIE Fighters — a symbol that fans have come to associate with the forces of evil in the galaxy, potent symbology that &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;’s first season finale relied on to great effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Su06Jh"&gt;And director Rick Fukuyama works to really sell the audience on the victory of the Empire: soaring music plays in the background, as the base’s garrison rushes out to protect the battered truck, the only one to make it through the natives’ blockade. Our hero stands as the lone survivor, triumphant in his stormtrooper armor.  We see troopers and officers cheering, all but high-fiving each other at the success. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/469rL2l2RBIfWkU4VK02CPsuJZQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22162695/HUC2_FF_003672.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Lucasfilm Ltd.&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XtBb4N"&gt;The scene is almost an inversion of one earlier in season 2, when Mando faces off against two New Republic officers, whose X-wings shift menacingly into attack mode in a scene that paints the heroic &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; ships in an almost chilling light. Deep down, Mayfield argues, “We’re all the same.” Hero? Villain? It’s just a matter of perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="npCV4a"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s what those in power do with that position that matters&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j0SFuZ"&gt;It’s an argument that &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; has explored before. Werner Herzog’s Client back in season 1 makes a similar case: “The Empire improves every system it touches,” Herzog’s character ponders. “Judge by any metric: safety, prosperity, trade opportunity, peace. Compare Imperial rule to what is happening now. Look outside. Is the world more peaceful since the revolution? I see nothing but death and chaos.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aLcQHq"&gt;And yet, despite the reversed framing, &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; rejects Mayfield’s hypothesis that everyone is the same underneath the different flags and uniforms. “Somewhere, someone in this galaxy is ruling, and others are being ruled,” Mayfield muses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wtfNrr"&gt;But it’s what those in power do with that position that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UliOgP"&gt;And at the end of the earlier episode, the New Republic officers &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; swoop back and save Mando and his ship from hordes of ravenous ice spiders. But the Empire? The Empire plans to use its newly acquired rhydonium to create weapons that would make the planetary destruction of &lt;a href="https://starwars.fandom.com/wiki/Operation:_Cinder"&gt;Operation: Cinder&lt;/a&gt; (the Emperor’s final order, designed to bring down the galaxy should he perish) look small. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n2E1HSHvqq6A7TOBzSpNzFQWZpI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22162696/HUC2_FF_003662.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Lucasfilm Ltd.&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PL5v3K"&gt;It’s a moment that reframes the “heroic” victory before. Mando and Mayfield aren’t bringing desperately needed supplies to a village under siege; they’re transporting raw materials to make explosives. The “pirates” attacking their transport are natives, trying to defend their home against the ravages of the Empire. And the soaring fighters and battalion of stormtroopers gun them all down so that they can perpetuate the fighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gtuxTS"&gt;It’s fitting that it’s Mayfield himself who answers the question: when faced with his former superior officer, who commanded the murder of thousands of his own troops as part of the Emperor’s destructive contingency plan following his death, the former Imperial sharpshooter isn’t able to just sit there and toast with the man who ordered it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pRR6Nj"&gt;Because the Empire and the New Republic aren’t the same — even if the former has its virtues, and the latter, its flaws. It’s a sort of clarity we’ll likely get more of next week: a hero going to save his imprisoned, adopted child from an armor-clad villain with a sword doesn’t leave much room for gray areas anymore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UW21IX"&gt;
&lt;aside id="n8et5n"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus","description":"$6.99 per month or $69.99 if you pay annually","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XITFay"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NRqqVZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22169673/the-mandalorian-season-2-episode-7-believer-star-wars-empire-good-evil"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22169673/the-mandalorian-season-2-episode-7-believer-star-wars-empire-good-evil</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:23:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:23:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>AMC warns it’ll run out of cash in January, calls out Warner Bros.’ shift to HBO Max</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="AMC Theaters reopen" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dWrVn8oT1dM6HYfYuWPQGqzv2Eg=/0x0:4400x2933/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68497030/1228141186.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rjAInS"&gt;AMC Theatres is warning its investors that if it doesn’t find $750 million, it will run out of cash by the middle of January 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m8Bjtj"&gt;The company issued &lt;a href="http://d18rn0p25nwr6d.cloudfront.net/CIK-0001411579/9d5c87fa-c2ae-4427-a711-4e311862af80.html"&gt;new public documents&lt;/a&gt; today announcing that because executives can’t predict what the supply of movies will be like, and it’s unclear if people will even file into theaters again soon, the company is unsure of how much money it can make. Specifically, AMC’s documents note that executives can’t know with “certainty the impact of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"&gt;the Warner Bros. announcement&lt;/a&gt; or any similar announcements regarding the release of movie titles concurrently to the home video or streaming markets.” Conversations with studios like Warner Bros. and Disney have yet to take place, the documents add. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gYdNOX"&gt;Now, AMC is facing challenges that “have been exacerbated” by Warner Bros.’ move. Last week, WarnerMedia announced that Warner Bros. will release its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22152626/hbo-max-2021-movies-release-date-matrix-dune-suicide-squad"&gt;movies on HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; on the same day they premiere in theaters. At the time, AMC CEO Adam Aron blasted the decision — one he only heard about an hour before WarnerMedia announced it publicly. In a statement, Aron said that WarnerMedia “intends to sacrifice a considerable portion of the profitability” in order to subsidize HBO Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1acEo"&gt;“As for AMC, we will do all in our power to ensure that Warner does not do so at our expense. We will aggressively pursue economic terms that preserve our business,” Aron said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="J5xi2I"&gt;&lt;q&gt;AMC is facing challenges that “have been exacerbated” by Warner Bros.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TuoKkO"&gt;It’s no secret that AMC — and other theater chains — are struggling. Back &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514822/amc-theaters-cash-movies-delays-closing-pandemic-debt-regal"&gt;in October&lt;/a&gt;, AMC noted in public documents that “at the existing cash burn rate, [AMC] anticipates that existing cash resources would be largely depleted by the end of 2020 or early 2021.” The company estimated that in October and November, the monthly cash burn rate was $125 million. AMC isn’t making much revenue, and the one silver lining was having a slate of 2021 movies that could bring people back to theaters. With WarnerMedia shifting a few to HBO Max, and Disney bringing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167323/disney-live-action-adaptations-plus-streaming-pinocchio-peter-pan-wendy"&gt;some of its titles over to Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt; (not all of them, though), that silver lining is disappearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y3UxIy"&gt;Disney CEO Bob Chapek reiterated the company’s commitment to theatrical releases when asked by analysts during an investors event yesterday. The company generated more than $13 billion at the box office in 2019, and many of its franchises are mega-blockbusters that Disney can only reap full profitability from in theaters (in pre-COVID times). Chapek did add that “flexibility is going to be a big dynamic for us going forward,” which is why certain movies are moving to Disney Plus (&lt;em&gt;Pinocchio, Peter Pan &amp;amp; Wendy&lt;/em&gt;), but they’re not fleeing theaters entirely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TvHFri"&gt;“We had $13 billion at box office last year,” Chapek said. “Obviously, that’s nothing to sneeze at.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z7kyd6"&gt;While WarnerMedia also isn’t fleeing theaters per se, the US is a big market for film distribution. Offering people the chance to watch a movie at home for $15 on HBO Max — especially during a pandemic — is likely something they’d pick over heading to a theater. In markets where theaters remain closed, like New York City and Los Angeles, HBO Max is the only option. It’s likely that if Warner Bros. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/20/21330990/christopher-nolan-tenet-warner-bros-online-release-streaming-theaters"&gt;had released &lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;on HBO Max in the United States, the company could have bolstered its streaming subscriber base and continued to generate revenue at theaters internationally. Instead, &lt;em&gt;Tenet &lt;/em&gt;only amassed $52 million domestically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R1pF6j"&gt;Questions about whether theaters will cease to exist have flown around Twitter a lot recently — closures and restrictions put in place because of the pandemic have led to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/2/21545812/amc-theaters-financial-earnings-q3-bankruptcy-streaming-warner-bros-disney-regal"&gt;record low revenues&lt;/a&gt; even before WarnerMedia’s announcement. While movie theaters are not going to suddenly disappear, AMC’s filing paints a bleak picture of where the largest theater chain in the United States is currently sitting. As the new documents read, the company has “substantial doubt” about its future. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169538/amc-theaters-revenue-closing-warner-bros-hbo-max-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169538/amc-theaters-revenue-closing-warner-bros-hbo-max-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T10:52:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T10:52:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Contact tracing apps promised big and didn’t deliver</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Phone App Warns Of Covid Exposure" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gbcbhhN9poOcr_8zbSNqYT7yr98=/213x0:5787x3716/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68496793/1290167857.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Leonard Ortiz/MediaNews Group/Orange County Register via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Emphasizing privacy makes data collection difficult&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="FZa0LO"&gt;California rolled out a COVID-19 contact tracing app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22159842/apple-google-covid-contact-tracing-tech-california"&gt;this week&lt;/a&gt;, and officials — including Apple CEO Tim Cook — touted it as an advancement that would help slow their ongoing surge in cases. Using the app will be easy. Measuring whether the app can deliver will be harder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q1bLcp"&gt;Nine months after Apple and Google first announced their partnership, contact tracing apps’ role in reducing viral transmission is still difficult to measure. Relatively few people have downloaded the apps, and because of the apps’ focus on privacy, it may be nearly impossible to quantify how well they’re actually able to help prevent disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cyJKwq"&gt;“It seems to me that it’s incumbent upon those who are behind these efforts to show evidence that they’re having some effect,” says Ryan Calo, law professor and a director of the Tech Policy Lab at the University of Washington. “So far, I’ve personally been unconvinced that there’s been any kind of significant showing of efficacy.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="0wWKtJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’ve personally been unconvinced that there’s been any kind of significant showing of efficacy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UDlWb0"&gt;States each spent hundreds of thousands of dollars to develop these contact tracing apps, rebranded over the summer as exposure notification apps. New York’s cost &lt;a href="https://gothamist.com/news/governor-cuomo-said-the-states-covid-app-could-make-a-big-difference-did-it"&gt;$700,000&lt;/a&gt;, for example, while Virginia’s had a &lt;a href="https://www.thecentersquare.com/virginia/virginia-uses-cares-act-funding-to-launch-covid-19-tracing-app/article_e8a0452c-d764-11ea-ba2b-8ba71d2d540f.html"&gt;$229,000&lt;/a&gt; price tag. The apps were designed to supplement state efforts to manually track and stop the spread of COVID-19. Anyone who tested positive for the coronavirus would still, ideally, get a phone call from a contact tracer. Contact tracers would ask who they’d interacted with during the time they may have been contagious, and ask those people to quarantine or be tested for the coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZAxCV9"&gt;Manual contact tracing isn’t perfect — contact tracers can only find the people that a sick person knows they were in touch with, and the process can be slow. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21222161/apple-google-bluetooth-contact-tracing-system-coronavirus-health"&gt;That’s the gap&lt;/a&gt; automated contact tracing apps aim to fill. In theory, they would let someone who tested positive alert strangers they stood by on a long subway ride or grocery store employees they interacted with that they’d been exposed to the virus. And it would happen fast: telling the app you’d tested positive would automatically notify those contacts, without waiting for a tracer to call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9MU6H0"&gt;There’s one major catch: that entire scenario relies on lots of people downloading the app. Those strangers on the subway have to use it in order for them to get any benefit from an alert. If only a handful of people turn on exposure notifications, the chances that the random people who they interact with in their daily lives will also have the system running is fairly low. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IS9Vbn"&gt;In many states, uptake has been slow. In &lt;a href="https://gothamist.com/news/governor-cuomo-said-the-states-covid-app-could-make-a-big-difference-did-it"&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt;, for example, only around 5 percent of people have downloaded COVID Alert NY, which launched at the start of October. Fewer than 3,000 of the 180,000 people who tested positive since the app launched had it installed, and only around 800 people were notified of an exposure. Nevada’s app was installed by around 4 percent of the population, a spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Around the same percentage of Michigan’s population uses MI COVID Alert, and only 142 people have reported positive test results, according to a spokesperson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QuYjf8"&gt;Virginia, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/5/21355500/virginia-apple-google-contact-tracing-app-covid-alabama"&gt;first state&lt;/a&gt; to launch an exposure notification app, has seen more success: around 10 percent of the population, and around 20 percent of the population between the ages of 18 to 65 who own smartphones, uses the app, a health department spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;Colorado’s app is also more popular — 20 percent of the population uses it, according to a statement from the state’s Emergency Operations Center. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PerA3m"&gt;The numbers reported by states are still far below the levels needed to make a dent in the pandemic, analysis suggests. It would take around &lt;a href="https://www.research.ox.ac.uk/Article/2020-04-16-digital-contact-tracing-can-slow-or-even-stop-coronavirus-transmission-and-ease-us-out-of-lockdown"&gt;60 percent&lt;/a&gt; of a population using a digital contact tracing system to stop transmission of COVID-19, according to a study by a team at the University of Oxford. &lt;a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/landig/article/PIIS2589-7500(20)30184-9/fulltext#seccestitle10"&gt;Other studies&lt;/a&gt; found that it would take that level or higher of adoption, along with other public health measures, to control outbreaks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="iwv5um"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We wouldn’t be expecting a huge effect”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pqnHhD"&gt;“We wouldn’t be expecting a huge effect based on the kind of 20 or 30 percent uptake. It would be a small effect,” says Isobel Braithwaite, a clinical fellow in public health at University College London and author on a review of automatic contact tracing. It’s not all or nothing, she says — a small effect could still nudge transmission down a few percentage points and keep people from getting sick. Another &lt;a href="https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.08.29.20184135v1.full.pdf"&gt;still-unpublished study&lt;/a&gt; from Google and the University of Washington found that if 15 percent of people in a Washington state county used an exposure notification app, infections could go down by 8 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMQT6e"&gt;“I’ve come to think about it in terms of a spectrum, where you increase the benefit with the higher level of uptake. But even at low levels, there’s still some benefit,” Braithwaite says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Zbkbl"&gt;The University of Washington study does show that even at low levels, there’s some utility to the apps, says Mike Reid, an assistant professor in infectious disease at the University of California, San Francisco, who works with the San Francisco Department of Public Health on contact tracing. “My feeling is that anything that can help us to reduce transmission has got to be leveraged,” he says. COVID-19 spreads exponentially, so cutting off even one potential infection matters. “Every time you reach a case and help them understand their need to isolate, you know you prevent thousands of subsequent infections,” Reid says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AMnFd8"&gt;The challenge is, researchers aren’t able to pick apart whether the apps are actually preventing those infections. Most of the research on the way exposure notification technology changes the trajectory of an outbreak is based on modeling, including the University of Oxford and University of Washington studies. Experts use data and estimates to map out what &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; happen if a certain number of people download an app, based on what they know about the way COVID-19 spreads and how contact tracing typically works. But they don’t track the progress of apps to find out what actually ended up happening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Coronavirus - Thu Sep 24, 2020" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/49X2nZqOXgW6EyTTlEi9I9YjOyg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22161170/1228692803.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Yui Mok / PA Images via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The exposure notification app in the UK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YgWNVl"&gt;Google and Apple made a big point of prioritizing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21216484/google-apple-coronavirus-contract-tracing-bluetooth-location-tracking-data-app"&gt;privacy and security&lt;/a&gt; when developing the apps. They wanted to minimize concern that the companies were tracking users’ whereabouts, so none of the information collected by the app is identifiable. But by reducing the amount of data they collect, there isn’t an easy way to evaluate how these exposure notification programs actually work once they’re implemented. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QA0AA8"&gt;“By the very nature of how they’re done in terms of prioritizing privacy, it’s very challenging to truly assess their impact,” Reid says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cRfCjn"&gt;The United Kingdom initially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21248288/uk-covid-19-contact-tracing-app-bluetooth-restrictions-apple-google"&gt;attempted&lt;/a&gt; to develop its own contact tracing app outside of the Google and Apple system, which would have collected more information on usage. “They moved to the more privacy preserving Apple and Google approach for the wider national rollout, because of political and public perception considerations,” Braithwaite says. “That makes studying the effect much, much harder.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="KV1yXs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“That makes studying the effect much, much harder”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e0k5kT"&gt;Researchers don’t know, for example, how many of the people who receive notifications on the apps follow isolation guidelines or get tested for COVID-19. They also don’t know how many of the people receiving notifications are people who wouldn’t have been flagged by a manual contact tracer. “You have to see if there are situations where they never would have known,” Calo says. A robust evaluation would figure out how many times someone was in a situation where they got a notification from a stranger, actually isolated, and ended up developing symptoms themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5v4qk0"&gt;That’s key to evaluating whether apps were worth the investment, Calo argues. “They never would have quarantined or gotten tested, and we saved a lot of people that way,” he says. “And then you have to put that number against the numbers of how much was paid for the app.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JmKocH"&gt;For Braithwaite, even a slight dip in virus transmission would make up for the millions of dollars it took to develop and roll out exposure notification apps. “We’re buying a bit more time until the vaccine by suppressing transmission slightly,” she says. Not having clear-cut evidence isn’t a reason to disregard the apps, she says. It took time for researchers to study how well masks helped slow the spread of the coronavirus, she notes, but public health experts still asked everyone to wear them while that process was ongoing. “We don’t have any evidence that they don’t work, either.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="COYUU1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s no precedent for using this type of technology&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bn3Nxl"&gt;There’s no precedent for using this type of technology as part of a public health response to any disease, Reid says. It’s never been used before and was developed in the middle of a pandemic. Its use against COVID-19 is, in some ways, just a trial run. Despite the intense data difficulties, researchers will likely still try to sort through how effectively they drove down viral transmission — maybe by comparing coronavirus spread in areas with an app to those without, Braithwaite says. Having at least a hint toward answers will help public health decision-making going forward.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Y9tF80"&gt;“The lessons we will learn will impact how we respond to future pandemics,” Reid says. “I think evaluating its impact right now, and determining whether this is going to be part of our plan for responding to future pandemics, is critical.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22168473/coronavirus-contact-tracing-apps-exposure-notification-covid-google-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22168473/coronavirus-contact-tracing-apps-exposure-notification-covid-google-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T09:49:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T09:49:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Oculus Rift S is $100 off at several retailers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zyDNNYsfH152uSq272GrWm8InqE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68496473/akrales_190429_3371_0043.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="howhVF"&gt;Oculus has knocked $100 off the cost of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/30/18523941/oculus-rift-s-review-vr-headset-price-specs-features"&gt;Rift S&lt;/a&gt; tethered virtual reality headset, which brings the price down to $299. This makes it the same price as the Oculus Quest 2 standalone headset that doesn’t require connecting to a PC to play games and experiences — yet the Rift S doesn’t require a Facebook account to use it. Oculus announced earlier this year that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21422717/facebook-oculus-rift-s-discontinued-quest-2-vr-connect"&gt;it discontinued the Rift S&lt;/a&gt;, so this discount could be its way of clearing out stock. You can get this price at several retailers, including on &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Frift-s%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oculus&lt;/a&gt;’ site, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lenovo.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Faccessories-and-monitors%2Fconsumer-electronics%2Far-vr%2FOculus-Rift-S-3D-virtual-reality-system%2Fp%2F78011328&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2020%2F12%2F11%2F22169460%2Foculus-rift-s-vr-headset-sale-discount-deal-amazon-walmart#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo&lt;/a&gt; (the headset’s manufacturer), as well as &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FOculus-Rift-S-PC-Powered-VR-Gaming-Headset%2F231668381&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PTMKYS7/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=965268772192b4a0e42821b659089186&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MkWsvk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221560"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ajWui8"&gt;If you’re considering your options, this price cut makes the Rift S far more affordable than the Valve Index, which currently takes weeks to deliver after placing an order. The Quest 2 has been a popular holiday gift item, resulting in it selling out at most stores. So if you don’t mind being tethered to your modest gaming PC with the Rift S, this might be your best option to get a solid VR headset in time for the holidays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VqVkDT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/11/22169460/oculus-rift-s-vr-headset-sale-discount-deal-amazon-walmart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/11/22169460/oculus-rift-s-vr-headset-sale-discount-deal-amazon-walmart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T09:01:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T09:01:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Happy Friday, have some pictures of squirrels posing like superheroes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jZQp9NEcObYWwL4gF7KKEn65pic=/0x1:960x641/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68496219/y42ymyu7qqa31.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/photoshopbattles/comments/ce3znb/psbattle_squirrel_superhero_landing/" target="_blank"&gt;u/TheCreativeNick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mdjLnD"&gt;We interrupt your anticipation of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;new Marvel content&lt;/a&gt; to bring you news that if you photograph a squirrel juuuuust right, you can make it look like the woodland creature has just pulled off one hell of a superhero landing. People have known about the phenomenon for a little while (the first reference we could find online appears to be &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/photoshopbattles/comments/ce3znb/psbattle_squirrel_superhero_landing/"&gt;this Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; from July 2019), but frankly, we don’t think it’s had the attention it deserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FLBjQ6"&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class="reddit-card" data-card-created='"2020-12-11T12:48:59.621069+00:00"'&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/d2r2ot/squirrels_doing_superhero_landings_is_my_spirit/?ref_source=embed&amp;amp;ref=share"&gt;Squirrels doing superhero landings is my spirit animal&lt;/a&gt; from
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/aww/"&gt;aww&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;script async="" src="https://embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MRJ6pg"&gt;Thankfully, considering &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EwUilIo036g"&gt;how hard superhero landings are on your knees&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn’t sound like squirrels actually pose like this after jumping out of a tree. Instead, as several Redditors have pointed out, they seem to assume this position when they want to scratch their stomach with a back leg. The single arm up in the air gives them space to itch. You can see what it looks like in motion &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wNIu3MRPuSk"&gt;in this YouTube clip&lt;/a&gt; or via the GIF below. (Note the subtle bicep kiss.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZeI1xTxVWrc2VjqvwHmepS8lMfs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22162349/squirrel_bicep_kiss_superhero_landing.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wNIu3MRPuSk" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A bicep kiss followed by a scratch.﻿&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WfURuI"&gt;Here’s a collection of photos &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/d2r2ot/squirrels_doing_superhero_landings_is_my_spirit/"&gt;posted to Reddit by u/GallowBoob&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22169346/squirrels-superhero-pose-photos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22169346/squirrels-superhero-pose-photos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Medal of Honor’s first VR spinoff falls apart when the shooting stops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="medal of honor above and beyond" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qszPDqbneILWZDfOEfHZtnR9vV0=/0x0:1440x960/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68496138/moh6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;EA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RNBk3b"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Medal of Honor: Above and Beyond, &lt;/em&gt;the new VR-only title from Respawn Entertainment, can’t get by on authenticity alone. It has the weaponry and set dressing players have come to expect from a first-person shooter set during WWII. But for a console shooter making the jump to VR, it’s sorely lacking in intimacy — a necessary ingredient for any virtual reality experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M29zOZ"&gt;The environments you’ll visit in the campaign range in size from an attic to the sprawling beaches of Normandy, France, but they rarely feel like real places. Outside of your main objective, there isn’t much else to get distracted by, which is often what I find to be the most fun thing about exploring worlds in VR. I want to turn dials on old radios to listen to music of the time, open drawers, throw folders, and just generally make a mess of everything. Even the most polished detailed locales feel somewhat lifeless to walk around in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6el85U"&gt;That lack of depth extends to the game’s story and characters. When you aren’t shooting your way through the campaign’s six missions, you’ll be stuck listening to cliched banter. These sections that sandwich the action mostly drag on the momentum. There are more warranted breaks in the action along the way to make room for “Hey, we’re in VR” moments. This could involve having a weapon tossed at you to catch, solving a very simple puzzle, or pushing a button or turning a crank that, for no reason at all, only you are specifically qualified to do. I’ll take these over just standing still, but they feel forced.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="medal of honor above and beyond" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mnx7v7ev4kiWakTDAOqQVG9scVo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22155467/moh4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: EA&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="crbTXP"&gt;Really, the only things you’ll become intimate with are your weapons. Unsurprisingly, given the studio’s pedigree for making games like &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Titanfall&lt;/em&gt;, this game is at its best when your objective is to simply gun down all of the enemies. The game’s frenetic shooting requires you to become adept at reloading and aiming down sights. Occasionally, the plot will cut you loose to battle in some of the largest VR environments I’ve played in yet, and that’s when all of the game’s movement and shooting mechanics feel like they’re at their best. The enemy AI demands a more aggressive playstyle than I’ve experienced in VR, resulting in some tense action sequences. For instance, enemies will often attempt to kick live grenades back at you if there’s enough time left on the fuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6lkL82"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Hte4Y_BnkpY?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kPwNuR"&gt;Some aspects of the gameplay need some refinement, though. For instance, it’s too hard to accurately throw a grenade right where you want it to land. I can understand there being a learning curve, but it feels like something is off with the tracking. Another problem area is scoped weapons, which are all but necessary to use at times in the story. Using one blacks out everything on the display except for what’s in sight through the scope. That was borderline nauseating, as was moving the reticle on turrets in planes and tanks with my head instead of being delegated to my hands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N8Yv46"&gt;The lack of movement options may be a usability issue for some. Teleporting to move around the map isn’t an option at launch, which is something I personally relied on in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/23/21188291/half-life-alyx-review-valve-index-oculus-quest-vr-shooter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll instead move by tilting the left analog stick as you would in a console first-person shooter, which might trigger nausea with some people in VR. If you want to use the right analog stick to turn the camera instead of physically turning your body, that can only be done with snap turning, which moves the camera in a stilted way with each adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="61Mxoc"&gt;The campaign features six missions, that are broken up into about 12 smaller sections. Additionally, there’s a single-player horde mode along with several multiplayer modes, though I didn’t get a chance to play those during the review period. This game doesn’t warrant a second playthrough unless you’re someone who loves scouting out collectible items. It feels like it’s meant to be played as an on-rails shooter, moving quickly from one point to the next, like an unintended homage to the PS1-era &lt;em&gt;Medal of Honor&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a far cry compared to other VR experiences that offer far richer interactivity with a myriad of objects — pointless as it might seem — to ground you in the game’s world, which is what games like &lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/em&gt; do so well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="medal of honor above and beyond" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P52UtvvaMHrW6DodG5jM0hNIvKQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22155469/moh6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: EA&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0x05yX"&gt;There are some technical hurdles to even play &lt;em&gt;Above and Beyond&lt;/em&gt;. At launch, it requires a wired Oculus headset, like the Rift or Rift S, to play. The game is also available on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1402320/Medal_of_Honor_Above_and_Beyond/"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;, so any SteamVR-ready headset like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/28/19102584/valve-index-steamvr-headset-review-shipping-today"&gt;Valve Index&lt;/a&gt; or HTC Vive will work, too. Additionally, Respawn recommends a PC with an Intel Core i7-9700K processor (or comparable AMD model), 16GB of DDR4 RAM, an Nvidia RTX 2080 or higher, and a fast NVMe SSD. But regardless of what kind of storage you have, you’ll need to reserve a staggering 180GB to unpack the game’s files on it, which results in a slightly smaller, but still huge 173GB install size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9ED5m"&gt;I ran the game without a hitch on the “high” resolution setting on my PC, which contains an Intel Core i5 9600K processor, 16GB of RAM, Nvidia’s RTX 2070, and a SATA-based SSD. For PCs that aren’t as powerful as mine or the one Respawn suggests you have, you can switch on dynamic resolution to let the game adjust settings on the fly to stay smooth. It even ran fine wirelessly via &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21455665/facebook-oculus-vr-indie-developers-power-monopoly-concerns"&gt;Virtual Desktop&lt;/a&gt; with my &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;Oculus Quest 2&lt;/a&gt;, but your results will vary depending on your PC’s power and the quality of your internet connection and router. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YYCmjG"&gt;Even with all the necessary specs, I wouldn’t call this game a stunner, visually speaking. The main character models are expressive, if cartoony in appearance, though most enemies and secondary characters could pass as something just above low-poly extras in a modern open-world game. Some of the smaller rooms are particularly impressive, though the graphical fidelity and attention to detail expectedly take a hit as the maps grow in size.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="medal of honor above and beyond" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y0swO9eqXE1lyuxWY1t0moP4Kz4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22155471/moh5.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: EA&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HFlN5l"&gt;1999’s &lt;em&gt;Medal of Honor&lt;/em&gt; was the game that helped make wartime first-person shooters popular, though the franchise struggled to distinguish itself from &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; since it launched in 2003. With this VR game’s title, Respawn and EA seem to be bragging that &lt;em&gt;Medal of Hono&lt;/em&gt;r has finally gone where no &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; game has gone before — “above and beyond” it, in fact. Despite moving into new territory, &lt;em&gt;Medal of Honor: Above and Beyond&lt;/em&gt; feels like it’s traveling a well-worn path but doesn’t provide enough reasons to make it worth buying a headset. Even with all of the necessary equipment, this game doesn’t rise to being a must-play experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E0R8HV"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Medal of Honor: Above and Beyond releases on Friday, December 11th, on the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fexperiences%2Frift%2F3002462869834439%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22163762%2Fmedal-of-honor-above-and-beyond-virtual-reality-vr-review-steam-oculus#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oculus store&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1402320/Medal_of_Honor_Above_and_Beyond/"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; for $59.99.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22163762/medal-of-honor-above-and-beyond-virtual-reality-vr-review-steam-oculus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22163762/medal-of-honor-above-and-beyond-virtual-reality-vr-review-steam-oculus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T08:51:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T08:51:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Doom Eternal is another impressive Switch port</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hyqijqxSmR24WIDGk4ccyFPrBws=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68496115/doom_eternal_switch_screenshot01.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cHhM2q"&gt;When the Switch version of the &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; reboot was released in the same year that Nintendo launched its hybrid console, it took quite a few people by surprise. Not only was it rare to see an ultraviolent first-person shooter on a Nintendo platform, but it was downright impressive to see such a technically advanced game &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/9/16627782/doom-nintendo-switch-review"&gt;work on the mobile hardware in the first place&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, the resolution was a little blurry and it only ran at 30fps, but it was &lt;em&gt;Doom &lt;/em&gt;in your hands, which felt impossible at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HCsO87"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; was the first of several unexpectedly ambitious third-party Switch ports, a list that has grown to include the likes of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20919715/overwatch-switch-port-review-impressions-blizzard-nintendo-game"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21143520/nintendo-switch-steam-cross-save-witcher-3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. So this week’s release of its sequel, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/19/21186572/doom-eternal-review-xbox-ps4-pc-stadia-date-battlegrounds"&gt;the excellent &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, doesn’t have quite the impact of the original &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; port. But in some ways, that’s to its credit: &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt; feels like a completely viable Switch game now, rather than an improbable technical feat stretching the limits of the hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vAoN9b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Doom Eternal is gory, goofy, and metal as hell ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/19/21186572/doom-eternal-review-xbox-ps4-pc-stadia-date-battlegrounds"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Tdqcw2"&gt;I’ve played through the opening hours of &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt; on the Switch, and it actually runs better than the original game did. It’s still locked to 30fps, of course, and it still makes use of much lower graphical settings and dynamic 720p resolution scaling to keep that frame rate locked in. But it generally stays sharper than the first &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; port, and the Switch has no problem keeping up with the fast-paced action, which is so hectic that it’s often difficult to pay attention to the resolution. Loading times are much improved, too, and you have the option to play with gyro aiming (which the original game also got in an update a few months after release). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L7kwJInAvFgT-1Mgc947lJRezF0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22162239/doom_eternal_switch_screenshot01.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="D9o1Vv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt; is based on id Tech 7, the latest version of id Software’s in-house engine — which is to say that it’s a more technically advanced game than &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt;, so it’s great to see the Switch turning in a performance like this. A Switch version was planned from the start, unlike its predecessor, which may well have helped with optimization. The Switch version is also arriving pretty late after originally having been intended for release at around the same time as other platforms, so it seems like porting studio Panic Button made good use of the extra time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNHJgt"&gt;The biggest noticeable cutback is in the cutscenes, which are quite a bit worse than on other platforms. They’re running in a letterboxed aspect ratio and at a lower framerate than the game itself, causing a jarring effect whenever control is taken away from you for a narrative sequence. It’s not a huge deal since it doesn’t affect the actual gameplay — and I didn’t like the cutscenes on PC in the first place — but it’s definitely a compromise. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EJ9E90-iErcdm3iaROgeEXIbJ7Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22162240/doom_eternal_switch_screenshot04.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VbcorK"&gt;A more powerful Switch console is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21400521/new-nintendo-switch-report-release-date-2021"&gt;rumored for release next year&lt;/a&gt;, and I do wonder what it could do for games like &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt;. Since it uses dynamic resolution to maintain performance, theoretically, the game could look a lot better right away if it were running on a Switch with a faster GPU. For now, though, &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt; on the current Switch is a perfectly reasonable way to play the game if it’s your only way to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lU3E5I"&gt;That brings me to the only other real problem I have with this version of &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt;, which is that I don’t really have much reason to play it. It would be perfect on a long flight, but I obviously haven’t been spending much time on planes lately, and it’s hard to see me opting for the Switch version when I’m staying at home with other hardware available. &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt; is also selling at $59.99 on the Switch even though you can find it for cheaper on other platforms — or try it for nothing if you’re an Xbox Game Pass subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NHoFRV"&gt;But again, if the Switch is your only console or if your TV is constantly tied up, this is still a great option. While it doesn’t feel quite as miraculous as &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; did three years ago, it’s ultimately a better conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YGSrEs"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Doom Eternal &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is out now for the Nintendo Switch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22169262/doom-eternal-switch-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22169262/doom-eternal-switch-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T06:18:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T06:18:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s old 29W chargers aren’t good enough for MagSafe Duo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aKC8xJQE0JxirWITjx_iRneaXqY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68495649/dbohn_201109_4283_0009.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="px1WFU"&gt;An &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT211925"&gt;Apple support page&lt;/a&gt; has confirmed that the company’s new MagSafe Duo wireless charger, which is designed to charge an iPhone and Apple Watch simultaneously, isn’t compatible with its older 29W USB-C power adapter. If you’re using an Apple power adapter it’s best to use one of the company’s newer 30W models, which &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2018/06/04/apple-29w-usb-c-power-adapter/"&gt;replaced the 29W model in 2018&lt;/a&gt; and retail for $49. It’s an unfortunate revelation for anyone with the old chargers since the MagSafe Duo doesn’t come with a charging brick in the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2rogl9"&gt;Apple’s page doesn’t say exactly what happens if you plug the MagSafe Duo into one of the older 29W bricks. &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/12/10/magsafe-duo-incompatible-with-apple-29w-charger/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that if you do it will only be able to charge a single device, an iPhone or an Apple Watch, rather than both at once. Although the 29W brick appears to meet the wattage requirements of the MagSafe Duo, it apparently doesn’t support the exact combination of volts and amps required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3VkLm6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Working out MagSafe’s charging speeds is a little complicated&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WRBh1x"&gt;At this point, working out how fast each of Apple’s MagSafe accessories will charge your devices is a little bit complicated. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMHXH3AM%2FA%2Fmagsafe-charger&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F11%2F22169285%2Fapple-29w-usb-c-power-adapter-brick-magsafe-duo-incompatible#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;standard MagSafe charger&lt;/a&gt; charges iPhones at up to 15W, and Apple recommends pairing it with a $19 Apple 20W USB-C power adapter. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMHXF3AM%2FA%2Fmagsafe-duo-charger&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F11%2F22169285%2Fapple-29w-usb-c-power-adapter-brick-magsafe-duo-incompatible#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MagSafe Duo charger&lt;/a&gt;, meanwhile, offers up to a slightly lower 14W of charging when paired with a 27W or higher brick, so long as that brick supports 9V/3A. You get 11W of charging by pairing it with a 20W power brick that supports 9V/2.22A, and Apple says you need “at least 15W (5V/3A or 9V/1.67A)” for the Duo to charge two devices simultaneously. If you’re charging an iPhone 12 mini, the maximum charge is capped at 12W with the Duo. Oh, and the maximum charge is also capped at 7.5W if you’re charging your phone with a Lightning accessory (like a pair of headphones) plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kteyRr"&gt;Plenty of devices have very specific requirements for the hardware you need to use to get the fastest charging speeds, so it’s hard to blame Apple too much here. But I think we can all agree that it could have made things much simpler for customers if it included a power brick in the box with its $129 wireless charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7ia5VA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Apple MagSafe Duo charger is overpriced and under-delivers","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/9/21557152/apples-magsafe-duo-charger-wireless-iphone-12"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169285/apple-29w-usb-c-power-adapter-brick-magsafe-duo-incompatible"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169285/apple-29w-usb-c-power-adapter-brick-magsafe-duo-incompatible</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T04:21:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T04:21:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hyundai takes control of Boston Dynamics in $1.1B deal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TkahY_b9x3eNtletWS904OiN824=/0x55:1300x922/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68495498/MPM_0342.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of Boston Dynamics most famous robots is Spot, pictured.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Boston Dynamics&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fCYfFZ"&gt;Hyundai is officially purchasing a controlling stake in robot maker Boston Dynamics from SoftBank in a deal that values the company at $1.1 billion, the &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/hyundai-motor-group-to-acquire-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics-from-softbank-group-opening-a-new-chapter-in-the-robotics-and-mobility-industry-301191028.html"&gt;company announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The deal has been in the works for a while, according to recent &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-09/softbank-is-said-to-be-in-talks-to-sell-robot-maker-to-hyundai"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and marks a major step into consumer robotics for Hyundai. Hyundai is taking approximately an 80 percent stake in the company while its previous owner, Softbank, will retain around 20 percent through an affiliate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ppjp6j"&gt;Hyundai says its investment will help its development of service and logistics robots, but that over time it hopes to build more humanoid robots for jobs like “caregiving for patients at hospitals.” Other areas of interest include autonomous driving and smart factories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GlwJwv"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Boston Dynamics Spot hands-on: new dog, new tricks|72353" data-volume-uuid="bf26a011d" data-volume-id="72353" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-398" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ehnkeBKpB2fLAAGR5BgilIkSME0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22162233/1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Boston Dynamics&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atlas, another one Boston Dynamic’s robots.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JmmVzP"&gt;Boston Dynamics started as a spin-off from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. The company has created robots using DARPA funding, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/3/1/4042708/bigdog-robot-sprouts-herculean-throwing-arm"&gt;BigDog&lt;/a&gt;, but is best known for the viral fame its robots have found online. Its two main stars have been Atlas, a humanoid bipedal robot &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/16/16667376/boston-dynamics-atlas-backflip-video-watch"&gt;that can run and do backflips&lt;/a&gt;, and Spot, a smaller quadrupedal “dog” that’s been tested in a variety of scenarios, from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21267379/robot-dog-rocos-boston-dynamics-video-spot-shepherd-reaction"&gt;sheep herding&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231855/boston-dynamics-spot-robot-covid-19-coronavirus-telemedicine"&gt;assisting health care workers during the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;. The company started selling Spot in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21292684/boston-dynamics-spot-robot-on-sale-price"&gt;June 2020 for $74,500&lt;/a&gt;, targeting businesses looking for an automated way to patrol and inspect warehouses. Despite the viral fame,  &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-17/boston-dynamics-needs-to-start-making-money-off-its-robots#lazy-img-366074900:~:text=It%E2%80%99s%20had%20bouts%20of%20profitability%20over,it%20did%20its%20previous%20owner%2C%20Google."&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; that Boston Dynamics has not been profitable in recent years, which could change &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-17/boston-dynamics-needs-to-start-making-money-off-its-robots"&gt;under a new CEO and Hyundai’s guidance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R3Dn0p"&gt;It’s been a long journey from its start in 1992 to being valued at $1.1 billion. Boston Dynamics &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/12/14/5209622/google-has-bought-robotics-company-boston-dynamics"&gt;spent time under Google&lt;/a&gt;, primarily focused on research and development, and more recently had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/8/15766434/alphabet-google-boston-dynamics-softbank-sale-acquisition-robotics"&gt;a stint with SoftBank&lt;/a&gt;, a deal that former Boston Dynamics CEO Marc Raibert announced with the lofty “mission to push the boundaries of what advanced robots can do and to create useful applications in a smarter and more connected world.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4U4pFe"&gt;Hyundai’s own industrial robots have been focused on factories in its automotive comfort zone, including a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/9/18173742/hyundai-walking-car-concept-elevate-ces-2019"&gt;“car with legs” concept&lt;/a&gt; that the company imagined could be used by first responders to travel across difficult terrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RR4QSJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction December 12th, 9:41AM ET :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article originally stated that Boston Dynamics has never been profitable. This is incorrect. The company was profitable prior to its acquisition by Google through sales of software and research contracts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22167835/hyundai-boston-dynamics-aquisition-consumer-robotics"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22167835/hyundai-boston-dynamics-aquisition-consumer-robotics</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
