<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-05T12:31:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T12:31:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T12:31:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s ambitious Minecraft Earth game is closing down on June 30th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xLpqGseSUsWrSscholUlT90gwGE=/159x0:1881x1148/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68622838/minecraftearth.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0kk4b4"&gt;Microsoft is closing down its &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt; mobile game in June, due to the ongoing pandemic. The ambitious game had aimed to rival &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; and cover the world in virtual blocks for players to meet and play together. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ul3t7p"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt; was designed around free movement and collaborative play – two things that have become near impossible in the current global situation,” &lt;a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/article/minecraft-earth-coming-end"&gt;says the &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; team&lt;/a&gt;. “As a result, we have made the difficult decision to re-allocate our resources to other areas that provide value to the &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; community and to end support for &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt; in June 2021.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lmb5Y1"&gt;The final build of the game is being released today, which reduces the amount of time it takes to craft in the game and the cost of certain materials. It’s designed to let players craft and build more easily and safely at home in the coming months before the game is disabled on June 30th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oHXx6q"&gt;Players will no longer be able to download or play &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt; after June 30th, and Microsoft is deleting player data on July 1st. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oS7Y8GxAjL6i6-b2keAjADFrjnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16280867/nwL4p5E.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;em&gt; aimed to cover the world in virtual blocks.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S2P1bg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/17/18627341/minecraft-earth-ios-android-free-ar-game-features-pokemon-go"&gt;Microsoft first unveiled &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt; in May 2019&lt;/a&gt;. The idea was to recreate the experience of playing &lt;em&gt;Minecraft &lt;/em&gt;in the real world through augmented reality and to allow players to build virtual buildings out of materials. The game focused on social interactions with others, and it was part of a bigger effort across Microsoft to leverage the help of the HoloLens and Azure cloud server teams. Before the game’s release, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/3/18650201/minecraft-earth-demo-apple-wwdc-2019-microsoft"&gt;Apple even invited Microsoft onstage&lt;/a&gt; at its Worldwide Developers Conference (WWDC) to demonstrate the new title. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="irH6he"&gt;Players will now no longer be able to purchase items in &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt;, and any paid ruby balances will be converted into Minecoins which you can use to buy skins, maps, and mini-games in the &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5G54LA"&gt;“We’re eternally grateful for the amazing talent in the Minecraft community,” says the Minecraft team. “This was not an easy decision, and we’re doing everything we can to make sure you get the most out of &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt; before it sunsets.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215253/minecraft-earth-closing-down-june-2021-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215253/minecraft-earth-closing-down-june-2021-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T12:01:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T12:01:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook ads made News Feeds in Georgia more partisan and less informative</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ITyr2uQ9uyIp_fMX9eiQKvJtKzo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68622689/acastro_180720_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bCOkVm"&gt;When Facebook lifted its ban on political ads in Georgia, local News Feeds became dramatically more partisan and less informative, according to research published &lt;a href="https://themarkup.org/citizen-browser/2021/01/05/in-georgia-facebooks-changes-brought-back-a-partisan-news-feed"&gt;on Tuesday by &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GkiTRW"&gt;Facebook banned US political advertising in the wake of the November 3rd presidential election as part of its broader effort to fight election misinformation. However, the platform partially lifted the ban on December 16th, allowing ads specific to the Georgia runoff on January 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vp27TJ"&gt;To study the effect of those ads,&lt;em&gt; The Markup&lt;/em&gt; paid 58 Facebook users in Georgia to provide data on the content that appeared in their News Feeds in the weeks leading up to the runoff election. The resulting data (which is &lt;a href="https://github.com/the-markup/citizen-browser-georgia"&gt;available on Github&lt;/a&gt;) showed a huge change in users’ feeds when Facebook reopened political advertising in Georgia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AQ1jia"&gt;&lt;q&gt;news content was overwhelmed by paid political content&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bUldmA"&gt;When the ban was in place, most political content on users’ feeds was from news organizations like the &lt;em&gt;Atlanta Journal-Constitution&lt;/em&gt;, CNN, or &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;. Once political ads were restored, that content was overwhelmed by paid political content from Raphael Warnock’s Senate campaign, VoteGOP, or other political groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gJp4iB"&gt;Notably, &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt; also found a specific instance in which Facebook was paid to promote false claims. The report highlights a $25,000 ad buy from incumbent Senator David Perdue claiming his opponent, Jon Ossoff, “is China-bought and would provide our adversaries with just another way to threaten our national security.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7zrSZ9"&gt;As a documentary filmmaker, Ossoff &lt;a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/does-ossoff-think-china-documentary-113001723.html"&gt;received some China-linked payments&lt;/a&gt; when two of his films were licensed for broadcast by a partially state-backed TV station in Hong Kong. But the broadcasts were only a small portion of the overall licensing business, and the claim that his campaign is funded or endorsed by the Chinese government has been &lt;a href="https://www.11alive.com/article/news/verify/jon-ossoff-chinese-government-claims-debunked/85-09658a41-08b7-4682-abec-92b4c862c2ea"&gt;labeled as false by fact-checkers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="epFOut"&gt;The report comes after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22213670/facebook-political-ads-georgia-republican-senate"&gt;multiple reports&lt;/a&gt; of demonstrably false ads being promoted by Facebook, often receiving promotion even after moderators had removed an earlier version of the ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BvIWYH"&gt;Facebook has long struggled with political ad policies, particularly during the 2016 presidential election when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/6/16263704/russia-election-hacking-facebook-ad-spending"&gt;a Russian influence operation&lt;/a&gt; successfully promoted multiple campaigns on the site. Competing platforms like Twitter have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/15/20966854/twitter-super-pacs-political-ads-facebook-climate-change-abortion-paid-promotion"&gt;disallowed campaign ads entirely&lt;/a&gt;, but Mark Zuckerberg has defended the importance of allowing political ads on the platform on free speech grounds, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/10/30/zuckerberg-defends-facebooks-political-ads-approach-after-twitter-ban.html"&gt;telling investors&lt;/a&gt;, “I don’t think it’s right for private companies to censor politicians and the news.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215067/facebook-ads-georgia-runoff-political-ad-ban-zuckerberg"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215067/facebook-ads-georgia-runoff-political-ad-ban-zuckerberg</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T10:57:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T10:57:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>FDA tells US health providers not to modify COVID-19 vaccine dose schedule</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="People queue at NHS Covid-19 vaccination centre in London as..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xlPOAgsPmucOyvKgniPhERF40XQ=/1x0:4249x2832/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68622259/1230430316.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Thomas Krych/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VKkE7l"&gt;Health care providers in the United States should stick to the two-dose schedule for both authorized COVID-19 vaccines, the Food and Drug Administration said in a statement this week. Some experts have suggested that delaying the second dose could stretch limited quantities of the vaccines further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2T3ROr"&gt;Any dose adjustments&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;could be evaluated in clinical trials, FDA Commissioner Stephen Hahn and Peter Marks, the director of the Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research, said &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-statement-following-authorized-dosing-schedules-covid-19-vaccines"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “However, at this time, suggesting changes to the FDA-authorized dosing or schedules of these vaccines is premature and not rooted solidly in the available evidence,” they said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9mG01"&gt;Moderna’s COVID-19 vaccine takes two doses given 28 days apart, and the Pfizer / BioNTech COVID-19 includes two doses given 21 days apart. Data from the clinical trials suggested that people had some protection against COVID-19 after the first shot, but the trials were not designed to test if only one dose worked. Still, the evidence was enough for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Bob_Wachter/status/1345911427278671872"&gt;some experts&lt;/a&gt; to say that we should get a first dose to as many people as possible, and then give a second shot when more supply is available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cc5qd8"&gt;The United Kingdom, which is currently battling a frightening COVID-19 surge driven by the more-contagious coronavirus variant, is &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/01/04/britain-takes-a-gamble-with-covid-19-vaccines-upping-the-stakes-for-the-rest-of-us/"&gt;taking that approach&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2020/dec/31/covid-vaccine-uk-doctors-criticise-rescheduling-of-second-doses"&gt;Health authorities there said&lt;/a&gt; that people should delay the second dose for up to three months. More controversially, they’re also allowing providers to mix-and-match vaccine brands in some circumstances — someone could get a first shot of Moderna and a second shot of Pfizer, if it’s the only one available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8WZjyP"&gt;One concern in delaying a second dose is that a single shot could give only partial immunity. Without a subsequent booster to lock in protection, the virus could still infect people who have only gotten one shot and could hypothetically mutate into forms that escape the vaccine. “You are essentially maximizing the opportunity for the virus to learn about the human immune system,” Paul Bieniasz, a virologist at Rockefeller University in New York, &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/01/04/britain-takes-a-gamble-with-covid-19-vaccines-upping-the-stakes-for-the-rest-of-us/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Stat News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LiVaVz"&gt;Sudden changes to vaccine recommendations could also shake fragile public trust in the COVID-19 vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="C4VLZe"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Regarding last-minute changes to vaccination strategy, I'm going to keep beating the same drum for a while. Please don't underestimate the importance of the public having *trust in the process* for long-term success. Social scientists - we need you! &lt;a href="https://t.co/IeiDZty4IN"&gt;https://t.co/IeiDZty4IN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Natalie E. Dean, PhD (@nataliexdean) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nataliexdean/status/1346191710888448000?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1A3MtP"&gt;The FDA statement should settle the debate in the US for the time being. “We know that some of these discussions about changing the dosing schedule or dose are based on a belief that changing the dose or dosing schedule can help get more vaccine to the public faster,” Marks and Hahn said in their statement. “However, making such changes that are not supported by adequate scientific evidence may ultimately be counterproductive to public health.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="chmy9L"&gt;Right now, the limiting factor for vaccination in the US isn’t doses — it’s the delivery of those doses. Over 15 million doses of the COVID-19 vaccines have been distributed, but &lt;a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#vaccinations"&gt;only 4.5 million people&lt;/a&gt; have gotten their first dose. Making more doses available won’t solve the current problem of getting shots in arms. The rollout has been slower than promised — the federal government left state and local health departments to figure out the logistics of vaccination programs, and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/covid-19-vaccines-slow-rollout-could-portend-more-problems-11609525711?reflink=desktopwebshare_twitter"&gt;the process&lt;/a&gt; has been inconsistent and confusing for both patients and health care providers. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214865/covid-vaccine-schedule-doses-fda-uk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214865/covid-vaccine-schedule-doses-fda-uk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T10:43:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T10:43:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hades, one of 2020’s best Switch games, is $20 at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/54B2uZQJcBH_ztXOTBDyMxiuoB4=/151x0:1770x1079/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68622174/Hades_Wallpaper_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e5V8K3"&gt;If you recently purchased a Nintendo Switch or received one as a gift during the holidays, and you want to start building out your game library, &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; is on sale for $20 at Best Buy today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MzyAJl"&gt;Released last September, &lt;em&gt;Hades &lt;/em&gt;is a roguelike hack-and-slash action RPG released by Supergiant Games. Players control Zagreus, the son of Hades, who is trying to fight his way out of the Underworld. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eknCzd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hades is a roguelike with hot gods to kiss and kill","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21496904/hades-supergiant-games-review-nintendo-switch"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="7CrXWt"&gt;The game was one of the more popular titles released last year, winning Best Indie and Best Action Game at the 2020 Game Awards last month. Several of our staff also really enjoyed the game, including news editor Chaim Gartenberg, who said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22159911/hades-best-game-2020-nintendo-switch-supergiant-pc"&gt;it was his favorite game of 2020&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oA5fsh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10267751"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LVYk7C"&gt;If the Windows PC is your platform of choice, &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; is also on sale on a few digital storefronts. The lowest price you can currently find for &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt;’ PC version is at the Epic Games Store, which is &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/coupons/holiday-sale-2020"&gt;offering one $10 coupon to users until January 7th&lt;/a&gt;; applying the coupon to the game at checkout knocks the game’s $25 price tag down to $15. If you’d rather get the game on Steam, it’s &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1145360/Hades/"&gt;currently $20&lt;/a&gt; as part of the storefront’s annual winter sale, which ends today at 10AM PT / 1PM ET. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/5/22214879/hades-nintendo-switch-best-buy-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/5/22214879/hades-nintendo-switch-best-buy-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T10:09:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T10:09:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>How the Google union could boost labor organizing in Silicon Valley</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9uU_DSsSzpOzvqGKiyA2k1RucKQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68621972/acastro_180427_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cfd8yt"&gt;Just over a year ago, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/16/21021005/google-youtube-moderators-ptsd-accenture-violent-disturbing-content-interviews-video"&gt;I spent some time in Austin meeting with Google contractors&lt;/a&gt;. They had been hired through Accenture to moderate some of the most disturbing content on YouTube: videos that contain violent extremism, including murders and acts of terrorism. Several told me they had either been diagnosed with or were suffering from symptoms of post-traumatic stress disorder. The people I talked with made about $37,000 a year, and several had immigrated to the United States from the Middle East. Many found their working conditions intolerable, but they feared speaking out publicly for fear they would be fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MgPvfc"&gt;They were, in short, the sort of people who benefit from membership in a union. But with a handful of &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/how-kickstarter-employees-formed-union/"&gt;exceptions&lt;/a&gt;, the labor movement has made few inroads in the world’s most valuable companies. White-collar workers earn high salaries, enjoy world-class perks, and should they ever grow unhappy, have ample opportunities to get lucrative jobs elsewhere. And the blue-collar workers who support and enable much of their work have been outsourced to companies like Accenture, making them ineligible for collective bargaining under the National Labor Relations Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SfP3yl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If the arrival of an Alphabet union, no matter how modest, seems surprising, perhaps it shouldn’t be&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MBqEHf"&gt;These and other factors have prevented unions from forming inside the tech giants, even as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/7/7/21314636/twitter-nyt-taylor-lorenz-balaji-labor-movement"&gt;tensions between workers and their employers have risen across the industry&lt;/a&gt;. But not anymore: a small number of Googlers announced on Monday that they &lt;a href="https://alphabetworkersunion.org/people/our-union/"&gt;have formed an unconventional union&lt;/a&gt;, and if successful, it could upend labor relations across the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AbXcYR"&gt;The initial group of 230 Googlers is not immediately seeking ratification for their union, which is being supported by the 700,000-member Communication Workers of America through the National Labor Relations Board. As such, the Googlers will not have collective bargaining rights. But the union does include contractors, greatly expanding its base of potential members. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/29/technology/google-rescinds-job-offers-to-contract-workers.html#:~:text=Google%20employs%20more%20than%20130%2C000,its%20123%2C000%20full%2Dtime%20employees."&gt;(Google has 123,000 full-time employees, and 130,000 contractors&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mW1nv6"&gt;Nitasha Tiku &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/01/04/google-union-cwa/"&gt;introduces us to the Alphabet Workers Union in &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="n8WDmQ"&gt;The Alphabet Workers Union will have an elected board of directors and paid organizing staff members, according to the group’s news release. Members will pay 1 percent of total compensation, which includes salary and equity. A representative declined to say how many of the 230 or so members are full-time employees versus contractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OlgJvm"&gt;“This union builds upon years of courageous organizing by Google workers,” Nicki Anselmo, Google program manager, said in a statement that referenced the company’s decision not to renew a Pentagon contract to analyze drone footage after employees protested. “From fighting the ‘real names’ policy, to opposing &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2018/06/01/google-to-drop-pentagon-ai-contract-after-employees-called-it-the-business-of-war/?itid=lk_inline_manual_29"&gt;Project Maven&lt;/a&gt;, to protesting the egregious, multi-million dollar payouts that have been given to executives who’ve committed sexual harassment, we’ve seen first-hand that Alphabet responds when we act collectively.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="3o2jh0"&gt;If the arrival of an Alphabet union, no matter how modest, seems surprising, perhaps it shouldn’t be. Collective Action in Tech’s Clarissa Redwine points out that &lt;a href="https://collectiveaction.tech/2021/the-abcs-of-googles-new-union/"&gt;organizing efforts inside Google have been building for some time&lt;/a&gt; — and have been met with increasing resistance from management:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="F2OxUH"&gt;In 2017, &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/after-five-years-of-fighting-google-and-facebook-secur-1828304237"&gt;security guards at Google&lt;/a&gt; and Facebook had their union recognized and fought through a long contract negotiation. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/12/31/21043467/google-union-cafeteria-workers-unionized-alphabet-silicon-valley-mountainview"&gt;Google cafeteria staff&lt;/a&gt; employed by vendor Bon Appetit won their union election. In September 2019 a group of 80 contract office workers in &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/08/30/google-contract-workers-vote-form-union-amid-employee-discord-over-treatment/"&gt;Pittsburgh voted to join the United Steelworkers&lt;/a&gt;, forming Google’s very first office worker union. But shortly after these workers won their union, the company that contracted these workers to Google outsourced their roles to Poland, decimating the union’s bargaining unit in retaliation for unionizing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iCEksB"&gt;Since then, Google has ramped up its anti-union strategy. In November 2020, Google illegally fired four workers for organizing. In an attempt to further chill worker organizing, the company has &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/11/19/google-employees-protested-security-team-interrogation-memo-says.html"&gt;shut down key channels&lt;/a&gt; for challenging leadership, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-10-23/google-accused-of-creating-spy-tool-to-squelch-worker-dissent"&gt;tracked expressions of dissent&lt;/a&gt;, and hired an &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/20/technology/Google-union-consultant.html"&gt;anti-union firm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="EM53Ct"&gt;The subsequent forced resignation of AI researcher Timnit Gebru last month only further galvanized organizing efforts inside the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pf1mj9"&gt;“We’ve always worked hard to create a supportive and rewarding workplace for our workforce,” Kara Silverstein, Google’s director of people operations, said in a statement. “Of course our employees have protected labor rights that we support. But as we’ve always done, we’ll continue engaging directly with all our employees.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4IjAI7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;members now have a powerful megaphone for talking about workplace inequality&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I8oIam"&gt;But Isaac Clerencia, a senior site reliability engineer who has worked at the company since 2010, told me he joined the union after coming to feel like managers had grown gradually less responsive to the workforce over time. “I feel like the culture has changed significantly,” he said. “It used to be possible to raise your voice internally and maybe get Google to change some decisions. [Now] it seems harder and harder.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i8cEnP"&gt;To be sure, the Alphabet union is tiny relative to the company’s total number of employees. Much of the early discussion around the effort has focused on how powerful the union can be given its unconventional structure. &lt;em&gt;The Markup&lt;/em&gt;’s Adrianne Jeffries, a longtime chronicler of Google, called it “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/adrjeffries/status/1346141274634678272"&gt;relatively toothless&lt;/a&gt;”; Kathryn Spiers, a former Googler &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/dec/17/fifth-google-worker-activist-fired-in-a-month-says-company-is-targeting-the-vulnerable"&gt;who was fired&lt;/a&gt; after organizing in the workplace, said Alphabet’s union “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/computerfemme/status/1346144351475429376"&gt;could and should be more radical&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tdY2yu"&gt;And if the Alphabet union &lt;em&gt;stays&lt;/em&gt; small, its impact could be limited. But with a quarter-million potential members, and tensions inside the company continuing to boil over, I wouldn’t bet on it staying tiny forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KRasPy"&gt;We’ll see how many Googlers sign up — and fork over 1 percent of their salaries for the cause — in due time. In the meantime, here are a few guesses about what we can expect to see next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8RNQNF"&gt;For the Googlers in the union: members now have a powerful megaphone for talking about workplace inequality, and they can assume their grievances will get wide attention. That they officially speak for just a few hundred employees won’t much matter because Twitter exists, and there’s nothing a Twitter user loves to retweet more than a Big Tech employee calling out their employer. More importantly, union members will now have real legal protections as they continue their work — and new resources to expand their ranks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DqxLUl"&gt;For Google management: managers now face an entrenched internal opposition with added legal protections, a growing social media presence, and prominent supporters in Congress. (Senators Elizabeth Warren and Tammy Baldwin were among the elected officials who publicly congratulated the group.) The union reportedly plans to weigh in on antitrust issues; &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-04/google-workers-launch-union-escalating-tension-with-management?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes that the CWA previously joined a coalition calling for the breakup of Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. During a fraught time, Google will now have a high-profile group of employees working to undermine its favored narratives on a variety of sensitive topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iChiNG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;it could serve as a model for organizing efforts elsewhere&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZAASbO"&gt;And for everyone else working for a tech giant? I expect a lot of nervous looking around. I expect more &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/10/24/how-amazon-prevents-unions-by-surveilling-employee-activism.html"&gt;surveillance of employees&lt;/a&gt;, more consulting with lawyers, and more outright union busting. The faster the Alphabet Workers Union grows, the faster I expect these efforts to accelerate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x0ybSd"&gt;But Google tried those things, too, and in the end it didn’t matter. At least, it didn’t stop the union from &lt;em&gt;forming&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe the company can stop it from growing; maybe it can rein in the union’s power. But the union is here, it has big plans, and it could serve as a model for organizing efforts elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QZhw98"&gt;Moreover, I’d argue that the very aspects of the union that make it appear weak — the fact that workers have to opt in to joining, that it won’t seek formal recognition, and that it won’t attempt to bargain for a contract — make it easier for workers at other tech giants to copy. It may turn out that traditional unions remain unpalatable, or simply unworkable, at most big tech companies. But a giant, legally protected megaphone to air your grievances with management? That might be something that a lot of workers find useful, in Silicon Valley and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o4btki"&gt;I get why some have been dismissive of the Alphabet Workers Union, particularly in its initial form. But the trend within tech companies over the past few years has been for labor movements to grow more powerful, not less. Viewed through that lens, today’s news was probably inevitable. And the organizing efforts that began inside Google are not likely to stop there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="eaxW0m"&gt;
&lt;p id="2dm9sa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This column was co-published with &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Platformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214929/alphabet-workers-union-google-labor-organizing-silicon-valley"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214929/alphabet-workers-union-google-labor-organizing-silicon-valley</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T09:37:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T09:37:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm president Cristiano Amon is taking over as CEO</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L3G3AB5uV5DDj1Ecvtrtb5RGeMk=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68621762/cristiano_amon_headshot_0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QRBrDk"&gt;Qualcomm is getting a new CEO: Cristiano Amon, who already serves as president for the company, will replace Steve Mollenkopf, who took over as CEO in 2014. Amon has already served as the public face of the company for some time, presiding over introductions of new products like the Snapdragon 888, making him an obvious choice to succeed Mollenkopf at the helm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="23LY1E"&gt;Mollenkopf’s tenure as CEO saw Qualcomm face numerous challenges: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363629/qualcomm-win-appeal-antitrust-ftc-lawsuit-frand-patents-chips"&gt;antitrust accusations&lt;/a&gt;, allegations of anticompetitive behavior, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/16/18410985/apple-qualcomm-settle-royalty-dispute-patent-licensing-terms-high-fees"&gt;massive fight with Apple&lt;/a&gt; that saw the two companies sever their relationship (before patching things up in a settlement). But he also oversaw Qualcomm’s growth into the juggernaut it is today, one that nearly completely dominates the industry for mobile processors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0dwKl6"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/3guY6dNe1shpzEl8rEEIKi" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 232px;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TvlvaN"&gt;“I am honored to be named the next CEO of Qualcomm and appreciate the confidence that Steve and the Board have in me,” said Amon in a statement. “Qualcomm is an incredible Company. We have been at the forefront of innovation for decades and I look forward to maintaining this position going forward. In addition to driving the expansion of 5G into mainstream devices and beyond mobile, Qualcomm is set to play a key role in the digital transformation of numerous industries as our technologies become essential to connecting everything to the cloud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="31eDgB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Vergecast: Qualcomm president Cristiano Amon on the Snapdragon 888, the future of 5G, and Apple’s M1 chip ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169567/vergecast-podcast-433-interview-qualcomm-snapdragon-888-airpods-max-ftc-facebook"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="jmtxO0"&gt;Amon is set to take the reins on June 30th, with Mollenkopf set to stick around as a “strategic advisor” for an unspecified amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214902/qualcomm-ceo-cristiano-amon-president-steve-mollenkopf-retiring"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214902/qualcomm-ceo-cristiano-amon-president-steve-mollenkopf-retiring</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus Nord N10 5G and N100 are coming to the US on January 15th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v457j4-eMg1RmWKd_qMOe1tvsBs=/0x24:1080x744/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68621543/Still_3.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus Nord N10 5G.&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;em&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KyUvC3"&gt;The original&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21337235/oneplus-nord-review-specs-features-camera-performance-battery-life-90hz-screen-oled"&gt; OnePlus Nord&lt;/a&gt; skipped North America, but OnePlus is finally bringing two cheaper, mid-range options from its Nord line to the US and Canada on January 15th. The OnePlus Nord N10 5G offers flagship standards like a high-refresh rate 90Hz display and fast charging for $299.99 ($389 CAD), while the OnePlus Nord N100 features an even larger display and battery for $179.99 ($239 CAD). After&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/26/21534004/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-n100-price-news-features-specs-battery-quad-triple-cameras"&gt; launching in Europe last year&lt;/a&gt;, both phones are now carrier-exclusives for T-Mobile and available unlocked from OnePlus and other online retailers in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2JtX1J"&gt;The N10 5G’s 6.49-inch high-refresh rate display, 128GB of expandable storage, and 30W fast charging make it similar to the original Nord. Where it differs is with its lower-tier Snapdragon 690 processor, an LCD screen instead of OLED, and 6GB instead of 8GB of RAM. The N10 5G does still feature four rear cameras, though: a 64-megapixel main camera, and wide-angle, macro and monochrome cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BdhqGjPdbn2E3yyUW-Kz9C3KX44=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989022/N10_Still.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus Nord N10 5G.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="naJ6lk"&gt;As its name suggests, the N10 5G supports 5G networks. The handset is limited to potentially slower low and mid-band 5G in the US, but should have better range and coverage than phones that only support millimeter wave 5G. Notably, the N10 5G doesn’t support mmWave 5G at all, OnePlus confirms to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Given &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21524288/apple-iphone-12-pro-review"&gt;the difficulty we’ve had with mmWave 5G on other phones&lt;/a&gt;, that might still be for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IHhySBrjtz9s46rdUd3u-3h4VNk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21989021/N100_Still.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus Nord N100.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tM9DEq"&gt;The cheaper N100 is a slight step down in features from the N10 5G, firstly because it only works with 4G. Its larger (but lower-resolution) 6.52-inch display and 5,000 mAh battery (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514174/oneplus-8t-review"&gt;larger than the OnePlus 8T&lt;/a&gt;) also make it less comparable to the Nord, and really brings it into the realm of an inexpensive battery-focused phone like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/16/21222512/moto-g-stylus-power-review-price-features-specs-android-10-camera"&gt;Moto G Power&lt;/a&gt;. The Snapdragon 460 and 64GB starting expandable storage mark this as a decidedly budget phone, which makes sense given the price. The N100 also only features 18W fast charging, around half what the N10 5G and Nord can handle. For cameras, The N100 has three on the back instead of four, with a 13-megapixel main camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wtxLIv"&gt;Both phones run Android 10 skinned with OxygenOS, and OnePlus says that they’ll be updated to Android 11 at some point in the future. OnePlus is also guaranteeing two years of security updates for each handset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1wS46l"&gt;In terms of price, the phones cost less than we expected and come in under the original Nord’s price of £379 (around $484). They might not be using the same “recipe” as the original, but a lower price is always worth considering. You’ll be able to purchase the N10 5G and the N100 from OnePlus’ carrier partners T-Mobile and Metro by T-Mobile, or unlocked from OnePlus, Amazon, Best Buy, and B&amp;amp;H. The phones will be available at OnePlus’ website on January 15th at 10:00AM ET, with pre-sale beginning on January 8th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="le98uf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus Nord N10 5G Review: Tall Phone, Small Price","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="UkyXd8"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22213714/oneplus-n10-5g-n100-nord-north-american-release"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22213714/oneplus-n10-5g-n100-nord-north-american-release</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Dell’s latest Latitude business laptops add an automated webcam shutter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vExrqAoE_4KuBVfuGHkOuuUDMvs=/0x466:4000x3133/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68621598/Dell_Latitude__9420_3_view.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The new Dell Latitude 9420 | Image: Dell&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kLfYEq"&gt;CES has almost arrived, and Dell is kicking things off with some new versions of its Latitude laptops (designed for business customers), led by the new Latitude 9420 and 9520. The devices will add Intel’s new 11th Gen vPro chips (once available in March 2021) and new features like an automated, integrated webcam shutter to physically block your camera when it’s not in use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2mUgMp"&gt;Dubbed “SafeShutter,” the new optional webcam system is an almost blindingly obvious addition, especially considering the shift in focus to videoconferencing in the past year as businesses have been forced to transition to remote work. The shutter can open and close automatically when the webcam is in use, but there are also “mute” keys to manually disable the microphone or camera as needed. Anyone who’s ever stuck a sliding shutter or taped over their webcam for security concerns should be able to see the benefit of an automatic, integrated setup here, and it’s something that will hopefully extend to other laptops in Dell’s lineup in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xS9TGzIrybH5ESTciyHSyXyfHOA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22214849/Latitude_9420_2_in_1_SafeShutter.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new camera system on the Latitude 9420.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WqgWNy"&gt;The other big update is the option to get Intel’s new 11th Gen vPro chips — the Latitude 9420 can be configured with up to a Core i7 model — bringing the benefits of Intel’s newest chips (including its powerful integrated Iris Xe graphics) to the new models. The updated 14-inch model will come in either a 2560 x 1600 2-in-1 form factor or a lower-resolution 1080p laptop configuration. RAM goes up to 32GB, while storage can be configured with up to a 1TB PCIe NVMe SSD. Lastly, the 9420 will offer both optional 5G or LTE support through Qualcomm’s Snapdragon X20 (for LTE) or X55 (for 5G and LTE) modems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KddkYT"&gt;Dell will also have an updated model of the larger 15.6-inch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21519885/dell-latitude-9510-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Latitude 9510&lt;/a&gt; — called, fittingly, the Latitude 9520 — available spring 2021, which will offer similar improvements, including the webcam shutter and the new 11th Gen commercial Intel chips. And given how impressive the battery life was on the 9510, it’ll be interesting to see how Dell does now that it has the benefit of the vPro versions of Intel’s 11th Gen processors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W1AGMu"&gt;The Latitude 9420 will start at $1,949, while the Latitude 9520 has yet to get any pricing information announced. Both will be available this spring. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-gLtZQjTa7-qSErJY7pl5wSgEko=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22214851/Latitude_7320_2_in_1_tent_.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell Latitude 7320.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cTTkmX"&gt;Dell is also upgrading its Latitude 7000 and Latitude 5000 lineups. The 7000 series receives a new model, the Latitude 7520, adding the option of a 15.6-inch configuration for the first time (alongside the 13.3-inch 7320 and 14-inch 7420 models, which are updated versions of last year’s versions). The new 7520, 7420, and 7320 models will also be configured with Intel’s 11th Gen vPro chips, offer up to 32GB of RAM, and a new, smaller design. Dell also says that it’s upgraded the camera and audio quality for better videoconferencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qirOLQ"&gt;As expected, some of the more premium features of the 9420 and 9520 are missing here, though: the 7000 models can only be configured with LTE, not 5G, and the optional webcam shutter is manual, lacking the new automated system of the high-end models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4RbkoF"&gt;Lastly, there are the new Latitude 5000 models, which come in 13.3-inch (5320), 14-inch (5420), and 15.6-inch (5520) sizes. The new 5000 series laptops are also getting the new 11th Gen vPro chips, but take things down a step further with less aluminum and more plastic in the design. Dell is using 21 percent bioplastic content (from tree waste) in the lids of the 5000 series laptops, though, in a new environmental move to improve sustainability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EUW1gr"&gt;The Latitude 5000 series will be available on January 12th, while the Latitude 7000 series will be available on March 30th, starting at $999. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214058/dell-latitude-business-laptops-9420-automated-webcam-shutter-ces-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214058/dell-latitude-business-laptops-9420-automated-webcam-shutter-ces-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-05T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Dell’s new monitors have a dedicated Microsoft Teams button</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jtfn_pbRTP7zLaqvhy44efB1vRw=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68621594/dellmonitorsmicrosoftteamsbutton.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="74tVIj"&gt;Dell is launching three new monitors next month, and all of them come with a dedicated Microsoft Teams button. Dell claims it has created the “world’s first video conferencing monitors certified for Microsoft Teams,” after Microsoft started &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoftteams/devices/usb-devices"&gt;certifying displays&lt;/a&gt;, webcams, and headsets last year. Three monitors will be available next month, all offering quick access to Microsoft Teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="csGIut"&gt;The button will let Microsoft Teams users quickly launch the app to make and receive video calls. Hands-free commands will also be supported through Cortana and the built-in microphone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gxav7pMIy-820oyoXogaCUFpbHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22214806/EzIgOS6.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dell’s new Microsoft Teams monitors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="b4eYHJ"&gt;This is the first time we’ve seen a Microsoft Teams button on a monitor, but headset manufacturers have been quick to add buttons that support Microsoft’s communications app. New and existing headphones got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/30/21242753/microsoft-teams-headphones-button-launch-app-certified-devices-upgrade"&gt;deeper integration with Teams last year&lt;/a&gt;, just as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21241972/microsoft-teams-75-million-daily-active-users-stats"&gt;usage of the app was soaring&lt;/a&gt; at the start of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZbCnGq"&gt;The Teams button is the main surprise with these displays, but Dell’s trio of videoconferencing monitors also have some useful specs designed for an era where remote work and video calling is key. Each includes a 5-megapixel pop-up infrared camera, which supports facial recognition with Windows Hello. Dell also bundles a noise-canceling microphone and dual 5-watt integrated speakers. There’s even a built-in mode to reduce blue light emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9vUnJx"&gt;Dell is launching a 24-inch (FHD) version for $519.99, a 27-inch (QHD) model for $719.99, and a curved 34-inch (WQHD) variant for $1,149.99. All three will launch on February 16th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214786/dell-monitor-microsoft-teams-button-features-specs-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22214786/dell-monitor-microsoft-teams-button-features-specs-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
