<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-10T18:02:28-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T18:02:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T18:02:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Toyota will debut its first mass-market EVs in the US this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AntPJtxPcvN0tDezp3HJx8VbWEQ=/695x0:5963x3512/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800807/Screen_Shot_2021_02_10_at_4.26.19_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="62OWk6"&gt;Toyota will finally introduce its first mass-market all-electric vehicles in the United States later this year, the &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/28/toyota-beats-volkswagen-to-become-worlds-nopoint1-car-seller-in-2020.html"&gt;world’s leading automaker&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://pressroom.toyota.com/toyota-to-debut-three-new-electrified-vehicles-for-u-s-market/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; Wednesday, though it offered no further details about vehicle type or pricing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jhk2Ib"&gt;Toyota has previously said it’s developing an electric SUV on &lt;a href="https://newsroom.toyota.eu/toyota-to-preview-all-new-battery-electric-suv/"&gt;a new flexible platform that can power multiple EVs&lt;/a&gt;, following in the footsteps of Volkswagen, General Motors, and others. The two new EVs will be announced alongside an unspecified Toyota hybrid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="juOhC1"&gt;“We continue to be leaders in electrification that began with our pioneering introduction of the Prius nearly 25 years ago,” Bob Carter, Toyota North America’s executive vice president of sales, said in a statement. “Toyota’s new electrified product offerings will give customers multiple choices of powertrain that best suits their needs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SF4T25"&gt;Toyota helped pioneer and popularize hybrid vehicles, which lean on electric motors to cut down on emissions and increase fuel economy. But unlike most other major automakers, it has resisted investing in fully electric vehicles &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2020/04/27/all-electric-lexus-goes-on-sale-in-china-this-week-two-toyota-evs-to-follow/"&gt;outside of China&lt;/a&gt;. It’s only ever sold one all-electric vehicle in the US: the Rav4 EV. It existed in a few different forms, though Toyota &lt;a href="https://insideevs.com/news/325649/toyota-sells-last-rav4-ev/"&gt;only ever made and sold a few thousand of them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V3oaue"&gt;In its announcement, Toyota touted the success of its hybrid models, but it once again leaned on a flimsy argument as to why it’s resisted all-electric vehicles. The company says it did internal research that found total greenhouse gas emissions of all-electric and hybrid vehicles to be “roughly the same ... when factoring in pollutants created by electricity production for the average US energy grid used to charge batteries.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGeCiP"&gt;It’s &lt;a href="https://blog.ucsusa.org/dave-reichmuth/are-electric-vehicles-really-better-for-the-climate-yes-heres-why"&gt;a debatable idea taken at face value&lt;/a&gt;, but this argument crucially ignores that all-electric vehicles only get cleaner as renewable energy makes up more of the grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e5aMoS"&gt;Still, it’s a popular line of thinking at Toyota; the company’s own billionaire CEO, Akio Toyoda, said in December that he &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/toyotas-chief-says-electric-vehicles-are-overhyped-11608196665"&gt;believes electric vehicles are overhyped&lt;/a&gt; in part because of power plant emissions — a statement that must have been music to the oil industry’s ears since it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/climate-consensus-97-per-cent/2018/may/21/yes-evs-are-green-and-global-warming-is-raising-sea-levels"&gt;been one of its favorite pieces of misinformation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22187113/toyota-electric-vehicles-us-suv-debut-hybrids"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22187113/toyota-electric-vehicles-us-suv-debut-hybrids</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T17:49:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T17:49:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>The CDC hopes Harry Potter, Wonder Woman, and Neo can actually convince people to wear masks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MVH2aU8D8kQN8CB6Y4Fi3LNGzkY=/258x0:2163x1270/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800749/Screen_Shot_2021_02_10_at_5.23.36_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="T5bGVF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/your-health/effective-masks.html"&gt;Wearing a mask&lt;/a&gt; is one of the easiest things individual people can do to help prevent the spread of COVID-19, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is partnering with WarnerMedia in the hopes that fan-favorite characters like Harry Potter, Wonder Woman, the Joker, and Imperator Furiosa can convince people to mask up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTfzHJ"&gt;The ad, which was created by a partnership between WarnerMedia, the Ad Council, and the CDC, features a wide variety of WarnerMedia characters from iconic films — but with digitally inserted masks. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D-RHQbIXKagAHvx-gZY-DHuuG_U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22295922/Screen_Shot_2021_02_10_at_5.24.39_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="u7irl5"&gt;Whether it’s heroes (like members of the Fellowship of the Ring or the Justice League) or villains (like the Joker doing his iconic stair dance), everyone masks up. Even the murderous clown demon Pennywise from &lt;em&gt;It &lt;/em&gt;sports a mask — albeit, a creepy, clown-faced one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FtpdIa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://adage.com/article/media/harry-potter-joker-and-wonder-woman-don-masks-covid-psa-warnermedia/2313221"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;AdAge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the ad will run across the US in donated media time, and it’s free for broadcast and digital news outlets to use. WarnerMedia, of course, will run the commercial on its own channels and platforms, including HBO and Turner TV channels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9XqD23"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/10/world/double-mask-protection-cdc.html"&gt;Recently released guidance&lt;/a&gt; from the CDC actually recommends doubling up on masks, with a cloth mask worn over a surgical one for better protection. Alternatively, the agency advocates that people tie the ear loops on their surgical masks so they fit tightly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RqON9t"&gt;“Let’s get back to doing our favorite things,” the ad reads, “whatever that might be.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277114/cdc-warnermedia-mask-ad-campaign-harry-potter-wonder-woman-neo-covid-19"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277114/cdc-warnermedia-mask-ad-campaign-harry-potter-wonder-woman-neo-covid-19</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T17:43:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T17:43:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Security researcher finds a way to run code on Apple, PayPal, and Microsoft’s systems  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/seye7mZfasFJ8sgGdL4Ac1YpOcU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800722/acastro_170621_1777_0007_v2_0001_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SxKNzB"&gt;Security researcher Alex Birsan has found a security vulnerability that allowed him to run code on servers owned by Apple, Microsoft, PayPal, and over 30 other companies (&lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/researcher-hacks-over-35-tech-firms-in-novel-supply-chain-attack/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Bleeping Computer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The exploit is also deviously simple, and it’s something that many large software developers will have to figure out how to protect themselves from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zn8KRX"&gt;The exploit takes advantage of a relatively simple trick: replacing private packages with public ones. When companies are building programs, they often use open-source code written by other people, so they’re not spending time and resources solving a problem that’s already solved. For example, I’ve worked on websites that had to convert text files to webpages in real time. Instead of writing code to do it ourselves, my team found a program that did that and built it into our site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F4mdQY"&gt;These publicly available programs can be found on repositories like npm for NodeJS, PyPi for Python, and RubyGems for Ruby. It is worth noting that Birsan found those repositories could be used to carry out this attack, but it’s not limited to just the three. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KQ0qvW"&gt;In addition to these public packages, companies will often build their own private ones, which they don’t upload, but instead distribute among their own developers. This is where Birsan found the exploit. He discovered if he could find the names of the private packages used by companies (a task that turned out to be very easy in most cases), he could upload his own code to one of the public repositories with the same name, and the companies’ automated systems would use his code instead. Not only would they download his package instead of the correct one, but they would also run the code inside it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LPrOPJ"&gt;To explain this with an example, imagine you had a Word document on your computer, but when you went to open it, your computer said, “Hey, there’s another Word document on the internet with the same name. I’ll open that one instead.” Now imagine the Word document could then automatically make changes to your computer. It’s not a great situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tQcEnf"&gt;It seems like the companies agreed that the problem was serious. &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@alex.birsan/dependency-confusion-4a5d60fec610"&gt;In his Medium post&lt;/a&gt;, Birsan wrote that “the majority of awarded bug bounties were set at the maximum amount allowed by each program’s policy, and sometimes even higher.” For those unfamiliar, bug bounties are cash rewards companies pay out to people who find serious bugs. The more severe the bug, the more money they’ll pay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zmYxN5"&gt;According to Birsan, most of the companies he contacted about the exploit were able to quickly patch their systems so they were no longer vulnerable. Microsoft has even &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fazure.microsoft.com%2Fmediahandler%2Ffiles%2Fresourcefiles%2F3-ways-to-mitigate-risk-using-private-package-feeds%2F3%2520Ways%2520to%2520Mitigate%2520Risk%2520When%2520Using%2520Private%2520Package%2520Feeds%2520-%2520v1.0.pdf" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;put together a white paper&lt;/a&gt; explaining how system administrators can protect their companies from these kinds of attacks, but it’s frankly astonishing that it took this long for someone to figure out that these massive companies were vulnerable to this sort of attack. Thankfully, this isn’t the type of story that ends with you having to immediately update every device in your house, but it seems like it will be a long week for system administrators who now have to change the way their company uses public code.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276857/security-researcher-repository-exploit-apple-microsoft-vulnerability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276857/security-researcher-repository-exploit-apple-microsoft-vulnerability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T17:18:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T17:18:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: if you use Slack on Android, you should update your password</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YQpXbibxcHWjonpk1m6OvZFTdVM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800611/acastro_190412_1777_slack_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="my2r08"&gt;You should change your Slack password if you used the app on Android, according to an email sent out by the company &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/02/05/that-slack-email-you-just-got-asking-to-reset-your-password-is-legit-not-a-scam/"&gt;and published by &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently, from December 21st to January 21st, the Android version of the Slack app would store users’ credentials in plain text, which theoretically means any other apps on your phone could have access to them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ib9jM5"&gt;If you’ve got the popular communications tool installed on your Android phone, the first thing you’ll want to do is update to the latest version from the Play Store since changing your password won’t do any good if you’re still running the old version. Then, if you got the email from Slack, you can click on the link to change your password. Otherwise, you’ll have to reset your password from a desktop computer &lt;a href="https://slack.com/help/articles/201909068-Reset-your-password"&gt;using Slack’s instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s5fLzM"&gt;First, &lt;a href="https://slack.com/signin#/signin"&gt;sign in to Slack&lt;/a&gt;, then go to your profile, which can be accessed by clicking your picture in the top right-hand corner of the app or web app and clicking View Profile. Then, click the More button and Account Settings. From there, you should be able to change your password, though it’s worth noting that the option won’t be available if your organization uses Single Sign-On.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eYqPGX"&gt;Of course, if you used your Slack password on other websites, you should change your passwords for those, too (preferably to something unique). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277054/slack-android-psa-password-reset-email-plaintext"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277054/slack-android-psa-password-reset-email-plaintext</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T17:18:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T17:18:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google is testing a dark mode for desktop search</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mqA596MFJlwA7s9DhGhXlNI2CJM=/0x3:1147x768/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68799457/capture.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="P2C9Nx"&gt;Google is testing a dark mode for desktop search, Google confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. If the test has rolled out to you and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/22/18270975/how-to-dark-mode-iphone-android-mac-windows-xbox-ps4-nintendo-switch"&gt;your system is set to dark mode&lt;/a&gt;, the background of Google’s search pages will be a very dark gray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3AVOV5"&gt;Here’s an example of what the dark mode looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A8iD1eb17R-1uVbKpkD6biNdQVw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22294957/capture__1_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ct0rJV"&gt;It’s unclear how widely the test has been rolled out. A couple of &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers had their search pages automatically switch to dark mode, and &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/10/google-search-dark-mode-on-desktop-will-be-able-to-match-your-system-theme/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and some &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ruchernchong/status/1359537637049028611"&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/olearycrew/status/1359525437643362305"&gt;on&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mkgirlnextdoor/status/1359522898067750913"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; have seen the new dark mode, too. But Google’s search pages are still white for me, even though I have dark mode turned on right now on macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="emezo5"&gt;It’s also unclear if or when dark mode for desktop search might be officially rolled out more broadly. “We’re always testing new ways to improve our experience for our users, but don’t have anything specific to announce right now,” Google said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s62hQy"&gt;This isn’t the first time a desktop search dark mode has appeared: &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; reported &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/01/29/google-search-dark-mode-web/"&gt;in January&lt;/a&gt; that some people were seeing dark mode then. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CopNrs"&gt;If you’re a dark mode fan, it’s been an eventful few days. Changes to Twitter’s dark mode caught some people unawares last week when their dark mode unexpectedly got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22265306/twitter-dark-mode-dim-lights-out-black-darker-light-settings"&gt;even darker&lt;/a&gt;. And Microsoft is now testing changes to Word to make &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274181/microsoft-word-dark-mode-canvas-update-beta"&gt;entire documents dark&lt;/a&gt; when you’re using dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CCz9rM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 10th, 5:18PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Google confirmed to &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt; that this rollout was a test, so we’ve updated the headline and article to reflect that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276553/google-search-dark-mode-desktop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276553/google-search-dark-mode-desktop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T16:38:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T16:38:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Floating virtual lawmaker pauses relief meeting</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wm0TdIQCFD5KLsm84hVBGMPdRjA=/131x0:1517x924/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800417/Screen_Shot_2021_02_10_at_4.13.10_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Rep. Tom Emmer tunes into a House Financial Services markup upside down.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iJNxue"&gt;Like plenty of other congressional committees this week, the House Financial Services Committee met Wednesday to press forward on the latest pandemic relief package. Unlike those other committees, however, this one had the floating head of an upside-down congressman. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fdgmpQ"&gt;It’s not unusual for lawmakers to appear virtually for committee hearings much anymore due to the coronavirus pandemic. But it &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;unusual for them to stream in as a bodiless apparition. Asking to speak during Wednesday’s hearing, Rep. Tom Emmer (R-MN) appeared flipped upside-down while making a standard statement on the underlying measure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hzS3Xo"&gt;“Mr. Emmer, are you okay?” Chairwoman Maxine Waters (D-CA) asked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0xHtQa"&gt;“I am,” Emmer responded. “I don’t know what happened. It just came out this way. I turned it off and turned it back on and I’m still... okay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9onG4k"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I am not a cat. &lt;a href="https://t.co/d4lhQd0sJ4"&gt;pic.twitter.com/d4lhQd0sJ4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Emmer (@RepTomEmmer) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepTomEmmer/status/1359598666638581774?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3HxZaz"&gt;With everything moving online — from birthday parties to congressional hearings — the learning curve has proven steep for some users. Just yesterday, a Zoom filter trapped a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/9/22274865/zoom-hearing-cat-filter-lawyer-texas-live-court-hearing"&gt;lawyer as an adorable cat&lt;/a&gt; during a live court hearing that went viral after the judge tweeted out a clip. Rod Ponton, cat lawyer, couldn’t figure out how to remove the filter before streaming into the hearing and even suggested continuing with the cat face on. But it didn’t take very long for Ponton to figure out how to remove it, and the hearing proceeded without further incident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P3sIm6"&gt;“At least he’s not a cat!” one lawmaker shouted, referencing Tuesday’s lawyer cat flub. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="25q6T9"&gt;“You’re going viral, Tom!” another lawmaker informed him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5Bj9Z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pY9tdo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276998/tom-emmer-coronavirus-relief-lawyer-cat-house-financial-services"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276998/tom-emmer-coronavirus-relief-lawyer-cat-house-financial-services</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T16:32:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T16:32:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>If you’re vaccinated against COVID-19, you won’t have to quarantine if you’re exposed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="New York’s Yankee Stadium Hosts Major Coronavirus Vaccination Site" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LbQVOotuGwH7N9cRVG9maqx2Glc=/0x0:5956x3971/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800375/1300510738.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michael M. Santiago/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uupTvW"&gt;People who have been fully vaccinated against COVID-19 and don’t have any symptoms don’t have to quarantine if they’re exposed to someone with the disease, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention said in &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/covid-19/info-by-product/clinical-considerations.html"&gt;new guidelines&lt;/a&gt; released today. They should still follow other public health guidelines, like wearing a mask. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EWnpIe"&gt;Someone is considered fully vaccinated if it has been more than two weeks since they’ve received the second dose of a two-dose vaccine or a dose of a single-dose vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2MFLFA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;As far as selling points for getting vaccinated go, "you won't have to quarantine after a COVID exposure anymore" might be a pretty strong one &lt;a href="https://t.co/RODB8pyNL5"&gt;https://t.co/RODB8pyNL5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ed MD (@notdred) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/notdred/status/1359588988621893633?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="odZmtS"&gt;Even the best vaccines aren’t perfect protection against COVID-19. The Moderna and Pfizer/BioNTech vaccines, the two authorized in the United States so far, are around 95 percent effective at protecting from symptomatic disease. That means there may be a small number of people who are vaccinated who could still get sick. The CDC says people who don’t quarantine should still watch out for symptoms and get tested if they experience any. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="snwi2m"&gt;Researchers still don’t know how long protection from the vaccines lasts. So for now, the CDC says people should only skip quarantine during the three months after their last dose. That’s the length of time pharmaceutical companies tracked people enrolled in their clinical trials. That could change as companies have more time to gather and analyze data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f7D0ZZ"&gt;The guidelines are similar to those for people who have &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/duration-isolation.html"&gt;already been sick&lt;/a&gt; with COVID-19 and presumably have some level of natural immunity. If someone is within three months of their initial infection, they also don’t have to quarantine unless they develop symptoms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gVcuYm"&gt;Scientists still aren’t sure if people who get vaccinated can spread the coronavirus to others. Research is ongoing, and there should be clearer answers soon. However, based on what we know about vaccines and viral infections, there’s a good chance someone who has been vaccinated would be less contagious if they have an asymptomatic infection. For the CDC, the benefits of minimizing quarantines outweigh the potential, likely small risk of viral spread. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EyTIjp"&gt;Over &lt;a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#vaccinations"&gt;33 million people&lt;/a&gt; in the US have received at least one dose of a COVID-19 vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276905/covid-vaccine-quarantine-symptoms-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276905/covid-vaccine-quarantine-symptoms-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T16:15:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T16:15:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk and Witcher hackers claim they’ll auction off stolen source code for millions of dollars</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O3CkIiabaXXcHmbarZp4cijtVRY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800290/acastro_170621_1777_0001_fin.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cPm7UR"&gt;The hackers who targeted video game developer CD Projekt Red (CDPR) with a ransomware attack are now auctioning off the stolen source code they acquired for a payday of potentially millions of dollars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XhjyKe"&gt;The breach, which CDPR &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274035/cd-projekt-hack-source-code-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-encrypt-data-ransom"&gt;first disclosed yesterday&lt;/a&gt; after learning of it on Monday of this week, involved critical game code related to high-profile releases like &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3 &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077. &lt;/em&gt;CDPR said at the time that it had no intention of meeting the hackers’ demands, even if that meant stolen material from the hack began circulating online. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s5KcXy"&gt;That has now started to happen, it appears. Earlier today, leaks of potentially legitimate source code information started appearing on online forums, as noted on Twitter by the cybersecurity account &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/1359473460448231425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1359473460448231425%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=about%3Asrcdoc"&gt;vx-underground&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bSGMBd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;CD Projekt Red's ransomed data has been leaked online. &lt;a href="https://t.co/T4Zzqfn78F"&gt;pic.twitter.com/T4Zzqfn78F&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— vx-underground (@vxunderground) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/1359473460448231425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ktYPsT"&gt;This initial leak is believed to include source code of the CDPR’s virtual card game &lt;em&gt;Gwent&lt;/em&gt;, while vx-underground disclosed that auctions for the more valuable source code were happening on a hacking forum known as Exploit. We haven’t been able to verify that information, and CDPR has not responded to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cd2j6r"&gt;But a cybersecurity firm called KELA, which specializes in providing threat intelligence to companies based on analyses of dark web websites and communities, says it has reason to believe the auctions are, in fact, legitimate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hD11qX"&gt;“We do believe that this is a real auction by a real seller who accessed the data. The seller offers to use a guarantor and he allows only those who have a deposit to participate — a tactic that is used by many sellers to show that they are serious and to ensure that no scam will occur,” a spokesperson for KELA tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YkUKkI"&gt;KELA says its threat intelligence analyst, Victoria Kivilevich, was able to download some of the information provided to him by an individual claiming to be involved with the auctions. Kivilevich believes it is genuine, and KELA shared screenshots with &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;of some of the file lists allegedly showing off stolen source code of CDPR’s Red Engine, its in-house game engine platform. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6e0KCL_fuEuXjsCtkbBaZRlEDdk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22295499/WhatsApp_Image_2021_02_10_at_14.12.09.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: KELA&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OOWPJFZMAQc0QaZobsLkX0-sJqc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22295501/WhatsApp_Image_2021_02_10_at_14.12.10.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: KELA&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pB9yL6"&gt;KELA says the auction is offering source code files for both the Red Engine and CDPR game releases, including &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Thronebreaker: The Witcher Tales &lt;/em&gt;spinoff, and the recently released &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;. The stolen material is also believed to include internal documents, though it’s not clear what types of documents or additional material the full cache includes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P7JTJB"&gt;KELA says the starting price of the auction is $1 million, with higher bids in increments of $500,000 and a buy-it-now price of $7 million. Only users who deposit 0.1 bitcoin can participate, which is why Kivilevich believes the hackers are serious about hosting the auction and that the material for sale is likely legitimate because it ensures nobody participating in the auction is trying to scam the sellers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="frH0A9"&gt;Vx-underground also independently verified the pricing terms of the auction after KELA had provided the information to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, including screenshots alleging it’s to take place tomorrow at 5AM ET / 1PM Moscow Standard Time and run until 48 hours after the last bid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JmANoV"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Update: a mistake was made. They stated starting bid $1kk. This was assumed as a typo for $1,000. They meant $1,000,000. They are also selling immediately for $7,000,000.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Attached images supplied by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrFurfagMD?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DrFurfagMD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/JnOcwnGqZk"&gt;pic.twitter.com/JnOcwnGqZk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— vx-underground (@vxunderground) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/1359568916339646466?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CuMxxm"&gt;It’s not clear whether the leak from earlier today — which has already been removed from file upload sites like Mega and scrubbed from hacking forums and other sites — is in any way associated with the ransomware attack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sBLeb6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PK9Vay"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276664/cyberpunk-witcher-hackers-auction-source-code-ransomware-attack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276664/cyberpunk-witcher-hackers-auction-source-code-ransomware-attack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T15:48:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T15:48:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Asus is killing off tiny easy-to-lose M.2 screws with this handy Q-Latch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ddgzNZuUm0uwJTzzvhctxB3xc6E=/0x0:1080x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68800119/q_latch_asus_gif_2.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qzxpmc"&gt;Is there anything worse than repeatedly dropping the super tiny screw that lets you install an M.2 solid-state drive in your PC? Yes, but it’s definitely up there on the list — and now, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ASUS_ROG/status/1358694010932449281?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1358694010932449281%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=about%3Asrcdoc"&gt;Asus has a solution&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFwjD1"&gt;It’s called the Q-Latch, and it’s about as simple as it gets: a plastic retaining lever that you can rotate into place with the single swipe of your thumb. You can get one in several of &lt;a href="https://www.asus.com/us/site/motherboards/Intel-Rocket-Lake-Z590-H570-B560-series/"&gt;Asus’ new Z590 and B560 motherboards&lt;/a&gt;, though it hasn’t rolled out to the company’s most expensive boards yet, &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/asus/m2-q-latch-installation"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;PCGamesN&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zBM1i4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;  &lt;a href="https://t.co/VaOz7YqG2G"&gt;pic.twitter.com/VaOz7YqG2G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— ROG Global (@ASUS_ROG) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ASUS_ROG/status/1358694010932449281?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eiYJEc"&gt;This isn’t a brand-new idea, as the kind of business-oriented laptops and desktops that your sysadmin might have procured have sometimes featured plastic retaining clips in the past, but it’s the first time I’ve seen anything like this on DIY desktop components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V2l8Er"&gt;More than one &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffer is happy to see Asus doing something about this. New SSDs don’t typically come with these screws, so you generally have to carefully save the ones from your motherboard if you want to install one later on. They’re also annoying to insert: I helped one of my buds remotely build a computer last week, and he dropped it repeatedly. (Sorry, friend. Your sad story is memorialized on &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; now.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UzwCy7"&gt;One trick is to place the M.2 screw on the lip of your SSD before you fully press it down against the motherboard, using both the spring tension of the SSD and the tip of your screwdriver to hold it in place as you push down. But if you’d rather not deal with that, I’m seeing Asus’ Q-Latch listed for the following motherboards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="xXLnzL"&gt;TUF Gaming Z590-Plus WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Yp0c80"&gt;ROG Strix Z590-A Gaming WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lQZ8vy"&gt;ROG Strix Z590-E Gaming WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="t69GFW"&gt;ROG Strix Z590-F Gaming WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4Bx0im"&gt;ROG Strix B560-A Gaming WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6HIWYA"&gt;ROG Strix B560-F Gaming WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="d44Ur3"&gt;ROG Strix B560-G Gaming WiFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="opCrjw"&gt;Hopefully, other manufacturers will follow Asus’ lead, but I’m not holding out hope. Remember when I asked whether there was anything worse than M.2 screws? One worse thing is tiny header cables — you know, the ones that seem to enjoy being guillotined by graphics cards and are a pain to slot if you’ve got big hands. Asus has something for that, too, but&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Q-Connector"&gt; its “Q-Connector”&lt;/a&gt; (see below) isn’t widespread, either.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A little plastic brick with pins that allows you to insert all the motherboard headers at once." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WEXmwYq-zs4F8v9VWiaR3QPBnGI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22295529/asus_q_connector.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s a little plastic brick with pins that allows you to insert all of the motherboard headers at once.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YptI1N"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oj3FfG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276815/asus-m2-screw-q-latch-motherboard-z590-b560"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276815/asus-m2-screw-q-latch-motherboard-z590-b560</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T15:01:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T15:01:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Pokémon cards are selling so well the Pokémon Company is rushing to print more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pokemon European International Championships" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8fw1DVYdjOnPoxWFq8gINtSslU8=/0x0:4944x3296/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68799905/875487558.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by John Keeble/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="svo9eH"&gt;Demand for Pokémon cards has been high the last few weeks as the series celebrates its 25th anniversary. To accommodate the high demand, The Pokémon Company announced today that it &lt;a href="https://support.pokemon.com/hc/en-us/articles/360056644571-Update-on-Pok%C3%A9mon-Trading-Card-Game-Product-Availability"&gt;will be reprinting trading cards&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="212vyK"&gt;The Pokémon Company &lt;a href="https://support.pokemon.com/hc/en-us/articles/360056644571-Update-on-Pok%C3%A9mon-Trading-Card-Game-Product-Availability"&gt;released a statement&lt;/a&gt; on its support page that it is “aware that some fans are experiencing difficulties purchasing certain Pokémon trading card products due to a very high demand and global shipping constraints impacting g availability,” while also confirming that it is reprinting impacted products at “maximum capacity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="W2UsoE"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We’re aware that some fans are experiencing difficulties purchasing certain Pokémon TCG products due to very high demand. In response, we are reprinting impacted products at maximum capacity to ensure more fans can enjoy the Pokémon TCG. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;More info here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/sClZo3BXsp"&gt;https://t.co/sClZo3BXsp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Play Pokémon (@playpokemon) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/playpokemon/status/1359548922780213249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HIeblb"&gt;There’s no specific time frame on when retailers are expected to receive new shipments, but the company pledged that it will “replenish stock at retailers as soon as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uo0NbP"&gt;Over the last several months, Pokémon trading cards have been &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/11/6/21551503/pokemon-card-charizard-appraisal-shadowless-collection-first-edition-prices"&gt;in high demand&lt;/a&gt; with products selling out quickly at retailers and older cards selling for as much as &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/10/28/21538821/box-of-first-edition-pokemon-cards-fake-375000-dumb-money-logan-paul"&gt;$375,000 by third-party sellers&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, card opening videos have &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bQB8scCtrKg"&gt;blown up on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; over the last year — in some cases, getting millions of views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bMdJQz"&gt;With the franchise celebrating a major milestone this year, Nintendo has been finding various ways to commemorate the occasion. This includes partnering with McDonald's to give out &lt;a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-news/collect-25th-anniversary-pokemon-tcg-cards-in-mcdonalds-happy-meals/"&gt;collectible cards when you buy a Happy Meal&lt;/a&gt; at the fast-food chain, but as our sister site &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/9/22274841/mcdonalds-pokemon-cards-anniversary-25-scalpers-ebay-prices-resell-happy-meal"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out, the demand for these items is high, and some people are taking advantage of the situation. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276738/pokemon-trading-card-game-printing-short-supply-high-demand"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276738/pokemon-trading-card-game-printing-short-supply-high-demand</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
