<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-12T16:54:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T16:54:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T16:54:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google adds more AR animals to mobile Search and most of them are pretty cute</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bFhYKvSkm3UZzH1AxSJTCrsZ5SE=/0x149:1061x856/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68503089/scary_giant_ar_cat.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Giant AR cat is giant&lt;/em&gt; | Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dTGiNQ"&gt;Google has added 50 new augmented reality animals to Search which can be either cute, or in the case of the giant cat in the photo above, a bit disconcerting. Of course it’s possible that I find the giant kitty menacing because I hate fun (or so I have been told), but I do not think I want that creature to greet me, anywhere, ever, in AR or any other reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zIcvMh"&gt;I do, however, want this red panda to play with a pumpkin in my dining room as long as she wants to. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P6cOo3WAytDE6Us4n7Uj92FGhOo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22165276/red_panda.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Kim Lyons/The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Look how cute she is with her little pumpkin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2avxY8"&gt;In addition to the red panda and cat, there’s a giraffe, cow, zebra, pig, and hippo among the new creatures you can welcome virtually into your home (or other space, but we’re all homebound right now). Just search for an animal on Google’s mobile app and tap “view in 3D” among the results. &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/12/11/google-opens-the-door-for-50-new-ar-animals-to-jump-into-your-living-room/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police &lt;/em&gt;has a pretty good list&lt;/a&gt; of all the AR animals they’ve discovered so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9e43Xi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hip(po), hip(po), hooray!   There are 50 new AR animals to discover on Search. Search for your favorite animal on your Google mobile app, tap "View in 3D" to see them in your space and don’t forget to share your best creations with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Google3D?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Google3D&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://t.co/u80Mn7wi1z"&gt;pic.twitter.com/u80Mn7wi1z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Google (@Google) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1337506620612485120?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Rtqe0A"&gt;When Google started putting 3D animals in Search last year it only had a few standard animals available like a tiger, a lion, a wolf, and a dog. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/2/18649312/google-ar-search-results-animals-3d-model-augmented-reality-lions-tigers-bears-oh-my"&gt;added more creatures in March&lt;/a&gt;, including alligators, ducks, and hedgehogs. In August, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21400577/google-arts-and-culture-augmented-reality-prehistoric-creatures-museum-exhibits"&gt;Google made prehistoric creatures&lt;/a&gt; and historical artifacts available in AR via its Arts and Culture app— and who among us wouldn’t love to check out the ancient crustacean &lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/asset/QwGIdPc45fzOug"&gt;Cambropachycope&lt;/a&gt; up close and personal? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="901gAX"&gt;I have to admit after playing with the AR animals in Search for a bit (in the name of research, obviously), it’s a pretty fun feature, and is likely to be very fun for kids stuck inside during — everything. Now, off to watch my new pet red panda wrestle with her pumpkin. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171601/google-adds-augmented-reality-ar-animals-search-3d"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171601/google-adds-augmented-reality-ar-animals-search-3d</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T15:31:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T15:31:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>The RestoMod is a limited-edition retro-looking PC with a fake floppy drive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yEc2DXwnadAMNo_Mt0iHi9BeGcY=/0x0:1405x937/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68502825/restomod.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Origin made its RestoMod PC to look like a throwback&lt;/em&gt; | Origin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FUqw44"&gt;Origin has made a new, limited edition PC that has the guts of a new model but the face of an ancient 1990s machine, complete with a fake floppy drive. In case you want some nostalgia while you wait for &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption&lt;/em&gt; to load, perhaps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KuV4UQ"&gt;The RestoMod has a custom Corsair 4000D case, and the &lt;a href="https://www.originpc.com/configurator/neuron-resto-mod/"&gt;standard build&lt;/a&gt; has 16GB of memory, a 2.9 GHz Core i5 processor, 250GB of storage, and a 6GB NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1660 Ti graphics card, for $2,080. The RetroMod can be customized as desired, Origin says, but they’ve only made 50 of them, so supplies are limited. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QP6-FGhpPm5fZiyIL7nrx5FjU9I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22165119/restomod2.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Origin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;RestoMod: New but with an old look&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yg38Ix"&gt;The front face of the machine is where you’ll get the old-school feel, Origin says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="WR3MWc"&gt;By using a custom HD UV print on the steel front panel, the RestoMod PC features a custom design inspired by PCs from the 1990s. The buttons and drives are just for looks, but you can always pretend that the Turbo button gives you that extra boost in performance. To complete the look, the RestoMod PC chassis has been painted in a matching beige color to accentuate how cases back in the day preferred simplicity over color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Jrkk1D"&gt;It’s a little disappointing that the Turbo button isn’t functional somehow, but this PC is all about its image: old and sorta dingy. Of course, for a limited run of only 50 machines it seems like Origin could have sourced some actual retro parts, like old disc drives, rather than what’s essentially a fun, but cosmetic paint job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KlPbXL"&gt;If you find the beige faux face of the RetroMod comforting, head over to &lt;a href="https://www.originpc.com/configurator/neuron-resto-mod/"&gt;Origin’s website &lt;/a&gt;to configure your new, but old, PC. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171472/origin-limited-edition-pc-floppy-drive-restomod"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171472/origin-limited-edition-pc-floppy-drive-restomod</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T12:42:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T12:42:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verge Weekender: Disney’s big day, Cyberpunk 2077, latest at Google, and our favorite gadgets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CBaRdCSUO5UiwA8jPrh6u3wm-co=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68502313/acastro_190228_1777_vpn_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="94r8lj"&gt;Happy Saturday and welcome to the inaugural edition of the Verge Weekender, a short recap of some of the stories we covered this week on &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s6c7QJ"&gt;The big event of the week was Disney’s investor day, where the company announced new Disney Plus series &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22168373/wandavision-trailer-disney-plus-marvel-studios-elizabeth-olsen-paul-bettany"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, showed trailers for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/21591343/falcon-winter-soldier-premiere-date-disney-plus-sebastian-stan-anthony-mackie-august"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22168459/loki-trailer-marvel-studios-disney-plus-tom-hiddleston-release-date"&gt;much-anticipated series&lt;em&gt; Loki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; as well as slew of new &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; series on Disney Plus, including &lt;em&gt;Rangers of the New Republic, Ahsoka, Obi-Wan Kenobi, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Lando. &lt;/em&gt;There’s also a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168623/alien-tv-show-noah-hawley-legion-fargo-fx-disney"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien &lt;/em&gt;TV&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; in the works. Check out the full roundup of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;everything Disney announced at its 2020 Investor Day&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QUC2bT"&gt;Perhaps the biggest news of the week/year/pandemic hit late Friday, as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22158608/fda-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-authorized-emergency-use"&gt;FDA approved the Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine&lt;/a&gt; for emergency use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="yVpeQ9"&gt;The vaccine is authorized in the US for people over the age of 16. It was found to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573072/pfizer-vaccine-effective-authorization-fda-safe"&gt;95 percent effective&lt;/a&gt; at preventing symptomatic COVID-19 in clinical trials. “That is extraordinary,” Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nowthisnews/status/1333146966985908224"&gt;said in a press conference&lt;/a&gt; at the end of November. It’s far better than experts had dared hope for. The FDA was prepared to authorize a vaccine as long as it was at least 50 percent effective. “We were shocked,” Pfizer’s chief executive officer, Albert Bourla, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/21/us/politics/coronavirus-vaccine.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We couldn’t believe it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Ekcfgy"&gt;Here’s what else went down over the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9hW6Vv"&gt;Google CEO Sundar Pichai addressed how the company handled the departure of AI ethics researcher Timnit Gebru&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="TScRsd"&gt;“We need to accept responsibility for the fact that a prominent Black, female leader with immense talent left Google unhappily,” Pichai wrote in an email to staff. He added that the company would consider “de-escalation strategies” in the future. In response, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/timnitGebru/status/1336758639785365506"&gt;Gebru tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that Pichai’s email wasn’t an apology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8szGFs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The backstory:&lt;/strong&gt; Gebru tweeted that Google had abruptly fired her after she voiced her frustration over how the company had handled a &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/12/04/1013294/google-ai-ethics-research-paper-forced-out-timnit-gebru/"&gt;research paper on the risks of large language processing models&lt;/a&gt;, and Google’s head of AI, Jeff Dean, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1f2kYWDXwhzYnq8ebVtuk9CqQqz7ScqxhSIxeYGrWjK0/edit"&gt;published a note&lt;/a&gt; explaining that Gebru’s paper hadn’t met company standards. Her own team &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158501/timnit-gebru-team-google-public-statement-fired"&gt;pushed back, writing that Google&lt;/a&gt; had applied its publication review policy “unevenly and discriminatorily.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="AWK4lS"&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 finally debuts after nearly a decade in development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JPWb0U"&gt;The long-awaited game from CD Projekt Red &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; to generally favorable reviews. But reports of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;bugs from users on older consoles&lt;/a&gt; put into doubt whether developers who helped make the game would earn their performance bonuses. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"&gt;company announced Friday&lt;/a&gt; it would pay devs full bonuses regardless of the game’s &lt;a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pc/cyberpunk-2077"&gt;critical reception&lt;/a&gt;. It also said it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"&gt;removing some flashing-light sequences&lt;/a&gt; in the game to reduce the potential for inducing seizures for some users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kU3wV5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 is huge, ambitious, and safe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h3 id="QTkOlt"&gt;Visa and Mastercard crack down on Pornhub after report of unlawful videos&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="LAxd9G"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/04/opinion/sunday/pornhub-rape-trafficking.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;reported &lt;/a&gt;the porn portal had videos of underage girls and assaults on its site, Pornhub &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164031/pornhub-upload-limit-blocked-download-nyt-kristof-child-abuse"&gt;banned uploads&lt;/a&gt; by unidentified users and blocked the downloading of videos. It disputed the &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;story, calling the allegations it hosted child sex abuse material “irresponsible and flagrantly untrue.” But on Thursday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168240/mastercard-ending-pornhub-payment-processing-unlawful-videos"&gt;Visa and Mastercard both said they would stop processing payments&lt;/a&gt; on the site as they conducted their own separate investigations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PCjTAg"&gt;In other news... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="oGr3QT"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163104/spacex-starship-prototype-test-flight-boca-chica-altitude"&gt;SpaceX aborts test flight of Starship prototype at one second to liftoff&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="faOcMP"&gt;The test of SpaceX’s next-generation Starship rocket had to abort before taking off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="F30Jiq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22163820/best-gadgets-2020-tech-samsung-apple-ps5-iphone"&gt;The Verge’s Favorite Gadgets of 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="CAf8BL"&gt;The Galaxy Buds Live (aka Galaxy Beans), Oculus Quest 2, and PlayStation 5 all made our list this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="gfWP9i"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166888/apple-airpods-max-design-comfort-price-features"&gt;Apple Airpods Max First Look&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="6PVjLr"&gt;Nilay Patel got a pair of Apple’s new $549 Airpods Max. First impressions: the case leaves a lot to be desired, but the sound quality matches competing— but less expensive— headphones. “Whether Apple has actually done enough here to justify the staggering premium over the competition is an open question that it’ll take us a little more time reviewing to answer,” he writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="KAbKzA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163225/google-fuchsia-os-call-contributors-mailing-list-governance"&gt;Google is still making its mysterious Fuchsia OS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="gdQbtI"&gt;The OS Google announced more than four years ago is still in the works, Dieter Bohn reports, and while the company says it’s not ready for general product development yet, it’s seeking more public contributors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="WFkTH7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168243/among-us-innersloth-new-map-airship-early-2021"&gt;Among Us developers reveal an all-new map, The Airship, coming early 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="8eNQr2"&gt;After winning best multiplayer game of the year at the Game Awards, Innersloth announced a new, more elaborate map for Among Us. Not sus at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TOzGPM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 14 biggest trailers and announcements from The Game Awards 2020","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166109/the-game-awards-2020-announcements-trailers-fortnite-smash-bros-among-us-mass-effect"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oDCQKc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22169555/verge-weekender-disney-cyberpunk-2077-google-gadgets-spacex-vaccine-airpods"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22169555/verge-weekender-disney-cyberpunk-2077-google-gadgets-spacex-vaccine-airpods</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T11:59:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T11:59:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Virgin Galactic aborts first powered spaceflight from New Mexico spaceport</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O-vknPqrRCneKsnLqbdckPAQLCw=/0x1:4000x2668/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68502175/VP01_2_Gliding_Home__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Virgin Galactic’s VSS Unity gliding home during a previous test flight.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Virgin Galactic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="y3CwBc"&gt;This morning, Richard Branson’s space tourism company Virgin Galactic had to abort its first powered test flight of its spaceplane from the company’s home in New Mexico, bringing the vehicle home before it could reach space. During the flight, the spaceplane’s engine cut out too early and the vehicle’s two pilots had to glide back down to the ground early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TH2MVI"&gt;The aborted engine ignition was caught live &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/dasvaldez"&gt;by a Twitch livestream&lt;/a&gt; provided by the outlet &lt;a href="https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/"&gt;NASASpaceflight&lt;/a&gt;. The video showed the spaceplane, called VSS Unity, dropping away from its carrier aircraft in mid-air as planned. The vehicle then briefly ignited its main engine, according to the video, but the ignition cut out after just a moment. On a typical flight, the spaceplane’s engine will stay ignited for a full minute, propelling the vehicle to the edge of space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XIybsK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the ignition cut out after just a moment&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ehgmju"&gt;Once the engine cut out, VSS Unity turned into a glider and returned to its launch site in New Mexico. The company confirmed that VSS Unity landed safely on a runway after the abort, and the flight’s two pilots, C.J. Sturckow and Dave Mackay, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/virgingalactic/status/1337800691075723266"&gt;made it “back safe and sound&lt;/a&gt;.” No passengers were on board this flight, though the vehicle was carrying a number of microgravity payloads for NASA. Virgin Galactic suggested it may replace the engine motor in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bZugZ9"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Early update on flight: The ignition sequence for the rocket motor did not complete.  Vehicle and crew are in great shape. We have several motors ready at Spaceport America. We will check the vehicle and be back to flight soon.&lt;/p&gt;— Virgin Galactic (@virgingalactic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/virgingalactic/status/1337802669482782720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 12, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hCbne9"&gt;Today’s flight was meant to be the third time that Virgin Galactic sent VSS Unity to space and back. The previous two test flights, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/13/18138279/virgin-galactic-vss-unity-spaceshiptwo-space-tourism"&gt;conducted in late 2018&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/22/18232354/virgin-galactic-vss-unity-spaceplane-test-spaceflight-passenger-beth-moses"&gt;early 2019&lt;/a&gt;, took place out of the company’s test facility at the Mojave Air and Spaceport out of California. After those last tests, Virgin Galactic moved its operations to the company’s new, primary home, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/30/21035125/virgin-galactic-spaceport-america-truth-or-consequences-new-mexico"&gt;a glittering facility known as Spaceport America in the New Mexico desert&lt;/a&gt;. It’s from this facility that Virgin Galactic plans to conduct all of its commercial tourist flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JuukbT"&gt;While Virgin Galactic has conducted a few glide flights of VSS Unity from the spaceport before, the vehicle has yet to reach space from the facility. This flight was meant to be an important step as the company prepares to send its first passengers to space on VSS Unity from Spaceport America. With 600 initial customers signed up for flights, Virgin Galactic hopes to start flying commercial passengers for the first time in 2021. Branson, the company’s founder, is supposed to take his first flight next year, kicking off commercial operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="2ZTXeJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With today’s abort, it’s unclear how Virgin Galactic will proceed&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8VvOSE"&gt;With today’s abort, it’s unclear how Virgin Galactic will proceed. If this flight had been a success, Virgin Galactic planned to conduct one more powered test flight before Branson took to the skies. The next flight would have included two test pilots, as well as a “full cabin of mission specialists,” according to the company. Virgin Galactic already flew its first test passenger, Beth Moses, on the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/22/18232354/virgin-galactic-vss-unity-spaceplane-test-spaceflight-passenger-beth-moses"&gt;second spaceflight in February of 2019&lt;/a&gt;. But the company has yet to fly a full cabin on one of these trips. It’s possible that Virgin Galactic may opt to perform a do-over of today’s test first, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4KIUzr"&gt;To get to space, VSS Unity actually takes off in mid-air. A giant carrier aircraft called VMS Eve transports the spaceplane, with its pilots in the cockpit, to a starting altitude of 50,000 feet. From there, VSS Unity falls away and the pilots ignite the vehicle’s main engine, initiating the climb to space. Eventually, the engine shuts off and the passengers on board experience a few minutes of weightlessness, while seeing the curvature of the Earth. To get back home, the pilots then shift the wings on VSS Unity and reenter Earth’s atmosphere, gliding back to the ground and landing on a runway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxejtC"&gt;Virgin Galactic had hoped to fly this test a few weeks earlier, but had to delay after new COVID-19 restrictions were introduced in New Mexico. The company said that today’s flight was “conducted under strict COVID-19 protocols with only essential personnel onsite.” No guests or members of the press were allowed to witness the flight from the spaceport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HFfNNQ"&gt;Once commercial operations begin, Virgin Galactic’s flights will include two test pilots and eventually up to six passengers in the crew cabin. Before they fly, passengers will spend up to three days training at Spaceport America before riding on VSS Unity. The first 600 passengers set to fly with the company have each paid $250,000 for their tickets, though Virgin Galactic claims those prices will change over time. The company also plans to reopen ticket sales sometime next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2RRAis"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171114/virgin-galactic-vss-unity-powered-test-flight-abort-spaceport-america-new-mexico"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171114/virgin-galactic-vss-unity-powered-test-flight-abort-spaceport-america-new-mexico</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T10:43:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T10:43:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter briefly restricts Trump’s disputed election tweets </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pwpu0eqX_k42vGa_5kXxQ9pUElI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68501890/acastro_200715_1777_twitter_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TTdXYq"&gt;It looked like Twitter was adding further restrictions to President Trump’s Twitter account on Saturday, as some users noticed the ability to like, retweet or reply to his tweets with “disputed” labels was not working. Copying the URL to one of the disputed tweets also appeared to be disabled, and quote-tweets were not appearing in search results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eqRaBB"&gt;Some users were able to access and like Trump’s tweets — several &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers confirmed they could engage with “disputed” tweets by clicking through the warning label— but others on Twitter could not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vZu1RU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;OK Based on my probing, for Trumps election fraud tweets:&lt;br&gt;- like, RT, reply, copy URL actions are disabled&lt;br&gt;- all counts disabled&lt;br&gt;- quote tweets allowed, if you click through warning &lt;br&gt;- maybe most importantly: QTs undiscoverable. No visible semantic connections. No search. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Fh7Xg5O5fg"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Fh7Xg5O5fg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ryan D Pants (@sixfoot6) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sixfoot6/status/1337757680388120578?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 12, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eMT9EF"&gt;A Twitter spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Saturday that the platform “inadvertently took action to limit engagements,” on Trump’s tweet and had since reversed the action. Tweets that violate Twitter’s  &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/election-integrity-policy"&gt;Civic Integrity Policy&lt;/a&gt; “will continue to be labeled in order to give more context for anyone who might see the Tweet,” the spokesperson said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pXO5Bq"&gt;Twitter began applying &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/2020-election-changes.html"&gt;“disputed” and other warning labels&lt;/a&gt; to tweets containing election misinformation ahead of the November 3rd US presidential election, and restricting engagement with those tweets. It announced that Tweets with premature claims of victory would be labeled, tweets intended to incite interference in the election or election results could be removed, and tweets from political figures with more than 100,000 followers — which includes President Trump — which receive a “misleading” label will be more difficult to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cLhVBg"&gt;Since the presidential race was called for Joe Biden, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552471/trump-twitter-restricted-false-election-claims-moderation"&gt;President Trump has tweeted numerous falsehoods&lt;/a&gt; about the election, stoking conspiracy theories that it was “rigged,” and claiming there was widespread fraud, without citing evidence. On Saturday, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1337745268591259648?s=20"&gt;he tweeted&lt;/a&gt; “I WON THE ELECTION IN A LANDSLIDE, but remember, I only think in terms of legal votes, not all of the fake voters and fraud that miraculously floated in from everywhere! What a disgrace!” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d6l4sg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/courts_law/supreme-court-texas-election-trump/2020/12/11/bf462f22-3bc6-11eb-bc68-96af0daae728_story.html"&gt;The Supreme Court on Friday rejected a request &lt;/a&gt;from the attorney general of Texas seeking to overturn election results in four key states, the latest unsuccessful attempt by the president and his team to try to change the election results in court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4XsYx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171126/trump-twitter-disputed-tweets-election-retweets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171126/trump-twitter-disputed-tweets-election-retweets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>We did the impossible thing, but not the hard thing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="NHS England Starts Covid-19 Vaccination Campaign" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jT-h33H3-dRpnqLmJvp1lxtlAL4=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68501758/1230031562.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Margaret Keenan, 90, the first patient in the United Kingdom to receive the Pfizer/BioNtech covid-19 vaccine outside of clinical trials gets ready to leave the hospital. | Photo by Jonny Weeks/The Guardian - Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sr3QSO"&gt;When researchers at pharmaceutical companies around the world started developing COVID-19 vaccines, experts reminded everyone to temper expectations. Vaccines usually take years. The frontrunners were made using &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21266897/coronavirus-vaccine-development-strategies-pros-cons"&gt;unproven technology,&lt;/a&gt; and there were dozens of ways things could go wrong. The Food and Drug Administration said it would be fine with anything over 50 percent effective. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUJoCz"&gt;Then, last month, Pfizer announced that it had a vaccine, and it was 95 percent effective. Moderna did too. It was better news than anyone dared hope for. Stéphane Bancel, chief executive at Moderna, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/21/us/politics/coronavirus-vaccine.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; he cried when he first heard the data. With the FDA’s blessing, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21922649"&gt;which came in late Friday night&lt;/a&gt;, health care workers in the United States could start getting shots next week, less than a year after the first case of COVID-19 was documented in the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lvxJbB"&gt;Scientists pulled off the impossible thing, and that’s worth celebrating. It is a remarkable, awe-inspiring achievement. I would say it’s miraculous, but calling it a miracle takes away from the work that went into making it possible — both over the past few months, and during the years of basic research on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeterHotez/status/1336472393271881728"&gt;coronaviruses&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/11/10/the-story-of-mrna-how-a-once-dismissed-idea-became-a-leading-technology-in-the-covid-vaccine-race/"&gt;gene-based vaccines&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="sRmmiC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DpK5PA"&gt;We’re celebrating as much as we are because we need this vaccine to turn the tide of the pandemic. But there’s a sad backstory to this party. We only need this vaccine so desperately because the United States failed at doing the hard, basic public health work. Providing contact tracing, ample testing, masks, gloves, and clear policies aren’t as exciting as the moonshot of a vaccine, but if the US government had done them well, the country wouldn’t have been so reliant on the impossible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yl1K7K"&gt;We’re lucky that the moonshot paid off. There was always a chance it wasn’t going to work, and some vaccines have hit serious roadblocks. On Friday, the drug company Sanofi announced a &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/11/sanofi-suffers-major-setback-in-development-of-a-covid-19-vaccine/"&gt;setback&lt;/a&gt; — it can’t start late-stage clinical trials this month, as planned, and its vaccine won’t be ready until the second half of 2021. There’s a world where Pfizer and Moderna hit snags, too, or where they didn’t work quite as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Hj11S"&gt;Even though they did work, the development of these vaccines took nearly a year. In that year, hundreds of thousands of people in the US died. They didn’t have to. Public health measures are designed to slow the spread of the virus — saving lives, and buying scientists time to develop life-saving vaccines. Doing the hard work would have made it so more people could have survived to benefit from them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b73WrX"&gt;Instead, we’re getting a vaccine just as COVID-19 is surging out of control across the country. Writing in &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, Juliette Kayyem, former assistant secretary in the Department of Homeland Security, said that the rest of the pandemic would unfold on &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/12/moral-imperative-get-vaccination-done-quickly/617310/"&gt;a split screen&lt;/a&gt;. On one side, continuous death and disease. On the other, the start of a vaccination campaign that could keep people safe from the virus. Thursday, an independent committee recommended that the FDA authorize the Pfizer and BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine. That same day, over 3,000 people in the US died from the disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vquXyw"&gt;Here in the US, we’re counting down the days before vaccines are widely available, knowing that every day of delay means more illness and more death. That’s not true everywhere. My dad recently told me that he had a meeting with some people living in Australia, and that he asked them what they thought of the vaccine news. Turns out, they didn’t really care. Australia controlled the pandemic so well that life is essentially &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/davidmack/countries-without-coronavirus-no-covid"&gt;normal&lt;/a&gt; — it doesn’t need a vaccine as an escape hatch. They did the hard thing, so they didn’t have to rely on the impossible.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j6YtlF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;—Nicole Wetsman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BFiCaE"&gt;Here’s what else happened this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xVwNol"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="dB2YnV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/12/11/health/superspreader-covid-boston-biotech-conference/index.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boston biotech conference led to 245,000 Covid-19 cases across US, genetic fingerprinting shows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;A Biogen conference in Boston in February was already known to be a superspreader event. But a new study that looks at genetic samples of the virus shows just how bad the aftermath of that event really was. (Maggie Fox, &lt;em&gt;CNN)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Y1ADqV"&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="fB6BLf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163146/covid-vaccine-fda-review-safe-effective-time-pfizer-biontech"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COVID-19 vaccine starts working within two weeks after first shot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Documents published by the FDA offered a more detailed window into how the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine worked. One key finding: the first shot of the vaccine did seem to provide some protection from the virus. (Nicole Wetsman, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RWVDTM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/11/world/australia/uq-coronavirus-vaccine-false-positive.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Australia Scraps Covid-19 Vaccine That Produced H.I.V. False Positives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Australia canceled its order for an Australian-made vaccine this week. The problem wasn’t that the vaccine didn’t work — it probably did. But it worked by using fragments from a protein found in HIV. Unfortunately, HIV tests were sensitive enough to pick up the antibodies created by the body after patients got the vaccine, resulting in false positives on HIV tests. (Mike Ives/ &lt;em&gt;The New York Times)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QW275v"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2020/12/07/v-safe-tool-covid-vaccine-side-effects/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New smartphone tool to track side effects of the coronavirus vaccine may be vulnerable to manipulation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Experts sounded an early alarm about a tool the CDC plans to use to track side effects of the coronavirus vaccine. They worry it could be easily manipulated. (Lena H. Sun and Isaac Stanley-Becker, &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0uSANf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/07/pledge-to-vaccinate-20-million-against-covid19-in-december-seems-unrealistic/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the ground, the pledge to vaccinate 20 million against Covid-19 in December seems unrealistic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;There’s not that much time left in the year, and a whole lot of vaccinations left to distribute. The US’ lofty goals may not be met by New Years’ Eve. (Olivia Goldhill, &lt;em&gt;STAT&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dI9frG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/08/business/covid-vaccine-oxford-astrazeneca.html?smtyp=cur&amp;amp;amp;smid=tw-nytimes"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blunders Eroded U.S. Confidence in Early Vaccine Front-Runner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is an epic saga of how one promising vaccine candidate made by Oxford and AstraZeneca stumbled badly, pushing it behind candidates produced by competitors Moderna and Pfizer/BioNTech. (Rebecca Robbins, Sharon LaFraniere, Noah Weiland, David D. Kirkpatrick and Benjamin Mueller, &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P33L09"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/people-with-severe-allergies-shouldnt-get-covid-19-vaccine-says-u-k-regulator-after-reactions-11607515727"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two in U.K. Suffer Allergic Reaction to Pfizer’s Covid-19 Vaccine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the FDA met to consider whether or not to approve the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine, regulators in the UK announced that two people had suffered allergic reactions to the vaccine. The regulators said that people with histories of severe allergic reactions should not receive the vaccine. (Joanna Sugden and Bojan Pancevski, &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yyracv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/11/sanofi-suffers-major-setback-in-development-of-a-covid-19-vaccine/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanofi suffers major setback in development of a Covid-19 vaccine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sanofi’s vaccine trial faces a major delay after they discovered that trial participants had been given doses that weren’t strong enough. The setback delays the vaccine’s potential deployment by months. (Helen Branswell/&lt;em&gt;STAT&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Wwv5id"&gt;Perspectives &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="qPpuMY"&gt;I push medications to sedate and paralyze them, and then put a tube through their vocal cords. Looking down at them as they go to sleep, I’m the last person they see. And for the ones who don’t survive, I will have been the only one to hear—or rather, not hear—their last words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="AeFmVn"&gt;—Anesthesiologist Kasey Grewe &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/12/new-york-doctors-know-how-bad-pandemic-can-get/617302/"&gt;writes for &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the grim reality of working in New York hospitals during the spring surge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="kQOPLG"&gt;When Smith’s colleagues couldn’t fit a massive piece of equipment through a door at the company’s headquarters one summer weekend, rather than wait until Monday to submit a work order to facilities, they found a sledgehammer and knocked down the wall themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fLstdy"&gt;— James D Walsh writes about one scientist’s experience working on the Moderna vaccine in &lt;a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2020/12/moderna-covid-19-vaccine-program.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intelligencer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="S0QKdR"&gt;More than Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="enKI4r"&gt;To the more than 70,074,860 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F7S9Fn"&gt;To the families and friends of the 1,590,998 people who have died worldwide — 294,320 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uOP24H"&gt;Stay safe, everyone&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22158376/covid-vaccine-pfizer-public-health-antivirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22158376/covid-vaccine-pfizer-public-health-antivirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
      <name>Mary Beth Griggs</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can still get free Stadia hardware when you buy Cyberpunk 2077</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/egGSH-qtyob_avyBRYXkMI8X6g4=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68501523/Cyberpunk_2077_screen_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nKTJyf"&gt;It’s a different kind of Cyber week. Cyber Monday is in the past, but the anticipated &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; game has finally launched, and it’s almost &lt;em&gt;impossible &lt;/em&gt;to avoid seeing buzz about it online. One of this week’s best deals is aimed right at people who don’t have a console or a beastly gaming PC. The game is available on Google Stadia, and until supplies last, Google is offering a complimentary hardware bundle worth $100 to people who buy &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; on its cloud game streaming platform. Find details on this and a few more deals below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="5WRnMf"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HfuM2f"&gt;Get Stadia hardware when you buy Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GOmCec"&gt;A few &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;writers found that playing &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;actually a fantastic experience&lt;/a&gt; on Stadia, Google’s cloud gaming streaming service that doesn’t require an expensive console or PC — just a controller, a Gmail account, and a strong internet connection. While supplies last, people who buy the $59.99 game through Stadia will get a free Premiere Kit, containing a Stadia controller and a 4K HDR-ready Chromecast Ultra, which is all you need to play games from your TV. It’s a $100 value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VauDUc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9585191"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VJaIHn"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xfKlEt"&gt;Get six months of HBO Max for 20 percent off&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A promotional picture of Wonder Woman 1984" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ePKGrOkaB8tivzdSNnbsVOMze8g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19821876/wonder_woman.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Warner Bros.&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="33tgfd"&gt;Warner Bros. recently announced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"&gt;all of its 2021 films will be released on HBO Max&lt;/a&gt;, for 30 days, at the same time that they’re released in theaters. If that sounds appealing to you, there’s a deal happening that will let you save 20 percent when you prepay for six months of service. The $14.99 per month service would normally cost $90 after half a year, &lt;a href="http://voxmediapartner.go2cloud.org/aff_c?offer_id=2&amp;amp;aff_id=1&amp;amp;aff_sub=verge"&gt;but you can get it for $70&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hEG5M"&gt;Even if you’re in it for the movies alone, the price works out in your favor versus going to the theater. Though, note that this payment is nonrefundable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="NmMYaU"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zTiewp"&gt;Get a great VR headset for $100 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="9VqI0M"&gt;Oculus has reduced the price of its Rift S tethered virtual reality headset by $100, making it $299. This is the biggest price cut yet and could be one of the last opportunities to pick it up since it’s technically discontinued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3attoz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221560"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="sXd4Ks"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="z52RXI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/12/22169431/cyberpunk-2077-google-stadia-deal-free-sale-hbo-max-oculus-rift-s-headset"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/12/22169431/cyberpunk-2077-google-stadia-deal-free-sale-hbo-max-oculus-rift-s-headset</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T23:52:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T23:52:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Get another glimpse inside the PlayStation 5 with iFixit’s new teardown</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The PS5’s pieces after being disassembled " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-mYu4OShJA-WX2f77wk14yuB-t8=/0x67:1600x1134/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68500683/3MqFL2AQmEZugiii.huge.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: iFixit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eGwg8C"&gt;iFixit has &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FTeardown%2FPlayStation%2B5%2BTeardown%2F138280%3Fvgo_ee%3D3bheJeT%252FPRsWKKl8dfWh0vlMy%252BOWWuyaZunZiCXh6gI%253D&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F11%2F22170536%2Fifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;released its teardown of the PlayStation 5&lt;/a&gt; and its DualSense controller — and it goes into even more detail than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505598/sony-ps5-playstation-5-tear-down-hardware"&gt;the one Sony did earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. The gadget repair company discovered that the console has a ton of screws holding it together, and that there’s a weird catch to replacing the optical drive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An x-ray image of the Playstation 5" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZbW9pl2FPKwHtX9Z_zSsS87cCEE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22164030/mt1GGBDVuMOiI22J.huge.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Creative Electron (via iFixit)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The company also released a always-fun X-ray of the PS5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="y91UFz"&gt;It turns out that the optical drive is software-locked to the motherboard. The physical swap is apparently a piece of cake, but any replacement you put in won’t read disks, so if your optical drive fails you’ll be sending it to Sony. It’s a bummer, especially for me: I’ve had terrible luck with PlayStation optical drives, and the only drive I haven’t had to replace is the one on my PS4 (which was only a few years old when I sold it). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYa5ZD"&gt;No sweat for the owners of the discless Digital edition, though — and as we’ve seen previously, adding an extra SSD is going to be easy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551165/sony-ps5-playstation-5-no-m2-ssd-expansion-launch"&gt;when the console finally supports it&lt;/a&gt;: it only involves unclipping a single side panel and taking out a screw.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The PS5’s power supply" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MhPu3s3lPkVqXaFDQr1PgePIbt8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22164085/Qx2tDqSSJ6DC5inI.huge.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: iFixit&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="O3Mg8c"&gt;The teardown also provides an inside look at the power supply (above), which Sony didn’t show us before. As someone who’s dabbled in PC gaming, it’s always shocking to me when I’m reminded of the PS5 only has a 350W power supply (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nRGNfqVvPtk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=287"&gt;and it uses as few as 200 of those watts&lt;/a&gt; under load!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A picture of the DualSense with the back taken off" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j35cEPc3CVTTPXvwxbrw6aq2T1o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22164070/eLQUaWaTxpN4JIWt.huge.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: iFixit&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;To me, the inside of the controller looks nicer than Cyberpunk does on the console.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1DpKFs"&gt;Turning to the DualSense controller, iFixit found its battery is relatively easy to replace — which is good considering it still uses an internal Li-ion that’ll degrade over time. It’s also &lt;em&gt;massive &lt;/em&gt;at 5.7 watt-hours, compared to the 3.7Wh pack in the DualShock 4. Those adaptive triggers and haptic feedback motors must be thirsty. We also get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/3/21547303/sony-ps5-dualsense-adaptive-triggers-haptics-teardown-features"&gt;another look&lt;/a&gt; at the awesome screw drive that powers those adaptive triggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZURv6J"&gt;What I don’t see is an easy way to unhook the LEDs that surround the DualSense’s touchpad. This may be a niche thing, but I absolutely hated the light on the DualShock 4, and while the new one isn’t as annoying, I still wish Sony would let you turn it off or let screwdriver-handy gamers unhook it without so much fuss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aR1e5T"&gt;You can head over &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FTeardown%2FPlayStation%2B5%2BTeardown%2F138280%3Fvgo_ee%3D3bheJeT%252FPRsWKKl8dfWh0vlMy%252BOWWuyaZunZiCXh6gI%253D&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F11%2F22170536%2Fifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to iFixit’s teardown page to see far more photos&lt;/a&gt;. And if you want a feel for what taking apart the devices might be like (without risking what’s now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;effectively a $1,000 console&lt;/a&gt;), the company has provided videos of the teardowns that you can watch below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uxMQfB"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r-rxy1rq2s8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="SH17fT"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/viqj_MWjb4I?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=2&amp;amp;start=2" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="WYRtsA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PlayStation 5: everything you need to know about Sony’s newest consoles","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21450334/playstation-5-ps5-sony-news-price-features-specs-hardware-games"},{"title":"Sony’s PS5 teardown video reveals removable sides, dust catchers, and storage expansion","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505598/sony-ps5-playstation-5-tear-down-hardware"},{"title":"Sony will optimize PS5 fan performance with software updates using individual game data","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/19/21522991/sony-ps5-fan-optimize-update-game-performance-data"},{"title":"The PS5’s new controller is amazing — here’s how it works","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/3/21547303/sony-ps5-dualsense-adaptive-triggers-haptics-teardown-features"},{"title":"Sony confirms the PS5 won’t support SSD storage expansion at launch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551165/sony-ps5-playstation-5-no-m2-ssd-expansion-launch"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170536/ifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170536/ifixit-teardown-playstation-5-dualsense-controller-gamepad</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T21:28:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T21:28:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>FDA authorizes first COVID-19 vaccine in US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Coronavirus - Wed Dec 9, 2020" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xpQrz1zF16wvrwFHfnb9nqck9gc=/4x0:4492x2992/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68500375/1230031767.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nurse in Belfast prepares a dose of the vaccine.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Liam McBurney / PA Images via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5A4HDt"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration has &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/144412/download"&gt;authorized &lt;/a&gt;the use of a COVID-19 vaccine developed by Pfizer and BioNTech, a landmark moment in the fight to suppress a virus that has killed nearly 300,000 people in the United States and sickened tens of millions around the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Zfj5m"&gt;“Today’s emergency use authorization of the Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 Vaccine holds the promise to alter the course of this pandemic in the United States,” Peter Marks, director of the FDA’s Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-takes-key-action-fight-against-covid-19-issuing-emergency-use-authorization-first-covid-19"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Z6n2O"&gt;The vaccine is authorized in the US for people over the age of 16. It was found to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573072/pfizer-vaccine-effective-authorization-fda-safe"&gt;95 percent effective&lt;/a&gt; at preventing symptomatic COVID-19 in clinical trials. “That is extraordinary,” Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nowthisnews/status/1333146966985908224"&gt;said in a press conference&lt;/a&gt; at the end of November. It’s far better than experts had dared hope for. The FDA was prepared to authorize a vaccine as long as it was at least 50 percent effective. “We were shocked,” Pfizer’s chief executive officer, Albert Bourla, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/21/us/politics/coronavirus-vaccine.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We couldn’t believe it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEFgKD"&gt;The shot appears to protect people against the most severe forms of the disease. It is also highly effective in people over the age of 65, who are particularly vulnerable to COVID-19. Scientists will continue to monitor the vaccine after it’s deployed to see how well it works in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="NquwhR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Scientists will continue to monitor the vaccine after it’s deployed&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cqNna2"&gt;The news of the clearance comes at the same time that the FDA has faced public pressure from the White House to authorize the vaccine. Chief of Staff Mark Meadows told Stephen Hahn, the commissioner of the FDA, to resign if the vaccine was not cleared by Friday, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2020/12/11/trump-stephen-hahn-fda-covid-vaccine/"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. The agency had originally planned to complete the authorization by Saturday. On Thursday, an independent committee said it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168565/covid-19-vaccine-independent-committee-recommends-authorization"&gt;recommended authorization&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kAeSxQ"&gt;The Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine has already been authorized by regulatory authorities in the United Kingdom, Canada, and Bahrain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YUchFa"&gt;The authorizations of this vaccine, which have come less than a year after development began, shatter the record for the fastest vaccine developed. The record was previously held by the mumps vaccine, which took four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ttI8Gt"&gt;Researchers were able to condense the normally years-long vaccine development process into months by, among other steps, shortening the time between clinical trial phases and scaling up manufacturing of potential candidates as trials were ongoing. Companies did not skip steps in the safety testing process, though. The FDA said that it needed to see &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2020/10/06/health/fda-covid-vaccine-safety-data-bn/index.html"&gt;two full months&lt;/a&gt; of safety data on any COVID-19 vaccine because that’s the window when most dangerous side effects could occur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2wJm2K"&gt;The vaccine will be made available under an Emergency Use Authorization, a designation that lets the FDA make products available during an emergency situation when there are no other options available. The process lets the agency sidestep some of the more lengthy regulatory steps it usually needs to formally approve or license a pharmaceutical. It typically takes the FDA a &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/fullarticle/2772943"&gt;full year&lt;/a&gt; to review vaccine data once it’s submitted by companies. For this emergency authorization, that was condensed to a few weeks; Pfizer and BioNTech submitted their data on November 20th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tsu4jG"&gt;The Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine is made from a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562309/pfizer-coronavirus-vaccine-gene-based"&gt;gene-based technology&lt;/a&gt; that’s never been used before in an authorized vaccine for people. It contains a tiny bit of the genetic material for the coronavirus spike protein, which the virus uses to enter cells. The body builds that spike protein from the genetic instructions and then generates defenses against it. The Moderna vaccine, which the FDA’s vaccine advisory committee will review on December 17th, also uses this technology. The platform is another reason why the vaccine was developed so quickly — once researchers have the genetic sequence of a virus, it’s relatively easy to design a gene-based vaccine to attack it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gsMPJY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Now starts an equally daunting task: distributing the vaccine and vaccinating people. &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yc9zGf"&gt;Now starts an equally daunting task: distributing the vaccine and vaccinating people. Pfizer’s vaccine has to stay at ultracold temperatures, which makes shipping it around the country and the world more challenging. Doses of the vaccine will also be limited through the start of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MKEwX3"&gt;Health care workers and residents in long-term care facilities will be the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21779433/covid-vaccine-priority-health-care-workers-long-term-care"&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; to receive the vaccine, and doses could be administered within days. Other high-risk groups, including older adults and people with underlying health conditions, will likely be next in line. On the most optimistic timeline, vaccinations for the general population could start in March or April, but hospitals say that some of those timelines &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/12/07/pledge-to-vaccinate-20-million-against-covid19-in-december-seems-unrealistic/"&gt;seem unrealistic&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flmYG0"&gt;The US has purchased 100 million doses of the Pfizer and BioNTech vaccine, enough to vaccinate 50 million people. The Trump administration &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/feds-pfizer-vaccine-doses-covid-19-88fd7c59fd0af8669ed3cdafdf08881e"&gt;reportedly declined&lt;/a&gt; an offer to secure an additional 100 million doses this summer. Although the US can acquire up to 500 million more doses, the rejected offer means they may not be available until the summer. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22158608/fda-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-authorized-emergency-use"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22158608/fda-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-authorized-emergency-use</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-11T20:55:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T20:55:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s long-struggling developers will see their bonuses after all</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iqRGhnhlDruA7bdIQQXbCG_xF1E=/65x0:299x156/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68500312/screen_image_mercenary_01_1x_20ad7dfe.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6J9IwN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, CD Projekt Red’s latest game,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;has been in development for nearly a decade. It was first announced &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2012/05/30/cd-projekt-red-announces-cyberpunk"&gt;in May 2012&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s had a rocky development cycle, with numerous delays and, in the final stretch of development, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494499/cyberpunk-2077-development-crunch-time-cd-projekt-red"&gt;a required six-day workweek&lt;/a&gt;. But despite the long development, the game didn’t review quite as well as CDPR wanted, meaning developers who had been toiling for years could have been on the brink of losing performance bonuses that were tied to review scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9JoqP"&gt;The studio’s developers won’t have to worry about review scores anymore, though: CDPR will now pay full performance bonuses regardless of the critical reception of the game, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-11/cd-projekt-changes-developer-bonus-structure-after-buggy-release"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8Ji7y4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We underestimated the lengths and complexity involved to make this a reality”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gql0RN"&gt;“We initially had a bonus system that was focused on the game’s ratings and the release date, but after consideration, we believe that measure is simply not fair under the circumstances,” Adam Badowski, studio head and creative director for &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, said in an email to staff obtained by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;. “We underestimated the lengths and complexity involved to make this a reality, and still you did everything you could to deliver an ambitious, special game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kU3wV5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; received favorable reviews this week — it currently has a &lt;a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pc/cyberpunk-2077"&gt;Metacritic score&lt;/a&gt; of 90 out of 100, which typically indicates that a game is very good. By contrast, some of the top games of this year &lt;a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game"&gt;edge it out&lt;/a&gt; with Metacritic scores in the low 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6PGsA9"&gt;But reviewers &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2020-12-11-cyberpunk-2077-launches-with-some-real-dystopia-in-tow-opinion"&gt;reportedly weren’t&lt;/a&gt; given review code for the console versions of the game, and there are now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;numerous reports&lt;/a&gt; of bugs and issues when playing &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; on older consoles. Given the current problems players are now finding, &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077’s&lt;/em&gt; Metacritic score could easily fall below 90 as more publications post reviews. If it falls below that score, developers wouldn’t have received their bonuses under the previous system, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ODYEh4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NEWS: CD Projekt executives took responsibility for Cyberpunk's buggy launch in an email to staff today, saying this year's performance bonuses will no longer be tied to review scores, given the circumstances. Before, the threshold was 90+ on Metacritic &lt;a href="https://t.co/poW86s3xaf"&gt;https://t.co/poW86s3xaf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jason Schreier (@jasonschreier) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasonschreier/status/1337555816417800194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 12, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tLSTEQ"&gt;CDPR leaders would hand out tokens every month to staffers who went above and beyond, and those tokens were supposed to be transferrable into bonuses if the game met “certain criteria, like critical acclaim and a timely release,” according to the report. Now, though, it sounds as if all staffers will get their performance bonuses no matter where the review score lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Hcc2y"&gt;CDPR didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IWpXRl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; has been a big retail success, despite the reviews and buggy release. It sold more than 8 million preorders, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CDPROJEKTRED_IR/status/1336941257965375489"&gt;according to CDPR&lt;/a&gt;, completely making back its development and marketing budget on day one. It also broke Steam’s concurrent player record for a single-player PC game, with more than one million concurrent players &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteamDB/status/1336924375212318721?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1336924375212318721%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.engadget.com%2Fcyberpunk-2077-beats-steam-record-for-concurrent-players-121942545.html"&gt;on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rGOko4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077’s 1.04 patch makes changes to reduce epilepsy risk ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"},{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 is huge, ambitious, and safe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"},{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 shines on next-gen consoles and Stadia, but older hardware struggles","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WCRrOq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o1KPok"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y0HLFR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yu9zUX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5kC556"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170655/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-developers-staff-bonuses-review-score"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170655/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-developers-staff-bonuses-review-score</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
