<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-09T20:45:20-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T20:45:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T20:45:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Idris Elba failed to make Knuckles not sound sexy in the first Sonic the Hedgehog 2 trailer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0UkFVsQ_VJlac4MxD8uH33ZK2J8=/423x0:1815x928/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252808/Screen_Shot_2021_12_09_at_8.39.34_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ki1Qmc"&gt;Sonic The Hedgehog 2, follow-up to Paramount Pictures &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/13/21133092/sonic-the-hedgehog-movie-review-paramount"&gt;surprisingly good&lt;/a&gt; live-action adaptation of Sega’s beloved speedy rodent platformer, has a new trailer. The trailer, announced during tonight’s Game Awards broadcast featureed Sonic trying to fit into his new life on Earth and his first encounter with Knuckles, voiced by Idris Elba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ieTeDx"&gt;Ben Schwartz will reprise his role as the titular Sonic, while Jim Carrey will once again look like he’s having so much fun playing Sonic’s mortal enemy Dr. Robotnik. During the first movie’s post-credits scene, Tails made a brief appearance, alluding he might play a role in the inevitable sequel. On December 7th, Tails’ long-time voice actor Colleen O’Shaughnessey, confirmed &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VOColleen/status/1468305802687483911"&gt;she will be voicing Sonic’s sidekick&lt;/a&gt;, presumably because Chris Pratt had a scheduling conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lED3Dz"&gt;Days before the trailer’s Game Awards debut, Paramount Pictures released the movie’s poster featuring Sonic and Dr. Robotnik with Tails piloting his signature biplane. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ovjuvm"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The first poster for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SonicMovie2?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SonicMovie2&lt;/a&gt; has arrived! And that’s not all – The world premiere of the new &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SonicMovie2?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SonicMovie2&lt;/a&gt; trailer drops tomorrow in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thegameawards?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TheGameAwards&lt;/a&gt; at 8pm ET. &lt;a href="https://t.co/dDZzd8EoG5"&gt;pic.twitter.com/dDZzd8EoG5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sonic the Hedgehog (@SonicMovie) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SonicMovie/status/1468581182979776513?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="96iOR4"&gt;In August, Paramount revealed international superstar and all around handsome chap &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618880/idris-elba-knuckles-voice-actor-sonic-the-hedgehog-2"&gt;Idris Elba had been cast&lt;/a&gt; as Sonic’s frenemy Knuckles the Echidna. The trailer gave audiences their first listen of Elba as Knuckles, a character Elba said &lt;a href="https://screencrush.com/idris-elba-knuckles-sexy-voice/"&gt;he’d try  not to make sound sexy&lt;/a&gt;. Well, he failed as Idris Elba can’t &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;sound sexy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3iZF0s"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sonic The Hedgehog 2&lt;/em&gt; hits theaters April 8th, here’s hoping the movie features some kind of industrial liquid manufacturing center... a chemical plant zone if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826714/sonic-the-hedgehog-2-movie-trailer-the-game-awards"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826714/sonic-the-hedgehog-2-movie-trailer-the-game-awards</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T20:42:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T20:42:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Monolith is making a Wonder Woman game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OuAcfadNGgSM4uqLY71IaD23CZE=/61x0:1438x918/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252798/Screen_Shot_2021_12_09_at_8.28.18_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman will star in her own video game.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Monolith Productions&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WBLUvC"&gt;Wonder Woman will be starring in her own game developed by Monolith Productions, a studio best-known for &lt;em&gt;Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Middle-earth: Shadow of War. &lt;/em&gt;The new game was announced at The Game Awards on Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vvvBk7"&gt;Basically no details were revealed about the game — all we were given was a brief CGI trailer showing Wonder Woman and a title card — so we don’t know what type of game it will be, when the game might come out, or even a release window. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4zJVQD"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;She will fight to unite the warriors of two worlds. You are Wonder Woman. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WonderWoman?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#WonderWoman&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WonderWomanGame?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#WonderWomanGame&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/uQY8xF8wS5"&gt;pic.twitter.com/uQY8xF8wS5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Warner Bros. Games (@wbgames) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wbgames/status/1469117231485177856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C9FKn7"&gt;Wonder Woman has had a resurgence lately due to Gal Gadot’s portrayals of her in the &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt;, and other movies in the DC Comics universe. It’s unclear if she’ll be voicing the superhero in the upcoming video game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J6MZV8"&gt;DC Comics is currently celebrating Wonder Woman’s 80th anniversary, and the comic book company has released a new book &lt;a href="https://www.dccomics.com/comics/wonder-woman-80th-anniversary-100-page-super-spectacular-2021/wonder-woman-80th-anniversary"&gt;in honor of the milestone&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22827161/wonder-woman-game-warner-bros-monolith-productions-the-game-awards"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22827161/wonder-woman-game-warner-bros-monolith-productions-the-game-awards</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T20:28:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T20:28:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Best Buy pulls TCL Google TVs amid complaints of slow, buggy software</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/speHBcienQnWeFQXFBYRIf-kme4=/20x0:2168x1432/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70251693/327063D4_692F_4275_A45A_6A2026E0BFEF.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VaLJJm"&gt;Back in late summer, TCL announced an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22616941/tcl-6-5-series-google-tv-price-specs"&gt;upgraded version of its high-end 6-Series TV&lt;/a&gt;. Aside from some technical improvements — the newer set fully supports HDMI 2.1 and 4K gaming at 120Hz — the biggest change had to do with software, with the latest 6-Series running Google TV instead of the Roku OS that has shipped on many of TCL’s most popular sets in the United States. The company has already released TVs powered by Android TV internationally and on a few budget models in North America, but the 2021 6-Series was meant to be a combined showcase for TCL hardware and Google software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fkl6Du"&gt;So far, it’s not working out that way, and things aren’t going quite as well as TCL might’ve hoped. Best Buy — the exclusive US retailer of the TCL Google TVs — has abruptly removed both models from its store listings, and TCL confirms to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that there are issues being ironed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XqmHWT"&gt;Some early buyers of the 6-Series with Google TV (model R646) have complained about what they describe as a buggy, sluggish user interface. I myself have been reviewing a 65-inch model over the past couple weeks, and while the Google TV home screen seems to work relatively well, it didn’t take long for me to notice some general slowness when pulling up and going through the settings menu. There can also be a lag before the TV reacts to remote control commands. My roommates have observed crashing apps and a few instances where the TV itself froze and became unresponsive. Some online reviews cite more annoying problems that require unplugging the TV altogether. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qAcBz9"&gt;Similar early criticisms have also been leveled at the 5-Series with Google TV; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1RPvpz5H0U4"&gt;Caleb at &lt;em&gt;Digital Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found his review unit to be on the slow side and ran into several bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZeQ5novFx3uBWAhquLlHq4PFo-s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23076791/E4A32016_080D_41C0_8688_6F461E5E3C4E.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tcltvs/comments/r9yiux/will_the_google_tv_os_get_faster_on_the_s546_new/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=ios_app&amp;amp;utm_name=iossmf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reddit thread&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; about the 5-Series with Google TV is equally applicable to the 6-Series.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ulo5vT"&gt;TCL has already rolled out several software updates meant to improve performance and stability. “Our priority is to deliver an optimized user experience with Google TV and have a cadence of planned software updates for TCL devices,” TCL spokesperson Rachelle Parks told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in late November. Some of those updates do seem to have made a positive difference, and Parks told us in a statement on Thursday that “customers will see marked improvements in the weeks to come.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y5nH2w"&gt;But as of this week, Best Buy removed both of those models from its store listings. &lt;a href="https://www.tcl.com/us/en/products/home-theater/6-series/55-class-6-series-4k-qled-hdr-smart-google-tv-55r646"&gt;TCL’s own website&lt;/a&gt; has a link to Best Buy that no longer works. Prior to the removal, the 65-inch 6-Series I’m testing &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Freviews%2Ftcl-65-class-6-series-mini-led-qled-4k-uhd-smart-google-tv%2F6470277&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;had an average review rating of 3.5 stars&lt;/a&gt;. Many reviews praise the panel and Mini LED picture quality but go on to list issues encountered with the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JAbZMa"&gt;TCL confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it’s aware “some are facing challenges with the stability of the user interface” and yet, that the company expects these TVs to be “available again in the coming weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9JZP4P"&gt;While TCL is familiar with Android TV, the Google TV software experience is new territory for the company, and clearly, it’s having a rough go at this early stage. I hope a lot of the performance issues can be ironed out with more updates; this really is a fantastic TV, with terrific peak brightness and excellent contrast thanks to that Mini LED backlighting. But it’s not where it needs to be right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cX4StJ"&gt;In fact, I’ve already gone ahead and plugged an Apple TV 4K into one of the HDMI ports just to avoid the sluggishness and jank. Streaming devices are a great way to speed up budget TVs, but they shouldn’t be a necessary bandaid for a TV with an MSRP of over $1,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S60Fdn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has reached out to Best Buy for more details. This could be a supply shortage situation (though it’d be odd for the pages to completely vanish in that case), or maybe TCL is taking a beat to assess next steps for its new Google TVs to turn around their buggy early reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HK7dTq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 9th, 8:28PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added information from TCL about software updates and availability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826619/tcl-6-5-series-google-tv-best-buy-removal-os-bugs-slow"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826619/tcl-6-5-series-google-tv-best-buy-removal-os-bugs-slow</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T20:23:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T20:23:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Star Wars: Eclipse is a new action-adventure game set in the High Republic era from Quantic Dream</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dwHtgS4nevlua6DUakcxbjY7who=/720x0:3120x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252752/star_wars_eclipse_still_17.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xSXDCj"&gt;Quantic Dream’s rumored Star Wars title has been officially announced at the 2021 Game Awards: &lt;a href="https://starwarseclipse.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Eclipse&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which will be set in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21152444/star-wars-the-high-republic-books-comics-jedi-knights-publishing-interconnected"&gt;“High Republic” era&lt;/a&gt; of the Star Wars universe, hundreds of years before the Skywalker Saga during the golden age of the Jedi Order and the Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DMJHUi"&gt;The High Republic began as an ambitious multimedia project last year, but until now has mostly been focused on an interconnected series of books and comics exploring the Jedi Order and its fight with the Nihil, a new faction of marauders who use unique hyperspace technology to raid across the galaxy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tflJT6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Star Wars: The High Republic is a new series of books and comics about the golden age of the Jedi","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21152444/star-wars-the-high-republic-books-comics-jedi-knights-publishing-interconnected"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WSJsXT9xyLNYbZdOIF3we9qdfCA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23077646/star_wars_eclipse_still_13.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="p1qTaT"&gt;Quantic Dream is best known for its interactive narrative titles, including &lt;em&gt;Heavy Rain, Beyond: Two Souls&lt;/em&gt;, and the somewhat controversial &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/19/15815190/detroit-become-human-david-cage-e3-2017-violence"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detroit: Become Human&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It sounds like &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Eclipse &lt;/em&gt;will be a different affair from the studio’s usual titles, though, with the company promising an “action-adventure” title, although no gameplay was shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MaN5y5"&gt;While details are slim on the upcoming title, the new game promises that players will “play as a diverse cast of charismatic characters, each with their own story, abilities, and role to play in the tapestry of events that could alter the carefully balanced peace of the Outer Rim.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5VoXJJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Eclipse&lt;/em&gt; is being developed together with Lucasfilm Games, and is said to still be in “early development,” so there’s no release window yet. No platforms were announced for the upcoming title yet, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eNwwVH"&gt;It’s not the only major Star Wars title in the works, either: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665460/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-ps5-darth-revan"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic Remake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was announced earlier this year for Playstation 5 and PC, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227235/ubisoft-star-wars-game-massive-entertainment-lucasfilm"&gt;Ubisoft’s Massive Entertainment is working on an open-world game&lt;/a&gt; set in the Star Wars universe. There’s also a sequel to 2019’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/15/20965741/star-wars-jedi-fallen-order-review-xbox-ps4-pc-respawn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; rumored to be development, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6G2bWq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22827178/quantic-dream-star-wars-eclipse-high-republic-announcement-game-awards"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22827178/quantic-dream-star-wars-eclipse-high-republic-announcement-game-awards</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T20:01:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T20:01:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Taco Bell had beef with Beyond Meat’s fake carne asada</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Taco Bell Struggles With Ingredients Shortage Due To Supply Transport Issues" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d8Y8jxPMTW2awMwnx0zT9qcX3NM=/0x0:6240x4160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252679/1329911498.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Spencer Platt/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2hUjQZ"&gt;Taco Bell, the restaurant known for having ground beef that's utterly indescribable, reportedly told Beyond Meat that its version of carne asada wasn’t good enough to serve. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-09/taco-bell-abandoned-plan-to-test-beyond-meat-s-carne-asada?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the chain canceled a test product that featured Beyond’s plant-based steak after samples failed to live up to its standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fx3q8s"&gt;The report doesn’t make it clear what the company wasn’t fond of — was it the texture? The taste? Was it just too high-end for Taco Bell, seeming more like something you’d find at a Chipotle rather than the restaurant known as the place you drunkenly get 2 AM takeout and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319868/taco-bell-nfts-gif-tacos-sell"&gt;NFTs&lt;/a&gt;? Whatever the case, people on Twitter have been having an absolute field day with the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jTXvu1"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"We already figured out how to make our stuff without real meat" &lt;a href="https://t.co/n5WQG1Ba8I"&gt;https://t.co/n5WQG1Ba8I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mike Nelson (@mikenelson586) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikenelson586/status/1469067547135856660?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="yDTmqi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;lol how bad did it taste for taco bell to say 'that's gonna be a no from us, dawg'? &lt;a href="https://t.co/4Pnzq8T3ej"&gt;https://t.co/4Pnzq8T3ej&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Fidel Martinez (@fidmart85) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fidmart85/status/1469075289560928258?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="2dVNgY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="in" dir="ltr"&gt;Carne nah-sada&lt;/p&gt;— Clementine Fletcher (@clemfletch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/clemfletch/status/1469062280096718850?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="pTEtco"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;That's a bummer but also wouldn't be that big of a deal if they actually subbed out the meat for black beans with 100% accuracy when I ask.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;My good Taco Bell is at about 85% and my bad one is at about 50%. &lt;a href="https://t.co/NUO1IWUvoQ"&gt;https://t.co/NUO1IWUvoQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ring My Bell (@RingMyBellPod) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RingMyBellPod/status/1469067305300598787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cShyL2"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, the two companies are still planning on working together to add plant-based meat to the menu, promising that it’d be something “entirely new.” Taco Bell is also testing out its own plant-based protein similar to its ground beef at some restaurants, &lt;a href="https://thebeet.com/taco-bell-is-testing-vegan-meat-at-nearly-100-us-locations/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Beet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (though &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/review-taco-bell-new-plant-based-meat-cravetarian-2021-4"&gt;one writer from &lt;em&gt;Insider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; described it as “very disappointing”) . Beyond Meat did, however, reportedly let go of two employees who worked on the carne asada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n0OQRX"&gt;A few other restaurants are currently trialing Beyond Meat products — the most notable is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728805/mcdonalds-mcplant-beyond-meat-burger-test"&gt;the McPlant from McDonalds&lt;/a&gt;, but Panda Express and KFC are also working on chicken-like products with Beyond as well. While some may read Taco Bell’s trial cancelation as bad news for vegetarians, the chain already sells the perfect meatless fast-food dish: the spicy potato taco, which makes up a far larger percentage of my diet than I’d care to admit.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22827004/taco-bell-beyond-meat-carne-asada-test-canceled-plant-based-fast-food"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22827004/taco-bell-beyond-meat-carne-asada-test-canceled-plant-based-fast-food</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T19:37:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T19:37:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s live-action Cowboy Bebop is canceled </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="‘Cowboy Bebop’ cast" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4qp9NTTr_wfkv361cePuNBg3sBA=/0x252:2400x1852/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252399/COWBOYBEB_ArtDept_01192RC4__1__long.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;‘Cowboy Bebop’ cast | NICOLA DOVE/NETFLIX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eT6bPt"&gt;Netflix has canceled its live-action adaptation of the &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;/em&gt; anime. The show, starring Jon Cho as Spike Spiegel, will not be renewed for a second season, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/cowboy-bebop-canceled-netflix-1235060256/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Though a lot of shows on Netflix are not renewed, &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt; alluded to the show’s poor reception as the reason for its abrupt cancellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jIbgu7"&gt;Reviews of &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;/em&gt; generally criticized the show’s weak pacing and cheap-looking costumes and sets, while it also failed to capture the essence of what made the 1996 anime one of the best examples of the genre. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s Andrew Webster &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22776962/cowboy-bebop-review-netflix"&gt;said the show&lt;/a&gt; eventually grew on him after failing in the first episodes while I, a &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;/em&gt; superfan, thought the show took some weird but interesting risks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VYYwX9"&gt;The live-action adaptation &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22463620/netflix-live-action-cowboy-bebop-release-date-john-cho"&gt;was originally announced in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, but production was delayed nearly a year due to an ACL injury John Cho suffered on the set, followed by the pandemic. After the news broke, Cho &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JohnTheCho/status/1469099377298132992"&gt;sent this tweet&lt;/a&gt;, a GIF with the caption “I’m okay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="c7KsRk"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/4xnUaQYU1u"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4xnUaQYU1u&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— John Cho (@JohnTheCho) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JohnTheCho/status/1469099377298132992?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bYzUPC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;/em&gt; premiered three weeks ago after dropping several trailers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22691323/cowboy-bebop-netflix-opening-title-sequence-watch"&gt;and a video of the opening title sequence&lt;/a&gt;, which was a shot-for-shot remake of the anime’s iconic opening theme. There will be some plotlines that will be left hanging (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6yyWgfLbW-M"&gt;Radical Edward!&lt;/a&gt;) by the sudden end of the show, but at least we got new Yoko Kanno music to enjoy, so the show’s cancellation isn’t a total loss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qU5cdm"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yq2N-9EmedA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RUjfFv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt; is currently producing a series with Netflix.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p29G1N"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 9th, 7:35PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added tweet from John Cho.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22827010/cowboy-bebop-netflix-live-action-cancel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22827010/cowboy-bebop-netflix-live-action-cancel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T18:37:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T18:37:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Epic Games Store finally has a shopping cart</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ksz9IsGVBTIvh_IWCnCoorgzAjY=/0x0:1394x929/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252422/Screen_Shot_2021_12_09_at_3.05.00_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;While shopping, you can now add things to a cart.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ADbRY6"&gt;The Epic Games Store finally has a shopping cart, &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/news/introducing-the-epic-games-store-shopping-cart"&gt;Epic announced Thursday&lt;/a&gt;, meaning you’re now able to buy multiple games in a single transaction. The feature arrives just over three years after the store’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/4/18124203/epic-games-fortnite-valve-steam-game-store-distribution-unreal-engine"&gt;December 2018 launch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7gumAi"&gt;As you’re shopping on the store, you’ll now see an “Add to Cart” button, which lets you, well, add something to your cart. According to Epic’s blog, you’ll be able to add free games and paid ones into your cart at the same time, “all in one shopping spree.” If you want to skip the cart, you can alternately hit the “Buy Now” button. And if you don’t want to buy something at all just yet, you can always wishlist it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vKYyDxHQAub9c8KvC5BqHIvLtw8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23077341/epic_games_store_shopping_cart_checkout_eae661cb82fd.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Epic Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Here’s an example of what the cart looks like, though I don’t recommend paying full price for &lt;/em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SHR3mt"&gt;Epic continues to offer free games every week, so this will make it a bit easier to claim them for your account. And beginning next week, Epic is rumored to be giving away &lt;a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/the-epic-games-store-will-reportedly-give-away-15-free-games-over-christmas/"&gt;15 free games for the holidays&lt;/a&gt;, so the new cart could be arriving just in time for that promotion (and for any last-minute holiday shopping).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HYcTLk"&gt;In the meantime, you might want to pick up the excellent &lt;em&gt;Tetris Effect&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/tetris-effect"&gt;which is 35 percent off&lt;/a&gt; on the Epic Games Store until December 11th at 11AM ET.  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826563/epic-games-store-shopping-cart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826563/epic-games-store-shopping-cart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T18:15:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T18:15:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Coinbase will let users earn interest on crypto but not in the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MKEvjgThbQ0l3a6P5ZqH1nCYvGk=/40x0:1240x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252320/1__9_tE5HVEXnSUwgJs75nUw.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hh7Dq6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/coinbase-makes-it-easy-to-earn-yield-with-defi-bd38156e2715"&gt;Coinbase has announced&lt;/a&gt; that it’ll let users earn interest on their cryptocurrency by lending it to a decentralized finance app called Compound (&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-09/coinbase-launches-defi-yield-product-for-non-u-s-customers"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The program isn’t currently available to US users, though, after plans for a similar feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684169/coinbase-crypto-lend-feature-discontinued-sec-lawsuit-threats"&gt;got the company into trouble&lt;/a&gt; with the Securities and Exchange Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BEqbrI"&gt;Coinbase says that customers in over 70 countries will be able to lend their Dai, a stablecoin whose value is tied to the US dollar, to borrowers from within its app. The process works using a protocol called Compound, which programmatically pools money from lenders and collects interest on that money from borrowers. Coinbase’s pitch is that it makes the system more user-friendly — lending through Compound &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kraken.com%2Fen-us%2Flearn%2Fwhat-is-compound-comp&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F9%2F22826888%2Fcoinbase-defi-interest-non-us-compound-lending-program" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;usually involves&lt;/a&gt; receiving multiple tokens when you make a deposit and paying transaction fees whenever you put crypto in or take it out (Coinbase says it’ll be covering these fees for its users).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YJRd7CbYG430QGvFf1te_0KDwFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23077318/1__9_tE5HVEXnSUwgJs75nUw.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Gif: Coinbase&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coinbase says you’ll be able to start earning interest with just a few taps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="r0yDMU"&gt;The program is similar to Coinbase Lend, which the company announced in June but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684169/coinbase-crypto-lend-feature-discontinued-sec-lawsuit-threats"&gt;canceled in September&lt;/a&gt; after the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662826/coinbase-sec-lend-regulation-crypto-lawsuit-exchange"&gt;SEC threatened to sue the company&lt;/a&gt;, saying that the feature would count as a security. Lend would have allowed users to earn interest on USDC, another stablecoin, though users would’ve been loaning it directly to Coinbase to manage instead of an outside protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eaaGrh"&gt;Coinbase also promised that you’d get whatever money you put into Lend back, but the company isn’t making any such guarantees with this new program. It also warns users that losses are possible and make sure to point out that the interest rates are variable — Compound’s rates for DAI fluctuated between 2.83 and 5.39 percent throughout October, according to Coinbase.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826888/coinbase-defi-interest-non-us-compound-lending-program"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826888/coinbase-defi-interest-non-us-compound-lending-program</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T18:01:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T18:01:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this investigation on the environmental racism of Amazon warehouses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An Amazon Fulfillment Center On Cyber Monday" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WZq7AbyK_5r49jxFbE1GpBdzjUw=/0x0:6390x4260/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252292/1236892446.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A truck arrives at an Amazon fulfillment center on Cyber Monday in Robbinsville, New Jersey, U.S., on Monday, Nov. 29, 2021.  | Michael Nagle/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PrE52l"&gt;Amazon is expanding its empire of warehouses at breakneck speed, and it’s building most of them in neighborhoods of color, according to a new investigation by Consumer Reports&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; That ultimately burdens Black and brown communities with the truck traffic, noise, and pollution that warehouses bring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ga8h7s"&gt;Almost 70 percent of Amazon warehouses in the US are in neighborhoods with a higher proportion of residents of color than what’s typical in other neighborhoods in the rest of the metro area, according to Consumer Reports. Fifty-seven percent of neighborhoods near Amazon warehouses have more low-income residents, too. To suss this out, Consumer Reports cross-referenced data from the Environmental Protection Agency, US Census Bureau, and a database of Amazon facilities that it purchased from a logistics consulting firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MIeIlw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Almost 70 percent of Amazon warehouses in the US are in neighborhoods with a higher proportion of residents of color&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mQfLgF"&gt;“Our communities are being sacrificed in the name of economic development,” José Acosta-Córdova, an organizer at the Chicago-based nonprofit Little Village Environmental Justice Organization, told Consumer Reports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GIjFUl"&gt;E-commerce is largely responsible for more and bigger warehouses. Online retail giants, with Amazon leading the way, generally need huge warehouses rather than retail space to store and distribute goods. $1 billion in online sales translates to 1.25 million square feet of warehouse space demand, according to commercial real estate firm &lt;a href="https://www.cbre.us/research-and-reports/2021-US-Real-Estate-Market-Outlook-Industrial-Logistics"&gt;CBRE&lt;/a&gt;. With online shopping rising for years and the pandemic further accelerating the trend, warehouses have recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816131/warehouses-natural-gas-emissions-climate-change"&gt;eclipsed offices as the most common commercial building&lt;/a&gt; in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DjJrOz"&gt;Amazon, in particular, has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22404044/amazon-earnings-q1-2021-performance-profit-operating-income"&gt;made a killing&lt;/a&gt; in sales during the pandemic and drastically increased the number of warehouses it operates to keep up. It opened almost 300 new facilities in 2020, Consumer Reports found, compared to an average of 75 annually during the five years prior. Amazon’s warehouse footprint dwarfs other retailers: its new additions in 2020 alone are already two-thirds that of all of Walmart’s warehouse space. Amazon did not immediately provide comment to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XgCs8n"&gt;The impacts of the warehouse boom will be felt most acutely by the Black, brown, and low-income communities where they’re going up. The Inland Empire, a once quiet community on the edge of Southern California’s deserts that’s now a warehouse hotspot, has the worst smog in the nation, &lt;a href="https://www.lung.org/getmedia/17c6cb6c-8a38-42a7-a3b0-6744011da370/sota-2021.pdf"&gt;according to the American Lung Association&lt;/a&gt;. And it’s far from an outlier: research is finding that neighborhoods in California with warehouses have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22800410/black-friday-holiday-shopping-supply-chain-pollution-ports-warehouses-california"&gt;significantly worse air pollution&lt;/a&gt; than similar areas without warehouses. Poor air quality is linked to a &lt;a href="https://www.edf.org/health/health-impacts-air-pollution"&gt;litany of health problems&lt;/a&gt;, including asthma and heart attacks, placing communities that often are least able to afford good health care at greater risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YY7tRU"&gt;If the new Consumer Reports investigation is any indicator, the problem will get worse before it gets better. Go read the &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/corporate-accountability/when-amazon-expands-these-communities-pay-the-price-a2554249208/"&gt;full story&lt;/a&gt; here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="gKPzSH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"As warehouses take off, they need to kick natural gas ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816131/warehouses-natural-gas-emissions-climate-change"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="nwXPCb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon and Target play ‘outsized’ role in port congestion and pollution, report finds ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808388/amazon-target-port-congestion-pollution-maritime-shipping"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="weUzDJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Holiday shopping is causing toxic traffic jams at ports and warehouses","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22800410/black-friday-holiday-shopping-supply-chain-pollution-ports-warehouses-california"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826615/investigation-environmental-racism-amazon-warehouses"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826615/investigation-environmental-racism-amazon-warehouses</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-09T17:33:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-09T17:33:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Paramount Plus launches new live channels hub for linear streaming </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_Gx3viNkrZ2O5aMQW1p5IHFkQ6g=/151x0:1780x1086/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70252163/Live_TV_Desktop_Star_Trek.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Paramount Plus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Hgyyz9"&gt;Paramount Plus is rolling out its own linear channels feature that’ll serve up linear movies and TV with a similar feel to traditional cable TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OLki6q"&gt;The new Live Channels feature launched on Paramount Plus today with more than a dozen curated 24/7 playlists for genres like crime and drama, as well as adult animation and kids programming. Some channels are dedicated entirely to a specific franchise, such as &lt;em&gt;SpongeBob&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Survivor&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PeEljT"&gt;The addition of Live Channels also allows Paramount Plus to more directly compete with streaming services that have similar live and linear integrations, including Peacock. Paramount Plus previously supported a Live TV hub for sports, breaking news, and programming from Entertainment Tonight. (Premium users can pay extra for coverage from their local CBS station.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6f0zvV"&gt;The linear programming hub was “informed by” ViacomCBS-owned free TV service Pluto TV, Tom Ryan, president and CEO of ViacomCBS Streaming, &lt;a href="https://www.viacomcbspressexpress.com/paramount-plus/releases/view?id=58796"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sSy5vd"&gt;“Even in the era of on-demand, there is clearly a strong consumer appetite for reimagined linear channels that provide effortless, lean-back entertainment,” Ryan said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U9fU0j"&gt;Paramount Plus will continue to roll out additional channels, the company said, including a &lt;em&gt;RuPaul’s Drag Race&lt;/em&gt; channel and a dedicated movies channel — both of which will land on the service later this month. The full list of supported channels is as follows, per Paramount Plus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="U5kOoK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24/7 Laughs&lt;/strong&gt; — A destination for feel-good, laugh-out-loud content from popular series such as HOT IN CLEVELAND, RENO 911 and TOSH.O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UwBX2e"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adult Animation &lt;/strong&gt;— Genre-defining series such as BEAVIS AND BUTT-HEAD, CELEBRITY DEATHMATCH and DARIA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sesq1E"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Day Drama &lt;/strong&gt;— The best in drama, including everything from EVIL and THE TWILIGHT ZONE to TOUCHED BY AN ANGEL and THE GUARDIAN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dMB4B8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animation Favorites&lt;/strong&gt; — Beloved kids’ animated series, such as AVATAR: THE LAST AIRBENDER, RUGRATS, SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS and THE FAIRLY ODDPARENTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7vmHsG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Voices&lt;/strong&gt; — A celebration of Black voices and stories with a collection of popular series such as CHAPPELLE’S SHOW, KEY &amp;amp; PEELE, THE GAME and THE NEIGHBORHOOD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uhLeqW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crime &amp;amp; Justice &lt;/strong&gt;— Primetime procedurals such as BULL, BLUE BLOODS, CSI: MIAMI, MACGYVER, SEAL TEAM and THE GOOD WIFE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oOlTtf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History &amp;amp; Undiscovered&lt;/strong&gt; — A curated selection for historians from the Smithsonian Channel, including SACRED SITES, SECRETS, AMERICA’S HIDDEN STORIES and SECRETS UNLOCKED&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qIlG4t"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kids &amp;amp; Family Fun &lt;/strong&gt;— A destination for the whole family to enjoy favorites such as HENRY DANGER, iCARLY, THE THUNDERMANS and ZOEY 101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qcRN0H"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nostalgic Hits&lt;/strong&gt; — A playlist featuring episodes from iconic series, including BEVERLY HILLS 90210, CHEERS, FRASIER, SABRINA THE TEENAGE WITCH and WINGS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qpfCaw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAW Patrol&lt;/strong&gt; — Home to all things PAW PATROL, including PAW PATROL: LIVE AT HOME!, PAW PATROL: THE MOVIE and, of course, the original series that started it all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q4DG8G"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preschool Corner &lt;/strong&gt;— Parent-approved programming for pint-sized viewers such as BLUE’S CLUES, BUBBLE GUPPIES, DORA THE EXPLORER, PAW PATROL and PEPPA PIG&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YkyFrF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reality TV: Competition&lt;/strong&gt; — A collection of reality TV’s most popular series, including INK MASTER, RUPAUL’S DRAG RACE and SURVIVOR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YGPTR0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reality TV: Shores&lt;/strong&gt; — Hours of content from the fist-pumping franchise, including episodes from JERSEY SHORE, JERSEY SHORE FAMILY VACATION and FLORIBAMA SHORE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oiucwU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SpongeBob Universe&lt;/strong&gt; — Home to all things Bikini Bottom, the channel will feature episodes from SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS and KAMP KORAL: SPONGEBOB’S UNDER YEARS, as well as popular SPONGEBOB movies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="faXP0S"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Trek &lt;/strong&gt;— A destination for STAR TREK fans, featuring popular originals such as STAR TREK: DISCOVERY and STAR TREK: PICARD, plus iconic series such as STAR TREK: ENTERPRISE and STAR TREK: THE NEXT GENERATION.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSqD61"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survivor&lt;/strong&gt; — Featuring 40 seasons of the long-running reality series&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ts8v53"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; — The best moments from the hit reality series, including THE CHALLENGE and THE CHALLENGE: ALL-STARS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9l3ff4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TV Classics&lt;/strong&gt; — A curated selection of timeless series such as I LOVE LUCY, THE LOVE BOAT and THE TWILIGHT ZONE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826909/paramount-plus-live-channels-linear-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826909/paramount-plus-live-channels-linear-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
