<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:42:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Honk introduces a real-time, ephemeral messaging app aimed at Gen Z</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/honk-introduces-a-real-time-ephemeral-messaging-app-aimed-at-gen-z/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/honk-introduces-a-real-time-ephemeral-messaging-app-aimed-at-gen-z/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gen z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new mobile app called Honk aims to make messaging with friends a more interactive, real-time experience. Instead of sending texts off into the void and hoping for a response, friends on Honk communicate via messages that are shown live as you type, with no saved chat history and no send button. The end result [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new mobile app called <a href="https://honk.me/">Honk</a> aims to make messaging with friends a more interactive, real-time experience. Instead of sending texts off into the void and hoping for a response, friends on Honk communicate via messages that are shown live as you type, with no saved chat history and no send button. The end result is a feeling of being more present in a conversation, as Honk will notify users the moment someone leaves a chat. And if you really want to get someone&#8217;s attention, you can send them a &#8220;Honk&#8221; &#8212; a hard-to-miss notification to join your chat.</p>
<p>If it&#8217;s even more urgent, you can even spam the Honk button by pressing it repeatedly. This sends notifications to a friend&#8217;s phone if they&#8217;re off the app, or a flood of colorful emoji if they have the app open.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f5e3.png" alt="🗣" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Need to get someone&#39;s attention fast? Honk them! They&#39;ll get a notification to come to the chat. If it&#39;s super important, you can spam the Honk button — that&#39;s hard to miss. <a href="https://t.co/VqcinmeeT2">pic.twitter.com/VqcinmeeT2</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Honk (@usehonk) <a href="https://twitter.com/usehonk/status/1341497424959795200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 22, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>After setting up an account by customizing your profile pic, selecting a username and adding friends, you can then tap on a friend&#8217;s name in your list to send them a message.</p>
<p>When you enter a chat in Honk, you&#8217;ll be presented with two, large conversation bubbles. The gray one on the top is where your friend&#8217;s messages are shown, while you type in the blue one. (You can change the colors and theme, if you choose.)</p>
<p>As you type, the other person will see the text you&#8217;re entering into this box in real-time &#8212; including the pauses and typos that would normally be missed. This &#8220;live typing&#8221; experience is reminiscent of older communication technology, like the early instant messaging app ICQ, or the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/05/28/google-wave-drips-with-ambition-can-it-fulfill-googles-grand-web-vision/">innovative collaboration tool Google Wave</a>, for example.</p>
<p>In Honk, you&#8217;re given 160 characters to type out your thoughts, and this is counted down on the right side of screen below the conversation bubbles. But you don&#8217;t tap a &#8220;Send&#8221; button to share the message &#8212; the recipient saw the text as it was entered, after all. Instead, you just tap the double arrow &#8220;refresh&#8221; button to clear the screen and type something new.</p>
<p>There are also buttons for sending emoji, snapping a photo, or accessing photos from your Camera Roll to share in the chat. The emoji here work more like iMessage&#8217;s &#8220;Send with Echo&#8221; screen effect, as you&#8217;re not just sending a single emoji when you use this feature &#8212; you&#8217;re sending several huge emoji that temporarily fill the screen.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> With Magic Words, you can assign any emoji to any word or phrase, which automatically trigger effects as you type. It&#39;s the best way to personalize your chats and bring them to life. Set up to 50 unique Magic Words per chat! <a href="https://t.co/2BYUyNrEzz">pic.twitter.com/2BYUyNrEzz</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Honk (@usehonk) <a href="https://twitter.com/usehonk/status/1341581571116056576?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>You can also optionally assign emoji to any word or phrase within an individual chat, using a &#8220;Magic Words&#8221; feature that will trigger effects as you type. (See above). Plus, you can customize chat themes on a per-conversation basis or turn off notifications from an individual user, if you don&#8217;t want to hear from them as much.</p>
<p>None of the conversations are stored and there&#8217;s no history to look back on. This is similar to messaging apps like Snapchat or<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/facebooks-snapchat-like-vanish-mode-feature-arrives-on-messenger-and-instagram/"> Messenger&#8217;s Vanish Mode</a>, for instance. (Honk hasn&#8217;t clarified its position on security, however, so proceed with caution before getting into riskier content.)</p>
<p>And, of course, if you need to get someone&#8217;s attention, you can tap &#8220;Honk&#8221; to flood them with notifications.</p>
<p>If this all seems somewhat silly, then you&#8217;re probably not the target market for the Honk messaging experience.</p>
<p>The app is clearly aiming for a young crowd of largely teenage users. When Honk asks for your age during setup, in fact, you can select an exact number from the list that appears &#8212; unless you&#8217;re &#8220;old,&#8221; that is. The last option on the list of ages is &#8220;21+&#8221; &#8212; the &#8220;older folks&#8221; age bracket that may sting a bit for the millennial crowd who often still think of themselves as the online trendsetters.</p>
<p>But Honk is aiming to grab Gen Z&#8217;s interest, it seems. It&#8217;s even <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@usehonk">marketing to them on TikTok</a>, where it&#8217;s already generated some 140K+ &#8220;Likes,&#8221; as of the time of writing, despite having only uploaded its first video yesterday. Honk founder Benji Taylor also noted on Twitter the app has seen 550,000 &#8220;Honks&#8221; sent so far, as of Wednesday, Dec. 23, 2020, shortly after noon Eastern.</p>
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" style="max-width: 605px; min-width: 325px;" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@usehonk/video/6909182677660847365" data-video-id="6909182677660847365">
<section><a title="@usehonk" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@usehonk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@usehonk</a>wait for it <a title="fyp" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">##fyp</a><a title="♬ original sound - Honk" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6909184731900873477" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">♬ original sound &#8211; Honk</a></p>
</section>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"></script></p>
<p>Per its website, Honk is the flagship product from software company and app publisher <a href="https://lfe.org/about">Los Feliz Engineering (LFE)</a>, which is backed by investors including Naval Ravikant, Elad Gil, Brian Norgard, David Tisch, Jeff Fagnan, Ryan Hoover, Sarah Downey, Josh Hannah, Sahil Lavingia, and others.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s exceptionally well designed,&#8221; said Product Hunt founder and Weekend Fund investor Ryan Hoover, about Honk. &#8220;[Honk founder] Benji [Taylor] and team labored over the small details, from the animations to the sounds. They&#8217;re also super focused on speed,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Taylor declined a full interview when TechCrunch reached out, noting the team was focused on building the product for the time being.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve been working on Honk for a while now. Our goal is to make messaging fun, and empower people to communicate in new, creative ways that take relationships deeper,&#8221; Taylor told TechCrunch. &#8220;Ultimately though, we’re a small team building this for ourselves and our friends. If other people like it, all the better,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Honk, we should note, has been <a href="https://twitter.com/usehonk/status/1341490665083924480">struggling</a> under the load of new signups at launch and high usage. Honk users report the app will sometimes say they&#8217;re offline when they&#8217;re not, for example, among other <a href="https://twitter.com/mitch_troy/status/1341588518976573441">bugs</a>. Honk <a href="https://twitter.com/usehonk/status/1341531287471837184">acknowledged</a> the issues on its Twitter and says it&#8217;s been working to resolve them.</p>
<p>The app is currently <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/honk/id1458452703">a free download on iOS.</a> It does not include in-app purchases or have any obvious business model.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/honk-introduces-a-real-time-ephemeral-messaging-app-aimed-at-gen-z/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090459</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letterhead wants to be the Shopify of email newsletters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/letterhead-wants-to-be-the-shopify-of-email-newsletters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/letterhead-wants-to-be-the-shopify-of-email-newsletters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Eldon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You’re probably investing in an email newsletter these days, whether you’re an international brand, a nonprofit, or a local news publisher. Maybe email is even your focus now, because you got burned by Facebook, Google or other closed platforms during the past decade. The problem is that the tools you have available are probably too [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You’re probably investing in an email newsletter these days, whether you’re an international brand, a nonprofit, or a local news publisher.</p>
<p>Maybe email is even your focus now, because you got burned by Facebook, Google or other closed platforms during the past decade. The problem is that the tools you have available are probably too generic, or are built specifically for marketers. What if you want to make money from the newsletter content itself?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tryletterhead.com/">Letterhead</a> is slicing through the vast market of existing email SaaS products, betting that a cross-section of revenue and collaboration needs are not being met properly for newsletter creators of all types. Instead, it puts all ad sales, paid subscriptions and newsletter content management into a single, streamlined product.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Its viewpoint on the future of newsletters — and its customer base so far — are intriguingly different from your typical SaaS startup in Silicon Valley. And there’s a reason for that. Letterhead is actually a product spinout of a community publisher in Miami called <a href="https://www.whereby.us/">Whereby.us</a> that began life in 2014 by launching a local media site, <a href="https://thenewtropic.com/">The New Tropic</a>. The publication became a rare success in online local news, once it focused on the email newsletter format.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2090591" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090591" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2090591" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/letterhead-herogif01-large.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="511" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090591" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.tryletterhead.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Letterhead <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>“Initially, our goal was to create a local media product that would help people learn about the city, get more involved and serve a new generation of local news users,” cofounder and CEO Chris Sopher tells me by video chat. “Our ideas had included opening a bar, events, and all kinds of other stuff. We quickly pared that back to the things that were working, and email was at the top of the list.”</p>
<p>Advertising inventory in these emails was in high demand, so the company built out a self-service payment system for advertisers, that allowed its newsletter writers to easily publish the correct ads in the correct place.</p>
<p>With this business model and technology as a foundation, it launched or acquired newsletters in <a href="https://theevergrey.com/">Seattle</a>, <a href="https://bridgeliner.com/">Portland</a>, <a href="https://pulp.town/">Orlando</a> and <a href="https://theincline.com/">Pittsburgh</a>. Through this process, it has continued to improve the tool itself.</p>
<p>It also discovered the broader demand.</p>
<p>“People would reach out to us and say ‘I love this newsletter, what tools do you use?’ because it was such a pain to produce emails with all of the different tools out there,” Sopher explains.</p>
<p>(Those tools, in this author’s experience, generally include a combination of Mailchimp, Constant Contact or Sailthru, together with your main web publishing CMS like WordPress, your separate subscription software like Piano and however you are managing ads.)</p>
<p>“We’d tell people that we used our own internal tools and they’d say ‘oh, can we use those, too? And we’d say ‘no, that’s not what we’re doing.’ Eventually, we said no enough that we looked at each other and said, ‘we should figure out how to get to yes on this.’ And that’s where Letterhead came from.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2090557" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="881" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png 2482w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png?resize=150,129 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png?resize=300,258 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png?resize=768,661 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png?resize=680,585 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png?resize=1536,1322 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png?resize=2048,1763 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-23-at-10.18.55-AM.png?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Today, Whereby.us is one of the few success stories from a catastrophic decade in local news. Sopher says that its five city newsletters are comfortably profitable via ads overall — having recovered from a pandemic dip earlier this year — and are continuing to grow.</p>
<p>But the new focus is on Letterhead’s tools, including the ad system, a new paid subscription feature that lets you do things like add paywalled subsections of emails, easy-to-use text editing and template formatting, and soon, analytics.</p>
<p>“Sponsorships and ads were [needs] we heard about most, so that’s where we started,” cofounder and COO Rebekah Monson said by email. “The bigger vision is to create a set of tools and services that feed into each other in one easy place, and help all of those revenue streams grow, eventually branching out from email. We&#8217;re seeing demand for that not just from traditional media publishers, but also from marketers, nonprofits, universities, professional associations — all these folks who have engaged communities and want to deepen those relationships and bring in revenue through that engagement.”</p>
<p>On the spectrum of email newsletter products, Letterhead’s focus on revenues and team collaboration places it adjacent to Substack’s focus on the individual writer, and to other products like Lede designed specifically around subscription news organizations.</p>
<p>Letterhead is explicitly a hosted software solution that you pay for your organization to use, not an open-source project like Ghost. Like how Shopify provides a suite of white-label ecommerce features for anyone who wants to run an online business, it wants to be the engine humming away under the hood of your newsletter.</p>
<p>On the much broader spectrum of all email solutions in the SaaS world, Letterhead is betting that its understanding of the market and its product design can beat out the brutally competitive world of SaaS email products.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2090592" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090592" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2090592" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/letterhead-herogif02-large.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="511" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090592" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.tryletterhead.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Letterhead <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Since soft-launching earlier this year, Sopher says it has already been signing up a broad range of customers. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Examples he cited include startups (</span><a href="https://www.shootmytravel.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shoot My Travel</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">), nonprofits (</span><a href="https://www.vidaysalud.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vida y Salud </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><a href="https://www.refreshmiami.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Refresh</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) and political groups (</span><a href="https://odaction.com/newsletters/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">OD Action</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) as customers, as well as local news publishers, of course (</span><a href="https://vtdigger.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">VTDigger</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.choose954.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Choose954</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://santacruzlocal.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Santa Cruz Local</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). </span> Letterhead is also a partner in <a href="https://newspack.pub/">WordPress’ News Pack program</a>, which is a collection of plugins for publishers on that CMS.</p>
<p>“We’re always going to have an affinity to media publishing… but there is a broader need than just that industry,” he explains. “And we’re also seeing this moment where a lot of other organizations are participating in [publishing]. You name a topic, there will be professional reporters out there doing great work. But it’s also pretty likely that there is a brand, an agency, a nonprofit, or some other organization creating interesting and useful content, and building a community around it — that would not raise its hand and say that it is part of the news industry.”</p>
<p>Sopher also notes that the product is designed to be modular, so that companies can just use parts of it and integrate its features with other email service providers and most any tech stack.</p>
<p>“What we’re seeing is that smaller customers are coming on for the simplicity of having it all in one place without sacrificing monetization,” he adds, “but larger customers are choosing us as one part of their stack as they build a multifaceted business or grow out of tools geared more to individual or independent creators.”</p>
<p>With the revenue options in place, Sopher says analytics and additional ESP options are coming next.</p>
<p>Over the course of its history, Whereby.us has raised $5 million from across tech and media. Backers include the Knight Foundation, Jason Calacanis&#8217; LAUNCH fund, Band of Angels, McClatchy, hundreds of smaller investors via Republic and SeedInvest, and most recently a round led by Brick Capital.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/letterhead-wants-to-be-the-shopify-of-email-newsletters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090540</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: What’s ahead for US immigration in 2021?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/dear-sophie-whats-ahead-for-u-s-immigration-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/dear-sophie-whats-ahead-for-u-s-immigration-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 19:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EB-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn Contributor Share on Twitter Sophie Alcorn is the founder of Alcorn Immigration Law in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives. More posts by this contributor Dear Sophie: How [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/dear-sophie-how-did-immigration-change-for-startup-founders-in-2020/">Dear Sophie: How did immigration change for startup founders in 2020?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/dear-sophie-can-founders-get-visas-in-2021-through-daca-or-other-means/">Dear Sophie: Can founders get visas in 2021 through DACA or other means?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie: </strong></p>
<p><strong>I’m in people ops and our team is trying to plan ahead for immigration in the new year and beyond. </strong></p>
<p><strong>What’s ahead for U.S. visas and green cards?</strong></p>
<p><strong>—Ready in Redwood City</strong></p>
<p>Dear Ready:</p>
<p>Ha! I love it. Well, although I don’t have a crystal ball (yet), there’s a lot of opportunity, predictability and security that we can anticipate for immigration ahead.</p>
<p>Our U.S. immigration policy will experience a tremendous growth spurt in the coming months as Trump completes his regulatory agenda, litigation culminates and Biden takes office on January 20. The changes I’m tracking will incentivize U.S. companies to hire and retain top global talent and will make it easier for them to do so. There are also going to be increased opportunities for families and founders, strengthening the U.S. and Silicon Valley tech startup communities.</p>
<p>We can anticipate that the first 100 days of President-elect Biden’s term will focus on undoing many Trump-era immigration changes. Some of this will happen by executive order (although probably not tweets!) and some of it will be required to follow the procedures set forth in law through the Administrative Procedure Act (APA). The APA governs the process by which federal agencies develop and issue regulations.</p>
<p>Following procedures to rescind or amend rules already put into place — even on an expedited basis — takes time to allow for adequate review and public comments. We can anticipate that due process will unfold to effectuate these changes.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/dear-sophie-whats-ahead-for-u-s-immigration-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090531</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No rules, no problem: DeepMind&#8217;s MuZero masters games while learning how to play them</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/no-rules-no-problem-deepminds-muzero-masters-games-while-learning-how-to-play-them/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/no-rules-no-problem-deepminds-muzero-masters-games-while-learning-how-to-play-them/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alphago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alphazero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeepMind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muzero]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DeepMind has made it a mission to show that not only can an AI truly become proficient at a game, it can do so without even being told the rules. Its newest AI agent, called MuZero, accomplishes this not just with visually simple games with complex strategies, like Go, Chess, and Shogi, but with visually [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/deepmind" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="deepmind">DeepMind <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has made it a mission to show that not only can an AI truly become proficient at a game, it can do so without even being told the rules. Its newest AI agent, called <a href="https://deepmind.com/research/publications/Mastering-Atari-Go-Chess-and-Shogi-by-Planning-with-a-Learned-Model">MuZero</a>, accomplishes this not just with visually simple games with complex strategies, like Go, Chess, and Shogi, but with visually complex <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/atari" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="atari">Atari <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> games.</p>
<p>The success of DeepMind&#8217;s earlier AIs was at least partly due to a very efficient navigation of the immense decision trees that represent the possible actions in a game. In Go or Chess these trees are governed by very specific rules, like where pieces can move, what happens when this piece does that, and so on.</p>
<p>The AI that beat world champions at Go, AlphaGo, knew these rules and kept them in mind (or perhaps in RAM) while studying games between and against human players, forming a set of best practices and strategies. The sequel, AlphaGo Zero, did this without human data, playing only against itself. AlphaZero did the same with Go, Chess, and Shogi in 2018, creating a single AI model that could play all these games proficiently.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But in all these cases the AI was presented with a set of immutable, known rules for the games, creating a framework around which it could build its strategies. Think about it: if you&#8217;re told a pawn can become a queen, you plan for it from the beginning, but if you have to find out, you may develop entirely different strategies.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2090576" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090576" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2090576 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1102" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg 1722w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg?resize=139,150 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg?resize=279,300 279w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg?resize=768,827 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg?resize=632,680 632w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg?resize=1427,1536 1427w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/muzero-diagram.jpg?resize=46,50 46w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2090576" class="wp-caption-text">This helpful diagram shows what different models have achieved with different starting knowledge.</p></div></p>
<p>As the company explains in a <a href="https://deepmind.com/blog/article/muzero-mastering-go-chess-shogi-and-atari-without-rules">blog post</a> about their new research, if AIs are told the rules ahead of time, &#8220;this makes it difficult to apply them to messy real world problems which are typically complex and hard to distill into simple rules.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s latest advance, then, is MuZero, which plays not only the aforementioned games but a variety of Atari games, and it does so without being provided with a rulebook at all. The final model learned to play all of these games not just from experimenting on its own (no human data) but without being told even the most basic rules.</p>
<p>Instead of using the rules to find the best-case scenario (because it can&#8217;t), MuZero learns to take into account every aspect of the game environment, observing for itself whether it&#8217;s important or not. Over millions of games it learns not just the rules, but the general value of a position, general policies for getting ahead, and a way of evaluating its own actions in hindsight.</p>
<p>This latter ability helps it learn from its own mistakes, rewinding and redoing games to try different approaches that further hone the position and policy values.</p>
<p>You may remember Agent57, another DeepMind creation that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/01/deepminds-agent57-ai-agent-can-best-human-players-across-a-suite-of-57-atari-games/">excelled at a set of 57 Atari games</a>. MuZero takes the best of that AI and combines it with the best of AlphaZero. MuZero differs from the former in that it does not model the entire game environment, but focuses on the parts that affect its decision-making, and from the latter in that it bases its model of the rules purely on its own experimentation and firsthand knowledge.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Qcn7PnGZPq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/01/deepminds-agent57-ai-agent-can-best-human-players-across-a-suite-of-57-atari-games/">DeepMind&#8217;s Agent57 AI agent can best human players across a suite of 57 Atari games</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DeepMind&#8217;s Agent57 AI agent can best human players across a suite of 57 Atari games&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/01/deepminds-agent57-ai-agent-can-best-human-players-across-a-suite-of-57-atari-games/embed/#?secret=Qcn7PnGZPq" data-secret="Qcn7PnGZPq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Understanding the game world lets MuZero effectively plan its actions even when the game world is, like many Atari games, partly randomized and visually complex. That pushes it closer to an AI that can safely and intelligently interact with the real world, learning to understand the world around it without the need to be told every detail (though it&#8217;s likely that a few, like &#8220;don&#8217;t crush humans,&#8221; will be etched in stone). As one of the researchers <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55403473">told the BBC</a>, the team is already experimenting with seeing how MuZero could improve video compression — obviously a very different problem than Ms. Pac-Man.</p>
<p>The details of MuZero were <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-03051-4">published today in the journal Nature</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/no-rules-no-problem-deepminds-muzero-masters-games-while-learning-how-to-play-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090542</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fluent Forever raises $4.9M for its language learning system</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/fluent-forever-raises-4-9m-for-its-language-learning-system/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/fluent-forever-raises-4-9m-for-its-language-learning-system/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babbel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crowdsourcing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[denver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fluent Forever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Calacanis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launch Accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stout Street Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fluent Forever, a startup that uses a novel learning system to help its users master a new language faster, has raised a $4.9 million funding round led by Denver-based Stout Street Capital. Other investors in this round include The Syndicate, LAUNCH, Mana Ventures, Noveus VC, Flight.VC, Insta VC, UpVentures, Firebrand Ventures, Cultivation Capital, Spero Ventures [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://fluent-forever.com/app/">Fluent Forever</a>, a startup that uses a novel learning system to help its users master a new language faster, has raised a $4.9 million funding round led by Denver-based <a href="https://stoutstreetcapital.com/">Stout Street Capital</a>. Other investors in this round include The Syndicate, LAUNCH, Mana Ventures, Noveus VC, Flight.VC, Insta VC, UpVentures, Firebrand Ventures, Cultivation Capital, Spero Ventures and Lofty Ventures.</p>
<p>In many ways, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/fluent-forever" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="fluent-forever">Fluent Forever <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is a direct competitor to <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/duolingo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="duolingo">Duolingo, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Babbel and similar online language learning services. What sets it apart is a focus on a personalized learning system that emphasizes ear training, visual aids and something akin to spaced-repetition for helping you memorize new words and phrases. It&#8217;s a paid service (after a 14-day free trial) with subscriptions starting at $10 per month for a monthly subscription and the usual discounts for longer-term commitments.</p>
<p>To teach himself his first languages, the company&#8217;s founder and CEO Gabriel Wyner used the popular flashcard service <a href="https://apps.ankiweb.net/">Anki</a>, <a href="https://fluent-forever.com/app/get-the-book.html">wrote a book</a> about his approach, and taught workshops on language learning using his system with Anki. But as he noted, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/anki" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="anki">Anki <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is a serious tool, and simply learning how to get the most out of it takes a lot of time and energy.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2090549" style="width: 360px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/6C284C47-A4D1-4217-8471-03FD82D9C152-576x1024-1.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090549" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2090549" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/6C284C47-A4D1-4217-8471-03FD82D9C152-576x1024-1.jpeg" alt="" width="350" height="623" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/6C284C47-A4D1-4217-8471-03FD82D9C152-576x1024-1.jpeg 576w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/6C284C47-A4D1-4217-8471-03FD82D9C152-576x1024-1.jpeg?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/6C284C47-A4D1-4217-8471-03FD82D9C152-576x1024-1.jpeg?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/6C284C47-A4D1-4217-8471-03FD82D9C152-576x1024-1.jpeg?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2090549" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fluent Forever</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve watched everyone else fail at language learning,&#8221; he told me. &#8220;And the first thought is, okay, well, if you just learn how to do it right, then that&#8217;s a fixable thing. That&#8217;s exciting. And then once you have a solution for people and they&#8217;re all excited about it &#8212; but then you watch them fail because of IT reasons. That&#8217;s extra frustrating.&#8221;</p>
<p>In many ways then, Fluent Forever uses Wyner&#8217;s flashcard approach &#8212; because building those flashcards by hand is at the core of his learning system &#8212; and turns it into a far-easier-to-use application.</p>
<p>What people want, Wyner acknowledged, is a tool where you just press some buttons and learn something. But that doesn&#8217;t work. &#8220;I had to have a really strong reaction to this &#8212; a really strong answer &#8212; and say, &#8216;absolutely not. That is the one thing that teaches you is building it.&#8217; &#8221;</p>
<p>Wyner is not afraid to <a href="https://blog.fluent-forever.com/not-progressing-with-duolingo-heres-why/">compare his approach to Duolingo&#8217;s</a> and argues that its focus on translation exercises doesn&#8217;t translate to real language skills in the long run. At the same time, he freely acknowledges that the Duolingo user experience and gamification are far better than Fluent Forever. But he also believes that learners see far better results with his system.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2090552" style="width: 359px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-05-11-at-11.16.01-AM-467x1024-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090552" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2090552" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-05-11-at-11.16.01-AM-467x1024-1.png" alt="" width="349" height="765" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-05-11-at-11.16.01-AM-467x1024-1.png 467w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-05-11-at-11.16.01-AM-467x1024-1.png?resize=68,150 68w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-05-11-at-11.16.01-AM-467x1024-1.png?resize=137,300 137w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-05-11-at-11.16.01-AM-467x1024-1.png?resize=310,680 310w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-05-11-at-11.16.01-AM-467x1024-1.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 349px) 100vw, 349px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2090552" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fluent Forever</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We ask [our users]: &#8216;Why are you with us? Why would you pay for us when you could just get Duolingo for free?&#8221; What they come back with is, &#8216;yeah, your product is rough around the edges. I wish you would fix this, this and that, but you had me thinking in Spanish in two weeks,&#8221; Wyner said.</p>
<p>Fluent Forever currently supports nine languages: Japanese, French, Russian, Mexican and Spanish Spanish, Italian, Korean, German and Brazilian Portuguese, with Dutch being the next language the team is tackling.</p>
<p>As Wyner told me, the company had trouble raising in 2019, in part because the service was seeing pretty flat growth at the time. &#8220;People are very skeptical about language learning &#8212; that is not a sexy field. People don&#8217;t like it. The idea of jumping and trying to be competitive with Duolingo was just not appealing to anyone,&#8221; he told me. Come 2020, though, growth picked up, even before the COVID pandemic. At the same time, Fluent Forever also participated in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/jason-calacanis" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="jason-calacanis">Jason Calacanis&#8217; <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Launch Accelerator.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Wyner tells me that Fluent Forever is looking at ways to bring live tutors into the loop. Live tutoring online has been done before, of course, and there are some companies like <a href="https://preply.com/">Preply</a> that specialize in it already, but what Fluent Forever wants to do is combine the online language learning service with short live sessions and then use the online component to go back to that conversation over the course of a week or so. One advantage here is that these users &#8212; who will likely pay a premium for the live service &#8212; will also use their time with live tutors to create their own personalized sentences in the Fluent Forever system, which could then over time become content that&#8217;s available to all users, too.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/T4WxqpCznhs?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/fluent-forever-raises-4-9m-for-its-language-learning-system/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090520</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Biden administration can change the world with new crypto regulations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/the-biden-administration-can-change-the-world-with-new-crypto-regulations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/the-biden-administration-can-change-the-world-with-new-crypto-regulations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Regulation shouldn't be a guessing game.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Asheesh Birla</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ashgoblue">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Asheesh Birla is the GM of RippleNet at <a href="https://ripple.com/">Ripple</a>. 
	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. government is failing us with regard to fintech and blockchain regulation.</p>
<p>Devoid of any regulatory framework in the past four years we’ve been operating in limbo when it comes to the development and advancement of crypto products. Innovators in the fintech and blockchain industries have the ability and vision to build products that solve real problems for everyone from individuals to large banks to governments, but without a clear path forward, these products are unable to grow and scale to their full potential.</p>
<p>Regulation shouldn’t be a guessing game. Since 2019, when the Securities and Exchange Commission declared that neither Bitcoin (BTC) nor Ethereum (ETH) are securities, the industry’s been at a standstill. Without clarity, blockchain innovation will be limited to just two coins &#8212; the industry is much larger than this. A lack of regulation stifles the immense potential that crypto and blockchain provide.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			If we know the rules of the game we’re playing, we can keep doing what we do best: innovating. 					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>A new administration presents a new opportunity for elected officials across the political spectrum to develop clear policies and regulations enabling banks, fintechs and corporations to custody and use crypto to improve efficiencies and to provide a better customer experience.</p>
<p>We can learn a lesson from recent history here. In 1991, we saw the passage of the High Performance Computing and Communications Act (HPCCA), a bipartisan effort led by Senator Al Gore and signed into law by President George H.W. Bush.</p>
<p>This legislation paved the way for companies like Amazon, eBay, Yahoo, Google and others to boom and made the U.S. an early internet leader. By 1993 we saw the introduction of web browsers, and shortly after, the start of the dot-com era in 1994 that cemented the U.S. as a symbol of innovation.</p>
<p>The browser changed everything. It’s created new jobs, new economic opportunities and new categories in technology that we couldn’t have predicted 30 years ago. In looking at the top 100 Fortune 500 companies in 1991, technology was barely a blip on the radar with IBM standing as the lone tech company. By 2020, it’s a drastically different picture, with the list completely dominated by technology giants like Microsoft, Apple, Alphabet, Facebook and Salesforce.</p>
<p>Technology companies in the top 100 have contributed close to three million jobs, with many leading in market value. Despite an unconventional year, we’ve continued to see successful technology IPOs like DoorDash, Snowflake, Asana and Palantir.</p>
<p>Products and services that we take for granted now like Google, the iPhone, Uber, Salesforce, Spotify, Postmates and more were made possible by the HPCCA. We now have another chance to create a bipartisan effort focused on crypto innovation, one with public and private sector support to ensure clear regulatory frameworks. Regulation will make it easier for innovators to create new products that keep the United States competitive with other countries and attract more investment.</p>
<p>There’s no disputing that the adoption of crypto and blockchain is on the rise. Major companies including PayPal, Square and Robinhood are leaning in to crypto and pushing it to the mainstream. With the validation from these brands, interest in the utility of cryptocurrencies and the ability of crypto to better serve businesses and their customers, continues to grow.</p>
<p>Leading crypto companies such as <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ripple-labs" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ripple-labs">Ripple, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Coinbase, Gemini, DCG and Chainalysis are currently based in the United States. However, unclear regulation will keep new entrepreneurs from innovating in the United States. While other countries move forward with defined regulatory frameworks, it’s possible that we will see new entrepreneurs and companies forgo setting up shop in the U.S. in favor of jurisdictions where the rules are clear.</p>
<p>If we know the rules of the game we’re playing, we can keep doing what we do best: innovating. We are only at the beginning — developers can build on open-source technologies, entrepreneurs can launch new companies and develop new products, and investors can invest in those companies.</p>
<p>We want the most innovative crypto and blockchain companies to be built and to grow here in the U.S., where they can create value and opportunities for U.S. citizens. Similar to the early days of the internet, we don’t know what the industry will look like in 5-10 years, but with flexible frameworks the opportunity is massive.</p>
<p>There’s a big opportunity for the Biden administration to influence new policies and new legislation and provide clear guidance that will accelerate innovation in fintech and crypto for many generations to come. The administration can:</p>
<ul>
<li>Create a national digital banking licensing charter (similar to <a href="https://www.mas.gov.sg/regulation/Banking/digital-bank-licence">Singapore’s Digital Banking Charter</a>), to streamline the process for fintechs to apply for crypto, lending and payments licensing. Today companies in the U.S. are left to apply state-by-state for licensing, which costs millions of dollars in legal fees and years to accomplish.</li>
<li>Define clear classifications for digital assets, derivatives (created via smart contracts) and stablecoins.</li>
<li>Create a bipartisan public and private sector group led by tech-savvy thought leaders such as Andrew Yang, to collaborate on landmark legislation that will do for fintech what the HPCCA did for internet companies.</li>
<li>Appoint an SEC chair that understands how to truly advance innovation while protecting consumers and the markets. The pro-innovation lip service we have been getting from this SEC is just that — lip service. Every crypto project this SEC has touched has ended up fleeing the U.S., in bankruptcy or left holding worthless tokens.</li>
</ul>
<p>Regardless of how policymakers and regulators decide to approach the issues that our industry faces, we need to continue to work alongside the government to ensure that the rapidly growing number of people who use fintech and blockchain products continue to get the best-in-class solutions with appropriate consumer and market protections in place.</p>
<p>It’s clear that this technology is here to stay, and I hope that elected leaders will recognize the power that it has to effect massive financial industry progress. Similar to the HPCAA, smart regulation can both protect our consumers and markets while allowing proud U.S. companies to create life-changing innovations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7G7MbcQcqB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/">Coinbase files to go public confidentially and we&#8217;re hyped</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase files to go public confidentially and we&#8217;re hyped&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/coinbase-files-to-go-public-confidentially-and-were-hyped/embed/#?secret=7G7MbcQcqB" data-secret="7G7MbcQcqB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/the-biden-administration-can-change-the-world-with-new-crypto-regulations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nuro acquires autonomous trucking startup Ike</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nuro-acquires-autonomous-trucking-startup-ike/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nuro-acquires-autonomous-trucking-startup-ike/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 17:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alden Woodrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous trucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bain capital ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Ferguson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greylock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ike Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Autonomous delivery company Nuro has acquired Ike, a startup founded by veterans of Apple, Google and Uber Advanced Technologies Group that aimed to commercialize self-driving trucks. The deal, the latest in a busy season of acquisitions and consolidation in the autonomous vehicle industry, brings together two companies that have deep ties and shared technology. And [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Autonomous delivery company <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/nuro-2" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="nuro-2">Nuro <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has acquired Ike, a startup founded by veterans of Apple, Google and Uber Advanced Technologies Group that aimed to commercialize self-driving trucks.</p>
<p>The deal, the latest in a busy season of acquisitions and consolidation in the autonomous vehicle industry, brings together two companies that have deep ties and shared technology. And while the two pursued different applications of autonomous vehicle technology — Nuro with local delivery and Ike on long-haul freight — their founders say there is a shared vision around logistics.</p>
<p>Financial terms of the deal were not disclosed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Nuro is the giant in this relationship, with a $5 billion valuation and more than 600 employees. Ike employs about 60 people, and as of last year had a post-money valuation of around $250 million, according to sources. However, the companies&#8217; founders don&#8217;t describe this as the classic Silicon Valley acqui-hire. More than 55 Ike employees as well as its three founders will go over to Nuro, according to <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/alden-woodrow" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="alden-woodrow">Alden Woodrow, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Ike&#8217;s CEO who co-founded the company with Jur van den Berg and Nancy Sun.</p>
<p>It was a clear opportunity to fulfill some of the principles that we founded the company for, Woodrow said, who also announced the acquisition Wednesday in a <a href="https://medium.com/ike-blog/our-next-chapter-1ebf9f5d88a0">blog post on Medium</a>.</p>
<p>Woodrow told TechCrunch that Ike still had runway, meaning it had the capital it needed to continue independently. Still, scaling an autonomous vehicle company into a commercial enterprise requires a pool of capital that extends beyond $52 million, as well as partnerships. Ike did reach agreements this fall with DHL, Ryder and NFI to provide its technology to their respective fleets, but those were still in the early stages.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think it&#8217;s pretty clear just how incredible Ike&#8217;s team is and the quality of the tech that they built,&#8221; <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/dave-ferguson-3" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="dave-ferguson-3">Dave Ferguson, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Nuro&#8217;s co-founder and president told TechCrunch. &#8220;What is particularly compelling for Nuro is because Ike licensed Nuro&#8217;s tech stack a couple years ago, all of the tech that they&#8217;ve built is on top of that stack, there&#8217;s a shared DNA. The tech that they built is also something that we can very readily transfer over and almost plug and play into our system.&#8221;</p>
<p>Nuro is able to leverage the technology that Ike built and pull that in to its own local delivery application as well as use it for potential future applications, Ferguson added.</p>
<p>What those future applications are is an unanswered question. Patent filings from Nuro show an array of ideas, from delivering piping hot pizzas and lattes to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/23/how-nuro-plans-to-spend-softbanks-money/">smaller robots</a>. With Ike&#8217;s team on board it&#8217;s possible that Nuro will expand beyond local delivery into other kinds of logistics applications, like middle-mile delivery, an area in which startup Gatik AI has gained attention, or other trucking use cases. Ferguson was quick to note that Nuro&#8217;s local delivery bot called R2 is its first and primary product.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9SjYSgORII"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/06/gatik-adds-autonomous-box-trucks-to-its-middle-mile-game-plan/">Gatik adds autonomous box trucks to its &#8216;middle mile&#8217; game plan</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gatik adds autonomous box trucks to its &#8216;middle mile&#8217; game plan&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/06/gatik-adds-autonomous-box-trucks-to-its-middle-mile-game-plan/embed/#?secret=9SjYSgORII" data-secret="9SjYSgORII" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While Nuro might seem like the best home for Ike, sources told TechCrunch that the self-driving trucks startup had talked to at least one other autonomous vehicle company about a deal. The two sources added these weren&#8217;t advanced talks.</p>
<h2>Founding story</h2>
<p>The founders of the two companies don&#8217;t like to describe Ike as a spinout of Nuro. That might technically be correct, but their roots are intertwined.</p>
<p>Nuro was founded in June 2016 by former <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google </a>engineers Dave Ferguson and Jiajun Zhu. The startup was initially bootstrapped by Ferguson and Zhu, but by June 2017, the pair quickly raised a $92 million A funding round with investments from Greylock and Banyan, and gave NetEase founder Ding Lei (aka William Ding) a seat on Nuro’s board.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, van den Berg and Sun were both working at Apple’s special projects group when they left to join Otto, an autonomous trucking startup that was acquired by Uber in 2016. Woodrow, who was product lead of Google X’s Makani project, would also end up at Uber ATG by February 2017 as group product manager of its self-driving truck program.</p>
<p>By 2018, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/17/otto-founded-by-ex-googlers-is-bringing-self-driving-technology-to-trucks/">last of Otto’s founders</a> had left Uber and the self-driving trucks program was in free fall. Sun, Woodrow and van den Berg left Uber by spring 2018. A few months later, Uber shuttered its self-driving trucks unit to focus on autonomous cars.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="P2suyMxpBm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/17/otto-founded-by-ex-googlers-is-bringing-self-driving-technology-to-trucks/">Otto, founded by ex-Googlers, is bringing self-driving technology to trucks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Otto, founded by ex-Googlers, is bringing self-driving technology to trucks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/05/17/otto-founded-by-ex-googlers-is-bringing-self-driving-technology-to-trucks/embed/#?secret=P2suyMxpBm" data-secret="P2suyMxpBm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The three initially worked out of Nuro&#8217;s office space, <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">which was too small to accommodate the delivery bots and growing team. Sun&#8217;s VW camper van acted as Ike&#8217;s conference room in those early days. Sun, van den Berg and Woodrow collaborated with Nuro&#8217;s team closely for months before officially incorporating Ike in July, </span>California and Delaware business records show. The company&#8217;s name Ike is a nod to former President Dwight D. Eisenhower and the U.S. interstate system he helped create when he signed the Federal Aid Highway Act.</p>
<p>The point of that initial collaboration was to figure out how to take what Nuro had built and apply it to a new use case in trucking. &#8220;This was an opportunity for us to head off in our own direction, and really focus on that while they continued to push forward on local delivery,&#8221; Woodrow said in a recent interview.</p>
<p>Ike would license Nuro&#8217;s technology, specifically the hardware designs, autonomous software as well as data logging, maps and simulation. In return, Nuro took a minority stake in Ike.</p>
<p>When Ike came out of stealth mode in October 2018, Nuro <a href="https://medium.com/nuro/ike-hits-the-road-fec294de7a5c">characterized its relationship</a> with the new company as a partnership, where “we gave Ike a copy of our autonomy and infrastructure software and, in exchange, Nuro got an equity stake in Ike.”</p>
<p>Ike started small and took an understated approach to the task ahead. By February of 2019, Ike employed about 30 people and finally the capital to hire more following $52 million in a seed and Series A funding round led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/bain-capital-ventures" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="bain-capital-ventures">Bain Capital Ventures <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. Redpoint Ventures, Fontinalis Partners, Basis Set Ventures and Neo also participated in the round. Bain Capital Ventures partner <a href="https://www.baincapitalventures.com/team/ajay/">Ajay Agarwal</a> has joined Ike’s board.</p>
<p>Unlike others pursuing autonomous trucks, Ike&#8217;s founders said in a <a href="https://medium.com/ike-robotics/the-journey-ahead-for-self-driving-trucks-c2309e288dc1">blog post</a> at the time that they weren&#8217;t pushing to have the first self-driving trucks on the road. Ike did garner a positive reputation in the industry for its systems engineering approach, motion planning and its simulation tool, according to several sources in the AV trucking world.</p>
<p>As Ike worked quietly, Nuro gained a higher profile thanks to a $940 million investment made by the SoftBank Vision Fund in February 2019. Nuro expanded its team to more than 600 employees and snagged a partnership in 2018 with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/kroger" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="organization" data-entity="kroger">Kroger </a>to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/16/nuro-and-kroger-are-deploying-self-driving-cars-for-grocery-delivery-in-arizona-today/">pilot a delivery service</a> in Arizona. The pilot, which initially used Toyota Prius vehicles, transitioned to its R1 delivery bot. Nuro has also partnered with companies like CVS, Domino’s and Walmart. The company developed a second-generation vehicle, known as the R2, which is designed for local delivery service for restaurants, grocery stores and other businesses. The R2 received an exemption from the federal government earlier this year that allows it to operate as a driverless vehicle.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="B86TnRRCbQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/autonomous-delivery-startup-nuro-hits-5-billion-valuation-on-fresh-funding-of-500-million/">Autonomous delivery startup Nuro hits $5 billion valuation on fresh funding of $500 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Autonomous delivery startup Nuro hits $5 billion valuation on fresh funding of $500 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/autonomous-delivery-startup-nuro-hits-5-billion-valuation-on-fresh-funding-of-500-million/embed/#?secret=B86TnRRCbQ" data-secret="B86TnRRCbQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Investors weren&#8217;t done with Nuro. The COVID-19 pandemic delayed the plans of many Silicon Valley startups. But there have been bright spots, including the potential for local delivery. Nuro raised another $500 million in November with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/autonomous-delivery-startup-nuro-hits-5-billion-valuation-on-fresh-funding-of-500-million/">post-money valuation of $5 billion</a>. The Series C round was led by funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price  Associates, Inc., with participation from new investors including Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company and Baillie Gifford. The round also includes existing investors such as SoftBank Vision Fund 1 and Greylock.</p>
<h2>What happens next</h2>
<p>The two companies will begin integrating with a number of Ike engineers taking on more senior roles at Nuro. Woodrow will no longer be CEO and it&#8217;s unclear exactly what his new title will be. His job will likely focus on product development based on his experience.</p>
<p>With Nuro focused on local delivery, Ike&#8217;s mission of commercializing trucks has been shelved, for now. That decision to turn toward local delivery seems counter to the public comments Ike&#8217;s founders have made on numerous occasions about their passion for trucks.</p>
<p>&#8220;Everything we eat, touch or have in our homes has probably been on a truck at some point in its life,&#8221; Sun said back in October at the TC Sessions: Mobility event. &#8220;You don&#8217;t really appreciate the immensity of the impact on our daily lives like trucking actually has.&#8221;</p>
<p>But Woodrow said for him and his co-founders it&#8217;s really about getting a product into the world and &#8220;fulfilling the promise of automation that many of us have worked on at a bunch of different companies for a number of years.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Ultimately, what this came down to was, we think Nuro is in an incredibly unique and really compelling position to fulfill that promise and to do it soon, and to do it at a very large scale,&#8221; Woodrow said. &#8220;And so that was really the driver of deciding to take their offer and move forward in this way.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nuro-acquires-autonomous-trucking-startup-ike/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090458</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heading into 2021: Venture fundraising, liquidity and the everything bubble</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-to-2021-venture-fundraising-liquidity-and-the-everything-bubble/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-to-2021-venture-fundraising-liquidity-and-the-everything-bubble/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 17:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GGV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sapphire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So, onto 2021 we go. Let's see if the bulls are right again.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The last 12 months have provided us with shocking lows and surprising highs. In startup land, great expectations in January and February were followed by dashed hopes in March.</p>
<p>Those woes were followed by April despair, surprised optimism from May through June, and, finally, a straight shot all the way to the moon through December.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>It&#8217;s been a lot. But it&#8217;s all behind us. We don&#8217;t need to spend more time thinking about 2020 for now. We need to look ahead.</p>
<p>This morning, I&#8217;ve compiled notes on what&#8217;s coming. We have notes from <a href="https://www.ggvc.com/">GGV&#8217;s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hanstung?lang=en">Hans Tung</a> on the 2021 IPO market, <a href="https://sapphireventures.com/">Sapphires&#8217;s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/beezer232?lang=en">Beezer Clarkson</a> on what fundraising will look like for VCs next year, and a prediction from the <a href="https://pitchbook.com/media/press-releases/pitchbook-publishes-2021-us-venture-capital-outlook-predicting-record-nontraditional-investor-participatio">PitchBook analyst crew</a> that caught my eye.</p>
<p>This is the last <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/">Exchange column</a> for 2020. Thanks for reading so I could keep having fun every day at my job. Now, to work!</p>
<h2>2021</h2>
<p>We&#8217;ll start with the 2021 IPO market, only because so many of you cared so very much about it this year.</p>
<p>Hans Tung, an investor at GGV and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/03/ggvs-jeff-richards-there-is-a-level-of-resiliency-in-silicon-valley-that-we-did-not-have-10-years-ago/">recent Extra Crunch Live guest</a>, is an investor with an international perspective and a good read on global startup liquidity. So, when I got on the phone with him last week to catch up, I wanted to know his read on the 2021 IPO market.</p>
<p>Given that we&#8217;ve seen a number of blockbuster IPOs this year, I was expecting him to forecast an active start to the year. Correct.</p>
<p>But Tung added that while Q1 could be very busy, Q2 could present a lull. Why? Tung expects IPOs that failed to finish the job in Q4 2020 to slip into the first quarter of next year. That explains why the first quarter is busy. But why the slowdown in the following three months?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-to-2021-venture-fundraising-liquidity-and-the-everything-bubble/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090449</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voyager Space Holdings to acquire majority stake in commercial space leader Nanoracks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-commercial-space-leader-nanoracks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-commercial-space-leader-nanoracks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 15:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firefly Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international space station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nanoracks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pioneer Astronautics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voyager Space Holdings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Voyager Space Holdings continues to build up its portfolio of strategic space service offerings with the acquisition of a majority stake in X.O. Markets, the parent company of Nanoracks. Nanoracks has provided commercial space services for years now, and most recently provided the Bishop Airlock that was installed on the International Space Station. Bishop is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/voyager-space-holdings" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="voyager-space-holdings">Voyager Space Holdings <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> continues to build up its portfolio of strategic space service offerings with the acquisition of a majority stake in X.O. Markets, the parent company of Nanoracks. Nanoracks has provided commercial space services for years now, and most recently provided the Bishop Airlock that was installed on the International Space Station. Bishop is the first dedicated commercial permanent airlock on the ISS, and will provide a major increase in capabilities in terms of providing access to the orbital platform for private small satellites and research.</p>
<p>This is Voyager&#8217;s third major acquisition this year, after it picked up a majority stake in The Launch Company, a launch support company that provides services and hardware to facilitate launches, and that works with companies including Relativity, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/firefly-aerospace" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="firefly-aerospace">Firefly Aerospace <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Virgin Orbit. Voyager also picked up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/13/more-new-space-consolidation-as-voyager-space-holdings-acquires-pioneer-astronautics/">Pioneer Astronautics</a> (an R&amp;D company that works on propulsion, fuels, rapid prototyping and much more) in 2020, as well as Altius Space Machines in 2019. Altius is a startup that works on technology for on-orbit satellite servicing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7Cs9wvZDgC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-multi-launch-site-startup-the-launch-company/">Voyager Space Holdings to acquire multi-launch site startup The Launch Company</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Voyager Space Holdings to acquire multi-launch site startup The Launch Company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-multi-launch-site-startup-the-launch-company/embed/#?secret=7Cs9wvZDgC" data-secret="7Cs9wvZDgC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Nanoracks is probably its highest-profile acquisition, as the company has been involved in more than 1,000 ISS projects, spanning on-station research and small satellite launches from the platform, as well as other orbital and deep space missions. Nanoracks created a commercial space testing platform outside the ISS, and will be demonstrating a technology on a SpaceX mission next year that could eventually be used to convert spent upper stages from launch vehicles into orbital commercial mini space stations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6XQj2ffjxL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/18/nanoracks-just-booked-a-spacex-launch-to-demo-tech-that-turns-used-spacecraft-into-orbital-habitats/">Nanoracks just booked a SpaceX launch to demo tech that turns used spacecraft into orbital habitats</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nanoracks just booked a SpaceX launch to demo tech that turns used spacecraft into orbital habitats&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/18/nanoracks-just-booked-a-spacex-launch-to-demo-tech-that-turns-used-spacecraft-into-orbital-habitats/embed/#?secret=6XQj2ffjxL" data-secret="6XQj2ffjxL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Voyager Space Holdings continues its strategic acquisition of new space companies, building out a portfolio that can offer clients significantly more &#8220;full-service&#8221; solutions than any of these individual companies taken together. Commercial details of these arrangements aren&#8217;t shared, but they increasingly represent one path to exit for smaller companies addressing elements of the larger commercial space sector in fairly specialized ways.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-commercial-space-leader-nanoracks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090451</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nikola&#8217;s stock crashes after announcing cancelation of contract with Republic Services for 2,500 garbage trucks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nikolas-stock-crashes-after-announcing-cancelation-of-contract-with-republic-services-for-2500-garbage-trucks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nikolas-stock-crashes-after-announcing-cancelation-of-contract-with-republic-services-for-2500-garbage-trucks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 14:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General-Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikola Motor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The undoing of Nikola continues. Today, the company announced the termination of its contract with Republic Services for 2,500 garbage trucks. Announced back in August, the deal had Nikola building garbage trucks in 2023 with on-road testing scheduled for 2024. This is the latest deal to unravel for Nikola as it tries to patch up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/sec-to-investigate-short-sellers-claims-against-nikola-report-says/">undoing</a> of Nikola continues. Today, the company announced the termination of its contract with Republic Services for 2,500 garbage trucks. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/nikola-stock-surges-on-order-for-2500-electric-garbage-trucks/">Announced back in August</a>, the deal had Nikola building garbage trucks in 2023 with on-road testing scheduled for 2024. This is the latest deal to unravel for Nikola as it tries to patch up following recent devastating reports.</p>
<p>According to Nikola, the separation of the two companies was mutual, though it&#8217;s hard to picture Nikola&#8217;s SEC troubles didn&#8217;t weigh heavily upon Republic Services.</p>
<p>&#8220;This was the right decision for both companies given the resources and investments required,&#8221; Nikola CEO Mark Russell said in a released statement. &#8220;We support and respect Republic Services&#8217; commitment to achieving environmentally responsible, sustainable solutions for their customers. Nikola remains laser-focused on delivering on our battery-electric and fuel-cell electric commercial truck programs, and the energy infrastructure to support them.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>News of this deal is sending Nikola&#8217;s stock down 10% in pre-market trading. If this level holds upon the stock market&#8217;s open, Nikola will be trading at its lowest levels following its monumental rise over the summer months.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UBzRZH2b03"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/nikola-stock-surges-on-order-for-2500-electric-garbage-trucks/">Nikola stock surges on order for 2,500 electric garbage trucks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nikola stock surges on order for 2,500 electric garbage trucks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/nikola-stock-surges-on-order-for-2500-electric-garbage-trucks/embed/#?secret=UBzRZH2b03" data-secret="UBzRZH2b03" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The deal with Republic Services was originally a victory banner for the once high-flying electric vehicle startup. Signaled as mainstream acceptance of the company, Republic Services&#8217; contract came before a mega $2 billion investment from General Motors. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/nikla-shares-drop-as-gm-pulls-plug-on-investment-deal/">That deal is also cancelled</a> following several key revelations about the company that lead to an SEC investigation and the company&#8217;s chairman stepping down.</p>
<p>In a statement, Nikola says deliveries of Nikola Tre battery-electric semi-trucks will begin in the U.S. in 2021, and the company expects to break ground on its first commercial hydrogen station in 2021. And then in 2023, the company expects to produce its fuel-cell-electric semi-trucks at its Coolidge, Arizona facility.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sA4ayZkTgn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/nikla-shares-drop-as-gm-pulls-plug-on-investment-deal/">Nikola shares drop as GM pulls plug on investment deal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nikola shares drop as GM pulls plug on investment deal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/nikla-shares-drop-as-gm-pulls-plug-on-investment-deal/embed/#?secret=sA4ayZkTgn" data-secret="sA4ayZkTgn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nikolas-stock-crashes-after-announcing-cancelation-of-contract-with-republic-services-for-2500-garbage-trucks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090446</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking ahead after 2020&#8217;s epic M&#038;A spree</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-after-2020s-epic-ma-spree/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-after-2020s-epic-ma-spree/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When we examine any year in enterprise M&#38;A, it&#8217;s tempting to highlight the biggest, gaudiest deals &#8212; and there were plenty of those in 2020. I&#8217;ve written about 34 acquisitions so far this year. Of those, 15 were worth $1 billion or more, 12 were small enough to not require that the companies disclose the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When we examine any year in enterprise M&amp;A, it&#8217;s tempting to highlight the biggest, gaudiest deals &#8212; and there were plenty of those in 2020. I&#8217;ve written about 34 acquisitions so far this year. Of those, 15 were worth $1 billion or more, 12 were small enough to not require that the companies disclose the price and the remainder fell somewhere in between.</p>
<p>Four deals involving chip companies coming together totaled over $100 billion on their own. While nobody does eye-popping M&amp;A quite like the chip industry, other sectors also offered their own eyebrow-raising deals, led by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">Salesforce buying Slack</a> earlier this month for $27.7 billion.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			We are likely to see more industries consolidate the way chips did in 2020, albeit probably not quite as dramatically or expensively.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Yet in spite of the drama of these larger numbers, the most interesting targets to me were the pandemic-driven smaller deals that started popping up in May. Those small acquisitions are the ones that are so insignificant that the company doesn&#8217;t have to share the purchase price publicly. They usually involve early-stage companies being absorbed by cash-rich concerns looking for some combination of missing technology or engineering talent in a particular area like security or artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>It was certainly an active year in M&amp;A, and we still might not have seen the last of it. Let&#8217;s have a look at why those minor deals were so interesting and how they compared with larger ones, while looking ahead to what 2021 M&amp;A might look like.</p>
<h2>Early-stage blues</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s always hard to know exactly why an early-stage startup would give up its independence by selling to a larger entity, but we can certainly speculate on some of the reasons why this year&#8217;s rapid-fire dealing started in May. While we can never know for certain why these companies decided to exit via acquisition, we know that in April, the pandemic hit full force in the United States and the economy began to shut down.</p>
<p>Some startups were particularly vulnerable, especially companies low on cash in the April timeframe. Obviously companies fail when they run out of funding, and we started seeing early-stage startups being scooped up the following month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XcuBU1sXtL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/zoom-acquires-keybase-to-get-end-to-end-encryption-expertise/">Zoom acquires Keybase to get end-to-end encryption expertise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zoom acquires Keybase to get end-to-end encryption expertise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/zoom-acquires-keybase-to-get-end-to-end-encryption-expertise/embed/#?secret=XcuBU1sXtL" data-secret="XcuBU1sXtL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We don&#8217;t know for sure of course if there is a direct correlation between April&#8217;s economic woes and the flurry of deals that started in May, but we can reasonably speculate that there was. For some percentage of them, I&#8217;m guessing it was a fire sale or at least a deal made under less than ideal terms. For others, maybe they simply didn&#8217;t have the wherewithal to keep going under such adverse economic conditions or the partnerships were just too good to pass up.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that I didn&#8217;t cover any deals in April. But, beginning on May 7, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/zoom-acquires-keybase-to-get-end-to-end-encryption-expertise/">Zoom bought Keybase</a> for its encryption expertise; five days later <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/atlassian-acquires-halp-to-bring-slack-integration-to-the-forefront/">Atlassian bought Halp</a> for Slack integration; and the day after that VMware bought <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/vmware-to-acquire-kubernetes-security-startup-octarine-and-fold-it-into-carbon-black/">cloud native security startup Octarine</a> &#8212; and we were off and running. Granted the big companies benefited from making these acquisitions, but the timing stood out.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/looking-ahead-after-2020s-epic-ma-spree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085750</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yayzy app automatically calculates the environmental impact of your spending</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/yayzy-app-automatically-calculates-the-environmental-impact-of-your-spending/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/yayzy-app-automatically-calculates-the-environmental-impact-of-your-spending/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 13:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antler Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citigroup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Years Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online pharmacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seedrs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yayzy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ahead of the turning of the New Year, many people are wishing they could do something about the environment. Now, a U.K. startup hopes to make our environmental impact more personal. Yayzy has now launched an iOS app (Android is coming) which literally links to your bank account to work out the environmental impact of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ahead of the turning of the New Year, many people are wishing they could do something about the environment. Now, a U.K. startup hopes to make our environmental impact more personal.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.yayzy.com/">Yayzy</a> has now launched an iOS app (Android is coming) which literally links to your bank account to work out the environmental impact of what you buy. It uses payment data via Open Banking standards to automatically calculate the carbon footprint of each purchase a user makes, giving them a picture of their total monthly carbon emissions. This makes the carbon footprint calculated more accurate and bespoke to the individual, allowing them to immediately connect their spending to its impact on the planet.</p>
<p>Yayzy has secured £900,000 in backing from Antler Venture Capital, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/seedrs" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="seedrs">Seedrs <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> (a crowdfunding round) and the CoreAngels Impact Fund. As the user sees what the carbon footprint is of their purchase, they can choose to offset it right then and there on the app via the carbon offsetter <a href="https://ecosphere.plus/">Ecosphere Plus</a>. In the app, users can also find tips to reduce their carbon footprint, eco-friendly retailers near them or insights into lifestyle choices that have the highest environmental impact.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Their competitors are people like <a href="https://cogo.co/">CoGo</a>, a real-time Carbon Footprint tracker, and <a href="https://doconomy.com/">Doconomy</a> and the soon to launch <a href="https://www.tred.earth/">Tred</a>.</p>
<p>But Yayzy is taking a different approach. It brings together all of a user’s spending and shows them item by item as they spend what the carbon footprint of that spend is. So far &#8212; it claims &#8212; its competitors don’t do that.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2090442" style="width: 577px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090442" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2090442" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Group-698@2x.png" alt="" width="567" height="402" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Group-698@2x.png 567w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Group-698@2x.png?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Group-698@2x.png?resize=300,213 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Group-698@2x.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 567px) 100vw, 567px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090442" class="wp-caption-text">Yayzy app. Image Credits: Yayzy</p></div></p>
<p>This can be done ad hoc, item by item, or by signing up to a monthly subscription to either carbon offsetting projects or the user&#8217;s own unique climate portfolio. This portfolio would bundle multiple projects for a more &#8220;holistic&#8221; impact. Yayzy says all of these projects have been carefully selected based on strict criteria, and also advance the UN Sustainable development goals.</p>
<p>For its underlying carbon data, Yayzy is using <a href="https://www.vitalmetricsgroup.com/">Vital Metrics</a>, as used by Google, Microsoft and both the U.K. and U.S. governments, among others.</p>
<p>Mankaran Ahluwalia, co-founder and CEO of Yayzy, said in a statement: &#8220;While emissions have gradually risen as lockdown eases, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/yayzy" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="yayzy">YAYZY <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> wants to put us all in the driver’s seat to control our own environmental impact… It is clear from a plethora of surveys that the majority of people want to address climate change before it is too late, but that a huge intention/action gap blocks much of it. Our solution with Yayzy is to make environmental impact ‘up close and personal’ and the action to tackle it super easy, all via your phone.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ahluwalia, was a technology analyst with Infosys and built a lending platform for alternate credit. Co-founder Cristian Dan, CTO, previously built a discounts platform and co-founder Pedro Cabrero, CFO was in equity sales and trading for <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ubs" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ubs">UBS <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/citigroup" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="citigroup">Citigroup, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and co-founded a leading online pharmacy in Mexico.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fs5TeZyGE1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/07/y-combinator-backed-project-wren-is-aiming-to-make-carbon-offsets-more-consumer-friendly/">Y Combinator-backed Project Wren is aiming to make carbon offsets more consumer friendly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Y Combinator-backed Project Wren is aiming to make carbon offsets more consumer friendly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/07/y-combinator-backed-project-wren-is-aiming-to-make-carbon-offsets-more-consumer-friendly/embed/#?secret=fs5TeZyGE1" data-secret="fs5TeZyGE1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/yayzy-app-automatically-calculates-the-environmental-impact-of-your-spending/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090439</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok parent ByteDance hiring for AI drug discovery team</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/bytedance-ai-drug/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/bytedance-ai-drug/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 12:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai drug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ByteDance, TikTok&#8217;s Chinese parent company, is entering the health industry as it seeks to diversify a business dependent on advertising and livestreaming sales. The company, which prides itself on content algorithms, has started seeking talent in AI drug discovery across Mountain View, Shanghai and Beijing, its recruiting page shows. &#8220;We are looking for candidates to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/bytedance" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="bytedance">ByteDance, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> TikTok&#8217;s Chinese parent company, is entering the health industry as it seeks to diversify a business <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/bytedance-valuation-under-huge-pressure-as-tiktok-sale-nears/">dependent on advertising and livestreaming sales</a>. The company, which prides itself on content algorithms, has started seeking talent in AI drug discovery across Mountain View, Shanghai and Beijing, its recruiting page <a href="https://jobs.bytedance.com/en/position?keywords=drug&amp;category=&amp;location=&amp;project=&amp;type=&amp;job_hot_flag=&amp;current=1&amp;limit=10">shows</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are looking for candidates to join our team and conduct cutting-edge research in drug discovery and manufacturing powered by AI algorithms,&#8221; one of the job postings said.</p>
<p>The drug discovery team, which is looking to fill at least five roles, including interns, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A6731781114626682880/?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A6725103577200693248%2C6731780990580137984%29">falls under</a> the <a href="https://ailab.bytedance.com/">ByteDance AI Lab</a>. The AI-focused research and development arm was first established in 2016 to serve ByteDance&#8217;s content services like TikTok&#8217;s Chinese version Douyin, but it&#8217;s unsurprising to see the lab extending its reach to pharmaceuticals, which can similarly benefit from the machine learning technologies that power short video feeds.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Given the number of research fields in AI, the applications of these new technologies can be found across every segment of our product portfolio,&#8221; said a description on the ByteDance AI Lab <a href="https://ailab.bytedance.com/">website</a>.</p>
<p>All five drug discovery research positions require a PhD degree in relevant disciplines, such as computer science, mathematics, computational biology and computational chemistry. Candidates will be working on drug development such as design, identification and simulation, according to the postings.</p>
<p>ByteDance cannot be immediately reached for comment.</p>
<p>Other Chinese tech behemoths have made similar moves into the health space. Tencent&#8217;s own AI-powered drug team, also under the firm&#8217;s AI Lab, has been actively publishing findings since at least<a href="https://drug.ai.tencent.com/en/paper/1"> August 2019</a>. Baidu planned to raise $2 billion for a new biotech startup focusing on drug discovery and AI-powered diagnosis, Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-baidu-biotech-exclusive/exclusive-baidu-investors-in-talks-to-raise-2-billion-for-biotech-startup-source-idUSKBN2600UH">reported</a> in September. Huawei has also made endeavors in drug discovery, as well as medical imaging through its cloud computing unit.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QXL6hFjSYc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/bytedance-valuation-under-huge-pressure-as-tiktok-sale-nears/">ByteDance valuation under huge pressure as TikTok sale nears</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ByteDance valuation under huge pressure as TikTok sale nears&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/bytedance-valuation-under-huge-pressure-as-tiktok-sale-nears/embed/#?secret=QXL6hFjSYc" data-secret="QXL6hFjSYc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/bytedance-ai-drug/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090432</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Telegram, nearing 500 million users, to begin monetizing the app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 09:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pavel Durov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instant messaging app Telegram is &#8220;approaching&#8221; 500 million users and plans to generate revenue starting next year to keep the business afloat, its founder Pavel Durov said on Wednesday. Durov said he has personally bankrolled the seven-year-old business so far, but as the startup scales he is looking for ways to monetize the instant messaging [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instant messaging app <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/telegram" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="telegram">Telegram <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is &#8220;approaching&#8221; 500 million users and plans to generate revenue starting next year to keep the business afloat, its founder Pavel Durov said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Durov said he has personally bankrolled the seven-year-old business so far, but as the startup scales he is looking for ways to monetize the instant messaging service. &#8220;A project of our size needs at least a few hundred million dollars per year to keep going,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The service, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/24/telegram-hits-400-million-monthly-active-users/">topped 400 million active users in April this year</a>, will introduce its own ad platform for public one-to-many channels &#8212; “one that is user-friendly, respects privacy and allows us to cover the costs of server and traffic,” he wrote on his Telegram channel.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;If we monetize large public one-to-many channels via the Ad Platform, the owners of these channels will receive free traffic in proportion to their size,&#8221; he wrote. Another way Telegram could monetize its service is through premium stickers with &#8220;additional expressive features,&#8221; he wrote. &#8220;The artists who make stickers of this new type will also get a part of the profit. We want millions of Telegram-based creators and small businesses to thrive, enriching the experience of all our users.&#8221;</p>
<p>Some analysts were hoping that Telegram would be able to monetize the platform through its blockchain token project. But after several delays and regulatory troubles, Telegram said in May that it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/telegram-abandons-its-ton-blockchain-platform/">decided to abandon the project</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MZjvxT6pN7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/telegram-abandons-its-ton-blockchain-platform/">Telegram abandons its TON blockchain platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Telegram abandons its TON blockchain platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/telegram-abandons-its-ton-blockchain-platform/embed/#?secret=MZjvxT6pN7" data-secret="MZjvxT6pN7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For this project, Dubai-based Telegram had raised $1.7 billion from investors in 2018. It had planned to distribute its token, called grams, after developing the blockchain software. Telegram offered to return $1.2 billion to investors earlier this year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Telegram has a social networking dimension. Our massive public one-to-many channels can have millions of subscribers each and are more like Twitter feeds. In many markets the owners of such channels display ads to earn money, sometimes using third-party ad platforms. The ads they post look like regular messages, and are often intrusive. We will fix this by introducing our own Ad Platform for public one-to-many channels,&#8221; Durov wrote today.</p>
<p>All existing features will remain free, said Durov, who is one of the biggest critics of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>-owned <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/whatsapp" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="whatsapp">WhatsApp, adding <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> that Telegram is committed to not introduce ads in private one-to-one chats or group chats because they are a “bad idea.”</p>
<p>“We are not going to sell the company like the founders of WhatsApp. The world needs Telegram to stay independent as a place where users are respected and high-quality service is ensured,” he wrote. “Telegram will begin to generate revenue, starting next year. We will do it in accordance with our values and the pledges we have made over the last 7 years. Thanks to our current scale, we will be able to do it in a non-intrusive way. Most users will hardly notice any change.”</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Telegram also introduced a new group Voice Chats feature. The new feature, which is similar to <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/discord" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="discord">Discord&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> always-on room, supports a few thousand participants.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Telegram groups get a new dimension with Voice Chats – persistent conference calls that run in parallel to existing text chats. Voice Chats add a live layer of ephemeral talk to the group and can be used as informal lounges or virtual office spaces.<a href="https://t.co/08dyFMWok6">https://t.co/08dyFMWok6</a> <a href="https://t.co/13XcszUzob">pic.twitter.com/13XcszUzob</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Telegram Messenger (@telegram) <a href="https://twitter.com/telegram/status/1341676702083248128?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090411</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI-driven energy startup Octopus hits $2B mark after $200M investment from Tokyo Gas</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/ai-driven-energy-startup-octopus-hits-2bn-mark-after-200m-investment-from-tokyo-gas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/ai-driven-energy-startup-octopus-hits-2bn-mark-after-200m-investment-from-tokyo-gas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 09:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greg Jackson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Octopus Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo gas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You’ve heard of challenger banks? Now meet the challenger energy suppliers. The U.K.’s Octopus Energy has attained a $2.06 billion valuation (£1.5 billion) after attracting a $200 million (£150 million) investment from Tokyo Gas, for a 9.7% stake, in order to launch a joint venture. Octopus will own 30% of the venture, with Tokyo Gas [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You’ve heard of challenger banks? Now meet the challenger energy suppliers. The U.K.’s <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/octopus-energy" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="octopus-energy">Octopus Energy <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has attained a $2.06 billion valuation (£1.5 billion) after attracting a $200 million (£150 million) investment from Tokyo Gas, for a 9.7% stake, in order to launch a joint venture. Octopus will own 30% of the venture, with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tokyo-gas" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tokyo-gas">Tokyo Gas <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> owning the majority. After five years of operation, Octopus is now close to the valuation of British Gas owner Centrica.</p>
<p>Octopus will now launch as a brand in Japan with its trademark 100% renewable electricity operation, which uses an innovative AI and data-based platform to balance loads around the grid. Its Kraken software is also licensed to Origin Energy, nPower and E.On, Good Energy and Hanwha Corporation, among others, reaching 17 million energy accounts worldwide.</p>
<p>“This joint venture will bring our exciting approach to renewable energy and technology to the world’s largest competitive energy market, and the investment will turbocharge our mission to revolutionize energy globally,” said chief executive <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/greg-jackson" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="greg-jackson">Greg Jackson <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> (pictured above) in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Australia’s Origin Energy is also set to take a stake in Octopus for $50 million (£37 million) following a larger investment in April when Origin bought a 20% stake.</p>
<p>Octopus says it is aiming for 100 million customers around the world by 2027, and recently launched in the U.S., Australia, Germany and New Zealand.</p>
<p>In the U.K., Octopus has a 5% share of the energy supply market and counts 1.8 million households in its retail portfolio, according to the company.</p>
<p>Tokyo Gas president Takashi Uchida said: “Through this partnership, we will contribute to the achievement of a better lifestyle for customers by realizing value creation and delivery tailored to every one of them.”</p>
<p>Japanese renewables lag the U.K. by 50% (renewables in Japan in 2019 accounted for 18.9% of electricity versus 37.9% in the U.K.), so the potential for growth is significant. Japanese Prime Minister Yoshihide Suga has set a target of reaching net-zero by 2050.</p>
<p>In the U.K., Octopus has also launched Electric Juice, an electric vehicle roaming network, and partnered with Tesla to launch Tesla Power.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="60sXBjRAdn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/">Residential renewable energy developer Swell is raising $450 million for distributed power projects in three states</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Residential renewable energy developer Swell is raising $450 million for distributed power projects in three states&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/embed/#?secret=60sXBjRAdn" data-secret="60sXBjRAdn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/ai-driven-energy-startup-octopus-hits-2bn-mark-after-200m-investment-from-tokyo-gas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090405</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-demand logistics company Lalamove gets $515 million Series E</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/on-demand-logistics-company-lalamove-gets-515-million-series-e/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/on-demand-logistics-company-lalamove-gets-515-million-series-e/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 06:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lalamove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on-demand delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lalamove will extend its network to cover more small Chinese cities after raising $515 million in Series E funding, the on-demand logistics company announced on its site. The round was led by Sequoia Capital China, with participation from Hillhouse Capital and Shunwei Capital. All three are returning investors. According to Crunchbase data, this brings Lalamove’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.lalamove.com/">Lalamove</a> will extend its network to cover more small Chinese cities after raising $515 million in Series E funding, the on-demand logistics company <a href="https://www.huolala.cn/articleid_1024.html">announced on its site</a>. The round was led by Sequoia Capital China, with participation from Hillhouse Capital and Shunwei Capital. All three are returning investors.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/easyvan/company_financials">Crunchbase data</a>, this brings Lalamove’s total raised so far to about $976.5 million. The company’s last funding announcement was in February 2019, when it hit unicorn status with a Series D of $300 million.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JCbrNbCDZB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/20/lalamove-raises-300m/">On-demand logistics startup Lalamove raises $300M for Asia growth and becomes a unicorn</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;On-demand logistics startup Lalamove raises $300M for Asia growth and becomes a unicorn&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/20/lalamove-raises-300m/embed/#?secret=JCbrNbCDZB" data-secret="JCbrNbCDZB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-16/hong-kong-s-lalamove-said-to-seek-funds-at-8-billion-valuation">reported last week</a> that Lalamove was seeking at least $500 million in new funding at $8 billion valuation, or four times what it raised last year.</p>
<p>Founded in 2013 for on-demand deliveries within the same city, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/easyvan" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="easyvan">Lalamove <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has since grown its business to include freight services, enterprise logistics, moving and vehicle rental. In addition to 352 cities in mainland China, Lalamove also operates in Hong Kong (where it launched), Taiwan, Vietnam, Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore, the Philippines and Thailand. The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/lalamove-enters-the-us/">entered the United States</a> for the first time in October, and currently claims about 480,000 monthly active drivers and 7.2 million monthly active users.</p>
<p>Part of its Series D had been earmarked to expand into India, but Lalamove was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/india-bans-another-43-chinese-apps/">among 43 apps </a>that were banned by the government, citing cybersecurity concerns.</p>
<p>In its announcement, Lalamove CEO Shing Chow said its Series E will be used to enter more fourth and fifth-tier Chinese cities, adding &#8220;we believe the mobile internet’s transformation of China’s logistics industry is far from over.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other companies that have recently raised significant funding rounds for their logistics operations in China include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/manbang-1-7-billion-funding/">Manbang</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/alibaba-6-6-billion-investment-yto/">YTO</a>.</p>
<p>Lalamove’s (known in Chinese as Huolala) Series E announcement said the company experienced a 93% drop in shipment volume at the beginning of the year, due to the COVID-19 pandemic, but has experienced a strong rebound, with order volume up 82% year-over-year even before Double 11.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rPwcM4rBpH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/china-3-billion-parcels-post-covid-singles-day/">China to ship 3 billion parcels during post-COVID Singles&#8217; Day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;China to ship 3 billion parcels during post-COVID Singles&#8217; Day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/china-3-billion-parcels-post-covid-singles-day/embed/#?secret=rPwcM4rBpH" data-secret="rPwcM4rBpH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/on-demand-logistics-company-lalamove-gets-515-million-series-e/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese autonomous driving startup WeRide bags $200M in funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/weride-200-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/weride-200-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 03:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yutong]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WeRide, one of China’s most-funded startups developing autonomous driving capabilities, said on Wednesday that it has raised a $200 million strategic round from Chinese bus maker Yutong. Mega investments aren’t uncommon at companies like WeRide developing the next-generation level 4 driving standard, which denotes that the car can handle the majority of driving situations independently without [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/weride" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="weride">WeRide, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> one of China’s most-funded startups developing autonomous driving capabilities, said on Wednesday that it has raised a $200 million strategic round from Chinese<a href="https://en.yutong.com/"> bus maker Yutong</a>.</p>
<p>Mega investments aren’t uncommon at companies like WeRide developing the next-generation level 4 driving standard, which denotes that the car can handle the majority of driving situations independently without human intervention.</p>
<p>WeRide did not disclose its valuation for this round, which is the first tranche of its Series B round, a company spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new funding will see WeRide joining hands with Yutong, a 57-year-old company, to make autonomous driving minibuses and city buses as well as work together on R&amp;D, vehicle platforms and mobility services. The partners have already jointly developed a front-loaded driverless minibus for mass-production. The model, which comes without a steering wheel, accelerator or brakes, is designed for operating in urban open roads, said WeRide.</p>
<p>Alliance Ventures, the strategic venture capital arm of Renault-Nissan-Mitsubishi, became WeRide&#8217;s strategic investor<a href="https://www.weride.ai/series-a/"> in 2018</a> following the completion of the startup&#8217;s Series A round, which was partially funded by the Chinese facial recognition giant SenseTime.</p>
<p>Autonomous driving startups in China are racing to showcase their progress, in part to attract funding for their cash-bleeding businesses. Alibaba-backed AutoX, for instance, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/autox-removes-safety-drivers/">began deploying driverless cars</a> on the roads in Shenzhen in a bold move. WeRide and its rivals are testing various levels of autonomous driving vehicles in both the United States and major Chinese cities where local policies are supporting the futurist transportation tech.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QCsmCObslI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/autox-removes-safety-drivers/">AutoX becomes China&#8217;s first to remove safety drivers from robotaxis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AutoX becomes China&#8217;s first to remove safety drivers from robotaxis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/autox-removes-safety-drivers/embed/#?secret=QCsmCObslI" data-secret="QCsmCObslI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Capital&#8217;s attitude is shifting and increasingly bullish about autonomous driving and its commercial future following the COVID-19 pandemic [in China]. Many investments are happening in this space because investors don&#8217;t want to miss out on any potential leaders in autonomous driving,&#8221; the WeRide spokesperson said. &#8220;Our Series B round has attracted a lot of interest.&#8221;</p>
<p>WeRide’s competitors include Pony.ai in its backyard Guangzhou, AutoX and Deeproute.ai in Shenzhen, Momenta in Suzhou and Baidu in Beijing, to name a few.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IxCRV8MNqk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/30/momenta-robotaxis/">Daimler-backed Momenta says its robotaxis will be fully driverless and profitable in 2024</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Daimler-backed Momenta says its robotaxis will be fully driverless and profitable in 2024&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/30/momenta-robotaxis/embed/#?secret=IxCRV8MNqk" data-secret="IxCRV8MNqk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/weride-200-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090387</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TaskRabbit is resetting customer passwords after finding &#8216;suspicious activity&#8217; on its network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/taskrabbit-resets-passwords-suspicious-activity-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/taskrabbit-resets-passwords-suspicious-activity-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 01:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ikea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TaskRabbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TaskRabbit has reset an unknown number of customer passwords after confirming it detected &#8220;suspicious activity&#8221; on its network. The IKEA -owned online marketplace for on-demand labor said it reset user passwords out of an abundance of caution and that it &#8220;took steps to prevent access to any user accounts,&#8221; a TaskRabbit spokesperson told TechCrunch. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/taskrabbit" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="taskrabbit">TaskRabbit <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has reset an unknown number of customer passwords after confirming it detected &#8220;suspicious activity&#8221; on its network.</p>
<p>The <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/ikea-systems" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="ikea-systems">IKEA <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>-owned online marketplace for on-demand labor said it reset user passwords out of an abundance of caution and that it &#8220;took steps to prevent access to any user accounts,&#8221; a TaskRabbit spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The company later confirmed it was a credential stuffing attack, where existing sets of exposed or breached usernames and passwords are matched against different websites to access accounts.</p>
<p>&#8220;We acted in an abundance of caution and reset passwords for many TaskRabbit accounts, including all users who had not logged in since May 1, 2020, as well as all users who logged in during the time period of the attack, even though most of the latter activity was attributable to users’ regular use of our services,&#8221; the spokesperson said.</p>
<p>&#8220;As always, the safety and security of the TaskRabbit community is our priority, and we will continue to be vigilant about protecting our users’ personal information,&#8221; said the spokesperson.</p>
<p>TaskRabbit customers were alerted to the incident in a vague email that only noted their password had been recently changed &#8220;as a security precaution,&#8221; without saying what specifically prompted the account change. TechCrunch confirmed that the email was legitimate.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2090374" style="width: 710px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2090374" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2090374" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/taskrabbit.jpg" alt="" width="700" height="818" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/taskrabbit.jpg 1101w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/taskrabbit.jpg?resize=128,150 128w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/taskrabbit.jpg?resize=257,300 257w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/taskrabbit.jpg?resize=768,897 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/taskrabbit.jpg?resize=582,680 582w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/taskrabbit.jpg?resize=43,50 43w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2090374" class="wp-caption-text">The password reset email sent to TaskRabbit customers. (Image: Sarah Perez/TechCrunch)</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s not uncommon for companies to reset passwords after a security incident where customer or account information is accessed or stolen in a breach.</p>
<p>Last year, online apparel marketplace StockX reset customer passwords after initially citing &#8220;system updates,&#8221; but later admitted it took action after it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/01/stockx-security-concerns-reset-passwords/">found suspicious activity</a> on its network. Days later, a hacker provided TechCrunch with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/03/stockx-hacked-millions-records/">6.8 million StockX account records</a> stolen from the company&#8217;s servers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2Yv6URp4lU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/03/stockx-hacked-millions-records/">StockX was hacked, exposing millions of customers&#8217; data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;StockX was hacked, exposing millions of customers&#8217; data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/03/stockx-hacked-millions-records/embed/#?secret=2Yv6URp4lU" data-secret="2Yv6URp4lU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>TaskRabbit&#8217;s freelance labor marketplace was founded in 2008, and grew over time from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/07/10/taskrabbit-debuts-revamped-platform-launches-new-website-and-mobile-apps/">an auction-style platform</a> for negotiating tasks and errands to a more mature and tailored marketplace to match customers with contractors. That eventually attracted the attention of furniture retailer IKEA, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/28/ikea-buys-taskrabbit/">bought the startup in September 2017</a> after TaskRabbit put itself on the market for a strategic buyer.</p>
<p>The year after the acquisition, however, TaskRabbit <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/16/taskrabbits-app-is-offline-while-it-investigates-a-cybersecurity-incident/">had to take its website and app down</a> due to a &#8220;cybersecurity incident.&#8221; The company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/18/taskrabbit-ceo-posts-statement-as-its-app-returns-following-a-cybersecurity-breach/">later revealed</a> an attacker had gained unauthorized access to its systems. Then-TaskRabbit CEO Stacy Brown-Philpot said the company had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/18/taskrabbit-ceo-posts-statement-as-its-app-returns-following-a-cybersecurity-breach/">contracted with an outside forensics team</a> to identify what customer information had been compromised by the attack, and urged both users and providers to stay vigilant in monitoring their own accounts for suspicious activity.</p>
<p>Following the attack, the company said it was implementing several new security measures and would work on making the log-in process more secure. It also said it would reduce the amount of data retained about taskers and customers as well as &#8220;enhance overall network cyber threat detection technology.&#8221;</p>
<p>Brown-Philpot <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/stacy-brown-philpot-is-stepping-down-as-ceo-of-taskrabbit/">left TaskRabbit earlier this year</a>, and the CEO role has <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ania-smith-named-chief-executive-officer-at-taskrabbit-301110433.html">since been filled by</a> former Airbnb and Uber Eats leader, Ania Smith.</p>
<p><em>Updated with additional comment from TaskRabbit.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nCKBBUdjpP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/how-to-respond-to-a-data-breach/">How to respond to a data breach</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to respond to a data breach&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/how-to-respond-to-a-data-breach/embed/#?secret=nCKBBUdjpP" data-secret="nCKBBUdjpP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/taskrabbit-resets-passwords-suspicious-activity-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090350</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Stimulus bill increases penalties for illegal streaming services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/daily-crunch-stimulus-streaming/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/daily-crunch-stimulus-streaming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The stimulus bill includes significant changes to copyright law and enforcement, the Biden administration may have to build a presidential Twitter following from scratch and we round up the startups that shut down this year. This is your Daily Crunch for December 22, 2020. The big story: Stimulus bill increases penalties for illegal streaming services [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The stimulus bill includes significant changes to copyright law and enforcement, the Biden administration may have to build a presidential Twitter following from scratch and we round up the startups that shut down this year. This is your Daily Crunch for December 22, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Stimulus bill increases penalties for illegal streaming services</strong></p>
<p>While we wrote several stories yesterday about the tech implications of the new stimulus bill (and highlighted it in yesterday&#8217;s Daily Crunch), more details are emerging — like the fact that it will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/stimulus-bill-streaming/">make illegal streaming for profit a felony</a>, punishable by fines or up to 10 years of imprisonment.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The language of the bill seems to focus on commercial piracy services, rather than individuals or Twitch streamers — a point that one of its sponsors, Senator Thom Tillis, emphasized in a statement, claiming that &#8220;no individual streamer has to worry about the fear of prosecution.&#8221;</p>
<p>On the copyright front, the bill also creates a new Copyright Claims Board to handle copyright infringement claims of up to $30,000.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/google-cisco-and-vmware-join-microsoft-to-oppose-nso-group-in-whatsapp-spyware-case/">Google, Cisco and VMware join Microsoft to oppose NSO Group in WhatsApp spyware case</a> — A coalition of companies have filed an amicus brief in support of a legal case brought by WhatsApp accusing NSO Group of using an undisclosed vulnerability to hack into at least 1,400 devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/twitters-potus-account-will-reportedly-be-reset-to-zero-followers-when-biden-takes-over/">Twitter’s POTUS account will reportedly be reset to zero followers when Biden takes over</a> — Twitter, meanwhile, says it has &#8220;been in ongoing discussions with the Biden transition team on a number of aspects related to White House account transfers.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/remember-the-startups-we-lost-in-2020/">Remembering the startups we lost in 2020</a> — A look back at startups large and small that didn&#8217;t make it through hell year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/horizon-robotics-700-million-funding/">Horizon Robotics, a Chinese rival to Nvidia, seeks to raise over $700M</a> — Horizon Robotics is a five-year-old unicorn specializing in AI chips for robots and autonomous vehicles.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/austin-based-returnsafe-raises-3-25-million-for-its-employee-health-management-tools/">Austin-based ReturnSafe raises $3.25M for its employee health management tools</a> — Management toolkits that track employee health are piling into the market.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/to-win-post-pandemic-edtech-needs-to-start-thinking-big/">To win post-pandemic, edtech needs to start thinking big</a> — After a noisy 2020, can the sector maintain momentum?</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/one-final-100m-arr-company-and-the-startups-we-want-to-meet-in-2021/">One final $100M ARR company and the startups we want to meet in 2021</a> — Let&#8217;s talk about Nexthink.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/with-a-50b-run-rate-in-reach-can-anyone-stop-aws/">With a $50B run rate in reach, can anyone stop AWS?</a> — AWS has taken advantage of first-to-market status to become the most successful player in the space.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/gift-guide-techcrunchs-favorite-things-of-2020/">Gift Guide: TechCrunch’s Favorite Things of 2020</a> — Many of the podcasts, songs, movies, people and more that got us through this year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/nasa-opens-new-launchpad-at-kennedy-space-center-meant-to-serve-multiple-commercial-launch-customers/">NASA opens new launchpad at Kennedy Space Center meant to serve multiple commercial launch customers</a> — The purpose of LC-48 is very explicitly to fill “a need for new, low-cost launch systems with very fast turnaround cycles.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/daily-crunch-stimulus-streaming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Substack explains its ‘hands-off’ approach to content moderation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/substack-explains-its-hands-off-approach-to-content-moderation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/substack-explains-its-hands-off-approach-to-content-moderation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 22:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Substack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090322</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Content moderation has been a thorny topic in 2020. And when I say “thorny,” I mean in the sense of having multiple congressional hearings on the subject. Twitter and Facebook in particular have been mired in concerns around the subject, fielding complaints that they both haven’t done enough to weed out problematic content and suggestions [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Content moderation has been a thorny topic in 2020. And when I say “thorny,” I mean in the sense of having multiple congressional hearings on the subject. Twitter and Facebook in particular have been mired in concerns around the subject, fielding complaints that they both haven’t done enough to weed out problematic content and suggestions that they’re a censorship-happy, shadow-banning enemy of the First Amendment.</p>
<p>The latter appears to be the sole reason for the existence of the right wing-focused Twitter competitor, Parler.</p>
<p>As <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/substack" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="substack">Substack <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> grows in popularity, the newsletter platform is going to face some tremendously difficult questions around content moderation. Today<a href="https://blog.substack.com/p/substacks-view-of-content-moderation"> it published a lengthy blog post</a> hoping to nip some of those concerns in the bud. The write-up offers some caveats, but largely espouses the platform’s commitment to free speech, noting:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>In most cases, we don’t think that censoring content is helpful, and in fact it often backfires. Heavy-handed censorship can draw more attention to content than it otherwise would have enjoyed, and at the same time it can give the content creators a martyr complex that they can trade off for future gain. We prefer a contest of ideas. We believe dissent and debate is important. We celebrate nonconformity.</p></blockquote>
<p>The stance reflects Substack’s commitment to a subscription-based model, rather than the ads that currently keep the lights on for services like Twitter and Facebook. Instead, it takes a 10% cut of writers’ subscription revenue. Certainly that frees it up from sponsorship boycotts to some degree. The subscription model also means that users have to opt into specific content more so than on platforms like Twitter and Facebook, where content boundaries are far more fluid.</p>
<p>“We are happy to compete with ‘Substack but with more controls on speech’ just as we are happy to compete with ‘Substack but with advertising,’ ” the company writes.</p>
<p>Of course, there are financial considerations &#8212; there always are. Substack has a vested interest in supporting right-wing and conservative voices who have decried Facebook and Twitter’s practices. Notably, The Dispatch is at the top of the service’s politics leaderboard. In an interview with TechCrunch earlier this year, editor Stephen Hayes called the service, “unapologetically center-right,” while its current blurb refers to it as “conservative.”</p>
<p>“None of these views are neutral,” Substack writes. “Many Silicon Valley technology companies strive to make their platforms apolitical, but we think such a goal is impossible to achieve.” There’s no doubt some truth in that. Any position on content moderation can be viewed as a political one to some degree. And equally, none will make everyone &#8212; or even most people &#8212; completely happy.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s also easy to see the service facing some major tests of its current hands-off approach as the service continues to grow in popularity. The service’s approach has involved putting its name out there in front of consumers, meaning it won’t be viewed as a kind of invisible publishing platform.</p>
<p>Substack is quick to add that there is, naturally, content that crosses the line in spite of this. “Of course, there are limits,” it writes. “We do not allow porn on Substack, for example, or spam. We do not allow doxxing or harassment.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZWi34M7xwg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/the-dispatch-substack-1-million-revenue/">The Dispatch, a news organization built on Substack, passes $1M in annual revenue</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Dispatch, a news organization built on Substack, passes $1M in annual revenue&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/the-dispatch-substack-1-million-revenue/embed/#?secret=ZWi34M7xwg" data-secret="ZWi34M7xwg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/substack-explains-its-hands-off-approach-to-content-moderation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090322</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
