<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 11:09:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Digital Diplomacy 4.0: Return of the Jedi?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/07/digital-diplomacy-4-0-return-of-the-jedi/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/07/digital-diplomacy-4-0-return-of-the-jedi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 18:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital diplomacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diplomacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Global Affairs Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technodiplomat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tom Fletcher Contributor Tom Fletcher, CMG, is principal of Hertford College, Oxford. He is a former U.K. ambassador and 10 Downing Street foreign policy adviser to three prime ministers, and a visiting professor at NYU. He is the author of the bestselling "The Naked Diplomat: Power and Politics in the Digital Age" (2016) and the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Tom Fletcher</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Tom Fletcher, CMG, is principal of Hertford College, Oxford. He is a former U.K. ambassador and 10 Downing Street foreign policy adviser to three prime ministers, and a visiting professor at NYU. He is the author of the bestselling "The Naked Diplomat: Power and Politics in the Digital Age" (2016) and the forthcoming "Ten Survival Skills for a World in Flux" (2022). 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><em>As British ambassador to Lebanon, Tom Fletcher was one of the first ambassadors to &#8220;go digital.&#8221; Ten years on, he reflects on what the first wave of &#8220;technodiplomats&#8221; got right and wrong, and where digital diplomacy goes next.</em></p>
<p>Like every industry or craft, diplomacy — a world once dominated by protocol and platitudes, maps and chaps — has already been hugely disrupted by digital technology.</p>
<p>Also like many professions, the most visible impact has been on the tools: better kit, better comms (internal and external), faster pace. Again like many, the real impact has been less visible and is about culture: the humility that comes from understanding how power has shifted, the agility that the new tools allow, the effectiveness that comes from being more inclusive and the transparency that comes from increased public understanding of what was once a closed world.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2228931" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2226330 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?w=300" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>Ten years ago this fall, I was posted as Her Majesty&#8217;s envoy to Lebanon. At 36, I was young for the role. The Arab Spring was firing up young people across the region and I wondered if technological change could transform the way statecraft engaged with people. I began experimenting with what we started to call (after a few clunky options like &#8220;Twiplomacy&#8221;) &#8220;digital diplomacy.&#8221; A decade on, digital diplomacy has already moved through several phases — three in fact — and stands on the threshold of a fourth. Much has been achieved. But if it is to succeed in putting more streetcraft into statecraft, we must take into account what we did right and wrong.</p>
<p>The first phase was a brave new world. With its 21st-century statecraft program under Secretary of State Hillary Clinton, the U.S. State Department led a period of excitement and optimism about the way that diplomats could use the new tools of communication and connection. For the ambassadors of that era who genuinely adopted and adapted, these were heady times. The rules from capitals were loose: One minister told me that he didn’t care what I tried as long as it stayed out of the U.K. media. Many of us were able to proceed until apprehended. There were plenty of mistakes. And risks: The smartphone I tweeted relentlessly from was also the device that terrorists used to track my movements.</p>
<p>But this was a period when we could surprise people with a desire to connect, engage and show some humility. It seemed possible to imagine that social media would open up societies and promote real agency and freedom. One British ambassador drank so much of the Kool-Aid that he even suggested that the most powerful weapon in the Middle East was the smartphone. I was wrong about that, so far.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The second phase was the institutionalization of digital diplomacy. We started to create structures around the wider dialogue between the old emperors and the new. Worried by the implications for geopolitics of the pace of technological change, I left the U.K. government to try to make the case for the urgency of this effort. After my 2017 <a href="https://www.unitednetworks.ae/">report</a> on the United Nations, the U.N. launched an effort for Big Tech and government to talk <em>to</em> rather than <em>past</em> each other. Both the U.N.’s High Level Panel and the Global Tech Panel were genuine and effective attempts to translate between those disrupting global politics, economics and society and those nominally still in charge, an alternative to trying to summon the Zuckerbergs before parliamentary or congressional committees. In <a href="https://tomfletcher.global/publications/details/8">&#8220;The Naked Diplomat,&#8221;</a> I had proposed that countries should appoint &#8220;tech ambassadors.&#8221; The Danes went for it, with success, challenging the tech companies to engage with states in a veritable dialogue.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, foreign ministries adjusted to social media far more quickly than to any previous technology. Having been one of only four U.K. ambassadors on Twitter in 2011, within a few years all but four were, with some like John Casson in Egypt amassing over <a href="https://twitter.com/johncassonuk?lang=en">one million followers</a>. For a profession without many ways to assess impact, there was real willingness to experiment with social media. I spoke at over 20 conferences of ambassadors, urging colleagues to give it a try, show the human behind the handle and engage (rather than transmit). I used to tell them it was like the largest diplomatic reception they could imagine: Don’t stand at the margins, say nothing or bellow across the room. Yes, there were risks. But the biggest risks were not to be in the conversation.</p>
<p>As more adopted this approach, foreign ministries faced new trade-offs over agility versus confidentiality of their communication. My 2016 <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/future-fco-report">review</a> of the Foreign Office recommended a pivot toward the former: Perhaps Sir Kim Darroch, the outstanding U.K. ambassador driven out by former President Trump over his leaked cables, might subsequently have disagreed. But we are now reliant on that ability to communicate at speed.</p>
<p>Diplomacy over the last two years would have been unimaginable without Zoom and WhatsApp. For a profession that used to do everything to minimize direct contacts between leaders, diplomats were quick to embrace videoconferencing once the tech made it a serious option. The pandemic drove summits and conferences online, saving enormous amounts of carbon with little obvious negative impact on the outcomes.</p>
<p>The third phase overlapped with the second: the empire struck back. Authoritarian governments found new ways to use digital technology to suppress freedom. Trump exploited Twitter to fire up xenophobia, prejudice and insurrection. More creatively he also used it — as at home — to court potential allies and to pressure diplomatic opponents. Meanwhile, Russia’s Vladimir Putin weaponized the internet against democracy and built troll factories. Twitter mobs made it harder to share the nuance of complex diplomatic positions, let alone use social media to reach compromise and common ground. Polarization was clickbait and the center did not hold. Governments realized that cyber was the new battleground and started to think in terms of defense.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Big Tech grew, morphing in some cases into entities more powerful and sometimes more reactionary than governments. Mischievously I had wondered aloud in 2013 whether we should ask Google to be on the U.N. Security Council. Google might now ask why it should bother. While Big Tech grew and flexed its muscles, it quietly recruited the talent, depriving governments of human capital as well as taxes. Symbolically, and perhaps inevitably, the (excellent) first Danish tech ambassador was poached by Microsoft and Britain’s Liberal Democrat leader was poached by Facebook. As the legal arms race intensified, the EU’s titanic clashes with Big Tech over data or incitement were a long way from the idealism of the brave new world phase, when we genuinely believed that we could solve more problems together.</p>
<p>Where does this leave us today? I am now more of a realist about technology and diplomacy, but I remain an optimistic one. We can still crack challenges together, including the <a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals">Sustainable Development Goals</a>. But to do so, governments must be more honest about what they can’t do alone. Tech needs more patience to stick with slower moving and often clumsy states, and more honesty about where it has become part of the problem.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, diplomats can continue to use technology to make them more effective: My research group at New York University worked on wearable technology to help a diplomat read a room; a Diplopedia to do a better job of conserving diplomatic records; and intelligent and transparent use of sentiment mining to better understand public opinion. I stand by the hypothesis that the more oversight the public has of issues of war, the more peaceful government policy will be. Perhaps one of the most exciting areas for diplomacy will be the potential to combine it with the latest advances in collective psychology and social media to make peace between societies rather than between states, and between nations and their histories.</p>
<p>The next phase of digital diplomacy should also see work on the next great peace processes: with the planet, with Big Tech, between young and old, between hosts and migrant communities, and ultimately maybe with technology itself. I think digital diplomacy can help us deliver better outcomes on each of those.</p>
<p>Finally, this next phase of digital diplomacy will see diplomats returning to the basics of the craft. We’ll need a more focused effort to develop citizen diplomats, equipped with vital diplomatic skills like empathy and emotional intelligence: Education is therefore upstream diplomacy. As <a href="https://www.tortoisemedia.com/2021/10/29/how-to-save-multilateralism/">I’ve proposed elsewhere</a>, we’ll need an old school pen and paper effort to rewrite the global rules for protection of our freedoms in an online world. We’ll need embassies to escape from the confines of buildings and return to their original mission as groups of people sent to connect. And we’ll need diplomats who can still do what Edward Murrow called the &#8220;last three feet,&#8221; that crucial human connection that will be the last diplomatic skill to be automated.</p>
<p>That is an exciting and urgent agenda. If diplomacy did not exist we would need to invent it. But now we need to <em>reinvent</em> it. And that is too important to leave to diplomats.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-footer.jpg" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/07/digital-diplomacy-4-0-return-of-the-jedi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228931</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>H2O.ai raises $100M at a $1.6B pre-money valuation for tools to make AI usable by any kind of enterprise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/07/h2o-ai-raises-100m-at-a-1-7b-valuation-for-tools-to-make-ai-usable-by-any-kind-of-enterprise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/07/h2o-ai-raises-100m-at-a-1-7b-valuation-for-tools-to-make-ai-usable-by-any-kind-of-enterprise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accenture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aetna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asset Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bare metal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celesta Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Commonwealth Bank of Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crane venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Franklin Templeton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[h2o]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H2O.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mountain View]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural language processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NetApp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nvidia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p&g]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PitchBook Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platfora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ServiceNow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sherpas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unilever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[H2O.ai &#8212; a startup that has developed an open-source framework as well as proprietary apps that make it easier for any kind of enterprise to build and operate artificial intelligence-based services &#8212; has seen a surge of interest as AI applications have become more ubiquitous, and enterprises beyond tech companies want to get in on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">H2O.ai &#8212; a startup that has developed an open-source framework as well as proprietary apps that make it easier for any kind of enterprise to build and operate artificial intelligence-based services &#8212; has seen a surge of interest as AI applications have become more ubiquitous, and enterprises beyond tech companies want to get in on the action. Now, it has raised $100 million to fuel its growth, a round of funding that values H2O.ai at $1.7 billion post-money ($1.6 billion pre-money).</p>
<p>This is a Series E round, and it&#8217;s being led by a strategic backer, the Commonwealth Bank of Australia (CBA), which has been a customer of the startup and will be using the backing to kick off a deeper partnership between the two to build new services. Others in the round include Goldman Sachs, Pivot Investment Partners, Crane Venture Partners and Celesta Capital. Further plans for the funding include building more products for H2O.ai as a whole, and hiring more talent to continue expanding the company&#8217;s H2O AI Hybrid Cloud platform.</p>
<p>This is not the first time that a customer has led a round as a strategic backer: in 2019, Goldman Sachs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/h20-ai-announces-72-5m-series-d-led-by-goldman-sachs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">led the company&#8217;s Series D of $72.5 million</a>. As a sign of how the company has been growing, and the general appetite for what it does, H2O&#8217;s valuation has leapfrogged since that last round, when it was valued at $400 million, per <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/55882-36/company/profile" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PitchBook data</a>. Mountain View-based H2O.ai has raised $246.5 million to date.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230290" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The fact that both of the last rounds have been led by big banks that are also customers of H2O.ai&#8217;s speaks a lot to where the opportunity has been for the startup. Sri Ambati, the founder and CEO (who previously was also a co-founder of Platfora, which was acquired by Workday), told me over email that about 40% of the company&#8217;s revenues currently come from the very wide and all-encompassing world of financial services.</p>
<p>&#8220;Retail banking, credit cards, payments &#8212; almost every payment system from PayPal to MasterCard are customers of H2O,&#8221; he said. On the equities side, companies power fixed income, asset management, and mortgage backed security services using H2O&#8217;s technology, with MarketAxess, Franklin Templeton, and BNY Mellon also &#8220;strong&#8221; customers, he said.</p>
<p>That is also seeing a growing complement of business from other verticals, he added: Unilever, Reckitt P&amp;G are among those in consumer goods; UPS is one of its users in logistics and delivery; Chipotle is among those in food services; and he said that AT&amp;T &#8220;is one of our largest customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Covid-19 has had a role to play here, too.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Manufacturing became a fast-growing vertical due to supply chain disruption and demand sensing,&#8221; he said of the pandemic. &#8220;We launched H2O AI Health to help our hospitals and providers, payers like Aetna and pharma customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Notably, H2O.ai is also now breaking ground into working more with other tech companies that want to build more AI into their own workflows to in turn provide services to their own customers. &#8220;Our latest wins are in vertical clouds and SaaS ISVs,&#8221; Ambati said.</p>
<p>The company has offered an open source component to its services, which it calls simply <a href="https://www.h2o.ai/products/h2o/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">H2O</a>, from its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/11/09/h2o-ai-raises-20m-for-its-open-source-machine-learning-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earliest days</a>, and that is now used by over 20,000 enterprises. Part of the reason for that is its flexibility: H2O.ai says that its open source framework works both on top of existing big data infrastructure, on bare metal or on top of existing Hadoop, Spark or Kubernetes clusters and is able to ingest data directly from HDFS, Spark, S3, Azure Data Lake or any other data source into it’s in-memory distributed key-value store.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our open source platform gives freedom and ability for customers to build their own AI centers of competence and excellence,&#8221; Ambati said of the open source tools. &#8220;We are like the Tenzing Sherpas of the AI mountains helping our customers to traverse and conquer AI peaks.&#8221;</p>
<p>That framework can be used by engineers to build customized applications, while H2O.ai&#8217;s proprietary tools provide more completed applications in areas like fraud detection, churn prediction, anomaly detection, price optimization and credit scoring &#8212; areas that can benefit from the ingestion of massive amounts of data in order to gain better insights into what might happen next: these sit either as a complement to what human analysts and data scientists might be able to unearth, or potentially, in some cases, as a replacement for the more basic work they might do. In all, there are currently some 45 applications in all.</p>
<p>The plan, Ambati said, is to over time build out more of these, which will reside in &#8220;app stores&#8221; in specific verticals offering a range of its proprietary, pre-built tools particular to the demands of each of them.</p>
<p>The trend fueling H2O.ai&#8217;s growth has been gaining momentum for several years now.</p>
<p>Artificial intelligence holds a lot of promise for the world of enterprise IT: used well, tools like machine learning, natural language processing and computer vision can speed up productivity, or even open up completely new areas of opportunity for an organization. Over time, it can save companies billions of dollars in operational and other costs.</p>
<p>One big issue, however, is that in many cases, organizations might lack the internal teams to build or carry through projects that use AI, and that&#8217;s before considering the fact that as needs and parameters evolve all of that infrastructure will need updating, too. Technology touches everything in an enterprise these days, but not every enterprise is a tech company.</p>
<p>H2O.ai is not the first or only startup that has aimed to fill this gap in the market, although it seems to have managed its task a little more successfully than others.</p>
<p>Notably, Element.AI out of Canada was built out on the back of a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/13/element-ai-raises-151m-on-a-600-700m-valuation-to-help-companies-build-and-run-ai-solutions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">large amount of funding and buy-in</a> from big tech companies like Microsoft and Nvidia also to address the idea of democratizing AI for the wider world of enterprises that might lack the resources to build and run AI tools themselves, but could very much benefit from them before their businesses simply get cannibalized by the many AI-fuelled tech companies moving into their spaces. It had a strong focus on integration (it was a little like an Accenture for AI services) but never managed to make a big enough jump from concept to business and was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/servicenow-is-acquiring-element-ai-the-canadian-startup-building-ai-services-for-enterprises/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">eventually acquired</a>, in 2020, by ServiceNow to complement its own efforts to build tools for businesses.</p>
<p>Ambati said that only about 10% of H2O.ai&#8217;s business is in the area of services, with the remainder, 90%, coming from its products, as an explanation for why one startup&#8217;s approach worked while another did not.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is easy to get lured by services in data science and AI,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Being true to our product maker culture and yet building deep customer empathy and listening is critical to success. Customers experience our maker culture and become makers themselves. We are continuously making our software easier (democratizing) low-code, reusable recipes and automation through AI Cloud and building data pipelines, AI AppStores and delivering AI as a service that our customers can use to improve their customer experiences, brands and communities.</p>
<p>&#8220;The big difference &#8212; we are raising a forest, not just a tree. H2O AI Cloud, H2O Wave our low-code Application Development, H2O AI AppStores, Marketplace and H2O-3 Open Source ML are at the core of AI Applications and software already and we are partnering with customers and their ecosystem of partners and developers.&#8221;</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a play, and business, resonating well with investors, too,</p>
<p>“Commonwealth Bank has a significant asset in the millions of data points collected every day. AI already has helped us to improve our customer experience, however, we know there is untapped potential to do more,&#8221; said Matt Comyn, CEO of CBA, in a statement. &#8220;The investment in and strategic partnership with H2O.ai extends our leadership in artificial intelligence and ultimately boosts the bank’s ability to offer leading digital propositions and reimagined products and services to customers.&#8221; Dr. Andrew McMullan, chief data and analytics officer at CBA, will join the H2O.ai board.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/07/h2o-ai-raises-100m-at-a-1-7b-valuation-for-tools-to-make-ai-usable-by-any-kind-of-enterprise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230290</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All things in moderation, including moderation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/all-things-in-moderation-including-moderation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/all-things-in-moderation-including-moderation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 18:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to Startups Weekly, a fresh human-first take on this week’s startup news and trends. To get this in your inbox, subscribe here. Indiegogo, an early startup that capitalized on the crowdfunding movement, will begin more closely screening crowdfunding campaigns on its platform, it announced this week. The Verge says that the company created an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to Startups Weekly, a fresh human-first take on this week’s startup news and trends. To get this in your inbox, </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><em>subscribe here.</em></a></p>
<p>Indiegogo, an early startup that capitalized on the crowdfunding movement, will begin more closely screening crowdfunding campaigns on its platform,<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22757421/indiegogo-crowdfunding-campaign-screening-fraud-gofundme"> it announced this week.</a></p>
<p>The Verge says that the company created an internal review board to oversee and evaluate the riskiest campaigns on its platform, as determined by its community of backers. This board can ban owners from launching campaigns or just enforce broader terms of service to ensure legitimacy. The startup also made an alliance with its chief rival, crowdfunding platform GoFundMe, to create a new entity for best practices and to remove bad actors.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230164" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Here’s a key excerpt from the story by <a href="https://twitter.com/SocialKimLy">Kim Lyons</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Candidly, we have not always lived up to our backers’ expectations,” said Will Haines, vice president of product and customer trust at Indiegogo. When the company launched in 2008, there were few restrictions on would-be entrepreneurs seeking to raise money from like-minded backers. But Haines says that “open” isn’t what the crowdfunding community really wants now, more than a decade later.</p></blockquote>
<p>I’m not going to lie, I was a little surprised this didn’t get more attention on Twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_/status/1455937547268288512">despite my best efforts)</a>. While I’m not in the business of theorizing why that was, I do have the luxury of asking people questions about their thoughts, retweets be damned. My immediate question for folks was, &#8220;What does Indiegogo’s new stance mean for the broader crowdfunding market?&#8221; After all, the ecosystem is built on access, optionality and turning scrappy ideas into actual products. So, I crowdsourced some thoughts!</p>
<p>Republic, a crowdfunding platform that recently raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/republic-may-build-a-secondary-exchange-for-digital-securities-fueled-by-150-million-in-new-funding/">$150 million Series B</a>, isn’t a direct competitor because it focuses more on equity crowdfunding campaigns versus Indiegogo’s specialty of rewards-based and donation-based crowdfunding. Chief of Staff Kyle McCormick says this makes his company “a very different beast.”</p>
<p>“Even though we may share users with platforms like Kickstarter and Indiegogo, we&#8217;re going after a different part of that user&#8217;s wallet — their investable assets on which they hope to make a return. Not checking for fraud (at a bare minimum) would be deeply negligent,” he said. Republic may be forced to have a more moderated platform due to its focus, but McCormick said that the company is “far from the most curated player” in the space.</p>
<p>As a result, a majority of companies raising through Republic already have momentum, either through venture capital money or accelerator signal, before they try to crowdfund. McCormick admitted that there are still challenges with this model: “How do we deliver quality in a scalable way? How do we support venture-backed companies without mirroring gender and race biases in venture capital? All things we think about everyday.&#8221;</p>
<p>Entrepreneur Sahil Lavingia built Gumroad to become an online platform for creators to buy and sell digital goods. Lavingia, who raised money for Gumroad through Republic, said that “manually reviewing each creator goes against the ethos that undergirds the excitement behind the creator economy and speeds up the transition to Web 3.0 — neither of which benefit Indiegogo.”</p>
<p>“The creator economy is about enabling a new set of artists and entrepreneurs to gain access to capital they were historically unable to get,” he said. “But perhaps there are unseen forces at play here, forcing their hand. The forces could be fear of failure. My colleague Brian Heater, who interviewed Indiegogo CEO Andy Yang months ago, pushed the executive on failure or shoddy <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/indiegogos-ceo-on-how-crowdfunding-navigated-the-pandemic/">campaigns that let down users.</a> Yang hinted that more trust and safety measures were to come.</p>
<blockquote><p>We’ve had our number of failures on our site, of campaigns that haven’t fulfilled or just, the campaigns have ghosted their backers, and we own up to that. Over the last two years, that’s been a major focus for us, of what can we do from a trust and safety perspective. It starts with education, making sure that the backers understand that crowdfunding is not shopping. It’s very visible on our checkout site, but again, Amazon and other companies have trained people, just click a button and I’m going to get it in two hours.</p></blockquote>
<p>The argument in favor of Indiegogo’s new constraints are thus that lack of moderation has burned users in the past, and since it’s hard to launch a project, why not hold everyone to a higher bar?</p>
<p>An early-stage entrepreneur thinks that the move to have more guardrails around campaigns is ultimately a quality assurance and traffic push. If the only campaigns that make it to the site, eventually, are ones that are aggressively pre-vetted, Indiegogo is creating a signal to consumers. It could create hype around select ideas and help those reach their funding goals. “To me, this isn’t about ‘risk,’ it&#8217;s about consumers not getting overwhelmed by optionality,” they said over DMs.</p>
<p>Ultimately, my question led to more questions around how moderation can lead to less accessibility, the importance of quality assurance with modern investors, and, ugh, how Web 3.0 fits into all of this (send study guides my way). It seems fair to think of Indiegogo’s move, while not revolutionary just yet, as yet another signal that people are rethinking the way we invest and exchange money.</p>
<p>In the rest of this newsletter, we’ll talk about new funding data for female founders, a very Chipper startup you need to know about and the economics of neobanks. As always, you can follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">@nmasc_</a> or direct message me on Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/natashathereporter/">@natashathereporter.</a></p>
<h2>Female founders are making a venture-backed comeback</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2191746" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191746" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2191746" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg" alt="Image of a magnet attracting a diverse group of hands." width="1024" height="512" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg 10000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg?resize=1536,768 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg?resize=2048,1024 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1313963674.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191746" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=melitas" target="_blank" rel="noopener">melitas <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>New PitchBook data shows that the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/female-founders-are-making-a-buzzing-venture-backed-comeback/">gender gap in startup fundraising is closing</a>, slowly. Female-founded companies raised $40.4 billion across 2,661 deals through the first three quarters of 2021, almost doubling 2019’s total of $23.7 billion and over 10 times 2011’s total of $3.6 billion.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>While funding for female founders is far from even and far from fair, the uptick in funding comes after a disappointing decline in 2020. The contrast makes the growth even more newsworthy, and I’d say it’s due to a change in who gets to be a decision-maker when writing checks. We talk more about tailwinds and our broader thoughts on the numbers in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/three-quarters-of-record-breaking-funding-for-female-founders-is-a-win/">the latest episode of Equity.</a></p>
<p><em>Oh, you want more numbers?</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/why-latams-fintech-boom-is-more-than-hype-and-superlative-venture-investment/">Why LatAm’s fintech boom is more than hype and superlative venture investment</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/tesla-recalls-11704-vehicles-after-identifying-full-self-driving-beta-software-error/">Tesla recalls 11,704 vehicles after identifying Full Self-Driving Beta software error</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/nerdwallets-ipo-proves-you-can-write-your-way-to-a-unicorn-valuation/">NerdWallet’s IPO proves you can write your way to a unicorn valuation</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>And the startup of the week is…</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099534" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099534" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2099534" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/africa-preseed-investment.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099534" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Chipper Cash! The fintech company, one of the most valuable private startups in Africa, was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/chipper-cash-gets-2b-valuation-with-150m-extension-round-led-by-ftx/">recently valued at over $2 billion </a>for its money-moving services. Sam Bankman-Fried’s cryptocurrency exchange platform FTX led the round. The investor said that they think Chipper will “make money transfer as simple as a text message and accelerate the adoption of crypto within Africa and beyond.”</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know:</strong> The startup recently landed a partnership with Twitter to help support the social media platform’s new Tip Jar integration — joining established companies like PayPal, Patreon, GoFundMe, Cash App and Venmo. Chipper Cash is also making strides outside of Africa, giving people from Europe the ability to send money to its other markets.</p>
<p><em>Honorable mentions:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/step-aside-nfts-aqua-thinks-modern-investors-should-dive-into-private-equity/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">Step aside NFTs, Aqua thinks modern investors should dive into private equity</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/guardians-collective-wants-to-make-parenting-easier-or-at-least-less-alone/">Guardians Collective wants to make parenting easier, or at least less alone</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/martie-launches-with-3m-to-divert-shelf-stable-food-items-from-landfills/">Martie launches with $3M to divert shelf-stable food items from landfills</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/neuro-id-takes-in-fresh-capital-to-combat-fraud-from-all-of-our-taps-types-and-swipes/">Neuro-ID takes in fresh capital to combat fraud from all of our taps, types and swipes</a></li>
<li>And, a reminder that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/the-inherent-tensions-within-venture-capital/">venture capital comes with strings attached</a>, often in the form of grow fast, make money incentives.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Neobanks needed this one</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2164365" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2164365" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2164365" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="686" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg?resize=768,515 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg?resize=680,456 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg?resize=1536,1029 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg?resize=2048,1372 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_Nubank-FINAL_q3_L.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2164365" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nigel Sussman</p></div></p>
<p>Nubank, a notorious neobank that we’ve been tracking for years, filed its F-1 this past week. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/nubanks-ipo-filing-gives-us-a-peek-into-neobank-economics/">Alex and I dissected the numbers</a> behind the massive consumer-focused fintech. And there was some solid, efficient evidence to pore over.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know:</strong> The fresh metrics could prove that neobanks are finally moving off their investing phase — spending a lot of money to eventually make a lot of money — and into a more stable, recurring revenue world. Other consumer banking IPOs in the pipeline include PicPay, which filed for a $100 million IPO on the Nasdaq in April and Chime, which raised a $750 million Series G in August and is reportedly going public by March 2022 at a valuation between $35 billion to $45 billion.</p>
<p><em>Need more Nu?</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-origin/">How contrarian hires and a pitch deck started Nubank’s $30 billion fintech empire</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-cofounder/">One woman’s drive to make a neobank as magical as Disney</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-scaling/">How Nubank’s CX strategy made it one of the most loved digital banks</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1-expansion/">Which Nubank will own the revolution?</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Around TC</h2>
<p>As some of you may know, I co-host <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, a podcast about the numbers and nuance behind tech headlines, with my colleagues Alex Wilhelm and Mary Ann Azevedo. We hit a new download record this month, so sending a big thank you to the millions of people who spend parts of their days with us.</p>
<p>I don’t do this often, but, if you like the podcast I’d love for you to go on<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780"> Apple Podcasts and give it a rating and review.</a> It’s free (!!!) and means a lot to our scrappy little team.</p>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<p><em>Seen on TechCrunch</em></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-google-wave/">Microsoft launches Google Wave</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/rivian-hit-with-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-that-alleges-toxic-bro-culture/">Rivian hit with gender discrimination lawsuit that alleges toxic ‘bro culture’</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-series-e/">Helion secures $2.2B to commercialize fusion energy</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/harry-potter-wizards-unite-shut-down-niantic/">Harry Potter: Wizards Unite, Niantic’s follow-up to Pokémon GO, is shutting down </a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/coinbase-acquires-indias-agara-for-over-40-million/">Coinbase to acquire India’s Agara for over $40 million </a></p>
<p><em>Seen on TechCrunch+</em></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/zillow-ibuying-exit-opendoor-offerpad/">What does Zillow’s exit tell us about the health of the iBuying market?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/vias-tiffany-chu-on-the-importance-of-govtech-for-planning-mobility-ecosystems/">Via’s Tiffany Chu on the importance of govtech for planning mobility ecosystems</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/why-we-rebuilt-our-equity-plan-for-flexibility-and-how-you-can-too/">Why we rebuilt our equity plan for flexibility (and how you can, too)</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/is-china-building-the-metaverse/">Is China building the metaverse?</a></p>
<p>Wishing you all a belated Happy Diwali and Sal Mubarak,</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/all-things-in-moderation-including-moderation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230164</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week in Apps: Facebook tests App Store rules, Apple fights sideloading, Netflix games go global</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/this-week-in-apps-facebook-tests-app-store-rules-apple-fights-sideloading-netflix-games-go-global/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/this-week-in-apps-facebook-tests-app-store-rules-apple-fights-sideloading-netflix-games-go-global/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 17:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[This Week In Apps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to This Week in Apps, the weekly TechCrunch series that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy. The app industry continues to grow, with a record 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also spent 3.5 trillion minutes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to This Week in Apps, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/">the weekly TechCrunch series</a> that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy.</p>
<p>The app industry continues to grow, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a record</a> 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">spent</a> 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices alone. And in the U.S., app usage surged ahead of the time spent watching live TV. Currently, the average American <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">watches</a> 3.7 hours of live TV per day, but now spends four hours per day on their mobile devices.</p>
<p>Apps aren’t just a way to pass idle hours — they’re also a big business. In 2019, mobile-first companies had a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/app-stores-saw-record-204-billion-app-downloads-in-2019-consumer-spend-of-120-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">combined</a> $544 billion valuation, 6.5x higher than those without a mobile focus. In 2020, investors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">poured</a> $73 billion in capital into mobile companies — a figure that’s up 27% year-over-year.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229922" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This Week in Apps offers a way to keep up with this fast-moving industry in one place with the latest from the world of apps, including news, updates, startup fundings, mergers and acquisitions, and suggestions about new apps and games to try, too.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you want This Week in Apps in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up here: <a href="http://techcrunch.com/newsletters">techcrunch.com/newsletters</a></strong></em></p>
<h1>Top Stories</h1>
<h3><strong>Google Play to allow support for alternative billing systems in South Korea</strong></h3>
<p id="speakable-summary">Following the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/south-korea-passes-anti-google-law-bill-to-curb-google-apple-in-app-payment-commission/">passage </a>of the so-called “anti-Google law” in South Korea, Google <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/google-play-to-support-alternative-billing-systems-in-south-korea-following-new-law/">says it will comply with the new mandate</a> by giving Android app developers on Google Play the ability to offer alternative payment systems alongside Google’s own. The legislation represents the first time a government has been able to force app stores to open up to third-party payment systems for in-app purchases — a change that could impact both app stores’ revenues, as developers look to skirt the tech giants’ commissions.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2229071" style="width: 508px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229071" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2229071" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png?w=498" alt="" width="498" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png 1172w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png?resize=110,150 110w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png?resize=220,300 220w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png?resize=768,1048 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png?resize=498,680 498w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png?resize=1125,1536 1125w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/example-south-korea-iap-1.png?resize=37,50 37w" sizes="(max-width: 498px) 100vw, 498px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229071" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In <a href="https://developers-kr.googleblog.com/2021/11/enabling-alternative-billing-in-korea-en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a blog post </a>this week, Google says developers in South Korea will be able to add an alternative in-app billing system in addition to Google Play’s billing system for their mobile and tablet users in the country. At checkout, users will be able to choose which billing system they want to use for their purchase. Details for developers about how to implement the third-party billing systems will be provided in the weeks ahead, Google said.</p>
<p>The situation in South Korea is interesting as something of a bellwether for how Apple and Google will behave if required by a country to change their app store businesses to promote better competition. In Apple&#8217;s case,<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/skorea-targets-apple-over-new-app-store-regulation-2021-10-15/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> the company is claiming</a> its current policies are already in compliance based on how the law is written, and has not yet made any changes to its policies related to the matter.</p>
<h3>Facebook skirts Apple&#8217;s fees with creator subscriptions</h3>
<p>Facebook is challenging Apple by avoiding App Store fees. The social network this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/facebook-apple-subscription-fees-custom-links/">introduced a new feature</a> that allows creators to share custom subscription links, giving them a way to collect direct payments from fans and make money from their work. When a fan signs up through the link, the creator keeps all the money, minus only taxes. As the links are on the web, these subscriptions aren&#8217;t being processed through Apple&#8217;s in-app payments system &#8212; which could be in possible violation of App Store policies.</p>
<p>But Facebook believes that these links are compliant because it&#8217;s the creators who are generating the revenue, not Facebook itself. Plus, the company isn&#8217;t removing the ability for users to sign up for a creator subscription through the native in-app payments system.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2230006" style="width: 636px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2230006" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2230006" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-11.59.34-AM.jpg?w=626" alt="" width="626" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-11.59.34-AM.jpg 1336w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-11.59.34-AM.jpg?resize=138,150 138w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-11.59.34-AM.jpg?resize=276,300 276w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-11.59.34-AM.jpg?resize=768,835 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-11.59.34-AM.jpg?resize=626,680 626w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-11.59.34-AM.jpg?resize=46,50 46w" sizes="(max-width: 626px) 100vw, 626px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2230006" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook screenshot</p></div></p>
<p>This would also be in line with the recent decision in the Epic Games lawsuit, where the court ruled that Apple can&#8217;t stop developers from adding links to alternative payment systems inside their apps alongside Apple&#8217;s own. Currently, Apple is in the process of asking the court to not enforce the deadline on compliance with its decision, as the case is now under appeal by both parties.</p>
<p>Facebook may be correct that it&#8217;s not breaking the rules, so long as it&#8217;s not taking a cut of transactions. Clubhouse earlier this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/clubhouse-payments/">launched a similar payments feature</a> that allowed users to virtually tip their favorite creators. Because creators kept all the revenue (minus only the card processing fee), Apple did not intervene.</p>
<p>But further down the road, Facebook could find a way to capture some of that subscription revenue &#8212; either by a cut of the payment itself, or via the payment processing fees with Novi, or even both. The company&#8217;s digital wallet platform Novi has only so far launched <a href="https://www.protocol.com/fintech/facebook-novi-wallet">limited support</a> for cross-border payments between the U.S. and Guatemala (and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/facebook-scales-back-its-crypto-ambitions-once-again/">has been criticized</a> for failing to live up to its original crypto ambitions). But Novi&#8217;s long-term plan is to monetize by offering lower fees than credit and debit cards, compared with traditional providers. Facebook could easily get Novi in front of creators, if it chose. First, however, it has to get its foot in the door and start the payment flow without being blocked by Apple. (Facebook said it won&#8217;t collect any fees through 2023.)</p>
<p>Facebook and Apple have been critical of each other&#8217;s business models, with Facebook accusing Apple of using its privacy changes as cover to allow itself to carve out a place for itself in the digital advertising business where Facebook and Google lead. CEO Mark Zuckerberg made no bones about the fact that Facebook believes Apple&#8217;s commissions are bad for creators, saying: &#8220;As we build for the metaverse, we’re focused on unlocking opportunities for creators to make money from their work,&#8221; <a href="https://www.facebook.com/4/posts/10114044739955341/">Zuckerberg wrote in a Facebook post.</a> “The 30% fees that Apple takes on transactions make it harder to do that, so we’re updating our Subscriptions product so now creators can earn more.&#8221;</p>
<h3><strong>Apple rails against sideloading</strong></h3>
<p>Apple’s head of software engineering <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/apple-craig-federighi-side-loading-apps-web-summit-keynote/">Craig Federighi gave a keynote address </a>at the Web Summit 2021 conference this week where he spoke out against the idea of &#8220;sideloading&#8221; apps &#8212; meaning, simply, installing an app outside of Apple&#8217;s App Store. The speech was given in response to the EU&#8217;s draft <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:52020PC0842&amp;from=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">legislation</a> that proposes Apple open up iPhone to third-party app stores. He argued Apple&#8217;s position on the matter, which is that sideloading will put users&#8217; privacy and security at risk and that Apple&#8217;s App Store&#8217;s vetting process will better protect users.</p>
<p>&#8220;Instead of creating choice, it would open up a Pandora’s box of unreviewed malware-ridden software and deny everyone the option of iPhone&#8217;s secure approach,&#8221; he said. At one point <a href="https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/apple-terms-sideloading-apps-cybercriminal-s-best-friend-in-push-against-draft-eu-policy-11636125401996.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">he called apps installed from the web</a>, &#8220;a cybercriminal&#8217;s best friend,&#8221; and painted a picture of how compromised devices could become networks, and malware could threaten government systems, public utilities and enterprises.</p>
<p>Apple is, to some extent, correct that allowing users to download apps from the web could weaken the current state of iPhone security. But, by comparison, Google&#8217;s Android already offers sideloading &#8212; and it hasn&#8217;t so far toppled governments! &#8212; even if Android users face more malware issues than their iPhone counterparts. But one issue with Apple&#8217;s response is that it blurs the lines between third-party app stores and other forms of sideloading where users install directly from a website. Presumably, a competitive app store would be incentivized to keep its marketplace safe in order to attract and retain its own users. A random app hosted on some website is not the same thing at all.</p>
<p>Apple knows the real threat isn&#8217;t to security &#8212; after all, the majority of Android users don&#8217;t sideload &#8212; it&#8217;s to its reputation and business model. Customers hitting up the Epic Games Store for downloads or maybe a Facebook Game Store would cut into its revenues significantly. And every time new malware was discovered &#8220;sideloaded&#8221; onto iPhones, Apple would take a PR hit that would make its platform seem just as vulnerable as Android, losing an advantage it has today over its rival due to being more locked down.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t the first time Apple has spoken out against sideloading so publicly. CEO Tim Cook already said something similar in June. Apple also recently published <a href="https://www.apple.com/privacy/docs/Building_a_Trusted_Ecosystem_for_Millions_of_Apps_A_Threat_Analysis_of_Sideloading.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 31-page document laying out its position in detail</a>.</p>
<h1>Weekly News</h1>
<h3><strong>Platforms: Apple</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>TestFlight launched on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/testflight/id899247664" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Mac App Store</a>,</strong> allowing developers to now test apps that work across Apple&#8217;s platforms, not just on mobile devices.</li>
<li><strong>An Apple job posting is looking for a senior iOS engineer for Apple Music, <a href="https://www.imore.com/unannounced-homeos-has-again-popped-apple-job-listing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">but referenced the</a> yet-to-be public OS name of &#8220;homeOS&#8221;</strong> as one of the platforms Apple is building for. Presumably, this refers to Apple&#8217;s HomePod, which runs a modified version of iOS, but may be getting a rebrand.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Platforms: Google</strong></h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2230167" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2230167" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2230167" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/play-choice-awards.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="361" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/play-choice-awards.jpg 958w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/play-choice-awards.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/play-choice-awards.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/play-choice-awards.jpg?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/play-choice-awards.jpg?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/play-choice-awards.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2230167" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>User voting for the Google Play Best of 2021 opened globally this week. Until November 17, Google Play users will have the opportunity <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/editorial_collection/promotion_topic_bestof2021_userschoice" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to vote on their favorite apps and games</a> of the year. The winners of the Users’ Choice awards and the Best of 2021 picks from the Google Play editorial team will be announced on November 30.</p>
<h3>E-commerce &amp; Food Delivery</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>DoorDash <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/doordash-rolls-out-safedash-an-in-app-security-toolkit-for-delivery-people-on-the-platform/">rolled out an in-app safety kit</a> called SafeDash,</strong> which offers drivers in larger markets the ability to call an ADT agent if they&#8217;re in a situation where they feel unsafe, who can escalate the call to 911 if the Dasher becomes unresponsive for a period of time. It also includes an in-app 911 button. Dashers, however, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763690/doordash-safety-button-delivery-worker-rights-accountability-adt-911" target="_blank" rel="noopener">argue that they want more protection</a>, including being able to choose their delivery areas and not face penalties for choosing their safety over completing a delivery.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Fintech</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2228569" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228569" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2228569" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="494" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png 2206w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?resize=150,109 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?resize=300,218 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?resize=768,558 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?resize=680,494 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?resize=1536,1117 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?resize=2048,1489 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CashApp13_Press_10.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228569" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Cash App</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Square Inc. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/squares-cash-app-opens-up-to-teens-ages-13-to-17-with-parental-oversight/">opened up its Cash App</a> to teens ages 13 to 17 with parental oversight.</strong> The teens can custom their own Cash card and take advantage of features like P2P payments, ATM access and paycheck direct deposit. However, in addition to spending restrictions by category, teens can&#8217;t use features like Borrow, Check Deposit, Paper Money Deposit, cross-border payments or Bitcoin or stock investing. Parents are legal owners of the account, have access to statements and can close the account at any time. The expansion may give Cash App, which has 70 million users, a better shot at passing Venmo, which is still 18 and up and has 76 million users.</li>
<li><strong>Square Inc. also <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/square-q3-revenue-eps-miss-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported disappointing Q3 earnings</a> due to a drop in Bitcoin-related revenue from Cash App compared with the prior period,</strong> <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-04/square-s-bitcoin-revenue-falls-from-prior-quarter-shares-slip?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sending shares down</a>. Revenue from Bitcoin rose 11% YoY to $1.81 billion, lower than the previous quarter&#8217;s total of $2.72 billion and lower than the 200% growth in Bitcoin revenue in Q2. Total revenue was up 27% YoY to $3.84 billion with EPS of 37 cents, versus analyst expectations of $4.39 billion and 38 cents.</li>
<li><strong>The top five worldwide crypto apps saw a combined 46 million installs in Q3,</strong> <a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/insights/mobile-minute/cryptocurrency-accelerates-on-mobile-globally/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said App Annie</a>. These include PayPal, Biance, Crypto.com, Metamask and Coinbase.</li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2230052" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2230052" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2230052" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="323" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png?resize=300,143 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png?resize=768,365 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png?resize=680,323 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png?resize=1536,730 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AA-Chart-1_WW-APAC-CryptocurrencyApps_Image.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2230052" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<h3>Social</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Twitter and Instagram <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22764539/instagram-twitter-timeline-image-preview-feud" target="_blank" rel="noopener">buried the hatchet</a> as Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/instagram-brings-back-twitter-card-preview-support-for-posts/">brought back Twitter Card preview support</a> for posts, meaning users will see a small photo when they tweet an Instagram link.</strong> Instagram had removed this support back in 2012, in retaliation for Twitter&#8217;s removal of access to its social graph.</li>
<li><strong>Twitter also this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/twitter-now-lets-you-tune-into-spaces-without-an-account-via-direct-links/">introduced</a> a way for users to tune into Spaces</strong> without a Twitter account, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/twitter-expands-api-with-support-for-posting-and-deleting-tweets-super-follows-and-more/">updated</a> its API, and more.</li>
<li><strong>Pinterest reported strong profits during <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/04/pinterest-pins-earnings-q3-2021.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its Q3 earnings</a>,</strong> with revenue of $633 million versus $630.9 million expected, adjusted EPS of 28 cents versus 23 cents expected, and ARPU of $1.41 versus $1.38 expected. However, one area where the company is not doing well is user growth. In fact, Pinterest, <strong>for the second quarter in a row, reported a decline in monthly users</strong>, 444 million versus 460 million expected, and down from the 454 million in the prior quarter. The company<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/04/pinterest-pins-earnings-q3-2021.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> didn&#8217;t discuss</a> the recent reports of a potential acquisition by PayPal.</li>
<li><strong>ByteDance founder Zhang Yiming<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/bytedance-tiktok-restructure/"> stepped down</a> as chairman after previously resigning as CEO, and is being replaced by new CEO Liang Rubo on the board.</strong> Shouzi Chew will also step down as CFO, as part of a larger restructuring that will establish six business units dedicated to various areas, including Douyin, TikTok, Dali Education, Lark (office collaboration), BytePlus (cloud) and Nuverse (gaming). The changes follow a crackdown on China&#8217;s tech industry, which sees the app maker moving away from content and entertainment to focus more on its work and cloud offerings. The CEO isn&#8217;t the only one to retreat this past week. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-01/kuaishou-ceo-is-latest-tech-founder-to-retreat-after-crackdown?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kuaishou&#8217;s CEO Su Hua did as well.</a></li>
<li><strong>Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/instagram-rolls-out-an-add-yours-sticker-in-stories-to-create-threads-users-can-respond-to/">rolled out an &#8220;Add Yours&#8221; sticker</a> in Stories that lets users create threads that others can respond to,</strong> like &#8220;show me your #OOTD, for example. The feature is reminiscent of TikTok&#8217;s Duets feature, but more organized as users can see all the responses in one place.</li>
<li><strong>Snap <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/snapchat-partners-with-nbcuniversal-to-give-users-access-to-more-audio-clips/">partnered</a> with NBCU to gain access to a suite of audio clips</strong> that its users can insert into their Snaps, including those sent to friends on posted to Spotlight.</li>
<li><strong>Facebook Groups got a huge update,</strong> including new personalization features, support for subgroups and even paid subgroups, chat and other tools for generating revenue. Admins will be able to change the group’s colors, post backgrounds, fonts and emoji that members use to react to its content. They’ll also be able to use feature sets to select from preset collections of posts, formats, badges, admin tools and more. Groups can also have subgroups that can be subscription-based, and moderators can enter real-time chats to discuss the group&#8217;s content, among other changes.</li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2229141" style="width: 330px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229141" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2229141" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/paid-subgroups.png?w=320" alt="" width="320" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/paid-subgroups.png 401w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/paid-subgroups.png?resize=71,150 71w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/paid-subgroups.png?resize=141,300 141w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/paid-subgroups.png?resize=320,680 320w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/paid-subgroups.png?resize=24,50 24w" sizes="(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229141" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<h3>Photos</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The founders of the photo app Phhhoto <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/04/technology/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-phhhoto.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have filed an antitrust lawsuit against Facebook</a>, claiming the company&#8217;s execs, including Mark Zuckerberg and Instagram founder Kevin Systrom, downloaded their app and approached them about a deal that never materialized. Instead, Facebook launched a clone</strong> of Phhhoto&#8217;s features and suppressed Phhhoto&#8217;s content within Instagram, the suit alleges. The now-defunct app was founded in 2012 and allowed users to edit photos together into looping videos and became popular for a time with celebs including Beyoncé, Miley Cyrus and Katy Perry trying it out.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Messaging</h3>
<ul>
<li>WhatsApp <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/whatsapp-brings-its-business-api-to-the-cloud-to-speed-adoption/">began beta testing</a> a new, cloud-based version of its WhatsApp Business API, hosted on parent company Facebook’s infrastructure. With the shift to the cloud, the setup time for integrating with the API will drop from weeks to only minutes, the company claims, so businesses can more quickly transition to WhatsApp’s API platform to communicate with their customers who have opted in to receive their messages.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Dating</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Match Group <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/match-group-details-plans-for-a-dating-metaverse-tinders-virtual-goods-based-economy/">detailed</a> its plans for a dating &#8220;metaverse&#8221; and Tinder&#8217;s upcoming virtual goods-based economy</strong> during its <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-02/match-forecast-misses-estimates-on-lingering-covid-in-asia?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">weaker-than-expected</a> Q3 earnings. The company&#8217;s long-term vision for Tinder and Explore, which will expand to include exclusive, shared and live experiences and a virtual goods-based economy, supported by Tinder’s new in-app currency, Tinder Coins. It also talked broadly about its larger plans for leveraging Hyperconnect, the Seoul-based social app maker it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/match-hyperconnect-acquisition/">acquired for $1.73 billion</a> earlier in 2021, which is now testing an avatar-based metaverse experience, where users interact with audio and meet in virtual spaces.</li>
<li>In the meantime, Tinder is bringing back Swipe Night. It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/tinders-new-murder-mystery-themed-swipe-night-returns-november-7/">relaunches</a> on November 7 at 6 PM as a whodunit-style murder mystery.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Streaming &amp; Entertainment</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new <a href="https://apptopia.com/streaming-video-benchmark-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Streaming Report from Apptopia</a> found that HBO Max was the most downloaded streaming app on U.S. mobile devices so far in 2021, with 38 million installs,</strong> and has the second-highest number of MAUs. Disney+ had 29 million installs in the first three quarters of the year, followed by Netflix with 28 million, Tubi (22.7 million) and Hulu (22.6 million).</li>
<li><strong>Spotify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/spotify-partners-with-peloton-to-launch-new-playlists-featured-in-its-workout-hub/">partnered</a> with Peloton to launch new playlists in a &#8220;Curated by Peloton&#8221; section within the app&#8217;s &#8220;Workout Hub.&#8221;</strong> The section will feature seven rotating playlists from Peloton instructors and will offer a quiz that will help match users to an instructor who shares their musical tastes.</li>
<li><strong>Clubhouse <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/clubhouse-language-support-android/">added 13 new languages</a> in an effort to reach more global users.</strong> The new additions include French, German, Hindi, Indonesian, Italian, Japanese, Kannada, Korean, Malayalam, Brazilian Portuguese, Spanish, Tamil and Telugu.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Gaming</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2194669" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2194669" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2194669" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg?w=680" alt="Netflix tests mobile gaming, netflix app, Android Netflix app" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/netflix-mobile-game-android-poland.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2194669" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Netflix</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Netflix <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/netflix-games-are-coming-to-all-members-on-android-starting-this-week/">released</a> its mobile lineup of games to all Android users worldwide.</strong> The full lineup includes two &#8220;Stranger Things&#8221; games and three casual games that were currently tested in select markets. Now, all the games will be made available from a dedicated Games tab in the mobile app which directs users to install the titles from the Play Store. Upon first launch, Netflix members will have to sign in to the games using their Netflix account info. The company&#8217;s broader plans include more mobile releases (it bought Night School Studio, for example), including those not tied to Netflix TV shows or movies, seeing gaming as just another entertainment option for users.</li>
<li><strong>Niantic&#8217;s &#8220;Harry Potter: Wizards Unite&#8221; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/harry-potter-wizards-unite-shut-down-niantic/">is shutting down</a>.</strong> The AR gaming title was meant to be the next big hit from the Pokémon Go maker, but didn&#8217;t find the same level of success, generating $39.4 million in consumer spend to date following its 2019 launch. Pokémon Go, by comparison, pulled in $1.1 billion in 2020 alone. The game will become unplayable on January 31, 2022 and is being pulled from app stores on December 6.</li>
<li><strong>In other gaming closures, Nintendo is <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/11/01/nintendo-officially-discontinues-dr-mario-world-game-for-ios-devices">officially discontinuing</a> Dr. Mario World for iOS.</strong> Nintendo has shut down other mobile games in the past, including Miitomo, Pokémon Duel and Pokémon Rumble Rush, and it&#8217;s stopping updating Pokémon Shuffle Mobile and Pokémon Magikarp Jump.</li>
<li><strong>Roblox (and now, Meta) rival <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/rec-room-touts-record-growth-meta-s-latest-quest-update?rc=ajsw4d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rec Room says it now has over 1 million MAUs on VR</a>, </strong>and that October 2021 delivered the company&#8217;s highest YoY user growth rate to date (up 400%). The company wouldn&#8217;t share other metrics, but it&#8217;s still a long way off from Roblox and its 43.3 million DAUs.</li>
<li><strong>Epic Games said it&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/epic-pulls-plug-on-fortnite-in-china/">shutting down its test of Fortnite</a> in China</strong> amid Beijing&#8217;s crackdown on the tech industry and gaming. The game will no longer be available as of November 15 and is not accepting any more users.</li>
<li><strong>Last week&#8217;s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/roblox-outage-ends-210646994.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">three-day</a><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/31/roblox-back-after-three-days-halloween-outage/"> Roblox outage</a> over Halloween benefitted other popular gaming apps,</strong> according to data from Sensor Tower. The firm found Minecraft’s usage saw a 2% week-over-week boost, and Among Us jumped 6%. Among Us also saw 19% more installs from the day prior the outage. Twitch usage was also up (but that could have been from other factors, too).</li>
<li><strong>The Backbone One iPhone controller <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/backbone-ones-companion-app-gets-an-overhaul-with-a-subscription-fee-for-new-users-only/">updated its companion application</a></strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"><strong> with new features</strong> like a smart recording mode that lets you retroactively record the last 15 seconds of gameplay, improved video quality (now 1080p 60 FPS on iOS 15), the ability to automatically switch into a &#8220;Gaming&#8221; Focus mode on iOS 15, sharing your screen directly with friends, improved game search, better load times and stability, and more. Users will also now be able to hardwire their controller to other devices like iPads, Macs, and PCs.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2229153" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229153" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2229153" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="424" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png 4008w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?resize=768,479 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?resize=680,424 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?resize=1536,958 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?resize=2048,1277 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/backbone-one.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229153" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Backbone</p></div></p>
<h3><strong>Travel &amp; Transportation</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Uber <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/04/uber-earnings-q3-2021.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported revenue</a> up 72% YoY to $4.8 billion versus $4.4 billion expected and a loss per share of $1.28 versus 33 cents expected.</strong> The company&#8217;s Didi stake contributed to a net loss of $2.4 billion in the quarter, but Uber <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/uber-reaches-income-milestone-as-rides-recover-delivery-grows-11636056300?mod=djemalertNEWS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">also reported</a> <strong>its first-ever adjusted EBITDA profit</strong> (earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization) of $8 million up from a loss of $507 million in the prior quarter.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Health &amp; Fitness</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Peloton, during earnings, said Apple&#8217;s privacy changes <a href="https://www.imore.com/peloton-says-apple-privacy-changes-partly-blame-revised-outlook" target="_blank" rel="noopener">led to some</a> &#8220;targeting headwinds&#8221; that were disrupting its business.</strong> The company joins others, like Facebook and Snap, that claimed similar issues in their latest earnings. Peloton said it would cut its annual revenue forecast by $1 billion, saying that modeling its future growth had been difficult due to COVID, and now exiting from the pandemic, the outlook needed to be updated.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Government &amp; Policy</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Apple is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-04/apple-attacks-record-1-3-billion-fine-over-french-sales-deals?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fighting back against</a> a $1.3 billion antitrust <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/11/05/apple-antitrust-fine-political" target="_blank" rel="noopener">penalty</a> in France</strong> over what regulators believed were anti-competitive agreements with two wholesalers of iPads and Macs, hurting premium resellers in the process while favoring its own stores and website. Apple also took action to force resellers to provide the same pricing as its store, among other things. Although Apple is already under regulatory scrutiny over its App Store business in global markets, it&#8217;s clear there are other areas where regulators want to hold it accountable, as well.</li>
</ul>
<h1>Funding and M&amp;A</h1>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4c8.png" alt="📈" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>South Korean mobile payments app Kakao Pay<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-03/korea-s-largest-payments-app-more-than-doubles-in-trading-debut?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> more than doubled</a> in its IPO,</strong> popping more than 150% in early trading. The company raised 1.53 trillion won ($1.3 billion), giving it a market cap of more than 11.7 trillion won.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Philippine fintech Mynt <a href="https://www.dealstreetasia.com/stories/mynt-philippines-unicorn-267965/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $300 million</a> in a round</strong> co-led by Warburg Pincus and Insight Partners that values its business at over $2 billion. The company is the fintech arm of Globe Telcom and the operator of the mobile wallet app GCash, which saw GTV of over $20 billion last year.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Mumbai-based neobank Fi <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/funding/neo-bank-fi-valued-at-315-million-after-50-million-funding-led-by-b-capital/articleshow/87438403.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $50 million</a> </strong>in a round led by Facebook co-founder Eduardo Saverin&#8217;s B Capital, valuing its business at $315 million. The service offers working professional free savings accounts which are owned by Federal Bank.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary"><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Chipper Cash, an African cross-border payments app, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/chipper-cash-gets-2b-valuation-with-150m-extension-round-led-by-ftx/">raised $150 million</a></strong> in a Series C extension round led by Sam Bankman-Fried’s cryptocurrency exchange platform FTX. The new funds come barely six months after the startup closed its first Series C round of $100 million, led by SVB Capital.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Play, a native iOS product design tool that works on the iPhone, announced it has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/play-puts-native-ios-product-design-tool-in-the-palm-of-your-hand/">raised $9.1 million</a> </strong>in seed rounds led by First Round Capital and including Oceans Ventures, which took place over the past year and in 2020.</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>When I Work, a messaging and scheduling app for shift-based workers, <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/11/01/timesheet-tracking-app-when-i-work-raises-200m-in-major-growth-round/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $200 million</a></strong> in a growth round from Bain Capital Tech Opportunities, with participation from Arthur Ventures. The app is used by around 10 million hourly workers in the U.S. across some 200,000 businesses, the company claims.</p>
<h1>Downloads</h1>
<h3><strong>Zynga&#8217;s FarmVille 3</strong></h3>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KELeZObZy6M?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Twelve years after the franchise debuted on Facebook, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/zynga-farmville-3-launches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zynga has introduced Farmville 3</a> on iOS, Android and Mac M1 desktops. The new imagining of the game for mobile devices evolves Farmville into more of a &#8220;metaverse,&#8221; the company claims, allowing players to not just harvest crops, but also nurture animals and participate in continuously updated new activities like hot air balloon rides or pig races, among other things.</p>
<p>&#8220;From the very first time I thought of FarmVille, I thought that could be the beginning of the metaverse where you could start with a square plot of dirt and build that into a persistent connected world. That was my original vision for Zynga and social gaming,&#8221; said Zynga founder Mark Pincus. The game will generate revenue through in-app purchases and ads, aiming for $100 million in annual revenue over the next five years.</p>
<h3><strong>Firefox Mobile (update)</strong></h3>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6Y8FVIiWyao?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Alternative mobile browser Firefox <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/firefox-brings-you-a-new-homepage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shipped</a> its latest release for iOS and Android with an update aimed at helping users address common issues — like the visual clutter of having too many open tabs or needing to pick up where you left off the last time the app was closed, among other things. The changes are a part of the Firefox Beta, which introduced a new homepage that will now serve as a re-entry point to the mobile web, says the browser’s maker, Mozilla. The changes could make Firefox more competitive with default options on mobile devices, like Apple’s Safari or Google’s Chrome. Among the new features are a &#8220;Jump back in&#8221; section for returning to internet research, easy access to saved searches, and other recent tabs &#8212; the latter of which are archived to reduce clutter, but still accessible as needed.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1952542" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="93" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=768,105 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=680,93 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=1536,210 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/this-week-in-apps-facebook-tests-app-store-rules-apple-fights-sideloading-netflix-games-go-global/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229922</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one startup is shaking up the consumer trading boom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/how-one-startup-is-shaking-up-the-consumer-trading-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/how-one-startup-is-shaking-up-the-consumer-trading-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 17:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter for your weekend enjoyment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s inspired by the </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>daily TechCrunch+ column</em></a><em> where it gets its name. </em><em>Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><em>here</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p>Happy Saturday, everyone. We have a metric <em>mountain</em> of things to get through today. Below you’ll find notes on a fascinating startup round in the consumer fintech market, notes from the low-code world thanks to an earnings day interview with Appian CEO Matt Calkins, and quick hits on IPOs, Kidas’ venture capital round, a public building and NFTs. Let’s go!</p>
<h2>How one startup is shaking up the consumer trading boom</h2>
<p>Robinhood <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/06/robinhoods-q2-revenue-appears-to-soar/">rode a wave of consumer interest</a> in investing and trading <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/robinhood-targets-ipo-valuation-up-to-35b-amid-warning-that-crypto-incomes-are-slipping/">all the way to the public markets</a>. Despite <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/robinhoods-nasty-quarter-shows-the-ups-downs-of-trading-incomes/">some recent setbacks</a>, the company remains evidence of how much interest there is in the market not only to buy stocks but also to make more exotic options trades.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230088" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It’s the latter that we’re talking about today. <a href="https://www.optionsai.com/">Options AI</a>, a distributed startup with ties to Chicago has raised a $4.1 million Seed round. I’ve known the company for some time as I go back with a member of its founding team but haven’t had a chance to write much about it.</p>
<p>Now that it raised capital from three lead investors — Akuna Capital, Miami International Holdings and Optiver Principal Strategic Investments — and others it fits into our remit.</p>
<p>Essentially options are complicated, and many folks approaching the trading varietal lack the tooling and sophistication to make good choices when they dive in. If you doubt me there, ask your trading friends about their options strategy. It will be an illustrative conversation.</p>
<p>Options AI has built a tool that allows traders better <em>see</em> trades before they execute them and make better choices when it comes to multileg options and the like. It’s a pretty neat tool, and as someone who has long had a loose comprehension of how options trading works and is priced, it helped me grok.</p>
<p>But better charting is only a bit of why Options AI has held my interest. The other reason is that it is <em>charging</em> for trades. The startup has a flat $5 trade cost, which means it is swimming against the free-trading push that Robinhood, Webull and others have pursued in recent years.</p>
<p>Today Options AI works with equity options but told The Exchange that it may add crypto and futures options in time. The company describes its current moment as poking its head out from where it has been building and testing, content that its early traction and user data indicates that it is onto something. Certainly its new investors agree.</p>
<p>A data point on options before we go. <em>Why</em> are major consumer trading platforms so interested in options trading? Because it is lucrative as all hell. For example, options trading generated $64 million <a href="https://s28.q4cdn.com/948876185/files/doc_financials/2021/q3/Q3-2021-Press-Release.pdf">for Robinhood in Q3 2021</a>. Equity trading brought in my $50 million. It’s a big business.</p>
<p>And with a flat-fee and PFOF revenues, Options AI could be in a pretty attractive market position if it can get enough folks to show up. Who is the startup&#8217;s target user? I reckon someone who has gotten into trading but wants slightly more specialized tooling. And Robinhood’s numbers indicate that there could be quite a few of those users out there.</p>
<p>More when we squeeze Options AI for trading growth data.</p>
<h2>Shaking up the SaaS pricing market</h2>
<p>Mostly TechCrunch has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/">explored the SaaS pricing debate</a> through the lens of <em>subscription</em> versus <em>on-demand</em> or <em>usage-based</em> pricing schemes. This is a good window through which to view market evolution as many startups today are born as APIs for which on-demand pricing simply makes more sense. And there’s some SaaS fatigue out in the market as well.</p>
<p>Enter <a href="https://appian.com/">Appian</a>, which is doing something a little different. I caught up with the company’s CEO Matt Calkins this week after his <a href="https://investors.appian.com/news-releases/news-release-details/appian-announces-third-quarter-2021-financial-results">company’s earnings call</a>, expecting to chat mostly about the low-code market, process automation and process mining. We did talk about those things — Appian operates a connected set of software that allows customers to mine their processes for things to automate, helping them design and then automate as needed — but we wound up talking about pricing.</p>
<p>Appian has put together something called <em>unlimited</em> pricing, which is a sort of SaaS with an open-ended cap on use. SaaS is often priced per seat or per application, but Calkins et al. are trying something that feels like a mix of what’s good about SaaS and on-demand. Or more simply, by charging a flat rate for a year’s service and not limiting use, the company is effectively daring customers to use lots of Appian’s service and get stuck in with its platform.</p>
<p>Calkins was unnaturally clear for a public company CEO that the unlimited plan may offer some customers what works out to a very good deal. Saying that he likes to “innovate” on pricing, Calkins argued that while its unlimited pricing model could lead to a customer building a bunch of stuff using Appian tech and perhaps paying less than they might through a different pricing mechanism, it was just the cost for getting them to go all-in on using its tech.</p>
<p>At which point Appian will have a long-term customer that it can generate high-margin top line from. Not a bad trade.</p>
<h2>IPO Roundup</h2>
<p>Golly gee did we want IPOs and gosh darn have they not come. A roundup:</p>
<ul>
<li>HashiCorp filed to go public, our dig into its numbers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/hashicorps-ipo-filing-reveals-a-growing-business-but-at-a-slower-pace/">can be found here</a>.</li>
<li>AllBirds priced its DTC IPO above range, and then ran up more points when it began trading. Pricing notes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/allbirds-prices-ipo-above-range-putting-more-points-on-the-board-for-dtc-startups/">here</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/allbirds-flotation-should-help-the-market-sort-the-value-of-tech-enabled-ipos/">financial coverage here</a>.</li>
<li>NerdWallet priced its IPO midrange, before trading higher. It has given up some ground since, but still had a cracking debut. Financial coverage <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/nerdwallets-ipo-filing-reveals-high-margin-content-business-accelerating-marketing-spend/">here</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/nerdwallets-ipo-proves-you-can-write-your-way-to-a-unicorn-valuation/">here</a>. (And shoutout to former TechCruncher <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/reelfeed/">Felicia Shivakumar,</a> who once took a shot on your current scribe launching a video show for TC and is a very excellent human, but also now works for NerdWallet!)</li>
<li>Nubank filed to go public, our first look at some of its economics <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/nubanks-ipo-filing-gives-us-a-peek-into-neobank-economics/">can be found here</a>.</li>
<li>The Bird SPAC deal completed, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/shareholders-approve-bird-spac-merger-stock-promptly-falls/">and it didn’t have the <em>best</em> first day</a>.</li>
<li>And, finally, Backblaze <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/backblazes-ipo-a-test-for-smaller-tech-concerns/">set first pricing notes for its own IPO</a>, which we found fascinating given the company’s old-school revenue scale.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Various, sundry</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://kidas.net">Kidas</a> ran into my eyeline this week, the startup works with parents to help keep kids safe in online gaming environments. It just raised $2 million, adding to its <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/kidas/company_financials">modest fundraising record</a>. The company told The Exchange that it “unlocks new information for parents they otherwise wouldn’t have and this helps them to better connect with their kids over something they love.”</li>
<li>I will never be <em>stoked</em> about anything that gives authority more purview over underlings’ digital activities, but given the spiraling number of communications methods in the gaming world, parents are going to want some oversight.</li>
<li>Notably the startup says that its tooling doesn’t interfere with gameplay, so it doesn’t trigger anti-cheat software, which really, <em>really </em>matters.</li>
<li>More on the company later, but it’s based in Philly, which I dug.</li>
<li><a href="https://therealdeal.com/2021/11/03/interested-in-investing-in-a-single-building-this-harlem-property-could-be-your-chance/">Building goes public</a>: Not in our IPO section, but a startup I’ve been passively tracking called <a href="https://www.lex-markets.com/">LEX Capital Markets</a> just took a single building public. The company has a really neat model. Worth peeking at.</li>
<li>And, finally, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/bring-on-the-low-cost-nfts/">extending our recent NFT coverage</a>, Mythical <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/11/04/mythical-raises-150m-at-1-25b-valuation-for-playable-nft-game-platform/">just raised $150 million</a> for its NFT-infused game. Perhaps that’s where the NFT wind is heading.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/alex">—Alex</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/06/how-one-startup-is-shaking-up-the-consumer-trading-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230088</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should your company be using a flexible pricing model?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/should-your-company-be-using-a-flexible-pricing-model/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/should-your-company-be-using-a-flexible-pricing-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 02:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Software Consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experts Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Consultants Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software consulting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's fair to say that this week's top story is located at the crossroads of growth marketing and software development.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This week&#8217;s top story is located at the crossroads of growth marketing and software development.</p>
<p>Usage-based pricing (UBP) for SaaS services is becoming more popular as companies of every type automate their processes, but one important result of the shift is that companies that adopt UBP see a return on their customer acquisition costs much sooner than the competition.</p>
<p>This week&#8217;s coverage of software development includes articles about Battery Venture&#8217;s State of the OpenCloud report, how developers can make the most of iOS 15.0 updates and an interview with Appetiser, who we found through our TechCrunch Experts <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl">survey</a>. As for growth marketing, I reached out to several marketers we&#8217;ve interviewed in the past to find out how they&#8217;re preparing for this year&#8217;s holiday season.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229971" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>Software consulting</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/were-still-just-scratching-the-surface-of-the-clouds-potential/">(TechCrunch+) We’re still just scratching the surface of the cloud’s potential:</a> TechCrunch&#8217;s own Ron Miller and Alex Wilhelm do a deep dive of the State of the OpenCloud report from Battery Ventures. Ron and Alex write, &#8220;Battery believes that the cloud market could eventually be worth $1 trillion. When you consider that the vast majority of work, development and computing will be done in the cloud at some point, the investment group’s round-number projection may prove modest.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/make-the-most-of-ios-15s-updates-to-the-app-store/">(TechCrunch+) Make the most of iOS 15’s updates to the App Store:</a> Ilia Kukharev, head of ASO at AppFollow, tells us how software developers can use iOS 15.0 updates to their advantage. Kukharev says, &#8220;If an internal event is planned in the app (for example, a live broadcast), it is now possible to promote it in App Store Connect any time before the event. After review approval, the event card will be shown in search results as well as on the app page.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/appetisers-co-founders-discuss-building-client-relationships-and-getting-to-mvp/">Appetiser’s co-founders discuss building client relationships and getting to MVP:</a> Anna had a chance to interview Appetiser&#8217;s co-founders Jamie Shostak and Michael MacRae. They discussed how Appetiser came to be, how they also work with clients on growth, and more. MacRae says, &#8220;When we build your team at Appetiser, it will be your team! Join standups, ideate with your team, discuss challenges or even have one-on-ones. We replicated the structure of successful startups with in-house teams, and then we rebuilt it in an agency form.&#8221;</p>
<div style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" data-tf-widget="MXehi2kl"></div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>Growth marketing</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/">(TechCrunch+) Why more SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based pricing:</a> Anna spoke with OpenView&#8217;s operating partner, Kyle Poyar, about OpenView&#8217;s 2021 State of Usage-Based Pricing Report and shares the highlights of their conversation with us. Anna says, &#8220;The survey also looks into how companies that adopt flexible pricing models perform compared to their counterparts, and how it impacts them more broadly.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">(TechCrunch+): The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?:</a> Miranda Halpern chatted with several marketers that we&#8217;ve come to know through our TechCrunch Experts project about how they&#8217;re preparing for holiday campaigns this year while facing the pandemic, supply chain issues, and more. &#8220;To maximize order flow and meet customer expectations, Dick said her company moved up its campaign start dates by 2-3 weeks and plans to lean more heavily on SMS and email campaigns than in the past.&#8221;</p>
<div style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" data-tf-widget="bwwIWF03"></div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/should-your-company-be-using-a-flexible-pricing-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teaching robots to socialize</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/teaching-robots-to-socialize/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/teaching-robots-to-socialize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 22:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Politeness doesn’t really amount to much when you’re programmed to get from point A to point B. But if robots are going to play an increased role in human society, questions arise around how precisely they’ll get along with the rest of us. “Robots will live in our world soon enough and they really need [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Politeness doesn’t really amount to much when you’re programmed to get from point A to point B. But if robots are going to play an increased role in human society, questions arise around how precisely they’ll get along with the rest of us.</p>
<p>“Robots will live in our world soon enough and they really need to learn how to communicate with us on human terms,” MIT CSAIL research scientist Boris Katz said in a statement tied to <a href="https://openreview.net/pdf?id=3HZLte8gMYS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a new research paper.</a> “They need to understand when it is time for them to help and when it is time for them to see what they can do to prevent something from happening.”</p>
<p>The team calls the paper, “the first very serious attempt for understanding what it means for humans and machines to interact socially.” The validity of such a claim may be up for dispute; the problem it’s attempting to solve in a very early stage is no doubt one roboticists will increasingly consider as robots begin to play an outsized role in our lives.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230189" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Researchers conducted tests in a simulated environment, to develop what they deemed “realistic and predictable” interactions between robots. In the simulation, one robot watches another perform a task, attempts to determine the goal and then either attempts to help or hamper it in that task.</p>
<p>“We have opened a new mathematical framework for how you model social interaction between two agents,” fellow project lead Ravi Tejwani said in a statement. “If you are a robot, and you want to go to location X, and I am another robot and I see that you are trying to go to location X, I can cooperate by helping you get to location X faster. That might mean moving X closer to you, finding another better X, or taking whatever action you had to take at X. Our formulation allows the plan to discover the ‘how’; we specify the ‘what’ in terms of what social interactions mean mathematically.”</p>
<p>The model is currently a relatively simple 2D simulation. The team is working to move toward a 3D version, while adding a neural network-based robot planner to increase the speed with which the robots learn from these actions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/teaching-robots-to-socialize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230189</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I learned building a fact-checking startup</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/what-i-learned-building-a-fact-checking-startup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/what-i-learned-building-a-fact-checking-startup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 22:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fact checking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factmata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fake news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Global Affairs Project]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our thesis was clear: If technology could drive people to seek truth, facts, statistics and data to make their decisions, we could build an online discourse of reason and rationality.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Dhruv Ghulati</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Dhruv Ghulati founded one of the first global startups tackling online misinformation and is one of the first machine learning scientists to research automated fact-checking. He holds degrees in economics and computer science from the London School of Economics and University College London.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In the aftermath of the 2016 U.S. election, I set out to build a product that could tackle the scourge of fake news online. My initial hypothesis was simple: build a semi-automated fact-checking algorithm that could automatically highlight any false or dubious claim and suggest the best-quality contextual facts for it. Our thesis was clear, if perhaps utopian: If technology could drive people to seek truth, facts, statistics and data to make their decisions, we could build an online discourse of reason and rationality instead of hyperbole.</p>
<p>After five years of <a href="https://medium.com/factmata/3-stage-plan-e2f9f06bdd62">hard work</a>, Factmata has had some successes. But for this space to truly thrive, there are a great deal of barriers, from economic to technological, that still must be overcome.</p>
<h2>Key challenges</h2>
<p>We quickly realized that automated fact-checking represents an extremely hard research problem. The first challenge was defining just what facts we were checking. Next, it was thinking about how we could build and maintain up-to-date databases of facts that would allow us to assess the accuracy of given claims. For example, the commonly-used <a href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Wikidata:Main_Page">Wikidata</a> knowledge base was an obvious option, but it updates too slowly to check claims about rapidly changing events.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2226330 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?w=300" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2228948" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>We also discovered that being a for-profit fact-checking company was an obstacle. Most journalism and fact-checking networks are nonprofit, and social media platforms prefer working with nonprofits in order to avoid accusations of bias.</p>
<p>Beyond these factors, building a business that can rate what is &#8220;good&#8221; is inherently complex and nuanced. Definitions are endlessly debatable. For example, what people called &#8220;fake news&#8221; often turned out to be extreme hyperpartisanship, and what people proclaimed &#8220;misinformation&#8221; were really contrarian opinions.</p>
<p>Thus, we concluded that detecting what was &#8220;bad&#8221; (toxic, obscene, threatening or hateful) was a much easier route from a business standpoint. Specifically, we decided to detect &#8220;gray area&#8221; harmful text — content that a platform is not sure should be removed but needs additional context. To achieve this, we built an API that scores the harmfulness of comments, posts and news articles for their level of hyperpartisanship, controversiality, objectivity, hatefulness and 15 other signals.</p>
<p>We realized that there was value in tracking all the claims evolving online about relevant corporate issues. Thus, beyond our API we built a SaaS platform that tracks rumors and &#8220;narratives&#8221; evolving in any topic, whether it is about a brand’s products, a government policy or COVID-19 vaccines.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If this sounds complicated, that’s because it is. One of the biggest lessons we learned was just how little $1 million in seed funding goes in this space. Training data around validated hate speech and false claims is no ordinary labeling task — it requires subject-matter expertise and precise deliberations, neither of which comes cheaply.</p>
<p>In fact, building the tools we needed — including multiple browser extensions, website demos, a data labeling platform, a social news commenting platform and live real-time dashboards of our AI’s output — was akin to building several new startups all at the same time.</p>
<p>Complicating things further, finding product-market fit was a very hard journey. After many years of building, Factmata has shifted to brand safety and brand reputation. We sell our technology to online advertising platforms looking to clean up their ad inventory, brands looking for reputation management and optimization, and smaller scale platforms looking for content moderation. It took us a long time to reach this business model, but in the last year we have finally seen multiple customers sign up for trials and contracts every month, and we are on target for $1 million in recurring revenues by mid-2022.</p>
<h2>What needs to be done</h2>
<p>Our journey demonstrates the high number of barriers to building a socially impactful business in the media space. As long as virality and drawing eyeballs are the metrics for the online advertising, search engines and newsfeeds, change will be hard. And small firms can’t do it on their own; they will need both regulatory and financial support.</p>
<p>Regulators need to step up and start enacting strong laws. Facebook and Twitter have taken massive strides, but the online advertising systems are far behind and emerging platforms have no incentive to evolve differently. Right now, there is no incentive for companies to moderate their platforms of any speech that isn’t illegal — reputational damage or fear of user churn are not enough. Even the most ardent supporters of free speech, as I am, recognize the need to create financial incentives and bans so that platforms really take action and start spending money to reduce harmful content and promote ecosystem health.</p>
<p>What would an alternative look like? Bad content will always exist, but we can create a system that promotes better content.</p>
<p>As flawed as they may be, algorithms have a big role to play; they have the potential to automatically assess online content for its &#8220;goodness,&#8221; or quality. These &#8220;quality scores&#8221; could be the basis to create new social media platforms that aren’t ad based at all but used to promote (and pay for) content that is beneficial to society.</p>
<p>Given the scope of the problem, it will take immense resources to build these new scoring algorithms — even the most innovative startups will struggle without tens, if not hundreds, of millions of dollars in funding. It will require multiple companies and nonprofits, all providing different versions that can embed in people’s newsfeeds.</p>
<p>Government can help in several ways. First, it should define the rules around &#8220;quality&#8221;; firms trying to solve this problem shouldn’t be expected to make up their own policies.</p>
<p>Government should also provide funding. Government funding would allow these companies to avoid watering down their goals. It would also encourage firms to make their technologies open to public scrutiny and create transparency around flaws and biases. The technologies could even be encouraged to be released to the public for free and available use, and ultimately provided for public benefit.</p>
<p>Finally, we need to embrace emerging technologies. There have been positive strides by the platforms to invest seriously in the deep technology required to do content moderation effectively and sustainably. The ad industry, four years on, has also made progress adopting new brand safety algorithms such as Factmata’s, that of the Global Disinformation Index and Newsguard.</p>
<p>Although initially a skeptic, I am also optimistic about the potential of cryptocurrency and token economics to present a new way of funding and encouraging good quality, fact-checked media to prevail and distribute at scale. For example, &#8220;experts&#8221; in tokenized systems can be encouraged to fact-check claims and efficiently scale data labeling for AI content moderation systems without firms needing large upfront investments to pay for labeling.</p>
<p>I don’t know if the original vision I set out for Factmata, as the technological component of a fact-based world, will ever be realized. But I am proud that we gave it a shot and am hopeful that our experiences can help others chart a healthier direction in the ongoing battle against misinformation and disinformation.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-footer.jpg" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/what-i-learned-building-a-fact-checking-startup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228948</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helion Energy will use $500M Series E to power up its fusion energy efforts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-energy-will-use-500m-series-e-to-power-up-its-fusion-energy-efforts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-energy-will-use-500m-series-e-to-power-up-its-fusion-energy-efforts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 22:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for November 5, 2021! We made it, everyone, happy Friday. Don’t forget to take off in the direction of our upcoming Space event before we reach exit velocity and leave you behind! And have a relaxed weekend. We’re all a little tired. — Alex All systems go: Buy your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for November 5, 2021! We made it, everyone, happy Friday. Don’t forget to take off in the direction of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/">our upcoming Space event</a> before we reach exit velocity and leave you behind! And have a relaxed weekend. We’re all a little tired. — <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TUQkIlmsNC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/">All systems go: Buy your pass to TC Sessions: Space 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All systems go: Buy your pass to TC Sessions: Space 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/embed/#?secret=TUQkIlmsNC" data-secret="TUQkIlmsNC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/"><strong>How Cruise intends to make robotaxis a commercial reality:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Curious why we are not yet zipping around in computer-driven cars, putting the days of wondering if right turns on a red light are allowed? Me too. The answer is that to get to that point is much more work than folks may have thought. Cruise is turning to simulators and custom silicon for its own efforts. Let’s hope they have cracked it. I hate driving.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/hashicorps-ipo-filing-reveals-a-growing-business-but-at-a-slower-pace/"><strong>HashiCorp’s IPO details an open source powerhouse:</strong></a> It’s always good fun to chat with companies building open source code. Once an oddity, many startups today are working on and with code that is open for all. HashiCorp has ridden the trend all the way to an IPO filing, which we were more than excited to read.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-series-e/"><strong>$500M+ for commercial fusion:</strong></a><strong> </strong>While we are on the subject of tricky tech challenges like self-driving cars, let’s talk about fusion for a minute. Helion Energy just raised $500 million for its efforts to pull energy from fusion reactions, with another $1.7 billion in the offing if it can hit certain milestones. The question, TechCrunch notes, is whether the company can yank more power from its fusion tech than it takes to operate. Let’s see.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we get into specific news items, if it feels like today’s venture capitalists are putting more capital to work, more quickly, while getting smaller ownership stakes in global startups, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/vcs-are-racing-to-pay-more-to-get-smaller-pieces-of-less-profitable-companies/">you are right!</a> The question is if they are growing more quickly.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230146" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/lime-raises-523-million-as-it-prepares-to-go-public/"><strong>Lime raises pre-IPO round:</strong></a> Now that Bird is a public company, it only seems fitting that its former archrival Lime is also prepping its own public offering. The green-branded scooter and e-bike company just locked in $523 million in new funding, including $418 million of convertible debt. Let’s see if Lime can <em>scoot</em> its way to an IPO in short order.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/momenta-500-million/"><strong>More money for self-driving tech:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Speaking of nine-figure rounds for things that move, Momenta has just added $500 million to its own coffers. The autonomous driving tech company from China had previously raised $300 million in a round that it just extended. That’s a lot of duckets. At this point I am curious if we’ve seen north of $100 billion invested privately to tackle this particular technology challenge.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/dji-mavic-3-best-drone-price-msrp-2199/"><strong>New DJI drone is good, expensive:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Drone tech has taken leaps and bounds in recent years, improving across nearly all strata that we care about. Our own Matt Burns confirms as much in his review of the new DJI Mavic 3. Sadly it costs north of $2,000, so will fly far from the hands of most consumers.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/"><strong>Thirteen Lune raises $3M, partners with major American retailer:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The beauty market is big business, and Thirteen Lune is taking its direct-to-consumer beauty platform to the masses with a partnership with Target. That deal made TechCrunch sit up and take note of the company’s funding and progress.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/milkrun-lands-new-capital-to-deliver-farm-fresh-groceries/"><strong>Today in good startup names, we present MilkRun:</strong></a> Regardless of if you buy milk by the gallon, or the <a href="https://www.chron.com/news/local/article/CNN-segment-Twitter-losing-it-Texas-milk-16592454.php">dozens of gallons</a>, we all eat and drink each day. MilkRun wants to feed you with its “subscription service delivering weekly grocery staples sourced from small, local farms,” TechCrunch reports. Now flush with a $6 million Series A, the startup is hoping to extend its growth that saw it bolster revenues by 15x in 2020.</li>
<li>And if you want the TechCrunch take on recent venture capital data regarding female founders, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/three-quarters-of-record-breaking-funding-for-female-founders-is-a-win/">we have just the podcast for you</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</h2>
<p>With only three weeks left to the start of the holiday shopping season, Miranda Halpern checked in with several growth marketers to find out how they&#8217;re advising their clients to prepare for supply chain disruptions.</p>
<p>Cargo ships are stacked up outside ports, and empty shipping containers are in short supply, as are the truck drivers who would take them to market. This is not the time for doing business as usual.</p>
<p>To gather advice and insights, she interviewed:</p>
<ul>
<li>Julio Lopez, director of client strategy, retail practice lead, Movable Ink</li>
<li>Chris Toy, CEO and co-founder, Marketer Hire</li>
<li>Kristin Dick, head of operations and growth marketer, Tuff</li>
<li>Dipti Parmar, founder, Dipti Parmar Consulting</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HSQWy16n9i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/embed/#?secret=HSQWy16n9i" data-secret="HSQWy16n9i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/tencent-chips-semiconductor/"><strong>Don’t be surprised that Tencent is making its own chips:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Thus argues our own Rita Liao, who does a killer job on the China beat. The Chinese tech giant got a stock market boost this week when it showed off new chips under its own imprint. With news from Cruise and Tencent this week on the silicon front, perhaps we should expect every company over a certain market cap to have its own chips coming in the future.</li>
<li>“A flagship framework used by Google and scores of other advertisers for gathering claimed consent from web users for creepy ad targeting looks set to be found in breach of Europe’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR),” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/"><strong>writes our own Natasha Lomas</strong></a>, our reporter on the EU privacy beat. It turns out that a method of collecting consent to comply with GDPR isn’t, well, in compliance.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this article on TechCrunch+ from Miranda Halpern, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">“The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?”</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-energy-will-use-500m-series-e-to-power-up-its-fusion-energy-efforts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230146</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New antitrust suit from Phhhoto alleges Facebook copied and killed the competition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/phhhoto-sues-meta-facebook-antitrust/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/phhhoto-sues-meta-facebook-antitrust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 21:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boomerang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gary reback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gif]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Systrom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Menlo Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phhhoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK parliament]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A former upstart Instagram rival is suing Meta, formerly known as Facebook, over allegations that the company violated antitrust laws by cloning a competing product and ultimately killing its business. The app, Phhhoto, launched in 2014, inviting users to create and share short GIF-like videos. If that sounds familiar, that&#8217;s because the same functionality was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A former upstart Instagram rival is suing Meta, formerly known as Facebook, over allegations that the company violated antitrust laws by cloning a competing product and ultimately killing its business.</p>
<p>The app, Phhhoto, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/15/phhhoto-is-an-addictive-albeit-poorly-named-gif-style-photo-app/">launched in 2014,</a> inviting users to create and share short GIF-like videos. If that sounds familiar, that&#8217;s because the same functionality was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/22/instagram-boomerang/">popularized in Boomerang</a>, an app made by Instagram. That feature is now integrated into Instagram&#8217;s core app experience.</p>
<p>The newly filed lawsuit, embedded below, alleges that Facebook&#8217;s behavior violated antitrust laws by cutting off the app&#8217;s access to its social graph, slow-walking a proposed relationship and then eventually releasing its own copy of Phhhoto&#8217;s core feature: the seconds-long looping video.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230141" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Menlo Park-based lawyer Gary Reback will represent Phhhoto in the suit. Reback is best known for his involvement in setting the stage for the federal government&#8217;s successful antitrust case against Microsoft, which ultimately didn&#8217;t split up the tech giant but did force the company to open up some aspects of its computing business — consequences that continue to reverberate in the tech industry today.</p>
<p>Reback argues that Phhhoto&#8217;s experience underlines why it&#8217;s detrimental to the market when a massive tech company buys out its competition and starts running those businesses.</p>
<p>&#8220;The record here demonstrates that Facebook would have partnered with Phhhoto and launched to prominence this great new social network that would have competed with Instagram,&#8221; Reback said. He highlighted the unusually hands-on approach that Facebook&#8217;s top leadership took with the nascent competitor.</p>
<p>Phhhoto climbed the iOS app charts after its launch, eventually boasting 3.7 monthly active users at its peak popularity. As the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/03/30/phhhoto-tops-1-million-users/">hot new social app attracted attention</a>, Facebook executives took interest — including Mark Zuckerberg.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;On or about August 8, 2014, Zuckerberg downloaded and installed the app onto his phone, entered the phone number of his device into the Phhhoto app, created a personal account, and posted a profile picture of himself (reproduced below) to his new Phhhoto account,&#8221; the suit reads.</p>
<p>The suit includes receipts — namely, Zuckerberg&#8217;s own selfie, taken as he was testing the app.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2230181" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2230181" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2230181" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?w=650" alt="Zuckerberg Phhhoto selfie" width="650" height="672" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png 650w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=145,150 145w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=290,300 290w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=48,50 48w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2230181" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Phhhoto</p></div></p>
<p>Instagram co-founder Kevin Systrom, who led Instagram at the time, also downloaded the app and explored its features. According to the lawsuit, Facebook began courting Phhhoto, offering partnership opportunities that it later reneged on:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8230; Hurren, then Facebook’s Strategic Partnerships Manager, reached out to Phhhoto, asserting that Phhhoto was &#8220;really awesome.&#8221; Hurren first offered to incorporate Phhhoto’s technology into the Facebook Messenger service. When Phhhoto declined, Hurren offered to incorporate Phhhoto’s content into Facebook’s users’ Newsfeeds. Phhhoto invested heavily in this project, but ultimately Hurren did not move forward, citing internal “legal conversations” that “hung” the project up.</p></blockquote>
<p>After the relationship failed to materialize, the suit alleges that Facebook took a number of actions meant to drive it out of business, including removing pre-populated Instagram hashtags that indicate where content on the app originated. Instagram also cut Phhhoto off from its social graph, blocking the perceived competitor&#8217;s users from connecting with their Instagram friends in the app.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zJGwjksstx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/24/nochill/">Instagram Cuts Off Hot GIF App Phhhoto From Its Social Graph</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram Cuts Off Hot GIF App Phhhoto From Its Social Graph&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/24/nochill/embed/#?secret=zJGwjksstx" data-secret="zJGwjksstx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Phhhoto&#8217;s demise had some dramatic moments: On October 22, 2015, the same day the company was set to launch an Android version of its app, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/22/instagram-boomerang/">Instagram launched Boomerang</a>. The suit identifies Boomerang product manager John Barnett as an &#8220;active Phhhoto user.&#8221; At the time of launch, TechCrunch noted that Boomerang appeared &#8220;suspiciously similar&#8221; to Phhhoto.</p>
<p>The suit alleges that Boomerang was the culmination of Facebook&#8217;s anticompetitive effort, effectively killing the smaller company with a copycat app that reproduced Phhhoto&#8217;s innovations &#8220;feature-by-feature.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to the suit, Phhhoto wasn&#8217;t even aware of the extent of Facebook&#8217;s aggressive behavior against other competitors at the time, learning more after the UK Parliament released a<a href="https://www.parliament.uk/globalassets/documents/commons-committees/culture-media-and-sport/Note-by-Chair-and-selected-documents-ordered-from-Six4Three.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> trove of the company&#8217;s internal documents in late 2018</a>.</p>
<p>Phhhoto wasn&#8217;t afraid to speak out about Facebook&#8217;s moves as this all went down. &#8220;We watched Systrom and his product team quietly using Phhhoto almost a year before Boomerang was released,&#8221; Phhhoto co-founder Champ Bennett <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/phhhoto-shuts-down/">told TechCrunch in 2017</a>.</p>
<p>After the app shut down, Bennett said that it &#8220;wasn’t a surprise at all&#8221; to see Instagram launch its own clone.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/537444585/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-sYNyLLMrS7fNrk06UG1w"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_537444585" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/537444585" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rEQfK0Z2y5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/15/phhhoto-is-an-addictive-albeit-poorly-named-gif-style-photo-app/">Phhhoto Is An Addictive, Albeit Poorly Named, Gif-Style Photo App</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Phhhoto Is An Addictive, Albeit Poorly Named, Gif-Style Photo App&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/15/phhhoto-is-an-addictive-albeit-poorly-named-gif-style-photo-app/embed/#?secret=rEQfK0Z2y5" data-secret="rEQfK0Z2y5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wcu6Vtiiih"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/phhhoto-shuts-down/">Phhhoto shutters app and pivots to photobooths, blaming Instagram</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Phhhoto shutters app and pivots to photobooths, blaming Instagram&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/phhhoto-shuts-down/embed/#?secret=wcu6Vtiiih" data-secret="wcu6Vtiiih" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/phhhoto-sues-meta-facebook-antitrust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230141</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter is rolling out a feature to make it easier to search a user&#8217;s tweets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/twitter-is-rolling-out-a-feature-to-make-it-easier-to-search-a-users-tweets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/twitter-is-rolling-out-a-feature-to-make-it-easier-to-search-a-users-tweets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 21:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real time Web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some Twitter users on iOS are starting to get access to a feature that makes it easy to search an individual user&#8217;s tweets. For those with access, when you navigate to a user&#8217;s profile, you&#8217;ll see a search icon in the top right corner of the screen on the user&#8217;s profile banner, next to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Some Twitter users on iOS are starting to get access to a feature that makes it easy to search an individual user&#8217;s tweets. For those with access, when you navigate to a user&#8217;s profile, you&#8217;ll see a search icon in the top right corner of the screen on the user&#8217;s profile banner, next to the three-dot menu. Then, you can type in keywords to search the user&#8217;s tweets. Twitter told TechCrunch that this feature is available to all global users on iOS and will continue to slowly roll out on web and Android.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Twitter <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f50d.png" alt="🔍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> search user’s tweets button on profiles is now available (for some users)</p>
<p>h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/RefaelCohe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RefaelCohe</a> <a href="https://t.co/K8QSUZ0iHr">pic.twitter.com/K8QSUZ0iHr</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229941" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&mdash; Matt Navarra (@MattNavarra) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1447556138145394692?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It was already possible to perform searches like this on Twitter &#8212; you just needed to know how to format an <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/twitter-advanced-search" target="_blank" rel="noopener">advanced search</a>. So, if you search &#8220;from:@TechCrunch Twitter,&#8221; for example, you&#8217;ll be able to see all TechCrunch tweets containing the word &#8220;Twitter,&#8221; regardless of whether you have access to the new search feature. Twitter&#8217;s longstanding <a href="https://twitter.com/search-advanced" target="_blank" rel="noopener">advanced search</a> feature can be accessed by searching for something, then clicking the three-dot menu next to the search bar on the web. You can filter searches by date, by the amount of engagement and more.</p>
<p>Still, this easily accessible search button makes it easier to find tweets from a specific user &#8212; so, using the same example, if you didn&#8217;t know how to perform an advanced search, it would be much easier to use the search button to look for &#8220;Twitter&#8221; on TechCrunch&#8217;s account, rather than scrolling through dozens of daily tweets to find what you&#8217;re looking for.</p>
<p>Of course, it&#8217;s possible that this feature could make it easier for people to dig up others&#8217; old, troublesome tweets. But, as always, it&#8217;s a great social media strategy to just not tweet potentially harmful content in the first place (also, delete old tweets).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/twitter-is-rolling-out-a-feature-to-make-it-easier-to-search-a-users-tweets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With a Section 1045 rollover, founders can salvage QSBS before 5 years</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/with-a-section-1045-rollover-founders-can-salvage-qsbs-before-5-years/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/with-a-section-1045-rollover-founders-can-salvage-qsbs-before-5-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 20:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capital gains tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[countries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228020</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Section 1045 allows a founder or stockholder whose company has been sold before the five-year holding period to defer the capital gain by rolling the sale proceeds into a replacement QSBS.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Peyton Carr</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/jpeytoncarr">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Peyton Carr is a financial adviser to founders, entrepreneurs and their families, helping them with planning and investing. He is a managing director of <a href="https://keystonegp.com/">Keystone Global Partners</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/advanced-tax-strategies-for-startup-founders/">Advanced tax strategies for startup founders</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/22/what-you-need-to-know-before-selling-your-companys-stock/">What you need to know before selling your company&#8217;s stock</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Calvin Lo</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/calvinlo">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://keystonegp.com/team-members/calvin-lo-cfa-cfpr">Calvin Lo</a>, CFA, CFP, is a managing director at Keystone Global Partners LLC.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The tax code contains provisions that encourage investments in the technology startup ecosystem and small businesses by rewarding founders, VCs and investors for taking high levels of risk in founding or investing in a startup. One of these provisions is the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/04/how-to-build-or-invest-in-a-startup-without-paying-capital-gains-tax/">Qualified Small Business Stock (QSBS) or Section 1202 stock</a>, which offers the opportunity to eliminate capital gains tax entirely if specific requirements are met.</p>
<p>It is important to note that this 100% capital gains exclusion, made permanent by the Obama administration, has been included in the draft legislation by the House Ways and Means Committee, and includes a proposed cut from 100% exclusion to a 50% exclusion for gains recognized on the sale of QSBS. For the purpose of this article, I’ll speak specifically to the 100% exclusion.</p>
<p>You can learn more about the QSBS rules and requirements <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/04/how-to-build-or-invest-in-a-startup-without-paying-capital-gains-tax/">here</a>. One rule we discuss today is that stockholders must meet a five-year holding period to qualify. However, not everyone can time when to sell their company. The fact that many acquisitions happen before five years leaves some founders and investors short of qualifying for these powerful tax savings.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Stockholders can multiply — or “stack” — the benefit of a 1045 rollover by spreading the QSBS exclusion to more than one new investment.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Section 1045 can salvage the opportunity in some cases.</p>
<h2>What is Section 1045?</h2>
<p>Section 1045 allows a founder or stockholder whose company has been sold before the five-year holding period to defer the capital gains by rolling the sale proceeds into a replacement QSBS.</p>
<h3>Benefits and opportunities</h3>
<p>A 1045 rollover enables founders and investors to take advantage of multiple tax benefits and opportunities they would otherwise miss.</p>
<h3>Extended tax deferral</h3>
<p>With a 1045 rollover, the stockholder can defer taxes on the sale of the original QSBS by investing in a replacement QSBS. Under the right circumstances, tax can be deferred until the replacement QSBS is sold.</p>
<p>If the combined holding period is five years and other requirements (discussed below) are met, no federal capital gains taxes are due. But if the requirements are not met, then taxes will be due upon the sale of the replacement QSBS.</p>
<h3>Shortened holding period</h3>
<p>Typically, the holding period for all taxable exchanges will begin the day after the exchange. However, the holding period for the replacement QSBS includes the holding period of the original QSBS, avoiding a reset of the five-year requirement. This means a 1045 rollover shortens the next QSBS holding period requirement and allows the clock to continue ticking.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2228078" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228078" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2228078" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg" alt="1045 Rollover" width="1024" height="569" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg 1429w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=768,427 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=680,378 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228078" class="wp-caption-text">1045 Rollover.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Keystone Global Partners</p></div></p>
<h3>QSBS exclusion stacking<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/with-a-section-1045-rollover-founders-can-salvage-qsbs-before-5-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228020</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why we rebuilt our equity plan for flexibility (and how you can, too)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/why-we-rebuilt-our-equity-plan-for-flexibility-and-how-you-can-too/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/why-we-rebuilt-our-equity-plan-for-flexibility-and-how-you-can-too/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postscript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[talent acquisition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[talent retention]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The most competitive startups will not only give staff the shares that they deserve but will also do so in a way that’s tax-advantaged, de-risked and highly customizable.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Colin Turner</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/cdturns">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Colin Turner is co-founder and COO of <a href="https://www.postscript.io/">Postscript</a>, an SMS marketing platform leveraged by thousands of Shopify businesses.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Mailchimp made <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/intuits-12b-mailchimp-acquisition-is-about-expanding-its-small-business-focus/">headlines last month</a> when it sold to Intuit for $12 billion, but many of the stories surrounding the news were far from glowing. Its 1,200 employees didn’t get any equity in the company and missed out on the life-changing financial upside that would typically come from a deal of this magnitude.</p>
<p>We know this isn’t the norm. Most startups follow a standard playbook for issuing employee equity, but it’s a system riddled with complications. The industry has even coined terms like &#8220;golden handcuffs&#8221; to describe one of the all too common scenarios where employees have millions in stock options but can’t afford the taxes they’d owe to leave their current company before a liquidity event like an IPO or acquisition.</p>
<p>The employee equity status quo isn’t going to work for much longer. As talent wars rage on, companies are getting more competitive on base salary, bonuses, benefits and workplace flexibility. Equity is bound to be the next to change in the battle for talent.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2228255" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The most competitive startups will not only give staff the shares that they deserve but will also do so in a way that’s tax-advantaged, de-risked and highly customizable. Early on in the journey to build my startup Postscript with my co-founders Adam Turner and Alex Beller, we decided an equity plan that puts employees first was going to be a top priority. We hadn’t done this before, and we weren’t following the standard playbook, so it took time, research and creativity.</p>
<h2>Flexibility and choice are paramount in employee equity</h2>
<p>Our first initiative focused on providing employees with an extended exercise window. If someone has been at the company for two years and quits, they don’t need to buy shares right away. In fact, they have up to five years to make that decision. This is a great option for employees that want to &#8220;wait and see,&#8221; and de-risks their equity.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Within the next few years, I predict that we’re going to see a shift in how employers approach equity as a benefit and that flexibility will become the norm, rather than the exception.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The next component of our program was in response to demand from employees confident in our long-term prospects. We crafted a plan that allows employees to exercise their stock early — at any time, in fact. This is a great option for employees that believe strongly in our success and want to reap the tax advantages of buying their shares early on.</p>
<p>With these two programs, we’re not assuming anything about each employee&#8217;s personal situation or forcing our beliefs on anyone. We’re also careful to not make promises about the future that would influence decisions, as we saw happen with Mailchimp. We don’t believe in declarative statements like &#8220;we’ll never go public&#8221; or &#8220;we’ll never be acquired,&#8221; even if well intentioned. No executive can fully predict the future with absolute certainty.</p>
<p>For businesses that are ready to revamp their employee equity plan, here are a few key lessons we figured out along the way:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h3>Get buy-in from your board of directors</h3>
<p>The first step should be a discussion with your board, likely during the next board meeting. This group of individuals usually hold significant equity in the business, so they may be just as invested in the decision as the founders. If you lead with the business benefits that the changes could have on recruiting, culture and morale, the opportunity for pushback will be limited.</p>
<h3>Get outside support from legal experts</h3>
<p>After the key stakeholders are aligned, loop in the experts. Unless they’re already on the team, find a law firm or legal consultant that knows employee equity inside out. They’ll need to consider every possibility and develop new documentation and contracts that might not already exist. Our legal partner played a huge role in making sure that our plan was initiated without a hitch.</p>
<h3>Double down on employee and candidate education</h3>
<p>Finally, the people and recruiting teams should be educated well on the program. It’s their responsibility to ensure that employees and prospects understand how the program works, as well as the implications of the decisions they make. Equity is complex and can be difficult to understand, so this undertaking shouldn’t be approached lightly and should be ongoing.</p>
<p>Within the next few years, I predict that we’re going to see a shift in how employers approach equity as a benefit and that flexibility will become the norm, rather than the exception. At the end of the day, this is good news for employees and employers alike.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/why-we-rebuilt-our-equity-plan-for-flexibility-and-how-you-can-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228255</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: Holiday marketing tips, low-cost NFTs, SaaS sprawl study</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/techcrunch-roundup-holiday-marketing-tips-low-cost-nfts-saas-sprawl-study/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/techcrunch-roundup-holiday-marketing-tips-low-cost-nfts-saas-sprawl-study/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer acquisition cost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiffany Chu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zillow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cargo ships are stacked up outside ports, and empty shipping containers are in short supply, as are the truck drivers who would take them to market. This is not the time for doing business as usual.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Boston-based VC firm OpenView interviewed nearly 600 SaaS companies for its annual pricing survey and the results are in: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/">Automation is taking usage-based pricing (USP) mainstream</a>.</p>
<p>Last year, 34% of survey respondents said they were using a flexible pricing model. This year, that figure rose to 45%.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription.</i></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230067" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p>“Seats are just an outdated way of charging and don’t allow a company to communicate value or invest in features that would add more value,&#8221; said OpenView operating partner Kyle Poyar.</p>
<p>“In fact,” he said, “it might even be negatively correlated: When AI can automate tasks, the more successful the solution is, the fewer people need to be logging in.&#8221;</p>
<p>The report had many interesting findings, but here&#8217;s the one that left the biggest impression on me: Startups that adopt USP and product-led growth strategies pay back customer acquisition costs faster <strong>and</strong> have higher net-dollar retention.</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading TechCrunch+ — I hope you have a relaxing weekend.</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jj4OcmWj56"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/">Why more SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based pricing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why more SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based pricing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/embed/#?secret=jj4OcmWj56" data-secret="jj4OcmWj56" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2229582" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229582" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2229582" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg" alt="Directly Above Shot Of Open Cardboard Box Over White Background" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229582" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=paolomartinezphotography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">paolomartinezphotography <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>With only three weeks left to the start of the holiday shopping season, Miranda Halpern checked in with several growth marketers to find out how they&#8217;re advising their clients to prepare for supply chain disruptions.</p>
<p>Cargo ships are stacked up outside ports, and empty shipping containers are in short supply, as are the truck drivers who would take them to market. This is not the time for doing business as usual.</p>
<p>To gather advice and insights, she interviewed:</p>
<ul>
<li>Julio Lopez, director of client strategy, retail practice lead, Movable Ink</li>
<li>Chris Toy, CEO and co-founder, Marketer Hire</li>
<li>Kristin Dick, head of operations and growth marketer, Tuff</li>
<li>Dipti Parmar, founder, Dipti Parmar Consulting</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KyAP1HElcL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/embed/#?secret=KyAP1HElcL" data-secret="KyAP1HElcL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Bring on the low-cost NFTs</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The NFT marketplace is still a bit of a head-scratcher for those of us without loads of expendable income, but new data from DappRadar provides some insight into what the masses value.</p>
<p>As Alex Wilhelm reports, a lot of  activity is focused on games like Axie Infinity, where players can collect and do battle with Pokémon-esque NFTs priced at around $250.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That gives us a look into the nascent non-fungible token ecosystem and what people want to buy and trade: more affordable, value-generating NFTs that &#8220;unlock an activity that are not artificially supply constrained.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SE3o4rzgcc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/bring-on-the-low-cost-nfts/">Bring on the low-cost NFTs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bring on the low-cost NFTs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/bring-on-the-low-cost-nfts/embed/#?secret=SE3o4rzgcc" data-secret="SE3o4rzgcc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The consequences of SaaS sprawl: A real-world study</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228116" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228116" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228116" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg" alt="Spaghetti and sauce spilled on kitchen floor" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228116" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Lew+Robertson" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lew Robertson <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no way to avoid SaaS sprawl: When employees can independently select software that meets their personal needs, every organization must dodge this pothole.</p>
<p>In a detailed breakdown of a recent research study, returning contributors Tomer Y. Avni and Mark Settle explore the myriad impacts of running a business partially on shadow IT.</p>
<p>Besides numerous administrative problems, SaaS sprawl can create fundamental security risks, especially for companies where many employees can access IP and personally identifiable information.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vdR8Hgne9t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/the-consequences-of-saas-sprawl-a-real-world-study/">The consequences of SaaS sprawl: A real-world study</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The consequences of SaaS sprawl: A real-world study&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/the-consequences-of-saas-sprawl-a-real-world-study/embed/#?secret=vdR8Hgne9t" data-secret="vdR8Hgne9t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>We’re still just scratching the surface of the cloud’s potential</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228389" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228389" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228389" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg" alt="The state of the public cloud in 2021 looks pretty good" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228389" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=your_photo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">your_photo <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The cloud storage and services market is nowhere near maturity, according to Battery Ventures&#8217; 2021 State of the OpenCloud report.</p>
<p>According to the firm&#8217;s estimate, the market could eventually be worth as much as $1 trillion.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you consider that the vast majority of work, development and computing will be done in the cloud at some point, the investment group’s round-number projection may prove modest,&#8221; write Ron Miller and Alex Wilhelm, who broke down the report and spoke to Battery General Partner Dharmesh Thakker.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uZc5o9PXkw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/were-still-just-scratching-the-surface-of-the-clouds-potential/">We&#8217;re still just scratching the surface of the cloud&#8217;s potential</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;We&#8217;re still just scratching the surface of the cloud&#8217;s potential&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/were-still-just-scratching-the-surface-of-the-clouds-potential/embed/#?secret=uZc5o9PXkw" data-secret="uZc5o9PXkw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What does Zillow’s exit tell us about the health of the iBuying market?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2229680" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229680" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2229680" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg" alt="For Sale sign board in front of a model home" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229680" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Glow+Images" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Glow Images <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>I always learn something while editing stories written by TechCrunch reporters: Because Ryan Lawler covers proptech for us, I asked him to explain the significance of Zillow&#8217;s decision to depart the iBuying business.</p>
<p>This story has been very well covered, but I haven&#8217;t seen anyone else put it this succinctly:</p>
<blockquote><p>Selling an asset at a loss is a bad idea in most areas of business, but it is a particularly bad idea in a market where sales cycles are slow, unpredictable and largely out of your control.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pymoK1Plro"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/zillow-ibuying-exit-opendoor-offerpad/">What does Zillow’s exit tell us about the health of the iBuying market?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What does Zillow’s exit tell us about the health of the iBuying market?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/zillow-ibuying-exit-opendoor-offerpad/embed/#?secret=pymoK1Plro" data-secret="pymoK1Plro" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Via’s Tiffany Chu on the importance of govtech for planning mobility ecosystems</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228055" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228055" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228055" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg" alt="Illustration of Tiffany Chu, SVP and co-founder of Remix by Via" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228055" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin</p></div></p>
<p>Robots that can make salads and cheeseburgers are fascinating, which means they&#8217;re more likely to hog the headlines than companies making technology that optimizes governmental operations.</p>
<p>But govtech and civic tech has a greater social impact than burger-flipping robots. Startups that bridge the public and private sectors can build sustainable businesses with strong returns, says Tiffany Chu, SVP of mobility firm Via and former CEO of Remix.</p>
<p>&#8220;What’s special about this space is that it’s the intersection of a customer base that will always be around,&#8221; Chu says.</p>
<p>&#8220;Governments rarely go out of business, so there’s a very direct, targeted customer base that makes it clear who your product needs to serve.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9Nfx9I1jZu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/vias-tiffany-chu-on-the-importance-of-govtech-for-planning-mobility-ecosystems/">Via&#8217;s Tiffany Chu on the importance of govtech for planning mobility ecosystems</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Via&#8217;s Tiffany Chu on the importance of govtech for planning mobility ecosystems&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/vias-tiffany-chu-on-the-importance-of-govtech-for-planning-mobility-ecosystems/embed/#?secret=9Nfx9I1jZu" data-secret="9Nfx9I1jZu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Female founders are making a buzzing, venture-backed comeback</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228491" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228491" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228491" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg" alt="Woman wearing floppy hat driving car with a giant piggy bank on top" width="1024" height="685" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=768,514 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=680,455 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228491" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Colin+Anderson+Productions+pty+ltd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Colin Anderson Productions pty ltd <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We are nowhere near achieving parity or representation when it comes to startup funding, but the gender gap is narrowing, according to PitchBook data.</p>
<p>Funding for U.S.-based, female-founded startups nearly doubled in the last year: So far in 2021, women-led companies have closed 2,661 deals worth $40.4 billion.</p>
<p>“Thus far in 2021, the backsliding has more than stopped,” report Natasha Mascarenhas and Alex Wilhelm. “Indeed, it has shot the other direction.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3bkLeFB8Ky"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/female-founders-are-making-a-buzzing-venture-backed-comeback/">Female founders are making a buzzing, venture-backed comeback</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Female founders are making a buzzing, venture-backed comeback&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/female-founders-are-making-a-buzzing-venture-backed-comeback/embed/#?secret=3bkLeFB8Ky" data-secret="3bkLeFB8Ky" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why LatAm’s fintech boom is more than hype and superlative venture investment</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Venture capital is flowing around the world in unprecedented volumes, but it&#8217;s not hyperbole to say that Latin America&#8217;s fintech startups are having their best year ever.</p>
<p>Unprecedented tailwinds, a wealth of opportunities and strong competition are together driving fintechs in the region to innovate faster than ever, report Anna Heim and Alex Wilhelm. And despite intense competition, VCs are jumping in feet first, looking for more opportunities.</p>
<p>&#8220;Nubank is setting the bar of how big can a business get on an IPO and will make VCs think more thoroughly about how big can a business get if everything [goes] right,&#8221; said one investor.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A69BQG5PDv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/why-latams-fintech-boom-is-more-than-hype-and-superlative-venture-investment/">Why LatAm&#8217;s fintech boom is more than hype and superlative venture investment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why LatAm&#8217;s fintech boom is more than hype and superlative venture investment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/why-latams-fintech-boom-is-more-than-hype-and-superlative-venture-investment/embed/#?secret=A69BQG5PDv" data-secret="A69BQG5PDv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/techcrunch-roundup-holiday-marketing-tips-low-cost-nfts-saas-sprawl-study/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All systems go: Buy your pass to TC Sessions: Space 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marquise Foster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Space Race 2.0 is heating up fast, and whether your role lies in the private or public sector, TC Sessions: Space 2021 focuses on the emerging trends, essential data science and creative collaborations required to build a sustainable space economy. Yesterday, we announced a portion of the fully virtual event&#8217;s agenda. Take a look.  We [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Space Race 2.0 is heating up fast, and whether your role lies in the private or public sector, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> focuses on the emerging trends, essential data science and creative collaborations required to build a sustainable space economy. Yesterday, we announced a portion of the fully virtual event&#8217;s agenda. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/announcing-the-agenda-for-techcrunch-sessions-space-2021/">Take a look. </a></p>
<p>We can’t divulge the full agenda quite yet, but TC Sessions events always deliver the foremost leaders from across the tech and investing spectrum. Space 2021 will be no exception.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=TRUE">If you buy your pass today</a>, you save $100 with the general admission price and will join the global, early-stage space startup community for two full days on December 14-15. Want to bring your space crew? Take advantage of group discounts when you buy four or more passes. We also offer discounts on student tickets.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225694" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Given the astronomical cost of virtually anything related to space, we’ll have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/find-out-what-it-takes-to-make-smart-early-bets-in-the-space-industry-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">plenty of investors in the house</a>, including Chad Anderson (Space Capital), Tess Hatch (Bessemer Venture Partners) and Jessica Robinson (Assembly Ventures), to name a few.</p>
<p>Panel discussions, interviews and breakout session will cover a range of topics, like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/learn-why-in-space-propulsion-systems-are-essential-for-a-sustainable-space-economy-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">in-space propulsion systems are essential</a> for a sustainable space economy</li>
<li>What <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/learn-how-studying-lunar-samples-may-help-sustain-human-life-beyond-our-planet-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">studying lunar samples</a> can teach us about sustaining human life beyond Earth</li>
<li>How <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/learn-about-the-benefits-of-on-orbit-operations-and-servicing-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">on-orbit operations and servicing technologies</a> extend the life of space craft, reduce space junk and save money (lots of money)</li>
</ul>
<p>You might go faster alone, but you go farther together. That’s a round-about way of saying take advantage of this prime networking opportunity. Whether you’re looking for funding, a potential space unicorn or to hire a brilliant mind, this is a solid way to build meaningful relationships.</p>
<p>Early-stage space founders &#8212; buy a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=TRUE">Space Startup Exhibitor Package</a> and demo your game-changing tech to this very targeted community. We’re talking top investors, aerospace primes and government entities &#8212; the folks who can make big things happen, like cutting through government red tape.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> takes place on December 14-15. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=TRUE">Buy your pass</a> and stay ahead of the orbital curve.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Space 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			width="100%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225694</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An inclusive new DTC beauty platform secures $3 million in funding &#8212; and a supercharged offline strategy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 18:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brick-and-mortar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fearless fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inclusivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jcpenney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nyakio Grieco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sephora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thirteen Lune]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this week, Thirteen Lune, a direct-to-consumer beauty platform that was launched last year in LA with $1 million in seed funding from Diddy, Gwyneth Paltrow and Beautycounter founder Gregg Renfrew, announced $3 million in additional seed funding. We might not normally pause on this kind of development, especially in a market where dozens of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this week, <a href="https://thirteenlune.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thirteen Lune</a>, a direct-to-consumer beauty platform that was launched last year in LA with $1 million in seed funding from Diddy, Gwyneth Paltrow and Beautycounter founder Gregg Renfrew, announced $3 million in additional seed funding. We might not normally pause on this kind of development, especially in a market where dozens of startups are announcing funding every day, but this deal stood out for a few reasons beyond its celebrity backing.</p>
<p>First, its co-founder is Nyakio Grieco, a veteran of the cosmetics industry who earlier launched a skin-care brand that she sold to Sundial Brands, which is now part of Unilever. Her new e-commerce platform sells products from 100 different brands, 90% of which were founded by Black, Indigenous, and people of color. And the outfit leading the financing is <a href="https://www.fearless.fund/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fearless Fund</a>, a venture firm that was founded by women of color and is making its mark by focusing exclusively on backing women of color.</p>
<p>Also very interesting: a tie-up with JCPenney that immediately gives Thirteen Lune the kind of reach that most nascent startups can only dream about. JCPenney long partnered with Sephora, but Sephora&#8217;s contract with JCPenney is expiring in 2023, and it chose not to renew, leaving the retailer &#8212; which last year <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-07/jcpenney-survives-going-bankrupt-now-comes-the-hard-part?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survived going bankrupt</a> &#8212; with space to fill. Going into those spots right now are in-store &#8220;JCPenney Beauty&#8221; shops, and Thirteen Lune is a featured part of that offering, with 10 locations already up and running and plans for 600 more locations by the end of 2023.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230031" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Put together, the pieces add up to what Thirteen Lune is characterizing, persuasively, as among one of the first truly inclusive beauty platforms. Grieco told us a bit more this week, though she declined to answer questions about the financial mechanics of the JCPenney deal, citing a confidentiality agreement with the outfit.</p>
<p>Excerpts from this conversation have been edited for length.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How did you get started in the beauty business?</strong></p>
<p>NG: I&#8217;m a first-generation American of Kenyan descent, and almost 20 years ago, I left my job working in Hollywood to create a beauty brand based on my Kenyan family beauty secrets. My grandmother was a Kenyan coffee farmer, and my grandfather was a medicine man, and I felt that the continent of Africa at the time was very underrepresented in premium beauty. So I left my job to start making my grandmother&#8217;s coffee scrub and to learn to create products based in sustainable oils, the kind that my grandfather had the ability to go out in nature and extract to treat the skin.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>I started as a very independent brand out of my apartment in my 20s and served every role: founder, shipping and receiving, customer service, accounting. I learned very quickly as a young Black woman and first-time entrepreneur how difficult it was to raise money, but I was able to get a little bit of friends-and-family capital together to take the products to market.</p>
<p><strong>You initially launched at Fred Segal; your skin creams were later carried in Ulta and are now <a href="https://www.target.com/s?searchTerm=nyakio" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available</a> at Target. Why dive back into a new brand last year?</strong></p>
<p>While we were dealing with the global pandemic, as well as the most heightened moment of the Black Lives Matter movement of our lifetime, I found myself showing up on all of the lists of, you know, top Black-owned, Black-founded brands to shop and to follow. And while we saw a significant increase in sales at Target, it was really built on the precipice of such a heartbreaking time. And I just thought to myself, how strange is it that this moment is making people pay attention to my brand? I was in deep gratitude, but they were asking me questions like, &#8216;Can I use your products on my skin because I don&#8217;t look like you?&#8217; [At the same time], I was seeing amazing initiatives like the <a href="https://15percentpledge.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15% Pledge</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/pullupforchange/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pull Up for Change</a> come about, and in my head, when I was shopping those lists, I thought to myself, &#8216;I could fill a whole store with these incredible beautiful brands, many of which had such little distribution and visibility and most of which were direct to consumer . . . So my co-founder and I built Thirteen Lune based on a 90/10 rule, which is that 90% of all the products that we carry are created by BIPOC founders who create products for people of all colors &#8212; we are Black and brown for all. And then 10% of our brands are dedicated to fostering allyship, because it&#8217;s not our fight to fight alone. We have to join together. We&#8217;ve lived too many years in divisive times.</p>
<p><strong>You are dealing with a lot of products that a third-party logistics provider sends out to customers because you want to own that experience. How do you vet what you&#8217;re selling?</strong></p>
<p>A product has to have a strong founder story, because people buy into people before they buy into product. We also have what we call our beauty vanguard, which is influencers, makeup artists, celebrities and friends who help us, because we have such an enormous amount of products coming our way. And we have certain standards, including that we want all products to be clean, nontoxic, with good-for-you ingredients. [And we want them] to really serve a need, focusing on our melanin-rich, textured-hair customer first &#8212; those who have been the most underserved &#8212; but also to really represent the globe.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the products that are geared more toward people with melanin-rich skin? Also, as a Greek-American with fair skin, what are some of the products that I perhaps haven&#8217;t been exposed to but might turn to Thirteen Lune to order?</strong></p>
<p>Melanin rich [could apply] all the way from somebody who&#8217;s just slightly darker than maybe you all the way to a tone much darker than myself, and we often have a sensitivity to certain acids and chemical exfoliators and things like that will burn our skin or just color our skin. We&#8217;re more prone to hyperpigmentation. We&#8217;re more prone to eczema and rosacea and those types of skin conditions. So the products that we bring to shelf are things like a chemical peel that&#8217;s made with maybe azelaic acid and not maybe other acids that would be too harsh for our skin.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the same with textured hair. Shampoo is shampoo and conditioner is conditioner, but at the end of the day, especially as we are moving to a place where we are living with such multiracial and generational qualities and properties to our hair and our hair texture, [brands are on the rise like] <a href="https://bombacurls.com/">Bomba Curls</a>, which was created by an Afro-Latina founder named Lulu Cordero. She grew up with Dominican culture and back in those days, it was about having the straight &#8212; they call it &#8220;pelo malo&#8221; &#8212; hair to look more like white women from the Western world. And it caused a lot of damage to her, so much so that she suffered hair loss going into her college years.</p>
<p>She also happens to be brilliant and she was a chemistry major and she started playing with ingredients while she was in her college chemistry lab that would help to stimulate her hair growth; she started researching things that come from the earth and her culture like coffee and castor oil, and she developed her own hair oil [that was later lab-certified as counter safe]. That doesn&#8217;t mean that my friends that are blond-haired and blue-eyed can&#8217;t use Bomba Curls. The difference is that [the product] was created by a Black woman who understands our hair texture and understands the damage that we have done to our hair for so long, and she&#8217;s able to deliver on her promise [to repair that damage].</p>
<p><strong>You are also planning to roll out a private label brand. Why?</strong></p>
<p>When we look at Thirteen Lune and the data that we&#8217;re getting and will have access to [regarding] what this customer still needs and how we can better serve he, she, them, they through the lens of inclusivity, I&#8217;m excited about being able to create again. I love being a beauty retailer, but I&#8217;m a beauty founder first. That&#8217;s my passion, and I&#8217;ve missed being in a lab and being able to create. It&#8217;s literally my happy place.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230031</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Appetiser&#8217;s co-founders discuss building client relationships and getting to MVP</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/appetisers-co-founders-discuss-building-client-relationships-and-getting-to-mvp/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/appetisers-co-founders-discuss-building-client-relationships-and-getting-to-mvp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 17:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[australian startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Software Consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outsourcing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prototyping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We interviewed Jamie Shostak and Michael MacRae, co-founders of Australian agency Appetiser, which focuses on designing, building and growing mobile and web apps.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://appetiser.com.au/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Appetiser</a>&#8216;s site lists three factors for app success: Technology, marketing and design. And while the Australian agency was recommended to TechCrunch via our <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl">our survey to identify software development partners for startups</a>, it could just have well have come through our survey to recommend growth marketers, which you can answer <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">here</a>.</p>
<p>With a focus on designing, building and growing mobile and web apps, Appetiser&#8217;s co-founders Jamie Shostak and Michael MacRae were endorsed by several clients who worked with them from the earliest days of their projects. &#8220;Every startup has to start with an idea. And some of the best startups can come from people who experience the problem firsthand, even if they are not the most technical,&#8221; Shostak noted.</p>
<p>TradeNow, an Australian pay-later financing option for trade businesses and their customers, is one such customer. “The Appetiser team has developed great leading applications and also believed in the vision of TradeNow from the very start,&#8221; its founder Matt Brennan wrote. &#8220;We were able to develop a great working relationship early on and continue this along the journey.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229520" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Fellow entrepreneur Andre Eikmeier praised the flexibility of Appetiser&#8217;s model. &#8220;We were able to use our CTO to lead a team of six devs from the Appetiser team, with occasional UX/UI, product management and project management as needed. It was properly collaborative, not a blackbox agency arrangement. So we were able to build capability in-house at the same time, rather than dependency.&#8221;</p>
<p>To find out more, we interviewed both Shostak and MacRae, in a discussion that went from prototyping to growth, and from MVP to design excellence.</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s note: This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</em></p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s Appetiser&#8217;s origin story?</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Jamie Shostak: </strong>Back in 2017, I ran into a tall German guy at the coffee machine of a co-working space in Melbourne: Michael. He had apps with millions of users, and I was running a growth marketing agency. After getting to know each other, we discovered a mutual passion for building and growing tech products. We had some healthy debates and identified how we could help others with their own product’s success: Speed to market, data-driven insights, top-level quality and strong teams. And that’s how Appetiser was born.</p>
<p><strong>What size is your team now, and how is it structured?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael MacRae: </strong>We have a team of 150 in Asia and 30 people in Australia. Our teams are built around efficiency: Small, client-embedded production squads comprising iOS, Android and back-end developers, as well as UX designers, product managers and QA/PM specialists. These squads work together in an agile environment and scale up or down based on the needs of the project. Appetiser itself is relatively flat, with a huge focus on data-driven decision-making via iterative testing.</p>
<p><strong>One of your clients told TechCrunch that Appetiser is &#8220;the opposite of a blackbox.&#8221; What does that mean?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>The “Telephone Game” is a popular children&#8217;s game to teach us the consequences of messages traveling from person to person. Sadly, agencies love “shielding” their team of developers, testers and designers from clients by introducing layers. Simply put, we do the opposite. When we build your team at Appetiser, it will be your team! Join standups, ideate with your team, discuss challenges or even have one-on-ones. We replicated the structure of successful startups with in-house teams, and then we rebuilt it in an agency form.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best software consultants for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Your site mentions that beyond designing and building apps, you are your clients’ &#8220;growth machine.&#8221; Can you explain?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>The vision for Appetiser was never to be an app development company. Instead, we think of ourselves as a product success agency. Simply put, we try to maximize the chances of a product becoming a success story. We measure how many of our apps become successful, how many users they’ve got, how much revenue they generate and how much money they raise.</p>
<p>Our entire team is held accountable to these success metrics, which means we do whatever it takes to help our clients get there. This may include design, development and growth, but often it’s also strategy, help with fundraising and more.</p>
<p><strong>Why does your strategy require defining a minimum viable product (MVP)?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Shostak: </strong>We’ve spent years refining internal IP based on data to rapidly deliver reliable, high-quality products. We use this to help entrepreneurs get to market fast with an MVP.</p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>Defining that MVP comes down to creating real-world value but also emotionally detaching ourselves from nice-to-haves. They can always be added later! As a result, we reduce the amount of time and iteration cycles to find product-market fit. Our clients save time and money, which will be invested into growing their products. Our client <a href="https://movewithus.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Move With Us</a> used this approach to cut development timelines in half, resulting in them gaining huge traction in both Australia and the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>But before that, you do prototyping. Why?<br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong>Shostak: </strong>Whether you’re someone with an idea or a big business, we always start with a standalone design stage and interactive prototype. It allows us to visually scope out the project whilst building an industry leading front-end experience. In Steve Jobs’ words, we like to start with the user experience and [work backward to the technology].</p>
<p>This also acts as a great starting point to raise capital, get stakeholder buy-in or validate their idea before taking steps into full development. We’re extremely proud of clients like <a href="https://goodempire.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Good Empire</a> and <a href="https://vello.vip/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vello</a> that have been able to raise [funding] even before development.</p>
<p><strong>Why do you value design quality?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>On the App Store, you’ve got seconds to convince a user to download your app. On the web, if you don&#8217;t convert a visitor within seconds, they’re gone forever. So at first, design excellence is a matter of understanding what users desire. This accelerates user acquisition. And once you’ve signed up your user, a strong user experience retains them.</p>
<p>We also believe that product design is not just a creative field; it’s a matter of performance: One design will always outperform the other. We try to centralize the learnings from all of our projects to design based on proven tactics to minimize risky assumptions.</p>
<p><strong>How do you share knowledge internally?<br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>Appetiser has created more internal IP than a majority of agencies. This includes our baseplate; our gold standards to unify the team based on best practices, which a large portion of our team ongoingly investigates, tests and iterates upon; and our educational materials and courses.</p>
<p>For the latter, we established the Appetiser University. It has a growing curriculum of production-relevant topics such as standards, best practices and guidelines, and also covers topics like economics, CRO and data analysis. Appetiser employees even have weekly exams that ask them to apply their learnings.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of your plans for the next year?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Shostak: </strong>With a remote-first culture, our plan was always to hire the best talent in the world. This started with a focus first on Asia Pacific. So far we’re in Davao, Cebu, Manilla, Melbourne and Sydney. In 2022, we are looking to expand this across a few more continents [ … ] and you can expect to see us in the U.S. within the next 12 months.</p>
<p>In addition, starting in 2022 and beyond, we want to build our own startup community and platform, and expand that globally. From partnering with investors, crowdfunding platforms, lawyers and accountants to creating our own educational content. We want to enable startups to conquer international markets. And we’re also currently building an incubator called Appetiser Ventures, where we will help accelerate clients&#8217; startups further and even potentially build some internally.</p>
<div style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" data-tf-widget="MXehi2kl"></div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/appetisers-co-founders-discuss-building-client-relationships-and-getting-to-mvp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229520</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cruise lays out its plan for &#8216;how&#8217; it will make robotaxis a reality</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ridehail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The string of engineers who spoke Thursday night during a deep dive into Cruise&#8217;s autonomous vehicle technology never mentioned Tesla&#8217;s name. They didn&#8217;t have to, although the message was clear enough. GM&#8217;s self-driving subsidiary Cruise presented a technical and deployment roadmap — at a granular level — that aimed to show how it has built [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The string of engineers who spoke Thursday night during a deep dive into Cruise&#8217;s autonomous vehicle technology never mentioned Tesla&#8217;s name. They didn&#8217;t have to, although the message was clear enough.</p>
<p>GM&#8217;s self-driving subsidiary Cruise presented a technical and deployment roadmap — at a granular level — that aimed to show how it has built autonomous vehicles that are safer and more scalable than any human-driven vehicle, including those equipped with advanced driver assistance systems.</p>
<p>While Cruise was clearly making a case for its own technology (not to mention trying to recruit fresh talent), the event was also an argument for autonomous vehicles in general. Each engineer or product lead who spoke Thursday presented various components, from how it uses simulations and the development of its own chips and other hardware to the design of its app and the vehicle itself.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229818" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The branded &#8220;Under the Hood&#8221; event built off of comments CEO Dan Ammann made last month during GM&#8217;s investor day, in which he laid out the company&#8217;s plan to launch a commercial robotaxi and delivery service <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/self-driving-company-cruise-on-track-for-early-commercial-operations-in-2022/">starting with retrofitted Chevy Bolts</a> and eventually scaling to an army of tens of thousands of purpose-built Origin AVs on the road over the next few years.</p>
<p>Cruise <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/cruise-waymo-get-ok-to-launch-robotaxi-service-in-san-francisco/">just gained approval in California</a> to perform commercial delivery services, and is still one permit away from being able to charge for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/cruise-launches-driverless-robotaxi-service-for-employees-in-san-francisco/">driverless ride-hailing</a>. Still, Cruise thinks it&#8217;ll be able to drive down costs enough to scale up and out quickly.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s how.</p>
<h2>Using simulations to scale, not just verify the system</h2>
<p>Cruise is relying on simulations not only to prove out its safety case, but also to scale to new cities without having to perform millions of miles of tests in them first.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company will still have to map the cities it enters. But it won&#8217;t have to remap cities to track changes to the environment that inevitably happen, like lane changes or street closures. When Cruise goes to new cities, it starts with a technology it calls WorldGen, which it says does accurate, large-scale generation of entire cities, &#8220;from their quirky layouts to the smallest details,&#8221; which allows engineers to test out new operational design domains, according to Sid Gandhi, technical strategy lead of simulation at Cruise. In other words, WorldGen becomes the stage where the future simulations are set.</p>
<p>To ensure optimal world creation, Cruise takes into account things like lighting at 24 different unique times of day and weather conditions, even going as far as to systematically measure light from a range of street lamps in San Francisco.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we combine a high-fidelity environment with a procedurally generated city, that&#8217;s when we unlock the capability to efficiently scale our business to new cities,&#8221; said Gandhi.</p>
<p>He then laid out the technology for the &#8220;Road to Sim,&#8221; which transforms into editable simulation scenarios real events that have been collected by AVs on the road. This ensures that the AV doesn&#8217;t regress by testing against scenarios it has already seen.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Road to Sim combines information from perception with heuristics learned from our millions of real-world miles to recreate a full simulation environment from road data,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;Once we have the simulation, we can actually create permutations of the event and change attributes like vehicle and pedestrian types. It&#8217;s a super easy and extremely powerful way to build test suites that accelerate AV development.&#8221;</p>
<p>For specific scenarios that Cruise hasn&#8217;t been able to collect in real-world road conditions, there&#8217;s Morpheus. Morpheus is a system that can generate simulations based on specific locations on the map. It uses machine learning to automatically enter as many parameters as it wants to generate thousands of interesting and rare scenarios against which it tests the AV.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we work on solving the longtail, we&#8217;ll rely less and less on real-world testing because when you have an event that happens rarely, it takes thousands of road miles to test it properly, and it&#8217;s just not scalable,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;So we&#8217;re developing technology to scalably explore large-scale parameter spaces to generate test scenarios.&#8221;</p>
<p>Test scenarios also include simulating the way other road users react to the AV. Cruise&#8217;s system for this is called non-player character (NPC) AI, which is usually a video game term, but in this context, refers to all of the cars and pedestrians in a scene that represent complex multi-agent behaviors.</p>
<p>&#8220;So Morpheus, Road to Sim and NPC AI work together in this really thoughtful way to let us perform more robust testing around rare and difficult events,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;And it really gives us the confidence that we can solve rare issues now and in future similar issues, as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Generating synthetic data helps the Cruise AV target specific use cases, said Gandhi, pointing specifically to identifying and interacting with emergency vehicles, presumably for no other reason than to take a dig at Tesla, whose Autopilot ADAS system has come under federal scrutiny for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/">repeated crashes into emergency vehicles</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Emergency vehicles are rare compared to other types of vehicles, but we need to detect them with extremely high accuracy, so we use our data generation pipeline to create millions of simulation images of ambulances, fire trucks and police cars,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;In our experience targeted synthetic data is about 180 times faster than collecting road data, and millions of dollars cheaper. And with the right mix of synthetic and real data, we can increase relevant data in our data sets by an order of magnitude or more.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Two custom silicon chips developed in-house</h2>
<p>During GM&#8217;s investor day in October, Cruise CEO Dan Ammann outlined the company&#8217;s plan to invest heavily into the compute power of the Origin in order to decrease costs by 90% over the next four generations so it can scale profitably. At the time, Ammann mentioned Cruise&#8217;s intention to manufacture custom silicon in-house to cut costs, but didn&#8217;t admit outright using that silicon to build a chip &#8212; but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/cruise-plans-to-have-tens-of-thousands-of-origin-avs-on-roads-in-coming-years/">TechCrunch had its theories</a>. On Thursday, Rajat Basu, chief engineer for the Origin program, validated those theories.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our fourth-generation compute platform will be based on our in-house custom silicon development,&#8221; said Basu. &#8220;This is purpose-built for our application. It enables focus and improves processing capability, while significantly reducing piece costs and power consumption. Compute is a critical system from a safety perspective, and has redundancy built into it. Add to that an AV system that is processing up to 10 gigabits of data every second, we end up consuming a fair amount of power. Our MLH chip allows us to run our complex machine learning pipelines in a much more focused manner, which in turn helps us to be more energy efficient without compromising on performance.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cruise&#8217;s AI team developed two chips: The sensor processing chip will handle edge processing for the range of sensors like cameras, radar and acoustics. The second chip, which is designed to be a dedicated neural network processor, supports and accelerates machine learning applications like those large, multitask models developed by the AI team. Basu says the machine learning accelerator (MLA) chip is just the right size to solve exactly a certain class of neural net and ML applications, and nothing more.</p>
<p>&#8220;This keeps the performance at an extremely high level, and it ensures that we are not wasting energy on doing anything that is not value added for us,&#8221; said Basu. &#8220;It can be paired with multiple external hosts or operate standalone. It supports single Ethernet networks up to 25G with a total bandwidth of 400G. The MLA chip we&#8217;re putting into volume production is just the start. Over time we will continue to make this even higher-performing while reducing power consumption.&#8221;</p>
<h2>The Cruise ecosystem</h2>
<p>One thing Cruise made clear during its event is that it hasn&#8217;t just thought of the AV tech needed to scale up successfully, but also the entire ecosystem, which includes things like remote assistance operators to validate the AV&#8217;s decision when it comes across unknown scenarios, customer service, a vehicle that people actually want to ride around in and an app that can efficiently and easily handle things like customer support and incidence response.</p>
<p>&#8220;To truly cross the chasm from research and development to a beloved product requires more than just artificial intelligence and robotics,&#8221; said Oliver Cameron, Cruise&#8217;s VP of product, at the event. &#8220;A safe self-driving vehicle alone is insufficient and simply the first step on a long, long journey. To truly build and scale a competitive product that is adopted by millions into their daily lives, you need to build a host of differentiated features and tools atop a safe self-driving foundation. How these features need to be implemented is non-obvious, especially if your company&#8217;s still heads-down solving safety issues.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IAB Europe says it&#8217;s expecting to be found in breach of GDPR</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behavioral advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belgium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data controller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iab europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johnny Ryan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is this the beginning of the end for the hated tracking cookie consent pop-up? A flagship framework used by Google and scores of other advertisers for gathering claimed consent from web users for creepy ad targeting looks set to be found in breach of Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). A year ago the IAB [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Is this the beginning of the end for the hated tracking cookie consent pop-up? A flagship framework used by Google and scores of other advertisers for gathering claimed consent from web users for creepy ad targeting looks set to be found in breach of Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/">A year ago</a> the IAB Europe&#8217;s self-styled Transparency and Consent Framework (TCF) was found to fail to comply with GDPR principles of transparency, fairness and accountability, and the lawfulness of processing in a preliminary report by the investigatory division of the Belgian data protection authority.</p>
<p>The complaint then moved to the litigation chamber of the DPA &#8212; and a whole year passed without a decision being issued, in keeping with the glacial pace of privacy enforcement against adtech in the region.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229932" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But the authority is now in the process of finalizing a draft ruling, according to a <a href="https://iabeurope.eu/all-news/update-on-the-belgian-data-protection-authoritys-investigation-of-iab-europe/">press statement</a> put out by the IAB Europe today. And the verdict it&#8217;s expecting is that the TCF breaches the GDPR.</p>
<p>It will also find that the IAB Europe is itself in breach. Oopsy.</p>
<p>The online advertising industry body looks to be seeking to get ahead of a nuclear finding of non-compliance, writing that the DPA &#8220;will apparently identify infringements of the GDPR by IAB Europe,&#8221; and trying to further spin the finding as &#8220;fixable&#8221; within six months (it doesn&#8217;t say how, however) &#8212; while simultaneously implying the breach finding may not itself be fixed because other EU DPAs still need to weigh in on the decision as part of the GDPR&#8217;s standard cooperation procedure (which applies to cross-border complaints).</p>
<p>The preemptive statement (and its Friday afternoon timing) looks very much like the IAB Europe trying to both fuzz and bury bad news and thereby calm the nerves of the tracking industry ahead of looming headlines that a flagship tool is unlawful &#8212; something EU privacy campaigners have of course been saying for literally years.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In terms of timing, a final verdict on the investigation is still likely months off &#8212; and may not emerge &#8217;til deep into 2022. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Appeals are also almost inevitable. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But the tracking industry&#8217;s problems are starting to look, well, appropriately sticky. </span></p>
<p>In the short term, the IAB says it expects a draft ruling to be shared by Belgium with other EU DPAs in the next two to three weeks &#8212; at which point they get 30 days to review it and potentially file objections.</p>
<p>If DPAs don&#8217;t agree with the lead authority&#8217;s finding and can&#8217;t agree among themselves, the European Data Protection Board may need to step in and take a binding decision &#8212; such as happened in another cross-border case against WhatsApp (which led to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/whatsapp-faces-267m-fine-for-breaching-europes-gdpr/">a $267 million fine</a>, a larger penalty that the lead DPA in that case had originally proposed).</p>
<p>So this GDPR cooperation mechanism can spin procedures out for many more months yet.</p>
<p>Complainants against the IAB Europe and its TCF, meanwhile, told us they have not seen nor been given details of the draft ruling by the DPA.</p>
<p>So it looks pretty whiffy that the ad industry body has had sight of an incoming decision ahead of the other parties to the complaint.</p>
<p>But one of complainants, the Irish Council for Civil Liberties&#8217; Johnny Ryan, quickly posted a <a href="https://www.iccl.ie/news/online-consent-pop-ups-used-by-google-and-other-tech-firms-declared-illegal/">press statement</a> of his own, in which he writes: &#8220;We have won. The online advertising industry and its trade body, &#8216;IAB Europe&#8217;, have been found to have deprived hundreds of millions of Europeans of their fundamental rights.</p>
<p>&#8220;IAB Europe designed the misleading &#8216;consent&#8217; pop-ups that feature on almost all (80%+) European websites and apps. That system is known as IAB Europe’s &#8216;Transparency &amp; Consent Framework&#8217; (TCF). These popups purport to give people control over how their data are used by the online advertising industry. But in fact, it does not matter what people click.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Big news. <br />Google and the entire tracking industry relies on IAB Europe’s consent system, which will now be found to be illegal. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TCF?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TCF</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDPR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDPR</a><a href="https://twitter.com/ICCLtweet?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ICCLtweet</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/panoptykon?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@panoptykon</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/bitsoffreedom?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@bitsoffreedom</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Jausl00s?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Jausl00s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/PiDewitte?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PiDewitte</a> <a href="https://t.co/yDWptBhI6V">https://t.co/yDWptBhI6V</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Johnny Ryan (@johnnyryan) <a href="https://twitter.com/johnnyryan/status/1456630527721680902?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The looming finding of unlawfulness comes at an interesting time for the tracking ads industry with moves afoot in the European Parliament to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/inside-a-european-push-to-outlaw-creepy-ads/">push for an outright ban on behavioral advertising</a> to be incorporated into incoming pan-EU regulations for digital services &#8212; in favor of privacy-safe alternatives like contextual advertising.</p>
<p>A finding that the flagship tool used by the tracking industry to claim &#8220;consent&#8221; to behavioral ads isn&#8217;t actually operating lawfully under EU law will surely amplify calls to clean house by outlawing the practice entirely.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hXIZ0cxz0Q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/inside-a-european-push-to-outlaw-creepy-ads/">Inside a European push to outlaw creepy ads</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Inside a European push to outlaw creepy ads&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/inside-a-european-push-to-outlaw-creepy-ads/embed/#?secret=hXIZ0cxz0Q" data-secret="hXIZ0cxz0Q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to the IAB Europe, the draft ruling by the Belgian DPA will find that it is a data controller for TCF “TC Strings,” aka &#8220;the digital signals created on websites to capture data subjects’ choices about the processing of their personal data for digital advertising, content and measurement,&#8221; as it puts it.</p>
<p>(Or &#8212; in Ryan&#8217;s words &#8212; &#8220;the identification code created about a person, based on which apps they use and which websites they visit, and what they click in consent popups.&#8221;)</p>
<p>It will also find the IAB Europe is a &#8220;joint controller&#8221; for TC Strings that are used in OpenRTB (Real-Time Bidding) &#8212; meaning the industry body will have a string of risky new responsibilities attached to the data processing around programatic behavioral advertising (with legal liability aplenty and the risk of big fines if they fail to live up to requirements in the GDPR such as privacy by design and default; consent that&#8217;s specific, informed and freely given; and appropriate security wrapping people&#8217;s data).</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s Ryan again, laying out the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/gdpr-adtech-complaints-keep-stacking-up-in-europe/">parallel case against RTB</a> in brief:</p>
<blockquote><p>For almost four years, websites and apps have plagued Europeans with this &#8220;consent&#8221; spam. But our evidence reveals that IAB Europe knew that conventional tracking-based advertising was “incompatible with consent under GDPR” before it launched the consent system.</p>
<p>This is because the primary tracking-based ad system, called &#8220;Real-Time Bidding&#8221; (RTB), broadcasts internet users’ behaviour and real-world locations to thousands of companies, billions of times a day. RTB is the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/irelands-data-watchdog-slammed-for-letting-adtech-carry-on-biggest-breach-of-all-time/">biggest data breach ever recorded</a>. There is no way to protect data in this free-for-all. (We are <a href="https://www.iccl.ie/rtb-june-2021/">litigating</a> against RTB in Hamburg, too.)</p>
<p>In proceedings initiated by a group of complainants coordinated by the Irish Council for Civil Liberties, the Belgian Data Protection Authority is close to adopting a draft decision that will find IAB Europe’s its &#8220;consent&#8221; pop-up system infringes the GDPR, vindicating our arguments over several years.</p></blockquote>
<p>The IAB Europe&#8217;s spin for trying to eschew responsibility for protecting people&#8217;s data is to try to spread blame elsewhere &#8212; claiming it has not considered itself a data controller &#8220;based on guidance from other DPAs up to now,&#8221; among other excuses.</p>
<p>&#8220;Therefore, it has naturally not fulfilled certain obligations that accrue to data controllers under the Regulation,&#8221; the IAB Europe goes on in studiously avoiding making any kind of apology.</p>
<p>(Here&#8217;s Ryan&#8217;s take again: &#8220;IAB Europe is jointly responsible and liable with thousands of online advertising firms when personal data are broadcast in to the RTB data free-for-all. IAB Europe had tried to deny this.&#8221;)</p>
<p>Instead of apologizing, the IAB Europe directs its energy toward suggesting there will be an easy way to fix the tracking industry&#8217;s lawfulness problem, writing: &#8220;The draft ruling will require IAB Europe to work with the APD to ensure that these obligations are met going forward.&#8221;</p>
<p>Making more market calming noises, it also describes itself as &#8220;optimistic&#8221; that the TCF can be fixed.</p>
<p>But, well, it would say that wouldn&#8217;t it?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IsJ9zIfe2p"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/behavioural-advertising-is-out-of-control-warns-uk-watchdog/">Behavioural advertising is out of control, warns UK watchdog</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Behavioural advertising is out of control, warns UK watchdog&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/behavioural-advertising-is-out-of-control-warns-uk-watchdog/embed/#?secret=IsJ9zIfe2p" data-secret="IsJ9zIfe2p" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The online ad industry body has previously denied there was any case to bring against the TCF or RTB&#8217;s use of people&#8217;s data.</p>
<p>So, well, its record here shouldn&#8217;t inspire confidence.</p>
<p>“Google and the entire tracking industry relies on IAB Europe’s consent system, which will now be found to be illegal,” added Ryan in a statement. “IAB Europe created a fake consent system that spammed everyone, every day, and served no purpose other than to give a thin legal cover to the massive data breach in at the heart of online advertising. We hope the decision of the Belgian Data Protection Authority will finally force the online advertising industry to reform.”</p>
<p>Another complainant in the case, Jef Ausloos, a postdoc researcher in data privacy at the University of Amsterdam, suggests the IAB Europe&#8217;s statement is an attempt to sow doubt among other EU DPAs &#8212; and called its claim that identification codes used for targeted advertising aren&#8217;t personal data &#8220;preposterous.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also described the Belgian finding as &#8220;only the very start of the process as I see it,&#8221; adding: &#8220;We&#8217;ve come a long way already but, regardless, this will still take a while.&#8221;</p>
<p>At the time of writing the Belgian DPA had not responded to our request for confirmation of an impending draft ruling.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the IAB Europe claimed it has &#8220;only been informed about the headline findings of the draft ruling.&#8221; She did not specify how it had obtained the information ahead of the complainants. (<strong>Update:</strong> We asked if the information came from the Belgian DPA and she said &#8220;yes, that&#8217;s correct.&#8221;)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zhd15gr6wG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/">IAB Europe&#8217;s ad tracking consent framework found to fail GDPR standard</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IAB Europe&#8217;s ad tracking consent framework found to fail GDPR standard&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/embed/#?secret=zhd15gr6wG" data-secret="zhd15gr6wG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US government offers $10M bounty for DarkSide ransomware hackers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CISA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colonial pipeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east coast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Bureau of Investigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of State is upping the ante in its fight against ransomware by offering a reward of up to $10 million for information that helps identify or track down leaders of the notorious DarkSide ransomware group. The State Department said it’s also offering as much as $5 million for information that leads to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. Department of State is upping the ante in its fight against <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ransomware/">ransomware</a> by offering a reward of up to $10 million for information that helps identify or track down leaders of the notorious DarkSide ransomware group.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.state.gov/reward-offers-for-information-to-bring-darkside-ransomware-variant-co-conspirators-to-justice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">State Department said</a> it’s also offering as much as $5 million for information that leads to the arrest or conviction of anyone ”conspiring to participate in or attempting to participate in a DarkSide variant ransomware incident.” This is likely a nod to the group’s affiliate program, in which members receive a custom variant of the DarkSide ransomware and receive a chunk of any ransom payment profits.</p>
<p>“In offering this reward, the United States demonstrates its commitment to protecting ransomware victims around the world from exploitation by cybercriminals,” the State Department said. “The United States looks to nations who harbor ransomware criminals that are willing to bring justice for those victim businesses and organizations affected by ransomware.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229968" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2229993" style="width: 706px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229993" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2229993 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg" alt="" width="696" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg 696w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=526,680 526w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229993" class="wp-caption-text">The FBI&#8217;s wanted poster for the DarkSide ransomware group. (<strong>Image Credits:</strong> FBI)</p></div></p>
<p>The State Department says it launched the bounty in the wake of DarkSide’s attack on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/colonial-pipeline/">Colonial Pipeline</a> earlier this year, which led to the shutdown of a 5,500-mile pipeline that carries 45% of the fuel used on the U.S. east coast.</p>
<p>The group went dark shortly after its servers were hacked, and later rebranded as BlackMatter, which went on to attack <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/12/technology-giant-olympus-hit-by-blackmatter-ransomware/">Japanese technology giant Olympus</a> in September and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/cisa-nsa-blackmatter-food-industry/">“multiple” organizations deemed critical infrastructure</a>, including two companies in the U.S. food and agriculture sector. BlackMatter said this week that it was also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/blackmatter-ransomware-shut-down/">ceasing operations</a> due to pressure from law enforcement agencies.</p>
<p>The $10 million reward is being offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which it manages with federal law enforcement partners as part of the government’s effort to disrupt and dismantle international crime syndicates. The State Department noted that it had paid $135 million in rewards since it was created in 1986.</p>
<p>Jake Williams, CTO at BreachQuest, told TechCrunch that the State Department’s bumper reward will cause ripples far beyond DarkSide: “With rewards this large, there’s a substantial incentive for these criminals to turn on one another. Perhaps more importantly than the specific impacts to DarkSide, this action undermines trust across the ransomware as a service affiliate model.</p>
<p>“This is especially good timing since it capitalizes on the recent REvil infiltration by law enforcement. The law enforcement action against REvil in July already caused significant trust issues among operators. This drives that wedge deeper and will extend far beyond DarkSide.”</p>
<p>This is the latest in a long line of efforts by the Biden administration to crack down on the growing ransomware threat. Most recently, the Treasury took steps to crack down on virtual currency exchanges <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/23/us-treasury-sanctions-suex-ransomware/">by sanctioning Suex for its role in facilitating ransomware payments</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HinRtcvjfX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/blackmatter-ransomware-shut-down/">BlackMatter ransomware gang says it&#8217;s shutting down over law enforcement pressure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BlackMatter ransomware gang says it&#8217;s shutting down over law enforcement pressure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/blackmatter-ransomware-shut-down/embed/#?secret=HinRtcvjfX" data-secret="HinRtcvjfX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229968</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
