<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 17:52:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Apple&#8217;s new editorial franchise, Apple Podcasts Spotlight, to highlight interesting creators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/apples-new-editorial-franchise-apple-podcasts-spotlight-to-highlight-interesting-creators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/apples-new-editorial-franchise-apple-podcasts-spotlight-to-highlight-interesting-creators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098099</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple today announced a new editorial franchise called Apple Podcasts Spotlight, which aims to highlight rising podcast creators in the U.S. The editorial team at Apple will select new podcast creators to feature every month and then give them prominent screen real estate in the Apple Podcasts app and promote them across social media and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple today announced a new editorial franchise called Apple Podcasts Spotlight, which aims to highlight rising podcast creators in the U.S. The editorial team at Apple will select new podcast creators to feature every month and then give them prominent screen real estate in the Apple Podcasts app and promote them across social media and elsewhere. This will allow creators to reach a wider audience, similar to how the App Store showcases a selection of recommended apps and games with large banners at the top of its screen.</p>
<p>The first Spotlight creator is Chelsea Devantez, who hosts the podcast Celebrity Book Club. On Fridays, Chelsea and special guests including Emily V. Gordon, Gabourey Sidibe, Ashley Nicole Black and Lydia Popovich will meet to discuss the memoirs of &#8220;badass celebrity womxn,&#8221; as an <a href="https://medium.com/stitcher-blog/apple-podcasts-names-chelsea-devantez-of-stitchers-celebrity-book-club-as-its-first-ever-e33a21a34fcf">announcement</a> describes it.</p>
<p>The idea for the show began a year ago when Devantez was reading Jessica Simpson&#8217;s memoir and started recapping it on Instagram. The reaction from her followers prompted her to expand the concept into a podcast.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Upcoming episodes will feature Oscar-nominated writer and producer Emily V. Gordon talking Drew Barrymore’s &#8220;Little Girl Lost;&#8221; actress Stephanie Beatriz discussing Celine Dion’s memoir &#8220;My Story My Dream;&#8221; Leighton Meester on Carly Simon’s &#8220;Boys in the Trees;&#8221; and a special Valentine’s Day episode where Chelsea and TikTok star Rob Anderson read Burt Reynolds’ and Loni Anderson’s competing divorce memoirs.</p>
<p>&#8220;Apple Podcasts Spotlight helps listeners find some of the world’s best shows by shining a light on creators with singular voices,&#8221; said Ben Cave, Global Head of Business for Apple Podcasts, in a statement about the launch. &#8220;Chelsea Devantez has created a fun, vibrant space with Celebrity Book Club for listeners to gain new perspectives on the celebrities we thought we knew. We are delighted to recognize Chelsea and Celebrity Book Club as our first Spotlight selection and look forward to introducing creators like Chelsea to listeners each month,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Apple says future Spotlight creators will be announced monthly from across a range of podcast genres, formats and locations, and will often focus on independent and underrepresented voices. The content is previewed ahead of selection to ensure quality, but there are no specific requirements about the podcast size and reach.</p>
<p>In general, the new Spotlight creators will debut toward the front of the week, but the specific days are fluid to adapt to holidays, major cultural events, and others. The next Spotlight selection, for example, will launch in mid-February.</p>
<p>The Spotlight creators will be featured at the top of the Browse tab of Apple Podcasts and will be promoted through the Apple Podcasts social media accounts. Some form of in-app featuring will continue throughout the entire month the creators are in the &#8220;spotlight.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apple says it will also collaborate with the featured creators on their own channels. And, over time, you&#8217;ll see promotion via additional Apple-operated channels including outdoor advertising in major U.S. metros.</p>
<p>The news of the new editorial program comes shortly after <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/apple-plans-podcasting-subscription-service-in-threat-to-spotify">a report from The Information</a> suggested Apple is working to expand its podcasts platform with the introduction of a podcast subscription service, threatening rivals like Spotify, SiriusXM and Amazon.</p>
<p>Though Apple Podcasts still leads the market, <a href="https://podnews.net/article/spotify-bigger-than-apple">Spotify has been catching up</a> by <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-10/spotify-agrees-to-buy-podcast-ad-tech-company-for-235-million">spending</a> over $800 million on podcast companies, like Anchor, the Ringer, Gimlet Media, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/spotify-buying-podcast-hosting-and-ad-company-megaphone-for-235m/">more recently,</a> podcast ad company Megaphone.</p>
<p>SiriusXM, meanwhile, bought podcast management and analytics platform Simplecast, ad tech platform AdsWizz, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/spotify-buying-podcast-hosting-and-ad-company-megaphone-for-235m/">and podcast app Stitcher</a>. Not to be left out, Amazon just a few weeks ago <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/amazon-acquires-podcast-network-wondery/">announced it was acquiring</a> the podcast network Wondery.</p>
<p>Beyond helping the creators grow their audience, Apple says the larger goal with the program is to welcome new audiences to podcasts, in general.</p>
<p>Though podcasts are growing in popularity, the <a href="https://www.edisonresearch.com/the-infinite-dial-2020/">monthly podcast listener base is just 37%</a> in the U.S., according to Edison Research. That means it&#8217;s nowhere near being an activity that&#8217;s popular among a majority of the U.S. population at this time. Before Apple can effectively monetize podcasts as a subscription service, it needs to help get more people listening to podcasts on a regular basis.</p>
<p>Apple declined to say if the program would expand outside the U.S. at a later date.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/apples-new-editorial-franchise-apple-podcasts-spotlight-to-highlight-interesting-creators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098099</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We’ll discuss the future of the gig economy and contract works at TC Sessions: Justice on March 3</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/well-discuss-the-future-of-the-gig-economy-and-contract-works-at-tc-sessions-justice-on-march-3/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/well-discuss-the-future-of-the-gig-economy-and-contract-works-at-tc-sessions-justice-on-march-3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prop 22]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Sessions: Justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2089841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like so many other subjects, the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic has brought concerns about the gig economy and contract workers into sharp focus over the past year which is why we&#8217;ll be diving into this topic at TC Sessions: Justice on March 3. From food delivery services like Seamless to warehouse and fulfillment jobs at places [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Like so many other subjects, the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic has brought concerns about the gig economy and contract workers into sharp focus over the past year which is why we&#8217;ll be diving into this topic at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TC Sessions: Justice on March 3</a>.</p>
<p>From food delivery services like Seamless to warehouse and fulfillment jobs at places like Amazon, these often low-paid jobs have kept people supplied with essentials during one of the most difficult moments in modern American history.</p>
<p>But why is it that jobs our society has labeled “essential” often carry the least number of protections for those who fulfill them? Is there a way to ensure a safety net for the people who need it the most?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As the pandemic continued to rage, California passed Proposition 22. The law was regarded as a big win for companies like Uber and Lyft (who pumped a collective $200 million into promotions) and a tremendous step back for workers looking for basic employment rights. But the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/">battle between the Prop 22 proponents and the gig workers who oppose it continues</a>. A group of rideshare drivers in California and the Service Employees International Union have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/gig-workers-seiu-file-lawsuit-alleging-prop-22-is-unconstitutional/">filed a lawsuit</a> alleging Proposition 22 violates California’s constitution.</p>
<p>To discuss the gig worker economy and its future in a post-Prop 22 world, we will be joined by Jessica E. Martinez, the co-executive director of the <a href="https://www.coshnetwork.org/">National Council for Occupational Safety and Health</a>, an organization devoted to promoting health and safety conditions for workplaces; Vanessa Bain, a gig worker activist who <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/10/gig-workers-collective/">co-founded</a> the <a href="https://www.gigworkerscollective.org/home">Gig Workers Collective</a>; and Christian Smalls, a former Amazon worker turned activist.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">TC Sessions: Justice</a> will be held online on March 3. G<a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/">et your tickets today!</a></p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			width="99%"
			height="500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/well-discuss-the-future-of-the-gig-economy-and-contract-works-at-tc-sessions-justice-on-march-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2089841</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wendy Xiao Schadeck becomes Northzone&#8217;s first New York partner</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/northzone-promotes-wendy-xiao-schadeck/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/northzone-promotes-wendy-xiao-schadeck/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northzone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring Health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Northzone&#8216;s new partner Wendy Xiao Schadeck isn&#8217;t new to the firm — she actually joined back in 2015. Before entering the venture world, Schadeck co-founded co-working and childcare startup CoHatchery. And as a Northzone principal, she&#8217;s already been involved in the firm&#8217;s investments in Spring Health (mental health), 3box (cloud infrastructure), Livepeer (blockchain-based video transcoding) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://northzone.com">Northzone</a>&#8216;s new partner Wendy Xiao Schadeck isn&#8217;t new to the firm — she actually joined back in 2015.</p>
<p>Before entering the venture world, Schadeck co-founded co-working and childcare startup <a href="http://www.cohatchery.com">CoHatchery</a>. And as a Northzone principal, she&#8217;s already been involved in the firm&#8217;s investments in <a href="https://www.springhealth.com">Spring Health</a> (mental health), <a href="https://3box.io">3box</a> (cloud infrastructure), <a href="https://livepeer.org">Livepeer</a> (blockchain-based video transcoding) and <a href="https://magic.link">Magic.link</a> (user authentication).</p>
<p>More broadly, Northzone says Schadeck helped to develop the firm&#8217;s investment theses around crypto, consumer technology, health, developer/web 3.0 infrastructure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Wendy has already proven herself through very insightful sector-driven thought leadership and has solidified our position in the New York ecosystem,&#8221; said General Partner Pär-Jörgen Pärson in a statement. &#8220;She has defined and redefined an honest, authentic and inspiring dialogue between herself as an investor and the entrepreneurs she supports.”</p>
<p>Schadeck told me that her interests have &#8220;crystallized&#8221; around three key areas — &#8220;open data, open finance and open community.&#8221; And she said that with her promotion to partner, she will be able to work even more closely with founders, a topic she&#8217;s become &#8220;obsessed&#8221; with.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve all seen this VC meme, <a href="https://medium.com/swlh/how-can-i-be-helpful-really-86fc98c0d1a3">&#8216;How can I be helpful?&#8217;</a> and I&#8217;ve sometimes accidentally literally said it,&#8221; Schadeck said. &#8220;But we mean it: Other than providing capital, first and foremost, on good terms, what other dimensions are there that are becoming more and more important? &#8230; How can I customize my approach to provide what the founder needs from me?&#8221;</p>
<p>While Schadeck is Northzone&#8217;s first New York-based partner (its other partners are in London and Stockholm), she said she will make investments outside the region, albeit with an NYC focus.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve tried to do this matrix approach, where we both have sectors that we’re pretty excited about and build expertise and experience in, as well as relationships&#8221; she said. &#8220;And those relationships are better with local entrepreneurs.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GXD128U9Z9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/northzone-raises-new-500m-fund/">Northzone raises new $500M fund to back startups in Europe (and the East Coast, US)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Northzone raises new $500M fund to back startups in Europe (and the East Coast, US)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/northzone-raises-new-500m-fund/embed/#?secret=GXD128U9Z9" data-secret="GXD128U9Z9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/northzone-promotes-wendy-xiao-schadeck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098090</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paramount+, the successor to CBS All Access, launches March 4 in the U.S., Canada, and Latin America</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/paramount-the-successor-to-cbs-all-access-launches-march-4-in-the-u-s-canada-and-latin-america/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/paramount-the-successor-to-cbs-all-access-launches-march-4-in-the-u-s-canada-and-latin-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBS All Access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viacom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ViacomCBS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, ViacomCBS announced its CBS All Access streaming service would soon rebrand as Paramount+, to better reflect the expanded content lineup following the Viacom-CBS merger in 2019. Today, the company says it has set a launch date for Paramount+ in the U.S.: March 4, 2021. It&#8217;s also sharing the launch dates for other international [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year, ViacomCBS <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/cbs-all-access-to-rebrand-to-paramount-expand-internationally-in-2021/">announced</a> its CBS All Access streaming service would soon rebrand as Paramount+, to better reflect the expanded content lineup following the Viacom-CBS merger in 2019. Today, the company says it has set a launch date for Paramount+ in the U.S.: March 4, 2021. It&#8217;s also sharing the launch dates for other international markets, including Latin America, Canada and the Nordics.</p>
<p>The service will debut on March 4 in Latin American markets, and will rebrand from CBS All Access to Paramount+ in Canada at the same time. However, Canada won&#8217;t receive the expanded lineup until later in 2021. The Nordics region will see the service arrive on March 25, 2021, which is followed by a launch in Australia in &#8220;mid-2021.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company had been touting its plans for the rebranded service <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/a-rebranded-and-updated-version-of-cbs-all-access-will-launch-this-summer/">since earlier last year</a>, explaining how the new streaming offering, an expansion of CBS All Access,  would allow it to showcase the company&#8217;s biggest franchises and its deep library, while also offering a home to its growing collection of original content, like the multiple &#8220;Star Trek&#8221; series now streaming on CBS All Access and &#8220;The Good Wife&#8221; spin-off, &#8220;The Good Fight,&#8221; among others.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The service will also continue to stream sports, like NFL games and those from other leagues, like the NCAA and PGA, and live stream news from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/08/01/cbs-adds-247-news-from-cbsn-to-its-standalone-streaming-service-cbs-all-access/">CBSN</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/01/cbs-launches-local-news-streaming-services/">local stations</a>.</p>
<p>Last year, ViacomCBS additionally <a href="https://fortune.com/2020/06/30/youtube-tv-price-hike-viacom-cbs-channels/">announced</a> other originals it had planned for the new service, including “The Offer,” a scripted limited series about the making of “The Godfather;” CIA spy drama “Lioness,” created by Taylor Sheridan; a reimagined version of MTV’s “Behind the Music,” which will focus on the past 40 years; a true crime docu-series, “The Real Criminal Minds,” based on the fictional TV hit; and a revival of BET’s “The Game.”</p>
<p>There will be expanded children&#8217;s programming, too, including a new kids original series “Kamp Koral,” from Nickelodeon’s &#8220;Spongebob Squarepants.&#8221; And it it will be the subscription video on demand home for the &#8220;The Spongebob Movie: Sponge on the Run.”</p>
<p>CBS All Access had <a href="https://deadline.com/2020/07/cbs-all-access-adds-tranche-of-mtv-bet-comedy-central-episodes-in-expansion-ahead-of-2021-rebrand-1202998712/">already been expanding</a> its lineup ahead of the full rebrand, with the goal of reaching more than 30,000 episodes and movies, by incorporating content from ViacomCBS-owned brands like BET, CBS, Comedy Central, MTV, Nickelodeon, and Paramount Pictures.</p>
<p>Despite its plans to make Paramount+ a standalone destination, ViacomCBS has been licensing its content to other streamers, as well. During its first full year as a newly combined company in 2020, ViacomCBS made carriage deals with Comcast, Dish, Verizon (TechCrunch’s parent), Nextstar, Meredith, Cox and Sinclair, and hashed out agreements with YouTube TV and Hulu for incremental revenues. Both <a href="https://fortune.com/2020/06/30/youtube-tv-price-hike-viacom-cbs-channels/">YouTube TV</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/hulus-live-tv-service-gains-14-new-channels-as-result-of-viacomcbs-deal/">Hulu</a> added over a half dozen ViacomCBS-owned channels to their respective lineups and hiked prices, as a result.</p>
<p>Because Paramount+ is built on CBS All Access&#8217; existing tech platform, it will have the same distribution across platforms (TV, web, and mobile) as its predecessor from day one.</p>
<p>Today, CBS All Access is <a href="https://digiday.com/future-of-tv/change-the-channel-how-viacomcbs-is-managing-the-transition-from-linear-tv-to-streaming/">estimated</a> to have around 8 million subscribers, which makes it far smaller than other newer rivals like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/disney-73-million-subscribers/">Disney+</a> (73M+) and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/08/att-has-added-4-million-hbo-max-subscribers-since-sept-30.html">HBO Max</a> (12.6M &#8220;activated users&#8221;).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/paramount-the-successor-to-cbs-all-access-launches-march-4-in-the-u-s-canada-and-latin-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rivian raises $2.65B as it pushes towards production of its electric pickup</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/rivian-raises-2-65-billion-in-new-capital-as-it-pushes-towards-production-of-its-electric-pickup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/rivian-raises-2-65-billion-in-new-capital-as-it-pushes-towards-production-of-its-electric-pickup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t.rowe price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rivian has raised $2.65 billion as it prepares to begin production this summer of its all-electric pickup truck. The round, which was led by funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates Inc., also included Fidelity Management and Research Company, Amazon’s Climate Pledge Fund, Coatue and D1 Capital Partners as well as several other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rivian has raised $2.65 billion as it prepares to begin production this summer of its all-electric pickup truck.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The round, which was led by funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates Inc., also included Fidelity Management and Research Company, Amazon’s Climate Pledge Fund, Coatue and D1 Capital Partners as well as several other existing and new investors.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Rivian is now valued at $27.6 billion, according to a person familiar with the investment round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The capital comes at a critical time for Rivian, which is undertaking the design, development, production and delivery of two consumer vehicles — the R1T pickup truck the R1S SUV — build out of its electric vehicle charging network as well as fulfilling an order for 100,000 commercial delivery vans for Amazon.</p>
<p>&#8220;The support and confidence of our investors enables us to remain focused on these launches while simultaneously scaling our business for our next stage of growth,” Rivian founder and CEO RJ Scaringe said in a statement.</p>
<p>This latest round follows two years of heavy investment activity that began in earnest after the company unveiled its electric SUV and pickup truck at the 2018 LA Auto Show.</p>
<p>Just months after that reveal, Rivian announced a $700 million funding round <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/15/amazon-leads-700m-round-in-electric-automaker-rivian/">led by Amazon</a>. More deals and investments would follow, including a $500 million investment from Ford — along with a promise to collaborate on a future EV program — and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/10/rivian-lands-350-million-investment-from-cox-automotive/">$350 million investment</a> by Cox Automotive in September 2019. The company closed the year with an announcement that it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/23/rivian-adds-1-3-billion-in-funding-for-its-electric-utility-and-adventure-vehicles/">raised a $1.3 billion round</a> led by funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates, Inc. with additional participation from Amazon, Ford Motor Company and funds managed by BlackRock.</p>
<p>The stream of capital didn&#8217;t stop in 2020. Rivian announced in July it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/10/rivian-raises-massive-2-5-billion-as-it-pushes-to-bring-its-electric-pickup-suv-to-market/">raised $2.5 billion</a> in a round led by funds and accounts advised by T. Rowe Price Associates Inc. New investors Soros Fund Management LLC, Coatue, Fidelity Management and Research Company and Baron Capital Group along with existing shareholders Amazon and BlackRock joined the round.</p>
<p>To date, Rivian has raised $8 billion since the start of 2019.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2098084" style="width: 3718px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2098084" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2098084 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg" alt="Rivian factor Normal Illinois" width="3708" height="2649" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg 3708w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg?resize=768,549 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg?resize=680,486 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg?resize=1536,1097 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg?resize=2048,1463 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/rivian-2019_03_normal.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3708px) 100vw, 3708px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2098084" class="wp-caption-text">Rivian&#8217;s factory in Normal, Illinois.</p></div></p>
<p>Rivian hasn&#8217;t held back on spending that capital. The company has put more than $1 billion into its factory in Normal, Illinois. The factory, which once produced the Mitsubishi Eclipse through a joint venture between Mitsubishi and Chrysler Corporation, has been completely updated and expanded.</p>
<p>The overhaul of the 3 million-square-foot is on schedule, but not yet complete, according to the company. A pilot line is operational and is producing validation prototypes of its R1T pickup truck daily.</p>
<p>Rivian also plans to produce the delivery vans for Amazon at the factory. The first van deliveries will be made to Amazon in late 2021.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m3LU51VSd0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/rivian-is-building-its-own-ev-charging-network-but-with-an-adventurous-twist/">Rivian is building its own EV charging network, but with an adventurous twist</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rivian is building its own EV charging network, but with an adventurous twist&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/rivian-is-building-its-own-ev-charging-network-but-with-an-adventurous-twist/embed/#?secret=m3LU51VSd0" data-secret="m3LU51VSd0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/rivian-raises-2-65-billion-in-new-capital-as-it-pushes-towards-production-of-its-electric-pickup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098058</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In 2020, VCs invested $428M into US-based startups every day</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/in-2020-vcs-invested-428m-into-us-based-startups-every-day/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/in-2020-vcs-invested-428m-into-us-based-startups-every-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitchbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture captial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite a pandemic that sparked a global recession, 2020 was still a record year for venture capital investments into American startups.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Despite a pandemic that sparked a global recession, 2020 was still a record year for venture capital investments into American startups.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/reports/q4-2020-pitchbook-nvca-venture-monitor">data shared</a> by PitchBook and the National Venture Capital Association, investors poured $156.2 billion into domestic startups last year, or around $428 million for each day of the year. The huge sum of money, however, was itself dwarfed by the amount of liquidity that American startups generated, some $290.1 billion.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>The exit-value figure was a record as well, as were the 321 rounds worth $100 million — nearly one for each day of the year.</p>
<p>But while the U.S. venture capital market in 2020 was hot, it was not newly so. In 2018 and 2019, VCs invested around $140 billion into domestic startups, making last year&#8217;s $156 billion result a record, but not a shocking departure from previous years.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995210 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-blu.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>A first read of the data indicates that the U.S. venture capital market is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/fintech-vc-keeps-getting-later-larger-and-more-expensive/">still getting larger in scale and later-stage in focus</a>. But inside those well-worn trends are a host of notable movements that both underscore <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/extension-rounds-help-some-startups-play-offense-during-covid-19/">what we observed last year in real time</a>, and teach us something new about today&#8217;s venture capital market.</p>
<p>So far, 2021&#8217;s startup financing and exit market appears to be the mirror of what we saw in late 2020. So we&#8217;d best understand the past so we can forecast what we&#8217;ll see in Q1 of 2021.</p>
<p>To avoid getting too lost in the data, we&#8217;ll proceed by stage, pulling out key facts for each step of the startup lifecycle. Feel free to scroll to the one that makes the most sense for where your company is, or fund invests today.</p>
<h2>Seed</h2>
<p>In the U.S., seed deal count was high in 2020, around 5,227 per PitchBook&#8217;s estimates. Those rounds were worth just over $10 billion, making it the third year in a row in which American seed-stage startups managed around $10 billion in capital against around 5,000 rounds.</p>
<p>Boring, yeah? Not really. Inside those numbers are the whole year&#8217;s ups-and-downs: the fact that the seed data is so close to 2018 and 2019 levels is almost silly.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2098054 size-large alignright" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-9.40.21-AM.png?w=381" alt="" width="381" height="324" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-9.40.21-AM.png 381w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-9.40.21-AM.png?resize=150,128 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-9.40.21-AM.png?resize=300,255 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-9.40.21-AM.png?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 381px) 100vw, 381px" /></p>
<p>The real surprise from seed, per PitchBook&#8217;s report, is that these valuations actually fell on a year-over-year basis in 2020. This, despite the fact that seed deal sizes rose.</p>
<p>Considering these two trends at once, it appears likely that, on average, VC ownership as a percentage of seed-stage companies rose in 2020.</p>
<p>Frankly I was just surprised to see a form of startup valuation decrease after expanding for nearly a decade.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/in-2020-vcs-invested-428m-into-us-based-startups-every-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098040</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Citrix is acquiring Wrike from Vista for $2.25B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/citrix-is-acquiring-wrike-from-vista-for-2-25b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/citrix-is-acquiring-wrike-from-vista-for-2-25b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citrix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[project management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vista equity partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wrike]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Citrix announced today that it plans to acquire Wrike, a SaaS project management platform, from Vista Equity Partners for $2.25 billion. Vista bought the company just two years ago. Citrix, which is best known for its digital workspaces, sees this as a good match, especially at a time where employees have been forced to work [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://citrix.com">Citrix</a> announced today that it plans to acquire <a href="http://wrike.com">Wrike</a>, a SaaS project management platform, from Vista Equity Partners for $2.25 billion. Vista bought the company just two years ago.</p>
<p>Citrix, which is best known for its digital workspaces, sees this as a good match, especially at a time where employees have been forced to work from home because of the pandemic. By combining the two companies, it produces a powerful combination, one that didn&#8217;t escape Citrix CEO and president David Henshall</p>
<p>&#8220;Together, Citrix and Wrike will deliver the solutions needed to power a cloud-delivered digital workspace experience that enables teams to securely access the resources and tools they need to collaborate and get work done in the most efficient and effective way possible across any channel, device or location,&#8221; Henshall said in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Andrew Filev, founder and CEO at Wrike, who has managed the company through these multiple changes and remains at the helm, believes his company has landed in a good spot with the Citrix purchase.</p>
<p>&#8220;First, as part of the Citrix family we will be able to scale our product and accelerate our roadmap to deliver capabilities that will help our customers get more from their Wrike investment. We have always listened to our customers and have built our product based on their feedback &#8212; now we will be able to do more of that, faster.,&#8221; Filev wrote in <a href="https://www.wrike.com/blog/citrix-agrees-to-acquire-wrike/">a company blog post</a> announcing the deal, stating a typical argument from CEOs of acquired companies.</p>
<p>The startup reports $140 million ARR, growing at 30% annually, so that comes out to approximately 16x its present-day revenue, which is the price companies are generally paying for acquisitions these days. However, as Wrike expects to reach $180 million to $190 million in ARR this year, the company&#8217;s sale price could look like a bargain in a few years&#8217; time if the projections come to pass.</p>
<p>The price was not revealed in the 2018 sale, but it surely feels like a big win for Vista. Consider that Wrike has previously raised just $26 million.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OOcq5ulRhx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/wrike-launches-new-ai-tools-to-keep-your-projects-on-track/">Wrike launches new AI tools to keep your projects on track</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wrike launches new AI tools to keep your projects on track&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/wrike-launches-new-ai-tools-to-keep-your-projects-on-track/embed/#?secret=OOcq5ulRhx" data-secret="OOcq5ulRhx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/citrix-is-acquiring-wrike-from-vista-for-2-25b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098078</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WeChat advances e-commerce goals with $250B in transactions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/wechat-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/wechat-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dingtalk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messaging apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinduoduo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sogou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeChat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WeChat continues to advance its shopping ambitions as the social networking app turns 10 years old. The Chinese messenger facilitated 1.6 trillion yuan (close to $250 billion) in annual transactions through its &#8220;mini programs,&#8221; third-party services that run on the super app that allow users to buy clothes, order food, hail taxis and more. That [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">WeChat continues to advance its shopping ambitions as the social networking app turns 10 years old. The Chinese messenger facilitated 1.6 trillion yuan (close to $250 billion) in annual transactions through its &#8220;mini programs,&#8221; third-party services that run on the super app that allow users to buy clothes, order food, hail taxis and more.</p>
<p>That is double the value of transactions on WeChat&#8217;s mini programs in 2019, the networking giant announced at its annual conference for business partners and ecosystem developers, which normally takes place in its home city of Guangzhou in southern China but was moved online this year due to the pandemic.</p>
<p>To compare, e-commerce upstart Pinduoduo, Alibaba&#8217;s archrival, saw total transactions of <a href="https://investor.pinduoduo.com/static-files/0d0c22e7-188a-4a4f-9692-a1c0c452c474">$214.7 billion</a> in the third quarter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>WeChat introduced mini programs in early 2017 in a move some saw as a challenge to Apple&#8217;s App Store and has over time shaped the messenger into an online infrastructure that keeps people&#8217;s life running. It hasn&#8217;t recently disclosed how many third-party lite apps it houses, but by 2018 the number <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/07/wechat-mini-apps-200-million-users/">reached one million</a>, half the size of the App Store at the time.</p>
<p>From Tencent&#8217;s strategic perspective, the growth in mini program-based transactions helps further the company&#8217;s goal to strengthen its fintech business, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/tencent-vs-alibaba-ant-fintech/">counts digital payments</a> as a major revenue driver.</p>
<p>A big proportion of WeChat&#8217;s mini programs are games, which the app said exceeded 500 million monthly users thanks to a boost in female and middle-aged users, as well as players residing in China&#8217;s Tier 3 cities, WeChat said.</p>
<p>The virtual conference also unveiled a set of other milestones from China&#8217;s biggest messaging app, which surpassed 1.2 billion monthly active users last year.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2097985" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="926" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png 1596w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png?resize=300,271 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png?resize=768,695 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png?resize=680,615 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png?resize=1536,1390 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-19-at-8.35.13-PM.png?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />Among its monthly users, 500 million have tried the WeChat Search function. The Chinese internet is carved into several walled gardens controlled by titans like Tencent, Alibaba and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/10/baidu-electric-car-making/">ByteDance</a>, which often block competitors from their services. When users search on WeChat, they are in effect retrieving information published on the messenger as well as Tencent&#8217;s allies like Sogou, Pinduoduo and Zhihu, rather than the open web.</p>
<p>WeChat said 240 million people have used its &#8220;payments score.&#8221; When the feature debuted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/14/wechat-credit-scoring/">back in 2019</a>, there was speculation that it signaled WeChat&#8217;s entry into consumer credit finance and participation in the government&#8217;s <a href="https://www.chinalawtranslate.com/en/tag/social-credit-system/">social credit system</a>. WeChat reiterated at this year&#8217;s event that the WeChat score does neither of that.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ChinaLawTransl8/status/1042040375060250624">Like Ant&#8217;s Sesame Score</a>, the rating system works more like a royalty program, &#8220;designed to build trust between merchants and users.&#8221; For instance, people who reach a certain score can waive deposits or delay payments when using merchant services on WeChat. The score, WeChat said, helped users save more than $30 billion in deposits a year.</p>
<p>WeChat&#8217;s enterprise version has surpassed 130 million active users. Its biggest rival, Dingtalk, operated by Alibaba, <a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/en/news/press_pdf/p200522.pdf">reached 155 million</a> daily active users last March.</p>
<p>The one-day event concluded with the much-anticipated appearance of Allen Zhang, WeChat&#8217;s creator. Zhang went to great lengths to talk about WeChat&#8217;s nascent short-video feature, which is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/24/wechat-adds-snap-like-stories/">somewhat similar to Snap&#8217;s Stories</a>. He didn&#8217;t disclose the performance of short videos because &#8220;the PR team doesn&#8217;t allow&#8221; him to, but said that &#8220;if we set a goal for ourselves, we will have to achieve it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zhang also announced the WeChat team is weighing up an input tool for users. It&#8217;d be a tiny project given Tencent&#8217;s colossal size, but the project reflects Zhang&#8217;s belief in &#8220;privacy protection,&#8221; despite public skepticism about how WeChat handles user data.</p>
<p>&#8220;If we analyze [users&#8217; chat history], we can bring great advertising revenue to the company. But we don&#8217;t do that, so WeChat cares a lot about user privacy,&#8221; asserted Zhang.</p>
<p>&#8220;But why do you still get ads [related to] what you have just said on WeChat? There are many other channels that process your information, not just WeChat. From there, our technical team said, &#8216;Why don&#8217;t we create an input tool ourselves?'&#8221;</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/wechat-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097982</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Tuesday: Everyone&#8217;s raising money, and Wrike exits yet again</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/equity-tuesday-everyones-raising-money-and-wrike-exits-yet-again/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/equity-tuesday-everyones-raising-money-and-wrike-exits-yet-again/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Auto1 Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Darwinbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LeoCare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wrike]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday Tuesday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/7844e32b-2c55-4585-88c1-1dc021b306d4?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity <del>Monday</del> Tuesday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and myself <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a> — and make sure to check out last week&#8217;s two episodes, covering <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/the-end-of-plaid-visa-and-palantirs-growing-startup-mafia/">all the news sans ecommerce</a>, and then <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/16/checkout-wants-to-be-rapyd-and-fast/">all the ecommerce news</a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re here on a Tuesday due to an American holiday, but that short break did not mean that the world&#8217;s news volume slowed down in the slightest. Here&#8217;s the rundown:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>From the weekend:</strong> The story of a fired GitHub employee <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/17/22235913/github-significant-mistakes-were-made-firing-jewish-employee-nazis?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4">ended as you expected it would</a>, with a small twist; the Microsoft company&#8217;s head of HR is leaving. Not sure from this remove is this is a firing, or merely finding someone to axe over the error, but the fact that they are leaving stood out.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-18/sequoia-said-to-invest-in-auto1-at-7-2-billion-value-before-ipo?sref=gni836kR">Auto1 Group is going public</a>, and Sequoia wants a piece.</li>
<li>In more news from German, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/personio-raises-125m-on-a-1-7b-valuation-for-an-hr-platform-targeting-smes/">Personio has put together a $125 million round at a $1.7 billion valuation</a>.</li>
<li>And Grab, the Southeast Asian food delivery and ride-hailing goliath <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/idUSKBN29N0AM">could raise $2 billion in a 2021 US IPO</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Turning to this morning:</strong> The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/india-asks-whatsapp-to-withdraw-new-privacy-policy-expresses-grave-concerns/">WhatsApp-India saga continues</a>, Citrix is <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/01/19/citrix-acquires-project-management-platform-wrike-for-2-25-billion/">buying Wrike for $2.25 billion</a>, and American stocks are looking up this morning.</li>
<li><strong>On the funding round front: LeoCare </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/leocare-raises-18-1-million-for-its-insurance-products-designed-to-fit-in-a-mobile-app/">raised €15 million</a> from Felix Capital, Ventech and Daphni. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/ppro-nabs-180m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-bring-together-the-fragmented-world-of-payments/">PPRO raised $180 million at a valuation of more than $1 billion</a>. And <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/salesforce-leads-15-million-investment-round-in-indian-hr-tech-platform-darwinbox/">Darwinbox raised from Salesforce Ventures</a>, something that we did not know that the American corporate VC did.</li>
<li>Finally, <a href="https://crypto-anonymous-2021.medium.com/the-bit-short-inside-cryptos-doomsday-machine-f8dcf78a64d3">read this crypto piece</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that&#8217;s that for today, we are back in short order on Thursday afternoon!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content"><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/equity-tuesday-everyones-raising-money-and-wrike-exits-yet-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098010</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech startup Vise brings on Andrew Fong (formerly Dropbox) as CTO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/fintech-startup-vise-brings-on-andrew-fong-formerly-dropbox-as-cto/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/fintech-startup-vise-brings-on-andrew-fong-formerly-dropbox-as-cto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dropbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vise, a fintech firm that focuses on helping financial advisors rather than automating them out of existence, has today announced that its bringing on Andrew Fong as its Chief Technology Officer. Fong hails from Dropbox, where he served as VP of Infrastructure Engineering. He actually started out as a Site Reliability Engineer at Dropbox back [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://vise.com/">Vise</a>, a fintech firm that focuses on helping financial advisors rather than automating them out of existence, has today announced that its bringing on Andrew Fong as its Chief Technology Officer.</p>
<p>Fong hails from Dropbox, where he served as VP of Infrastructure Engineering. He actually started out as a Site Reliability Engineer at Dropbox back in 2012 climbing the ranks to Engineering Director, and then Senior Director of Engineering &#8211; Head of Infrastructure before becoming to vice president.</p>
<p>Before Dropbox, Fong was an engineer at YouTube and Aol.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Vise brought on Fong to scale up its technical team following its most recent fundraise, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/12/trillions-are-at-stake-in-the-retirement-wars-and-vise-nets-14-5m-from-sequoia-to-manage-it/">$45 million in Series B</a> led by Sequoia Capital. In total, Vise has raised $63 million since launching on the TC Disrupt stage in 2019.</p>
<p>You can check out the video of their demo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/03/meet-vise-ai-the-startup-reimagining-portfolio-management/">here</a>.</p>
<p>Vise uses AI to support financial advisors in their relationships with clients, giving them the ability to justify and explain (with data) the reason for making this or that investment, as well as the ability to customize a portfolio quickly.</p>
<p>Top of mind for Fong is scaling up the engineering department from 20 people to 75 by the end of the year, and Fong explained that diversity, equity and inclusion must be front and center in that endeavor.</p>
<p>&#8220;Vise is in the early stages of building out its engineering organization,&#8221; Fong told TechCrunch. &#8220;It&#8217;s imperative that we weave in DEI as a first principle to our recruiting at this stage and ensure we are maturing our processes with DEI in mind.&#8221;</p>
<p>At Dropbox, Fong started out as a team leader building a team of 40 and by the time he left, led a team of more than 250 people. He explained that he learned a lot during that 8+ year period, and made a lot of mistakes, and was eager to see how that knowledge could be reapplied at a different firm.</p>
<p>&#8220;What would it be like to do this again with the knowledge I have now?&#8221; asked Fong. &#8220;What things would I do differently? How would I improve upon it? How can I actually take that knowledge and leverage it in a way that helps others in the industry or my peers at Vise? Can I provide a perspective that they don&#8217;t necessarily have today?&#8221;</p>
<p>Fong was first connected with Vise while he was still at Dropbox. He spoke to Vise cofounder Runik Mehrotra on an explanatory call, and remembers feeling like no matter where his path took him, he wanted to stay connected to Mehrotra and Vise.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is somebody that just has something about him,&#8221; he said of Mehrotra. &#8220;There&#8217;s just like an &#8216;it&#8217; factor that made me feel like I wanted to work with him.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fong says that recruiting during COVID, with extremely limited face-to-face contact, is one of the biggest challenges ahead for both himself and Vise in general.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/fintech-startup-vise-brings-on-andrew-fong-formerly-dropbox-as-cto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097992</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senator: &#8216;More transparency is needed&#8217; by exam proctoring tech firms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/senator-more-transparency-is-needed-by-exam-proctoring-tech-firms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/senator-more-transparency-is-needed-by-exam-proctoring-tech-firms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[higher education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet speeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard blumenthal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webcam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three of the leading exam proctoring companies are facing calls to be more transparent, amid continued claims of bias by students forced to take remote exams because of the ongoing pandemic. Exam proctoring tech lets students take remotely invigilated tests from home. Students are told to install their university’s choice of proctoring software, which allows [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Three of the leading exam proctoring companies are facing calls to be more transparent, amid continued claims of bias by students forced to take remote exams because of the ongoing pandemic.</p>
<p>Exam proctoring tech lets students take remotely invigilated tests from home. Students are told to install their university’s choice of proctoring software, which allows the exam monitor deep access to the student’s computer, including their webcams and microphones, to monitor their activity to spot potential cheating.</p>
<p>But companies like Proctorio, ExamSoft, and ProctorU have faced a barrage of criticism from students who say that their proctoring technology is fraught with problems, including issues of bias — all of which could impact their test results.</p>
<p>Chief among the complaints are that their proctoring software cannot recognize faces with darker skin tones or religious headgear, and discriminates against students with disabilities and those in lower-income areas who may not have the internet speeds to meet the standards of the test-taking tech.</p>
<p>Several U.S. Democratic senators sent Proctorio, ExamSoft, and ProctorU letters in December calling on the companies to explain their technology and policies better. In their responses seen by TechCrunch, the companies rejected claims of discrimination and all said that it&#8217;s up to the teachers to decide whether a student has cheated, not the companies themselves.</p>
<p>But lawmakers say that the companies are not transparent enough, and worry teachers could be making decisions about a student&#8217;s conduct based on little more than what the technology tells them.</p>
<p>“Proctorio, ExamSoft, and ProctorU claim they don’t have problems with bias, yet alarming reports from students tell a different story,&#8221; Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) told TechCrunch. &#8220;These responses from the companies are only the first step in learning more about how they operate, but much more transparency is needed into the systems that have the power to accuse students of cheating. I will work on every fix necessary to ensure students are protected.&#8221;</p>
<p>Students across the U.S. have already <a href="https://www.change.org/p/washington-state-university-students-boycott-proctoru">called on their schools</a> to <a href="https://www.change.org/p/mark-b-rosenberg-request-to-ban-fiu-from-forcing-students-to-use-honorlock">stop using proctoring software</a> citing privacy and security risks.</p>
<p>We sent the companies several questions. ProctorU&#8217;s chief executive Scott McFarland declined to comment citing the holiday weekend. Proctorio and ExamSoft did not respond.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kIV7sJkkGA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/proctorio-dmca-copyright-critical-tweets/">Proctorio used DMCA to take down a student&#8217;s critical tweets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Proctorio used DMCA to take down a student&#8217;s critical tweets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/proctorio-dmca-copyright-critical-tweets/embed/#?secret=kIV7sJkkGA" data-secret="kIV7sJkkGA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/senator-more-transparency-is-needed-by-exam-proctoring-tech-firms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>StackPulse announces $28M investment to help developers manage outages</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/stackpulse-announces-28m-investment-to-help-developers-manage-outages/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/stackpulse-announces-28m-investment-to-help-developers-manage-outages/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bessemer Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disaster recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GGV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[site reliability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[StackPulse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When a system outage happens, chaos can ensue as the team tries to figure out what&#8217;s happening and how to fix it. StackPulse, a new startup that wants to help developers manage these crisis situations more efficiently, emerged from stealth today with a $28 million investment. The round actually breaks down to a previously unannounced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When a system outage happens, chaos can ensue as the team tries to figure out what&#8217;s happening and how to fix it. <a href="http://stackpulse.com">StackPulse</a>, a new startup that wants to help developers manage these crisis situations more efficiently, emerged from stealth today with a $28 million investment.</p>
<p>The round actually breaks down to a previously unannounced $8 million seed investment and a new $20 million Series A. GGV led the A round, while Bessemer Venture Partners led the seed and also participated in the A. Glenn Solomon at GGV and Amit Karp at Bessemer will join the StackPulse board.</p>
<p>Nobody is immune to these outages. We&#8217;ve seen incidents from companies as varied as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/amazon-web-services-outage-takes-a-portion-of-the-internet-down-with-it/">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/its-not-just-you-slack-is-struggling-this-morning/">Slack</a> in recent months. The biggest companies like Google, Facebook and Amazon employ site reliability engineers and build customized platforms to help remediate these kinds of situations. StackPulse hopes to put this kind of capability within reach of companies, whose only defense is the on-call developers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Ofer Smadari says that in the midst of a crisis with signals coming at you from Slack and PagerDuty and other sources, it&#8217;s hard to figure out what&#8217;s happening. StackPulse is designed to help sort out the details to get you back to equilibrium as quickly as possible.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TvDEgpQ3Ve"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/firehyrdant-lands-8m-series-a-for-disaster-management-tool/">FireHydrant  lands $8M Series A for disaster management tool</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FireHydrant  lands $8M Series A for disaster management tool&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/20/firehyrdant-lands-8m-series-a-for-disaster-management-tool/embed/#?secret=TvDEgpQ3Ve" data-secret="TvDEgpQ3Ve" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>First off, it helps identify the severity of the incident. Is it a false alarm or something that requires your team&#8217;s immediate attention or something that can be put off for a later maintenance cycle. If there is something going wrong that needs to be fixed right now, StackPulse can not only identify the source of the problem, but also help fix it automatically, Smadari explained.</p>
<p>After the incident has been resolved, it can also help with a post mortem to figure out what exactly went wrong by pulling in all of the alert communications and incident data into the platform.</p>
<p>As the company emerges from stealth, it has some early customers and 35 employees based in Portland, Oregon and Tel Aviv. Smadari says that he hopes to have 100 employees by the end of this year. As he builds the organization, he is thinking about how to build a diverse team for a diverse customer base. He believes that people with diverse backgrounds build a better product. He adds that diversity is a top level goal for the company, which already has an HR leader in place to help.</p>
<p>Glenn Solomon from GGV, who will be joining the company board, saw a strong founding team solving a big problem for companies and wanted to invest. &#8220;When they described the vision for the product they wanted to build, it made sense to us,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Customers are impatient with down time and Solomon sees developers on the front line trying to solve these issues. &#8220;Performance is more important than ever. When there is downtime, it&#8217;s damaging to companies,&#8221; he said. He believes StackPulse can help.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OFDIOdVEZc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/">How you react when your systems fail may define your business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How you react when your systems fail may define your business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/embed/#?secret=OFDIOdVEZc" data-secret="OFDIOdVEZc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/stackpulse-announces-28m-investment-to-help-developers-manage-outages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097999</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK&#8217;s WhiteHat rebrands as Multiverse, raises $44M to build tech apprenticeships in the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/uks-whitehat-rebrands-as-multiverse-raises-44m-to-build-tech-apprenticeships-in-the-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/uks-whitehat-rebrands-as-multiverse-raises-44m-to-build-tech-apprenticeships-in-the-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[University education is getting more expensive, and at the moment it feels a bit like a petrie dish for infections, but the long-term trends continue to show a dramatic growth in the number of people worldwide getting degrees beyond high school, with one big reason for this being that a college degree generally provides better [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">University education is getting more <a href="https://research.collegeboard.org/trends/college-pricing/highlights" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">expensive</a>, and at the moment it feels a bit like a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/12/us/covid-colleges-nursing-homes.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">petrie dish for infections</a>, but the long-term trends continue to show a <a href="https://monitor.icef.com/2018/10/study-projects-dramatic-growth-global-higher-education-2040/">dramatic growth</a> in the number of people worldwide getting degrees beyond high school, with one big reason for this being that a college degree generally provides better economic security.</p>
<p>But today, a startup that is exploring a different route for those interested in technology and knowledge worker positions &#8212; specifically by way of apprenticeships to bring in and train younger people on the job &#8212; is announcing a significant round of growth funding to see if it can provide a credible, scalable alternative to that model.</p>
<p><a href="http://multiverse.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Multiverse</a>, a UK startup that works with organizations to develop these apprenticeships, and then helps source promising, diverse candidates to fill those roles, has raised $44 million, funding that it will be using to spearhead a move into the US market after picking up some 300 clients in the UK and thousands of apprentices.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Series B is being led by General Catalyst (which has been especially active this week with UK startups: it also led a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/uks-bloom-wild-raises-102m-to-seed-its-flower-delivery-service-across-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">large round yesterday for Bloom &amp; Wild</a>), with GV (formerly known as Google Ventures), Audacious Ventures, Latitude and SemperVirens also participating. Index Ventures and Lightspeed Venture Partners, who first invested in the company in its $16 million Series A in 2020, also participated.</p>
<p>Valuation is not being disclosed but for what it&#8217;s worth, the round was one that generated a lot of interest. In between getting pitched this story and publishing it, the size of the Series B grew by $8 million (it was originally closed at $36 million). The <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/2d396375-41bd-4793-9148-8696498c95a0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FT</a> notes that the valuation was around $200 million with this round, but the company says that is &#8220;speculation on the FT&#8217;s part.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company was originally co-founded as WhiteHat and is officially rebranding today. Co-founder Euan Blair (who happens to be the son of the former UK prime minister Tony Blair and his accomplished barrister wife Cherie Booth Blair) said the name change was because the original name was a reference to how the startup sought to &#8220;hack the system for good.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, he added, &#8220;T<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">he scale has become bigger and more evolved.&#8221; The new name is to convey that &#8212; as in gaming, which is probably the arena where you might have heard this term before &#8212; &#8220;anything is possible.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">There are &#8220;multiple universes&#8221; one can inhabit as a post-18 young adult, Blair continued. While it&#8217;s been assumed that to get into tech, the obvious route was a two-to-four year (and often more) tour through college or university to pick up a higher education degree, the bet is that Multiverse is making here is that apprenticeships can easily, and widely, become another. &#8220;We want to b</span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">uild an outstanding alternative to university and college,&#8221; he said. These typically last 1.5 years. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The idea of an &#8220;outstanding alternative&#8221; is especially important when thinking of how to target more marginalized groups and how this ties up with how tech companies are looking to be more diverse in the future, without cutting down on the quality of what people are getting out of the experience, or the resulting talent that is getting recruited. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">There&#8217;s long been a stigma attached less prestigious institutions, and putting money or effort into another channel to perpetuate that doesn&#8217;t really make sense or point to progress.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Blair said that currently over half of the people making their way through Multiverse are people of color, and 57% are women, and the plan is to build tools to make that an even firmer part of its mission. </span></p>
<p>The startup sees itself as part-tech company and part-education enterprise.</p>
<p>It works with tech companies and others to open up opportunities for people who have not had any higher education or any training, where fresh high school graduates can come in, learn the ropes of a job while getting paid, and then continue on working their way up the ladder with that knowledge base in place.</p>
<p><a href="https://platform.multiverse.io/apprenticeships" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apprenticeships on the platform right now</a> range from data analysts through to exhibition designers, and the idea is that by opening up and targeting the US market, the breadth, number and location of roles will grow.</p>
<p>This is not just a social enterprise: there is actual money in this area. Blair prices that it charges the companies it works with range by qualification &#8220;but are broadly around the $15,000 mark.&#8221; (The individuals applying don&#8217;t pay anything, and they will also be paid by the companies providing the apprenticeships.)</p>
<p>On the educational front, Multiverse doesn&#8217;t just connect people as a recruiter might: it has a team in place to build out what the &#8220;curriculum&#8221; might be for a particular apprenticeship, and how to deliver and train people with the requisite skills alongside the practice experience of working, and more.</p>
<p>That latter role, of course, has taken on a more poignant dimension in the last year: concepts like remote training and virtual mentorship have very much come into their own at a time when offices are largely standing empty to help reduce the spread of Covid-19.</p>
<p>Regardless of what happens in the year ahead &#8212; fingers crossed that vaccinations and other efforts will help us collectively move past where we are right now &#8212; many believe that the infrastructure that has been put into place to keep working virtually will continue to be used, which bodes well for a company like Multiverse that is building a business around that, both with technology it creates itself and will bring in from third parties and partners.</p>
<p>Indeed, the ecosystem of companies building tools to deliver educational content, provide training and work collaboratively has really boomed in the pandemic, giving companies like Multiverse a large library of options for how to bring people into new work situations. (Google, which is now an investor in Multiverse, is very much one of the makers of such education tools.)</p>
<p>Apprenticeships are an interesting area for a startup to tackle. Traditionally, it&#8217;s a term that would have been associated mainly with skilled labor positions, rather than &#8220;knowledge workers.&#8221;</p>
<p>But you can argue that with the bigger swing that the globe has seen away from industrial and towards knowledge economies, there is an argument to be made for building more enterprises and opportunities for an ever wider pool of users, rather than expecting everyone to be shoehorned into the models of the last 50 years. (The latter would essentially imply that college is possibly the only way up.)</p>
<p>You might also be fair to claim that Blair&#8217;s connections helped him secure funding and open doors with would-be customers, and that might well be the case, but ultimately the startup will live or die by how well it executes on its premise, whether it finds a good way to connect more people, engage them in opportunities, and keep them on board.</p>
<p>This is what really attracted the investors, said Joel Cutler, managing director and co-founder of General Catalyst.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Euan has a genuine belief that this is important, and when you talk to him, you get a  feeling of manifest destiny,&#8221; Cutler said in an interview. In response to the question of family connections, he said that this was precisely the kind of issue that the technology industry should be tackling to fight.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Of all the industries to break the mold of where you went to school, it should be the tech world that will do that, since it is far more of a meritocracy than others. This is the perfect place to start to break that mold,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Education will be super valuable but apprenticeships will also be important.&#8221; He noted that another company that General Catalyst invests in, <a href="https://www.guildeducation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Guild Education</a>, is addressing similar opportunities, or rather the gaps in current opportunities, for older people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/uks-whitehat-rebrands-as-multiverse-raises-44m-to-build-tech-apprenticeships-in-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft invests in Cruise in new $2 billion round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/microsoft-invests-in-cruise-in-new-2-billion-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/microsoft-invests-in-cruise-in-new-2-billion-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cruise Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cruise has raised $2 billion in a new equity round that has pushed its valuation up to $30 billion and delivered Microsoft as an investor and partner. GM, Honda and other institutional investors have also put more capital into Cruise as the autonomous vehicle company inches closer to commercializing its technology. While Microsoft&#8217;s capital is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Cruise has raised $2 billion in a new equity round that has pushed its valuation up to $30 billion and delivered Microsoft as an investor and partner.</p>
<p>GM, Honda and other institutional investors have also put more capital into Cruise as the autonomous vehicle company inches closer to commercializing its technology.</p>
<p>While Microsoft&#8217;s capital is important, the partnership might provide equal and longer term value for Cruise, at least in the two companies&#8217; views. Under the long-term strategic partnership, Cruise will use Azure, Microsoft&#8217;s cloud and edge computing platform, for its yet-to-be launched autonomous vehicle ride-hailing service.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Any autonomous vehicle company aiming to commercialize — meaning bring their tech to the public at scale — needs a robust cloud computing platform. Operating fleets of self-driving vehicles that will shuttle people and even packages generates a massive amount of data, making cloud services one of the bigger costs for an AV company.</p>
<p>Cruise&#8217;s partnership with Microsoft aims to provide benefits for both companies. Cruise will be able to lock in lower prices for cloud services and Microsoft will be able to test some of its bleeding edge systems that can handle workloads needed to bring machine learning and robotics — like autonomous vehicles — to life and at scale.</p>
<p>&#8220;Advances in digital technology are redefining every aspect of our work and life, including how we move people and goods,&#8221; Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella said in a statement. &#8220;As Cruise and GM&#8217;s preferred cloud, we will apply the power of Azure to help them scale and make autonomous transportation mainstream.&#8221;</p>
<p>The partnership extends to GM as well, according to Tuesday&#8217;s announcement. Microsoft will be GM&#8217;s preferred public cloud provider to help the automaker accelerate several of it digitization initiatives as well as streamline operations across digital supply chains.</p>
<p>The partnership will not only allow Cruise to accelerate the commercialization of its all-electric, self-driving vehicles, it help &#8220;GM realize even more benefits from cloud computing as we launch 30 new electric vehicles globally by 2025 and create new businesses and services to drive growth, GM Chairman and CEO Mary Barra said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/microsoft-invests-in-cruise-in-new-2-billion-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ETH spin-off LatticeFlow raises $2.8M to help build trustworthy AI systems</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/eth-spin-off-latticeflow-raises-2-8m-to-help-build-trustworthy-ai-systems/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/eth-spin-off-latticeflow-raises-2-8m-to-help-build-trustworthy-ai-systems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btov Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep neural networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeepCode]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging-Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global founders capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LatticeFlow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siemens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snyk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zalando]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LatticeFlow, an AI startup that was spun out of ETH Zurich in 2020, today announced that it has raised a $2.8 million seed funding round led by Swiss deep-tech fund btov and Global Founders Capital, which previously backed the likes of Revolut, Slack and Zalando. The general idea behind LatticeFlow is to build tools that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://latticeflow.ai/">LatticeFlow</a>, an AI startup that was spun out of ETH Zurich in 2020, today announced that it has raised a $2.8 million seed funding round led by Swiss deep-tech fund <a href="https://btov.vc/">btov</a> and Global Founders Capital, which previously backed the likes of Revolut, Slack and Zalando.</p>
<p>The general idea behind LatticeFlow is to build tools that help AI teams build and deploy AI models that are safe, reliable and trustworthy. The problem today, the team argues, is that models get very good at finding the right statistical patterns to hit a given benchmark. That makes them inflexible, though, since these models were optimized for accuracy in a lab setting, not for robustness in the real world.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the most commonly used paradigms for evaluating machine learning models is just aggregate metrics, like accuracy. And, of course, this is a super coarse representation of how good a model really is,&#8221; Pavol Bielik, the company&#8217;s CTO explained. &#8220;What we want to do is, we provide systematic ways of monitoring models, assessing their reliability across different relevant data slices and then also provide tools for improving these models.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2097263" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2097263" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2097263" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png" alt="" width="1024" height="351" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png 2205w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png?resize=150,51 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png?resize=300,103 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png?resize=768,263 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png?resize=680,233 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png?resize=1536,526 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png?resize=2048,701 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/example.png?resize=50,17 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2097263" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> LatticeFlow</p></div></p>
<p>Building these kinds of models that are more flexible yet still provide robust results will take a new arsenal of tools, though, as well as the right team with deep expertise in these areas. Clearly, though, this is a founding team with the right background. In addition to CTO Bielik, the founding team includes Petar Tsankov, the company&#8217;s CEO and former senior researcher and lecturer at ETH Zurich, as well as ETH professors Martin Vechev, who leads the Secure, Reliable and Intelligence Systems lab at ETH, and Andreas Krause, who leads ETH&#8217;s Learning &amp; Adaptive Systems lab.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7uNqqAWIEA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/snyk-bags-another-200m-at-2-6b-valuation-9-months-after-last-raise/">Snyk bags another $200M at $2.6B valuation 9 months after last raise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Snyk bags another $200M at $2.6B valuation 9 months after last raise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/snyk-bags-another-200m-at-2-6b-valuation-9-months-after-last-raise/embed/#?secret=7uNqqAWIEA" data-secret="7uNqqAWIEA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It&#8217;s also worth noting that Vechev, who previously co-founded ETH spin-off ChainSecurity, and his group at ETH previously developed <a href="https://github.com/eth-sri/eran">ERAN</a>, a verifier for large deep learning models with millions of parameters, that last year won the first competition for certifying deep neural networks. While the team was already looking at creating a company before winning this competition, Vechev noted that gave the team the confirmation that it was on the right path.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2097264" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2097264" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2097264" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png" alt="" width="1024" height="332" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png 3948w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png?resize=150,49 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png?resize=300,97 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png?resize=768,249 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png?resize=680,220 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png?resize=1536,498 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png?resize=2048,664 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/LatticeFlow_Team.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2097264" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> LatticeFlow</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We want to solve the main AI problem, which is making AI usable. This is the overarching goal,&#8221; Vechev told me. &#8220;[&#8230;] I don&#8217;t think you can actually found the company just purely based on the certification work. I think the kinds of skills that people have in the company, my group, Andreas [Krause]&#8217;s group, they all complement each other and cover a huge space, which I think is very, very unique. I don&#8217;t know of other companies who have covered this range of skills in these pressing points and have done groundbreaking work before.&#8221;</p>
<p>LatticeWorks already has a set of pilot customers who are trialing its tools. These include Swiss railways (SBB), which is using it to build a tool for automatic rail inspections, Germany’s Federal Cyber Security Bureau and the U.S. Army. The team is also working with other large enterprises that are using its tools to improve their computer vision models.</p>
<p>“Machine Learning (ML) is one of the core topics at SBB, as we see a huge potential in its application for an improved, intelligent and automated monitoring of our railway infrastructure,&#8221; said Dr. Ilir Fetai and Andre Roger, the leads of SBB&#8217;s AI team. &#8220;The project on robust and reliable AI with LatticeFlow, ETH, and Siemens has a crucial role in enabling us to fully exploit the advantages of using ML.&#8221;</p>
<p>For now, LatticeFlow remains in early access. The team plans to use the funding to accelerate its product development and bring on new customers. The team also plans to build out a presence in the U.S. in the near future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/eth-spin-off-latticeflow-raises-2-8m-to-help-build-trustworthy-ai-systems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097262</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversa Health expands its Series B round to $20M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/conversa-health-expands-its-series-b-round-to-20m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/conversa-health-expands-its-series-b-round-to-20m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board member]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[builders vc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conversa Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Murray Brozinsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[northwell ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oregon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[primary care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Portland, Oregon-based Conversa Health, a virtual care and communication platform that helps health organizations stay in touch with their patients and customers, today announced that it has expanded its Series B funding round from $12 million to $20 million. The round is still co-led by Builders VC and Northwell Health&#8217;s venture arm Northwell Ventures. Additional [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Portland, Oregon-based <a href="https://conversahealth.com/">Conversa Health</a>, a virtual care and communication platform that helps health organizations stay in touch with their patients and customers, today announced that it has expanded its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/conversa-health-raises-12m-series-b-for-its-digital-health-platform/">Series B funding round</a> from $12 million to $20 million. The round is still co-led by Builders VC and Northwell Health&#8217;s venture arm Northwell Ventures. Additional investors include UH Ventures, the venture arm of University Hospitals and VC firms P5 <span class="il">Health</span> Ventures, Epic Ventures, StartUp <span class="il">Health</span> and Nassau Street Ventures, as well Genesis Merchant Capital and J-Ventures, which came in as new investors in this expanded round.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s been a recognition, especially with COVID, that the need for automated and virtual &#8212; which are two big trends in healthcare &#8212; were on the horizon but now the horizon has been pulled in because of COVID and the healthcare system recognizes that that&#8217;s going to be required to be able to allow access for patients and improve both the experience for patients and providers, and get better outcomes and do it at lower cost,&#8221; Conversa CEO Murray Brozinsky told me.</p>
<p>Brozinsky actually believes that within the next decade, 80% of care will be done remotely. This will allow for more personalized and evidence-based care, but it will also require investments in automation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Conversa links providers’ EHRs and other patient data to best-of-breed interactive digital care pathways and clinical analytics engine to automate care management 24&#215;7. This improves care plan adherence pre and post visit, reducing costs and generating better outcomes for patients,&#8221; said Builders VC partner and Conversa board member Mark Goldstein. &#8220;Conversa’s enterprise platform and library of digital pathways are used by providers to care for patients across their populations, as opposed to one-off point solutions. It fills an enormous gap in the market.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="v0EMOHJEoC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/conversa-health-raises-12m-series-b-for-its-digital-health-platform/">Conversa Health raises $12M Series B for its digital health platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Conversa Health raises $12M Series B for its digital health platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/conversa-health-raises-12m-series-b-for-its-digital-health-platform/embed/#?secret=v0EMOHJEoC" data-secret="v0EMOHJEoC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Given the pandemic, it&#8217;s maybe no surprise that Conversa&#8217;s business also boomed. The number of customers the company its services has grown fourfold while its financial metrics are up 6x because a lot of its larger companies have expanded their use of the platform.</p>
<p>The team decided to expand the existing Series B round to help it capitalize on this momentum and to bring on more engineers in order to scale the platform. Brozinsky believes that the need for a platform like Conversa&#8217;s will remain after the pandemic ends. In addition, the company is also already rolling out support for vaccination programs in its service to help educate consumers but also help in monitoring efforts after people get their shots.</p>
<p>&#8220;Everything we&#8217;re hearing from health systems, they recognize that they need to be prepared for this to happen again, they still need to care for the core demographics that haven&#8217;t changed &#8212; this aging population &#8212; with an acute shortage of healthcare workers,&#8221; Brozinsky said. &#8220;So the need for the systems and these platforms is going to be more acute and the investment is not so much an additional cost but an enormous return.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/conversa-health-expands-its-series-b-round-to-20m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097324</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>K Health expands into virtual childcare and raises $132 million at a $1.5 billion valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/k-health-expands-into-virtual-childcare-and-raises-132-million-at-a-1-5-billion-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/k-health-expands-into-virtual-childcare-and-raises-132-million-at-a-1-5-billion-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 13:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxgroup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burger King]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[K Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaiser Permanente]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayo Clinic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pharmaceutical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[primary care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teladoc Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valor equity partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[K Health, the virtual health care provider that uses machine learning to lower the cost of care by providing the bulk of the company&#8217;s health assessments, is launching new tools for childcare on the heels of raising cash that values the company at $1.5 billion. The $132 million round raised in December will help the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://getcare.khealth.ai">K Health</a>, the virtual health care provider that uses machine learning to lower the cost of care by providing the bulk of the company&#8217;s health assessments, is launching new tools for childcare on the heels of raising cash that values the company at $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>The $132 million round raised in December will help the company expand and help pay for upgrades including an integration with most electronic health records &#8212; an integration that&#8217;s expected by the second quarter.</p>
<p>Throughout 2020 K Health has leveraged its position operating at the intersection of machine learning and consumer healthcare to raised $222 million in a single year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This appetite from investors shows how large the opportunity is in consumer healthcare as companies look to use technology to make care more affordable.</p>
<p>For K Health, that means a monthly subscription to its service of $9 for unlimited access to the service and physicians on the platform, as well as a $19 per-month virtual mental health offering and a $19 fee for a one-time urgent care consultation.</p>
<p>To patients and investors the pitch is that the data K Health has managed to acquire through partnerships with organizations like the Israel health maintenance organization <a href="https://www.maccabi4u.co.il/1781-he/Maccabi.aspx">Maccabi Healthcare Services</a>, which gave up decades of anonymized data on patients and health outcomes to train K Health&#8217;s predictive algorithm, can assess patients and aid the in diagnoses for the company&#8217;s doctors.</p>
<p>In theory that means the company&#8217;s service essentially acts as a virtual primary care physician, holding a wealth of patient information that, when taken together, might be able to spot underlying medical conditions faster or provide a more holistic view into patient care.</p>
<p>For pharmaceutical companies that could mean insights into population health that could be potentially profitable avenues for drug discovery.</p>
<p>In practice, patients get what they pay for.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s mental health offering uses medical doctors who are not licensed psychiatrists to perform their evaluations and assessments, according to one provider on the platform, which can lead to interactions with untrained physicians that can cause more harm than good.</p>
<p>While company chief executive Allon Bloch is likely correct in his assessment that most services can be performed remotely (Bloch puts the figure at 90%), they should be performed remotely by professionals who have the necessary training.</p>
<p>There are limits to how much heavy lifting an algorithm or a generalist should do when it comes to healthcare, and it appears that K Health wants to push those limits.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Drug referrals, acute issues, prevention issues, most of those can be done remotely,&#8221; Bloch said. &#8220;There’s an opportunity to do much better and potentially cheaper. </span></p>
<p>K Health has already seen hundreds of thousands of patients either through its urgent care offering or its subscription service and generated tens of millions in revenue in 2020, according to Bloch. He declined to disclose how many patients used the urgent care service vs. the monthly subscription offering.</p>
<p>Telemedicine companies, like other companies providing services remotely, have thrived during the pandemic. Teladoc and Amwell, two of the early pioneers in virtual medicine have seen their share prices soar. Companies like Hims, that provide prescriptions for elective conditions that aren&#8217;t necessarily covered by health, special purpose acquisition companies <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-10-01/hims-inks-1-6-billion-deal-to-go-public-via-oaktree-spac?sref=AwwRcx4b">at valuations of $1.6 billion</a>.</p>
<p>Backing K Health are a group of investors led by GGV Capital and Valor Equity Partners. Kaiser Permanente&#8217;s pension fund and the investment offices of the owners of 3G Capital (the Brazilian investment firm that owns Burger King and Kraft Heinz), along with <span style="font-weight: 400;">14W, Max Ventures, Pico Partners, Marcy Venture Partners, Primary Venture Partners and BoxGroup, also participated in the round. </span></p>
<p>Organizations working with the company include Maccabi Healthcare; the Mayo Clinic, which is investigating virtual care models with the company; and Anthem, which has white labeled the K Health service and provides it to some of the insurer&#8217;s millions of members.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/k-health-expands-into-virtual-childcare-and-raises-132-million-at-a-1-5-billion-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097958</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PPRO nabs $180M at a $1B+ valuation to bring together the fragmented world of payments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/ppro-nabs-180m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-bring-together-the-fragmented-world-of-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/ppro-nabs-180m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-bring-together-the-fragmented-world-of-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ppro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic has hastened a shift of most commerce becoming e-commerce in the last year, and that has brought a new focus on startups that are helping to enable that process. In the latest development, PPRO, a London-based startup that has built a platform to make it easier for marketplaces, payment providers and other e-commerce [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The pandemic has hastened a shift of most commerce becoming e-commerce in the last year, and that has brought a new focus on startups that are helping to enable that process.</p>
<p>In the latest development, <a href="http://ppro.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PPRO</a>, a London-based startup that has built a platform to make it easier for marketplaces, payment providers and other e-commerce players to enable localised payments &#8212; that is, make and take payments in whatever form local customers prefer to use, which extend well beyond basic payment cards &#8212; has closed a round of $180 million, funding that catapults PPRO&#8217;s valuation to over $1 billion.</p>
<p>PPRO (pronounced &#8220;P-pro&#8221;, as in payments professionals) plans to use the funding to continue expanding in newer markets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Simon Black, PPRO&#8217;s CEO, said in an interview that two particular areas of focus in the coming year will be more activity in Asian countries like Singapore and Indonesia, as well as Latin America, where the company acquired a local player, <a href="https://www.ppro.com/news/ppro-acquires-allpago-to-become-the-market-leader-in-local-payments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">allpago</a>, back in 2019.</p>
<p>In both cases, the opportunity comes in the form of high growth stemming from more transactions moving online, as well as the chaos that is the fragmented payments market.</p>
<p>The capital is coming from a group of investors that includes Eurazeo Growth, Sprints Capital, and Wellington Management. It comes on the heels of a $50 million round the company<a href="https://www.ppro.com/news/ppro-announces-85-volume-growth-despite-pandemic-accelerates-plans-with-new-investment-from-sprints-and-citi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> raised last August</a> from Sprints, along with Citi and HPE Growth; and a further <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/16/paypal-leads-50m-round-for-cross-border-payment-specialist-ppro/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$50 million it picked up in 2018</a> led by strategic investor PayPal.</p>
<p>PayPal, alongside Citi, Mastercard Payment Gateway Services, Mollie, and Worldpay are among PPRO&#8217;s 100 large global customers, which use the company&#8217;s APIs for a variety of functions, including localised gateway, processing and merchant acquirer services.</p>
<p>The flood of activity coming from consumers and businesses buying more online &#8212; a by-product of the pandemic leading to many businesses shutting down physical operations for the moment &#8212; has seen the company double transaction volumes between Q4 2020 and the same quarter in 2019.</p>
<p>PPRO is not the only company to be targeting that opportunity.</p>
<p>The fragmentation of financial services overall &#8212; where realistically, there is only handful of types of transactions that might be made (usually: deposits, payments, credit), but quite literally thousands of permutations and methods to make them, with specific markets and their populations typically coalescing around their own localised selections.</p>
<p>That has led to the rise of a number of companies providing what has come to be called &#8220;banking as a service&#8221; or &#8220;fintech as a service,&#8221; where a tech provider stitches together in the background a number of services, sometimes thousands, and makes it easier for their customers, by way of an API, to plug those services in for their own customers to use more easily, most often connected to a range of other services provided to them like money management.</p>
<p>Others in this wider space that includes payments and other fintech services include the likes of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/rapyd-raises-300m-on-a-2-5b-valuation-to-boost-its-fintech-as-a-service-api/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rapyd</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/mambu-raises-135m-at-a-2b-valuation-for-an-saas-platform-that-powers-banking-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mambu</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/01/thought-machine-nabs-83m-for-a-cloud-based-platform-that-powers-banking-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thought Machine</a>, <a href="https://www.temenos.com/">Temenos</a>, <a href="http://www.ederabs.com/">Edera</a>, Adyen, Stripe and newer players like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/unit-raises-18-6m-to-offer-banking-features-as-a-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Unit</a>, with many of these raising large amounts of money in recent times in particular to double down on what is currently a rapidly expanding market.</p>
<p>The unique aspect of PPRO is that it was an early mover in the area of identifying the conundrum of fragmentation in payments for companies that operate in more than one country or region, and that it has continued to play only in payments, without a jump to adjacent services.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re ultra focused because the local payments problem is actually growing,&#8221; said Black, who believes that &#8220;the disconnect between what a consumer wants to use, but also their appetite and the proliferation of payment options&#8221; all contribute to more complexity (with the trade-off being more choices for consumers, but equally possibly too much choice?).</p>
<p>As Black sees it, the company&#8217;s focus on payments has given it more momentum to build better tech specifically to address that globally.</p>
<p>&#8220;PPRO is building solutions for performance in industrial strength. It’s growing rapidly because there are no other players that are truly global. We are globalizing to support the needs of customers who want to nationalize, so we have an opportunity to focus on payments, to be a strategic outsource partner.&#8221;</p>
<p>This doesn&#8217;t mean that there isn&#8217;t room for product expansion: alongside payments, Black highlighted product compliance and providing better analytics as two areas where the company is already active and will be doing more for customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Where we partner and provide value is in anticipating changes in consumer demand,&#8221; he noted. &#8220;We monitor how customers are using those methods and &#8212; whether you are are service provider or furniture or travel company &#8212; determine which are the best relevant payment methods.&#8221; Services like open banking, tools for banks to enable allowing payments directly from customers&#8217; accounts, or buy-now-pay-later payments, are examples, he said, of areas that speak of further opportunities.</p>
<p>“We are delighted to support Simon and the team at PPRO as they continue to develop best-in-class local payment solutions,” commented Nathalie Kornhoff-Brüls, Managing Director at Eurazeo Growth, in a statement. “All signs for the future indicate that digital commerce, and even more so cross-border commerce, will continue to grow exponentially while innovation in payment methods remains strong. As a result, facilitating local payments is becoming increasingly complex. Payment service providers, however, no longer have a choice as merchants and their customers are pushing for the adoption.”</p>
<p>“PPRO has proven to be the go-to problem solver in this area, providing the local payments technology and expertise that the world’s biggest payment players rely on. Our investment reflects our confidence in the growth potential for PPRO and we’re excited to support PPRO and its team on their journey,” added Voria Fattahi, a partner at Sprints Capital, in a separate statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/ppro-nabs-180m-at-a-1b-valuation-to-bring-together-the-fragmented-world-of-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097940</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling Athens VCs: Be featured in The Great TechCrunch Survey of European VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/calling-athens-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/calling-athens-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is embarking on a major project to survey the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities. Our survey of VCs in Athens, Greece will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic. We’d like to know how Greece&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, how [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is embarking on a major project to <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> the venture capital investors of Europe, and their cities.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey of VCs in Athens, Greece</a> will capture how the country is faring, and what changes are being wrought amongst investors by the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>We’d like to know how Greece&#8217;s startup scene is evolving, how the tech sector is being impacted by COVID-19, and, generally, how your thinking will evolve from here.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Our survey will only be about investors, and <strong>only the contributions of VC investors will be included.</strong> More than one partner is welcome to fill out the survey. (Please note, if you have filled the survey out already, there is no need to do it again).</p>
<p>The shortlist of questions will require only brief responses, but the more you can add, the better.</p>
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6"><strong>You can fill out the survey here.</strong></a></p>
<p>Obviously, investors who contribute will be featured in the final surveys, with links to their companies and profiles.</p>
<p>What kinds of things do we want to know? Questions include: Which trends are you most excited by? What startup do you wish someone would create? Where are the overlooked opportunities? What are you looking for in your next investment, in general? How is your local ecosystem going? And how has COVID-19 impacted your investment strategy?</p>
<p>This survey is part of a broader <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/">series of surveys</a> we’re doing to help founders find the right investors.</p>
<p>https://techcrunch.com/extra-crunch/investor-surveys/</p>
<p>For example, here is the recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/14-vcs-discuss-covid-19-and-londons-future-as-a-tech-hub/">survey of London</a>.</p>
<p>You are not in Greece, but would like to take part? That&#8217;s fine! Any European VC investor can STILL fill out the survey, as we probably will be putting a call out to your country next anyway! And we will use the data for future surveys on vertical topics.</p>
<p>The survey is covering almost every country on in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Union_for_the_Mediterranean">Union for the Mediterranean</a>, so just look for your country and city on the <a href="https://forms.gle/k4Ji2Ch7zdrn7o2p6">survey</a> and please participate (<em>if</em> you&#8217;re a venture capital investor).</p>
<p>Thank you for participating. If you have questions you can email mike@techcrunch.com</p>
<p>(Please note: Filling out the survey is not a guarantee of inclusion in the final published piece).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/calling-athens-vcs-be-featured-in-the-great-techcrunch-survey-of-european-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097949</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India asks WhatsApp to withdraw new privacy policy over &#8216;grave concerns&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/india-asks-whatsapp-to-withdraw-new-privacy-policy-expresses-grave-concerns/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/india-asks-whatsapp-to-withdraw-new-privacy-policy-expresses-grave-concerns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2097943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India has asked WhatsApp to withdraw the planned change to its privacy policy, posing a new headache to Facebook-owned service that identifies the South Asian nation as its biggest market by users. In an email to WhatsApp head Will Cathcart, the nation&#8217;s IT ministry said the upcoming update to the app&#8217;s data-sharing policy has raised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India has asked WhatsApp to withdraw the planned change to its privacy policy, posing a new headache to Facebook-owned service that identifies the South Asian nation as its biggest market by users.</p>
<p>In an email to WhatsApp head Will Cathcart, the nation&#8217;s IT ministry said the upcoming update to the app&#8217;s data-sharing policy has raised “grave concerns regarding the implications for the choice and autonomy of Indian citizens&#8230; Therefore, you are called upon to withdraw the proposed changes.”</p>
<p>The ministry is additionally seeking clarification from WhatsApp on its data-sharing agreement with Facebook and other commercial firms and has asked why users in the EU are exempt from the new privacy policy but their counterpoint in India have no choice but to comply.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Such a differential treatment is prejudicial to the interests of Indian users and is viewed with serious concern by the government,&#8221; the ministry wrote in the email, a copy of which was obtained by TechCrunch. &#8220;The government of India owes a sovereign responsibility to its citizens to ensure that their interests are not compromised and therefore it calls upon WhatsApp to respond to concerns raised in this letter.&#8221;</p>
<p>Through an in-app alert earlier this month, WhatsApp had asked users to agree to new terms of conditions that grants the app the consent to share with Facebook some personal data about them, such as their phone number and location. Users were initially provided until February 8 to comply with the new policy if they wished to continue using the service.</p>
<p>&#8220;This &#8216;all-or-nothing&#8217; approach takes away any meaningful choice from Indian users. This approach leverages the social significance of WhatsApp to force users into a bargain, which may infringe on their interests in relation to informational privacy and information security,&#8221; the ministry said in the email.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2097183" style="width: 6058px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2097183" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2097183 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg" alt="" width="6048" height="4024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg 6048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg?resize=1536,1022 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg?resize=2048,1363 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/GettyImages-1230557386-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 6048px) 100vw, 6048px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2097183" class="wp-caption-text">An advertisement from WhatsApp is seen in a newspaper at a stall in New Delhi on January 13, 2021. (Photo by Sajjad HUSSAIN / AFP) (Photo by SAJJAD HUSSAIN/AFP via Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>The notification from WhatsApp prompted a lot of confusion &#8212; and in some cases, anger and frustration &#8212; among its users, many of which have explored alternative messaging apps such as Telegram and Signal in recent weeks.</p>
<p>WhatsApp, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/02/19/facebook-buying-whatsapp-for-16b-in-cash-and-stock-plus-3b-in-rsus/">Facebook bought for $19 billion in 2014</a>, has been sharing some limited information about its users <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/25/whatsapp-to-share-user-data-with-facebook-for-ad-targeting-heres-how-to-opt-out/">with the social giant since 2016</a> — and for a period allowed users to opt-out of this. Responding to the backlash last week, the Facebook-owned app, which serves more than 2 billion users worldwide, said it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/whatsapp-delays-new-data-sharing-policy-enforcement-to-may-15/">deferring the enforcement of the planned policy</a> to May 15.</p>
<p>WhatsApp also ran front-page ads on several newspapers in India, where it has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/youtube-and-whatsapp-inch-closer-to-half-a-billion-users-in-india/">amassed over 450 million users</a>, last week to explain the changes and debunk some rumors.</p>
<p>New Delhi also shared disappointment with the timing of this update, which to be fair WhatsApp unveiled last year. The ministry &gt;said that it was reviewing the Personal Data Protection Bill, a monumental privacy bill that is meant to oversee how data of users are shared with the world.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since the Parliament is seized of the issue, making such a momentous change for Indian users at this time puts the cart before the horse. Since the Personal Data Protection Bill strongly follows the principle of &#8216;purpose limitation,&#8217; these changes may lead to significant implementational challenges for WhatsApp should the Bill become an Act,&#8221; the letter said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, India&#8217;s IT and Law Minister Ravi Shankar Prasad also offered a loud advice to Facebook. &#8220;Be it WhatsApp, be it Facebook, be it any digital platform. You are free to do business in India but do it in a manner without impinging upon the rights of Indians who operate there.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/27a1.png" alt="➡" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Be it WhatsApp, Facebook or any other digital platform they are free to do business in India but it should be done in a manner without impinging upon the rights of Indians who operate it. The sanctity of personal communications needs to be maintained: <a href="https://twitter.com/rsprasad?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rsprasad</a> at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/15IDS?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#15IDS</a> <a href="https://t.co/p33qynU6Ur">pic.twitter.com/p33qynU6Ur</a></p>
<p>&mdash; RSPrasad Office (@OfficeOfRSP) <a href="https://twitter.com/OfficeOfRSP/status/1351431260913057793?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 19, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/india-asks-whatsapp-to-withdraw-new-privacy-policy-expresses-grave-concerns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2097943</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
