<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:29:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Google fined $592M in France for breaching antitrust order to negotiate copyright fees for news snippets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyright law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Le Monde]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Showcase]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[France has hit Google with a fine of half a billion euros after finding major breaches in how it negotiated with publishers to remunerate them for reuse of their content &#8212; as is required under a pan-EU reform of digital copyright law which extended neighbouring rights to news snippets. The size of the fine is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">France has hit Google with a fine of half a billion euros after finding major breaches in how it negotiated with publishers to remunerate them for reuse of their content &#8212; as is required under a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/european-parliament-votes-for-controversial-copyright-reform/">pan-EU reform of digital copyright law</a> which extended neighbouring rights to news snippets.</p>
<p>The size of the fine is notable as it&#8217;s over half of the entire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/">$1BN news licensing pot that Google announced last October</a> &#8212; when it said it would be paying news publishers “to create and curate high-quality content” to appear on its platforms.</p>
<p>At the time, the move that looked intended to shrink Google&#8217;s exposure to legal mandates to pay publishers for content reuse by pushing them to accept commercial terms which give it broad rights to &#8216;showcase&#8217; their content.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>France&#8217;s watchdog has now called out &#8212; and sanctioned &#8212; the practice.</p>
<p>The half a billion euro penalty is also notable for being considerably more than Google had already agreed to pay French publishers, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-google-france-copyright-exclusive-idUSKBN2AC27N">Reuters</a> &#8212; which reported, back in February, that the tech giant had inked a deal with a group of 121 publishers to pay them just $76M over three years.</p>
<p>France&#8217;s competition authority <a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/article/remuneration-des-droits-voisins-lautorite-sanctionne-google-hauteur-de-500-millions-deuros">said today</a> that it&#8217;s applying the sanction of €500 million ($592M) against the tech giant for failing to comply with a number of injunctions related to its earlier, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/frances-competition-watchdog-orders-google-to-pay-for-news-reuse/">April 2020 decision</a> &#8212; when the watchdog ordered Google to negotiate in good faith with publishers to remunerate them for displaying their protected content.</p>
<p>Initially, Google sought to evade the neighbouring news right by stopping displaying snippets of content alongside links it showed in Google News in France. But the watchdog found that was likely to be an abuse of its dominant position &#8212; and ordered Google to stop circumventing the law and negotiate with publishers to pay for the reuse in good faith.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="r5bx5CKu02"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/frances-competition-watchdog-orders-google-to-pay-for-news-reuse/">France&#8217;s competition watchdog orders Google to pay for news reuse</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;France&#8217;s competition watchdog orders Google to pay for news reuse&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/09/frances-competition-watchdog-orders-google-to-pay-for-news-reuse/embed/#?secret=r5bx5CKu02" data-secret="r5bx5CKu02" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The<em> Autorité de la Concurrence</em> is not happy with how Google has gone about this, though.</p>
<p>A number of publishers complained to it that the negotiations were not carried out in good faith and that Google did not provide them with key information necessary to inform payments.</p>
<p>The Syndicate of magazine press publishers (SEPM), the Alliance de Presse d&#8217;Information Générale (APIG) and Agence France Presse (AFP) made complaints in August/September 2020 &#8212; kicking off the investigation by the watchdog and today&#8217;s announcement of a major penalty.</p>
<p>Further fines &#8212; of up to €900,000 per day &#8212; could be headed Google&#8217;s way if it continues to breach the watchdog&#8217;s injunctions and fails to supply publishers with all the required information within a new two-month deadline.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/communiques-de-presse/remuneration-des-droits-voisins-lautorite-sanctionne-google-hauteur-de-500">press release</a> detailing its investigation, the <em>Autorité </em>said Google sought to unilaterally impose its global news licensing product, aka &#8216;Showcase&#8217;, under a partnership the tech giant calls Publisher Curated News &#8212; in negotiations with publishers &#8212; pushing for the legal neighbouring right to be incorporated as &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">an ancillary component with no separate financial valuation&#8221;.</span></p>
<p>Publishers requests to break out copyright remuneration negotiations were denied, per the watchdog&#8217;s investigation.</p>
<p>It also found Google &#8220;unjustifiably&#8221; reduced the scope of negotiations with regard to the scope of income derived from the display of protected news content &#8212; with Google telling publishers that only advertising income from Google Search pages posting news content should be taken into account in determining the level of remuneration due.</p>
<p>The authority found this exclusion of income from other Google services and all indirect income related to this content to be in breach of the copyright law and its earlier compliance order.</p>
<p>Google also &#8220;deliberately circumscribed&#8221; the scope of the law on neighboring rights by excluding titles that do not have a Political and General Information certificate &#8212; which the watchdog couched as a &#8220;bad faith&#8221; interpretation of the code on intellectual property.</p>
<p>It also found the tech giant sought to exclude press agencies from renumeration related to their content when used by third party publishers &#8212; highlighting that as another breach of its April 2020 decision, by further noting: &#8220;The French legislator has been very explicit on the need to include press agencies.&#8221;</p>
<p>In another finding, it said Google had only provided publishers with &#8220;partial&#8221; and &#8220;insufficient&#8221; information for a &#8220;transparency assessment of renumeration due&#8221;; and further accused the tech giant of delaying until just a few days before the injunction deadline to provide it &#8212; so of being &#8220;late&#8221; too.</p>
<p>The authority&#8217;s investigation highlights compliance problems with another injunction &#8212; related to an obligation of neutrality in how protected content is presented on Google&#8217;s platforms &#8212; with the watchdog writing on that: &#8220;The strategy put in place by Google has thus strongly encouraged publishers to accept the contractual conditions of the <em>Showcase</em> service and to renounce negotiations relating specifically to the current uses of protected content, which was the subject of the Injunctions, under penalty of seeing their exposure and their remuneration degraded compared to their competitors who would have accepted the proposed terms. Google cannot therefore claim to have taken the necessary measures to prevent its negotiations from affecting the presentation of protected content in its services.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another injunction sought to prevent Google from seeking to leverage its dominance by offsetting remunerations paid to publishers for the neighbouring rights.</p>
<p>On this the watchdog also took issue with its approach &#8212; noting that its Showcase product requires publishers to make not just snippets of their content available for display on Google&#8217;s platforms but &#8220;large extracts&#8221; and even whole articles.</p>
<p>It also found that Google linked participation in the <em>Showcase</em> program to subscription to another service called <em>Subscribe with Google</em> (SwG) &#8212; enabling it to link negotiation on neighboring rights with the subscription of new services that could financially benefit its business.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MUKLVkgHz9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/google-inks-agreement-in-france-on-paying-publishers-for-news-reuse/">Google inks agreement in France on paying publishers for news reuse</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google inks agreement in France on paying publishers for news reuse&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/google-inks-agreement-in-france-on-paying-publishers-for-news-reuse/embed/#?secret=MUKLVkgHz9" data-secret="MUKLVkgHz9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Under a subhead which denounces what it found as &#8220;extremely serious practices&#8221;, the authority goes on to accuse Google of &#8220;a deliberate, elaborate and systematic strategy of non-compliance&#8221; &#8212; and of continuing an already years-long &#8220;opposition strategy&#8221; to the principle of neighbouring rights; and then, after they&#8217;d been baked into EU and French law, seeking to &#8220;minimize the concrete scope of those rights as much as possible&#8221;.</p>
<p>Google has, the authority asserts, sought to use a global strategy to close down publishers&#8217; ability to negotiate for remuneration for their content reuse at a national level &#8212; using its Showcase product as a cloak for &#8220;avoiding or limiting as much as possible&#8221; payments to publishers; and, simultaneously, seeking to use negotiations on neighboring rights as an opportunity to obtain access to new content by press publishers that could allow it to collect additional income, such as from subscriptions to press titles.</p>
<p>&#8220;The sanction of 500 million euros takes into account the exceptional seriousness of the breaches observed and that the behavior of Google has further delayed the proper application of the law on neighboring rights, which aimed to better take into account the value of content from publishers and news agencies included on the platforms. The Authority will be extremely vigilant about the correct application of its decision, as non-execution can now lead to periodic penalty payments,&#8221; added the watchdog&#8217;s president, Isabelle de Silva, in a statement (which we&#8217;ve translated from French).</p>
<p>The half a billion euro fine and the warning to Google that its practices will attract daily fines if it persists in ignoring the injunctions put the tech giant on notice that the detail of commercial deals won&#8217;t be allowed to fly under the radar in France.</p>
<p>Any more attempts to shape a self-serving version of &#8216;compliance&#8217; are likely to attract further sanction from the watchdog &#8212; which also recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/france-fines-google-268m-for-adtech-abuses-and-gets-interoperability-commitments/">applied a number of interoperability requirements</a> on Google&#8217;s ad business (and slapped it with a $268M fine), also acting on complaints from publishers.</p>
<p>While anything Google agrees to in France on the neighbouring rights issue is likely to set the bar for what it can achieve with commercial deals elsewhere &#8212; at least in other EU markets, where the copyright extension also applies (once it&#8217;s been transposed into a Member State&#8217;s national law).</p>
<p>In a statement responding to the authority&#8217;s sanction, Google expressed disappointment with the outcome of the investigation &#8212; claiming to have acted in good faith throughout negotiations with publishers:</p>
<blockquote><p>“We are very disappointed with this decision &#8212; we have acted in good faith throughout the entire process. The fine ignores our efforts to reach an agreement, and the reality of how news works on our platforms. To date, Google is the only company to have announced agreements on neighbouring rights. We are also about to finalize an agreement with AFP that includes a global licensing agreement, as well as the remuneration of their neighbouring rights for their press publications.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The tech giant went on to suggest that the authority&#8217;s decision is &#8220;primarily&#8221; related to negotiations in France which took place between May and September 2020, further claiming it has continued to engage with publishers and press agencies since then to find &#8220;solutions&#8221;.</p>
<p>By way of example it pointed to a January 2021 framework agreement inked with the Alliance de la Presse d’Information Générale &#8212; which it claims covers every IPG title (Information de Presse Générale) in a &#8220;transparent and non-discriminatory way&#8221;. It also pointed to agreements it has inked with other publications in the market, including Le Monde, Courrier International, L&#8217;Obs, Le Figaro, Libération, and L’Express.</p>
<p>Google also reiterated its confident it can sign a global licensing agreement with Agence France Presse &#8212; which it said it also wants to include remuneration of neighbouring rights for press publications from the agency.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our objective remains the same: We want to turn the page with a definitive agreement,&#8221; it added, saying it would take the French Competition Authority’s &#8220;feedback into consideration and adapt our offers&#8221; and that: &#8220;We are already engaging with press publishers and agencies beyond IPG, by covering publications that are recognised by the CPPAP as &#8216;online press services&#8217;, and we reiterate our offer to have an independent third party in a position to evaluate our offers and allow us to base our discussions on facts.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other major fines for Google in France in recent years include the aforementioned <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/france-fines-google-268m-for-adtech-abuses-and-gets-interoperability-commitments/">$268M for adtech abuses</a> last month; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/">$120 for dropping tracking cookies without consent</a> back in December; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/20/france-slaps-google-with-166m-antitrust-fine-for-opaque-and-inconsistent-ad-rules/">$166M in December 2019</a> for opaque and inconsistent ad rules; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">$57M for privacy violations</a> in January 2019.</p>
<p>Beyond the EU, Australia <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/">recently passed a law</a> which requires tech giants, Google and Facebook, to enter mandatory arbitration with publishers for reuse of their content if they fail to agree commercial terms on their own.</p>
<p>Its law has attracted considerable attention worldwide as legislators grapple with how to rein in powerful tech platforms and ensure the sustainability of traditional news businesses whose revenues have been hit by the Internet-driven shift to digital publishing.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/uks-digital-markets-unit-starts-work-on-pro-competition-reforms/">UK&#8217;s Competition and Markets Authority</a> has, for example, described Australia&#8217;s backstop of mandatory arbitration if commercial negotiations fail as a “sensible” approach &#8212; at at time when the government is working on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/">shaping an ex ante regulation regime</a> to enable competition authorities to pro-actively tackle abuses by platforms with strategic market power.</p>
<p>Ahead of Australia&#8217;s law being passed, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/google-threatens-to-close-its-search-engine-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-digital-news-code/">Google had warned that it might have to close its services in the country</a> if legislators went ahead and also suggested the quality could degrade or that it may have to start to charge for products. In the event, it did not shut up shop down under.</p>
<p>The tech giant was also an active lobbyist against the EU&#8217;s plan to extend digital copyright to cover snippets of news content &#8212; and, as recently as <a href="https://blog.google/perspectives/richard-gingras/how-google-invests-news/">2019</a>, it was vowing never to pay for news.</p>
<p>A few years later it announced the $1BN pot to pay publishers to licence content. But Google&#8217;s eventual bill for its ad business piggybacking upon others&#8217; journalism may be rather larger than that.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7tWNg7QmMx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/">Google to pay out $1B to publishers to license content for new Google News Showcase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google to pay out $1B to publishers to license content for new Google News Showcase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/embed/#?secret=7tWNg7QmMx" data-secret="7tWNg7QmMx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7vCHx6GVjC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/">After Facebook&#8217;s news flex, Australia passes bargaining code for platforms and publishers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After Facebook&#8217;s news flex, Australia passes bargaining code for platforms and publishers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/embed/#?secret=7vCHx6GVjC" data-secret="7vCHx6GVjC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yKRGJvUymY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/google-threatens-to-close-its-search-engine-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-digital-news-code/">Google threatens to close its search engine in Australia as it lobbies against digital news code</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google threatens to close its search engine in Australia as it lobbies against digital news code&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/google-threatens-to-close-its-search-engine-in-australia-as-it-lobbies-against-digital-news-code/embed/#?secret=yKRGJvUymY" data-secret="yKRGJvUymY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176580</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>End-to-end moving startup Updater buys on-demand moving startup Dolly</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/end-to-end-moving-startup-updater-buys-on-demand-moving-startup-dolly/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/end-to-end-moving-startup-updater-buys-on-demand-moving-startup-dolly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contractor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[costco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[craigslist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dolly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyde Park Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lowes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maveron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[updater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[version one ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Moving services giant Updater is bringing on the team from Dolly as the New York company looks to expand its scope of offerings with the acquisition of the on-demand startup known for helping consumers execute small-scale moves. Dolly connects users in need of moving a large item like a piece of furniture with a contractor [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Moving services giant <a href="https://updater.com/">Updater</a> is bringing on the team from <a href="https://dolly.com/">Dolly</a> as the New York company looks to expand its scope of offerings with the acquisition of the on-demand startup known for helping consumers execute small-scale moves.</p>
<p>Dolly connects users in need of moving a large item like a piece of furniture with a contractor ready to lend a hand. Like competing services such as Lugg, the app has been a popular solution for picking up items from peer-to-peer marketplaces like Craigslist. Dolly boasts a partnership with Facebook Marketplace that has allowed its users to coordinate picking up items with the service, available in 45 major cities across the US, according to their website.</p>
<p>In addition to its user-facing service, Dolly has also built a major business partnering with retailers directly allowing them to tap into their mover network and coordinate same-day delivery for customers. Dolly&#8217;s retail partners include companies like Costco, Lowe&#8217;s and The Container Store.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yDOpkazuFX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/18/on-demand-delivery-and-moving-app-dolly-hits-1-million-in-revenue-and-expands-into-sf-and-dc/">On-demand delivery and moving app Dolly hits $1 million in revenue and expands into SF and DC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;On-demand delivery and moving app Dolly hits $1 million in revenue and expands into SF and DC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/18/on-demand-delivery-and-moving-app-dolly-hits-1-million-in-revenue-and-expands-into-sf-and-dc/embed/#?secret=yDOpkazuFX" data-secret="yDOpkazuFX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>A price tag for the deal wasn&#8217;t disclosed and couldn&#8217;t be learned. Dolly raised $17.2 million over several rounds, including a $7.5 million Series B in May of 2019. The startup&#8217;s backers include Maveron, Hyde Park Venture Partners and Version One Ventures.</p>
<p>As part of the acquisition, Dolly will be living on an independent, wholly-owned subsidiary of Updater.</p>
<p>The SoftBank-backed Updater is an &#8220;invite-only&#8221; service focused on building a more premium end-to-end moving experience. The team has partnered with a number of major brokerage firms whose customers are given the option to use Updater&#8217;s services to coordinate their move, pairing them with moving companies who use Updater&#8217;s MoveHQ software platform. Today, a quarter of US household moves are facilitated using one of Updater&#8217;s products, the company says.</p>
<p>The firm has raised nearly $200 million since its founding in 2010. Dolly&#8217;s acquisition will allow Updater to expand their services to customers that are &#8220;conducting a small move or don’t want to book a full-service moving company,&#8221; CEO David Greenberg tells TechCrunch. &#8220;We want to be the go-to place for Americans to conquer their move.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A1uUimYywk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/04/08/updater-the-dashboard-for-your-move-packs-up-8-million-in-funding/">Updater, The Dashboard For Your Move, Packs Up $8 Million In Funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Updater, The Dashboard For Your Move, Packs Up $8 Million In Funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/04/08/updater-the-dashboard-for-your-move-packs-up-8-million-in-funding/embed/#?secret=A1uUimYywk" data-secret="A1uUimYywk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/end-to-end-moving-startup-updater-buys-on-demand-moving-startup-dolly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176343</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Abu Dhabi-based micromobility operator Fenix launches 10-minute grocery delivery service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/abu-dhabi-based-micromobility-operator-fenix-launches-10-minute-grocery-delivery-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/abu-dhabi-based-micromobility-operator-fenix-launches-10-minute-grocery-delivery-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abu dhabi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fenix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united arab emirates]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United Arab Emirates-based shared micromobility operator Fenix is expanding the use of its electric scooters and back-end logistics to not only move people, but also to move goods. On Tuesday, the company announced the launch of a 10-minute fresh grocery delivery service on Reem Island, a dense, mixed-use development off the coast of Abu Dhabi.  [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">United Arab Emirates-based shared micromobility operator Fenix is expanding the use of its electric scooters and back-end logistics to not only move people, but also to move goods. On Tuesday, the company announced the launch of a 10-minute fresh grocery delivery service on Reem Island, a dense, mixed-use development off the coast of Abu Dhabi. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Fenix’s new service, F10, will utilize available vehicles from the operator’s normal shared fleet for deliveries. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Delivery riders will also be considered shared resources with Fenix’s e-scooter service, taking turns between making fast deliveries and swapping batteries. The company is building a single integrated platform to manage the fleets and services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The shared e-scooter business is still new and has not yet been incredibly profitable for existing operators due in large part to the low life expectancy of the vehicles and the cost of paying workers to swap batteries. Fenix’s expanded business model is a novel way to make the most out of the sunk cost of its hardware and employee base while also exploring a market that is expected to grow by nearly $632 billion over the next three years, according to market research and advisory company <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/-631-84-billion-growth-in-online-grocery-delivery-services-market-2020-2024--includes-insights-on-key-products-offered-by-major-vendors--technavio-301242113.html">Technavio</a>.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ws6IpyEBJV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/">Bird&#8217;s SPAC filing shows scooter-nomics just don&#8217;t fly</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bird&#8217;s SPAC filing shows scooter-nomics just don&#8217;t fly&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/bird-rides-spac-filing-shows-scooter-nomics-just-doesnt-fly/embed/#?secret=ws6IpyEBJV" data-secret="ws6IpyEBJV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Logistically speaking, Fenix might be onto something. Its “dark stores,” or compact, private retail facilities, are scattered around Reem Island in optimized locations, each with a large catchment area that falls within a narrow delivery radius, according to Jaideep Dhanoa, co-founder and CEO of Fenix. Dhanoa did not reveal how many dark stores the company has placed throughout the island.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Fenix, the dark store is also a distributed charging center for our swappable battery e-scooter operations, which allows us to share the real estate costs between the two businesses and also increase the productivity of our e-scooter operations via more distributed charging locations,” said Dhanoa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dhanoa said Fenix’s full-time employees, who are all company stakeholders, are trained to accept, pick and pack items for delivery in the dark stores within two minutes before relaying the goods to a rider who has a mere eight minutes to make it to the customer. Not a stressful situation at all! It wouldn’t be surprising to see Fenix&#8217;s next funding round focus on R&amp;D for robots that will gather groceries faster and without the pressure of human error.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Such quick delivery couldn’t be done without urban density, which is largely what drew Fenix to Reem Island. The small island, which is one of the only free zones in the city where foreign nationals can buy property, holds a residential population of about 100,000 people. Dhanoa said the island also presents multiple use cases in the form of residential and commercial towers and shopping malls. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Wherever there is a dense population, there will be a market for F10,” said Dhanoa. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new business expansion was in part funded by an undisclosed round that was recently raised from existing investors, like Maniv Mobility, the Israeli venture firm that also funded electric mobility company Revel and invested </span><a href="https://www.menabytes.com/fenix-seed/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$3.8 million in Fenix’s seed round</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last November. (Maniv Mobility’s investment in Fenix was the first time an Israeli firm invested in a business from the UAE, a sign that companies are making good on the </span><a href="https://www.state.gov/the-abraham-accords/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Abraham Accords’ </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">promise to normalize relations between the two countries.) But Dhanoa told TechCrunch that the costs of launching the F10 delivery service didn’t require deep pockets, “given the unique synergies with our existing micromobiltiy business.”</span></p>
<p>The F10 app can be downloaded in the Google Play Store and the iOS App Store. To kick things off, Fenix is offering new users their first order up to AED 50 (~$14 USD) for free.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fRJMlTsOoW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/revels-frank-reig-shares-how-he-built-his-business-and-what-hes-planning/">Revel&#8217;s Frank Reig shares how he built his business and what he&#8217;s planning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Revel&#8217;s Frank Reig shares how he built his business and what he&#8217;s planning&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/revels-frank-reig-shares-how-he-built-his-business-and-what-hes-planning/embed/#?secret=fRJMlTsOoW" data-secret="fRJMlTsOoW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/abu-dhabi-based-micromobility-operator-fenix-launches-10-minute-grocery-delivery-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176522</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria leads mobile app market growth in Africa as use of gaming apps surge 44% from Q1 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/nigeria-leads-mobile-app-market-growth-in-africa-as-use-of-gaming-apps-surge-44-from-q1-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/nigeria-leads-mobile-app-market-growth-in-africa-as-use-of-gaming-apps-surge-44-from-q1-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 08:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AppsFlyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic&#8217;s effect on the global app market has not been hard to miss. In the first quarter and first half of this year, consumer spending in mobile apps hit new records at $32 billion and $64.9 billion, respectively. In Africa, it can be tough to call out exact numbers on consumer spending because the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic&#8217;s effect on the global app market has not been hard to miss. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first quarter and first half of this year, consumer spending in mobile apps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/consumer-spending-on-apps-hit-record-64-9b-in-first-half-of-2021-but-install-growth-slowed-to-1-7/">hit new records</a> at $32 billion and $64.9 billion, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Africa, it can be tough to call out exact numbers on consumer spending because the continent gets hardly a mention in global app market reports. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet, other metrics are worth looking at, and a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> new <a href="https://www.appsflyer.com/resources/others/african-mobile-apps-landscape/">report</a> from <a href="https://www.appsflyer.com/">AppsFlyer</a> in collaboration with Google has some important insights into how the African app market has fared since the pandemic broke out last year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The report tracked mobile app activities across three of Africa&#8217;s largest app markets (Kenya, Nigeria and South Africa) between Q1 2020 and Q1 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From the first half of 2020 to the first half of 2021, the African mobile app industry (which is predominantly Android) increased by 41% </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">overall</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> installs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was analyzed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from 6,000 apps and 2 billion installs in the three markets. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nigeria registered the highest growth, with a 43% rise; South Africa&#8217;s market increased by 37% and Kenya increased 29%</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CmRwYrP6mj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/consumer-spending-on-apps-hit-record-64-9b-in-first-half-of-2021-but-install-growth-slowed-to-1-7/">Consumer spending on apps hit record $64.9B in first half of 2021, but install growth slowed to 1.7%</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Consumer spending on apps hit record $64.9B in first half of 2021, but install growth slowed to 1.7%&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/consumer-spending-on-apps-hit-record-64-9b-in-first-half-of-2021-but-install-growth-slowed-to-1-7/embed/#?secret=CmRwYrP6mj" data-secret="CmRwYrP6mj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Lockdown numbers</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On March 22, 2020, Rwanda imposed Africa&#8217;s first lockdown. Subsequently,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> other countries followed; (those in the report) Kenya (March 25), South Africa (March 27), and Nigeria (March 30)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As more people spent time at home from Q2 2020, app installs increased by 20% across the three countries. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">South Africans were the quickest to take to their phones as the lockdowns hit with installs increasing by 17% from the previous quarter</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other hand</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Nigerians and Kenyans recorded a 2% and 9% increase, respectively. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The report attributes the disparity to the varying levels of restrictions each country faced; South Africa experienced the strictest and most frequent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per the report, gaming apps showed strong performance between Q1 and Q2 2020. The segment experienced a 50% growth compared to an 8% increase in nongaming apps pulled. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It followed a global trend where gaming apps <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/07/08/app-annie-mobile-gamers-broke-app-store-records-in-q2-2020/">surged to a record high in Q2 2020</a>, at 14 billion downloads globally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2>In-app purchasing revenue and almost year-on-year growth</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to AppsFlyer, the biggest trend it noticed was in in-app purchasing revenue. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Q3 2020, in-app purchasing revenue numbers grew with a staggering 136% increase compared to Q2 2020, and accounted for 33% of 2020&#8217;s total revenue, &#8220;highlighting </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> how much African consumers were spending within apps, from retail purchases to gaming upgrades</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In-app purchasing revenue among South African consumers increased by 213%, while Nigeria and Kenyan consumers recorded 141% and 74% increases, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the advertising front and on an almost year-on-year basis, in-app advertising revenue also increased </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">significantly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as Africans </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were glued</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to their smartphones more than ever</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Per the report, in-app advertising revenue increased 167% between Q2 2020 to Q1 2021.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For gaming and non-gaming apps, which </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was highlighted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> between the first two quarters, they both increased by 44% and 40% respectively in Q1 2021 compared to Q2 2020</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2>Fintech and super apps</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the last five years, fintech has dominated VC investments in African startups. It&#8217;s a no brainer why there is so much affinity for the sector. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fintechs create so much value for Africa&#8217;s mobile-first population, with large sections of unbanked, underbanked and banked people</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This value is why all but one of the continent&#8217;s billion-dollar startups are fintech.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">African fintechs have grown by 89.4% between 2017 and 2021, according to a Disrupt Africa <a href="https://disrupt-africa.com/finnovating-for-africa/">report</a>. Now, there are more than 570 startups on the continent. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many fintechs are mobile-based, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">therefore</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> reflecting the number of fintech apps Africans use each day</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consumers in South Africa and Nigeria saw year-on-year growth in finance app installs by 116% and 60%, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mGyyZ2VpPv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/02/nigeria-is-becoming-africas-unofficial-tech-capital/">Nigeria is becoming Africa’s unofficial tech capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nigeria is becoming Africa’s unofficial tech capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/02/nigeria-is-becoming-africas-unofficial-tech-capital/embed/#?secret=mGyyZ2VpPv" data-secret="mGyyZ2VpPv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AppsFlyer says that like fintech apps, super apps are on the rise as well. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">These &#8220;all-in-one&#8221; apps offer users a range of functions such as banking, messaging, shopping and ride-hailing</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The report says their rise, partly due to device limitations on the continent, owes much to the same conditions that have led to a surge in fintech apps: systemic underbanking</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Super apps remove some of the barriers that these users face, as well as providing a level of customer insight and experience that traditional banks cannot,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8221; the report said.</span></p>
<p>Daniel Junowicz, RVP EMEA &amp; Strategic Projects for AppsFlyer, commenting on the trends highlighted in the report said, “&#8230;The mobile app space in Africa is thriving despite the turmoil of last year. Installs are growing, and consumers are spending more money than ever before, highlighting just how important mobile can be for businesses when it comes to driving revenue.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/nigeria-leads-mobile-app-market-growth-in-africa-as-use-of-gaming-apps-surge-44-from-q1-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176444</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quantexa raises $153M to build out AI-based big data tools to track risk and run investigations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/quantexa-raises-153m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/quantexa-raises-153m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 06:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantexa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As financial crime has become significantly more sophisticated, so too have the tools that are used to combat it. Now, Quantexa &#8212; one of the more interesting startups that has been building AI-based solutions to help detect and stop money laundering, fraud, and other illicit activity &#8212; has raised a growth round of $153 million, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As financial crime has become significantly more sophisticated, so too have the tools that are used to combat it. Now, <a href="https://www.quantexa.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quantexa</a> &#8212; one of the more interesting startups that has been building AI-based solutions to help detect and stop money laundering, fraud, and other illicit activity &#8212; has raised a growth round of $153 million, both to continue expanding that business in financial services and to bring its tools into a wider context, so to speak: linking up the dots around all customer and other data.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve diversified outside of financial services and working with government, healthcare, telcos and insurance,&#8221; Vishal Marria, its founder and CEO, said in an interview. &#8220;That has been substantial. Given the whole journey that the market’s gone through in contextual decision intelligence as part of bigger digital transformation, was inevitable.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Series D values the London-based startup between $800 million and $900 million on the heels of Quantexa growing its subscriptions revenues 108% in the last year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Warburg Pincus led the round, with existing backers Dawn Capital, AlbionVC, Evolution Equity Partners (a specialist cybersecurity VC), HSBC, ABN AMRO Ventures and British Patient Capital also participating. The valuation is a significant hike up for Quantexa, which was valued between $200 million and $300 million in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/quantexa-raises-64-7m-to-bring-big-data-intelligence-to-risk-analysis-and-investigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its Series C last July</a>. It has now raised over $240 million to date.</p>
<p>Quantexa got its start out of a gap in the market that Marria identified when he was working as a director at Ernst &amp; Young tasked with helping its clients with money laundering and other fraudulent activity. As he saw it, there were no truly useful systems in the market that efficiently tapped the world of data available to companies &#8212; matching up and parsing both their internal information as well as external, publicly available data &#8212; to get more meaningful insights into potential fraud, money laundering and other illegal activities quickly and accurately.</p>
<p>Quantexa&#8217;s machine learning system approaches that challenge as a classic big data problem &#8212; too much data for a humans to parse on their own, but small work for AI algorithms processing huge amounts of that data for specific ends.</p>
<p>Its so-called &#8220;Contextual Decision Intelligence&#8221; models (the name Quantexa is meant to evoke &#8220;quantum&#8221; and &#8220;context&#8221;) were built initially specifically to address this for financial services, with AI tools for assessing risk and compliance and identifying financial criminal activity, leveraging relationships that Quantexa has with partners like Accenture, Deloitte, Microsoft and Google to help fill in more data gaps.</p>
<p>The company says its software &#8212; and this, not the data, is what is sold to companies to use over their own datasets &#8212; has handled up to 60 billion records in a single engagement. It then presents insights in the form of easily digestible graphs and other formats so that users can better understand the relationships between different entities and so on.</p>
<p>Today, financial services companies still make up about 60% of the company&#8217;s business, Marria said, with 7 of the top 10 UK and Australian banks and 6 of the top 14 financial institutions in North America among its customers. (The list includes its strategic backer HSBC, as well as Standard Chartered Bank and Danske Bank.)</p>
<p>But alongside those &#8212; spurred by a huge shift in the market to relying significantly more on wider data sets, to businesses updating their systems in recent years, and the fact that, in the last year, online activity has in many cases become the &#8220;only&#8221; activity &#8212; Quantexa has expanded more significantly into other sectors.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Financial crisis [of 2007] was a tipping point in terms of how financial services companies became more proactive, and I&#8217;d say that the pandemic has been a turning point around other sectors like healthcare in how to become more proactive,&#8221; Marria said. &#8220;To do that you need more data and insights.&#8221;</p>
<p>So in the last year in particular, Quantexa has expanded to include other verticals facing financial crime, such as healthcare, insurance, government (for example in tax compliance), and telecoms/communications, but in addition to that, it has continued to diversify what it does to cover more use cases, such as building more complete customer profiles that can be used for KYC (know your customer) compliance or to serve them with more tailored products. Working with government, it&#8217;s also seeing its software getting applied to other areas of illicit activity, such as tracking and identifying human trafficking.</p>
<p>In all, Quantexa has &#8220;thousands&#8221; of customers in 70 markets. Quantexa cites figures from IDC that estimate the market for such services &#8212; both financial crime and more general KYC services &#8212; is worth about $114 billion annually, so there is still a lot more to play for.</p>
<p>&#8220;Quantexa’s proprietary technology enables clients to create single views of individuals and entities, visualized through graph network analytics and scaled with the most advanced AI technology,&#8221; said Adarsh Sarma, MD and co-head of Europe at Warburg Pincus, in a statement. &#8220;This capability has already revolutionized the way KYC, AML and fraud processes are run by some of the world’s largest financial institutions and governments, addressing a significant gap in an increasingly important part of the industry. The company’s impressive growth to date is a reflection of its invaluable value proposition in a massive total available market, as well as its continued expansion across new sectors and geographies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Interestingly, Marria admitted to me that the company has been approached by big tech companies and others that work with them as an acquisition target &#8212; no real surprises there &#8212; but longer term, he would like Quantexa to consider how it continues to grow on its own, with an independent future very much in his distant sights.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Sure, an acquisition to the likes of a big tech company absolutely could happen, but I am gearing this up for an IPO,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/quantexa-raises-153m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176198</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This limited-edition Super Mario smartwatch will run you $2,150</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/this-limited-edition-super-mario-smartwatch-will-run-you-2150/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/this-limited-edition-super-mario-smartwatch-will-run-you-2150/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 06:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wearables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartwatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tag heuer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Those who’ve followed Nintendo with any sort of frequency over the years know the gaming giant has a tendency to be extremely protective with its IP. Ultimately, it’s probably for the best that the market wasn’t flooded with cheap Mario knickknacks the way it easily could have been. In recent years, however, the company has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Those who’ve followed Nintendo with any sort of frequency over the years know the gaming giant has a tendency to be extremely protective with its IP. Ultimately, it’s probably for the best that the market wasn’t flooded with cheap Mario knickknacks the way it easily could have been.</p>
<p>In recent years, however, the company has seemingly loosened its approach, more readily embracing brand partnerships in ways it has shunned in the past. Heck, we’ve even gotten a bunch of mobile games and a theme park out of the deal.</p>
<p>Today, it takes the wraps off of one of the more surprising brand partnerships in recent memory, in a deal with Swiss watch company TAG Heuer, which makes very nice &#8212; and extremely expensive &#8212; timepieces. The “long-term collaboration” is kicking off with a limited-edition (2,000 units) Mario smartwatch that will set you back $2,150.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2176177" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176177" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176177" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1006" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg 2396w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=150,147 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=300,295 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=768,755 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=680,668 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=1536,1510 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=2048,2013 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_2_MASTER.jpg?resize=64,64 64w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176177" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TAG Heuer/Nintendo</p></div></p>
<p>Clearly there’s a bit of a disconnect between the pricing on the TAG Heuer Connected and the sort of accessibility the company offers with hardware like the Switch. In fact, you can buy six of the high-end new OLED Switches for the price of a single Mario-branded smartwatch &#8212; or, for that matter, five Apple Watch Series 6s.</p>
<p>I will give it this &#8212; it’s a pretty sweet-looking watch. And, given the barrier of entry, there’s a pretty good chance you’ll be the only person you know who owns one (forget for a moment that, unlike expensive analog watches, smartwatches aren’t designed to last forever). The hook here are little Mario animations that pop up throughout the day as you hit your step count and meet other goals. It’s fun and something that would play really well on a fitness watch for kids (for, one imagines, a fraction of the price).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176176" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176176" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176176" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_DOS.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176176" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TAG Heuer/Nintendo</p></div></p>
<p>The watch is, effectively, a redesigned version of the TAG Heuer Connected, a $2,000 Wear OS device that launched last April. The timepiece got high marks for design quality &#8212; as one would expect from the company. This version adds touches like a Mario “M” on the dial, red accents throughout and a matching red rubber strap (along with a black leather version).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176178" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176178" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176178" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg 1568w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/High-Quality-JPG-SBG8A13.EB0238_STILLLIFE_3_16-9.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176178" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TAG Heuer/Nintendo</p></div></p>
<p>The case measures 45mm in diameter and the watch sports a 430 mAh battery the company says should get you between six and 20 hours of life, depending on usage. That’s due in part to the inclusion of GPS and a heart rate monitor.</p>
<p>It’s available starting July 15.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xUgbonHJs7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/12/lego-super-mario-is-coming-later-this-year/">Lego Super Mario is coming later this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lego Super Mario is coming later this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/12/lego-super-mario-is-coming-later-this-year/embed/#?secret=xUgbonHJs7" data-secret="xUgbonHJs7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/this-limited-edition-super-mario-smartwatch-will-run-you-2150/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eka Ventures closes $95M Impact VC fund for sustainable consumption, healthcare and society</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eka-ventures-closes-95m-impact-vc-fund-for-sustainable-consumption-healthcare-and-society/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eka-ventures-closes-95m-impact-vc-fund-for-sustainable-consumption-healthcare-and-society/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 05:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s clear that there is an enormous and growing appetite amongst consumers to switch to products and services which address some of the biggest issues of our era, whether it be climate change or problems with society. So we’ve seen the rise of ethical investing apps, or ways to reduce our carbon footprint, or shop [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s clear that there is an enormous and growing appetite amongst consumers to switch to products and services which address some of the biggest issues of our era, whether it be climate change or problems with society. So we’ve seen the rise of ethical investing apps, or ways to reduce our carbon footprint, or shop more ethically. so it follows that VC should come up with funds to invest in these consumer spaces.</p>
<p>That’s been the focus of UK-based <a href="https://www.ekavc.com/">Eka Ventures</a> ventures since started investing in April 2020, prior to today&#8217;s announcement of the fund&#8217;s closing.</p>
<p>It’s now reached a final close on its $95m (£68m) fund, and now claims to be the “largest impact-driven early-stage venture capital fund focused on the UK” although TechCrunch was unable to verify that claim.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Investors in the fund include British Business Bank, BSC, Isomer, Guys and St Thomas Foundation, Planet First Partners, Draper Esprit, Snowball and others. It’s also backed, it says, by 24 entrepreneurs, 12 of whom are founders the Eka partners have previously backed either at fund or individual level.<br />
 <br />
Eka’s aim will be to invest in consumer technology companies focused on sustainable consumption, consumer healthcare, and the ‘inclusive economy’. The fund will focus on the UK at between £500k and £3m per deal.<br />
 <br />
Founders Jon Coker, Camilla Dolan and Andrew Richardson has previous experience in venture where they were involved in VC deals for Gousto, Bloom &amp; Wild, Peak and Elder. Coker was previously with London-focused VC MMC Ventures.<br />
 <br />
Jon Coker, General Partner of Eka told me: “We only invest in companies where we see a clear impact directly connected to the product or service that they sell. So as they grow, the impact grows with the company. We won&#8217;t invest in companies where we don&#8217;t see that. We’ve said to all of our investors that we will only invest in companies where that is delivered. We&#8217;re assessing companies we look for founder alignment, so understanding how the founders are thinking about building their company and the impact that&#8217;s delivered through the products and services. Once we&#8217;ve gone through that process of alignment and assessment we then measure that impact over time. We will also co invest with investors that don&#8217;t have a specific impact focus on their fund.”</p>
<p>I asked him how they expect to measure the impact of their investments: “We use a framework called the Impact management project framework which is trying to create an industry-standard around the measurement of impact in venture. It looks at different dimensions to identify the specific impact that the company you&#8217;re investing in is creating. When you&#8217;re backing really early-stage companies, you can measure the impact that their product is currently having but you also want to measure progress against projects that will deliver future impact. We have a number of impact-focused LPs in the fund who have done a lot of work with us actually on helping us think about this framework.”<br />
 <br />
Camilla Dolan, general partner of Eka, said: “One of our first investments was Urban Jungle insurance. This is an example where we think about it as being inclusive, as they saw a big opportunity to try and serve the segment that has historically been underserved. They do that through underwriting using behavioral characteristics rather than demographic characteristics, which is how the incumbent industry does it. This excludes a lot of the customers. They&#8217;re now launching a social housing-specific product because they had so many testimonials from social housing.”</p>
<p>She added: “When it comes to working with companies, we are clear in our desire for scale, and we will do everything in our power to help the founders we work with achieve their ambitious goals. We are looking for entrepreneurs who set the bar for impact-driven innovation high and who are focused on fundamentally changing or creating a category, in the same way Tesla has single-handedly propelled the electric vehicle industry forward. We set Eka up to back companies with that level of ambition.”<br />
 <br />
Timo Boldt, Founder of Gousto said: “Jon and Camilla are two of the best investors a founder could possibly hope for. They supported Gousto with our Series A back in 2013 and have been cheerleaders ever since. Their new venture, Eka, is tightly aligned with our own philosophy because of their focus on sustainability. Much like them, we believe in the power of people to drive change.”<br />
 <br />
Ken Cooper, Managing Director, Venture Solutions, British Business Bank said: “The Bank’s Enterprise Capital Funds programme is a key tool in helping to develop and maintain an effective venture capital provision in the UK, lowering the barriers to entry for emerging fund managers and for those targeting less well-served areas of the market.  Our commitment [of £36m] to Eka Ventures, will enable them to support new and growing sustainable consumer technology businesses in the UK.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eka-ventures-closes-95m-impact-vc-fund-for-sustainable-consumption-healthcare-and-society/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176491</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carsome Group will acquire iCar Asia in a deal worth $200M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/carsome-group-will-acquire-icar-asia-in-a-deal-worth-200m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/carsome-group-will-acquire-icar-asia-in-a-deal-worth-200m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 03:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automotive marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carsome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carsome Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catcha group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCar Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Southeast Asia’s car marketplace wars are going into high drive. Today Carsome Group, one of the region’s largest online used car marketplaces, said it plans to acquire listings platform iCar Asia in a transaction worth more than $200 million. Carsome has agreed to acquire 19.9% of iCar Asia from Malaysia internet conglomerate Catcha Group. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Southeast Asia’s car marketplace wars are going into high drive. Today <a href="https://www.carsome.my/">Carsome Group</a>, one of the region’s largest online used car marketplaces, said it plans to acquire listings platform <a href="https://www.icarasia.com/">iCar Asia </a>in a transaction worth more than $200 million.</p>
<p>Carsome has agreed to acquire 19.9% of iCar Asia from Malaysia internet conglomerate Catcha Group. In exchange, Catcha Group will become a shareholder in Carsome Group. Carsome and Catcha Group have also made a joint proposal to iCar Asia’s directors to buy the rest of the company from its shareholders.</p>
<p>Carsome rival Carro <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/automotive-marketplace-carro-hits-unicorn-status-with-360m-series-c-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2/">revealed one month ago that it raised a $360 million Series C</a> led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2, boosting it to unicorn status. A day after Carro’s announcement, <a href="https://www.dealstreetasia.com/stories/carsome-raising-200m-pre-ipo-245775/">DealStreetAsia reported that Carsome</a> is in talks to raise over $200 million in a pre-IPO round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Carsome hasn’t confirmed the funding, but it has been making moves to expand its reach, including <a href="https://www.carsome.my/news/item/carsome-indonesia-universal">a strategic investment in PT Universal</a>, an offline car and motorcycle auction company that has retail branches in five Indonesian cities. Carsome said its investment in PT Universal will allow it to double its automotive transaction volumes in Indonesia.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Hj46f9Y8Fw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/automotive-marketplace-carro-hits-unicorn-status-with-360m-series-c-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2/">Automotive marketplace Carro hits unicorn status with $360M Series C led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Automotive marketplace Carro hits unicorn status with $360M Series C led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/automotive-marketplace-carro-hits-unicorn-status-with-360m-series-c-led-by-softbank-vision-fund-2/embed/#?secret=Hj46f9Y8Fw" data-secret="Hj46f9Y8Fw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Now Carsome says its integration with iCar Asia will create a marketplace that is targeting $1 billion in revenue for this year, with about 100,000 cars transacted annually, more than 460,000 live partner listings and over 13,000 car dealers in its network. iCar Asia, which is listed on the Australian stock exchange,<a href="https://www.techinasia.com/icar-asia-reveals-acquisition-proposal-chinas-autohome"> announced last year</a> that it had received a takeover offer from China-based online auto marketplace Autohome.</p>
<p>In a press statement, Carsome co-founder and group chief executive officer Eric Cheng said the deal “is the first step toward consolidation to form the largest digital automotive group in terms of revenue, user base, largest live listing and the best end-to-end fulfilment capacity in the region.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KZKqQdvN5E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/the-roadmap-to-startup-consolidation-in-southeast-asia-is-becoming-clearer/">The roadmap to startup consolidation in Southeast Asia is becoming clearer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The roadmap to startup consolidation in Southeast Asia is becoming clearer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/the-roadmap-to-startup-consolidation-in-southeast-asia-is-becoming-clearer/embed/#?secret=KZKqQdvN5E" data-secret="KZKqQdvN5E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/carsome-group-will-acquire-icar-asia-in-a-deal-worth-200m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176554</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vara raises $4.8M from investors like Go Ventures and Sequoia India&#8217;s Surge to digitize Indonesian SMEs&#8217; payrolls</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vara-raises-4-8m-from-investors-like-go-ventures-and-sequoia-indias-surge-to-digitize-indonesian-smes-payrolls/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vara-raises-4-8m-from-investors-like-go-ventures-and-sequoia-indias-surge-to-digitize-indonesian-smes-payrolls/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 03:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[staff management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vara]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you follow startup news from Indonesia, you know that the country’s estimated 60 million small businesses are a hot target for tech companies. BukuKas and BukuWarung, for example, both recently raised large rounds to fuel their race to digitize SMEs’ operations. Founded in November 2020, Vara is focused specifically on making staff management easier [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2176545" style="width: 2232px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176545" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2176545 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png" alt="A Zoom group screenshot of Vara's team" width="2222" height="1000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png 2222w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png?resize=150,68 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png?resize=300,135 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png?resize=768,346 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png?resize=680,306 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png?resize=1536,691 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png?resize=2048,922 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Team-Photo.png?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2222px) 100vw, 2222px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2176545" class="wp-caption-text">Staff management platform Vara&#8217;s team</p></div></p>
<p>If you follow startup news from Indonesia, you know that the country’s <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-fintech-can-help-indonesias-small-and-medium-enterprises-survive-the-covid-19-pandemic-148528">estimated 60 million small businesses</a> are a hot target for tech companies. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/">BukuKas</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/">BukuWarung</a>, for example, both recently raised large rounds to fuel their race to digitize SMEs’ operations. Founded in November 2020, <a href="https://varaapp.com/">Vara</a> is focused specifically on making staff management easier for small businesses and their workers, replacing the notebooks or spreadsheets many relied on to keep track of payroll with an app called Bukugaji.</p>
<p>The company announced today it has raised $4.8 million in seed funding from Go Ventures, RTP Global, AlphaJWC, Sequoia Capital India’s Surge, FEBE Ventures and Taurus Ventures. Founded by Vidush Mahansaria and Abhinav Karale, who met while studying at the Wharton School at the University of Pennsylvania, Vara is part of the Surge accelerator program’s fifth cohort of startups. It says more than 100,000 small businesses are already using Bukugaji.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The app has features to track attendance, calculate salaries and worker loans and disburse payroll. Mahansaria told TechCrunch that Bukugaji is aimed at companies that have less than 30 employees. Many of them are in retail, food and beverage or labor-heavy service sectors like construction and transportation. Bukugaji has features for specific employee segments, like operational staff who usually work in shifts, or permanent staff whose paychecks are fixed over a specific time period.</p>
<p>“Before downloading and onboarding on Bukugaji, the vast majority of our users utilized notebooks to mark attendance and track payroll,” Mahansaria said. “A small portion used the notes features on their phones or simple Excel sheets.” Bukugaji is designed to be fully self-service, so businesses can download and start using the app on their own. Its main app is mobile only, but the platform also has a web version.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FvdF7YND4i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/">BukuKas gets $50M from investors including DoorDash&#8217;s Gokul Rajaram and TransferWise founder Taavet Hinrikus</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BukuKas gets $50M from investors including DoorDash&#8217;s Gokul Rajaram and TransferWise founder Taavet Hinrikus&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/bukukas-gets-50m-from-investors-including-doordashs-gokul-rajaram-and-transferwise-co-founder-taavet-hinrikus/embed/#?secret=FvdF7YND4i" data-secret="FvdF7YND4i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The businesses Bukugaji serves often have workers who are unbanked, meaning they don’t have access to a bank account or traditional financial services. Vara’s founders say many of them live paycheck to paycheck and this means they sometimes have to take out loans from their employers.</p>
<p>“Employees often request cash advances from their employers toward the end of the month, when they need the money the most because sometimes they can’t make ends meet,” said Mahansaria. “This has two outcomes: first, it ties up working capital for the employer. Second, it makes the employee increasingly reliant on the employer to meet emergency needs. It’s hard to break out of this cycle given the current limited accessibility to formal financial infrastructure for this market segment.”</p>
<p>Earned wage access (EWA) platforms are focused on solving this problem by giving employees on-demand access to wages, instead of having to wait for their paycheck. EWA companies are gaining traction around the world, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/wagely-an-indonesian-earned-wage-access-and-financial-services-platform-raises-5-6m/">Wagely</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/gajigesa-a-fintech-startup-serving-underbanked-indonesian-workers-raises-2-5-million-seed-round/">GajiGesa</a> in Indonesia. Vara doesn’t have immediate plans to add an EWA feature to Bukugaji, but it is something the company is thinking about as part of the value-additive services it will build into the platform.</p>
<p>“Owning end-to-end payroll and attendance gives us an information edge that is unparalleled for this labor segment,” Mahansaria said, noting that the data can enable companies to add things like benefits that their employees usually don’t have access to, and in turn give workers a digitally-verified work history.</p>
<p>In the near future, Bukugaji will add time-saving features like automated allowances and overtime, dashboard shortcuts, reminders and customizable reports. It also plans to allow employers to disburse salaries directly through the platform. Over the longer term, Bukugaji will offer data analytics to companies and their workers. For example, employees will also be able to see how their earnings have changed over time. Employers, meanwhile can spot trends in attendance and salary.</p>
<p>Though Vara may eventually expand into markets, Mahansaria said it is currently “razor-focused on Indonesia,” where <a href="https://www.thejakartapost.com/academia/2020/07/17/smes-safeguard-economy.html">SMEs account </a>for about 60% of the country’s gross domestic product and employ the vast majority of its workforce.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UiUhPV7xbD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/">BukuWarung, a fintech for Indonesian MSMEs, scores $60M Series A led by Valar and Goodwater</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BukuWarung, a fintech for Indonesian MSMEs, scores $60M Series A led by Valar and Goodwater&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/bukuwarung-a-fintech-for-indonesian-msmes-scores-60m-series-a-led-by-valar-and-goodwater/embed/#?secret=UiUhPV7xbD" data-secret="UiUhPV7xbD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vara-raises-4-8m-from-investors-like-go-ventures-and-sequoia-indias-surge-to-digitize-indonesian-smes-payrolls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176541</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nasir Qadree just announced one of the largest debut funds for a solo VC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/nasir-qadree-grew-up-in-the-projects-now-hes-announcing-one-the-largest-debut-funds-for-a-solo-vc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/nasir-qadree-grew-up-in-the-projects-now-hes-announcing-one-the-largest-debut-funds-for-a-solo-vc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 02:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debut fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176364</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nasir Qadree entered the world of venture capital six years ago, beginning with a role at Village Capital in Washington, then as an associate director of social investments at AT&#38;T. Qadree encountered even more opportunities to join established venture firms recently. In fact, he says that after deciding early last year to embark on launching [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nasir Qadree entered the world of venture capital six years ago, beginning with a role at Village Capital in Washington, then as an associate director of social investments at AT&amp;T.</p>
<p>Qadree encountered even more opportunities to join established venture firms recently. In fact, he says that after deciding early last year to embark on launching his own firm &#8212; and garnering capital commitments for it &#8212; he became quite interesting to investors who tried bringing him aboard their own organizations.</p>
<p>He gets it, he says. &#8220;I think it&#8217;s great that organizations want to find new lines of business through their connections with fund managers who have differentiated sourcing and who will yield, I&#8217;d imagine, a more diversified portfolio.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Still, he wasn&#8217;t going to hitch his wagon to another firm once he got going. &#8220;Venture capital is a wealth-creating business,&#8221; says Qadree. &#8220;I&#8217;m a first-generation college student. I grew up in the projects [and became] president&#8221; of numerous student-led organizations at his alma mater, Hampton University.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think it&#8217;s up to someone like myself and people who are constantly being asked these questions to have strong conviction around how to think about building your franchise. I&#8217;ve been through so much to get to this point that to give up my equity, give up my branding and ideas&#8221; was not going to happen, he says.</p>
<p>Qadree&#8217;s bet on himself appears to be paying off. His Washington-based venture firm, <a href="https://www.zealvc.co/">Zeal Capital Partners</a>, today announced that it has closed its oversubscribed subscribed first fund with $62.1 million, making it one of the largest funds to be raised by a solo general partner to date. It was initially targeting $25 million.</p>
<p>That Qadree&#8217;s pitch resonated so widely isn&#8217;t surprising. Zeal is focused primarily on two sectors that are being reshaped fast: financial tech and the future of work. The themes play neatly into the firm&#8217;s overarching thesis around inclusive investing, meaning in this case that the startups which interest Zeal need in some way to address the yawning economic inequality in the U.S.</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s <a href="https://www.zealvc.co/portfolio">current portfolio</a> &#8212; it has announced five investments publicly &#8212; offers a flavor of what&#8217;s to come. For example,<a href="https://www.kanarys.com/"> Kanarys</a>, is a three-year-old SaaS platform that provides metrics to help companies prioritize and optimize diversity, equity, and inclusion efforts in the workplace. Zeal led its <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/kanarys-boosts-diversity-equity-inclusion-platform-following-3m-seed/">$3 million seed round</a>, joined by Revolution&#8217;s Rise of the Rest seed fund and others.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, three-year-old <a href="https://esusurent.com/">Esusu</a> automates credit building by reporting its customers&#8217; monthly rent payments to credit bureaus in an effort to boost their credit score. The app also allows users to pool and withdraw money for big-ticket transactions, then reports the fulfillment of those obligations to credit bureaus to improve their credit profiles. Forbes <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/ruthumoh/2020/08/26/minority-owned-fintech-app-esusu-closes-23-million-seed-round-announces-plans-to-address-credit-inequality/?sh=13d5c1ee28db">wrote about the company</a> &#8212; which has raised $4 million in seed funding &#8212; last August.</p>
<p>Kanary and Esusu&#8217;s founders are Black, as is Qadree. But Qadree isn&#8217;t exclusively funding Black founders or Latino founders or women-led teams (though women founders currently represent 40% of the portfolio). While he says he is leaning into empowering founders who have been underrepresented in the tech world for decades, &#8220;being Black doesn&#8217;t mean we will only fund Black and brown entrepreneurs.&#8221;</p>
<p>He says he is far more focused on ensuring that a team has a specific strategy to evolve (quickly) into a more diverse group if it doesn&#8217;t start that way. Says Qadree, &#8220;If you&#8217;re building out a fintech company that&#8217;s rethinking FICO scores and you&#8217;re an all-white team, you have to show us that diversifying your management team is top of mind, that you recognize your blind spot.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zeal is also focused on founders who are outside of major tech hubs like the Bay Area, New York, and Boston. These &#8220;secondary markets&#8221; as Qadree calls them (using air quotes during a Zoom call), are just as important to Zeal&#8217;s mission around inclusive investing. &#8220;We want to level the playing field geographically so that an entrepreneur in Nashville or Detroit receives their fair share of investment capital, just as the Harvard grad who lives in Silicon Valley and is an alum of Google.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zeal&#8217;s new fund is anchored by investors Truist and Paypal, with additional investments from Synchrony Financial, the Skoll Foundation, Foot Locker, DC’s RockCreek, Hampton University Endowment, Southern New Hampshire University, and Gary Community Investment.</p>
<p>It also counts as investors numerous individuals who are also advising the firm, including NEA cofounder Frank Bonsal and Wes Moore, the former CEO of the Robin Hood Foundation (and current gubernatorial candidate in Maryland).</p>
<p>Not last, Qadree has brought into the fold several operating partners, including Rachel Williams, who is the head of equity, inclusion and diversity at X, the &#8220;moonshot factory&#8221; that is part of Alphabet; and Kam Syed, a senior sales and business development exec at Amazon.</p>
<p><em>Pictured above, left to right: Andy Will, a senior associate with Zeal; Nicole Wardlaw, an analyst with the firm; Nasir Qadree; Nicole West, an executive in residence who was formerly a managing director with Legg Mason; and Jason Green, who cofounded SkillSmart and is also now an executive in residence with Zeal.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/nasir-qadree-grew-up-in-the-projects-now-hes-announcing-one-the-largest-debut-funds-for-a-solo-vc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176364</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whisper Aero emerges from stealth to quiet drones and air taxis</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/whisper-aero-emerges-from-stealth-to-quiet-drones-and-air-taxis/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/whisper-aero-emerges-from-stealth-to-quiet-drones-and-air-taxis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerial ridesharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archer Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joby Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber Elevate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban air mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The skies are on the cusp of getting busier — and louder — as drone delivery and electric vertical take-off and landing passenger aircraft startups move from moonshot to commercialization. One former NASA engineer and ex-director of Uber&#8217;s air taxi division is developing tech to ensure that more air traffic doesn&#8217;t equal more noise. Mark [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The skies are on the cusp of getting busier — and louder — as drone delivery and electric vertical take-off and landing passenger aircraft startups move from moonshot to commercialization. One former NASA engineer and ex-director of Uber&#8217;s air taxi division is developing tech to ensure that more air traffic doesn&#8217;t equal more noise.</p>
<p>Mark Moore, who was most recently director of engineering at Uber Elevate until its acquisition by Joby Aviation, has a launched his own company called <a href="http://whisper.aero">Whisper Aero</a>. The startup, which came out of stealth this week, is aiming to designing an electric thruster it says will blend noise emitted from delivery drones and eVTOLs alike into background levels, making them nearly imperceptible to the human ear.</p>
<p>It’s a formidable challenge. Solving the noise problem comes down to more than simply cranking down the volume. Noise profiles are also characterized by other variables, like frequency. For example, helicopters have a main rotor and tail rotor that generate two separate frequencies, which makes them much more irritating to the human ear than if they were at a single frequency, Moore told TechCrunch in a recent interview.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Complicating the picture even further is that eVTOL companies are designing entirely new types of aircraft, ones that may generate different acoustic profiles than other rotorcraft (like helicopters). The U.S. Army recently undertook a research study confirming that eVTOL rotors generate more of a type of noise referred to as broadband, rather than tonal noise which is generated by helicopters. And as each eVTOL company is developing its own design, not all of the electric aircraft will generate the same level or kind of noise.</p>
<p>Whisper is designing its scalable product to be adoptable across the board.</p>
<p>Moore said the idea for the company had been fomenting for years. He and Whisper COO Ian Villa, who headed strategy and simulation at Elevate, realized years ago that noise (that is, less of it) was key to air taxis taking off.</p>
<p>“The thing that was abundantly clear was, noise matters most,” Villa said. “It is the hardest barrier to break through. And not enough of these developers were spending the time, the resources, the mindshare to really unlock that.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176470" style="width: 3850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176470" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2176470 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg" alt="" width="3840" height="5760" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Whisper-Aero-Mark-1.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 3840px) 100vw, 3840px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176470" class="wp-caption-text">Whisper CEO Mark Moore. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://whisper.aero" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Whisper Aero <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Helicopters have mostly been able to get away with their terrible noise profile because they are used so infrequently. But eVTOL companies like Joby Aviation are envisioning far higher ride volumes. Moore is quick to point out that companies like Joby (which purchased Elevate at the end of 2020) are already developing aircraft that are many times quieter than helicopter, and are “a step in the right direction.”</p>
<p>“The question is, &#8216;is it enough of a step to get to significant adoption?&#8217; And that’s what we’re focused on.”</p>
<p>Whisper is staying mum on the details of its thruster design. It has managed to attract around $7.5 million investment from firms like Lux Capital, Abstract Ventures, Menlo Ventures, Kindred Ventures and Robert Downey Jr.’s FootPrint Coalition Ventures. It’s also aiming to convert its provisional patents with the United States Patent and Trademark Office sometime next year.</p>
<p>From there, the startup envisions launching in the small drone market around 2023, before scaling progressively up to air taxis. Moore said the goal is to get the thrusters manufactured and in vehicles by the end of the decade. Should the first generation of eVTOL go to market in 2024 (as Archer Aviation and Joby have proposed), Whisper’s product could potentially appear in second generation eVTOL.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Whisper will continue testing and working out remaining technical challenges – least among which is how to manufacture the end product at a reasonable cost. Whisper is also preparing to conduct dynamic testing in a wind tunnel, in addition to the static tests it has undertaken at its Tennessee headquarters, some in partnership with the U.S. Air Force.</p>
<p>“It’s got to be quiet enough to blend into the background noise,” Moore said. “We know this and that’s the technology we’re developing.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/whisper-aero-emerges-from-stealth-to-quiet-drones-and-air-taxis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vaayu&#8217;s carbon tracking for retailers raises $1.6M, claims it could cut CO2 in half by 2030</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vaayus-carbon-tracking-for-retailers-raises-raises-1-6m-claims-it-could-cut-co2-in-half-by-2030/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vaayus-carbon-tracking-for-retailers-raises-raises-1-6m-claims-it-could-cut-co2-in-half-by-2030/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 23:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapitalT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vaayu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webflow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zalando]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carbon tracking is very much the new hot thing in tech, and we’ve previously covered more generalist startups doing this at scale for companies, such as Plan A Earth out of Berlin. But there’s clearly an opportunity to get deep into a vertical sector and tailor solutions to it. That’s the plan of Vaayu, a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Carbon tracking is very much the new hot thing in tech, and we’ve previously covered more generalist startups doing this at scale for companies, such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/softbank-demeter-and-coparion-invest-3m-into-plan-as-b2b-carbon-monitoring-and-esg-platform/">Plan A Earth out of Berlin</a>.</p>
<p>But there’s clearly an opportunity to get deep into a vertical sector and tailor solutions to it.</p>
<p>That’s the plan of <a href="https://www.vaayu.tech/">Vaayu</a>, a carbon tracking platform aimed specifically at retailers. It has now raised $1.57 million in pre-seed funding in a round led by <a href="https://www.capitaltvc.com/">CapitalT</a>. Several angels also took part, including Atomico’s Angel Program, Planet Positive LP, Saarbrücker 21, Expedite Ventures and NP-Hard Ventures.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Carbon tracking for the retail fashion industry, in particular, is urgently needed. Unfortunately, the fashion industry remains <a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2019/09/23/costo-moda-medio-ambiente">responsible</a> for 10% of annual global carbon emissions, which ads up to more than all international flights and maritime shipping combined.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GsTbyAd83r"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/softbank-demeter-and-coparion-invest-3m-into-plan-as-b2b-carbon-monitoring-and-esg-platform/">SoftBank, Demeter and Coparion invest $3M into Plan A&#8217;s B2B carbon monitoring and ESG platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank, Demeter and Coparion invest $3M into Plan A&#8217;s B2B carbon monitoring and ESG platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/softbank-demeter-and-coparion-invest-3m-into-plan-as-b2b-carbon-monitoring-and-esg-platform/embed/#?secret=GsTbyAd83r" data-secret="GsTbyAd83r" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Vaayu says it integrates with various point-of-sale systems, such as Shopify and Webflow. It then pulls in data on logistics, operations and packaging to monitor, measure and reduce their carbon emissions. Normally, retailers calculate emissions once a year, which is obviously far less accurate.</p>
<p>Vaayu was founded in 2020 by Namrata Sandhu (CEO), former head of Sustainability at fashion retailer Zalando, as well as Anita Daminov (CPO) and Luca Schmid (CTO). Vaayu currently has 25 global brand customers, including Missoma, Armed Angels and Organic Basics.</p>
<p>Commenting on the fundraise, Sandhu said: &#8220;We have only nine short years left to achieve the UN’s goal of reducing carbon emissions by 50% by 2030 and as the third-largest contributor to global emissions, retailers need to take action &#8212; and fast. Vaayu is here to help retailers measure, monitor, and reduce their carbon footprint at scale across the entire supply chain &#8212; something that I know from my own experience can be complex and expensive.&#8221;</p>
<p>Speaking to me over a call, Sandhu told me: “Putting the focus on retail basically allows us to automate the calculation, which means in three clicks you can get your carbon footprint right away. That then allows us to really get accurate data, and with that, we can basically do reductions specific to the business but using software, rather than any kind of manual intervention or a kind of ‘intermediate’ state where you need to put together an Excel sheet. Because we focus on retail we can automate the entire process and also automate the reductions.”</p>
<p>“We are delighted to be backed by female-led CapitalT who understood us and our vision right from the start. We look forward to developing Vaayu further in the coming months so we can reach as many retailers as possible and help put the brakes on the impending climate crisis,” she added.</p>
<p>Janneke Niessen, founding partner, CapitalT commented: “We are very excited to join Vaayu on their mission to reduce carbon emission for retailers worldwide. The Vaayu product is very scalable and its quick and easy implementation allows for fast adoption. We are confident that with this experienced team, Vaayu will soon be one of the fastest-growing climate tech companies in Europe and the world.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/vaayus-carbon-tracking-for-retailers-raises-raises-1-6m-claims-it-could-cut-co2-in-half-by-2030/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176459</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Flipkart raises $3.6 billion, setting another record for Indian startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/daily-crunch-30/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/daily-crunch-30/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for July 12, 2021. You likely spent yesterday watching a football game, watching a space plane or both. We have a little bit more on the latter than the former today in the newsletter, but <a href="https://twitter.com/HKane/status/1414639048031805441">we can all agree with this</a> regardless of whether you were waving an English or Italian flag yesterday. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/flipkart-valued-at-37-6-billion-in-new-3-6-billion-fundraise/">Flipkart now worth $37.6B:</a> </strong>An anticipated investment into Flipkart has come to be, with the Indian e-commerce player raising some $3.6 billion in a single deal. It’s a massive round and a huge endorsement of the larger Indian startup ecosystem. Now we have just to wait for the company to go public!</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/11/virgin-galactic-and-richard-branson-celebrate-launch-of-first-passengers-into-space/"><strong>Virgin Galactic goes to space (mostly):</strong></a><strong> </strong>Quite a few folks tuned into the Virgin Galactic rocket-plane space dalliance this weekend. The production had a few hiccoughs and more than a few self-indulgent moments that could have been edited out, but largely went off without a hitch. The recently SPAC’d former startup quickly decided to raise a half-billion dollars after its success. Unlike its space tourism vehicle, however, shares of Virgin Galactic did not take off on the news.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/eat-the-rich-but-let-them-build-rockets-in-the-meantime/"><strong>Let the billionaires fight:</strong></a> Your humble servant dove into the controversy surrounding the current contest between various billionaires building space companies and fighting to be the first to various space feats. Tax the rich, I think, but let them fight it out in the meantime.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>We have our regular list of funding rounds in a moment, but today we’re kicking off our startup coverage with this headline from earlier today: “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elevate-brands-banks-250m-to-roll-up-third-party-merchants-selling-on-amazons-marketplace/">Elevate Brands banks $250M to roll up third-party merchants selling on Amazon’s marketplace</a>.”</p>
<p>The headline should feel somewhat familiar as we’ve seen comparable bits of news from other groups. As our own <a href="https://twitter.com/ingridlunden">Ingrid Lunden</a> reports, we’ve seen <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/">similar deals from Thrasio</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/berlins-razor-group-raises-400m-to-buy-and-scale-amazon-marketplace-merchants/">The Razor Group</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/target-global-leads-150m-round-for-amazon-marketplace-consolidator-branded/">Branded</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/sellerx-raises-118m-to-buy-up-and-grow-amazon-marketplace-businesses/">SellerX</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/perch-raises-123-5m-to-grow-its-stable-of-d2c-brands-that-sell-on-amazon/">Perch</a> and others. The idea of buying up smaller Amazon retailers is such a potentially lucrative wager that kajillions of dollars are flooding the zone. How many winners that we will see is the next question.</p>
<p>Now, back to our regularly scheduled programming:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/gembah-raises-11m-to-democratize-product-innovation/"><strong>Gembah wants to make product creation easier:</strong></a> The Austin-based startup now has $11 million to follow its vision. How does it go about meeting its mission? By building a platform/marketplace that helps guide users through the work of product creation. Did we need more stuff? Probably. Gembah wants to help.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/indian-financial-services-firm-mobikwik-looks-to-raise-255-million-in-ipo/"><strong>India’s next tech IPO:</strong></a><strong> </strong>This time it’s MobiKwik, a mobile wallet startup that is targeting a $255 million IPO. We have some of its financials, including that revenue in its most recent fiscal year dipped to $40.5 million. So, it’s a smaller company, but we do love seeing IPOs regardless of their scale.</li>
</ul>
<p>To close out startup coverage today, fake toys. If you’ve been on Twitter today there’s a good chance that you’ve seen folks posting pictures of toys that look like failed tech products. Think Theranos’ unit or the Juicero machine.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Grand Duke <a href="https://twitter.com/panzer">Matthew Panzarino</a> wrote that an “idea factory/art house” called MSCHF is making the “hardness of hardware” more real by selling Dead Startup Toys made of vinyl.</p>
<p>Don’t laugh. This is actually somewhat neat. Think of this: Don’t you want a fake, small Juicero on your desk to throw at the wall here and there when you get mad? I do.</p>
<h2>The most important API metric is time to first call</h2>
<p>Publishing an API isn&#8217;t enough for any startup: Once it&#8217;s released, the hard work of cultivating a developer base begins.</p>
<p>Postman&#8217;s head of Developer Relations, Joyce Lin, wrote a guest post for Extra Crunch based on the findings of a study aimed at increasing adoption of APIs that utilize a public workspace.</p>
<p>Lin found that the most important metric for a public API is time to first call (TTFC). It makes sense — faster TTFC allows developers to begin using new tools quickly. As a result, &#8220;legitimately streamlining TTFC results in a larger market potential of better-educated users for the later stages of your developer journey,&#8221; writes Lin.</p>
<p>This post isn&#8217;t just for the developers in our audience: TTFC is a metric that product and growth teams should also keep top of mind, they suggest.</p>
<p>&#8220;Even if your market is defined as a limited subset of the developer community, any enhancements you make to TTFC equate to a larger available market.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="M2XXLXyIb5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-most-important-api-metric-is-time-to-first-call/">The most important API metric is time to first call</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The most important API metric is time to first call&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-most-important-api-metric-is-time-to-first-call/embed/#?secret=M2XXLXyIb5" data-secret="M2XXLXyIb5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>There was a lot going on with the larger tech companies of the world today, so let’s dive right in:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/android-12-will-let-you-play-games-before-they-finish-downloading/">A modest improvement to Android:</a> </strong>If you are running Android 12, you will be able to start playing games a bit faster in the future. Google just announced a feature that will allow users to launch new games before they are fully downloaded. This has been accessible for some PC games for a while, but it’s nice to see on the mobile platform. That said, we’re really at the end of the innovation cycle for the current era of smartphones.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/microsoft-to-acquire-riskiq/">Microsoft buys more cybersecurity:</a></strong> Microsoft confirmed earlier reports that it was looking to buy RiskIQ. The price was not disclosed, but Bloomberg previously reported that it would be more than $500 million in cash. On the podcast this morning, we noted that that wasn’t a huge price for Microsoft, though the larger company has a huge vested interest in more folks being more secure.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elon-musk-defends-teslas-2-6b-acquisition-of-solarcity-in-delaware-court/">Elon defends the SolarCity deal</a>:</strong> Today’s MuskWatch is all about a deal from the past. Namely the Tesla-SolarCity deal that was worth $2.6 billion. Some shareholders call the deal a bailout. Musk blamed various factors for what could be called underperformance at his car company’s solar division.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/controversial-whatsapp-policy-change-hit-with-consumer-law-complaint-in-europe/">WhatsApp takes flak in Europe:</a> </strong>Facebook’s ability to annoy regulators is a global affair, with the company being accused of “multiple breaches of European Union consumer protection law as a result of its attempts to force WhatsApp users to accept controversial changes to the messaging platforms’ terms of use,” TechCrunch reports.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We’re reaching out to startup founders to tell us who they turn to when they want the most up-to-date growth marketing practices. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Read one of the recommendations we’ve received below!</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong>Maya Moufarek, <a href="https://marketingcube.co/">Marketing Cube</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommender: </strong>Nikki O’Farrell<strong>, </strong><a href="http://www.katkin.club">www.KatKin.club</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommendation: </strong>“Expert ear and eye from the world of startups/scaleups and growth. Her functional and direct approach allows you to execute at speed and see results quickly.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/daily-crunch-30/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176373</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 advanced-ish SEO tactics to win in 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/5-advanced-ish-seo-tactics-to-win-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/5-advanced-ish-seo-tactics-to-win-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Marketing Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine optimization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web analytics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In nearly every Google algorithm update in recent memory, Google has rewarded old, megatraffic sites, sending their search rankings soaring at the expense of smaller, newer sites.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mark Spera</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/growthmktingpro">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mark Spera is the head of growth marketing at <a href="https://www.minted.com/">Minted</a>. He's the co-founder of growth marketing blog <a href="https://www.growthmarketingpro.com/">Growth Marketing Pro</a> and content generation tool <a href="https://growthbarseo.com/">GrowthBar</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/5-companies-doing-growth-marketing-right/">5 companies doing growth marketing right</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In nearly every Google algorithm update in recent memory, Google has rewarded old, megatraffic sites, sending their search rankings soaring at the expense of smaller, newer sites. Big sites have increased their search traffic by 28% year over year, according to <a href="https://growthbarseo.com/">GrowthBar</a>’s organic search data on the 100 most visited sites.</p>
<p>Why? Large sites such as Wikipedia, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Amazon, Home Depot and Target have something the rest of us don’t — they’ve got years of built-up Google trust signals.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Start with best practices like making incredible content and securing backlinks to your best web pages, but also be willing to think a bit outside the box.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>I’d contend that Google favors large sites more than ever before — and it’s a trend that doesn’t seem to be slowing down. After all, Google exists to deliver the best search experience to users. Bad search results would be a death sentence for their business, since Googlers would flock to alternatives like DuckDuckGo and Bing.</p>
<p>Especially today, where distrust of the media is at an <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/andymeek/2021/02/20/fewer-americans-than-ever-before-trust-the-mainstream-media/?sh=6d3ef34e282a">all-time high</a>, Google can’t risk its reputation by surfacing bad search results, so I think their algorithm errs on the side of caution. It’s simply safer for their business to surface household names at the top of the search engine results page, particularly in ultrasensitive <a href="https://ignitevisibility.com/ymyl-pages-what-are-ymyl-google-seo-pages/">your money, your life</a> categories.</p>
<p>John Mueller, Google’s SEO mouthpiece, practically settled the debate that older sites are preferred by the algorithm when he said, &#8221; … freshness is always an interesting one because it’s something that we don’t always use. Because sometimes it makes sense to show people content that has been established (<a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/why-old-pages-rank-google/288919/">SEJ</a>).&#8221;</p>
<p>So, how can you hope to compete if you’re deploying an SEO strategy on one of the billions of smaller sites?</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Of course, you should start with best practices like making incredible content and <a href="https://www.growthmarketingpro.com/how-to-get-backlinks-to-your-site-for-seo/">securing backlinks</a> to your best web pages, but you should also be willing to think a bit outside the box. The cards aren’t in your favor, so you need to be even more strategic than the big guys. This means executing on some cutting-edge hacks to increase your SEO throughput and capitalize on some of the arbitrage still left in organic search. I call these five tactics &#8220;advanced-ish,&#8221; because none of them are complicated, but all of them are supremely important for search marketers in 2021.</p>
<h2>Scaling your time with content generators</h2>
<p>Businesses spent over <a href="https://www.cision.com/resources/tip-sheets/2018-the-ultimate-list-of-content-marketing-statistics/">$300 billion</a> on content marketing last year. That’s in part because creating new content is the most straightforward way to draw in organic search traffic. Whether you’ve got a mature site or you’re just starting a <a href="https://kinsta.com/blog/wordpress-seo/">WordPress SEO site</a>, content is likely a large part of your SEO strategy.</p>
<p>But to scale content like a startup, you’ll need to devote a lot of time to it and/or manage a fleet of writers. Your time is probably better spent building your product or helping customers than on planning hundreds of blog articles. This is precisely where a <a href="https://growthbarseo.com/blog/the-best-content-generators-for-every-business-need/">content generator</a> tool comes into play.</p>
<p>A whole new era of <a href="https://www.growthmarketingpro.com/best-seo-software-tools/">SEO tools</a> is emerging, and some of these are augmented by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/openai-makes-an-all-purpose-api-for-its-text-based-ai-capabilities/">OpenAI’s GPT-3</a> technology, the most advanced artificial intelligence language model. These tools have changed the game for SEOs and content creators by automating parts of the content creation cycle. Several tools utilize SEO signals and combine them with OpenAI to help you create blog outlines that include SEO-optimized titles, word counts, keywords, headlines, intro paragraphs and much more.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/5-advanced-ish-seo-tactics-to-win-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176360</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Q3 IPO cycle starts strong with Couchbase pricing and Kaltura relisting</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/q3-ipo-cycle-starts-strong-with-couchbase-pricing-and-kaltura-relisting/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/q3-ipo-cycle-starts-strong-with-couchbase-pricing-and-kaltura-relisting/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[couchbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaltura]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Both bits of news should help us get a handle on how the Q3 2021 IPO cycle is shaping up at the start.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today we have new filings from Couchbase and Kaltura: Couchbase <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001845022/000119312521212359/d73036ds1a.htm">set</a> an initial price range for its IPO, something we&#8217;ve been waiting for, and Kaltura&#8217;s offering is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/kaltura-puts-debut-on-hold-is-the-tech-ipo-window-closing/#:~:text=This%20morning%2C%20Kaltura%2C%20a%20technology%20company%20that%20provides,expected.%E2%80%9D%20The%20Exchange%20explores%20startups%2C%20markets%20and%20money.">back from hiatus</a> with a new price range and some fresh financial information to boot.</p>
<p>Both bits of news should help us get a handle on how the Q3 2021 IPO cycle is shaping up at the start.</p>
<p>TechCrunch has long expected the third quarter&#8217;s IPO haul to prove strong; investors said as 2020 closed that quarters one, three and four would prove very active in terms of public market exits this year. Then the second quarter surpassed expectations, with more companies going public than at least some market observers anticipated.</p>
<p>With that in mind, you can imagine why the newly launched Q3 could prove an active period.</p>
<p>So! Let&#8217;s start with a dig into the filing from NoSQL provider Couchbase, working to understand its first price range and what the numbers may say about market demand for technology debuts. Here&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/what-does-red-hats-sale-to-ibm-tell-us-about-couchbases-valuation/">our first look at the company&#8217;s value</a>. Then we are taking <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/kaltura-puts-debut-on-hold-is-the-tech-ipo-window-closing">the Kaltura saga back up</a>, checking into the pricing and second-quarter results from the technology company that provides video-streaming software and services.</p>
<p>Frankly, I&#8217;ve been waiting for these filings to drop. So, let&#8217;s cut the chat and get into the numbers:</p>
<h2>Couchbase&#8217;s IPO price range</h2>
<p>In its <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001845022/000119312521212359/d73036ds1a.htm">new S-1/A filing</a>, Couchbase reports that it anticipates a $20 to $23 per share IPO price. With a maximum sale of just over 8 million shares, Couchbase could raise as much as $185.15 million in its public offering.</p>
<p>The company will have 40,072,801 shares outstanding after its IPO, not including 1,050,000 shares that are reserved for possible release. The math from here is simple. To calculate Couchbase&#8217;s possible <em>simple</em> IPO valuation we can just do a little multiplication:</p>
<ul>
<li>Couchbase simple valuation at $20 per share: ~$802 million.</li>
<li>Couchbase simple valuation at $23 per share: ~$922 million.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want to include the company&#8217;s reserved shares, add $21 million to the first figure, and $24.2 million to the second. Notably, TechCrunch wrote before it priced that using a historical analog from the Red Hat-IBM sale &#8212; both Couchbase and Red Hat work in the OSS space &#8212; the company would be worth around $900 million. So, we were pretty close.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/q3-ipo-cycle-starts-strong-with-couchbase-pricing-and-kaltura-relisting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176252</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bambee founder talks about entrenched fundraising challenges facing Black founders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/bambee-founder-talks-about-entrenched-fundraising-challenges-facing-black-founders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/bambee-founder-talks-about-entrenched-fundraising-challenges-facing-black-founders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 19:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allan Jones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bambee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HR software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMBs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2172788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Allan Jones dropped out of college and spent a decade learning how to run a startup. In 2016, that education resulted in the launch of Los Angeles-based Bambee, which helps small companies by acting as their HR department with the goal of keeping them in compliance with government rules and regulations. But he found getting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Allan Jones dropped out of college and spent a decade learning how to run a startup. In 2016, that education resulted in the launch of Los Angeles-based <a href="http://bambee.com">Bambee</a>, which helps small companies by acting as their HR department with the goal of keeping them in compliance with government rules and regulations.</p>
<p>But he found getting funded a challenge in spite of his background. He said that as a Black man, he had to move more carefully in the startup world.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think it came as part of the complexities of navigating a mostly white male ecosystem, a mostly straight cis white male ecosystem that either helps you create some skills that make you really effective at the job, or generates so much resentment that it becomes hard to be effective. [&#8230;] I think that I was always one comment away from the opposite direction [I ended up going],&#8221; he explained.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Fortunately, that didn&#8217;t happen, and he kept on climbing and gaining skills and single-handedly founded his own company, one which has reached Series B and raised $33 million, a significant amount of money for any startup, but particularly for a startup run by a Black founder.</p>
<p>A study published by Crunchbase in February found that VC firms distributed $150 billion in venture funding in 2020. Of that, less than 1%, or around $1 billion, went to Black founders. That highlights just how difficult it has been for him to raise from such a limited pool of money in spite of having a great idea and the business skill and acumen to pull it off.</p>
<p>Jones got his start at the age of 20 at a startup called Helio, which targeted the youth market for multimedia services on mobile phones. It was eventually acquired by Virgin Mobile. He went on to run product at a couple of companies before landing as CMO at ZipRecruiter in 2013. He left that position after three years to launch Bambee in 2016.</p>
<p>In spite of all that experience, he felt that as a gay Black man in Silicon Valley that he was continually saddled with the label of &#8220;the kid with potential,&#8221; and not always taken as seriously as his straight white counterparts. &#8220;And I don&#8217;t think those intentions necessarily were bad, I think it was quite the opposite, which actually makes them almost worse because they were entrenched in a bias of how to characterize [my abilities].&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iKAI3lgabN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/blendoor-data-lets-you-know-if-companies-are-living-up-to-diversity-pledges/">Blendoor data lets you know if companies are living up to diversity pledges</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Blendoor data lets you know if companies are living up to diversity pledges&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/blendoor-data-lets-you-know-if-companies-are-living-up-to-diversity-pledges/embed/#?secret=iKAI3lgabN" data-secret="iKAI3lgabN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Jones launched Bambee, a startup that is going after SMBs with fewer than 500 employees, most of which are operating without an HR department, and could be out of compliance with federal mandates because they don&#8217;t have anyone in charge who is aware of the rules.</p>
<p>&#8220;Bambee aims to put an HR manager in every American small business. We&#8217;ve done so by building a model that allows you to hire one on our platform for $99 a month. So you pay us a flat fee and you get access to our platform and your own dedicated HR professional. [&#8230;] She acts as your human resource manager and your human resource arm for your company. And our platform helps keep those companies compliant,&#8221; Jones explained.</p>
<p>Jones says that while he might not encounter direct bias as he builds his business, there is an unconscious bias that investing in Bambee could be riskier than investing in someone who fits the prototypical startup founder mold, and this is especially true in early-stage investing when investors are essentially betting on the entrepreneur.</p>
<p>&#8220;They take bets that they deem as a bit safer &#8212; entrepreneurs that look like a certain profile &#8212; white cis-gender males that come from Stanford and Harvard that match the profile of confidence and they have kind of built in an anti-bias determination around, so they automatically get the benefit of the doubt to those pedigrees, and those profiles,&#8221; Jones said.</p>
<p>He says that means that Black founders have to work that much harder to overcome those biases. Today Bambee has some decent metrics to show investors with revenue reaching tens of millions, growing 300% year over year with thousands of customers across all 50 states, according to Jones. With 100 employees, he plans to double that number by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Even with that, he says there are still barriers to entry he has to deal with. Even if it&#8217;s harder for investors to ignore the company&#8217;s numbers, he still sees a tendency to accentuate the negative.</p>
<p>&#8220;Building a great company with the deficit in belief in you that starts so early on in the venture process, the [obstacles] that you have to [overcome] to get here. It seems impossible with less than 1% of venture capital dollars going to Black founders, and it isn&#8217;t because Black founders don&#8217;t exist, it&#8217;s because the belief in us is not there at scale,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>As Jones continues to build the company, he has learned to look for investors who believe in him and his vision for the company. If he senses that negativity from a potential investor, he moves on because he wants to work with people who want to help build the company and believe in it as much as he does. He says this won&#8217;t change when he goes to raise his C round, a stage few Black entrepreneurs reach.</p>
<p>&#8220;Is it going to be easier for me going forward? I don&#8217;t think so. I think the type of bias that I have to combat based on the class of entrepreneur I&#8217;m becoming, it starts to shift and change, and I&#8217;ve seen that in every round and I&#8217;m prepared for it in my Series C, as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>He says that the progress he&#8217;s made in the company and his belief in the business will help him find the right partners to continue on that journey, just as he has in previous rounds.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will navigate this [&#8230;] and I think we&#8217;ll build a really great business, and ultimately the partners we discover along this journey will be the exact right ones who we were meant to.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="f5vCeaMIRa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/07/why-a-startup-with-10m-in-annual-revenue-took-18-months-to-get-vc-funding/">Why a startup with $10M in annual revenue took 18 months to get VC funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why a startup with $10M in annual revenue took 18 months to get VC funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/07/why-a-startup-with-10m-in-annual-revenue-took-18-months-to-get-vc-funding/embed/#?secret=f5vCeaMIRa" data-secret="f5vCeaMIRa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YDNnKDfkwt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/">On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;On the diversity front, 2020 may prove a tipping point&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/on-the-diversity-front-2020-may-prove-a-tipping-point/embed/#?secret=YDNnKDfkwt" data-secret="YDNnKDfkwt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/bambee-founder-talks-about-entrenched-fundraising-challenges-facing-black-founders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2172788</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Papa co-founder lands seed funding for a second swing in eldercare: UpsideHōM</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/upsidehom-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/upsidehom-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 19:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elder care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freestyle capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jake rothstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Papa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Triple Impact Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UpsideHōM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jake Rothstein is the co-founder of Papa, a Miami-based company that offers care and companionship to seniors. The business, which pairs elderly Americans with uncertified-yet-vetted pals, helps offer casual services, such as technology support, grocery delivery or even a fun conversation. It has raised upwards of $91 million in venture capital to date. While Rothstein [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jakerothstein/">Jake Rothstein</a> is the co-founder of <a href="https://www.joinpapa.com/">Papa</a>, a Miami-based company that offers care and companionship to seniors. The business, which pairs elderly Americans with uncertified-yet-vetted pals, helps offer casual services, such as technology support, grocery delivery or even a fun conversation. It has raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/2137375/">upwards of $91 million in venture capital to date.</a></p>
<p>While Rothstein left day to day responsibilities at Papa in 2017, his experience there gave him a deeper look into the priorities of older adults and families as they go through the aging journey. While Papa was about meeting the elderly where they are, the co-founder began to think of a more complex question: What if &#8220;where they are&#8221; isn’t as supportive as it should be 24/7?</p>
<p>After a stint at another tech company, Rothstein launched a more modern take on senior living communities in January 2020, alongside co-worker turned co-founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-d-badgley">Peter Badgley.</a> <a href="https://www.upsidehom.com/">UpsideHōM</a> is a fully managed, tech-enabled living space for older adults in the United States. After a year of beta testing, the duo announced today that they have raised a $2.25 million seed round for UpsideHōM, led by Triple Impact Capital and Freestyle Capital, with participation from Techstars.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VLLQuUlHi9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/2137375/">Elder tech company, Papa, raises $60M Led by Tiger Global</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Elder tech company, Papa, raises $60M Led by Tiger Global&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/2137375/embed/#?secret=VLLQuUlHi9" data-secret="VLLQuUlHi9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Alongside the funding, UpsideHōM announced its next big bet, dubbed a relaunch, that will sit atop furnished and furnished apartments that sit throughout Raleigh, Atlanta, Jacksonville, Tampa and South Florida: a software platform to take out all the clutter from move-in and maintenance. The platform will give residents one spot to chat with their house manager, pay bills and access perks such as on-demand tech support, house-keeping and companion visits thanks to a partnership with Papa. The company also offers add-on services and amenities, including freshly prepared meals, grocery delivery, fitness programming and accompanied transportation.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176303" style="width: 843px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176303" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2176303" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png" alt="upsidehom-platform" width="833" height="598" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png?resize=768,551 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png?resize=680,488 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png?resize=1536,1103 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png?resize=2048,1471 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Admin-Manangement.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 833px) 100vw, 833px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176303" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> UpsideHōM</p></div></p>
<p>Part of UpsideHōM’s focus is in creating personalized solutions. Elders are diverse in age, needs and financial circumstances &#8212; which means the turnkey solution needs to be easily adaptable to service needs when they pop up. The company needs to be careful though: It can’t offer traditional caregiver services due to state by state compliance; instead Rothstein describes the offerings as supportive services, not in replacement of health assistant caregivers.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176309" style="width: 868px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176309" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2176309" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg" alt="upsidehomhouse" width="858" height="574" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg?resize=768,514 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg?resize=680,455 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg?resize=1536,1028 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/UpsideHōM-2.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 858px) 100vw, 858px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176309" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> UpsideHoM</p></div></p>
<p>When the company first launched, it was betting on a more unconventional idea.</p>
<p>“I thought, let’s solve loneliness even more completely than what Papa is doing by building in companionship,” Rothstein said, instead of letting people order it on demand. The company decided to offer roommate matching services for elders as one of its core services, alongside the aforementioned supported living characteristics. It didn’t fully stick. Over half of inbound participants responded to the marketing efforts by saying that they liked the idea, but didn’t want to share the space. Today, 50% of UpsideHōM&#8217;s business covers individuals or people with spouses or significant others; the other half covers those looking to share units.</p>
<p>The synergies between UpsideHōM and Papa, Rothstein’s previous company, are clear beyond an overlapping customer base. Papa offered up to and almost including actual care, stopping at traditional care-giving services, which require their own vetting and compliance measures. UpsideHōM offers up to and almost including traditional senior living services, but gives supportive services instead of assisted living services, which similarly have their own logistic hurdles to figure out.</p>
<p>As for why Rothstein didn’t just launch supportive living services as a new product vertical within his earlier company, he chalked it up to the &#8220;tremendous&#8221; opportunity in the former, which warranted it’s own company. He also said that customer acquisition looks different between the two companies.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="knjSGKowA7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/">Venture investing in elder tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture investing in elder tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/embed/#?secret=knjSGKowA7" data-secret="knjSGKowA7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“At Papa, what we found was that acquiring customers in this space was incredibly challenging [so we went through] the Medicare Advantage route,” he said. “But senior living is a completely different segment.”</p>
<p>The millions in new venture capital money are coming as UpsideHōM prepares for aggressive growth. While the company did not disclose revenue or total residents, it did say it has hit 1,000% in new resident headcount in the first half of 2021 as a vague proxy. As the startup prepares for its next phase of growth, the co-founders will need to focus heavily on sustainable customer acquisition.</p>
<p>Rothstein thinks that downsizing elders into homes that work for them is a simple argument to make.</p>
<p>“You can age in place for as long as it’s practical, but there&#8217;s going to be a day and time when it&#8217;s not [going to] be practical,” Rothstein said. “Why would you want to make this decision after you&#8217;ve broken your hip, after you run out of money or after your spouse died?”</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s note: A previous version of this story wrote that Rothstein had spent six years scaling Papa. This is incorrect. He left in 2017 but remains an investor in the company. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZeTccKhH2g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/">10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/embed/#?secret=ZeTccKhH2g" data-secret="ZeTccKhH2g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/upsidehom-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176301</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The most important API metric is time to first call</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-most-important-api-metric-is-time-to-first-call/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-most-important-api-metric-is-time-to-first-call/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 18:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web analytics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Legitimately streamlining TTFC results in a larger market potential of better-educated users for the later stages of your developer journey.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Joyce Lin</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/PetuniaGray">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Joyce Lin is head of developer relations at <a href="https://www.postman.com/">Postman</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">API publishers among <a href="https://www.postman.com/">Postman</a>’s community of more than 15 million are working toward more seamless and integrated developer experiences for their APIs. Distilled from hundreds of one-on-one discussions, I recently shared a study on <a href="https://blog.postman.com/increasing-adoption-of-an-api-with-a-public-workspace/">increasing adoption of an API with a public workspace</a> in Postman. One of the biggest reasons to use a public workspace is to enhance developer onboarding with a faster time to first call (TTFC), the most important metric you’ll need for a public API.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			If you are not investing in TTFC as your most important API metric, you are limiting the size of your potential developer base throughout your remaining adoption funnel.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>To understand a developer’s journey, let’s first take a look at factors influencing how much time and energy they are willing to invest in learning your technology and making it work.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Urgency</strong>: Is the developer actively searching for a solution to an existing problem? Or did they hear about your technology in passing and have a mild curiosity?</li>
<li><strong>Constraints</strong>: Is the developer trying to meet a deadline? Or do they have unlimited time and budget to explore the possibilities?</li>
<li><strong>Alternatives</strong>: Is the developer required by their organization to use this solution? Or are they choosing from many providers and considering other ways to solve their problem?</li>
</ul>
<h2>Developer journey to an API</h2>
<p>With that context in mind, the following stages describe the developer journey of encountering a new API:</p>
<h3>Step 1: Browse</h3>
<p>A developer browses your website and documentation to figure out what your API offers. Some people gloss over this step, preferring to learn what your tech offers interactively in the next steps. But judgments are formed at this very early stage, likely while comparing your product among alternatives. For example, if your documentation and onboarding process appears comparatively unorganized and riddled with errors, perhaps it is a reflection of your technology.</p>
<h3>Step 2: Signup</h3>
<p>Signing up for an account is a developer’s first commitment. It signals their intent to do something with your API. Frequently going hand-in-hand with the next step, signing up is required to generate an API key.</p>
<h3>Step 3: First API call</h3>
<p>Making the first API call is the first payoff a developer receives and is oftentimes when developers begin more deeply understanding how the API fits into their world. <a href="https://stripe.com/docs/checkout/integration-builder">Stripe</a> and <a href="https://www.algolia.com/doc/onboarding/#/pick-dataset">Algolia</a> embed interactive guides within their developer documentation to enable first API calls. <a href="https://www.postman.com/stripedev/workspace/stripe-developers/documentation/665823-cb38bcd7-307b-41aa-9282-f4dd72d299a3">Stripe</a> and <a href="https://www.postman.com/twitter/workspace/twitter-s-public-workspace/overview">Twitter</a> also use Postman public workspaces for interactive onboarding. Since many developers already use Postman, experiencing an API in familiar territory gets them one step closer to implementation.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/the-most-important-api-metric-is-time-to-first-call/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176259</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cutting out carbon emitters with bioengineering at XTC Global Finals on July 22</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/cutting-out-carbon-emitters-with-bioengineering-at-xtc-global-finals-on-july-22/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/cutting-out-carbon-emitters-with-bioengineering-at-xtc-global-finals-on-july-22/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 16:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algiknit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative protein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bioengineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotechnology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultured meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jennifer Holmgren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LanzaTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orbillion Bio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bioengineering may soon provide compelling, low-carbon alternatives in industries where even the best methods produce significant emissions. Utilizing natural and engineered biological process has led to low-carbon textiles from AlgiKnit, cell-cultured premium meats from Orbillion and fuels captured from waste emissions via LanzaTech — and leaders from those companies will be joining us onstage for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Bioengineering may soon provide compelling, low-carbon alternatives in industries where even the best methods produce significant emissions. Utilizing natural and engineered biological process has led to low-carbon textiles from AlgiKnit, cell-cultured premium meats from Orbillion and fuels captured from waste emissions via LanzaTech — and leaders from those companies will be joining us onstage <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extreme-tech-challenge-global-finals-presented-by-techcrunch?ref=aa110dd2add8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for the Extreme Tech Challenge Global Finals on July 22</a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re co-hosting the event, with panels like this one all day and a pitch-off that will feature a number of innovative startups with a sustainability angle.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be moderating a panel on using bioengineering to create change directly in industries with large carbon footprints: textiles, meat production and manufacturing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.algiknit.com/">AlgiKnit</a> is a startup that is sourcing raw material for fabric from kelp, which is an eco-friendly alternative to textile crop monocultures and artificial materials like acrylic. CEO Aaron Nesser will speak to the challenge of breaking into this established industry and overcoming preconceived notions of what an algae-derived fabric might be like (spoiler: it&#8217;s like any other fabric).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.orbillion.com/">Orbillion Bio</a> is one of the new crop of alternative protein companies offering cell-cultured meats (just don&#8217;t call them &#8220;lab&#8221; or &#8220;vat&#8221; grown) to offset the incredibly wasteful livestock industry. But it&#8217;s more than just growing a steak — there are regulatory and market barriers aplenty that CEO Patricia Bubner can speak to, as well as the technical challenge.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.lanzatech.com/">LanzaTech</a> works with factories to capture emissions as they&#8217;re emitted, collecting the useful particles that would otherwise clutter the atmosphere and repurposing them in the form of premium fuels. This is a delicate and complex process that needs to be a partnership, not just a retrofitting operation, so CEO Jennifer Holmgren will speak to their approach convincing the industry to work with them at the ground floor.</p>
<p>It should be a very interesting conversation, so tune in on July 22 to hear these and other industry leaders focused on sustainability discuss how innovation at the startup level can contribute to the fight against climate change. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extreme-tech-challenge-global-finals-presented-by-techcrunch?ref=aa110dd2add8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Plus it&#8217;s free!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/cutting-out-carbon-emitters-with-bioengineering-at-xtc-global-finals-on-july-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Android 12 will let you play games before they finish downloading</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/android-12-will-let-you-play-games-before-they-finish-downloading/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/android-12-will-let-you-play-games-before-they-finish-downloading/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google stadia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[play store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its Game Developer Summit, Google today announced a new feature for Android game developers that will speed up by almost 2x the time from starting a download in the Google Play store to the game launching &#8212; at least on Android 12 devices. The name of the new feature, &#8220;play as you download,&#8221; pretty [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At its Game Developer Summit, Google today announced a new feature for Android game developers that will speed up by almost 2x the time from starting a download in the Google Play store to the game launching &#8212; at least on Android 12 devices. The name of the new feature, &#8220;play as you download,&#8221; pretty much gives away what this is all about. Even before all the game&#8217;s assets have been downloaded, players will be able to get going.</p>
<p>On average, modern games are likely the largest apps you&#8217;ll ever download, and when that download takes a couple of minutes, you may have long moved on to the next TikTok session before the game is ever ready to play. With this new feature, Google promises that it&#8217;ll take only half the time to jump into a game that weighs in at 400MB or so. If you&#8217;re a console gamer, this whole concept will also feel familiar, given that Sony pretty much does the same thing for PlayStation games.</p>
<p>Now, this isn&#8217;t Google&#8217;s first attempt at making games load faster. With &#8220;<a href="https://developer.android.com/topic/google-play-instant">Google Play Instant</a>,&#8221; the company already offers a related feature that allows gamers to immediately start a game from the Play Store. The idea there, though, is to completely do away with the install process and give potential players an opportunity to try out a new game right away.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Like Play Instant, the new &#8220;play as you download&#8221; feature is powered by Google&#8217;s <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/06/the-future-of-android-app-bundles-is.html">Android App Bundle format,</a> which is, for the most part, replacing the old APK standard</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176169" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Google_Play_As_You_Download_Mid.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176169" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2176169" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Google_Play_As_You_Download_Mid.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="857" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2176169" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/android-12-will-let-you-play-games-before-they-finish-downloading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176165</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
