<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 11:34:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Hyundai buys controlling interest in Boston Dynamics</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/hyundai-buys-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/hyundai-buys-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 11:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyundai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPOT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s official. Boston Dynamics is becoming part of the Hyundai family (pending regulatory approval, naturally). The Waltham, Massachusetts-based robot maker confirmed that the South Korean technology company is acquiring controlling interest in a press release today. The deal, which values the company at $1.1 billion, gives Hyundai Motor Group an 80% stake, with SoftBank controlling [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s official. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/boston-dynamics" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="boston-dynamics">Boston Dynamics <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is becoming part of the Hyundai family (pending regulatory approval, naturally). The Waltham, Massachusetts-based robot maker confirmed that the South Korean technology company is acquiring controlling interest in <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/hyundai-motor-group-to-acquire-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics-from-softbank-group-opening-a-new-chapter-in-the-robotics-and-mobility-industry-301191028.html">a press release</a> today. The deal, which values the company at $1.1 billion, gives Hyundai Motor Group an 80% stake, with SoftBank controlling the remaining 20%.</p>
<p>The transaction marks the Spot-maker’s third change of hands in a mere seven years. After nearly a quarter-century operating as a research firm (with some big financial help from organizations like DARPA), it sold to Google in 2013, becoming part of a new robotics wing led by then-executive Andy Rubin.</p>
<p>After Google X Robotics was largely dissolved, Boston Dynamics changed hands in 2017, becoming a subsidiary of Japanese investment giant, Softbank. It was an odd fit for the company, and a rough year for Softbank likely hasn’t helped matters. At very least, Hyundai is a more logical home for the company, after being owned by a firm whose best-known robot is Pepper, the humanoid hospitality ‘bot.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iSxz07VGq1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/hyundai-reportedly-in-talks-to-buy-softbank-owned-boston-dynamics/">Hyundai reportedly in talks to buy SoftBank-owned Boston Dynamics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hyundai reportedly in talks to buy SoftBank-owned Boston Dynamics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/09/hyundai-reportedly-in-talks-to-buy-softbank-owned-boston-dynamics/embed/#?secret=iSxz07VGq1" data-secret="iSxz07VGq1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As we noted while reporting on earlier rumors about the acquisition, Hyundai has been making some big investments in the category. The list includes a recent joint venture with Aptiv to commercialize autonomous driving systems. There’s also the recently announced ultimate mobility vehicles or UMV – a borderline sci-fi vehicle with legs.</p>
<p>“Boston Dynamics’ commercial business has grown rapidly as we&#8217;ve brought to market the first robot that can automate repetitive and dangerous tasks in workplaces designed for human-level mobility,&#8221;CEO Rob Playter said in a release tied to the deal. &#8220;We and Hyundai share a view of the transformational power of mobility and look forward to working together to accelerate our plans to enable the world with cutting edge automation, and to continue to solve the world’s hardest robotics challenges for our customers.”</p>
<p>Boston Dynamics, of course, has been blurring the lines between science fiction and reality for several decades now. More recently, however, it’s taken a much stronger interest in commercializing its advanced technologies. Under Softbank, the company launched Spot, a quadruped robot that draws on years of robotic innovation, including the iconic Big Dog.</p>
<p>Spot went up for sale last year in limited quantities. It’s now available for anyone in the U.S. with $74,500 burning a hole in their pocket. The company is also pushing to commercialize its wheeled Handle robot for warehouse and fulfillment related purposes. That robot is due out some time next year. While the sophistication and resulting price tags for the company’s robots have drawn a fair bit of skepticism, investors have taken increased interest in robots and automation firms in the wake of year-long COVID-19-related shutdowns.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hyundai Motor Group will provide Boston Dynamics a strategic partner affording access to Hyundai Motor Group’s in-house manufacturing capability and cost benefits stemming from efficiencies of scale,&#8221; according to the release. &#8220;Boston Dynamics will benefit substantially from new capital, technology, affiliated customers, and Hyundai Motor Group’s global market reach enhancing commercialization opportunity for its robot products.&#8221;</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close in by June.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SmuMBj3xv2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/24/boston-dynamics-puts-its-robotic-quadruped-spot-up-for-sale/">Boston Dynamics puts its robotic quadruped Spot up for sale</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Boston Dynamics puts its robotic quadruped Spot up for sale&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/24/boston-dynamics-puts-its-robotic-quadruped-spot-up-for-sale/embed/#?secret=SmuMBj3xv2" data-secret="SmuMBj3xv2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/hyundai-buys-controlling-interest-in-boston-dynamics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085203</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sweden&#8217;s Tink raises $103M as its open banking platform grows to 3,400 banks and 250M customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/swedens-tink-raises-103m-as-its-open-banking-platform-grows-to-3400-banks-and-250m-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/swedens-tink-raises-103m-as-its-open-banking-platform-grows-to-3400-banks-and-250m-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 08:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tink]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Open banking platforms, where services that might not have previously lived next to each other are now joined up by way of APIs, has been one of the emerging trends of the last couple of years, and today one of the leaders in the space out of Europe has closed a round of funding to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Open banking platforms, where services that might not have previously lived next to each other are now joined up by way of APIs, has been one of the emerging trends of the last couple of years, and today one of the leaders in the space out of Europe has closed a round of funding to expand its business.</p>
<p><a href="http://tink.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tink</a>, a startup out of Stockholm, Sweden that aggregates a number of banks and financial services by way of an API so that those can in turn be accessed via new channels, has raised €85 million (or $103 million at current rates), at a post-money valuation of €680 million (or around $825 million). It plans to use the capital to double down on expanding its network of banks and payment services in Europe. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tink" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tink">Tink <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> already links up 3,400 banks, covering some 250 million people, with partners including PayPal, NatWest, ABN AMRO, BNP Paribas, Nordea and SEB, some of which are also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/03/tink-paypal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">strategic investors</a>. On the other side, it has some 8,000 developers using its APIs.</p>
<p>This latest tranche of funding is being co-led by new investor Eurazeo Growth and Dawn Capital, with PayPal Ventures, HMI Capital, Heartcore, ABN AMRO Ventures, Poste Italiane and BNP Paribas’ venture arm, Opera Tech Ventures, also participating.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding comes less than a year after it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/19/tink-raises-e90m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced a round of €90 million</a> ($105 million) in January 2020, and is more specifically an extension of that round. For context, that previous round was at a €415 million ($503 million) valuation, and the company has definitely grown since then: in January it said it had 2,500 banking partners in its network. It has now raised €175 million in total.</p>
<p>The last year &#8212; shaped by a global health pandemic &#8212; has been all about bringing more services online and into the cloud, in order for people and businesses that can no longer do things like banking or selling/shopping in person can still get things done. That has most definitely played out strongly in the world of financial services, with banks, bank competitors, and their tech partners seeing a surge in demand for more flexible, digital channels.</p>
<p>“Despite the difficulties of 2020, it was a year of great growth for Tink,&#8221; said Daniel Kjellén, co-founder and CEO of Tink, in a statement. &#8220;2020 has seen payments powered by open banking take-off, and in 2021 we expect to see this scale – most prominently in the UK, followed by Europe. This funding extension will further facilitate the development of our payment initiation services across Europe, while continuing to deliver new data-products built on open banking technology to our customers.”</p>
<p>Tink is not the only company that is looking to capitalize on this. Just earlier this week, another startup, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/unit-raises-18-6m-to-offer-banking-features-as-a-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Unit, came out of stealth with $18.6 million in funding</a>. It also has ambitions to provide a way to integrate banking features, and banks, into environments where they might have not previously existed. Others also linking up financial services and helping them integrate into other platforms and apps include Plaid and Rapyd.</p>
<p>Plaid is in the process of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/13/visa-is-acquiring-plaid-for-5-3-billion-2x-its-final-private-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">getting acquired by Visa</a> for $5.3 billion, although that deal is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/doj-files-antitrust-lawsuit-challenging-visas-5-3-billion-acquisition-of-plaid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">currently under antitrust scrutiny</a>. Rapyd remains VC-backed and was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/rapyd-which-offers-fintech-as-a-service-via-a-single-api-adds-20m-more-to-its-coffers-at-a-1-2b-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">last valued at $1.3 billion</a>. The proliferation and growth of these might prove to be a strong argument in favor of the market not being sewn up by Plaid (no pun intended), although having one owned by a single payments giant would definitely shift how the market is evolving.</p>
<p>&#8220;The open banking movement continues to pick up pace, with 2021 showing every sign that it will bring increased collaboration between fintechs and large enterprises, who want to take digitally enabled services to their customers with a tried and trusted partner,&#8221; said Zoé Fabian, MD of Eurazeo Growth, in a statement. &#8220;Since its inception eight years ago, Tink has proven itself to be the leading open banking platform in Europe, and our investment underlines the confidence we and the industry have in Tink and open banking. We look forward to supporting them on their continued journey.”</p>
<p>Tink&#8217;s business is based around payment initiation technology, providing easy integrations into existing banking services, and then making a commission on transactions that subsequently take place. The company said that it currently processes around 1 million payment transactions per month in five markets.</p>
<p>Although it doesn&#8217;t specify the value of those transactions, or how much it makes itself, it notes that current customers include Kivra, a digital mailbox provider with 4 million adults in Sweden; and, as of earlier this year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/07/lydia-partners-with-tink-to-improve-open-banking-features/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">payment fintech Lydia</a>, with over 5 million customers. It is live in Sweden, UK, France, Spain, Germany, Italy, Portugal, Denmark, Finland, Norway, Belgium, Austria and the Netherlands and the plan is to expand to 10 markets in 2021.</p>
<p>While the company will be using the funding to expand partnerships and its footprint, it&#8217;s also not shying away from inorganic growth. This year it made no less than three acquisitions to expand its business &#8212; a sign also of how there is likely more consolidation to come as not every company can find the scale and funding to grow in the current market. Tink&#8217;s acquisitions included Swedish credit decisioning firm Instantor, to expand in credit risk products; Spanish account aggregation provider Eurobits, and UK aggregation platform OpenWrks.</p>
<p>“Tink has truly emerged as Europe&#8217;s leading open banking platform and is quickly becoming a key strategic piece of financial technology infrastructure,&#8221; said Josh Bell, General Partner of Dawn, in a statement. &#8220;We have seen activity across Tink&#8217;s network rapidly accelerate this year, with increasing adoption and implementation of open banking products and services across their platform. We are delighted to support Tink’s latest funding round, and look forward to working with the team across 2021 to expand the breadth and depth of its already considerable network of banks, accelerate the rollout of its account-to-account payments initiation solutions, and continue to deliver exceptional value to its fast-growing customer base.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/swedens-tink-raises-103m-as-its-open-banking-platform-grows-to-3400-banks-and-250m-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cosmos Video &#8211; a &#8216;Club Penguin for adults&#8217; to socialise and work &#8211; raises $2.6M  from LocalGlobe</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/cosmos-video-a-club-penguin-for-adults-to-socialise-and-work-raises-2-6m-from-localglobe/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/cosmos-video-a-club-penguin-for-adults-to-socialise-and-work-raises-2-6m-from-localglobe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 08:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angellist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citymapper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Club-Penguin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groupware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommunications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teleconferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video conferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual world]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All over the world startups are piling into the space marked “virtual interaction and collaboration”. What if a startup created a sort of &#8216;Club Penguin for adults&#8217;? Step forward Cosmos Video, which has a virtual venues platform that allows people to work, hang out and socialize together. It has now raised $2.6m in seed funding [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">All over the world startups are piling into the space marked “virtual interaction and collaboration”. What if a startup created a sort of &#8216;Club Penguin for adults&#8217;?</p>
<p>Step forward <a href="http://cosmos.video">Cosmos Video</a>, which has a virtual venues platform that allows people to work, hang out and socialize together. It has now raised $2.6m in seed funding LocalGlobe with participation from Entrepreneur First, Andy Chung and Phillip Moehring (AngelList), and Omid Ashtari (former President of Citymapper).</p>
<p>Founders Rahul Goyal and Karan Baweja previously led product teams at <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/citymapper-limited" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="citymapper-limited">Citymapper <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and TransferWise respectively.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Cosmos allows users to create virtual venues by combining game mechanics with video chat. The idea is to bring back the kinds of serendipitous interactions we used to have in the real world. You choose an avatar, then meet up with their colleagues or friends inside a browser-based game. As you move your avatars closer to one another person you can video chat with them, as you might in real life.</p>
<p>The competition is the incumbent video conferencing platforms such as Zoom and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/microsoft" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="microsoft">Microsoft <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Teams, but calls on these platforms have a set agenda, and are timeboxed &#8211; they’re rigid and repetitive. On Cosmos you sit on the screen and consume one video call after another as you move around the space, so it is mimicking serendipity, after a fashion.</p>
<p>As well as having a social application, office colleagues can work collaboratively on tools such as whiteboards, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> documents and Figma; play virtual board games or gather around a table to chat.</p>
<p>Cosmos is currently being used in private beta by a select group of companies to host their offices and for social events such as Christmas parties. Others are using it to host events, meetup groups and family gatherings.</p>
<p>Co-founder Rahul Goyal said in a statement: “Once the pandemic hit, we both saw productivity surge in our respective teams but at the same time, people were missing the in-office culture. Video conferencing platforms provide a great service when it comes to meetings, but they lack spontaneity. Cosmos is a way to bring back that human connection we lack when we spend all day online, by providing a virtual world where you can play a game of trivia or pong after work with colleagues or gather round a table to celebrate a friend’s birthday.”</p>
<p>George Henry, partner, LocalGlobe: “We were really impressed with the vision and potential of Cosmos. Scaling live experiences online is one of the big internet frontiers where there are still so many opportunities. Now that the video infrastructure is in place, we believe products like Cosmos will enable new forms of live online experiences.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/cosmos-video-a-club-penguin-for-adults-to-socialise-and-work-raises-2-6m-from-localglobe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085774</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Massachusetts governor won&#8217;t sign police reform bill with facial recognition ban</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/massachusetts-governor-returns-police-reform-bill-asking-lawmakers-to-drop-facial-recognition-ban/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/massachusetts-governor-returns-police-reform-bill-asking-lawmakers-to-drop-facial-recognition-ban/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 23:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[george floyd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[massachusetts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video surveillance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Massachusetts Governor Charlie Baker has returned a police reform bill back to the state legislature, asking lawmakers to strike out several provisions — including one for a statewide ban on police and public authorities using facial recognition technology, the first of its kind in the United States. The bill, which also banned police from using [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Massachusetts Governor Charlie Baker has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/massachusetts-votes-to-pass-statewide-police-ban-on-facial-recognition/">returned a police reform bill</a> back to the state legislature, asking lawmakers to strike out several provisions — including one for a statewide ban on police and public authorities using facial recognition technology, the first of its kind in the United States.</p>
<p>The bill, which also banned police from using rubber bullets and tear gas, was passed on December 1 by both the state&#8217;s House and Senate after senior lawmakers overcame months of deadlock to reach a consensus. Lawmakers brought the bill to the state legislature in the wake of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/diversity-equity-inclusion-overview/">the killing of George Floyd</a>, an unarmed Black man who was killed by a white Minneapolis police officer, later charged with his murder.</p>
<p>Baker said in a letter to lawmakers that he objected to the ban, saying the use of facial recognition helped to convict several criminals, including a child sex offender and a double murderer.</p>
<p>In an interview <a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/2020/12/10/metro/baker-sends-police-bill-back-legislature-asking-changes/">with The Boston Globe</a>, Baker said that he&#8217;s &#8220;not going to sign something that is going to ban facial recognition.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jdYJ3iy5fv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/diversity-equity-inclusion-overview/">A beginner&#8217;s guide to diversity, equity and inclusion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A beginner&#8217;s guide to diversity, equity and inclusion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/diversity-equity-inclusion-overview/embed/#?secret=jdYJ3iy5fv" data-secret="jdYJ3iy5fv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Under the bill, police and public agencies across the state would be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/massachusetts-votes-to-pass-statewide-police-ban-on-facial-recognition/">prohibited from using facial recognition</a>, with a single exception to run facial recognition searches against the state’s driver license database with a warrant. The state would be required to publish annual transparency figures on the number of searches made by officers going forward.</p>
<p>The Massachusetts House voted to pass by 92-67, and the Senate voted 28-12 — neither of which were veto-proof majorities.</p>
<p>The Boston Globe said that Baker did not outright say he would veto the bill. After the legislature hands a revised (or the same) version of the bill back to the governor, it&#8217;s up to Baker to sign it, veto it or — under Massachusetts law, he could allow it to become law without his signature by waiting 10 days.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unchecked police use of surveillance technology also harms everyone’s rights to anonymity, privacy, and free speech. We urge the legislature to reject Governor Baker&#8217;s amendment and to ensure passage of commonsense regulations of government use of face surveillance,&#8221; said Carol Rose, executive director of the ACLU of Massachusetts.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Baker&#8217;s office did not immediately return a request for comment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FzaSMc7ljr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/massachusetts-votes-to-pass-statewide-police-ban-on-facial-recognition/">Massachusetts lawmakers vote to pass a statewide police ban on facial recognition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Massachusetts lawmakers vote to pass a statewide police ban on facial recognition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/massachusetts-votes-to-pass-statewide-police-ban-on-facial-recognition/embed/#?secret=FzaSMc7ljr" data-secret="FzaSMc7ljr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/massachusetts-governor-returns-police-reform-bill-asking-lawmakers-to-drop-facial-recognition-ban/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085866</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: First impressions of the AirPods Max</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/daily-crunch-first-impressions-of-the-airpods-max/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/daily-crunch-first-impressions-of-the-airpods-max/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 23:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AirPods Max]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We try out Apple&#8217;s new headphones, Spotify resets passwords and Airbnb goes public. This is your Daily Crunch for December 10, 2020. The big story: First impressions of the AirPods Max Our fearless leader Matthew Panzarino has written what he insists is &#8220;not a review&#8221; of the AirPods Max, (not a full review because he&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We try out <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> new headphones, Spotify resets passwords and Airbnb goes public. This is your Daily Crunch for December 10, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: First impressions of the AirPods Max</strong></p>
<p>Our fearless leader Matthew Panzarino has written what he insists is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/this-is-not-a-review-of-apples-new-airpod-max-headphones/">&#8220;not a review&#8221; of the AirPods Max</a>, (not a full review because he&#8217;s had them for less than 24 hours).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Still, Matthew seems impressed by the quality of the build — which you&#8217;d certainly hope to be, since the AirPods Max cost $550, but he says, &#8220;Judging from materials execution alone, the AirPod Max feels like it should be <em>more</em> expensive if anything.&#8221;</p>
<p>And yes, the sound quality is solid, too.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/spotify-resets-user-passwords-after-a-bug-exposed-private-account-information/">Spotify resets passwords after a security bug exposed users’ private account information</a> — The company blamed a software vulnerability in its systems for exposing private account information to its business partners.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-to-add-covid-19-vaccine-information-panels-to-search/">Google to add COVID-19 vaccine information panels to Search</a> — The new feature will surface a list of authorized vaccines in users’ locations, as well as informational panels about each individual vaccine.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/pinterest-adds-favorites-notes-and-a-new-toolbar-after-increased-use-of-boards-during-pandemic/">Pinterest adds favorites, notes and a new toolbar after increased use of boards during pandemic</a> — According to Pinterest, there’s been a 35% increase in the number of monthly boards created during the last six months.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/leaflink-raises-40m-from-founders-fund-others-to-cultivate-its-cannabis-wholesale-market/">LeafLink raises $40M from Founders Fund, others to cultivate its cannabis wholesale market</a> — This is Founder Fund’s largest technology investment in the cannabis space.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/gorgias-series-b/">Customer support startup Gorgias raises $25M</a> — This brings the startup&#8217;s pre-money valuation to $300 million.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/providing-healthcare-to-lower-income-communities-values-cityblock-health-at-1-billion/">Cityblock Health valued at $1B</a> — Cityblock works with community caregivers to provide low-income residents with primary care, behavioral health and other services.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/">Airbnb’s first-day pop caps off a stellar week for tech IPOs</a> — Airbnb opened this morning at $146 per share, up around 115% to kick off its life as a public company.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/despite-limitations-3d-and-ar-are-creating-new-realities-in-retail/">Despite limitations, 3D and AR are creating new realities in retail</a> — Startups that create digital products and design interactive experiences are thriving.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/as-next-insurance-makes-its-first-acquisition-insurtech-looks-energetic/">As Next Insurance makes its first acquisition, insurtech looks energetic</a> — A snapshot of recent activity in a bustling startup category.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/announcing-the-final-agenda-for-tc-sessions-space-2020/">Announcing the final agenda for TC Sessions: Space 2020</a> — This is a live, virtual two-day conference featuring the most important people in the space industry, across public, private and defense.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/diy-crafting-gifts/">Gift Guide: 8 DIY and crafting gifts to help your friends make more stuff and learn new skills</a> — We’ve put together a wide variety of gifts that should be fun for the makers in your life.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/do-the-celebrities-help-the-startups-or-do-the-startups-help-the-celebrities/">Do the celebrities help the startups or do the startups help the celebrities?</a> — Deep questions on the Equity podcast.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/daily-crunch-first-impressions-of-the-airpods-max/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085920</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Residential renewable energy developer Swell is raising $450 million for distributed power projects in three states</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 23:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electrical grid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar Power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swell Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban.us]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swell Energy, an installer and manager of residential renewable energy, energy efficiency and storage technologies, is raising $450 million to finance the construction of four virtual power plants representing a massive amount of energy storage capacity paired with solar power generation. It&#8217;s a sign of the distributed nature of renewable energy development and a transition [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.swellenergy.com/">Swell Energy</a>, an installer and manager of residential renewable energy, energy efficiency and storage technologies, is raising $450 million to finance the construction of four virtual power plants representing a massive amount of energy storage capacity paired with solar power generation.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a sign of the distributed nature of renewable energy development and a transition from large-scale power generation projects feeding into utility grids at their edge to smaller, point solutions distributed at the actual points of consumption.</p>
<p>The project will pair 200 megawatt hours of distributed energy storage with 100 megawatts of solar photovoltaic capacity, the company said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Los Angeles-based Swell was commissioned by utilities across three states to establish the dispatchable energy storage capacity, which will be made available through the construction and aggregation of approximately 14,000 solar energy generation and storage systems. The goal is to make local grids more efficient.</p>
<p>To finance these projects &#8212; and others the company expects to land &#8212; Swell has cut a deal with Ares Management Corp. and Aligned Climate Capital to create a virtual power plant financing vehicle with a target of $450 million.</p>
<p>That financing entity will support the development of power projects like the combined solar and battery agreement nationwide.</p>
<p>Over the next 20 years, Swell is targeting the development of over 3,000 gigawatt hours of clean solar energy production, with customers storing 1,000 gigawatt hours for later use, and dispatching 200 gigawatt hours of this stored energy back to the utility grid.</p>
<p>It has the potential to create a more resilient grid less susceptible to the kinds of power outages and rolling blackouts that have plagued states like California.</p>
<p>“Utilities are increasingly looking to distributed energy resources as valuable ‘grid edge’ assets,” said Suleman Khan, CEO of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/swell-energy" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="swell-energy">Swell Energy, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> in a statement. “By networking these individual homes and businesses into virtual power plants, Swell is able to bring down the cost of ownership for its customers and help utilities manage demand across their electric grids,” said Khan. “By receiving <i>GridRevenue</i> from Swell, customers participating in our VPP programs pay less for their solar energy generation and storage systems, while potentially reducing the risk of a local power outage, and keeping their homes and businesses securely powered through any outages.”</p>
<p>Along with the launch of the virtual power plant financing vehicle, Swell is also giving homeowners a way to finance their home energy systems through Swell. They need the buy-in from homeowners to get these power plants off the ground, and for homeowners, there&#8217;s a way to get some money back by feeding power into the grid.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a win-win for the company, customers and early investors like Urban.us, which was seed investor in the company.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/residential-renewable-energy-developer-swell-is-raising-450-million-for-distributed-power-projects-in-three-states/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085735</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Disney+ has plans for 10 Marvel shows and 10 Star Wars shows in the next few years</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 22:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[espn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the walt disney company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085874</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Disney just wrapped up the first segment of an investor day in which it laid out its plans for its direct-to-consumer streaming business, including Disney+, Hulu, ESPN+ and Hotstar/Star. The company kicked off the presentation with some new subscriber numbers — 86.8 million for Disney+ (roughly 30% of those are subscribers to Disney+ Hotstar, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Disney just wrapped up the first segment of an investor day in which it laid out its plans for its direct-to-consumer streaming business, including Disney+, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/hulu" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="hulu">Hulu, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> ESPN+ and Hotstar/Star.</p>
<p>The company kicked off the presentation with some new subscriber numbers — 86.8 million for Disney+ (roughly 30% of those are subscribers to Disney+ Hotstar, which<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/02/disney-plus-india-launched-netflix-amazon-prime-video/"> leveraged an existing streaming service in India</a>), 38.8 million for Hulu and 11.5 million for ESPN+, adding up to more than 137 million subscribers across the company&#8217;s streaming business.</p>
<p>The rest of the event is expected to focus on content announcements and previews, but Chairman of Media and Entertainment Distribution Kareem Daniel has already hinted at big plans for the next &#8220;few years.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While high-profile Disney+&#8217;s originals have largely been limited to &#8220;The Mandalorian&#8221; and &#8220;Hamilton&#8221; in year one, Daniels said the company has plans to launch 10 Marvel series, 10 Star Wars series, 15 Disney Animation/Disney live action/Pixar series and 15 Disney Animation/Disney live action/Pixar feature films exclusively on Disney+.</p>
<p>At the same time, Daniel said that Disney remains committed to a variety of distribution strategies, particularly &#8220;theatrical exhibition’s ability to establish major franchises.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FhrWdi4jZu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/disney-73-million-subscribers/">Disney+ has more than 73M subscribers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disney+ has more than 73M subscribers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/disney-73-million-subscribers/embed/#?secret=FhrWdi4jZu" data-secret="FhrWdi4jZu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>He also announced that the Disney Animation film &#8220;Raya and the Dragon&#8221; will follow the same distribution strategy as &#8220;Mulan&#8221; this fall, with the film launching simultaneously in theaters and on Disney+ as a Premier Access release that subscribers will need to pay extra to see.</p>
<p>The presentation also made it clear that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/02/disney-plus-india-launched-netflix-amazon-prime-video/">the Hotstar/Star brand will be key to Disney&#8217;s international growth plans</a>. In Latin America, the company plans to launch a standalone Star+ service, while a new Star section in the Disney+ app will become the home to &#8220;general entertainment&#8221; content (basically, the kinds of content that U.S. viewers will find on Hulu) in other markets like Europe.</p>
<p>Adding a Star section will mean introducing mature content to Disney+, which was previously limited to family-friendly content. So Disney also offered a quick demonstration of new parental controls that will allow subscribers to turn access to more mature content on and off — that should also introduce new content to other parts of Disney+, for example bringing the R-rated film &#8220;Logan&#8221; to the Marvel section.</p>
<p>You can also expect to see more integrations between different Disney streaming services. For example, Star+ will include content from ESPN, while Hulu will introduce the ability to subscribe and watch ESPN+ content directly in the app.</p>
<p>And if you&#8217;re a subscriber to the Disney bundle, which combines Disney+, Hulu and ESPN+ for $12.99 per month, the company plans to add a new tier in January that offers ad-free Hulu for an extra $6 per month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ae4gEOlwkE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/original-content-mandalorian/">Original Content podcast: Disney&#8217;s &#8216;Mandalorian&#8217; is never boring</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Original Content podcast: Disney&#8217;s &#8216;Mandalorian&#8217; is never boring&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/original-content-mandalorian/embed/#?secret=Ae4gEOlwkE" data-secret="Ae4gEOlwkE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> And now we have some details on those shows. On the Star Wars side, they include two series developed by &#8220;Mandalorian&#8221; executive producers Jon Favreau and Dave Filoni — &#8220;Rangers of the New Republic&#8221; and a spinoff focused on Ahsoka Tano, the beloved &#8220;Clone Wars&#8221; character who recently made the jump to live action on &#8220;The Mandalorian.&#8221; Lucasfilm&#8217;s Kathleen Kennedy said the three shows will come together in a &#8220;climactic storytelling event.&#8221;</p>
<p>There will also be previously announced shows focused on &#8220;Rogue One&#8221; character Cassian Andor and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/23/confirmed-disney-is-making-an-obi-wan-series-with-ewan-mcgregor/">Obi-Wan Kenobi</a> — the latter will see the return not just of Ewan McGregor, but also Hayden Christiansen, who played Anakin Skywalker in the prequel trilogy. Plus, a Lando Calrissian series is in the works, as well as &#8220;The Acolyte,&#8221; a series from &#8220;Russian Doll&#8221; writer Leslye Headland.</p>
<p>Kennedy also announced that the next theatrically released Star Wars film will be a Rogue Squadron movie directed by &#8220;Wonder Woman&#8221; director Patty Jenkins, due for release on Christmas 2023.</p>
<p>Beyond Star Wars, Lucasfilm is also developing a &#8220;Willow&#8221; series with Jon M. Chu, plus an adaptation of Tomi Adeyemi&#8217;s &#8220;Childen of Blood and Bone.&#8221; And it plans to start production on the much-delayed fifth Indiana Jones film next spring, with James Mangold directing and Harrison Ford returning, due for release in July 2022.</p>
<p>Non-Marvel, non-Star Wars Disney+ live action shows in development include a &#8220;Mighty Ducks&#8221; sequel with Emilio Estevez and Lauren Graham, a &#8220;Turner and Hooch&#8221; reboot and a &#8220;Swiss Family Robinson&#8221; reboot from Chu and acclaimed &#8220;Battlestar Galactica&#8221; rebooter Ron Moore.</p>
<p>Hulu and FX had a few announcements of their own as well, including a fifth season of &#8220;The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale&#8221; and an &#8220;Alien&#8221; series from Noah Hawley.</p>
<p>Disney will also continue reviving its classic animation titles, with Disney+ Originals including a new version of &#8220;Pinocchio&#8221; directed by Robert Zemeckis and starring Tom Hanks, a new version of &#8220;Peter Pan and Wendy&#8221; and &#8220;Sister Act 3&#8221; with Whoopi Goldberg.</p>
<p>And Pixar has three series coming to Disney+, starting with the &#8220;Up&#8221; spinoff &#8220;Dug Days&#8221; next fall, followed by a &#8220;Car&#8221; series and an original show called &#8220;Win or Lose.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lastly, on the Marvel side, &#8220;WandaVision&#8221; launches on January 15, &#8220;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&#8221; (which Marvel&#8217;s Kevin Feige described as &#8220;a Marvel Studios movie played out over six episodes&#8221;) is coming in March, &#8220;Loki&#8221; in May, &#8220;Ms. Marvel&#8221; sometime next year (and the character will also appear in &#8220;Captain Marvel 2,&#8221; illustrating what Feige called the &#8220;interconnectedness&#8221; of the TV shows and films) and &#8220;Hawkeye&#8221; late next year. Also on the horizon are &#8220;She-Hulk&#8221; with Tatiana Maslany (and Mark Ruffalo returning as the Hulk) and &#8220;Moon Knight.&#8221;</p>
<p>Feige also announced the Disney+ series &#8220;Secret Invasion&#8221; (based on the popular crossover, with Samuel L. Jackson returning as Nick Fury), &#8220;Ironheart&#8221; and an &#8220;Iron Man&#8221; tie-in &#8220;Armor Wars&#8221; with Don Cheadle. And there&#8217;s a &#8220;Guardians of the Galaxy&#8221; holiday special written and directed by James Gunn due out in Christmas 2022.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZvzodxKva1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-will-fuel-international-growth-with-star-brand-and-star-app/">Disney will fuel international growth with Star brand and Star+ app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disney will fuel international growth with Star brand and Star+ app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-will-fuel-international-growth-with-star-brand-and-star-app/embed/#?secret=ZvzodxKva1" data-secret="ZvzodxKva1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085874</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early DoorDash investor Saar Gur makes the case for 10x growth from here</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/early-doordash-investor-dismisses-froth-talk-says-company-could-grow-10x-from-here/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/early-doordash-investor-dismisses-froth-talk-says-company-could-grow-10x-from-here/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 22:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on-demand delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saar Gur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank Vision Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The stunning debut of the food delivery company DoorDash on the public market this week has plenty of people puzzled. While undeniably fast-growing, the unprofitable delivery company has come under fire numerous times over its employment practices, and its IPO, like that of other gig-economy companies, leaves a lot of economic issues unresolved. So why [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">stunning</a> debut of the food delivery company <a href="https://www.doordash.com/en-US">DoorDash</a> on the public market this week has plenty of people puzzled. While undeniably <a href="https://secondmeasure.com/datapoints/food-delivery-services-grubhub-uber-eats-doordash-postmates/">fast-growing</a>, the unprofitable delivery company has come <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/doordash-still-be-pocketing-tips-despite-pay-model-change-2019-8">under fire</a> numerous times over its <a href="https://www.salon.com/2020/01/19/doordash-drivers-make-an-average-of-145-an-hour-analysis-finds/">employment practices</a>, and its IPO, like that of other gig-economy companies, leaves a lot of <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/d75f4dd3-6f48-4fea-93e8-4f60172aa9cf">economic issues unresolved</a>.</p>
<p class="p1">So why is a company that lost $667 million in 2019 and $149 million in the first nine months of 2020 &#8212; during a period of hypergrowth because of the pandemic &#8212; being valued at $55.8 billion by public market investors? Have they lost their minds?</p>
<p class="p1"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/saar-gur" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="saar-gur">Saar Gur <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> thinks he has answers to such questions. Gur, a longtime general partner with the early-stage venture firm <a href="https://crv.com/">CRV</a>, was able to write a check to DoorDash in its earliest rounds, including its seed, Series A and Series B financings, and we gather the firm&#8217;s stake in the business will return multitudes of the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/crvvc" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="crvvc">CRV <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> fund from which those checks came. In short, he&#8217;s very far from biased. However, in a call earlier today, he painted a picture of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/doordash" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="doordash">DoorDash <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> wherein it not only becomes profitable but is 10 times larger than it is today. It was an interesting conversation, one that has been edited lightly for length and clarity.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p id="speakable-summary"><strong>TC: You wrote a seed check to DoorDash. Did you seek out the company or did the team pitch CRV?</strong></p>
<p class="p1">SG: I went on this hunt, looking for Tony. [Rival delivery service] Postmates had started two-and-a-half to three years earlier, and I thought the founder was great [but I wasn&#8217;t sure about investing]. Another company, Fluc, was run by this very scrappy entrepreneur, Adam, who was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/09/27/fluc-a-lyft-for-food-launches-in-san-francisco-and-mountain-view/">getting some buzz</a> in Palo Alto, and I was quite curious and met the team because we were in the food business and knew a lot of restaurant owners; my wife was a food entrepreneur and built this chain of homemade yogurt stores called Fraiche.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WjMuhY0gAO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">DoorDash, C3.ai skyrocket in public market debuts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DoorDash, C3.ai skyrocket in public market debuts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/embed/#?secret=WjMuhY0gAO" data-secret="WjMuhY0gAO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p1">So I emailed my friend Misty, who was the general manager at the time of <a href="https://orenshummus.com/">Oren&#8217;s Hummus</a> on University Avenue [in Palo Alto] and said, &#8216;We&#8217;re looking at this company, Fluc, and we&#8217;d love to get your thoughts.&#8217; And she said, &#8216;The team at Fluc is okay; their technology is better [than some others], but they don&#8217;t understand our problems in a way that&#8217;s truly helpful to us. You should talk to these kids out of Stanford at DoorDash.&#8217;</p>
<p class="p1">If there&#8217;s any skill in investing, it&#8217;s not just confirmation bias of investing in Fluc [whose founders later moved on] but we did a hard pivot and chased down the DoorDash team. We met them at Fraiche in Palo Alto, and from that moment, it was like we were finishing each other&#8217;s sentences.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>TC: What did you talk about?</strong></p>
<p class="p1">SG: The team from day one talked about building a logistics company. For example, they understood Oren&#8217;s Hummus, which at that time was quite popular but had limited front-of-house seating and a big kitchen in the back. And [co-founder and CEO] Tony [Xu] and [co-founder turned VC] <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/who-is-doordash-fourth-cofounder-evan-moore-2020-12">Evan Moore</a> said, &#8216;We want to target customers of popular concepts that have limited [seating] and extra kitchen capacity, and to integrate directly with the kitchen so we don&#8217;t have to interact with front-of-the-house staff.&#8217;</p>
<p>At the time, Postmates had pivoted from waiting in line to get you an iPhone to delivering food, including from Fraiche, but they would send someone to your store, place the order and wait. DoorDash instead put an iPad in the kitchen.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You&#8217;ve said that CRV missed out on Uber, that Travis Kalanick left your offices and headed over to Benchmark, where they wouldn&#8217;t let him leave until he signed a term sheet. Do you think Uber could or should have been DoorDash? I met with Travis in 2011, before DoorDash was founded, and he called Uber a logistics company that <a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:N2vBq1zyuWMJ:https://www.venturecapitaljournal.com/on-a-ride-with-uber/+&amp;cd=3&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us">would deliver food and a lot of other things</a>. Given DoorDash&#8217;s dominant market share, do you think Uber waited too long to jump into deliveries? </strong></p>
<p>SG: The<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> original Uber was not at all about food; it was that ride hailing hadn&#8217;t changed [over time]. Its Series A deck was a picture of a guy holding his hand up and trying to hail a taxi, with no real vision about food &#8212; at least that&#8217;s my recollection. Over time, it became Uber for everything.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But in terms of what happened, DoorDash launched in Palo Alto. A number of other companies were in San Francisco, and Tony and the team had to decide whether to launch in San Francisco as its next major city or whether to launch somewhere else. And after a number of discussions that I was a part of, they focused on San Jose. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Most people don&#8217;t know, but San Jose is something like the 10th largest city in the United States and its layout is much more similar to other mid-tier cities and suburban America than it is to San Francisco. </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">I think that was one key strategic decision. At the time, [larger rivals] Grubhub and Seamless had proven [the model] in dense cities. It was really <em>not</em> obvious that it would work in San Jose or any suburb.</span></p>
<p><strong>TC: Clearly, investors are excited about what DoorDash has built &#8212; so excited that its stock went crazy yesterday. Are you, <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/bill-gurley-doordash-ipo-pop-2020-12">like Bill Gurley</a>, frustrated that money was left on the table by its underwriters? Do you think traditional IPOs are broken?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">SG: I actually started my career at Lehman Brothers on the investment banking team, and so having seen the IPO process, while I can appreciate [frustration that a] company left some money on the table based on the pricing, the tactical challenge [is that] it&#8217;s very hard to predict. You know what the market will bear once it moves to retail investors. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">What&#8217;s exciting to me is [that] DoorDash is raising money because they are just getting started. I do think this could be a $500 billion-plus company. There&#8217;s so much to be excited about. As for the capital-raising event, I think it&#8217;s hard for the bankers to know where it will land with the broader market, so I&#8217;m not as negative as maybe some others.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">TC: Five-hundred billion dollars is a big number. How do you get there?</span></strong></p>
<p>SG: Let&#8217;s just start with food delivery. DoorDash&#8217;s suburban market share has grown to more than 60% and its overall U.S. market share is over 52%, so they&#8217;ve won the market in food delivery. And if you look at the [Chinese shopping platform] Meituan and other global food delivery businesses, that alone paints a path where DoorDash should be [valued at] $100 billion, assuming they continue to execute on the path that they&#8217;re on.</p>
<p>But the bigger story to me is, if you go back to U.S. Postal Service, it used to take two weeks to get a letter. Then FedEx launches and all of a sudden the mail seems slow. The [net promoter score] was really high for the USPS until FedEx launched. Or [think of] dial-up [internet access], which was great until [we had] broadband.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2085912" style="width: 2148px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085912" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2085912 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png" alt="" width="2138" height="1020" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png 2138w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png?resize=150,72 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png?resize=300,143 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png?resize=768,366 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png?resize=680,324 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png?resize=1536,733 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png?resize=2048,977 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-10-at-3.00.00-PM.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2138px) 100vw, 2138px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085912" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> CRV</p></div></p>
<p>What we&#8217;re seeing is that consumers prefer immediacy and this magic ability to press a button and have ice cream delivered in under 25 minutes, or milk, and you start to layer [items on] from there. We&#8217;ve partnered with Macy&#8217;s in December, for example, so if you buy a shirt or a dress, you can now have it at your house in an hour. When you look at the infrastructure that DoorDash has built to deliver on that vision, that&#8217;s where this company looks more like <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="amazon">Amazon <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s dreaming the dream, and that&#8217;s a very different business than ridesharing and Uber&#8217;s core business.</p>
<p><strong>TC: You&#8217;re comparing DoorDash to Amazon, which is a much more capital-intensive business with lots of hard assets. Do you see DoorDash moving in that direction? Relatedly, what kinds of acquisitions would DoorDash be potentially interested in making?</strong></p>
<p class="p1"><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">SG: The company is always focused on technology first. <a href="https://www.doordash.com/drive/portal/discover">DoorDash Drive</a> is a product that many people don&#8217;t understand but it powers merchants that don&#8217;t want to roll out their own delivery network. Say you go to Walmart.com and order a bunch of groceries. DoorDash is powering those deliveries. Macy&#8217;s wants to roll out one-hour delivery. DoorDash Drive is allowing them to do that. DoorDash also now has a product that&#8217;s purely like a SaaS business that enables larger chains that want to control the whole experience of delivery with their own drivers to do that. Jimmy John&#8217;s [a sandwich chain] is now running its entire order and delivery business with their own drivers, using DoorDash software.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">There are parts of DoorDash that are a true software business, just like AWS, and there are parts of it that are capital-intensive, like <a href="https://blog.doordash.com/introducing-dashmart-1891ecc0257d">Dashmart</a> [that rolled out this summer and which are convenience stores are owned and operated by DoorDash]. Will they buy 7-Eleven or something like that? We saw [delivery startup] goPuff <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/">acquire BevMo</a> last month; it&#8217;s not out of the question that there might be a reason to do that. With Dashmart, they already can see a lot of stuff based on data that people want to have immediately.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GjAhsdaYq7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/">Delivery startup goPuff acquires BevMo for $350M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delivery startup goPuff acquires BevMo for $350M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/embed/#?secret=GjAhsdaYq7" data-secret="GjAhsdaYq7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>TC: DoorDash has also ventured into the ghost kitchen market, <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/doordash-ghost-kitchen-silicon-valley-chick-fil-a-photos-2019-11">opening a facility</a> in Redwood City, south of San Francisco. Could this become a bigger initiative?</strong></p>
<p>SG: I think it&#8217;s definitely in the zone. DoorDash can use data and say, you know, you don&#8217;t need to build another Long John Silver or Taco Bell [to get closer to some of your customers]; you use our Redwood City kitchen. We can already show you the data that [highlights how] deliveries that might take an hour could be turned into 15 minutes. They&#8217;re really facilitating the revenue growth of these concepts.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s another set of entrepreneurs where they can use the data to say, for example, &#8216;Hey, there is no pizza restaurant in Palo Alto, so we&#8217;re just going to launch Saar&#8217;s Pizza Company to fill that hole and do it cost-effectively because we don&#8217;t need to build a location out with seating and all the building codes involved serving customers in person.&#8217;</p>
<p><strong>TC: In the meantime, one reads stories of restaurateurs who <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/09/technology/delivery-apps-restaurants-fees-virus.html">complain about the fees</a> involved in working with DoorDash. </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">SG: Having been a restaurant owner, I can tell you, even for my wife, who has a Wharton MBA, it&#8217;s very hard to keep track of all the numbers. You feel like everyone is screwing you; it&#8217;s just really hard to run a small business. So it&#8217;s not based on great data, or even if it is, if you view that DoorDash is adding incremental revenue, and if you understand the concept of marginal profit, then you should continue to sell things as you can make money on the margins of the food and you have the excess kitchen capacity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> If you look, that&#8217;s why DoorDash has signed [roughly] 45 of the top 50 quick-service restaurants. Those are quantitative groups, and they wouldn&#8217;t do it do it for as long as they have and invest in these partnerships if it wasn&#8217;t working. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But there&#8217;s always going to be a sticker shock. </span></p>
<p><strong>TC: Regarding these quick-service restaurants and ghost kitchens, these systems are so efficient that the worry is that mom-and-pop restaurants get wiped out over time. How do you think about that concern?</strong></p>
<p>SG: I think we are<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> social beings and we look for experiences [and] breaking bread with someone is not going away. I think smarter brands will &#8212; just like what we see in retail with physical locations and online locations &#8212; [be both offline and online]. Smarter concepts will understand how to build those brands across channels. And then I still think that the Saisons of the world and The French Laundry will only continue to to do well post-COVID as people look for these experiences of how to be together and share food, which is a passion of many folks.</span></p>
<p><strong>TC: How does DoorDash itself become profitable? </strong></p>
<p>SG: If you check the facts, this summer the company was actually profitable. Not only that, they gave $120 million, or they give credit, to other small businesses, in support of COVID, so had they not done that, they actually would have produced quite a bit of cash.</p>
<p>With a company like DoorDash, you have to sell a big vision and be able to recruit, but you also need to be highly quantitative, and Tony has always been able to spit out numbers that are accurate and set goals that are very quantitative. And while they&#8217;re not profitable in the newer markets [because they are growing], they&#8217;ve got the cohorts to show you not only how they&#8217;re profitable in older markets but how their profitability expands over time in those markets.</p>
<p>At any point, they could kind of slow their growth and become more profitable, but that&#8217;s not the playbook.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/early-doordash-investor-dismisses-froth-talk-says-company-could-grow-10x-from-here/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085710</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FDA panel recommends approving Pfizer&#8217;s COVID-19 vaccine emergency use authorization</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/fda-panel-recommends-approving-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-emergency-use-authorization/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/fda-panel-recommends-approving-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-emergency-use-authorization/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 22:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BioNTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pfizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An independent panel of experts has recommended the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approve an official Emergency Use Authorization (EUA) for the Pfizer and BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine. This means that it&#8217;s one step closer to beginning to be administered to people in special circumstances &#8212; including for front-line healthcare workers dealing with healthcare facilities stressed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">An independent panel of experts has recommended the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approve an official Emergency Use Authorization (EUA) for the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/pfizer" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="pfizer">Pfizer <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine. This means that it&#8217;s one step closer to beginning to be administered to people in special circumstances &#8212; including for front-line healthcare workers dealing with healthcare facilities stressed to the breaking point due to the ongoing and rising pandemic crisis in the U.S., which continues to break grim records for single-day death counts among afflicted patients.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O0uZiWmt8u"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/pfizer-and-biontech-to-submit-request-for-emergency-use-approval-of-their-covid-19-vaccine-today/">Pfizer and BioNTech to submit request for emergency use approval of their COVID-19 vaccine today</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pfizer and BioNTech to submit request for emergency use approval of their COVID-19 vaccine today&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/pfizer-and-biontech-to-submit-request-for-emergency-use-approval-of-their-covid-19-vaccine-today/embed/#?secret=O0uZiWmt8u" data-secret="O0uZiWmt8u" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The Pfizer/BionNTech vaccine is an mRNA vaccine, which means that it provides a set of instructions to a person&#8217;s cells to prompt them to begin creating antibodies that are effective against the SARS-CoV-2 virus that leads to COVID-19. So far, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/pfizer-says-its-covid-19-vaccine-is-95-effective-in-final-clinical-trial-results-analysis/">vaccine has been shown to be 95% effective according to Pfizer&#8217;s own final trial data</a>. Based on the strength of those Phase 3 results, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/pfizer-and-biontech-to-submit-request-for-emergency-use-approval-of-their-covid-19-vaccine-today/">Pfizer applied for an EUA from the FDA toward the end of November</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Already, Pfizer&#8217;s vaccine has been approved for use in other countries, including Canada, where the national health regulator cleared it earlier this week. The FDA&#8217;s EUA process involves reviewing key information about efficacy and safety, and the <a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-holds-advisory-committee-meeting-discuss-authorization-covid-19?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=govdelivery">agency says that it has &#8220;reviewed thousands of pages of technical information&#8221;</a> about the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine, including materials related to its development and manufacturing, as well as the results of its clinical trials to date.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WYb5iTfDmo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/pfizer-says-its-covid-19-vaccine-is-95-effective-in-final-clinical-trial-results-analysis/">Pfizer says its COVID-19 vaccine is 95% effective in final clinical trial results analysis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pfizer says its COVID-19 vaccine is 95% effective in final clinical trial results analysis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/pfizer-says-its-covid-19-vaccine-is-95-effective-in-final-clinical-trial-results-analysis/embed/#?secret=WYb5iTfDmo" data-secret="WYb5iTfDmo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Now that the panel has voted in favor of approval, the FDA will make a final determination on granting the EUA, and that should come within the next few days.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/fda-panel-recommends-approving-pfizers-covid-19-vaccine-emergency-use-authorization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085453</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Disney will fuel international growth with Star brand and Star+ app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-will-fuel-international-growth-with-star-brand-and-star-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-will-fuel-international-growth-with-star-brand-and-star-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 22:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Disney+, the on-demand streaming service that launched a year ago and has already courted over 86 million subscribers, is ready to expand to more international markets. At its annual investor day Thursday, the American entertainment giant announced a new streaming brand called “Star” that will feature content from ABC, FX and 20th Century Studios. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Disney+, the on-demand streaming service that launched a year ago and has already courted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/">over 86 million subscribers</a>, is ready to expand to more international markets.</p>
<p>At its annual investor day Thursday, the American entertainment giant announced a new streaming brand called “Star” that will feature content from ABC, FX and 20th Century Studios.</p>
<p>In some markets, such <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/with-lower-bandwidth-disney-opens-streaming-service-in-uk-ireland-5-other-european-countries-france-to-come-online-april-7/">as Europe</a>, Canada, Singapore, Australia and New Zealand, Star will be unveiled to customers as a new hub within Disney+ app beginning February 20 next year, the company said. It will expand Star to more markets next year, the company said, but it did not identify those markets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Star will come at a price: The company said it will be increasing the monthly subscription price of Disney+ from £5.99 to £8.99 in Europe. The tariff will be similarly adjusted (raised) in every other market where Disney+ subscribers get access to Star, the company said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2085892" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085892" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2085892 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/star-brand.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/star-brand.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/star-brand.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/star-brand.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/star-brand.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/star-brand.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/star-brand.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085892" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Disney</p></div></p>
<p>In Latin America, Star will be a standalone streaming service and offered under the brand name “Star+.” The service will launch there in June 2021, and will feature general entertainment movies and television shows as well as a lineup of live sports &#8212; thanks to ESPN &#8212; including soccer and tennis.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s announcement appears to be an admission that Hulu, another streaming service owned by Disney and which has amassed about 39 million subscribers, might never go international.</p>
<p>Disney also hinted that it plans to expand Disney+ Hotstar, an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/08/disney-plus-hotstar-subscribers-india/">on-demand streaming service it currently offers in India and Indonesia</a>, to more markets, but it did not name those markets. The company said that Disney+ Hotstar accounts for roughly 30% of Disney+’s subscriber base &#8212; which roughly translates to 26 million. Disney+ Hotstar had about 18 million subscribers at the end of September, the company revealed last month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pDZ87ey0CJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/08/disney-plus-hotstar-subscribers-india/">Disney+ Hotstar has about 8 million subscribers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disney+ Hotstar has about 8 million subscribers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/08/disney-plus-hotstar-subscribers-india/embed/#?secret=pDZ87ey0CJ" data-secret="pDZ87ey0CJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Hotstar had millions of subscribers before Disney rebranded the service in India earlier this year. The streaming service became part of Disney <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/20/disney-closes-it-71-3b-fox-acquisition/">as part of the acquisition of Fox</a>, which owned Hotstar-operator Star India (<a href="https://twitter.com/refsrc/status/1337158216392687616">a different Star!</a> Star India operates dozens of TV channels in India and is now owned by Disney.)</p>
<p>Disney has used a similar strategy of relying on existing regional properties and industry collaborations to expand to several other international markets. In France, for instance, the service is available through a partnership with Canal. In Spain, with Moviestar.</p>
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter">
<div class="c-message_kit__gutter__right" data-qa="message_content">
<div class="c-message_kit__blocks c-message_kit__blocks--rich_text">
<div class="c-message__message_blocks c-message__message_blocks--rich_text">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer" data-qa="block-kit-renderer">
<div class="p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper p-block_kit_renderer__block_wrapper--first">
<div class="p-rich_text_block" dir="auto">
<div class="p-rich_text_section">Disney+ Hotstar is priced at $20 a year in India. The company generated an average revenue of about $2.17 per user in India in the quarter that ended in September, it said last month, compared to $5.3 it clocked from Disney+ subscribers in the U.S. during the same period.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="c-message_actions__container c-message__actions" role="group">
<div class="c-message_actions__group" role="group" aria-label="Message shortcuts" data-qa="message-actions"></div>
</div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9ZqGCHSeFu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/">Disney+ has plans for 10 Marvel shows and 10 Star Wars shows in the next few years</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disney+ has plans for 10 Marvel shows and 10 Star Wars shows in the next few years&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-investor-day/embed/#?secret=9ZqGCHSeFu" data-secret="9ZqGCHSeFu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/disney-will-fuel-international-growth-with-star-brand-and-star-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085876</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google will let you turn off YouTube ads for alcohol and gambling</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-youtube-ads-alcohol-gambling/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-youtube-ads-alcohol-gambling/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 22:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gambling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve ever had a Father&#8217;s Day ad offering great deals for your dead dad sail into your inbox, you know that online advertising can be disturbing sometimes. Children&#8217;s gifts for people struggling to get pregnant, pet toys for your deceased doggo, the list goes on. Google is taking a small but helpful step to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you&#8217;ve ever had a Father&#8217;s Day ad offering great deals for your dead dad sail into your inbox, you know that online advertising can be disturbing sometimes. Children&#8217;s gifts for people struggling to get pregnant, pet toys for your deceased doggo, the list goes on.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is taking a small but helpful step to help people control which ads they run into. Starting with YouTube in the U.S., users will be able to toggle off ads for alcohol and gambling — two subjects that are very sensitive for a big swath of people. The new option will roll out to Google Ads and non-U.S. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/youtube" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="youtube">YouTube <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> early next year.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://blog.google/technology/ads/greater-controls-sensitive-ad-topics-your-ad-settings">blog post Thursday</a>, the company said that it would add the option to its ad settings controls, which already allow people to turn off targeted advertising altogether. Technically, Google says that users who opt to limit gambling and booze ads will see &#8220;fewer&#8221; of them, but that language is likely allowing for anything that slips through accidentally.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As a sober person, this is a helpful decision for a lot of people I know who&#8217;d rather not run into booze deals online out of the blue. More of this please!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8z57IkMQ1d"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/08/tempest-virtual-sobriety-school/">Startup says ‘Sober is the new black’</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startup says ‘Sober is the new black’&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/08/tempest-virtual-sobriety-school/embed/#?secret=8z57IkMQ1d" data-secret="8z57IkMQ1d" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-youtube-ads-alcohol-gambling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085855</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Customer support startup Gorgias raises $25M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/gorgias-series-b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/gorgias-series-b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 20:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gorgias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sapphire Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gorgias announced today that it has raised $25 million in Series B funding, bringing the startup&#8217;s pre-money valuation to $300 million. When the company raised its Series A just over a year ago, CEO Romain Lapeyre (who founded Gorgias with CTO Alex Plugaru) told me that it works with e-commerce businesses to automate responses to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.gorgias.com">Gorgias</a> announced today that it has raised $25 million in Series B funding, bringing the startup&#8217;s pre-money valuation to $300 million.</p>
<p>When <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/26/gorgias-series-a/">the company raised its Series A</a> just over a year ago, CEO Romain Lapeyre (who founded Gorgias with CTO Alex Plugaru) told me that it works with e-commerce businesses to automate responses to their most common customer service questions, while also providing tools that help the support team respond more quickly and even convince customers to buy additional products and services.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/gorgias" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="gorgias">Gorgias <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> says it now supports more than 4,500 stores, including Steve Madden, Timbuk2, Fjällräven, Marine Layer, Ellana, Electrolux and Sergio Tacchini. And revenue has grown 200% this year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That may not be surprising, given the overall growth in e-commerce during the pandemic. As Lapeyre put it, merchants saw &#8220;a huge boost&#8221; in online orders, which resulted in a similar rise in customer service requests — so they&#8217;re increasingly turning to Gorgias for help.</p>
<p>Initially, Lapeyre said merchants are just eager to respond to their customers more quickly and to make their support team more efficient. But over time, they become more interested in using customer support &#8220;as way to drive sales.&#8221; In fact, he recalled talking to one business that used to compensate its support team based on response time and now offers them a sales commission.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1916983" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1916983" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1916983" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/basic.png?w=680" alt="Gorgias screenshot" width="680" height="517" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/basic.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/basic.png?resize=150,114 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/basic.png?resize=300,228 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/basic.png?resize=768,584 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/basic.png?resize=680,517 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/basic.png?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1916983" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Gorgias</p></div></p>
<p>He said he expects these trends to continue after the pandemic ends: &#8220;We just jumped five years into the future.&#8221;</p>
<p>Gorgias has now raised a total of $40 million. The new round was led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sapphire-ventures" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sapphire-ventures">Sapphire Ventures, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> with participation from SaaStr, Alven, Amplify Partners, CRV and Greycroft.</p>
<p>Lapeyere said the money will allow Gorgias to continue hiring (it went from a team of 30 people to more 100 people this year), particularly on the engineering side, where it can develop even more automation for the platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;As consumers increasingly shop online, the Gorgias platform powers a new breed of customer support for high-growth e-commerce brands,” said Sapphire Ventures Managing Director Rajeev Dham in a statement. “Co-founder and CEO Romain Lapeyre and team have built an incredible product that provides e-commerce merchants with a single app to manage all of their customer communications — ultimately delivering a far better customer experience.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dMoMXoNg8o"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/26/gorgias-series-a/">Gorgias raises $14M to help e-commerce companies deliver faster (and more lucrative) customer service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gorgias raises $14M to help e-commerce companies deliver faster (and more lucrative) customer service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/26/gorgias-series-a/embed/#?secret=dMoMXoNg8o" data-secret="dMoMXoNg8o" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/gorgias-series-b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085791</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: 8 DIY and crafting gifts to help your friends make more stuff and learn new skills</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/diy-crafting-gifts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/diy-crafting-gifts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 20:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluetooth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crochet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knitting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laser]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crafting and DIY tools are wonderful gifts right now. We're all stuck inside and, for many of us, the days are sort of blurring together. Why not help your friends and family learn to make stuff? And if they already know how to make stuff, why not help them make more stuff?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch&#8217;s 2020 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We&#8217;re here to help! We&#8217;ll be rolling out gift guides from now through the end of December. </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><em>You can find our other guides right here.</em></a></p>
<p>Crafting and DIY tools are wonderful gifts right now. We&#8217;re all stuck inside and, for many of us, the days are sort of blurring together. Why not help your friends and family learn to make stuff? And if they already know how to make stuff, why not help them make <em>more</em> stuff?</p>
<p>It&#8217;ll help break up the monotony, maybe teach them a new skill, and give them something to point at and say &#8220;Hey! I made that!&#8221; Plus, making stuff just rules.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We&#8217;ve put together a wide variety of things that should be fun for the makers in your life. Some are super-focused kits that&#8217;ll help them explore a potential new hobby; others are broadly useful tools they&#8217;ll be able to take with them into every DIY project they take on moving forward. Enjoy!</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</i></p>
<h2>A Dremel kit</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2081551" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081551" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2081551" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg" alt="Dremel Stylo+ kit" width="1024" height="681" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Dremel-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2081551" class="wp-caption-text">Dremel Stylo+ kit. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dremel</p></div></p>
<p>A Dremel is always practical to have around the home for DIY projects. Plus, there are tons of attachments and carving bits available for a huge range of uses. Lighter and more ergonomic than regular Dremels, the Dremel 2050 15 Stylo+ kit includes accessories to get started with wood carving, glass etching, leather burnishing and several other crafts so your recipient can customize almost anything.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $49 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B077Y86FKJ/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B077Y86FKJ&amp;linkId=7198258013d59d73ea23d8791964380f">on Amazon</a></p>
<h2>Soap making kits</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2081549" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081549" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2081549" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg" alt="Bramble Berry soap making kits" width="1000" height="1000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Brambleberry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2081549" class="wp-caption-text">Bramble Berry soap making kits. <strong>Image Credits</strong>: Bramble Berry</p></div></p>
<p>Making cold process soap is fun and rewarding, but as a newbie, it can be daunting to stare at an ingredient list that includes lye, oils, fragrances and pigments. Bramble Berry&#8217;s beginners kits are the perfect way to get started and include everything your recipient needs, including safety googles (EXTREMELY important when handling lye) and a digital scale. Beginner kits include <a href="https://www.brambleberry.com/shop-by-product/kits/soap-making/natural-soap-kit-for-beginners---relaxing-lavender/V700027.html">lavender</a> and <a href="https://www.brambleberry.com/shop-by-product/kits/soap-making/natural-soap-kit-for-beginners---energizing-orange/V700041.html">orange</a> or, for soap makers with a bit more experience, <a href="https://www.brambleberry.com/shop-by-product/kits/soap-making/swirl-handmade-soap-kit---complete-kit/V700024.html">marble-like swirls</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $60 to $150 <a href="https://www.brambleberry.com/">from Bramble Berry</a></p>
<h2>Cricut Explore Air 2</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2085766" style="width: 1035px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085766" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2085766 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Cricut.jpg" alt="" width="1025" height="456" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Cricut.jpg 1025w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Cricut.jpg?resize=150,67 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Cricut.jpg?resize=300,133 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Cricut.jpg?resize=768,342 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Cricut.jpg?resize=680,303 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Cricut.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1025px) 100vw, 1025px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085766" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Cricut</p></div></p>
<p>Anyone who dabbles in crafting and DIY probably already knows what a Cricut is, but if not: it&#8217;s a robot with a friggin&#8217; knife attached to it.</p>
<p>That oversimplifies things a bit, but the Cricut is a device capable of cutting incredibly intricate designs with high precision, fast. It can handle cuts in a few minutes that would take <em>hours</em> to do by hand (and would totally leave your hand cramping.)</p>
<p>Tired of cutting things out? Swap out the blade for a pen, and have it draw or write, instead, or a scoring tool to prep paper projects for any folding they might need. It&#8217;ll help you make greeting cards, or gift boxes, or custom t-shirts, or stickers, or a mountain of other things. Cricut loaned me (Greg) a machine to check out a few weeks ago and I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s been turned off for a full day since.</p>
<p>The Explore Air 2 is the company&#8217;s latest midrange device and can handle cutting paper, vinyl, cardstock, poster board, various fabrics and loads of other thin materials. The free design software that comes with it is way more capable than I expected, and they&#8217;ve got an add-on subscription service that can help you source ready-to-use art until you&#8217;re ready to bring your own. It&#8217;s got built-in Bluetooth for when you want to control it from your iOS or Android device, and can handle materials up to 12&#8243; wide. If you know anyone who already has a Cricut up and running, mats (sticky sheets that hold your material in place while the machine is cutting) and things like vinyl/cardstock are probably welcome stocking stuffers.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><em>(And for anyone who&#8217;s ever thought about getting into laser cutting, the fundamentals are incredibly similar. While I hesitate to recommend anyone randomly buy a laser cutter as a gift because they require training to use safely, a lot of the core knowledge you pick up here — working with vector art, efficiently arranging things on your cutting surface, dealing with different materials, etc — will translate quite easily.)</em></p>
<p><b>Price: </b>$180 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B078WFWM1F/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B078WFWM1F&amp;linkId=31a863b81c71bbb161857aed4e78307f">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2>Electric Eel Wheel Nano</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2081552" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081552" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2081552" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg" alt="Electric Eel Wheel Nano spinning wheel" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_EEWNano.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2081552" class="wp-caption-text">Electric Eel Wheel Nano spinning wheel. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dreaming Robots</p></div></p>
<p>Do you know someone who loves knitting, crocheting or weaving? Chances are if they love working with yarn, they might want to level up to spinning their own yarn. If you have a friend who is curious about spinning, but not ready to commit to a full-sized spinning wheel yet, consider gifting them the compact Electric Eel Wheel Nano. Of course, they’ll need fiber to spin. The Woolery’s hand spinner bundle includes five different kinds of wool so they can decide which one they like best.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $110 for the <a href="https://www.dreamingrobots.com/product/eew-nano">Electric Eel Wheel Nano</a> | $70 for <a href="https://woolery.com/hand-spinner-wool-bundle.html">the wool bundle</a></p>
<h2>Caran D’Ache Neocolor II</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2081553" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081553" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2081553" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg" alt="Caran D'Ache Neocolor II water soluble pastels" width="1024" height="876" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg?resize=150,128 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg?resize=300,257 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg?resize=768,657 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg?resize=680,582 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Neocolor.jpg?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2081553" class="wp-caption-text">Caran D&#8217;Ache Neocolor II water soluble pastels. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Caran D&#8217;Ache</p></div></p>
<p>Caran D’Ache Neocolor II water-soluble pastels are extremely satisfying to work with. First, you lay down a light or thick layer of pigment. Then you can smush it around, like with oil pastels. And <em>then</em> you can brush water over everything to turn it into a vibrant painting. Depending on how Neocolor II is used, it works on many different materials in addition to paper, including glass and textiles (cover designs with a piece of scrap fabric and then heat set it with an iron).</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> Starts at $14.99 for a box of 10 colors<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0009I8LEU/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B0009I8LEU&amp;linkId=5e77356554a5b1dcac0aa686a6e1e7c9"> on Amazon</a></p>
<h2>Apple Pencil</h2>
<p><div style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/appleevent_2015_62.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1280" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>This one really only works if they&#8217;ve already got a relatively recent iPad (or you&#8217;re looking to buy them one of those, too). But if they do, an <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Pencil can really help them take things to the next level. From sketching out ideas in Procreate (also a great gift, if they don&#8217;t have it!), to jotting down measurements in the Notes app, to creating vector art for cutting/etching/t-shirt making, a really good stylus is<em> leagues </em>ahead of just poking at the screen with your finger. It can be a<em> little </em>tricky to determine which Pencil is compatible with which iPad, so you might have to do some sleuthing there.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$99 to $129 <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/select-apple-pencil">from Apple</a>, depending on which one you want.</p>
<h2>Macrame kit</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2081558" style="width: 882px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081558" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-full wp-image-2081558" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png" alt="Modern Macrame's plant hanger kit" width="872" height="1300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png 872w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png?resize=101,150 101w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png?resize=201,300 201w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png?resize=768,1145 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png?resize=456,680 456w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screen-Shot-2020-12-02-at-2.09.02-PM.png?resize=34,50 34w" sizes="(max-width: 872px) 100vw, 872px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2081558" class="wp-caption-text">Modern Macrame&#8217;s plant hanger kit. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Modern Macrame</p></div></p>
<p>Macrame plant hangers are in style and practical. It’s also really easy to learn. Modern Macrame’s <a href="https://modernmacrame.com/products/diy-plant-hanger-kit">beginner kit</a> comes with everything your recipient needs, including rope, beads and a pattern. If they’re not into indoor flora or live with aggressive plant-loving cats, try <a href="https://modernmacrame.com/collections/kits/products/diy-wall-hanging-kit">a wall-hanging kit instead</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> Kits <a href="https://modernmacrame.com/products/diy-plant-hanger-kit">start at $36</a></p>
<h2>Robotime puzzles and miniature houses</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2081557" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081557" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2081557" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg" alt="Robotime miniature house kit" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/GG2020_Robotime.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2081557" class="wp-caption-text">Robotime miniature house kit. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Robotime</p></div></p>
<p>Know someone who loves jigsaw puzzles but is looking for a new challenge? Get them a kit from Robotime. The company is known for its elaborate wooden puzzle kits made out of lightweight plywood and extremely detailed miniature house kits.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> <a href="https://store.robotime.com/rolife/modern-3d-wooden-puzzle/">Wooden puzzles start at $10.99</a> | <a href="https://store.robotime.com/rolife/diy-miniature-house/">Miniature house kits at $31.99</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/diy-crafting-gifts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081548</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do the celebrities help the startups or do the startups help the celebrities?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/do-the-celebrities-help-the-startups-or-do-the-startups-help-the-celebrities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/do-the-celebrities-help-the-startups-or-do-the-startups-help-the-celebrities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 20:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initial public offering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skyflow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast (now on Twitter!), where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. What a week, yeah? Instead of the news cycle slowing as the year races to a close, things are still as hot as ever. We have funding rounds big and small, IPOs, first-day extravaganza and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/2e3bfad3-14af-4d1f-98e8-134a88e31fa8?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast (<a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">now on Twitter!</a>), where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>What a week, yeah? Instead of the news cycle slowing as the year races to a close, things are still as hot as ever. We have funding rounds big and small, IPOs, first-day extravaganza and more.</p>
<p>Luckily we had the whole crew around &#8212; <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/dannycrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">me</a>. Here’s the rundown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Career Karma <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/career-karma-series-a/">raised $10 million</a>, and we have thoughts and concerns.</li>
<li>Skyflow <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/skyflow-raises-17-5m-more-to-help-companies-protect-your-personal-data/">raised $17.5 million</a> in an effort to try to get the Equity team to understand the nuances of different encryption types.</li>
<li>Calm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/calm-raises-75m-more-at-2b-valuation/">raised $75 million</a>, which felt pretty reasonable given reports and its fundraising history.</li>
<li>Squire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/squire-series-c/">tripled its valuation</a> in a new round that included $45 million in equity capital along with some debt.</li>
<li>We also talked about the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">DoorDash and C3.ai IPO pops</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/">where Airbnb priced</a>, and who is coming next.</li>
<li>We rounded off with what&#8217;s up with TikTok stars investing in tech startups. Danny was not a fan.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that&#8217;s that! If you aren&#8217;t tired, have you even been paying attention?</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/do-the-celebrities-help-the-startups-or-do-the-startups-help-the-celebrities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085658</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airbnb&#8217;s first-day pop caps off a stellar week for tech IPOs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 19:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C3.AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After pricing above its raised range last night, Airbnb opened this morning at $146 per share, up around 115% to kick off its life as a public company. The company is now worth $158 per share. Using its IPO share count inclusive of shares reserved for underwriters, the company is worth $95.1 billion, but on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After pricing above its raised range last night, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/airbnb" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="airbnb">Airbnb <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> opened this morning at $146 per share, up around 115% to kick off its life as a public company.</p>
<p>The company is now worth $158 per share. Using its IPO share count inclusive of shares reserved for underwriters, the company is worth $95.1 billion, but on a fully diluted basis, including shares that could be exercised or awarded in the future, Airbnb is worth much more.</p>
<p>The home-sharing unicorn initially targeted $44 to $50 per share in its debut, later raising that range to $56 to $60 before <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/airbnb-said-to-price-ipo-between-67-and-68/">pricing at at $68 per share</a>. To open at such a premium is not shocking given <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">how the debuts of DoorDash and C3.ai performed earlier in the week</a>.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Taken as a trio, the companies&#8217; amped public debut are stoking concerns of mispriced IPOs.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>However, taken as a trio, the companies&#8217; amped public debut are stoking concerns of mispriced IPOs and, at least in my head, public markets that are more enthusiastic than reasonable.<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>The explosive debuts of the enterprise AI company, the home-sharing giant and the food-delivery leader were not the first IPOs of 2020 to set off fireworks when trading began. Snowflake, another megadebut, gained more than 100% in its first trading day, despite pricing above its own raised IPO price range.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s going on? Let&#8217;s use Snowflake as a prism through which we can figure it out. Lemonade, the summer insurtech IPO, will also provide some useful guidance.</p>
<h2>Was Snowflake underpriced?</h2>
<p>When Snowflake&#8217;s IPO <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/go-public-now-while-software-valuations-make-no-sense-part-ii/">went out with a thunderclap</a>, it was more ammunition for critics of the traditional public offering. <em>The company and its private investors had done so much work to get Snowflake to the public markets,</em> complaints seemed to go, <em>and then some idiot bankers mispriced its debut by 100%, rewarding their clients and screwing the company? Awful!</em></p>
<p>So went the argument. However, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/19/was-snowflakes-ipo-mispriced-or-just-misunderstood/">as I wrote at the time</a>, leaning on the work of Forbes&#8217; excellent reporting, Snowflake&#8217;s CEO was not fully bought into the concept:</p>
<blockquote><p>Alex Konrad at Forbes — a good chap, follow him on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/alexrkonrad">here</a> — caught up <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/2020/09/17/snowflake-ceo-frank-slootman-talks-ipo-pop-narrative-of-lost-billions-is-nonsense-talk/#79e69e937d1d">with Snowflake CEO Frank Slootman about the matter</a>. He called the “chatter” that his company left money on the table “nonsense,” adding that he could have priced higher but that he “wanted to bring along the group of investors that [Snowflake] wanted, and [he] didn’t want to push them past the point where they really started to squeal.”</p></blockquote>
<p>This is the &#8220;long-term investor&#8221; argument that you will hear on any call with a CEO on their IPO day. It goes like this: If you want long-term holders of the stock, you have to find a price that they will accept; that price may be different than what retail investors will pay when the company begins to trade. So, the gap, or pop, is fine as you are trading one thing for another.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085539</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>COVID-19 made our tech addiction worse: It’s time to do something about it </title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/covid-19-made-our-tech-addiction-worse-its-time-to-do-something-about-it/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/covid-19-made-our-tech-addiction-worse-its-time-to-do-something-about-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Addiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Social Dilemma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ucla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zillow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Governments are no more likely to help manage unhealthy tech consumption than consumption of sugar or illegal drugs. We need to take control.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Stuart Wall</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stuartwall">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stuartwall/">Stu Wall</a> is a technology executive and entrepreneur who founded <a href="https://www.signpost.com/">Signpost</a>, a cloud-based customer communication platform that helps small businesses scale.
	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The coronavirus pandemic accelerated America’s addiction to technology, and it’s making us <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/">sad, anxious and unproductive</a>.</p>
<p>Companies like <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> TikTok and Snapchat earn more advertising revenue the more frequently we use their products. These firms use push notifications and personalized feeds to capture our attention, manipulate our emotions and influence our actions.</p>
<p>Business is good. Americans now spend <a href="https://eyesafe.com/covid-19-screen-time-spike-to-over-13-hours-per-day/">more than five hours each day</a> on their devices.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>So what? As discussed in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/netflix" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="netflix">Netflix’s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> &#8220;The Social Dilemma,&#8221; tech firms will continue to follow their profit motive to <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/1/6/21048116/tech-companies-time-well-spent-mobile-phone-usage-data">capture our attention</a>. Governments are no more likely to help manage unhealthy tech consumption than consumption of sugar or illegal drugs. We need to take control.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The coronavirus pandemic accelerated America’s addiction to technology, and it’s making us sad, anxious and unproductive.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>My perspective is as a former tech CEO and technology addict. The marketing platform I founded raised over $100 million, grew to 350 employees and sold to a private equity firm last year. Along the way I picked up some terrible tech habits; I checked email constantly and allowed push notifications to interrupt every in-person interaction.</p>
<p>My tech use hit rock bottom last year on a visit with family. I resolved to put down my phone and garden with my mom, who has advanced Parkinson&#8217;s and moves slowly and with intention.</p>
<p>I felt like an addict in withdrawal. My phone was like a magnet pulling me to check for missed work emails or breaking news. Tech overuse had rewired my brain, lowered the quality of everyday consciousness and prevented me from being present.</p>
<p>I stepped down as CEO of my company earlier this year. I’ve spent my time off learning about mindfulness, neuroplasticity and technology addiction. Most importantly, I developed a strategy for managing my tech use that’s made me happier and more productive.</p>
<p>Here’s what I learned.</p>
<h2>Tech firms exploit our brains to capture our attention</h2>
<p>In their quest for our attention, some tech firms target the oldest parts of our brain, what UCLA psychiatrist Daniel Siegel calls the <em>downstairs brain</em>. The <em>downstairs brain </em>includes your brainstem and limbic regions, which control innate reactions and impulses (fight or flight) and strong emotion (like anger and fear). In contrast, your <em>upstairs brain</em>, including your cerebral cortex, is where intricate mental processes take place, like <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mindsight-New-Science-Personal-Transformation/dp/0553386395">thinking, imagining and planning</a>.</p>
<p>The downstairs brain is reactive. It’s designed to protect us in emergencies; it can make quick judgements, hijack our consciousness and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4678200/">drive action through strong emotion.</a> The downstairs brain is what is targeted by attention-seeking products. Headlines that make us feel outraged and TikTok notifications that make us feel reactive appeal to our downstairs brain.</p>
<h2>Spending time in a reactive state rewires our brains</h2>
<p>Our brains change with training. Research has shown that our brains are reprogrammed with the firing patterns of neurons. Our nervous system can be rewired and transformed through repetitive, focused attention or activity in a process called <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.01657/full">neuroplasticity</a>.</p>
<p>Repetitive device usage is a perfect example of neuroplasticity at work. The more time we spend responding to push notifications, watching videos in infinite scroll or looking for social validation from social media, the more our brains will rewire to want the same.</p>
<h2>Our addiction will get worse as firms get better at capturing attention</h2>
<p>While many tech firms acknowledge problems from overusing their products, none will make radical changes needed to decrease their share of the attention profit pool. If they did, someone else would eat their lunch.</p>
<p>These firms are selling us sugary drinks. The taste is improving exponentially and the sweetest drinks haven’t been invented yet. The more we drink, the harder it gets to stop. We need to take control of our consumption and habits — we need to follow a technology diet — or we will suffer the mental equivalent of morbid obesity.</p>
<h2>We can can rewire our brains to be more productive and happier by changing our habits</h2>
<p>If we think of technology consumption as an analog to food consumption, tech products fall into four food groups based on the quality of information and method of delivery. Content quality is important: Some content is valuable (e.g., MIT’s online courseware) or critical (work email), while most is not useful (<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/tiktok" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="tiktok">TikTok) <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>.</p>
<p>The delivery model is also important. Healthy platforms give agency to the user and allow us to pull content that’s useful when we need it. Conversely, harmful platforms often rely on push, sending us information that’s often not useful at a time when we’re doing something else. Based on my experience, here are three steps we can take to implement a tech diet:</p>
<h3><strong>1. Eliminate products that reinforce your downstairs brain (low-quality content pushed to you)</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ego_depletion">Willpower is finite</a>. If we don’t want sugary drinks, don’t keep them in the house. We keep the most distracting applications ever developed within arms reach at all times. These applications prey on our downstairs brain, which hijacks our better intentions <a href="https://www.inc.com/jeff-haden/its-official-more-you-use-facebook-worse-you-will-feel-about-yourself.html">and delivers negative value for most people</a>. I believe our best defense is abstinence; we shouldn’t use these apps.</p>
<p><strong>Tip: </strong>I use Apple’s Content Restrictions on the iPhone and MacBook. I added the obvious offenders: TikTok, Instagram, Facebook, Snapchat, and some specific to me, which includes <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/zillow" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="zillow">Zillow, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> StreetEasy and NYPost. My spouse has the override code. I can break it if needed, but the process is hard enough that it doesn’t enter everyday consciousness.</p>
<h3><strong>2. Consume more products that reinforce your upstairs brain (high-quality content that’s available when we need it)</strong></h3>
<p>Good content expands our knowledge and skills and may contribute to rewiring our upstairs brain in a way that adds to our empathy, imagination and mindfulness.</p>
<p>Consuming good content is rewarding but effortful. It requires <a href="http://www.theinvisiblegorilla.com/gorilla_experiment.html">uninterrupted focus</a>. Unlike sugary beverages, which we’re wired to consume subconsciously, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Thinking-Fast-Slow-Daniel-Kahneman/dp/0374533555">leafy greens have to be consumed intentionally</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Tip: </strong>Make a list of your favorite leafy greens. For me, this includes Kindle, Feedly, tech periodicals and my favorite curation platforms: HackerNews and Product Hunt. Calm, one of several booming mindfulness apps, also makes the list. These are the only apps on my home screen, which encourages me to use them more often. Like a food diet, I set attainable goals for “good” consumption and monitor my progress.</p>
<p>I recommend fasting on technology periodically; I leave my phone at home for walks with my son and dinner with friends. I also recommend nontech activities that promote upstairs brain rewiring like an outdoor hike or learning to play an instrument.</p>
<h3><strong>3. Redesign consumption patterns for productivity tools</strong></h3>
<p>Email is required for most people. It has the potential to make us productive. But the average message quality is low, and the always-on, high frequency, push-by-default design <a href="https://blog.rescuetime.com/context-switching/">prevents us from doing our best work</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Tip: </strong>I’ve turned off notifications on everything that’s not meant for urgent or timely messages (e.g., texts, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/lyft" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="lyft">Lyft, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Tovala oven). <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/boomerang-for-gmail/mdanidgdpmkimeiiojknlnekblgmpdll?hl=en">Boomerang’s Chrome Extension</a><sup> </sup>can be set up to deliver all of your emails every hour on the hour. Batch processing email every hour dramatically reduces the volume of interruption without impacting my responsiveness.</p>
<p>We live in relative abundance, with food, goods and security that would make even our recent ancestors envious. But abundance doesn’t make us happy; <a href="https://worldhappiness.report/ed/2019/the-sad-state-of-happiness-in-the-united-states-and-the-role-of-digital-media/">we’re the least happy on record</a>. We seem to be living in a collective state of <em>downstairs brain</em>, a continuous adult temper tantrum focused on strong feelings, emotion and impulsiveness.</p>
<p>But there’s hope.</p>
<p>As individuals, I found that even a few months of technology dieting helped me become less impulsive and more mindful. As employees, we can stop working for companies that profit from the attention economy. As managers, we can insist that our teams turn off their devices at night, turn off their Slack notifications and take real vacations. As parents, we can help our children develop healthy consumption patterns.</p>
<p>Collective action — and rewiring of our brains — could change the course of our politics and our ability to collaborate and solve the most important challenges of the 21st century.</p>
<p>American innovation dominates the attention economy. It’s time for American innovation to dominate the way we use technology.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ec335FSUER"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/ignore-the-social-media-echo-chambers/">Ignore the social media echo chambers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ignore the social media echo chambers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/ignore-the-social-media-echo-chambers/embed/#?secret=ec335FSUER" data-secret="ec335FSUER" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/covid-19-made-our-tech-addiction-worse-its-time-to-do-something-about-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085163</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google, Intel, Zoom and others launch a new alliance to get enterprises to use more Chrome</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-intel-zoom-and-others-launch-a-new-alliance-to-get-enterprises-to-use-more-chrome/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-intel-zoom-and-others-launch-a-new-alliance-to-get-enterprises-to-use-more-chrome/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome os]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citrix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citrix Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ringcentral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A group of industry heavyweights, including Google, Box, Citrix, Dell, Imprivata, Intel, Okta, RingCentral, Slack, VMware and Zoom, today announced the launch of the Modern Computing Alliance. The mission for this new alliance is to &#8220;drive ‘silicon-to-cloud’ innovation for the benefit of enterprise customers &#8212; fueling a differentiated modern computing platform and providing additional choice [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A group of industry heavyweights, including <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Box, Citrix, Dell, Imprivata, Intel, Okta, RingCentral, Slack, VMware and Zoom, today announced the launch of the <a href="https://chromeenterprise.google/moderncomputing/">Modern Computing Alliance</a>.</p>
<p>The mission for this new alliance is to &#8220;drive ‘silicon-to-cloud’ innovation for the benefit of enterprise customers &#8212; fueling a differentiated modern computing platform and providing additional choice for integrated business solutions.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Whoever wrote this mission statement was clearly trying to see how many words they could use without actually saying something.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here is what the alliance is really about: Even though the word <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/chrome-37d2" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="chrome-37d2">Chrome <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> never appears on its homepage and Google&#8217;s partners never quite get to mentioning it either, it&#8217;s all about helping enterprises adopt Chrome and Chrome OS. &#8220;The focus of the alliance is to drive innovation and interoperability in the Google Chrome ecosystem, increasing options for enterprise customers and helping to address some of the biggest tech challenges facing companies today,&#8221; a Google spokesperson told me.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bh-QHw71ptg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure why it&#8217;s not called the Chrome Enterprise Alliance, but Modern Computing Alliance may just have more of a ring to it. This also explains why <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/microsoft" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="microsoft">Microsoft <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> isn&#8217;t part of it, though this is only the initial slate of members and others may follow at some point in the future.</p>
<p>Led by Google, the alliance&#8217;s focus is on bringing modern web apps to the enterprise sector, with a focus on performance, security, identity management and productivity. And all of that, of course, is meant to run well on Chrome and Chrome OS and be interoperable.</p>
<p>&#8220;The technology industry is moving toward an open, heterogeneous ecosystem that allows freedom of choice while integrating across the stack. This reality presents both a challenge and an opportunity,&#8221; Google&#8217;s Chrome OS VP John Solomon writes today.</p>
<p>As enterprises move to the cloud, building better web applications and maybe even progressive web applications that work just as well as native solutions is obviously a noble goal and it&#8217;s nice to see these companies work together. Given the pandemic, all of this has taken on a new urgency now, too. The plan is for the alliance to release products &#8212; though it&#8217;s unclear what form these will take &#8212; in the first half of 2021. Hopefully, these will play nicely with any browser. A lot of these &#8220;alliances&#8221; fizzle out quite quickly, so we&#8217;ll keep an eye on what happens here.</p>
<p><strong>Bonus</strong>: The industry has a long history of alliances like these. Here&#8217;s a fun 1991 story about a CPU alliance between <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1991/04/08/business/new-computer-alliance-forms.html">Intel, IBM, MIPS and others</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xHNC2mbhbu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-to-add-covid-19-vaccine-information-panels-to-search/">Google to add COVID-19 vaccine information panels to Search</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google to add COVID-19 vaccine information panels to Search&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-to-add-covid-19-vaccine-information-panels-to-search/embed/#?secret=xHNC2mbhbu" data-secret="xHNC2mbhbu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/google-intel-zoom-and-others-launch-a-new-alliance-to-get-enterprises-to-use-more-chrome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085622</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify resets passwords after a security bug exposed users&#8217; private account information</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/spotify-resets-user-passwords-after-a-bug-exposed-private-account-information/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/spotify-resets-user-passwords-after-a-bug-exposed-private-account-information/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credential stuffing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085675</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spotify said it has reset an undisclosed number of user passwords after blaming a software vulnerability in its systems for exposing private account information to its business partners. In a data breach notification filed with the California attorney general&#8217;s office, the music streaming giant said the data exposed &#8220;may have included email address, your preferred [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/spotify" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="spotify">Spotify <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said it has reset an undisclosed number of user passwords after blaming a software vulnerability in its systems for exposing private account information to its business partners.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://beta.documentcloud.org/documents/20422370-spotify-breach-notice-letter-californiadocx">a data breach notification</a> filed with the California attorney general&#8217;s office, the music streaming giant said the data exposed &#8220;may have included email address, your preferred display name, password, gender, and date of birth only to certain business partners of Spotify.&#8221; The company did not name the business partners, but added that Spotify &#8220;did not make this information publicly accessible.&#8221;</p>
<p>Spotify said the vulnerability existed as far back as April 9 but wasn&#8217;t discovered until November 12. But like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/decoding-data-breach-notice/">most data breach notices</a>, Spotify did not say what the vulnerability was or how user account data became exposed.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have conducted an internal investigation and have contacted all of our business partners that may have had access to your account information to ensure that any personal information that may have been inadvertently disclosed to them has been deleted,&#8221; the letter read.</p>
<p>Spotify spokesperson Adam Grossberg confirmed that a &#8220;small subset&#8221; of Spotify users are affected, but did not provide a specific figure. Spotify has more than 320 million users, and 144 million subscribers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the second time in as many months that the company has reset user passwords.</p>
<p>Last month security researchers found an unsecured database, <a href="https://blog.malwarebytes.com/reports/2020/11/spotify-resets-some-user-logins-after-hacker-database-found-floating-online/">likely operated by hackers</a>, allegedly containing around 300,000 stolen user passwords. The database was probably used to launch credential stuffing attacks, in which lists of stolen passwords are matched against different websites that use the same password.</p>
<p>Although in that case the exposed data did not come from Spotify, the company reset the passwords on affected user accounts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j6nCtRjQSB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/decoding-data-breach-notice/">How to decode a data breach notice</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to decode a data breach notice&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/decoding-data-breach-notice/embed/#?secret=j6nCtRjQSB" data-secret="j6nCtRjQSB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/spotify-resets-user-passwords-after-a-bug-exposed-private-account-information/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085675</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Providing healthcare to lower-income communities values Cityblock Health at $1 billion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/providing-healthcare-to-lower-income-communities-values-cityblock-health-at-1-billion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/providing-healthcare-to-lower-income-communities-values-cityblock-health-at-1-billion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cityblock Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maverick Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redpoint ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco bay area]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thrive Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cityblock Health, a company that provides healthcare services to low-income communities, is now commanding a high-priced valuation of over $1 billion after venture capitalists poured $160 million into the company. The round was led by new investor General Catalyst with participation from crossover investor Wellington Management and support from major existing investors, including Kinnevik AB, Maverick [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.cityblock.com/">Cityblock Health</a>, a company that provides healthcare services to low-income communities, is now commanding a high-priced valuation of over $1 billion after venture capitalists poured $160 million into the company.</p>
<p>The round was led by new investor <a href="https://www.generalcatalyst.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.generalcatalyst.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1607709142336000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEQEG2QTPZJwVJdxy2jpE2nVlitGg">General Catalyst</a> with participation from crossover investor <a href="https://www.wellington.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.wellington.com/en/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1607709142336000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH9yKKhZsp3sIC8z0qc0Cg4t0UKUA">Wellington Management</a> and support from major existing investors, including Kinnevik AB, Maverick Ventures, Thrive Capital, Redpoint Ventures and more, according to a statement from the company.</p>
<p>Cityblock works with community caregivers to work with residents to provide primary care, behavioral health and other services to address social determinants of health, in person and&#8230; increasingly&#8230; through virtual consultations.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company first spun out of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/alphabet" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="alphabet">Alphabet&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Sidewalk Labs in 2017 and initially partnered with EmblemHealth. By relying primarily on licensed clinical social workers, community health partners and a network of specialized practice clinicians and doctors to provide basic primary care and supporting health services, Cityblock believes it can drive down the costs of healthcare.</p>
<p>Some 70,000 patients use Cityblock services in four major U.S. cities, the company said.</p>
<p dir="ltr">To date, Cityblock has raised $300 million.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The company said in a statement that the new funding will be used to support Cityblock’s national expansion in caring for Medicaid and dually-eligible communities, to attract and onboard talent across its product, engineering, data science, clinical and business operations, to launch new service lines and to continue investing in its proprietary technology platform, Commons.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/providing-healthcare-to-lower-income-communities-values-cityblock-health-at-1-billion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085676</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snap launches a native Twitter integration</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/snap-launches-a-native-twitter-integration/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/snap-launches-a-native-twitter-integration/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soundcloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical Video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2085303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter is partnering with Snap to bring tweets into Snapchat with a native integration that both companies hope will push users away from screenshots and toward more interactive embeds. Twitter users who are also logged into the Snapchat app on their phone will be able to access the functionality by tapping share on a particular [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/twitter" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="twitter">Twitter <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is partnering with Snap to bring tweets into Snapchat with a native integration that both companies hope will push users away from screenshots and toward more interactive embeds.</p>
<p>Twitter users who are also logged into the Snapchat app on their phone will be able to access the functionality by tapping share on a particular tweet and navigating to the Snapchat icon where they&#8217;ll be able to share and react or comment on a Twitter post and send it to a friend or share on their story. The functionality will notably only work for tweets from public accounts, not protected ones.</p>
<p>The feature is rolling out on iOS for now, with Android integration &#8220;coming soon.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2085315" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2085315" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2085315 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="258" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png 3531w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=150,57 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=300,114 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=768,291 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=680,258 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=1536,582 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=2048,777 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Snap-x-Twitter.png?resize=50,19 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2085315" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/snapchat" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="snapchat">Snap</p></div></p> <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>
<p>Given how much content across Snapchat, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/instagram" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="instagram">Instagram, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Facebook and Reddit originates from Twitter, it&#8217;s surprising that this functionality is arriving so deep into Twitter&#8217;s life as a company. They&#8217;ve long had a web embed integration which has allowed reporters to embed tweets into stories, but when it came to sharing on social media, Twitter&#8217;s strategy has deferred to the un-trackable and un-monetizable screenshot.</p>
<p>This has been low-hanging product rollout for Twitter, which will likely be able to coax some non-Twitter users to enjoy content straight from the source, something the company has been vaguely alluding to in marketing campaigns over the years but is just now approaching with a direct integration into another company&#8217;s platform.</p>
<p>With Twitter now starting to roll out its Stories product Fleets to users, the company likely feels as though they have more feature familiarity to bring new users onboard from Snap who might not have experimented with the platform previously.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wPoYjxTdVn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/">Twitter rolls out Stories, aka &#8216;Fleets,&#8217; to all users; will also test a Clubhouse rival</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter rolls out Stories, aka &#8216;Fleets,&#8217; to all users; will also test a Clubhouse rival&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/17/twitter-rolls-out-stories-aka-fleets-to-all-users-will-also-test-a-clubhouse-rival/embed/#?secret=wPoYjxTdVn" data-secret="wPoYjxTdVn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The truth is there aren&#8217;t a ton of integrations across social media channels; screen recordings and screen shots tell one platform&#8217;s story in an imperfect way on another&#8217;s. This integration comes as a result of updates made to Snap&#8217;s Snap Kit API and a particular feature called Creative Kit. Snap says that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/spotify" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="spotify">Spotify, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Reddit, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/soundcloud" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="soundcloud">SoundCloud, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Sendit, YOLO and GOAT have also created integrations that allow content from those apps to be shared across Snapchat.</p>
<p>Twitter didn&#8217;t rule out the expansion of this feature to other platforms in the future.</p>
<p>&#8220;This agreement with Snap was focused on this feature,&#8221; a Twitter spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;We would love to partner with other platforms to enable people to share Tweets more widely. We hope this will be the first of many integrations of its kind.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/snap-launches-a-native-twitter-integration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2085303</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
