<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:58:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>As it hits $100 million run rate, The Pill Club adds former Uber exec Liz Meyerdirk as CEO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/as-it-hits-100-million-run-rate-the-pill-club-adds-former-uber-exec-liz-meyerdirk-as-ceo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/as-it-hits-100-million-run-rate-the-pill-club-adds-former-uber-exec-liz-meyerdirk-as-ceo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief financial officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contraception]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reproductive health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supreme court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber Eats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Liz Meyerdirk made a name for herself at Uber as the Senior Director &#38; Global Head of Business Development for the company&#8217;s Uber Eats business and she&#8217;s now turning her attention to women&#8217;s health as the new chief executive of The Pill Club. The move comes at a perilous time for the remote delivery of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Liz Meyerdirk made a name for herself at Uber as the Senior Director &amp; Global Head of Business Development for the company&#8217;s Uber Eats business and she&#8217;s now turning her attention to women&#8217;s health as the new chief executive of <a href="https://thepillclub.com/">The Pill Club</a>.</p>
<p>The move comes at a perilous time for the remote delivery of women&#8217;s healthcare as the Supreme Court has taken steps to limit the provision of sexual healthcare to women in recent months.</p>
<p>&#8220;Women’s health care has never been more tested than right now,&#8221; Meyerdirk noted in a blog post announcing her new role. &#8220;COVID-19 has upended access to care; dozens of states have—and continue—to try and limit women&#8217;s choice; and last year, the Supreme Court voted to uphold the rollback of the ACA contraceptive mandate decision, a stunning move that could end up impacting as many as 126,000 women who previously received covered contraception through employer-based health insurance.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A seasoned corporate executive, Meyerdirk is hoping to navigate The Pill Club through these treacherous times. &#8220;These events have shown that reliable, safe, and affordable access to women’s health and birth control is<br />
just one more vulnerability in our health care system,&#8221; Meyerdirk wrote.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100041" style="width: 372px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100041" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2100041" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg" alt="" width="362" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg 3800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg?resize=544,680 544w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Liz_Meyerdirk.jpg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100041" class="wp-caption-text">Liz Meyerdirk, chief executive of The Pill Club: Image Credit: The Pill Club</p></div></p>
<p>As it faces an uncertain legal environment on some fronts, the company couldn&#8217;t be in a better position financially.</p>
<p>The Pill Club, which is profitable and now has a $100 million run rate, is now ready for its closeup with Meyerdirk at the helm.</p>
<p>The company has managed to make its mark in the crowded world of online prescriptions and refill fulfillment by focusing specifically on women&#8217;s health and ensuring that those services are available to as many potential patients as possible.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re now serving hundreds of thousands of women nationwide with 20% on Medicaid,&#8221; says Meyerdirk. &#8220;We prescribe in 43 states and the District of Columbia.&#8221;</p>
<p>For Meyerdirk, the background she had in logistics and fulfillment from her time at Uber Eats made the transition to the pill prescription and delivery service natural.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a heavy logistics element to it,&#8221; said Meyerdirk.</p>
<p>As Meyerdirk takes the reins of the company, she said there&#8217;s a few areas that The Pill Club will expand into beyond its focus on birth control and contraception. &#8220;There are areas that our customers are asking for,&#8221; Meyerdirk said.</p>
<p>These areas include, initially, dermatology. Last year the company launched a delivery service for contraceptives and women&#8217;s hygiene products like pads and tampons.</p>
<p>As it continues to expand its product suite, it&#8217;s also growing its executive staff. The company not only added Meyerdirk, but also David Hsu as chief financial officer and Jeremy Downs as senior vice president of growth. Hsu joins the company from Honey, where led the $4 billion acquisition negotiations with PayPal, and Downs comes from Uber Eats, where he spent five years leading growth.</p>
<p>&#8220;We need sustained, long-term access to women’s health care, not just a bridge while the pandemic persists; and we need coverage for essential health services like birth control and prenatal care, regardless of whether or not you’re insured,&#8221; Meyerdirk wrote. &#8220;Reproductive care has and continues to be an essential part of our business, but there are countless opportunities to serve women in all of their life stages from puberty to menopause.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/as-it-hits-100-million-run-rate-the-pill-club-adds-former-uber-exec-liz-meyerdirk-as-ceo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virgin Orbit will launch first Dutch defense satellite in mission that will demo rapid response capabilities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/virgin-orbit-will-launch-first-dutch-defense-satellite-in-mission-that-will-demo-rapid-response-capabilities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/virgin-orbit-will-launch-first-dutch-defense-satellite-in-mission-that-will-demo-rapid-response-capabilities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communications satellites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of defense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LauncherOne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VOX Space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit isn&#8217;t slowing down after joining the exclusive club of small launch companies that have made it to orbit – the company just announced that it&#8217;s flying a payload on behalf of customer the Royal Netherlands Air Force (RNAF). This is the first ever satellite being put up by the Dutch Ministry of Defense, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Virgin Orbit isn&#8217;t slowing down after joining the exclusive club of small launch companies that have made it to orbit – the company just announced that it&#8217;s flying a payload on behalf of customer the Royal Netherlands Air Force (RNAF). This is the first ever satellite being put up by the Dutch Ministry of Defense, and it&#8217;s a small satellite that will act as a test platform for a number of different communications experiments.</p>
<p>The satellite is called &#8216;BRIK-II&#8217; – not because it&#8217;s the second of its kind, but rather because it&#8217;s named after Brik, the first airplane ever owned and operated by the RNAF. This mission is one of Virgin Orbit&#8217;s first commercial operations after its successful test demonstration, and will fly sometime later this year. It&#8217;s also being planned as a rideshare mission, with other payloads expected to join – likely from the U.S. Department of Defense, which is working with Virgin Orbit&#8217;s dedicated U.S. defense industry subsidiary VOX Space on planning what they&#8217;ll be adding to the mission load out.</p>
<p>This upcoming mission is actually a key demonstration of a number of Virgin Orbit&#8217;s unique advantages in the launch market. For one, it&#8217;ll show how the U.S. DOD and its ally defense agencies can work together in the space domain when launching small communications satellites. Virgin Orbit is also going to use the mission as an opportunity to show off its &#8220;late-load integration&#8221; capabilities – effectively, how it can add a payload to its LauncherOne rocket just prior to launch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For this particular flight, there&#8217;s no real reason to do a late-load integration, since there&#8217;s plenty of lead time, but part of Virgin&#8217;s appeal is being able to nimbly add satellites to its rocket just before the carrier jet that flies it to its take-off altitude leaves the runway. Demonstrating that will go a long way to help illustrate how it differentiates its services from others in the launch market including Rocket Lab and SpaceX.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/virgin-orbit-will-launch-first-dutch-defense-satellite-in-mission-that-will-demo-rapid-response-capabilities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100024</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlackCart raises $8.8M Series A for its try-before-you-buy platform for online merchants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/blackcart-raises-8-8m-series-a-for-its-try-before-you-buy-platform-for-online-merchants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/blackcart-raises-8-8m-series-a-for-its-try-before-you-buy-platform-for-online-merchants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigcommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magento]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A startup called BlackCart is tackling one of the key challenges with online shopping: an inability to try on or test out the merchandise before making a purchase. That company, which has now closed on $8.8 million in Series A funding, has built a try-before-you-buy platform that integrates with e-commerce storefronts, allowing customers to ship [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A startup called <a href="https://blackcart.com/">BlackCart</a> is tackling one of the key challenges with online shopping: an inability to try on or test out the merchandise before making a purchase. That company, which has now closed on $8.8 million in Series A funding, has built a try-before-you-buy platform that integrates with e-commerce storefronts, allowing customers to ship items to their home for free and only pay if they choose to keep the item after a &#8220;try on&#8221; period has lapsed.</p>
<p>The new round of financing was led by Origin Ventures and Hyde Park Ventures Partners, and saw participation from Struck Capital, Citi Ventures, 500 Startups, and several other angel investors including Christian Sullivan of Republic Labs, Dean Bakes of M3 Ventures, Greg Rudin of Menlo Ventures, Jordan Nathan of Caraway Cookware, and First National Bank CFO Nick Pirollo, among others.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100017" style="width: 419px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100017" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2100017" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?w=594" alt="" width="409" height="468" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png 2340w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?resize=131,150 131w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?resize=262,300 262w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?resize=768,880 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?resize=594,680 594w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?resize=1341,1536 1341w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?resize=1788,2048 1788w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/donny.png?resize=44,50 44w" sizes="(max-width: 409px) 100vw, 409px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100017" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> BlackCart</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>BlackCart founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/donnyouyang/?originalSubdomain=ca">Donny Ouyang</a> had previously founded online tutoring marketplace Rayku before joining a seed stage VC fund, Caravan Ventures. But he was inspired to return to entrepreneurship, he says, after experiencing a personal problem with trying to order shoes online.</p>
<p>Realizing the opportunity for a &#8220;try before you buy&#8221; type of service, Ouyang first built BlackCart in 2017 as a business-to-consumer (B2C) platform that worked by way of a Chrome extension with some 50 different online merchants, largely in apparel.</p>
<p>This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product">MVP</a> of sorts proved there was consumer demand for something like this in online shopping shopping.</p>
<p>Ouyang credits the earlier version of BlackCart with helping the team to understand what sort of products work best for this service.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think, in general, for try-before-you-buy, anything that&#8217;s moderate to higher price points, lower frequency of purchase, where the customer makes a considered purchase decision &#8212; those perform really well,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>Two years later, Ouyang took BlackCart to 500 Startups in San Francisco, where he then pivoted the business to a B2B offering it is today.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100020" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100020" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100020" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product3.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="329" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product3.png 1189w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product3.png?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product3.png?resize=300,145 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product3.png?resize=768,372 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product3.png?resize=680,329 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product3.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100020" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> BlackCart</p></div></p>
<p>The startup now provides a try-before-you-buy platform that integrates with online storefronts, including those from Shopify, Magento, WooCommerce, Big Commerce, SalesForce Commerce Cloud, WordPress, and even custom storefronts. The system is designed to be turnkey for online retailers and takes around 48 hours to set up on Shopify around a week on Magento, for example.</p>
<p>BlackCart has also developed its own proprietary technology around fraud detection, payments, returns, and the overall user experience, which includes a button for retailers&#8217; websites.</p>
<p>Because the online shoppers aren&#8217;t paying upfront for the merchandise they&#8217;re being shipped, BlackCart has to rely on an expanded array of behavioral signals and data in order to make a determination about whether the customer represents a fraud risk. As one example, if the customer had read a lot of helpdesk articles about fraud before placing their order, that could be flagged as a negative signal.</p>
<p>BlackCart also verifies the user&#8217;s phone number at checkout and matches it to telco and government data sets to see if their historical addresses match their shipping and billing addresses.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100021" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100021" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100021" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product4.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="446" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product4.png 896w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product4.png?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product4.png?resize=300,197 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product4.png?resize=768,504 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product4.png?resize=680,446 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/product4.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100021" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> BlackCart</p></div></p>
<p>After the customer receives the item, they are able to keep it for a period of time (as designated by the retailer) before being charged. BlackCart covers any fraud as part of its value proposition to retailers.</p>
<p>BlackCart makes money by way of a rev share model, where it charges retailers a percentage of the sales where the customers have kept the products. This amount can vary based on a number of factors, like the fraud multiplier, average order value, the type of product and others. At the low end, it&#8217;s around 4% and around 10% on the high-end, Ouyang says.</p>
<p>The company has also expanded beyond home try-on to include try-before-you-buy for electronics, jewelry, home goods, and more. It can even ship out makeup samples for home try-on, as another option.</p>
<p>Once integrated on a website, BlackCart claims its merchants typically see conversion increases of 24%, average order values climb by 51%, and bottom-line sales growth of 27%.</p>
<p>To date, the platform been adopted by over 50 medium-to-large retailers as well as e-commerce startups, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/22/koio-the-d2c-luxury-sneaker-brand-raises-6-million/">luxury sneaker brand Koio</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/15/diaco-gets-another-70m-from-sequoia-usv/">clothing startup Dia&amp;Co</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/29/helix-sleep-raises-7-4-million-to-sell-made-to-order-mattresses-online/">online mattress startup Helix Sleep</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/caraway-seed-funding/">cookware startup Caraway</a>, among others. It&#8217;s also under NDA now with a top 50 retailer it can&#8217;t yet name publicly, and has contracts signed with 13 others who are waiting to be onboarded.</p>
<p>Soon, BlackCart aims to offer a self-serve onboarding process, Ouyang notes.</p>
<p>&#8220;This would be later, end of Q2 or early Q3,&#8221; he says. &#8220;But I think for us, it will still be probably 80% self-serve, and then larger enterprises will want to be handheld.&#8221;</p>
<p>With the additional funding, BlackCart aims to shift to paying the merchant immediately for the items at checkout, then reconciling afterwards in order to be more efficient. This has been one of merchants&#8217; biggest feature requests, as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100015" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100015" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100015" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="392" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png 2040w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png?resize=300,173 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png?resize=768,443 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png?resize=680,392 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png?resize=1536,886 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blackcart-team.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100015" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> BlackCart; team photo</p></div></p>
<p>The funding will also allow BlackCart to expand its remotely distributed 10-person team to around 50 by year-end, including engineers, product specialists, customer support staff, and sales.</p>
<p>More broadly, it aims to quickly capitalize on the growth in the e-commerce market, driven by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>&#8220;[We want to] take advantage of the favorable macroeconomic situation to scale as quickly as possible,&#8221; Ouyang explains. &#8220;We&#8217;re hoping to get to around $250 million in transactions through our platform by the end of 2021. And this would be driven by both engineering and sales hires, and just pushing it up,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>Longer-term, Ouyang envisions adding more consumer-facing features to BlackCart&#8217;s platform, like on-demand returns where a courier comes to the house to pick up your return, for example.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our firm is excited to partner with BlackCart as it makes try-before-you-buy the standard in online shopping,&#8221; said Prashant Shukla of Origin Ventures, who now sits on BlackCart&#8217;s board, as result of the new financing. &#8220;Its underwriting technology provides merchants with peace of mind, and its best-in-class consumer experience delivers significant sales and conversion lifts. Digital Native generations expect to be able to shop online exactly as they would in a retail store, and BlackCart is the only company providing this experience,&#8221; he adds.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/blackcart-raises-8-8m-series-a-for-its-try-before-you-buy-platform-for-online-merchants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099981</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Melio raises $110M on a $1.3B valuation to bring B2B payments for SMBs into the 21st century</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/melio-raises-110m-on-a-1-3b-valuation-to-bring-b2b-payments-for-smbs-into-the-21st-century/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/melio-raises-110m-on-a-1-3b-valuation-to-bring-b2b-payments-for-smbs-into-the-21st-century/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Payments for consumers have made a huge shift to the online world in the last year, a time when they have moved more of their purchasing to the internet to minimize in-person transactions in the midst of a virus-based health pandemic. Today, a startup that has built a similar kind of payments infrastructure &#8212; but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Payments for consumers have made a huge shift to the online world in the last year, a time when they have moved more of their purchasing to the internet to minimize in-person transactions in the midst of a virus-based health pandemic. Today, a startup that has built a similar kind of payments infrastructure &#8212; but specifically targeting small businesses and the payments they need to make &#8212; has raised a big round of funding to double down on its own slice of the market.</p>
<p><a href="http://melio.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Melio</a>, which provides a platform for SMBs to pay other companies electronically using bank transfers, debit cards or credit &#8212; along with the option of cutting paper checks for recipients if that is what the recipients request &#8212; has closed $110 million in funding at a valuation that the company said was now $1.3 billion.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s focus to date has been building and growing system to replace the paper invoices, snail mail, and bank transfers that might take multiple days to clear and still dominate payments for small and medium enterprises. The company was founded in Israel but has to date focused a lot of its attention on the U.S. market, where it saw growth of 2,000% last year (it doesn&#8217;t disclose the actual number of customers that it has). CEO Matan Bar said that this is where the company will continue to focus for now.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This latest round was led by Coatue and also included participation from previous backers Accel, Aleph, Bessemer Venture Partners, Corner Ventures, General Catalyst, and Latitude. It caps off a huge year for the company, which raised $130 million in 2020 (and $256 million overall), with other recent backers including others like American Express and Salesforce.</p>
<p>The latter two are strategic backers: AmEx is one of the options given to customers paying other businesses through Melio&#8217;s rails.</p>
<p>Salesforce, meanwhile, is not yet an integration partner, but Bar &#8212; who co-founded the company with Ilan Atias and Ziv Paz (respectively CTO and COO) &#8212; described its interest as similar to that of Intuit-owned accounting giant Quickbooks. Quickbooks connects with Melio so that users of one can seamlessly import activity from one platform into the other, and Bar hinted that there is an interest from the CRM giant, which provides a number of other business and productivity tools, to work together in a similar fashion.</p>
<p>Bar came to found Melio on the heels of years of experience in peer-to-peer payments focused on the consumer market. He previously ran PayPal&#8217;s business unit focused on peer-to-peer payments, which included Venmo in the US and equivalent services (not branded Venmo) outside of it. He came to PayPal, which at the time was a part of eBay, through eBay&#8217;s acquisition of his previous startup, a social gifting platform called <a href="https://en.globes.co.il/en/article-1000681080" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gifts Project</a>.</p>
<p>As Bar describes it, PayPal &#8220;was the first time I experienced what the digitization of payments looked like as they were shifting from cash to mobile payments. Consumers were buying online instead of at brick-and-mortar stores, and even when they were getting physical items, they were paying online.&#8221; What he quickly realized, though, was that the same was not applying to the businesses themselves.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are still trillions being transferred via paper checks in the B2B space,&#8221; he said, with paper invoices and paper checks dominating the market. &#8220;The space is way behind other payment areas. I would be talking with SMB owners who would be using fancy Square or PayPal point of sale devices, but when they had to pay, say, a coffee bean supplier, they stuffed checks in envelopes. That’s very intriguing obviously, and it triggered our interest.&#8221;</p>
<p>Interestingly this isn&#8217;t a problem that hasn&#8217;t been identified before, but many of the solutions, such as Bill.com or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/tipalti-receives-150m-at-a-2b-valuation-after-its-accounts-payable-platform-sees-a-surge-in-use/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tipalti</a>, are really designed for larger enterprises. &#8220;They are too overwhelming for SMBs,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Even their names say it all: Accounts Payable Automation Solutions. It’s about tens of thousands of payments, and accounting departments, not an order from a wine shop.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>That formed the basis of what the startup started to build, which has been, in essence, a very pared-down version of these other payments platforms with SMB needs in mind.</p>
<p>The first of these is a focus on cashflow, Bar said. Specifically, the Melio platform lets payments be made automatically but businesses themselves can delay the timing on when money actually leaves their accounts: &#8220;Buyers keep cash longer, vendors get paid faster&#8221; is how Bar describes it.</p>
<p>This is in part enabled by the tech that Melio has built, which builds in risk assessment, as well as fraud management, and balances payments across the whole of its platform to send money in and out without the need for the company to raise debt to back up those payments.</p>
<p>&#8220;We leverage data to assess risk,&#8221; said Bar. &#8220;Every dollar in this round is going towards R&amp;D and sales and marketing. We don’t need the capital in our model.&#8221; It also works with the likes of AmEx and its own credit system in cases where people are paying on credit, but Bar also noted that currently most of the transactions that happen on its platform are not credit based. Most are bank transfers.</p>
<p>While others like Stripe have also built B2B payment services to pay out suppliers, Bar points out that what it has created is unique in that it is a standalone service: no need to be a part of Stripe&#8217;s wider ecosystem of services to use this if you already use another payments provider you are happy with.</p>
<p>Given that focus on cashflow for SMBs, what&#8217;s also interesting is the low bar to entry that Melio has built into its platform. Specifically, the service is completely free for businesses to use &#8212; that is, no fee is charged &#8212; as long as companies are making bank transfers or using debit cards. It takes a 2.9% fee when a business elects to use a credit card for a transaction (and even then Melio says that the fee is tax deductible in the US).</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">He noted that one of the reasons that Melio has to date targeted the US market is because of how antiquated it still is. &#8220;The average bank transfer still takes three to four business days, if you don’t want to take any risk,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We have developed models to do it same day. We take the risk that the buyer might not have the funds in that account but think about how that impacts cash flows. With Melio you still pay in three days, but money will be delivered the same day. That is how you can keep cash longer, without a payments risk.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Targeting a market that remains very underserved at a time when so much has gone virtual in payments is why investors are also interested.</p>
<p>“Melio has identified both the opportunity and duty to help small businesses manage their finance remotely and improve cash flow, in normal times as well as during this crisis, as physical payments supply chains are interrupted and overwhelmed,&#8221; said Michael Gilroy, a general partner at Coatue, in a statement. &#8220;Going digital is the only way small businesses can compete against larger rivals and stay ahead of the curve.”</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In terms of more product development, Bar said that the company has </span>received &#8220;a lot of incoming interest from partners to enable B2B payments within their products on their product,&#8221; similar to what Quickbooks is doing and Salesforce is likely to do. &#8220;Payments are contextual and they want to enable a quicker way to get there. The SMB is underserved. And yes, from a unit economics it’s much better to go after Nike. But this is also to really create some financial inclusion. We want to enable services for the small shop that the big guys already have.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/melio-raises-110m-on-a-1-3b-valuation-to-bring-b2b-payments-for-smbs-into-the-21st-century/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099970</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: Clubhouse, Taboola, and why the SPAC wave will get worse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/equity-monday-clubhouse-taboola-and-why-the-spac-wave-will-get-worse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/equity-monday-clubhouse-taboola-and-why-the-spac-wave-will-get-worse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 15:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chamath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IMVU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postmates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pula]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taboola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wolt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday,  our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/b1215c5f-98a7-4a59-bd38-45a3067fdf99?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday,  our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and myself <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a> — and make sure to check out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/the-only-take-about-the-future-of-media-is-that-media-is-the-future/">last week’s main ep</a>, which was super-packed and a real treat.</p>
<p>This morning the news was <em>heavy</em>, so here&#8217;s your rundown to get you into the show:</p>
<ul>
<li>New funds for Clubhouse! TechCrunch has the story <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/clubhouse-announces-plans-for-creator-payments-and-raises-new-funding-led-by-andreessen-horowitz/">here</a>, but I wonder why the app needs more money this soon. You can lay your own bets on how it performs, but at least it&#8217;s fun to see consumer stuff get funded.</li>
<li>Postmates staff are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/23/technology/uber-postmates-layoffs.html">heading for the exits</a>, and there&#8217;s an IPO coming up that is both huge and under your radar.</li>
<li>Chamath is <a href="https://twitter.com/chamath/status/1353673101901369345">doing the SPAC thing again</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/chamath/status/1353674959789256705">Again</a>. And Taboola is also going public via a SPAC.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/imvu-35-million-funding/">IMVU raised $35 million</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/kenyan-insurtech-startup-pula-raises-6m-series-a-led-by-tlcom-capital/">Pula raised $6 million</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/wolt-closes-530m-round-to-continue-expanding-beyond-restaurant-delivery/">Wolt raised $530 million</a></li>
<li>And the hungry SPAC market is only going to get <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/when-spacs-attack-a-new-force-is-invading-wall-street-11611378007?mod=djemalertNEWS"><em>more</em> busy</a> in the coming months. Brace yourself, we are merely a boat on the waves of the news. And this is the latest squall.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hugs, and we are back Thursday, if not before. Stay safe!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST and Thursday afternoon as fast as we can get it out, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts.</i></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/equity-monday-clubhouse-taboola-and-why-the-spac-wave-will-get-worse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099969</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early-stage African VC firm, Microtraction reports portfolio boom despite the weight of COVID-19</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/early-stage-african-vc-firm-microtraction-reports-portfolio-boom-despite-the-weight-of-covid-19/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/early-stage-african-vc-firm-microtraction-reports-portfolio-boom-despite-the-weight-of-covid-19/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 14:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[500 startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google for startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-seed capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a year marred by the coronavirus pandemic, it seems that early-stage startups on the African continent are continuing to see some notable growth, both in terms of their business and from investors looking to back them.  Microtraction, an early-stage venture capital firm based in Lagos, Nigeria, saw funding nearly quadruple for its portfolio. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a year marred by the coronavirus pandemic, it seems that early-stage startups on the African continent are continuing to see some notable growth, both in terms of their business and from investors looking to back them. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.microtraction.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microtraction</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an early-stage venture capital firm based in Lagos, Nigeria, saw funding nearly quadruple for its portfolio.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a </span><a href="https://opentraction.com/microtraction-2020-in-review-2e2a24ed6c3d"><span style="font-weight: 400;">review of the year published</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last week, the firm noted that 21 companies in its portfolio have raised more than $33 million in funding. This represents nearly four-fold growth over a year ago when its portfolio raised $6 million (and just $3 million in 2018). The companies’ combined valuation stands at over $147 million according to the firm.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded by </span><a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/yelebademosi"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yele Badamosi</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2017, Microtraction arrived on the continent&#8217;s early-stage investment scene with all intent to be &#8220;the most accessible and preferred source of pre-seed funding for African tech entrepreneurs.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Badamosi, who returned to Nigeria from the UK in 2015, worked as the general manager for Starta Africa, an online community for African tech entrepreneurs. After his stint there, he saw the need to plug the gap of early-stage funding in Nigeria and the continent at large with Microtraction.</span></p>
<p>Microtraction does not specify the size of its fund, but what is more clear is that <span style="font-weight: 400;">it has attracted a great deal of attention and has built a strong network in part because of who backs it. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/mwseibel?lang=en"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Michael Seibel</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the CEO of Y Combinator, is a global advisor and an investor in the firm, and so is </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andyvolk"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andy Volk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the head of ecosystem for Google Sub-Saharan Africa. Other investors include Pave Investments and US-based angel investor, </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/cbschultz"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chris Schultz</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Being entrepreneurs in the past, some of these investors know what it takes to build a startup in the U.S. But it&#8217;s completely different in Africa. With no on the ground know-how as to which startups to fund but an interest to do so, for portfolio diversification and other personal reasons, Microtraction and a few other early-stage investors present the best bets to accomplish this goal.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At first, Microtraction&#8217;s standard deal was to offer portfolio startups $15,000 in exchange for a 7.5% equity. But as a sign of how the market is firming up, that changed last year and now the firm invests $25,000 for 7% equity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microtraction revealed that it accepted over 500 applications from startups in Nigeria, Ghana, Zambia, and Mauritius in its first full year of operation. Though, just eight of those companies got investments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The introductory batch was all Nigerian. Four fintech startups &#8212; </span><a href="https://cowrywise.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cowrywise</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://riby.me/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Riby</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://wallets.africa/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wallets Africa</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://thankucash.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ThankUCash</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; a crypto-exchange startup, </span><a href="https://buycoins.africa/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">BuyCoins</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; a SaaS platform, Accounteer; an edtech startup, </span><a href="https://schoolable.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Schoolable</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; and healthtech startup, </span><a href="https://54gene.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">54gene</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 saw the local VC firm invest in six companies. This time there was a representative outside Nigeria &#8212; Ghanaian fintech startup, </span><a href="https://bitsika.africa/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitsika</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The Nigerian startups included social commerce startup, </span><a href="https://sendbox.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sendbox</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; events startup, </span><a href="https://twitter.com/festivalcoins?lang=en"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Festival Coins</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; communications-as-a-service platform, </span><a href="https://termii.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Termii</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The rest were unannounced.</span></p>
<h2>Half of its portfolio companies are backed by YC and other global accelerators</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year (the one this latest review covers), Microtraction announced seven startups. The latest selection includes Nigerian fintech startups, </span><a href="https://www.evolvecredit.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evolve Credit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://chaka.ng/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chaka</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; edtech startup, </span><a href="https://gradely.ng/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gradely</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; bus-hailing platform, </span><a href="https://www.plentywaka.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">PlentyWaka</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; and Kenyan credit data marketplace, </span><a href="https://carmachain.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CARMA</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of the total investments raised in 2019 and 2020, 54gene contributed more than half of those numbers by raising $4.5 million in seed and </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/14/african-genomics-startup-54gene-raises-15m-led-by-adjuvant-capital/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$15 million Series A investment</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. With an ingenious solution to solve the underrepresentation of African genomics data in global genomics research, 54gene got accepted into the winter batch in January 2019, the same month it officially launched.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Excluding 54gene, there were </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/20/seven-africa-focused-startups-present-at-y-combinators-demo-day/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">six other African-focused startups</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the YC W19 batch. Two out of the six, Schoolable and Wallets Africa, were Microtraction portfolio companies. Others accepted into YC before and after included BuyCoins, Cowrywise, Termii, and two unannounced startups.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microtraction-backed ThankUCash and a second unannounced startup have also joined cohorts at 500 Startups. On the other hand, Festival Coins is the only startup to be selected into Google for Startups Accelerator. With all accounted for, 11 out of the 21 startups are either backed by Y Combinator, 500 Startups, or Google for Startups.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2099939" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099939" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2099939 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PhotoPictureResizer_210125_143131447_crop_810x577.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="484" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PhotoPictureResizer_210125_143131447_crop_810x577.jpg 810w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PhotoPictureResizer_210125_143131447_crop_810x577.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PhotoPictureResizer_210125_143131447_crop_810x577.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PhotoPictureResizer_210125_143131447_crop_810x577.jpg?resize=768,547 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PhotoPictureResizer_210125_143131447_crop_810x577.jpg?resize=680,484 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PhotoPictureResizer_210125_143131447_crop_810x577.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099939" class="wp-caption-text">The Microtraction team with founding partner, Yele Badamosi (far right)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Getting into these global accelerators is a surefire way to receive follow-up investment, ranging from $125,000 to $150,000. From the outside in, startups see Microtraction and other early-stage VC firms like Ventures Platform as a means to that end. There have also been arguments that these firms build startups to be &#8220;YC or any global accelerator ready.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, </span><a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/natekorl"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dayo Koleowo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a partner at Microtraction alongside <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chidinma-iwueke-b1b8491a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chidinma Iwueke</a>, debunks it saying there&#8217;s no formula behind the numbers we see. He believes YC and other accelerators share the same fundamentals with Microtraction which revolves around the team, the market, and traction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We love super technical teams, understand the industry they are in and are likely to succeed without us. We are always looking for companies that are solving huge problems that a lot of people face,&#8221; he told TechCrunch. &#8220;Also, the tech and startup world moves fast, so we like teams that understand that and can show in real-time that they can execute. I believe that these global accelerators look for these same things.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typically, YC and other accelerators may perform extended due diligence and risk assessments before cutting cheques for any African startup without a local backer. Koleowo points out that this might be why Microtraction portfolio companies get accepted quicker. &#8220;The icing on the cake is that there is a level of de-risking that has been done by Microtraction and other local investors on the ground before these global accelerators step in,&#8221; he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, there&#8217;s no denying the significance of Microtraction&#8217;s advisory board in playing a part as to why half the firm&#8217;s portfolio are in global accelerators. Besides the names mentioned earlier, Lexi Novitske, PIO at Singularity Investments and Dotun Olowoporoku, managing partner at Starta act as regional advisors, and Monique Woodward, a venture partner at 500 Startups is a global advisor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And with the growing trends of globalization, plus the acceptance of a more decentralised approach to building and operations in the tech industry because of COVID-19, it&#8217;s a trend that might continue for a while.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/early-stage-african-vc-firm-microtraction-reports-portfolio-boom-despite-the-weight-of-covid-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099935</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple’s new Fitness+ feature brings celebrity-guided walks to your wrist</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/apples-new-fitness-feature-brings-celebrity-guided-walks-to-your-wrist/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/apples-new-fitness-feature-brings-celebrity-guided-walks-to-your-wrist/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 14:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here’s a bit of a curve ball from Apple. A month-and-a-half or so after launching the Fitness+ app premium workout service, the company’s offering up an add-on intended to offer an exercise dimension beyond the confines of iOS (and your living room). Arriving today for Fitness+ subscribers, Time to Walk is a new, guided walking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Here’s a bit of a curve ball from Apple. A month-and-a-half or so after launching the Fitness+ app premium workout service, the company’s offering up an add-on intended to offer an exercise dimension beyond the confines of iOS (and your living room). Arriving today for Fitness+ subscribers, Time to Walk is a new, guided walking tour hosted by a rotating cast of celebrity guests.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a pretty diverse cast, as evidenced by the first round of names, which are dropping via a software update today. Included in the first five are Dolly Parton – who is probably about as universally beloved a celebrity as exists in 2021 – and Warriors power forward Draymond Green, who is no doubt a less universal, because, well, sports. Also included in the first round are musician Shawn Mendes and <em>Orange is the New Black</em> star Uzo Aduba.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2099964" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099964" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2099964" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-draymond-green_01252021.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099964" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>There are five episodes up front, which will be available as activity cards on the Apple Watch Workout app. In fact, they should start showing as cards in the app&#8217;s feed shortly.  Going forward, they’ll be updated at a pace of one a week.</p>
<p>The experience is straightforward on the face of it. Essentially, Apple asks guests to record themselves on a walk, telling stories and sharing three songs. Music is played through the app and images are delivered to the small screen in an effort to build a semi-immersive (but not distracting) accompaniment for your own walk. You can save the songs on an Apple Music playlist or save the episode for later, if you want to listen again. For those who utilize wheelchairs for mobility, the feature will appear as &#8220;Time to Push,&#8221; which builds on top of the wheelchair-based fitness tracking Apple introduced several year back.</p>
<p>An Apple Fitness+ subscription is required to follow along. That&#8217;s due, in part, to a deeper integration with the premium fitness service. Both are also tied directly into other Apple services, like Music, which the company has made a kind of foundational element of its workouts.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve always been a big walker &#8212; trying to avoid driving or public transit when time and distance allow. But the past year has really prioritized the activity for me as both an excuse to leave my one-bedroom apartment and way to get a workout in with all of the gyms closed for months on end. It is, frankly, a pretty big factor in keeping me going throughout the pandemic.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2099965" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099965" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2099965" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/apple_time-to-walk_apple-watch-uzo-aduba_01252021.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099965" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>When I walk, I do so with music or podcasts. I&#8217;ve tried some &#8220;walking meditations&#8221; in the past, but found that the experiences have revolved around notions of &#8220;quiet reflection,&#8221; which doesn&#8217;t quit do the trick when you&#8217;re walking over the 59th street bridge into midtown Manhattan. Time to Walk turns the idea on its head a bit, by approximating the experience of walking along with someone. As they walk, they relate a kind of stream-of-consciousness, relating often personal stories in the process. The idea of course, being that walking is a head-clearing tool for many &#8212; creatives especially.</p>
<p>“Walking is the most popular physical activity in the world, and one of the healthiest things we can do for our bodies. A walk can often be more than just exercise: It can help clear the mind, solve a problem, or welcome a new perspective,” Apple&#8217;s Jay Blahnik <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/01/time-to-walk-an-inspiring-audio-walking-experience-comes-to-apple-fitness-plus/">said in a release</a>. “Even throughout this challenging period of time, one activity that has remained available to many is walking. With Time to Walk, we’re bringing weekly original content to Apple Watch in Fitness+ that includes some of the most diverse, fascinating, and celebrated guests offering inspiration and entertainment to help our users keep moving through the power of walking.”</p>
<p>Like Fitness+ before it, the new feature is well-timed, as many parts of the world (the U.S. in particular) are still very much in the throes of pandemic-fueled shutdowns. It seems there&#8217;s a new story about a new potential mutation warning us off the sorts of things we used to do every day. Time to Walk is an effort to give you some interesting company for those walks.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EPEu1WDkA5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/fitness-wont-replace-the-gym-but-it-will-help-you-break-a-sweat/">It won’t replace the gym, but Fitness+ will help you break a sweat</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;It won’t replace the gym, but Fitness+ will help you break a sweat&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/fitness-wont-replace-the-gym-but-it-will-help-you-break-a-sweat/embed/#?secret=EPEu1WDkA5" data-secret="EPEu1WDkA5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/apples-new-fitness-feature-brings-celebrity-guided-walks-to-your-wrist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099637</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moderna says it&#8217;s making variant-specific COVID-19 vaccines, but its existing vaccine should still work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/moderna-says-its-making-variant-specific-covid-19-vaccines-but-its-existing-vaccine-should-still-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/moderna-says-its-making-variant-specific-covid-19-vaccines-but-its-existing-vaccine-should-still-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 14:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BioNTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clinical trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oxford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pfizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Moderna has detailed some of the steps it&#8217;s taking to ensure that its vaccine remains effective in the face of emerging strains of the SARS-CoV-2 virus that leads to COVID-19. These include testing how adding a second booster, for a total of three shots, works with its existing COVID-19 vaccine, and also developing a strain-specific [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Moderna has detailed some of the steps it&#8217;s taking to ensure that its vaccine remains effective in the face of emerging strains of the SARS-CoV-2 virus that leads to COVID-19. These include testing how adding a second booster, for a total of three shots, works with its existing COVID-19 vaccine, and also developing a strain-specific variant designed to target spike proteins on the new variants of the virus that were first identified in the UK and in South Africa.</p>
<p>The company is pursuing these measures &#8220;out of an abundance of caution,&#8221; the biotech firm said in <a href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/moderna-covid-19-vaccine-retains-neutralizing-activity-against">a press release</a>, since early studies show that the existing vaccine continues to prove effective against these new strains, albeit with some loss of efficacy specifically with the B.1.351 variant which was first identified in patients in South Africa. Even so, it&#8217;s heartening to see the company moving quickly to address the virus&#8217; mutation, since it&#8217;s likely that similar adaptations will be required longer term to keep COVID-19 in control even once the current pandemic is ended.</p>
<p>Further, Moderna says that in fact, it expects both its forthcoming candidate and its existing booster vaccine should be able to provide additional immunity posting capabilities when used in combination with &#8220;all of the leading vaccine candidates&#8221; on the market. That means the company believes it could be used in combination with the Oxford or Pfizer/BioNTech vaccines to boost immunity, which could be helpful in cases where supplies of one or the other are low and there&#8217;s an urgent need to provide a booster in a timely manner.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The best news of all of this is, of course, that Moderna now has evidence that suggests the mRNA-based vaccine it&#8217;s already providing to people globally will still provide protection against SARS-CoV-2, and by extension, COVID-19. Specifically for the UK variant in particular, the study data shows no reduction in immune performance in patients who received the vaccine. As for the South African variant, that reduction in efficacy mostly translates to a potential of quicker waning of immunity provided by the jab – which hopefully just means people will need another jab sooner than expected, but shouldn&#8217;t lead to any dramatic changes in our combined global approach to providing inoculations, especially initially.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/moderna-says-its-making-variant-specific-covid-19-vaccines-but-its-existing-vaccine-should-still-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099926</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple hit with another European class action over throttled iPhones</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/apple-hit-with-another-european-class-action-over-throttled-iphones/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/apple-hit-with-another-european-class-action-over-throttled-iphones/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 13:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class action lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 6]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A third class action lawsuit has been filed in Europe against Apple seeking compensation &#8212; for what Italy&#8217;s Altroconsumo consumer protection agency dubs &#8220;planned obsolescence&#8221; of a number of iPhone 6 models. The action relates to performance throttling Apple applied several years ago to affected iPhones when the health of the device&#8217;s battery had deteriorated [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A third class action lawsuit has been filed in Europe against Apple seeking compensation &#8212; for what Italy&#8217;s Altroconsumo consumer protection agency dubs &#8220;planned obsolescence&#8221; of a number of iPhone 6 models.</p>
<p>The action relates to performance throttling Apple applied several years ago to affected iPhones when the health of the device&#8217;s battery had deteriorated &#8212; doing so without clearly informing users. It later apologized.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mg1YYnNjqv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/28/apple-apologizes-for-not-being-clearer-about-slowing-down-iphones-with-older-batteries/">Apple apologizes for not telling customers iPhones with older batteries would slow over time</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple apologizes for not telling customers iPhones with older batteries would slow over time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/28/apple-apologizes-for-not-being-clearer-about-slowing-down-iphones-with-older-batteries/embed/#?secret=mg1YYnNjqv" data-secret="mg1YYnNjqv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The class action suit in Italy is seeking €60M in compensation &#8212; based on at least €60 in average compensation per iPhone owner. Affected devices named in the suit are the iPhone 6, 6S, 6 Plus and 6S Plus, per a <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/iapmw8ie3ije/4zMgaeXbZ5sZEqwiSNyVck/dea9914bb631761645b034b120ec7f9f/Euroconsumers_Class_Action_Apple_-_Italy_.pdf">press release</a> put out by the umbrella consumer organization, Euroconsumers, which counts Altroconsumo a a member.</p>
<p>The suit is the third to be filed in the region over the issue &#8212; following suits filed in Belgium and Spain <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/iapmw8ie3ije/6m97Djfmp1oq0sur5Jj3jk/99eae93b117925fd204ebe341131a76c/Euroconsumers_Press_release_Apple_Class_Action_Lawsuits.pdf">last month</a>.</p>
<p>A fourth &#8212; in Portugal &#8212; is slated to be filed shortly.</p>
<p>The tech giant settled similar charges in the US <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/02/apple-agrees-to-settlement-of-up-to-500-million-from-lawsuit-alleging-it-throttled-older-phones/">last year</a> &#8212; where it was accused of intentionally slowing down the performance of older iPhones to encourage customers to buy newer models or fresh batteries &#8212; shelling out $500M, or around $25 per phone, to settle that case (while denying any wrongdoing).</p>
<p>&#8220;When consumers buy Apple iPhones, they expect sustainable quality products. Unfortunately, that is not what happened with the iPhone 6 series. Not only were consumers defrauded, and did they have to face frustration and financial harm, from an environmental point of view it is also utterly irresponsible,&#8221; said Els Bruggeman, Euroconsumers&#8217; head of policy and enforcement, in a statement.</p>
<p>“This new lawsuit is the latest front in our fight against planned obsolescence in Europe. Our ask is simple: American consumers received compensation, European consumers want to be treated with the same fairness and respect.”</p>
<p>Euroconsumers has produced a video (embedded below) to drum up wider support for the class actions in which it satirizes Apple&#8217;s &#8220;genius&#8221; in coming up with clever ways to accelerate its products&#8217; end of life&#8230;</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/TsJ0quKrMqY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Apple has been contacted for comment on the European class actions.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/07/apple-fined-27-million-for-throttling-old-iphones-without-telling-users/">Almost a year</a> ago the company was fined €25M by France&#8217;s competition watchdog over an iOS update that capped performance of aging devices. It was also made to display a statement regarding the action on its website for a month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PLP1mi4K2J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/07/apple-fined-27-million-for-throttling-old-iphones-without-telling-users/">Apple fined $27 million in France for throttling old iPhones without telling users</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple fined $27 million in France for throttling old iPhones without telling users&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/07/apple-fined-27-million-for-throttling-old-iphones-without-telling-users/embed/#?secret=PLP1mi4K2J" data-secret="PLP1mi4K2J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/apple-hit-with-another-european-class-action-over-throttled-iphones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proving voicemail doesn&#8217;t have to be wack, the Slack-backed startup Yac raises $7.5 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/proving-voicemail-doesnt-have-to-be-wack-the-slack-backed-startup-yac-raises-7-5-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/proving-voicemail-doesnt-have-to-be-wack-the-slack-backed-startup-yac-raises-7-5-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 13:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Active Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Draper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ggv capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groupware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orlando]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Product Hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yac]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yac, the Orlando, Fla.-based startup that&#8217;s digitizing voice messages for remote offices, has raised $7.5 million in a new round of funding. The company&#8217;s service has garnered enough attention to pick up a pretty sizable new round from investors led by GGV Capital and a return investment from the Slack Fund. Apparently, reinventing voicemail is a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.yac.com/">Yac</a>, the Orlando, Fla.-based startup that&#8217;s digitizing voice messages for remote offices, has raised $7.5 million in a new round of funding.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s service has garnered enough attention to pick up a pretty sizable new round from investors led by <a href="https://www.ggvc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.ggvc.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1611662714445000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHtJNAUe7dFIqzHbxw3ZeCDgyOPwg">GGV Capital</a> and a return investment from <a href="https://slack.com/fund" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://slack.com/fund&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1611662714445000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEft9Wh-da_8gYkjWv9exVq8y27Uw">the Slack Fund</a>.</p>
<p>Apparently, reinventing voicemail is a multi-million dollar endeavor.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The future of meetings will be asynchronous, in your ears and hands free,” says Pat Matthews, the chief executive and founder of Active Capital, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/yac-is-reinventing-voicemail-for-the-slack-generation/">when the company announced its seed round nearly a year ago</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CdsNVNJxjW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/yac-is-reinventing-voicemail-for-the-slack-generation/">Yac is reinventing voicemail for the Slack generation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Yac is reinventing voicemail for the Slack generation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/yac-is-reinventing-voicemail-for-the-slack-generation/embed/#?secret=CdsNVNJxjW" data-secret="CdsNVNJxjW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Co-founded by Justin Mitchell, Hunter McKinley and Jordan Walker, Yac was spun out of the digital agency SoFriendly, and was developed as a pitch for Product Hunt&#8217;s Maker Festival. The voice messaging service won that startup competition at the event and attracted the interest of Boost VC and its founder, the third-generation venture capitalist Adam Draper.</p>
<p>About six months after that seed round, Yac received outreach from Slack thanks to a referral from another entrepreneur. Throughout their negotiations last year, the teams used Yac to conduct due diligence, according to Mitchell. At the time of the company&#8217;s August announcement that Slack had come on to finance the company, Yac had a bit over 5,000 users on its service and charges per seat, in the same way Slack does.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/proving-voicemail-doesnt-have-to-be-wack-the-slack-backed-startup-yac-raises-7-5-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099913</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok has until Friday to respond to Italy&#8217;s order to block users it can&#8217;t age-verify after girl&#8217;s death</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 12:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok has until Friday to respond to an order by Italy&#8217;s data protection agency to block users whose age it cannot verify, TechCrunch has learned. The GPDP made an &#8216;immediate&#8217; order Friday in response to the death of a 10-year-old girl from Palermo who died of asphyxiation after participating in a &#8216;blackout challenge&#8217; on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok has until Friday to respond to an order by Italy&#8217;s data protection agency to block users whose age it cannot verify, TechCrunch has learned.</p>
<p>The GPDP made an &#8216;immediate&#8217; order <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9524224">Friday</a> in response to the death of a 10-year-old girl from Palermo who died of asphyxiation after participating in a &#8216;blackout challenge&#8217; on the social network, according to reports in local media.</p>
<p>The agency said the ban would remain place until February 15 &#8212; suggesting it would make another assessment about any additional action at that point.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At the time of writing it does not appear that TikTok has taken action to comply with the GPDP&#8217;s order.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman told us it is reviewing the notification. &#8220;We have received and are currently reviewing the notification from Garante,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Privacy and safety are top priorities for TikTok and we are constantly strengthening our policies, processes and technologies to protect all users, and our younger users in particular.&#8221;</p>
<p>The GPDP had already raised concerns about children&#8217;s privacy on TikTok, warning in <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9508923">December</a> that its age verification checks are easily circumvented and raising objections over default settings that make users&#8217; content public. On December 22 it also announced it had opened a formal procedure &#8212; giving TikTok 30 days to respond.</p>
<p>The order to block users whose age it cannot verify is in addition to that action. If TikTok does not comply with the GPDP&#8217;s administrative order it could face enforcement from the Italian agency, drawing on penalty powers set out in the GDPR.</p>
<p>TikTok&#8217;s spokeswoman declined to answer additional questions about the order &#8212; which prohibits it from further processing user data &#8220;for whom there is no absolute certainty of age&#8221;, per GPDP&#8217;s <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9524224">press release</a> Friday.</p>
<p>The company also did not respond when we asked if it had submitted a response to the agency&#8217;s formal procedure.</p>
<p>In a statement last week following the girl&#8217;s death the company said: &#8220;Our deepest sympathies are with the girl&#8217;s family and friends. At TikTok, the safety of our community &#8212; in particular our younger users &#8212; is our priority, and we do not allow content that encourages, promotes, or glorifies dangerous behaviour that might lead to injury. We offer robust safety controls and resources for teens and families on our platform, and we regularly evolve our policies and protections in our ongoing commitment to our community.&#8221;</p>
<p>TikTok has said it has found no evidence of any challenge involving asphyxiation on its platform.</p>
<p>Although, in recent years, there have been a number of <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/tiktok-challenge-boy-hangs-self-wearing-mangalsutra-bangles-kota-rajasthan-1553087-2019-06-20">previous</a> <a href="https://sg.style.yahoo.com/mum-finds-4-old-hanging-134436062.html">reports</a> of underage users hanging themselves (or attempting to) after trying to copy things they saw on the platform.</p>
<p>Users frequently create and respond to content challenges, as part of TikTok&#8217;s viral appeal &#8212; such as (recently) a trend for singing sea shanties.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, a search on the platform for &#8216;#blackoutchallenge&#8217; returns no user content but displays a warning that the phrase &#8220;may be associated with behavior or content that violates our guidelines&#8221;.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2099906" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099906" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2099906" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-25-at-12.26.53.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="326" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-25-at-12.26.53.png 1322w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-25-at-12.26.53.png?resize=150,72 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-25-at-12.26.53.png?resize=300,144 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-25-at-12.26.53.png?resize=768,368 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-25-at-12.26.53.png?resize=680,326 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screenshot-2021-01-25-at-12.26.53.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099906" class="wp-caption-text">Screengrab of the warning users see if they search for &#8216;blackout challenge&#8217; (Image credit: TechCrunch)</p></div></p>
<p>There have been TikTok challenges related to &#8216;hanging&#8217; (as in people hanging by parts of their body other than their neck from/off objects) &#8212; and a search for <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/hangingchallenge?lang=en">#hangingchallenge</a> does still return results (including some users discussing the death of the 10-year-old girl).</p>
<p>Last year a number of users also participated in an event on the platform in which they posted images of black squares &#8212; using the hashtag #BlackOutTuesday &#8212; which related to Black Lives Matters protests.</p>
<p>So the term &#8216;blackout&#8217; has similarly been used on TikTok in relation to encouraging others to post content. Though not in that case in relation to asphyxiation.</p>
<p>Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission, which has been lined up as TikTok&#8217;s lead data supervisor in Europe &#8212; following the company&#8217;s <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-gb/updates-we-are-making-to-our-terms-of-service-and-privacy-policy">announcement</a> last year that its Irish entity would take over legal responsibility for processing European users&#8217; data &#8212; does not have an open inquiry into the platform &#8220;at present&#8221;, per a spokesman.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But TikTok is already facing a number of other investigations and legal challenges in Europe, including an investigation into how the app handles users data by France&#8217;s watchdog CNIL &#8212; announced </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/tiktok-is-being-investigated-by-frances-data-watchdog/">last summer</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">.</span></p>
<p>In recent years, France&#8217;s CNIL has been responsible for handing out some of the largest penalties for tech giants for infringing EU data protection laws (including fines for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/19/french-court-slaps-down-googles-appeal-against-57m-gdpr-fine/">Google</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/">Amazon</a>).</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55497350">December</a>, it also emerged that a 12-year-old girl in the UK is bringing a legal challenge against TikTok &#8212; claiming it uses children&#8217;s data unlawfully. A court ruled she can remain anonymous if the case goes ahead.</p>
<p>Last month Ireland&#8217;s data protection regulator put out <a href="https://www.dataprotection.ie/index.php/en/news-media/consultations/children-front-and-centre-fundamentals-child-oriented-approach-data-processing">draft guidelines</a> on what it couched as &#8220;the Fundamentals for a Child-Oriented Approach to Data Processing&#8221; &#8212; with the stated aim of driving improvements in standards of data processing related to minors.</p>
<p>While the GDPR typically requires data protection complaints to be funnelled through a lead agency, under the one-stop-shop mechanism, Italy&#8217;s GPDP&#8217;s order to TikTok to cease processing is possible under powers set out in the regulation (Article 66) that allow for &#8216;urgency procedures&#8217; to be undertaken by national watchdogs in instances of imperative risk.</p>
<p>Although any such provisional measures can only last for three months &#8212; and only apply to the country where the DPA has jurisdiction (Italy in this case). Ireland&#8217;s DPC would be the EU agency responsible for leading any resulting investigation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Lx8V2yj1Nl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/tiktok-is-being-investigated-by-frances-data-watchdog/">TikTok is being investigated by France&#8217;s data watchdog</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok is being investigated by France&#8217;s data watchdog&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/tiktok-is-being-investigated-by-frances-data-watchdog/embed/#?secret=Lx8V2yj1Nl" data-secret="Lx8V2yj1Nl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099904</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wolt closes $530M round to continue expanding beyond restaurant delivery</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/wolt-closes-530m-round-to-continue-expanding-beyond-restaurant-delivery/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/wolt-closes-530m-round-to-continue-expanding-beyond-restaurant-delivery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 12:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eqt ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs Growth Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[helsinki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Highland Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pharmaceuticals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vintage Investment Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wolt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wolt, the Helsinki-based online ordering and delivery company that initially focused on restaurants but has since expanded to other verticals, has raised $530 million in new funding. The round was led by Iconiq Growth, with participation from Tiger Global, DST, KKR, Prosus, EQT Growth and Coatue. Previous backers 83North, Highland Europe, Goldman Sachs Growth Equity, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://wolt.com/en">Wolt</a>, the Helsinki-based online ordering and delivery company that initially focused on restaurants but has since expanded to other verticals, has raised $530 million in new funding. The round was led by Iconiq Growth, with participation from Tiger Global, DST, KKR, Prosus, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/carolina-brochado-eqt-growth/">EQT Growth</a> and Coatue.</p>
<p>Previous backers 83North, Highland Europe, Goldman Sachs Growth Equity, EQT Ventures and Vintage Investment Partners also followed on. The new round takes the total amount of financing Wolt has raised to $856 million. Wolt declined to disclose the company&#8217;s latest valuation, although we know from the previous D round that the company is one of Europe&#8217;s so-called unicorns.</p>
<p>“We operate in an extremely competitive and well-funded industry, and this round allows us to have a long-term mindset when it comes to doubling down on our different markets,” says co-founder and CEO Miki Kuusi in a statement. “Despite the turbulence of 2020, we’ve remained focused on growth, tripling our revenue to a preliminary $330 against a net loss of just $38 million. Compared to the $670 million in new capital that we’ve raised during this year, this puts us into a strong position for investing in our people, technology, and markets when thinking about the next few years ahead”.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eY9pf7rbSw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/carolina-brochado-eqt-growth/">Former Atomico and SoftBank VC Carolina Brochado has joined EQT to help build its new growth fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Former Atomico and SoftBank VC Carolina Brochado has joined EQT to help build its new growth fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/carolina-brochado-eqt-growth/embed/#?secret=eY9pf7rbSw" data-secret="eY9pf7rbSw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Since launching with 10 restaurants in its home city in 2015, five years on Wolt has expanded to 23 countries and 120 cities, mostly in Europe but also including Japan and Israel. More recently, like others in the restaurant delivery space, Wolt has expanded beyond restaurants and takeout food into the grocery and retail sectors. This, says the company, sees it offer anything from cosmetics to pet food and pharmaceuticals on its platform.</p>
<p>“This was mostly a primary raise,” Kuusi tells me when I ask if the new round includes secondary funding (i.e. shareholders that exited to new investors). “We&#8217;re not looking to disclose the valuation at this time, but we&#8217;ve previously shared that the Series D round that we raised in early 2020 valued that company at above €1 billion,” he adds.</p>
<p>Kuusi says that the latest funding round is based on the belief that local services in the offline world will gradually be brought online by players “that can execute and maintain a great customer experience”. “We started with an exclusive focus on the restaurant, as it&#8217;s the biggest local service with an underlying high-frequency use case,” he says. “We quickly learnt that the magical product market fit for bringing the restaurant online was to offer a quick and predictable delivery experience from restaurants that didn&#8217;t use to be available for delivery. We do this by handling the complexity of the delivery on the restaurant&#8217;s behalf”.</p>
<p>However, this was especially difficult to do efficiently and sustainably in small and difficult home market in the Nordics. To solve this, Wolt needed to build an “optimization-heavy logistics setup for last-mile delivery” that Kuusi says lets the service operate even in “very small cities with low income disparity, limited population density and high labor costs”.</p>
<p>“This means that we can operate efficiently even with relatively low order volumes, enabling us to grow and expand rapidly with much less financing than some of the other players in the market. We simply had no other choice than to do it this way was we came from such a difficult home market”.</p>
<p>On this foundation, Wolt is expanding into other ordering and local delivery verticals, aiming to be what Kuusi dubs as “the everything app” of goods and services. “Today, Wolt is much more than a restaurant delivery service, you can order groceries, electronics, flowers, clothes and many other things on our platform,” he explains. “We believe that the future of how people buy Nike shoes is a few taps on Wolt and some 30 minutes later you get any pair of shoes brought to your door. This is what we strive to make into a reality with our team at Wolt”. (I’m an Adidas guy myself, steadfastly European.)</p>
<p>Asked what he thinks about all the money being pumped into the dark convenience store model, Kuusi says Wolt is investing into its own dark store operation called Wolt Market. “It&#8217;s not surprising to also see a growing amount of financing going into this sector,&#8221; he admits. &#8220;We&#8217;re huge believers in a hybrid model where there will be both offline/online retailers as well as focused online retailers in the mix. Obviously the latter category is only getting started, and we should see a massive amount of growth for the coming years ahead”.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mmX3tm9dB3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/">Gorillas, the on-demand grocery delivery startup taking Berlin by storm, has raised $44M Series A</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gorillas, the on-demand grocery delivery startup taking Berlin by storm, has raised $44M Series A&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/gorillas/embed/#?secret=mmX3tm9dB3" data-secret="mmX3tm9dB3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/wolt-closes-530m-round-to-continue-expanding-beyond-restaurant-delivery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099911</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taboola is going public via SPAC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/taboola-is-going-public-via-spac/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/taboola-is-going-public-via-spac/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special-purpose acquisition company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taboola]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taboola is the latest company seeking to go public via special purpose acquisition corporation — more commonly known as a SPAC. To achieve this, it will merge with ION Acquisition Corp, which went public in 2020 with the aim of funding an Israeli tech acquisition (Haaretz reported last month that Taboola was in talks with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.taboola.com">Taboola</a> is the latest company seeking to go public via special purpose acquisition corporation — more commonly known as a SPAC.</p>
<p>To achieve this, it will merge with ION Acquisition Corp, which went public in 2020 with the aim of funding an Israeli tech acquisition (<a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/tech-news/.premium-exclusive-taboola-in-talks-for-ion-spac-merge-1.9395460">Haaretz reported last month that Taboola</a> was in talks with ION). The transaction is expected to close in the second quarter, and the combined company will trade on the New York Stock Exchange under the ticker symbol TBLA.</p>
<p>Founded in 2007, Taboola powers content recommendation widgets (and advertising on those widgets) across 9,000 websites for publishers including CNBC, NBC News, Business Insider, The Independent and El Mundo. It says it reaches 516 million daily active users while working with more than 13,000 advertisers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company had previously planned to merge with competitor Outbrain before the deal was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/taboola-and-outbrain-call-off-their-850m-merger/">canceled last fall</a>, with sources pointing to the market impact of the COVID-19 pandemic, a &#8220;challenging culture fit&#8221; and regulatory issues to explain the deal&#8217;s end.</p>
<p>Taboola&#8217;s founder and CEO Adam Singolda (pictured above) told me that this didn&#8217;t lead directly the SPAC deal. But he said, &#8220;I always wanted to go public,&#8221; which wasn&#8217;t possible while the merger was in the works. Once that deal was called off, and with 2020 turning out to be a strong year for Taboola — it&#8217;s projecting revenue of $1.2 billion, including $375 million ex-TAC revenue (revenue after paying publishers), with over $100 million in adjusted EBITDA — the time seemed right, and ION seemed like the right partner.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EP8OwCZ8HR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/taboola-and-outbrain-call-off-their-850m-merger/">Taboola and Outbrain call off their $850M merger</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Taboola and Outbrain call off their $850M merger&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/08/taboola-and-outbrain-call-off-their-850m-merger/embed/#?secret=EP8OwCZ8HR" data-secret="EP8OwCZ8HR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We believe Taboola is an open web recommendation leader which is well positioned to challenge the walled gardens,&#8221; said ION CEO Gilad Shany in a statement. &#8220;We were looking to merge with a global technology leader with Israeli DNA and we found that in Taboola. The combination of long-term partnerships built by the company with thousands of open web digital properties, their direct access to advertisers, massive global reach and proven AI technology, allows Taboola to provide significant value to their partners while also achieving attractive unit economics as the company grows.&#8221;</p>
<p>The deal will value Taboola at $2.6 billion. Through this transaction, the company plans to raise a total of $545 million, including $285 million in PIPE financing secured from Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company, Baron Capital Group, funds and accounts managed by Hedosophia, the Federated Hermes Kaufmann Funds and others.</p>
<p>Singolda said that the company plans to invest $100 million in R&amp;D this year, and that he hopes to expand the technology into areas like e-commerce and TV advertising, with the goal of moving &#8220;beyond the browser.&#8221; More broadly, he said he wants Taboola to be be &#8220;a strong public company that champions the open web.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The open web is a $64 billion advertising market [according to Taboola estimates], but there&#8217;s no Google for the open web,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Yes, Google itself spends plenty of time <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/22/google-proposes-new-privacy-and-anti-fingerprinting-controls-for-the-web/">talking about similar ideas</a>, but Singolda argued that while Google has consumer products like search and YouTube that compete with other publishers for time and attention, &#8220;Taboola is not in the consumer business &#8230; We serve our partners, and it&#8217;s in our identity to drive audience growth, engagement and revenue.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Etgp41TCvM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/almost-everything-you-need-to-know-about-spacs/">Almost everything you need to know about SPACs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Almost everything you need to know about SPACs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/almost-everything-you-need-to-know-about-spacs/embed/#?secret=Etgp41TCvM" data-secret="Etgp41TCvM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/taboola-is-going-public-via-spac/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google pledges grants and facilities for COVID-19 vaccine programs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/google-pledges-grants-and-facilities-for-covid-19-vaccine-programs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/google-pledges-grants-and-facilities-for-covid-19-vaccine-programs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 10:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine distribution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google said today it is taking several steps to help with COVID-19 vaccine distribution in the United States, including grants and opening its facilities to vaccination programs. The tech giant is among several other large corporations, including Amazon, Walmart, Starbucks and Microsoft, that have pledged support to local government agencies and medical providers to help [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google <a href="https://blog.google/technology/health/vaccines-how-were-helping/">said today</a> it is taking several steps to help with COVID-19 vaccine distribution in the United States, including grants and opening its facilities to vaccination programs. The tech giant is among <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/01/22/retailers-coronavirus-vaccine-distribution/">several other large corporations</a>, including Amazon, Walmart, Starbucks and Microsoft, that have pledged support to local government agencies and medical providers to help increase vaccinations.</p>
<p>Google will pledge ad grants and funding worth a total of $150 million to health organizations and public health agencies to promote vaccine education. It will also provide support for vaccine distribution by making Google facilities available, including buildings and parking lots.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6hS5NoU3YC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/amazon-offers-biden-resources-for-covid-19-vaccine-rollout/">Amazon offers Biden resources for COVID-19 vaccine rollout</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon offers Biden resources for COVID-19 vaccine rollout&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/amazon-offers-biden-resources-for-covid-19-vaccine-rollout/embed/#?secret=6hS5NoU3YC" data-secret="6hS5NoU3YC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company said it partnering with One Medical and public health authorities to open vaccination sites in Los Angeles and the San Francisco Bay Area in California; Kirkland, Washington; and New York City, with more sites planned in the U.S. depending on vaccine availability. Its technology, including the Intelligent Vaccine Impact Platform, is being used to help with logistics planning for vaccine distribution.</p>
<p>In terms of funding, about $100 million will be part of Google’s Ad Grants Crisis Relief program, and go to non-profits like the CDC Foundation and the World Health Organization. Another $50 million will be invested &#8220;in partnership with public health agencies to reach underserved communities with vaccine-related content and information,&#8221; the company said. Google.org has committed about $5 million in grants to organizations focused on access to vaccines among people of color and in rural areas, including the Morehouse School of Medicine&#8217;s Satcher Health Leadership Institute and the CDC Foundation.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lVuJIu3G9i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/">Tech and health companies including Microsoft and Salesforce team up on digital COVID-19 vaccination records</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech and health companies including Microsoft and Salesforce team up on digital COVID-19 vaccination records&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/embed/#?secret=lVuJIu3G9i" data-secret="lVuJIu3G9i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/google-pledges-grants-and-facilities-for-covid-19-vaccine-programs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099900</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virtual social network IMVU raises $35M from China&#8217;s NetEase and others</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/imvu-35-million-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/imvu-35-million-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avatar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IMVU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual network]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The line between social networking and gaming is increasingly blurring, and internet incumbents are taking notice. NetEase, the second-largest gaming company in China behind Tencent, is among a group of investors who just backed IMVU, an avatar-focused social network operating out of California. Menlo Park-based Structural Capital among other institutions also joined in the strategic [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The line between social networking and gaming is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/26/why-social-networks-want-even-more-gaming/">increasingly blurring</a>, and internet incumbents are taking notice. NetEase, the <a href="https://newzoo.com/insights/rankings/top-25-companies-game-revenues/">second-largest gaming company</a> in China behind Tencent, is among a group of investors who just backed IMVU, an avatar-focused social network operating out of California.</p>
<p>Menlo Park-based Structural Capital among other institutions also joined in the strategic round totaling $35 million. IMVU has raised over $77 million from five rounds since it was co-founded by <a href="https://www.inc.com/magazine/201110/eric-ries-usability-testing-product-development.html"><em>The Lean Startup </em>author Eric Ries</a> back in 2004. The company declined to disclose its post-money valuation.</p>
<p>The fresh investment will be used to fund IMVU&#8217;s product development and comes fresh off a restructuring at the company. A new parent organization called Together Labs was formed to oversee its flagship platform IMVU, in which users can create virtual rooms and chat with strangers using custom avatars, a product that&#8217;s today considered by some a dating platform; a new service called Vcoin that lets users buy, gift, earn and convert a digital asset from the IMVU platform into fiat; among other virtual services.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;NetEase operates some of the most successful, biggest in scale, and evergreen MMO [massively multiplayer online] games in China and they see in IMVU business highlights echoing theirs,&#8221; Daren Tsui, chief executive officer at Together Labs, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>&#8220;IMVU operates one of the world’s oldest, yet most vibrant and young &#8212; in terms of our user base &#8212; metaverses. We have many shared business philosophies and complementary know-how. It is a natural fit for us to become partners,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Founded in 2005, NetEase is now known for its news portal, music streaming app, education products, and video games that compete with those of Tencent. It has over the years made a handful of minority investments in companies outside China, though it&#8217;s not nearly as aggressive as Tencent in terms of investment pace and volume.</p>
<p>A NetEase spokesperson declined to comment on the investment in IMVU.</p>
<p>The partnership, according to Tsui, would allow the virtual networking company to tap NetEase&#8217;s game development and engineering capabilities as well as leverage NetEase&#8217;s knowledge in global market strategy as Together Labs launches future products, including one called WithMe.</p>
<p>In 2020, IMVU saw record growth with over 7 million monthly active users and 400,000 products created every month by IMVU users. The service currently has a footprint in over 140 countries and is &#8220;always looking to expand&#8221; in existing markets, including Asia, in which it already has a localized Korean app, according to Tsui.</p>
<p>&#8220;With IMVU’s accelerating growth over recent years, the launch of VCOIN, and the development of the new WithMe platform, we felt timing was right to bring all of these products under a new roof to reinforce our commitment for creating authentic human connections in virtual spaces,&#8221; said the chief executive.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/imvu-35-million-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sano Genetics, a startup helping with Long Covid research, raises £2.5M in seed funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/sano-genetics/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/sano-genetics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cambridge Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cambridge university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetic testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genomics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multiple sclerosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parkinson's Disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sano Genetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SeedCamp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2098538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sano Genetics, a startup with a broad mission to support personalised medicine research by increasing participation in clinical trials, has raised £2.5 million in seed funding. The round is led by Episode1 Ventures, alongside Seedcamp, Cambridge Enterprise, January Ventures, and several Europe and U S.-based angel investors. It adds to £500,000 in pre-seed funding in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://sanogenetics.com/">Sano Genetics</a>, a startup with a broad mission to support personalised medicine research by increasing participation in clinical trials, has raised £2.5 million in seed funding.</p>
<p>The round is led by Episode1 Ventures, alongside Seedcamp, Cambridge Enterprise, January Ventures, and several Europe and U S.-based angel investors. It adds to £500,000 in pre-seed funding in 2018.</p>
<p>Sano Genetics says part of the new capital will be to fund free at-home DNA testing kits for 3,000 people affected by Long Covid. It will also further invest in the development of its tech platform and grow the team</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in 2017 by Charlotte Guzzo, Patrick Short and William Jones after they met at Cambridge University while studying genomics as postgrads, Sano Genetics has built what it describes as a &#8220;private-by-design&#8221; tech platform to help patients take part in medical research and clinical trials. This includes at-home genetic testing capabilities, and is seeing the company support research into multiple sclerosis, ankylosing spondylitis, NAFLD, and ulcerative colitis2, with a research programme for Parkinson&#8217;s disease on the agenda for later in 2021.</p>
<p>“For participants in medical research, the process is not user friendly,” says Sano Genetics CEO Patrick Short.  “There is usually little to no benefit for participants beyond altruism, taking part is difficult and time consuming, and people are also concerned about the privacy of their sensitive genetic and medical information.</p>
<p>“[Therefore], for researchers in biotech, pharma, and academia, it is very difficult to attract and retain research participants, which adds substantial costs and time to their research. In particular for research involving genetics and precision therapies, it is doubly challenging to find the ‘right’ patients because genetic testing is not routine in the healthcare system”.</p>
<p>To help solve this, Sano Genetics matches relevant participants to research via its platform. It then makes participation easier by enabling at-home genetic testing and by guiding participants through the process.</p>
<p>“The system is designed so users know exactly what will happen with their data, and we give them straightforward ways to control their data,” explains Short. “We keep our users engaged and involved in the research process by giving them updates on the research they have been a part of, and with free personalised content including genetic reports, and stories from other people like them on our blog”.</p>
<p>A typical end user is someone who has a chronic or rare disease and is using the platform to take part in research that helps them personally (e.g. access to a new therapy via a clinical trial) or to help others like them.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Sano Genetics generates revenue by charging biotech and pharma companies fees to find the right patients for their studies. “The typical study for us consists of a set-up fee, a per-test fee for our at-home genetic testing and analysis, and a fee for each referral we make of an interested and eligible participant to their research study,” adds the Sano Genetics CEO.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/sano-genetics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2098538</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kenyan insurtech startup Pula raises $6M Series A to derisk smallholder farmers across Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/kenyan-insurtech-startup-pula-raises-6m-series-a-led-by-tlcom-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/kenyan-insurtech-startup-pula-raises-6m-series-a-led-by-tlcom-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 09:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pula]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tlcom Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pula, a Kenyan insurtech startup that specialises in digital and agricultural insurance to derisk millions of smallholder farmers across Africa, has closed a Series A investment of $6 million. The round was led by Pan-African early-stage venture capital firm,  TLcom Capital, with participation from nonprofit Women’s World Banking. The raise comes after Pula closed $1 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.pula-advisors.com/">Pula</a>, a Kenyan insurtech startup that specialises in digital and agricultural insurance to derisk millions of smallholder farmers across Africa, has closed a Series A investment of $6 million.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round was led by Pan-African early-stage venture capital firm, </span><a href="https://tlcomcapital.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">TLcom Capital</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, with participation from nonprofit</span> <a href="https://www.womensworldbanking.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Women’s World Banking</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The raise comes after Pula closed $1 million in seed investment from Rocher Participations with support from Accion Venture Lab, Omidyar Network and several angel investors in 2018.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded by </span><a href="https://ke.linkedin.com/in/rose-goslinga-523926b3"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rose Goslinga</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://ke.linkedin.com/in/thomas-njeru-75850028"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thomas Njeru</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2015, Pula delivers agricultural insurance and digital products to help smallholder farmers navigate climate risks, improve their farming practices and bolster their incomes over time.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Agriculture insurance has traditionally relied on farm business. In the U.S. or Europe with typically large farms, an average insurance premium is $1,000. But in Africa, where smallholding or small-scale farms are the norms, the number stands at an average of $4.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is particularly telling that the value of agricultural insurance premiums in Africa represents less than 1 percent of the world&#8217;s total when the continent has 17 percent of the world&#8217;s arable land. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This disparity stems from the fact that the traditional method of calculating insurance through farm visits is often unaffordable for these smallholder farmers. Thus, they are often neglected from financial protection against climate risks like flood, drought, pestilence and hail.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pula is solving this problem by using technology and data. Through its</span><a href="https://www.pula-advisors.com/products-and-services/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Area Yield Index Insurance</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> product, the insurtech startup leverages machine learning, crop cuts experiments and data points relating to weather patterns and farmer losses, to build products that cater to various risks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But getting farmers on board has never been easy, Goslinga told TechCrunch. According to her, Pula has understood not to sell insurance directly to small-scale farmers, because they can suffer from optimism bias. “Some think a climate disaster wouldn’t hit their farms for a particular season; hence, they don&#8217;t ask for insurance initially. But if they witness any of these climate risks during the season, they would want to get insurance, which is counterproductive to Pula,” said the founder in a phone call.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2099839" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099839" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2099839 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1282" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg?resize=1536,1026 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Farmer-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099839" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pula</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So the startup instead partners with banks. Banks provide loans to farmers and make it compulsory for them to have insurance. With the loan, banks can pay the insurance on behalf of the farmers at the start of the season. But at the end of the season, the farmer has to repay the loan with interest.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The unit economics doesn’t work for us to work with farmers directly. But with banks, we know they provide loans to farmers with much better margins to pay for insurance. Also, we work together with government subsidy programs since they&#8217;re also interested in protecting their farmers.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through its partnerships with banks, governments and agricultural input companies, Pula is at the center of an ecosystem that provides insurance to smallholder farmers and has amassed 50 insurance partners and six reinsurance partners. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its clientele includes the likes of the World Food Programme and Central Bank of Nigeria as well as the Zambian and Kenyan governments.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Social enterprises like One Acre Fund, startups like Apollo Agriculture, and agribusiness giants like Flour Mills and Export Trading Group are also among Pula’s clients.</span></p>
<h2>Co-CEOs with agricultural backgrounds</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When Goslinga met Njeru in 2008, she worked for Syngenta Foundation for Sustainable Agriculture (SFSA). There, she started </span><a href="https://kilimosalama.wordpress.com/about/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kilimo Salama</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, as a micro-insurance program for more than 200,000 farmers in Kenya and Rwanda. She met Njeru who was the lead actuary at UAP Insurance, a partner to the Kilimo Salama program, at the time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After staying with Syngenta for six years and recognising the need to provide standard insurance products for smallholder farmers, Goslinga left to start Pula with Njeru in 2015. However, it wasn&#8217;t until two years later that Njeru joined fulltime as he had a six-year engagement with Deloitte South Africa from 2012 as a consultant actuary. The pair both act as co-CEOs.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;When Thomas and I launched Pula in 2015, we had one goal in mind: to build and deliver scalable insurance solutions for Africa’s 700 million smallholder farmers,&#8221; Goslinga said. &#8220;With our latest funding, now is the time to break into new ground. In our five years since launching, we’ve built strong traction for our products. However, the fact remains that across Africa and other emerging markets, there are still millions of smallholder farmers with risks to their livelihoods that have not been covered.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Goslinga, the COVID-19 pandemic helped Pula double its footprint and size as rural farming activities and operations continued despite pandemic-induced lockdowns. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2099838" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099838" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2099838 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="431" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg 1777w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg?resize=300,190 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg?resize=768,486 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg?resize=680,431 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg?resize=1536,972 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Pula-Co-Founders-and-Co-CEOs-Thomas-Njeru-Rose-Goslinga-1.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099838" class="wp-caption-text">Pula co-founders and Co-CEOs (Rose Goslinga and Thomas Njeru)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, the new financing will scale up operations in its existing 13 markets across Africa, where it has insured over 4.3 million farmers. They include Senegal, Ghana, Mali, Nigeria, Ethiopia, Madagascar, Tanzania, Kenya, Rwanda, Uganda, Zambia, Malawi and Mozambique. Likewise, the Kenyan startup hopes to propel its expansion for smallholder farmers in Asia and Latin America.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pula is one of the few African startups disrupting the farming industry with technology. Its Series A investment attests that investors&#8217; appetite for agritech startups is still on the rise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A week ago, Aerobotics, a South African startup that uses artificial intelligence to help farmers protect their trees and fruits from risks, raised a Series B round of $17 million. Last month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/sunculture-wants-to-turn-africa-into-the-worlds-next-bread-basket-one-solar-water-pump-at-a-time/">SunCulture, a Kenyan startup</a> that provides solar power systems, water pumps and irrigation systems for small-scale farmers, raised $14 million. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lESAzrBFSm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/south-africa-startup-aerobotics-raises-17m-led-by-naspers-foundry/">South African startup Aerobotics raises $17M to scale its AI-for-agriculture platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;South African startup Aerobotics raises $17M to scale its AI-for-agriculture platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/south-africa-startup-aerobotics-raises-17m-led-by-naspers-foundry/embed/#?secret=lESAzrBFSm" data-secret="lESAzrBFSm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another startup is Apollo Agriculture <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/kenyas-apollo-agriculture-raises-6m-series-a-led-by-anthemis/">which raised $6 million Series A</a>, akin to Pula. Not only did the pair raise the same round, Apollo Agriculture and Pula both deal with providing financial resources to smallholder farmers. But while both companies might look like competitors, even to the admission of Goslinga, she argues that the startups are partners and complement each other.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As part of the new fundraise, TLcom’s senior partner </span><a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/omobola-johnson-b12461183"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Omobola Johnson</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will join Pula’s board. However, it was her colleague, <a href="https://ke.linkedin.com/in/maurizio-caio-1580a97" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maurizio Caio</a>, the firm&#8217;s managing partner, who had something to say about the round. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The potential for the insurance market for smallholder farmers in Africa is huge, and under the leadership of Rose and Thomas, Pula has rapidly established a strong presence throughout the continent and has several high-profile clients on their books. We are confident of Pula’s potential for growth in spite of the pandemic and look forward to partnering with them as they execute the next phase of their journey,” he said in a statement.</span></p>
<p>For the lead investor, Pula&#8217;s investment marks the culmination of its busiest run of investments having led and co-led rounds in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/nigerias-okra-raises-1m-from-tlcom-connecting-bank-accounts-to-apps/">Okra</a>, Shara, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/nigerias-autochek-raises-3-4m-for-car-sales-and-service-platform/">Autochek</a> and Ilara Health within the past year.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christinajuhasz"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Christina Juhasz</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, CIO at Women&#8217;s World Banking, the other investor in the round, explained that the organisation cut a check for Pula &#8220;given the legions of women engaged in small-hold farming and securing the food supply for communities around the globe.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/kenyan-insurtech-startup-pula-raises-6m-series-a-led-by-tlcom-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099841</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alma raises $59.4 million for its Klarna-like payment option</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/alma-raises-59-4-million-for-its-klarna-like-payment-option/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/alma-raises-59-4-million-for-its-klarna-like-payment-option/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 08:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ALMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Alma is raising a $59.4 million Series B funding round (€49 million). The company has been building a new payment option for expensive good. You can choose to pay over three or four installments. This product sounds familiar if you’ve used Klarna in the past. But Klarna isn’t available in France. Cathay Innovation, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://getalma.eu">Alma</a> is raising a $59.4 million Series B funding round (€49 million). The company has been building a new payment option for expensive good. You can choose to pay over three or four installments. This product sounds familiar if you’ve used <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/">Klarna</a> in the past. But Klarna isn’t available in France.</p>
<p>Cathay Innovation, Idinvest, Bpifrance’s Large Venture fund, Seaya Ventures and Picus Capital are participating in today’s funding round. In addition to today’s equity round, Alma is raising a credit line of $25.5 million (€21 million) to finance merchant payments.</p>
<p>What makes Alma attractive to merchants is that the startup is handling 100% of the risk involved with a payment over multiple installments. When a customer buys a bike over four installments, they’ll get charged over several months. But the merchant gets paid on day one.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Since I first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/alma-is-a-klarna-like-payment-startup-that-lets-you-buy-now-and-pay-later/">covered</a> Alma, the startup has launched the ability to pay later. You enter your card information right now but you get charged 15 days or a month later. It can be particularly useful if you’re unsure about something you’re buying and if you think there’s a chance you’ll send it back.</p>
<p>And it’s an attractive option in France where debit cards are the norm — not credit cards. Alma also plans to offer longer plans, such as the ability to buy now and pay over 6, 10 or 12 installments.</p>
<p>Thanks to the new influx of cash, the startup plans to triple the size of its team and reach €1 billion in annual payment volume within two years. It’s also going to expand to other countries, but with a specific focus on helping French merchants reach European customers living in other European countries.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TNwIwlqZyD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/alma-is-a-klarna-like-payment-startup-that-lets-you-buy-now-and-pay-later/">Alma is a Klarna-like payment startup that lets you buy now and pay later</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Alma is a Klarna-like payment startup that lets you buy now and pay later&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/alma-is-a-klarna-like-payment-startup-that-lets-you-buy-now-and-pay-later/embed/#?secret=TNwIwlqZyD" data-secret="TNwIwlqZyD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3vSjt8gNn4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/">Making sense of Klarna</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Making sense of Klarna&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/making-sense-of-klarna/embed/#?secret=3vSjt8gNn4" data-secret="3vSjt8gNn4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/alma-raises-59-4-million-for-its-klarna-like-payment-option/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099004</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cybersecurity startup SpiderSilk raises $2.25M to help prevent data breaches</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/spidersilk-pre-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/spidersilk-pre-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 05:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clearview ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dubai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spidersilk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dubai-based cybersecurity startup SpiderSilk has raised $2.25 million in a pre-Series A round, led by venture firms Global Ventures and STV. In the past two years, SpiderSilk has discovered some of the biggest data breaches: Blind, the allegedly anonymous social network that exposed private complaints by Silicon Valley employees; a lab leaked highly sensitive Samsung [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Dubai-based cybersecurity startup SpiderSilk has raised $2.25 million in a pre-Series A round, led by venture firms Global Ventures and STV.</p>
<p>In the past two years, SpiderSilk has discovered some of the biggest data breaches: Blind, the allegedly anonymous social network that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/20/blind-anonymous-app-data-exposure/">exposed private complaints</a> by Silicon Valley employees; a lab leaked <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/08/samsung-source-code-leak/">highly sensitive Samsung source code</a>; an inadvertently public code repository revealed apps, code, and apartment building camera footage belonging to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/clearview-source-code-lapse/">controversial facial recognition startup Clearview AI</a>; and a massive spill of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/moviepass-thousands-data-exposed-leak/">unencrypted customer card numbers</a> at now-defunct MoviePass may have been the final nail in the already-beleaguered subscription service&#8217;s casket.</p>
<p>Much of those discoveries were found from the company&#8217;s proprietary internet scanner, SpiderSilk co-founder and chief security officer Mossab Hussein told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Any company would want their data locked down, but mistakes happen and misconfigurations can leave sensitive internal corporate data accessible from the internet. SpiderSilk helps its customers understand their attack surface by looking for things that are exposed but shouldn&#8217;t be.</p>
<p>The cybersecurity startup uses its scanner to map out a company&#8217;s assets and attack surfaces to detect vulnerabilities and data exposures, and it also simulates cyberattacks to help customers understand where vulnerabilities are in their defenses.</p>
<p>&#8220;The attack surface management and threat detection platform we built scans the open internet on a continuous basis in order to attribute all publicly accessible assets back to organizations that could be affected by them, either directly or indirectly,&#8221; SpiderSilk&#8217;s co-founder and chief executive Rami El Malak told TechCrunch. &#8220;As a result, the platform regularly uncovers exploits and highlights how no organization is immune from infrastructure visibility blind-spots.&#8221;</p>
<p>El Malak said the funding will help to build out its security, engineering and data science teams, as well as its marketing and sales. He said the company is expanding its presence to North America with sales and engineering teams.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the company&#8217;s second round of funding, after a seed round of $500,000 in November 2019, also led by Global Ventures and several angel investors.</p>
<p>&#8220;The SpiderSilk team are outstanding partners, solving a critical problem in the ever-complex world of cybersecurity, and protecting companies online from the increasing threats of malicious activity,&#8221; said Basil Moftah, general partner at Global Ventures.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="U22LlCUCiR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/moviepass-thousands-data-exposed-leak/">MoviePass exposed thousands of unencrypted customer card numbers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MoviePass exposed thousands of unencrypted customer card numbers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/20/moviepass-thousands-data-exposed-leak/embed/#?secret=U22LlCUCiR" data-secret="U22LlCUCiR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/spidersilk-pre-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Autonomous driving startup Uisee attracts Chinese state investor in $150M round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/uisee-150-million-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/uisee-150-million-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 03:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uisee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no lack of state funding for China&#8217;s smart driving startups nowadays as the country advances its goal to become a global leader in artificial intelligence in a decade&#8217;s time. The latest to get a financial boost is Uisee, a Beijing-based company founded by a group of tech veterans including the former head of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There is no lack of state funding for China&#8217;s smart driving startups nowadays as the country advances its goal to become a global leader in artificial intelligence in a decade&#8217;s time. The latest to get a financial boost is Uisee, a Beijing-based company founded by a group of tech veterans including the former head of Intel Labs China, Wu Gansha.</p>
<p>Uisee said Monday it has closed a funding round north of 1 billion yuan ($150 million) from investors including the National Manufacturing Transformation and Upgrade Fund, a $21 billion state-backed fund <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-china-fund-manufacturing-idUSKBN1XU02M">set up in 2019</a> to promote and upgrade the manufacturing value chain in China, with the Ministry of Finance as the biggest shareholder.</p>
<p>Five-year-old Uisee is the first autonomous driving company the Fund has ever backed, according to the announcement, and the firm is expected to help propel forward the public transit and logistics sectors and become a &#8220;benchmark&#8221; autonomous driving enterprise in China, said a manager from the Fund in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Unlike Mobileye or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/momenta-profile/">China&#8217;s Momenta</a>, which sell advanced driver-assistance systems as they invest in the development of more advanced Level 4 driving, Uisee leapfrogs ADAS and focuses on unmanned driving, co-founder and CEO Wu Gansha said in a previous <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzAwMzQ4OTE5Mg==&amp;mid=2654428948&amp;idx=1&amp;sn=084fc21c835bb132d0944f5fa0394c08&amp;scene=1&amp;srcid=0511c877PeBIfwEO00dnrDCl&amp;key=b28b03434249256b4f0d164da8b6cfc72a9c9e9a8a9bb401e6169bfe8becd969bb8c14a2bae0ed85913a4b4d1085338f&amp;ascene=0&amp;uin=MTQxMjA2OTEyMQ%3D%3D&amp;devicetype=iMac+MacBookAir7%2C2+OSX+OSX+10.10.5+build(14F27)&amp;version=11000003&amp;pass_ticket=fkfoLtpBMPj4TCoqlnYMA10f4aEEjngtCXgMI7RzOzM7m%2FXCcITA0ZFszaoqf%2BQQ">interview</a>.</p>
<p>Uisee supplies technology for cases ranging from robotaxis and city buses to airports and logistics hubs. It&#8217;s secured a handful of major customers, including the Hong Kong International Airport, which is using Uisee&#8217;s solutions to <a href="https://www.hongkongairport.com/en/media-centre/news-stories-updates/AET">automate its baggage tractors</a>, alongside state-backed automakers FAW Group, Dongfeng Motor, and more.</p>
<p>The new financial injection, which also counts a number of undisclosed &#8220;industrial investors,&#8221; will allow Uisee to ramp up research and development and promote the industry&#8217;s at-scale monetization. The company claims that the joint venture between SAIC Motor, General Motors, and Liuzhou Wuling Motors has used its technology to enable 300,000 kilometers of vehicle operation without safety drivers inside a logistics hub.</p>
<p>Existing investors include Bosch the German electronics giant, which participated in Uisee&#8217;s Series B round last year, alongside Shenzhen government-backed Shenzhen Capital Group and state-backed CCI Investment.</p>
<p>Several other Chinese startups have also received sizable fundings in recent months to accelerate their smart driving solutions such as WeRide, which closed its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/weride-200-million-funding/">Series B</a> of $310 million at the start of 2021; chipmaker Horizon Robotics, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/21/horizon-robotics-700-million-funding/">landed $150 million</a> in December; Pony.ai, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/chinese-autonomous-vehicle-startup-pony-ai-hits-5-3-billion-valuation/">pocked $267</a> million in November; and ride-hailing platform Didi, which from last May <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/softbank-pours-500m-into-didi-in-chinas-biggest-autonomous-driving-round/">raised $500 million</a> for its new entity dedicated to autonomous driving.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/24/uisee-150-million-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099854</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
