<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 16:09:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Forum Brands raises $27M as crowded Amazon roll-up space continues to heat up</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/forum-brands-raises-27m-as-crowded-amazon-roll-up-space-continues-to-heat-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/forum-brands-raises-27m-as-crowded-amazon-roll-up-space-continues-to-heat-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roll up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roll-ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The number of startups acquiring e-commerce businesses, especially those operating on Amazon, to grow and scale is increasing as more people than ever are shopping online. The latest such startup to raise capital is Forum Brands, which today announced it has raised $27 million in equity funding for its technology-driven e-commerce acquisition platform.  Norwest Venture [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The number of startups acquiring e-commerce businesses, especially those operating on Amazon, to grow and scale is increasing as more people than ever are shopping online.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest such startup to raise capital is </span><a href="https://www.forumbrands.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forum Brands</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which today announced it has raised $27 million in equity funding for its technology-driven e-commerce acquisition platform. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Norwest Venture Partners led the round, which also included participation from existing backers NFX and Concrete Rose.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brenton Howland, Ruben Amar and Alex Kopco founded New York-based Forum Brands last summer during the height of the COVID-19 pandemic. Its self-proclaimed goal was to use data to innovate through acquisition.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re buying what we think are A+ high-growth e-commerce businesses that sell predominantly on Amazon and are looking to build a portfolio of standalone businesses that are category leaders, on and off Amazon,” Howland said. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">A source of inspiration for us is that we saw how consumer goods and services changed fundamentally for what we think is going to be for decades and decades to come, accelerating the shift toward digital.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171124" style="width: 5194px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171124" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171124 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg" alt="" width="5184" height="3456" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg 5184w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5184px) 100vw, 5184px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171124" class="wp-caption-text">Forum Brands founding team. <strong>Image Credits: </strong>Forum Brands</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forum&#8217;s technology employs &#8220;advanced&#8221; algorithms and over 60 million data points to populate brand information into a central platform in real time, instantly scoring brands and generating accurate financial metrics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The M&amp;A team also uses data to contact brand owners “in just three clicks.” But Forum says it already knows which brands meet its acquisition criteria before ever making contact with brand owners.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The decision to acquire comes within 48 hours and once terms are agreed upon, entrepreneurs get paid in 30 days or less for their brand, with additional income benefits through post-acquisition partnerships,” according to the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its apps leverage analytics to push recommendations to drive growth and financial performance for brands. Then, its multichannel approaches aimed at positioning the brands for “long-term category leadership.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are using a lot of data science and machine learning techniques to build technology that allows us to eventually operate efficiently a large portfolio of digital brands at scale,” Kopco said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is undeterred by the increasingly crowded space based on the belief that the market opportunity is so huge, there’s plenty of room for multiple players.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are very much in the day zero consolidation of the e-commerce space, and the market is very, very large,” Amar told TechCrunch. “And based on our data, 98% or 99% of all sellers are still operating independently. So, this is not a winner-takes-all market. There will be multiple winners, and we’ve built a strategy to be one of these winners.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Norwest Venture Partners’ Stew Campbell believes that the number of sellers who reach a point where they have trouble scaling either due to the lack of resources or time is only going to grow. And Forum Brands intends to capitalize on that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s a continued need for more liquidity options for the entrepreneurs behind many Amazon-first brands. Forum helps entrepreneurs recognize value, which can be significant too many,” he said. ”After acquisition, the Forum team drives operational efficiencies and scale to create better customer experiences for shoppers on Amazon.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campbell emphasizes that his firm was drawn to Forum Brands’ team, which the company also touts as a differentiator.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Co-founder and COO Kopco worked in a variety of product roles for several years at Amazon and John Derkits, Forum&#8217;s VP of brand growth, is also ex-Amazon. Overall, three-fourths </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">of its operating team are former Amazonians. Co-CEO and co-founder Howland was an investor for two years at Cove Hill Partners and is a former McKinsey consultant.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campbell says his firm has seen many other models in this market, “but the Forum team blends long-term mindsets and focus on technology, while bringing operational and M&amp;A expertise.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If this all sounds familiar, it’s because TechCrunch also recently covered the raise of</span> <a href="https://www.acqu.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Acquco</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has a similar business model to that of Forum Brands and also involves former Amazon employees. In May, that startup </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/acquco-raises-160m/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $160 million in debt and equity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to scale its business. Thrasio is another high-profile player in the space, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">and has raised $850 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in funding this year. Other startups that have recently attracted venture capital include Branded, which recently </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/target-global-leads-150m-round-for-amazon-marketplace-consolidator-branded/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">launched its own roll-up business on $150 million in funding,</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">as well as </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/berlin-brands-group-commits-302m-to-acquire-d2c-and-amazon-merchants/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Berlin Brands Group</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/sellerx-raises-118m-to-buy-up-and-grow-amazon-marketplace-businesses/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SellerX</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.thestreet.com/press-releases/heyday-emerges-from-stealth-with-175m-series-a-funding-to-accelerate-marketplace-native-brands-15493868"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heyday</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/heroes/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heroes</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/perch-raises-123-5m-to-grow-its-stable-of-d2c-brands-that-sell-on-amazon/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perch</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And, </span><a href="https://valoreo.com/en/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Valoreo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a Mexico City-based acquirer of e-commerce businesses, raised $50 million of equity and debt financing in </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/valoreo-raises-50m-to-roll-up-latam-e-commerce-brands/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a seed funding round</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> announced in February.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, earlier this month, Moonshot Brands announced </span><a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/06/16/2248574/0/en/Moonshot-Brands-Backed-by-Y-Combinator-Others-Raises-160M-to-Build-A-Founder-First-Multi-Brand-E-Commerce-Platform.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $160 million debt and equity raise</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">acquire high-performing Amazon third-party sellers and direct-to-consumer businesses on Shopify and WooCommerce with established brand equity.” That company says that since its founding in 2020, it has achieved a $30 million revenue run rate. Among its investors are Y Combinator, Joe Montana’s</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Liquid 2 Ventures and the founders of Hippo, Lambda School and Shift. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ErRCktz5JS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/why-amazon-should-pay-attention-to-shein/">Why Amazon should pay attention to Shein</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Amazon should pay attention to Shein&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/why-amazon-should-pay-attention-to-shein/embed/#?secret=ErRCktz5JS" data-secret="ErRCktz5JS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dmzSK0XFPJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/acquco-raises-160m/">Led by ex-Amazonians, Acquco raises $160M to buy and scale e-commerce businesses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Led by ex-Amazonians, Acquco raises $160M to buy and scale e-commerce businesses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/acquco-raises-160m/embed/#?secret=dmzSK0XFPJ" data-secret="dmzSK0XFPJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/forum-brands-raises-27m-as-crowded-amazon-roll-up-space-continues-to-heat-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171043</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GitHub previews new AI tool that makes coding suggestions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/github-previews-new-ai-tool-that-makes-coding-suggestions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/github-previews-new-ai-tool-that-makes-coding-suggestions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 15:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenAI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GitHub has unveiled a new product that leverages artificial intelligence to help you write code more efficiently. Named GitHub Copilot, today’s new product can suggest lines of code and even sometimes entire functions. GitHub has partnered with OpenAI to develop this tool. It doesn’t replace developers, it’s just a tool that should improve productivity and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">GitHub has unveiled a new product that leverages artificial intelligence to help you write code more efficiently. Named <a href="https://copilot.github.com">GitHub Copilot</a>, today’s new product can suggest lines of code and even sometimes entire functions.</p>
<p>GitHub has partnered with <a href="https://openai.com">OpenAI</a> to develop this tool. It doesn’t replace developers, it’s just a tool that should improve productivity and make it easier to learn how to code. GitHub frames this new tool as an AI pair programmer.</p>
<p>The model behind GitHub Copilot has been trained on billions of lines of code — many of them are hosted and available publicly on GitHub itself. When you’re writing code, GitHub Copilot suggests code as you type. You can cycle through suggestions, accept or reject them.</p>
<p>In order to figure out what you’re currently coding, GitHub Copilot tries to parse the meaning of a comment, the name of the function you are writing, or the past couple of lines. The company shows a few demos on <a href="https://copilot.github.com">its website</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GitHub-Copilot-1.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="600" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2171483" /></p>
<p>In particular, you can describe a function in plain English in a comment and then convert it to actual code. If you’re getting started with a new language or you’ve been using no-code or low-code tools in the past, that feature could be useful.</p>
<p>If you’re writing code every day, GitHub Copilot can be used to work with a new framework or library. You don’t have to read the documentation from start to finish as GitHub Copilot already knows the specific functions and features of the framework you’re working with. It could also replace many <a href="https://stackoverflow.com">Stack Overflow</a> queries.</p>
<p>GitHub Copilot integrates directly with Visual Studio Code. You can install it as an extension or use it in the cloud with <a href="https://github.com/features/codespaces">GitHub Codespaces</a>. Over time, the service should improve based on how you interact with GitHub Copilot. As you accept and reject suggestions, those suggestions should get better.</p>
<p>Currently available as a technical preview, GitHub plans to launch a commercial product based on GitHub Copilot. It currently works best with Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby and Go.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GitHub-Copilot-2.gif" alt="" width="1024" height="850" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2171486" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/github-previews-new-ai-tool-that-makes-coding-suggestions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171482</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zoom to acquire German startup to bring real-time translation to meetings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zoom-to-acquire-german-startup-to-bring-real-time-translation-to-meetings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zoom-to-acquire-german-startup-to-bring-real-time-translation-to-meetings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 15:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As companies expand worldwide, and meet online in tools like Zoom, the language barrier can be a real impediment to getting work done. Zoom announced that it intends to acquire German startup Karlsruhe Information Technology Solutions or Kites for short, to bring real-time machine learning-based translation to the platform. The companies did not share the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As companies expand worldwide, and meet online in tools like Zoom, the language barrier can be a real impediment to getting work done. <a href="http://zoom.com">Zoom</a> announced that it intends to acquire German startup Karlsruhe Information Technology Solutions or <a href="http://www.karlsruhe-it-solutions.com/">Kites</a> for short, to bring real-time machine learning-based translation to the platform.</p>
<p>The companies did not share the terms of the deal, but with Kites, the company gets a team of top researchers, who can help enhance the machine learning translation knowledge at the company. &#8220;Kites’ talented team of 12 research scientists will help Zoom’s engineering team advance the field of [machine translation] to improve meeting productivity and efficiency by providing multi-language translation capabilities for Zoom users,&#8221; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The deal appears to be an acquihire as the company adds those 12 researchers to the Zoom engineering group. It intends to leave the team in place in Germany with plans to build a machine learning translation R&amp;D center with additional hires over time as the company puts more resources into this area.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While the Kites website reveals little about it other than an address, the company <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/kites-karlsruhe-information-technology-solutions-%E2%80%93-kites-gmbh/about/">About page on LinkedIn</a> indicates that the startup was founded in 2015 by two researchers who taught at Carnegie Mellon and Karlsruhe Institute of Technology with the goal of building machine learning translation tooling.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Kites mission is to break down language barriers and make seamless cross language interaction a reality of everyday life,&#8221; the LinkedIn overview stated. It claims to be among a handful of companies, that include Google and Microsoft, to have developed &#8220;leading speech recognition and translation technologies,&#8221; which would suggest that Zoom has acquired some key technologies.</p>
<p>It does not appear the company had a commercial product, but the site does indicate that there is a machine learning translation platform that is in use in academia and government. Regardless, the fruits of the company&#8217;s research will now belong to Zoom.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9BEtj9IfzH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/expect-an-even-hotter-ai-venture-capital-market-in-the-wake-of-the-microsoft-nuance-deal/">Expect an even hotter AI venture capital market in the wake of the Microsoft-Nuance deal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Expect an even hotter AI venture capital market in the wake of the Microsoft-Nuance deal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/expect-an-even-hotter-ai-venture-capital-market-in-the-wake-of-the-microsoft-nuance-deal/embed/#?secret=9BEtj9IfzH" data-secret="9BEtj9IfzH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/zoom-to-acquire-german-startup-to-bring-real-time-translation-to-meetings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171422</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Training platform Virti raises $10M Series A led by IQ Capital to teach soft skills in VR</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/training-platform-virti-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-iq-capital-to-teach-soft-skills-in-vr/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/training-platform-virti-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-iq-capital-to-teach-soft-skills-in-vr/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 15:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the pandemic took hold, training staff had to ‘go virtual’. Typically, that would have meant falling back on existing corporate training solutions, which we all know and “love”. Could there be another way? In 2018, trauma surgeon Dr. Alex Young took the training required for high-stress scenarios like surgery and applied it to a virtual [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the pandemic took hold, training staff had to ‘go virtual’. Typically, that would have meant falling back on existing corporate training solutions, which we all know and “love”. Could there be another way?</p>
<p>In 2018, trauma surgeon Dr. Alex Young took the training required for high-stress scenarios like surgery and applied it to a virtual reality environment, ending up with, he says, a radical and effective approach to training.</p>
<p>His digital training platform <a href="https://virti.com/">Virti</a> has now raised $10 million in a Series A round led by IQ Capital, which was joined by Cedars-Sinai Medical Center and a new, UK-based learning technology VC fund, Descenture Capital. In additional news, Kurt Kratchman and Mark Ashworth join Virti from Oracle as CRO and CFO/COO respectively.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in Bristol, UK, the <a href="https://virti.com/">Virti</a> platform works across mobile or desktop devices, or VR/AR headsets and captures data across all three to analyze, measure, and give feedback on employee performance, turning a lot of subjectively assessed skills into more objective and measurable data. It’s even managed to have been named one of TIME’s Best Inventions of 2020.</p>
<p>Virti claims its deep learning technology is improving training outcomes by up to 230% and the startups says it has increased revenues by 978%. It also has a cloud-based, no-code simulation creation suite allowing organizations to build their own bespoke training modules.</p>
<p>Dr Alexander Young, CEO and founder of Virti, commented: “At Virti, our goal is to maximize human performance by making experiential learning affordable and accessible for everyone. In-person training has always been expensive with e-learning often unengaging &#8211; and research shows that employees forget upwards of 80% of episodic training.”</p>
<p>Max Bautin, managing Partner at IQ Capital, said: “E-learning has seen strong growth over the last 5 years, and COVID-driven shift to remote work has increased demand many times over. Virti’s deeptech experiential learning platform is by far the best in the world.”</p>
<p>Virti competes with normal desktop-based training solutions. But on the VR side, more so with StriVR which has raised $51 million, and Mursiun which has raised $35.1 million.</p>
<p>Speaking to me over a call Young told me: “Our system, which we&#8217;ve patented in terms of the analytics, can actually track what people are looking at if they&#8217;re in a virtual reality headset. So we can really pull out some deep engagement metrics, a bit like heat map data you might see on marketing platforms. Combined with how people are interacting and doing things like making decisions in these environments, we can then predict how they may perform better in real-world environments and share that on a reporting dashboard. The other aspect is if you&#8217;re not practicing things you forget about 80% of what you can learn. Our system allows people to jump back in and reminds them and because it&#8217;s accessible on mobile as well as VR, AR headsets, they get that hit of updates and learning to keep them up-skilled and remembering information for longer.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/training-platform-virti-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-iq-capital-to-teach-soft-skills-in-vr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171446</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Max Q: Licensed to space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/max-q-licensed-to-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/max-q-licensed-to-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 15:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orbion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Max Q is a weekly newsletter from TechCrunch all about space. Sign up here to receive it weekly on Mondays in your inbox. Space this week was all about preparatory steps — and it&#8217;s looking more and more like we&#8217;re setting up for an out-of-this-world July, with just a few days left before the month [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Max Q is a weekly newsletter from TechCrunch all about space. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here to receive it weekly on Mondays in your inbox</a>.</em></p>
<p>Space this week was all about preparatory steps — and it&#8217;s looking more and more like we&#8217;re setting up for an out-of-this-world July, with just a few days left before the month kicks off.</p>
<h2>Starship headed to orbit?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2149000" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2149000" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2149000" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg" alt="Starship SN15 in flight" width="1024" height="473" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg 2600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg?resize=150,69 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg?resize=300,138 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg?resize=768,354 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg?resize=680,314 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg?resize=1536,709 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg?resize=2048,945 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/HP_SN15_Desktop.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2149000" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SpaceX</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>SpaceX President Gwynne Shotwell told virtual conference attendees on Friday that the company is hoping to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/spacex-aiming-for-first-orbital-test-launch-of-starship-in-july/">fly its Starship rocket to orbit for the first time as early as next month</a>. Starship has completed quite a few test flights to date, including one that went as well as could be expected right from launch to landing.</p>
<p>The first orbital test of Starship is a significant milestone for the spacecraft&#8217;s development program, and if it does indeed happen in July that&#8217;s an impressive turnaround for the launch company, which has been working on both Starship and its Super Heavy booster in south Texas.</p>
<p>Getting to orbit with Starship won&#8217;t mean that SpaceX is ready to use the vehicle for commercial missions, however; this first attempt, which if the history of rocket testing is any indication, might not go so well, will just be about seeing how the prototype handles space. SpaceX will use later tests to refine other key components of Starship, including its controlled re-entry and landing burn.</p>
<p>Before Starship can attempt to leave Earth&#8217;s atmospheric confines, it needs to get clearance from the FAA to even do so, and that&#8217;s still pending. SpaceX and the FAA seem to have a somewhat fraught relationship, however, especially as regards Starship testing.</p>
<h2>Virgin Galactic gets green light for &#8216;spaceline&#8217; operations</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1984211" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1984211" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1984211" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg 3600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/GettyImages-166300865.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1984211" class="wp-caption-text">MOJAVE, UNITED STATES &#8211; OCTOBER 10: (EDITORIAL USE ONLY, NO SUBJECT SPECIFIC TV BROADCAST DOCUMENTARIES OR BOOK USE) Virgin Galactic vehicle SpaceShipTwo completes it&#8217;s successful first glide flight at Mojave on October 10, 2010 over Mojave in California. (Photo by Mark Greenberg/Virgin Galactic/Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>Virgin Galactic is gearing up for a final series of crewed test flights before it begins taking its paying passengers up to space. It also just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/faa-clears-virgin-galactic-for-commercial-astronaut-spaceflight/">received approval from the FAA for its &#8216;spaceline&#8217; operator&#8217;s license</a>, which is like an airline but with space.</p>
<p>This is an adaptation of its existing commercial spaceflight license that now allows it to also begin transporting paying passengers, including space tourists and researchers, to low Earth orbit using its SpaceShipTwo vehicle. That&#8217;s a key ingredient, but the company will still be doing its series of three test flights, the first ever with a full crew on board, before it actually does begin operating in that capacity. Richard Branson is set to be a passenger on the second of those three test flights, according to the current plan.</p>
<h2>Orbion raises $20M for space thrusters</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1874736" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png" alt="orbion factory" width="1024" height="575" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png 2618w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png?resize=1536,863 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png?resize=2048,1151 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/orbion-factory.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a>tartup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/orbion-manufacturer-of-in-space-plasma-propulsion-systems-raises-20m-series-b/">Orbion has raised a $20 million Series B</a> for its plasma thruster technology. Plasma thrusters are a key means of in-space propulsion, and that&#8217;s a booming sector in light of the emergence of more and more small spacecraft operators as low Earth orbit becomes a high-traffic zone.</p>
<p>Orbion&#8217;s approach reduces the cost of production and, by extension, the cost to its clients, which puts the technology more within reach for resource-constrained satellite startups.</p>
<h2>Join us at TC Sessions: Space in December</h2>
<p>Last year we held our first dedicated space event, and it went so well that we decided to host it again in 2021. This year, it&#8217;s happening December 14 and 15, and it&#8217;s once again going to be an entirely virtual conference, so people from all over the world will be able to join — and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/">you can, too</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/max-q-licensed-to-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171442</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Late-stage capital is having a &#8216;cascading effect&#8217; on European VC activity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/late-stage-capital-is-having-a-cascading-effect-on-european-vc-activity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/late-stage-capital-is-having-a-cascading-effect-on-european-vc-activity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 15:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Series A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re taking a look at the early-stage venture capital market, this time through a European lens, helped by a few investors from the continent.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Capping off our dig into the early-stage venture capital market, we’re taking a quick look at Europe this morning. Previously, The Exchange <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/the-early-stage-venture-capital-market-is-weird-and-chaotic/">tucked into the United States’ early-stage market for startup capital</a>, uncovering startups using abundant seed capital to get more done before raising a Series A, while others were using pedigree, team and market size to accelerate their first lettered raise.</p>
<p>For both cohorts, it appeared that a rapid-fire Series B could be in the offing, with VCs looking to get capital into winners early.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>The Latin American venture capital market for early-stage startups <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/like-the-us-a-two-tier-venture-capital-market-is-emerging-in-latin-america/">had a number of similar hallmarks</a>. That shouldn’t have been surprising. According to <a href="https://twitter.com/slpierre?lang=en">Seth Pierrepont</a>, a partner at London-based Accel, “fundraising dynamics are now no longer U.S.- or European-specific &#8212; they’re global.” Fundraising over videoconferencing services like Zoom has done more than make geographical distances less impactful inside of countries &#8212; it&#8217;s even made national borders and even oceans less meaningful.</p>
<p>Is the European startup market similar to what we’ve seen in Latin America and the United States &#8212; a cognate for the North American venture capital scene, given its outsized global weight by round count and amount invested?</p>
<p>Largely, yes, a trend that appears to be shaking up prices and the talent wars. This morning, we’re taking a final look at the early-stage venture capital market, this time through a European lens, with an assist from a few investors from the continent.</p>
<h2><strong>An influx of late-stage capital</strong></h2>
<p>Broadly, early-stage venture capital rounds in Europe are happening “earlier and are larger in size,” according to <a href="https://twitter.com/vinothj?lang=en">Draper Esprit’s Vinoth Jayakumar</a>, an investor based in London. The correlate of larger rounds being raised while startups are younger is valuation expansion, according to Jayakumar, who said that prices are going up “because larger rounds are very dilutive to founders if done at normal &#8212; or in this case too low &#8212; valuations.”<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/late-stage-capital-is-having-a-cascading-effect-on-european-vc-activity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171398</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital greeting card startup Givingli raises $3 million seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/digital-greeting-card-startup-givingli-wraps-3-million-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/digital-greeting-card-startup-givingli-wraps-3-million-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 14:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexis Ohanian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthdays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gift card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greeting cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louisiana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postcards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snap inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While the digital revolution has transformed nearly every social interaction and communication type in the past couple decades, the humble birthday card has shown surprising resiliency. Givingli, a small LA-based startup with an app aiming to challenge how Gen Z sends digital greeting cards, is picking up some seed funding from investors betting on their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While the digital revolution has transformed nearly every social interaction and communication type in the past couple decades, the humble birthday card has shown surprising resiliency.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.givingli.com/">Givingli</a>, a small LA-based startup with an app aiming to challenge how Gen Z sends digital greeting cards, is picking up some seed funding from investors betting on their philosophy around modern gifting. The startup has raised a $3 million seed round led by Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian’s Seven Seven Six, while Snap’s Yellow Accelerator also participated in the raise.</p>
<p>The wife and husband co-founding team stumbled into the world of digital greetings and gifts after abandoning physical invitations for their wedding and exploring how the digital greetings space had and hadn&#8217;t evolved. They&#8217;ve taken a mobile-first approach to tackling greetings for special events and moments where users just want to let someone know they&#8217;re thinking of them.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2171425" style="width: 368px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171425" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171425" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png" alt="" width="358" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png 2924w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png?resize=132,150 132w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png?resize=263,300 263w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png?resize=768,876 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png?resize=596,680 596w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png?resize=1347,1536 1347w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png?resize=1796,2048 1796w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Checkout-Screen.png?resize=44,50 44w" sizes="(max-width: 358px) 100vw, 358px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171425" class="wp-caption-text">Image via Givingli</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Initially, we thought it would mainly be birthdays and categories like weddings, graduation, etc., and I think we just threw in some &#8216;just because&#8217; cards, but then that became the most popular category, by far,&#8221; CEO Nicole Emrani Green tells TechCrunch. &#8220;I think that it&#8217;s what kicked off our virality, because obviously with every Givingli sent you&#8217;re pulling someone else in and then the conversation continues.&#8221;</p>
<p>The app monetizes through a $3.99 monthly premium subscription which gives users access to a greater variety of digital greeting designs from the more than 40 artists that the startup has licensed work from. Alongside paying for premium subscriptions, users can also shop for digital gift cards to send along with their greetings. Givingli&#8217;s gift card storefront has more than 150 brands available including Amazon, Spotify, Nike and DoorDash.</p>
<p>A big sell for Givingli&#8217;s offering has been its customization. Although users are pushed to select from the hundreds of available greeting cards, they can also spice them up by adding photos or videos in addition to writing text. The aim is to create a moment that rivals messages that can be shared via email, text or on social media services.</p>
<p>“For a generation of digitally native users, it’s not surprising that the ability to like, swipe, upvote or shoot a quick text from our phones have become the predominant ways we connect with others,” said Ohanian in a press release announcing the seed round. “What first attracted me to Givingli is that Nicole and Ben acutely understood this evolution and built a platform that provides the creative tools needed to elevate those interactions and deepen connections. Whether it’s sending a digital birthday gift, or a note just because &#8211; it’s clear that Givingli has put snail mail on notice.”</p>
<p>One of the team&#8217;s big challenges has been highlighting the visibility of their native app which users download to send greetings. Last fall, the Givingli team debuted a partnership with Snap that brought their gifting service inside Snapchat via a bite-sized Snap Mini app integration. The rollout followed the startup&#8217;s participation in Snap&#8217;s Yellow Accelerator program.</p>
<p>Emrani Green says that partnership has helped bring more users to their platform, and that more than 5 million people have used Givingli to send greetings since the app launched in 2019.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UMZjDD8zUH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/snapchat-debuts-minis-bite-sized-third-party-apps-that-live-inside-chat/">Snapchat debuts Minis, bite-sized third-party apps that live inside chat</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Snapchat debuts Minis, bite-sized third-party apps that live inside chat&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/snapchat-debuts-minis-bite-sized-third-party-apps-that-live-inside-chat/embed/#?secret=UMZjDD8zUH" data-secret="UMZjDD8zUH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/digital-greeting-card-startup-givingli-wraps-3-million-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doug Landis, Emerge Capital growth partner, will talk startup storytelling at TC Early Stage in July</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/doug-landis-emerge-capital-growth-partner-will-talk-startup-storytelling-at-tc-early-stage-in-july/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/doug-landis-emerge-capital-growth-partner-will-talk-startup-storytelling-at-tc-early-stage-in-july/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 14:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Caryn Marooney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Designer Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emergence Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IFTTT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Vernal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scott tong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2169352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How psyched are you about our TC Early Stage: Marketing &#38; Fundraising event? Still need some convincing? Here’s another great session we’ve got planned for the show, which will span July 8 and 9. Emerge Capital Growth Partner Doug Landis will be joining us to discuss how early stage companies can build out the proper [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">How psyched are you about our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2">TC Early Stage: Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a> event? Still need some convincing? Here’s another great session we’ve got planned for the show, which will span July 8 and 9.</p>
<p>Emerge Capital Growth Partner Doug Landis will be joining us to discuss how early stage companies can build out the proper story for pitching VCs. It’s an important, but underdiscussed aspect of helping set your company apart from countless other startups vying for the same venture funding.</p>
<p>Landis knows a thing or two about storytelling. Before joining Emergence as a growth partner, it was actually part of his job title, serving as the chief storyteller and VP of sales productivity and enablement at Box. Before that, he served as a skills training manager at Google and senior director of corporate sales productivity at Salesforce.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>These days, Landis drives sales and go-to-market strategies for Emergence Capital’s portfolio companies, working to help develop the next major player in the SaaS world.</p>
<p>Landis is joining <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2">a stacked lineup</a> for our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2">TC Early Stage: Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a> event. The list includes Sequoia’s Mike Vernal (Product Market Fit Is All About Tempo), Coatue’s Caryn Marooney (formerly Facebook’s head of comms) and Superhuman’s Rahul Vohra (Growth Hacking) and Designer Fund’s Scott Tong (IFTTT co-founder and former head of product design at Pinterest). <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2?display=true">Grab your ticket now</a> to attend Landis&#8217;s session plus 20 others (including a pitch off)!</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			width="99%"
			height="1010"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/doug-landis-emerge-capital-growth-partner-will-talk-startup-storytelling-at-tc-early-stage-in-july/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2169352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revel unveils electric vehicle fast charging superhub with 25 chargers in Brooklyn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/revel-unveils-electric-vehicle-fast-charging-superhub-with-25-chargers-in-brooklyn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/revel-unveils-electric-vehicle-fast-charging-superhub-with-25-chargers-in-brooklyn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 14:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EV charging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frank Reig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tritium]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On a muggy Tuesday morning in Brooklyn, electrified mobility company Revel unveiled its first electric vehicle fast charging superhub. U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm joined the New York-based startup, alongside Revel’s founder and CEO Frank Reig in a ribbon cutting ceremony.  &#8220;Thank you, ⁦Revel, for being an example of what we need in this country[…] Thank [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">On a muggy Tuesday morning in Brooklyn, electrified mobility company Revel unveiled its first electric vehicle fast charging superhub. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm joined the New York-based startup, alongside Revel’s founder and CEO Frank Reig in a ribbon cutting ceremony. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Thank you, ⁦Revel, for being an example of what we need in this country[…] Thank you for showing the county how it can be done,&#8221; said Granholm at the opening event on Tuesday.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revel’s superhub will have 25 brand-agnostic, RTM75 chargers from DC fast charging manufacturer Tritium. According to Reig, this Bed-Stuy charging station, which is open 24-7, will be the largest universal charging station in North America. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.urbangreencouncil.org/sites/default/files/state_of_the_nyc_grid_urban_green_council.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than two-thirds of New York City’s energy grid is currently powered by fossil fuels</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, meaning about a quarter of NYC’s greenhouse gas emissions come from electricity. The state has ambitious plans to require statewide electricity to be 70% renewable by 2030 and 100% carbon-free by 2040. This might be difficult to accomplish given the imminent shutting down of Indian Point’s two nuclear reactors which provide the city with about a quarter of its energy, according to 2018 data from the mayor’s office. In addition, most forms of renewable energy require plenty of space to harness solar or wind power, which will be doubly difficult in a dense and expensive city like New York. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking of power, the superhub is located at the old Pfizer manufacturing building on Flushing Avenue, a site with seven megawatts of power. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There’s enough power at this site and we have built this site in a future-proofing sort of way, so that every single charger can be upgraded in the future without having to dig up any infrastructure,” Reig told TechCrunch. “So if we want to put a 250 or 350 charger in two years from now, three years from now, as cars are able to accept those kinds of speeds, we can do that.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revel also chose to place its charging station at the Pfizer building because it’s at “New York City’s urban core,” rather than far out at the airports or in private garages where chargers are inaccessible to the majority of New Yorkers who would ideally like to charge on the street. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/mobility-startups-can-be-equitable-accessible-and-profitable/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We were on a panel recently about equity</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and one of the things that Revel feels very strongly about is making sure not just this site but any site in the future as well, there won’t be parking fees to get access to the charger,” said Reig. “So as opposed to many fast chargers in New York where you have to pay a parking garage $10 to $20 to park your car, and then you have to pay for the charger, this site is completely publicly available 24-7. There are no entrance fees. The only thing you&#8217;re paying is electricity itself.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="J68d8frSdy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/mobility-startups-can-be-equitable-accessible-and-profitable/">Mobility startups can be equitable, accessible and profitable</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mobility startups can be equitable, accessible and profitable&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/mobility-startups-can-be-equitable-accessible-and-profitable/embed/#?secret=J68d8frSdy" data-secret="J68d8frSdy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Charging up a car costs 39 cents per kilowatt hour, which turns into about $15 to $20 for a full charge, and that shouldn’t take more than 15 to 30 minutes. While drivers wait, they can access the redesigned space inside the old Pfizer building, which is now a co-working space for startups and a food giant court, because that’s what Brooklyn does.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171400" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171400" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2171400" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg" alt="Revel Chargers" width="1024" height="1031" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=298,300 298w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=768,773 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=676,680 676w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/revel-chargers.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2171400" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Revel</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revel’s chargers will take up about a third of the parking lot at the site, and Revel’s fleet of 50 Teslas that make up its troubled ridehail service also have designated parking where they’ll charge overnight. Reig says this makes energy demand available for individual EV owners at the hours they tend to charge their cars, which is in the morning, afternoon and early evening.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reig is expecting the biggest usage of the chargers at first to come from Revel’s ridehail fleet, but the </span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22546955/nyc-tlc-electric-vehicle-license-taxi-vote-revel-tesla"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NYC Taxi and Limousine Commission (TLC) voted last week to block the issuance of new for-hire vehicle licenses</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for electric vehicles. When </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/revel-launches-an-all-electric-rideshare-service-with-a-fleet-of-50-teslas/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Revel announced its new service in April</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it was hoping to skirt by on a loophole in the city’s rules that exempts wheelchair-accessible and electric vehicles from the new vehicle-for-hire cap that was designed to curb the amount of new Uber and Lyft drivers taking over the streets. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;re absolutely working with the TLC,” said Reig. “Obviously we&#8217;re disappointed by their recent ruling to take away the EV exemption in the future. But, you know, we&#8217;re exploring ways with them right now to get on the road, and we&#8217;re going to be finding a solution in the future. We operate legally with every product line always offered, and we&#8217;re going to continue to do that here with this business.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HFxsxZqX4H"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/revels-frank-reig-shares-how-he-built-his-business-and-what-hes-planning/">Revel&#8217;s Frank Reig shares how he built his business and what he&#8217;s planning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Revel&#8217;s Frank Reig shares how he built his business and what he&#8217;s planning&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/revels-frank-reig-shares-how-he-built-his-business-and-what-hes-planning/embed/#?secret=HFxsxZqX4H" data-secret="HFxsxZqX4H" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/revel-unveils-electric-vehicle-fast-charging-superhub-with-25-chargers-in-brooklyn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171304</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Soft Robotics raises another $10M, citing pandemic-related demand</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/soft-robotics-raises-another-10m-citing-pandemic-related-demand/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/soft-robotics-raises-another-10m-citing-pandemic-related-demand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 14:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ABB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soft Robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171410</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Add Soft Robotics to the long list of automation companies that have seen a boost in investment interest amid the pandemic. The New England-based firm announced this morning a $10 million raise that serves as an extension of the $23 million Series B it announced in January of last year. The extension was led by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Add Soft Robotics to the long list of automation companies that have seen a boost in investment interest amid the pandemic. The New England-based firm <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/food-robotics-leader-soft-robotics-raises-10m-to-meet-pandemic-induced-demand-and-bring-its-3d-vision-and-ai-powered-solutions-to-market-301321728.html">announced this morning</a> a $10 million raise that serves as an extension of the $23 million Series B it announced in January of last year.</p>
<p>The extension was led by Material Impact, Scale Venture Partners and Calibrate Ventures and featured existing investors Tekfen Ventures and industrial robotics giant ABB. The latest round brings the company’s total funding to around $58 million.</p>
<p>Founded in 2013, the company takes a novel approach to picking machines, with a soft, pneumatic-powered gripper that’s ideal for fragile food stuffs that might otherwise be damaged by rigid robotics. Food, of course, has been a prime target for interest in automation during the pandemic, due to labor shortages and fears of disease transmission.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/8jnsv10t1nc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>&#8220;Today&#8217;s industrial robots are unable to deal with product variability or unstructured environments typically found across the labor challenged food supply chain in areas such as agriculture, food processing, and logistics,&#8221; Soft Robotics COO Mark Chiappetta said in a release. &#8220;With our revolutionary soft grasping, 3D perception, and AI technologies, Soft Robotics unlocks robotic automation by augmenting widely available industrial robots with true hand-eye coordination allowing them to perform tasks that traditionally could only be performed by human workers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The round also sees Tyson Food’s investment wing, Tyson Ventures joining the fold. Tyson, which produces poultry, beef and pork in massive volumes, is an existing customer.</p>
<p>&#8220;At Tyson Ventures, we are continually exploring new areas in automation that can enhance safety and increase the productivity of our team members,&#8221; Tyson Ventures’ Rahul Ray said in the release. &#8220;Soft Robotics&#8217; best-in-class robotic technology, computer vision and AI platform have the potential to transform the food industry and will play a key role in any company&#8217;s automation journey.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NhRociaY4t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/soft-robotics-raises-23-million-from-investors-including-industrial-robot-giant-fanuc/">Soft Robotics raises $23 million from investors including industrial robot giant FANUC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Soft Robotics raises $23 million from investors including industrial robot giant FANUC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/soft-robotics-raises-23-million-from-investors-including-industrial-robot-giant-fanuc/embed/#?secret=NhRociaY4t" data-secret="NhRociaY4t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/soft-robotics-raises-another-10m-citing-pandemic-related-demand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171410</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beeflow raises $8.3 million to save the bees AND put them to work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/beeflow-raises-8-3-million-to-save-the-bees-and-put-them-to-work/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/beeflow-raises-8-3-million-to-save-the-bees-and-put-them-to-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 14:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AgTech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bees are absolutely critical to the health of our agricultural system, ecosystem, and overall wellbeing as a species here on Earth. And yet bee populations are decreasing and extinction concerns are growing. Beeflow, a startup that today announced the close of a $8.3 million Series A round, is looking to both save the bees and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Bees are absolutely critical to the health of our agricultural system, ecosystem, and overall wellbeing as a species here on Earth. And yet bee <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-22/bee-extinction-worries-grow-as-species-numbers-drop">populations are decreasing and extinction concerns are growing</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.beeflow.com/">Beeflow</a>, a startup that today announced the close of a $8.3 million Series A round, is looking to both save the bees and help farmers be more efficient and effective at the same time.</p>
<p>The startup uses proprietary scientific technology that essentially makes bees healthier, particularly in cold weather. A wealth of research led the company to understand that certain plant-based foods and molecules, when fed to the bees, can reduce the mortality rate of bees by up to 70 percent, and help them perform better in colder weather.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You might be wondering what I mean by performance. That&#8217;s fair.</p>
<p>Bees are the planet&#8217;s natural pollinators. They turn flowers into fruit, spreading pollen from one landing spot to another. Many farmers will &#8216;rent out&#8217; bees from beekeepers to hang out on their farms and pollinate their plants. In almost every way, the effectiveness of this can&#8217;t be measured, and the bees themselves can&#8217;t truly be controlled.</p>
<p>Beeflow&#8217;s technology ensures that the bees are healthy and strong, and can fly up to 7x more during colder weather than they&#8217;d be able to without it. This means that those bees are much more likely to effectively and efficiently pollinate crops for the farmers.</p>
<p>Beyond reducing the mortality rate of bees, the company also offers a second product called ToBEE, which trains the bees to target a specific crop, such as blueberries or almonds.</p>
<p>Combined, these Beeflow products have increased crop yields for farmers up to 90 percent.</p>
<p>Beeflow&#8217;s business model is two-fold. They have their own bees that they loan out to farmers for pollination, and also work with beekeepers to bring them into the Beeflow network. Bee keepers do not pay for Beeflow&#8217;s technology, but do hand over the rights to their relationships with farmers.</p>
<p>The startup was founded by Matias Viel, who is from Argentina, and is mostly operational in Latin America and the West Coast of the U.S., with plans to expand to the East Coast and Mexico.</p>
<p>&#8220;The greatest challenge is operational and around execution,&#8221; said Viel. &#8220;There is so much demand and we need to scale our team and our operations now.&#8221;</p>
<p>The financing round was led by Ospraie Ag Science, with participation from Future Ventures&#8217; Steve Jurvetson, Jeff Wilke, Vectr Ventures, SOSV&#8217;s IndieBio and Grid Exponential.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/beeflow-raises-8-3-million-to-save-the-bees-and-put-them-to-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171360</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon introduces Reading Sidekick, a kids reading companion for Alexa, and Voice Profiles for Kids</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/amazon-introduces-reading-sidekick-a-kids-reading-companion-for-alexa-and-voice-profiles-for-kids/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/amazon-introduces-reading-sidekick-a-kids-reading-companion-for-alexa-and-voice-profiles-for-kids/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 14:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Echo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart speakers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speech Recognition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon today announced a new feature that will turn Alexa into a reading companion for children as well as new support for Alexa Voice Profiles for Kids, which personalize the child&#8217;s Alexa experience across all Echo devices in the household. The two features go hand in hand, as the Voice Profile allows Alexa to identify [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon today announced a new feature that will turn Alexa into a reading companion for children as well as new support for Alexa Voice Profiles for Kids, which personalize the child&#8217;s Alexa experience across all Echo devices in the household. The two features go hand in hand, as the Voice Profile allows Alexa to identify who&#8217;s speaking, so the device can appropriately respond to a request like &#8220;Alexa, let&#8217;s read.&#8221; Alexa will then start the reading companion experience, which Amazon is calling <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/browse/21556915011">Reading Sidekick</a>.</p>
<p>This feature isn&#8217;t available to all Alexa device owners, as it requires an <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ftu/home">Amazon Kids+ subscription</a>. This is the $2.99 per month subscription service that also provides families with children access to thousands of kid-friendly books, TV shows, movies, educational apps and games, in addition to premium content for Echo devices, like ad-free radio stations and playlists, Audible books, and exclusive Alexa skills.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171383" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171383" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2171383" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="340" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png?resize=1536,768 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Reading-Sidekick-Echo-Show-Book-List.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171383" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Once subscribed, the child can then direct Alexa to read with them and they&#8217;ll pick up a compatible book or ebook to get started. Alexa will ask what book they&#8217;re reading and how much does the child want to read: a lot, a little, or taking turns? The feature works with the hundreds of children&#8217;s books for ages 6 to 9 that are included as part of the Amazon Kids+ subscription, including both the print or digital versions. When it&#8217;s the child&#8217;s turn reading. Alexa will listen and provide encouragement when the child is doing well, and will offer support when the child is struggling.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, support for new Alexa Voice Profiles for Kids will also begin rolling out, starting today. This opt-in feature allows parents or guardians to create a voice profile for each child in their family (up to 4 kids). When enabled, the Alexa experience will be personalized to the individual speaking. That means Alexa will automatically apply the appropriate parental controls that have been configured, automatically filter explicit music, limit calls and messages sent through Alexa only to approved contacts, and restrict the child only to the Alexa skills parents have pre-approved. Alexa will also provide the child with access to kid-friendly games, skills, music, and videos and will provide kid-friendly responses to kids&#8217; inquiries.</p>
<p>While features like these can make the Alexa experience more fun and useful for families, parents have to weigh their comfort with having their children&#8217;s voices recorded and analyzed and determine how long they would want such recordings stored. Today, Amazon uses kids&#8217; voice recordings to train its speech recognition and natural language understanding systems in order to improve Alexa&#8217;s ability to understand children&#8217;s questions and requests. In some number of cases, these recordings are also manually reviewed. Parents who don&#8217;t want to participate can delete recordings associated with their child&#8217;s history either one-by-one or all at once via the Alexa app Settings. They can also set recordings to automatically delete on an ongoing 3-month or 18-month basis and can delete recordings via voice requests.</p>
<p>However, if the parent chooses not to save the child&#8217;s recordings, they&#8217;ll not be able to go back through the history to see the requests their child has made over time from the <a href="https://parents.amazon.com/">Parent Dashboard</a>.</p>
<p>Every parent will need to make a decision about what&#8217;s right for their own household before enabling features like Reading Sidekick or Voice Profiles, or, more broadly about whether they want to bring a smart speaker of any kind into their home.</p>
<p>Amazon says the new Alexa Voice Profiles for Kids should reach all Amazon customers by Friday, July 2. Reading Sidekick is available today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/amazon-introduces-reading-sidekick-a-kids-reading-companion-for-alexa-and-voice-profiles-for-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171361</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Co-op raises $5.8M to help online merchants land customers for less</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/co-op-raises-5-8m-round-to-help-online-merchants-land-customers-for-less/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/co-op-raises-5-8m-round-to-help-online-merchants-land-customers-for-less/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 13:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bessemer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[co-op]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ask anyone looking to sell online about their customer acquisition costs compared to a few years ago, and you&#8217;ll hear a tale of woe. Channels that were once a cost-effective ground for acquiring customers, like various social networks, have become increasingly pricey real estate. Facebook&#8217;s recent broaching of the $1 trillion market cap threshold attests [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ask anyone looking to sell online about their customer acquisition costs compared to a few years ago, and you&#8217;ll hear a tale of woe. Channels that were once a cost-effective ground for acquiring customers, like various social networks, have become increasingly pricey real estate. Facebook&#8217;s recent <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1409609918055956483">broaching of the $1 trillion market cap threshold</a> attests to the fact.</p>
<p>But <a href="https://www.coopcommerce.com/">co-op</a> wants to shake up how online sellers find new customers, and it wants to do so with a spirit of collaboration at a discount. The startup announced a $5.8 million round today that closed earlier this month, evidence that it has found backers for its model that has already collected 500 brands.</p>
<p>That final figure matters because co-op is an almost uniquely collaborative company. Brands that sign up to be part of co-op include its technology on their post-purchase page, allowing for other, related items to be shown to customers who just finished buying something. By including the widget, a company&#8217;s product will be shown on the post-purchase page of another company.</p>
<p>That sounds anti-capitalist at the very least, which wouldn&#8217;t work in a venture-backed world. So, what&#8217;s the twist? The post-purchase page widget shows three or four products, giving it extra inventory that it can sell to its partnered brands. Presto, revenue.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s founder and CEO, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/connersherline/">Conner Sherline,</a> told TechCrunch that his startup can deliver advertising space at around half the cost-per-action of Facebook and other channels; how the economics of its model scale as more brands join will be fascinating to watch.</p>
<p>The startup also offers software tooling, including a post-purchase survey feature that costs 5 cents per order for customers to leverage.</p>
<p>Sherline&#8217;s startup appears to be growing quickly. When it raised pre-seed capital last July, it had around 20 brands onboarded to its service. Today, the company is adding another 50 to 100 each month. At that rate, it could reach 1,000 brands in total by the end of the year, barring any deceleration in its ability to attract new brands to its network.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s early progress attracted <a href="https://sugarcap.com/">Sugar Capital</a> to lead its latest round, which also saw participation from <a href="https://www.bvp.com/">Bessemer Venture Partners</a> and online e-commerce giant Shopify. The Shopify check is interesting; co-op already <a href="https://apps.shopify.com/co-op-commerce-1">exists on the Shopify app store</a>, for example. TechCrunch will keep an eye out for more integrations between the two companies, something that could turbo-charge the startup&#8217;s growth.</p>
<p>There are a number of places for co-op to expand into. Sherline told TechCrunch in an interview that its collaborative network is the first thing that the company is working on. But with lots of sales data and a wealth of partners, co-op could build out partner networks aimed at other parts of the e-commerce sales life cycle pretty easily, we reckon.</p>
<p>Regardless, the company now has a multiple of the $1.6 million that it had raised before. Let&#8217;s see how quickly it can scale its brand base with the new funds.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/co-op-raises-5-8m-round-to-help-online-merchants-land-customers-for-less/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171215</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arrows raises $2.75M to build out its customer onboarding software</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/arrows-raises-2-75m-to-build-out-its-customer-onboarding-software/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/arrows-raises-2-75m-to-build-out-its-customer-onboarding-software/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 13:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arrows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gradient Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Arrows, a startup building software to help software companies onboard their customers, announced that it has raised a $2.75 million round led by Google&#8217;s Gradient Ventures. The round was joined by a host of angels, including funds from Sprout Social founder and CEO Justyn Howard. Per Arrows CEO Daniel Zarick, the company had [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://arrows.to/">Arrows</a>, a startup building software to help software companies onboard their customers, announced that it has raised a $2.75 million round led by <a href="https://www.gradient.com/">Google&#8217;s Gradient Ventures</a>. The round was joined by a host of angels, including funds from Sprout Social founder and CEO Justyn Howard.</p>
<p>Per Arrows CEO Daniel Zarick, the company had bootstrapped until this round. That allowed the startup to allow dozens of smaller investors to take part in this funding event, including 28 micro-checks that it rolled into a single cap-table line-item thanks to an AngelList service that allows for smaller investments to be combined.</p>
<p>Arrows sells to software CEOs and heads of customer success, the people who care the most about ensuring that new customers get up and running with new digital products as quickly as possible. Per Zarick, successful customer onboarding to a new product or service can speed up adoption, helping boost revenue from usage-based products; it&#8217;s also generally known that stronger onboarding can also lead to better adoption inside of customer organizations, potentially limiting later churn.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Given the scale of the modern software market, Arrows is selling into fertile ground. That&#8217;s the reason that Zarick and his co-founder Benedict Fritz decided to stop being a two-person shop, and raise more capital. They were worried, Zarick explained, about suffocating their company without more capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nyD4cdfTNk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/six-tips-for-saas-founders-who-dont-want-vc-money/">6 tips for SaaS founders who don’t want VC money</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;6 tips for SaaS founders who don’t want VC money&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/six-tips-for-saas-founders-who-dont-want-vc-money/embed/#?secret=nyD4cdfTNk" data-secret="nyD4cdfTNk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Luckily for Arrows, one investor had already taken a keen eye to their work. Namely Gradient Ventures&#8217; <a href="https://twitter.com/darian314">Darian Shirazi</a>, who had reached out a number of times before the startup was even considering raising external funds. Per the Arrows CEO, Shirazi had already sent the startup his own portfolio companies as leads before he invested, some of whom have become customers. So, when Zarick and Fritz decided to pursue venture capital, there was a leading name already on hand.</p>
<p>The $2.75 million round was raised using a SAFE at a single cap, sans discount.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2171211" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2171211" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2171211 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-5.53.50-PM.png?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="164" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-5.53.50-PM.png 774w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-5.53.50-PM.png?resize=150,82 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-5.53.50-PM.png?resize=300,164 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-5.53.50-PM.png?resize=768,419 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-5.53.50-PM.png?resize=680,371 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Screen-Shot-2021-06-28-at-5.53.50-PM.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2171211" class="wp-caption-text">Arrows CEO Daniel Zarick, via YouTube.</p></div></p>
<p>Arrows initially <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/arrows-3">launched its service in March</a>, but is revamping its pricing this week, closing its self-serve model for the near-term.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s interesting to listen to the CEO of a seed-stage startup discuss evolving from a bootstrapped model to one backed by a good-sized amount of venture funding. Zarick described to TechCrunch in an interview how much his job was changing now that the company is working to scale up to a team of around eight. The company intends to stay at that human scale for a little while.</p>
<p>Per its CEO, Arrows can get along for two years with its current capital sans revenue growth; though we&#8217;d expect that now that it has attracted seed capital, other VCs will look to pile on &#8212; a trend that we&#8217;ve seen often in recent weeks and months.</p>
<p>The Arrows product is also going to evolve in the coming months. While attacking customer onboarding teams&#8217; use of spreadsheets with modern software has worked thus far, the startup has lots of planned work ahead of it, including more integrations with external software. Let&#8217;s see how quickly we hear from Arrows again. I&#8217;ll wager anyone a high-five that it&#8217;s before the end of the year.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/arrows-raises-2-75m-to-build-out-its-customer-onboarding-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Construction robotics company Toggle raises $8M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/construction-robotics-company-toggle-raises-8m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/construction-robotics-company-toggle-raises-8m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toggle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New York-based construction startup Toggle this morning announced that it has raised an $8 million Series A. The round was led by Tribeca Venture Partners and featured Blackhorn Ventures, Point72 Ventures, New York State and Twenty Seven Ventures. It follows a $3 million seed round raised in late-2019. Robotics in general have been a massively [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">New York-based construction startup <a href="https://www.toggle.is/">Toggle</a> this morning announced that it has raised an $8 million Series A. The round was led by Tribeca Venture Partners and featured Blackhorn Ventures, Point72 Ventures, New York State and Twenty Seven Ventures. It follows a $3 million seed round raised in late-2019.</p>
<p>Robotics in general have been a massively popular investment target during the pandemic. Construction startups have also begun to heat up. Early this month, Dusty announced a $16.5 million raise for its Field Printer device.</p>
<p>Toggle automates an entirely different part of the construction process. The company’s robotics technology specifically targets rebar, using robotics to assemble the foundational building material at a fraction of the time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“At a time when global construction is accelerating to an unprecedented pace, Toggle offers a way to add capacity while saving time and cost on some of the largest types of projects,” cofounder and CEO Daniel Blank said in a statement, “We are especially grateful for our partners who are helping us to bring new tools and approaches to the fundamental building block of our built environment with a focus on renewable energy and sustainable urban development.”</p>
<p>Toggle says the new round will go toward expanding production on the tech. That includes increasing headcount and upgrading the production space to a new 50,000 square foot facility.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="geZCGepTzo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/investment-in-construction-automation-is-essential-to-rebuilding-us-infrastructure/">Investment in construction automation is essential to rebuilding US infrastructure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investment in construction automation is essential to rebuilding US infrastructure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/investment-in-construction-automation-is-essential-to-rebuilding-us-infrastructure/embed/#?secret=geZCGepTzo" data-secret="geZCGepTzo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/construction-robotics-company-toggle-raises-8m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171129</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SaaS-focused Acceleprise rebrands, raises $30M in new capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/saas-focused-acceleprise-rebrands-raises-30m-in-new-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/saas-focused-acceleprise-rebrands-raises-30m-in-new-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceleprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch has covered Acceleprise several times over the years, including a look at its mid-2020 accelerator startup batch from its three accelerators. The firm has long focused on business-to-business SaaS startups, helping them get their start in a competitive global software market. As of today, Acceleprise is now Forum Ventures, according to the group&#8217;s CEO [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch has covered Acceleprise several times over the years, including a look at its<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/acceleprise-announces-26-saas-startups-from-its-trio-of-accelerators/"> mid-2020 accelerator startup batch</a> from its three accelerators. The firm has long focused on business-to-business SaaS startups, helping them get their start in a competitive global software market.</p>
<p>As of today, Acceleprise is now Forum Ventures, according to the group&#8217;s CEO and managing partner, <a href="https://twitter.com/mgcardamone?lang=en">Michael Cardamone</a>, and it has a bushel of funds to power its work. And befitting its new name, the company is now more than merely a collection of software-focused accelerators.</p>
<p>In addition to a new, larger $17 million fund for its pre-seed work, Forum Ventures has also raised its first seed fund. The new seed vehicle totals $13.2 billion, with Cardamone telling TechCrunch that the group intends to write checks ranging from $100,000 to $650,000 into rounds valued between $1 million and $4 million. It&#8217;s an actual seed fund, in other words.</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s interesting that Forum has put together a seed fund that will invest both in its accelerator graduates and other SaaS companies, the firm&#8217;s new pre-seed investing vehicle is noticeably larger than its preceding accelerator fund. Why is it so much bigger? Per Cardamone, the group added a third accelerator since its last fund, helping explain the size shift.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5CWpdfu47R"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/acceleprise-announces-26-saas-startups-from-its-trio-of-accelerators/">Acceleprise announces 26 SaaS startups from its trio of accelerators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Acceleprise announces 26 SaaS startups from its trio of accelerators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/acceleprise-announces-26-saas-startups-from-its-trio-of-accelerators/embed/#?secret=5CWpdfu47R" data-secret="5CWpdfu47R" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The technology market is also simply more expensive in every way than it was, and Forum has expanded its staff, so more capital under management makes sense.</p>
<p>There is synergy between the pre-seed and seed funds, of course. Forum can now better defend early ownership in standout companies from its accelerator batches. But why keep the door open to investing in other startups that it didn&#8217;t help incubate? It comes back to the company&#8217;s new name, it turns out. Cardamone and the team chose Forum Ventures because of the work it has done to build a SaaS community that from time to time spins up companies that didn&#8217;t go through Forum&#8217;s programs, he said, and it wants to invest in some of them.</p>
<p>Reasonable.</p>
<p>Undergirding Forum&#8217;s new raise are results from its earlier funds. Its first accelerator fund, deployed from the end of 2014 through the next two years, has returned &#8220;86% of committed capital to date and the rest of the fund is marked at 3.36X and growing with 18 companies still live at various stages,&#8221; the firm shared in an email.</p>
<p>Funds 2 and 3 are a bit nascent yet to have similarly concrete returns; we&#8217;ll have to wait a bit to see how they perform.</p>
<p>But TechCrunch did want to know, regardless, what impact COVID-19 had on Forum and its various funds and batches. Did they catch a COVID-induced wave? We wondered if some good recent results may have helped the firm raise not only larger funds, but two of them at the same time.</p>
<p>According to Cardamone, the answer is <em>somewhat</em>. In its most recent pre-seed fund, the CEO said that its accelerator cohorts are seeing more startups raise faster seed and Series A rounds. And, as TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/the-early-stage-venture-capital-market-is-weird-and-chaotic/">has written lately</a>, they are, at times, raising Series A deals at lower ARR thresholds than we might have expected. So, it&#8217;s a good time to be putting pre-seed dollars to work, we reckon, provided that you have the deal flow.</p>
<p>Forum is now 11 people, including six women and one nonbinary individual. That&#8217;s about as diverse in gender terms as we&#8217;ve seen in the SaaS venture capital world. From its new seed fund, 53% of Forum&#8217;s investments have had a woman or otherwise underrepresented founder. Not bad.</p>
<p>Now let&#8217;s see if Forum can replicate its early accelerator returns with more capital, more financial vehicles and more people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/saas-focused-acceleprise-rebrands-raises-30m-in-new-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170892</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orum raises $56M to help speed up interbank transfers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/orum-raises-56m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/orum-raises-56m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexa von Tobel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bain capital ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canapi Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspired Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeffrey Reitman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jpmorgan chase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silicon valley bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orum, which aims to speed up the amount of time it takes to transfer money between banks, announced today it has raised $56 million in a Series B round of funding. Accel and Canapi Ventures co-led the round, which also included participation from existing backers Bain Capital Ventures, Inspired Capital, Homebrew, Acrew, Primary, Clocktower and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://orum.ai/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orum</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which aims to speed up the amount of time it takes to transfer money between banks, announced today it has raised $56 million in a Series B round of funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accel and Canapi Ventures co-led the round, which also included participation from existing backers Bain Capital Ventures, Inspired Capital, Homebrew, Acrew, Primary, Clocktower and Box Group. The financing comes barely three months after Orum announced a $21 million Series A, and brings <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/orum-the-platform-for-frictionless-financial-infrastructure-raises-56m-in-series-b-funding-from-accel-and-canapi-ventures-to-transform-how-money-moves-301322041.html">its total raised</a> to over $82 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orum CEO Stephany Kirkpatrick launched the company in 2019 after working for </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">several years at LearnVest, a personal finance site founded by Alexa von Tobel that was acquired by Northwestern Mutual in 2015 for an estimated $375 million. Tobel went on to form Inspired Capital, a venture capital firm that put money in Orum’s </span><a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/orum-io-seed--f13df00c"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$5.2 million seed round</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last August. Prior to that, the firm also provided Orum</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> with an &#8220;inspiration check&#8221; that was the first money into the business.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="gs">
<div class="">
<div id=":5av" class="ii gt adO">
<div id=":5am" class="a3s aiL ">
<div class="yj6qo ajU">
<div id=":5b2" class="ajR" tabindex="0" role="button" data-tooltip="Show trimmed content" aria-label="Show trimmed content" aria-expanded="false"><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">As a certified financial planner, Kirkpatrick says she saw firsthand what she describes as “deep cracks” in this country’s financial infrastructure. The fact that it takes days for money to move from one bank to another is not only inconvenient for many, but unnecessary, she believes.</span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most Americans are not familiar with the intricacies of ACH [automated clearing house) or why it takes multiple business days to move money between accounts,” Kirkpatrick said. “But none of us can allow money to wait 5-7 days to hit our accounts. It needs to be instant.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her mission with Orum is straightforward even if the technology behind it is complex. Put simply, Orum aims to use machine learning-backed APIs to “move money smartly across all payment rails, and in doing so, provide universal financial access.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orum’s first embeddable product, Foresight, launched in September of 2020. It’s an automated programming interface designed to give financial institutions a way to move money in real time. The platform uses machine learning and data science to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">predict when funds are available and to identify any potential risks. Its Momentum product “intelligently” routes funds across payments rails and is powered by banking providers JPMorgan Chase and Silicon Valley Bank.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They power the back end of our Momentum platform that allows the money to move on a multirail basis,” Kirkpatrick told TechCrunch. “They power our access to real-time payments.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orum says it serves a range of enterprise partners, including Alloy, HM Bradley, First Horizon Bank and Zero Financial (which was </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/avant-doubles-down-on-digital-banking-with-acquisition-of-zero-financial-and-its-neobank/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">recently acquired by Avant</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The volume of transactions being conducted with Orum is growing 100% month over month, Kirkpatrick said. Most of its early growth has come from word of mouth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The remote-first company prides itself on diversity — in both its employee and investor base. For one, 48% of its 55-person headcount are female, and 48% are “nonwhite,” according to Kirkpatrick. Orum also recently joined the </span><a href="https://captablecoalition.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cap Table Coalition</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> — a partnership between high-growth startups and emerging investors who want to work to close the racial wealth gap — to allocate over 10% of its Series B round to underrepresented founders. For example, the financing includes investors such as the Neythri Features Fund, a group of South Asian women investing in the next generation of female founders and diverse teams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jeffrey Reitman, partner at Canapi Ventures (a firm whose LPs mostly consist of banks), told TechCrunch that those bank LPs </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">conduct hundreds of millions of ACH transactions annually, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They need a path to achieving a state where funds can be transferred instantly,” he said. “Orum’s product paves the path for many players in financial services and fintech — and beyond — to partake in faster money movement without compromising key risk principles.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To Reitman, the company’s major differentiators are its team, which he describes as consisting of “the best group of data scientists and engineers in the space.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Many of their customers consider the team to be instrumental in helping to set the risk dials on how they fund transactions by teasing out key data and insights from historical transaction data,” he said. “Second, Orum is building one of the densest and most comprehensive data sets around the risks of money movement. Better data means better risk models, and it will be hard for other offerings to match Orum’s approach to building this rich data set.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accel Partner Sameer Gandhi, who joined Orum’s board as part of the latest financing, agrees. He believes that in an 18-month period, Orum has built “game-changing technology and an exceptional team.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Orum is tackling financial infrastructure from its foundation,” he said.</span></p>
<p><em>The headline was updated post-publication to reflect the correct funding amount.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9BH8dwc4ON"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/">The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The fintech endgame: New supercompanies combine the best of software and financials&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/the-fintech-endgame-new-supercompanies-combine-the-best-of-software-and-financials/embed/#?secret=9BH8dwc4ON" data-secret="9BH8dwc4ON" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/orum-raises-56m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170736</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visier raises $125M at a $1B valuation for its big-data approach to HR analytics and planning</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/visier-raises-125m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-big-data-approach-to-hr-analytics-and-planning/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/visier-raises-125m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-big-data-approach-to-hr-analytics-and-planning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The world of work has changed massively in the last year, and with it a rush of startups have emerged with new technology and approaches to improve how it is shaped, and specifically how human resources departments do their jobs. In the latest chapter, Visier, a Canadian startup that has built a big-data engine to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The world of work has changed massively in the last year, and with it a rush of startups have emerged with new technology and approaches to improve how it is shaped, and specifically how human resources departments do their jobs. In the latest chapter, <a href="https://www.visier.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Visier</a>, a Canadian startup that has built a big-data engine to ingest and analyze information from disparate human resources and related applications to develop more accurate profiles of people and departments &#8212; useful when considering remuneration, promotions, and wider hiring budgets &#8212; has raised $125 million (USD), a Series E that the company confirms now values it at $1 billion.</p>
<p>The funding comes on the heels of the company seeing massive growth in particular in the last year, with companies scrambling more than ever before, in a new world of more hybrid and remote work, to get a better grip on how and what teams and individuals are doing. Visier said it now processes employee records for 8,000 customers, large and high-profile enterprises like Adobe, BASF, Bridgestone, Electronic Arts, McKesson, Merck KGaA and Uber that collectively represent some 12 million individual users across 75 countries.</p>
<p>New backer Goldman Sachs Asset Management is leading the round, with previous investors Sorenson Capital, Foundation Capital, Summit Partners, and Adams Street Partners also participating. Visier &#8212; pronounced &#8220;busier,&#8221; which co-founder and chairman John Schwarz joked you are <em>not</em> supposed to be when using its product &#8212; has now raised just under $220 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As Schwarz described it to me, the challenge that Visier is addressing is that while everyone uses HR management tools like Workday, Success Factors, any number of payroll applications and more &#8212; on average 20 applications per department, he said &#8212; to chart a lot of basics of how an employee works day to day or month to month, a lot of that data remains in silos and so it&#8217;s hard to get a &#8220;360&#8221; view based on all of it, and that&#8217;s before considering how to take that information and benchmark it against other information outside the business.</p>
<p>The solution that Visier provides to address that is a big-data engine that it has built that can connect to any and all of those apps, ingest the data contained in it, match it up to provide visualizations of the current state of things, and increasingly also predictive insights. Today, this is done typically for HR departments, but this has applicability to managers, finance departments and really the employees themselves.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the future we want to help everyone understand the policy today, which impacts the outcome tomorrow,&#8221; he said in an interview.</p>
<p class="p1">The move to build big data analytics targeting particular areas of an organization has been an interesting trend that has played out in other departments too such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/dooly-raises-80m-more-for-its-ai-tools-to-help-salespeople-manage-their-busywork/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sales</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/11/12/tidemarks-latest-release-uses-big-data-to-help-finance-look-forward-instead-of-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">finance</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/quantexa-raises-64-7m-to-bring-big-data-intelligence-to-risk-analysis-and-investigations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">risk analysis</a> and other areas. The idea here is not unlike what data scientists have been working on for years with wider analytics questions: tapping troves of data from disparate sources to order it better, match it up with each other, to provide insight into wider trends and activities within an organization.</p>
<p class="p1">As data science becomes more democratized &#8212; and thanks to advances in no-code and low-code tooling, turned into tools that even non-technical people can implement and use &#8212; we will likely see many more use cases where this idea gets applied. After all, data is the new oil, but unlike actual oil, we seem to be supplied with an endless amount of it these days.</p>
<p class="p1">And yes, we&#8217;ve seen a real rush of HR tools come to the market in recent years &#8212; and see a lot of funding in the current climate as their businesses see customer interest rise &#8212; they include HR platforms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/hibob-raises-70m-on-a-500m-valuation-for-its-new-take-on-hr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hibob</a>, HR aimed at particular verticals like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/personio-raises-125m-on-a-1-7b-valuation-for-an-hr-platform-targeting-smes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Personio</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/factorial-raises-16m-to-take-on-the-hr-world-with-a-platform-for-smbs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Factorial</a>, or for distributed workforces like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/oyster-an-hr-platform-for-distributed-workforces-snaps-up-50m-on-a-475m-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Oyster</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/remote-raises-35m-to-help-orgs-with-global-workforce-payroll-benefits-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Remote</a>, or those that are building supercharged org-charts like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/charthop-raises-35m-for-its-internal-org-chart-and-people-analytics-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ChartHop</a>.</p>
<p class="p1">But Visier believes that there are no big-data players looking not to be primary-source repositories of information but big data integrators from other platforms. Schwarz notes that in most cases, the &#8220;competition&#8221; will be custom-made implementations built by systems integrators using Tableau or something similar but not the same as what it provides in terms of real-time analytics.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s all about using data from other sources,&#8221; he said, pointing out that it&#8217;s telling that Workday tried to build something like what Visier provides, but that more than half of Visier&#8217;s customers also use Workday (meaning whatever is there is not quite doing the trick).</p>
<p>“Access to information about employees and the health of an organization has never been more critical,” said Holger Staude, managing director within Goldman Sachs Asset Management. “We’re excited to partner with Visier at this pivotal moment and support the company’s continued growth.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/visier-raises-125m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-big-data-approach-to-hr-analytics-and-planning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gympass, the corporate wellness unicorn, raises a $220M series E</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gympass-the-corporate-wellness-unicorn-raises-a-220m-series-e/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gympass-the-corporate-wellness-unicorn-raises-a-220m-series-e/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marcella McCarthy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[classpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harvard Business School]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaszek Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McKinsey & Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pricewaterhousecoopers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2170357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gympass, the exercise and corporate wellness unicorn that originated in Brazil, today announced a $220 million Series E. The company has seen tremendous growth in the last few months, as more and more people are vaccinated and flocking back to the gym. Gympass is like ClassPass, but on steroids. However, unlike ClassPass’ BTC and B2B [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gympass, the exercise and corporate wellness unicorn that originated in Brazil, today announced a $220 million Series E. The company has seen tremendous growth in the last few months, as more and more people are vaccinated and flocking back to the gym.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://site.gympass.com/web/us">Gympass</a> is like ClassPass, but on steroids. However, unlike ClassPass’ BTC and B2B model, Gympass partners only with employers who then pay a flat fee for the platform (an app) which then allows their employees to choose from several wellbeing plans that give them access to myriad in-person gyms and studios, and a directory of health apps, such as Calm. The offerings are broken up into the following categories: physical health, emotional health, nutrition and sleep. ClassPass already has clients like Google and Morgan Stanley on board.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the company, in May, Gympass saw a record 4 million monthly check-ins across its network of more than 50,000 global partners. In fact, for some of the partners, usage hit above pre-COVID levels. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Between increased anxiety rates and documented weight gain during the pandemic, it’s clear that people are eager to get active again with the hopes of improving their mental health and their waistlines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GymPass is the brainchild of Cesar Carvalho, a former McKinsey &amp; Company consultant in Brazil who was always on the road and yearned for a corporate wellness product that would comply with his hectic work schedule.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6ZiSW1GSFD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/">The Tonal EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Tonal EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/embed/#?secret=6ZiSW1GSFD" data-secret="6ZiSW1GSFD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Some days I worked from home, other days I worked from the office, and then there was the time I was traveling. I could never go to the gym in one place,” Carvalho told TechCrunch. “I realized that my needs were the same as others,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He decided to pursue his business idea while he was at Harvard Business School.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m one of those crazy entrepreneurs that drops out of their MBA to start a company, but looking back now, it worked out okay,” he said, later telling TechCrunch that Gympass is now in Brazil, Mexico, Chile, Argentina, the U.S., Germany, Spain, Italy, Ireland, and the U.K. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since its launch in São Paulo in 2012, the company achieved product-market fit fairly quickly, and its growth and expansion have been largely organic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Originally, Gympass was a BTC concept, and one of its first clients was an executive at PricewaterhouseCoopers in Brazil. He liked the product so much that he eventually said to Carvalho, “Can’t I communicate this to my 5000 employees in all the cities where we have offices in Brazil?” With that question &#8211; and offer &#8211; Carvalho saw the need to pivot and build a B2B company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After only three years in Brazil, one of his biggest Brazilian clients asked Carvalho to expand to Mexico, because his company had a large presence there and he wanted to offer Gympass to its employees. And so follows most of the expansion stories. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We expanded to Spain, because we worked with a Spanish bank in Mexico, and they wanted their employees in Spain to have access to our product,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This round, which doubles the company’s valuation to $2.2 billion, includes participation from SoftBank, General Atlantic, More Strategic Ventures, Kaszek Ventures and Valor. Carvalho plans to use the money to grow the company in the U.S., expand its offerings, and work on making the tech smarter. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We want [the app] to be able to recommend the best partners for your complete well-being journey based on your workout patterns, for example: ‘This is the best meditation app for you to use with your workout profile,’” Carvalho said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5XKoCEGyTH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/">How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/embed/#?secret=5XKoCEGyTH" data-secret="5XKoCEGyTH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/gympass-the-corporate-wellness-unicorn-raises-a-220m-series-e/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2170357</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>4G Clinical&#8217;s clinical trial management software attracts over $200M in new funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clinical trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic significantly changed how we do medical research, and now companies are trying to figure out what trends will stay and which ones will go. One that 4G Clinical is hoping will survive the pandemic is a need for speed and flexibility in therapeutics trials.  4G Clinical creates software to run the back-end of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic significantly changed how we do medical research, and now companies are trying to figure out what trends will stay and which ones will go. One that 4G Clinical is hoping will survive the pandemic is a need for speed and flexibility in therapeutics trials. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G Clinical creates software to run the back-end of a clinical trial. That means randomizing patients into treatment and placebo groups, locating medicines and placebos, keeping the supply of those medicines stocked, and, at least during the pandemic, delivering those medicines to patients. All of these tasks fall under the umbrella of Randomized Trial Supply Management, or RTSM for short. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically, 4G Clinical&#8217;s software, called Prancer, uses natural language processing to take specific requirements needed to manage a clinical trial, which are often written in long, complex documents, and configures them into a platform.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fastest the company has been able to move from a phone call to the first dose in a clinical trial was 6 days – a sprint that created the software needed for a COVID-19 study during the pandemic. That was an exceptionally fast case, but in general, 4G Clinical says it can beat standard timelines by considerable margins.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most vendors in the world would say that they are probably, you know, between 10 and 16 weeks from, you know, from the kicking off a study until they can dose a patient,” says Dave Kelleher, a company co-founder. “Our typical timeline is generally four to six weeks post spec signature.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Generally, large pharmaceutical companies are capable of creating these trial management systems internally. Small companies, however, may not have the capability to do so. 4G Clinical goal is to provide a service that can be of use to both. 4G Clinical has currently designed systems for over 230 companies – though the company would not disclose the specific trials in which its systems are being used. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Y1OUCuhR4C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/4-strategies-for-building-a-digital-health-unicorn/">4 strategies for building a digital health unicorn</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 strategies for building a digital health unicorn&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/4-strategies-for-building-a-digital-health-unicorn/embed/#?secret=Y1OUCuhR4C" data-secret="Y1OUCuhR4C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G clinical is also announcing over $200 million in a growth equity round led by Goldman Sachs. Before Goldman, the primary investment came from Boston-based Schooner Capital and First Analysis, a VC firm out of Chicago. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kelleher declined to say what the plans for the round were, other than company has plans to pursue more go-to-market strategies and R&amp;D, and ultimately aims to “take up as much air” in the eClinical and RTSM space as possible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The eClinical market is expected to reach about </span><a href="https://www.gminsights.com/pressrelease/eclinical-solutions-market"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$14.7 billion by 2027</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. RTSM made up about 17 percent of market share in 2020. With the complexity of clinical trials increasing, and the number of trials growing – even after COVID-19 related issues shut many trials down in 2020 – there may be room for more growth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before COVID-19, there was evidence that the amount of clinical trials had </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/resources/trends"><span style="font-weight: 400;">steadily been increasing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. In 2000, there were 2,119 clinical trials registered at Clinicaltrials.gov. By 2010, 100,208, and by 2020, 362,532 registered by the end of the year (that includes massive slowdowns created by the pandemic for non-COVID research). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Within that landscape, there is some evidence that sponsors of clinical trials are using more external applications to manage those clinical trials. Of 500 clinical operations professionals respondents </span><a href="https://www.veeva.com/eu/resources/clinical-operations-survey-report-2020/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">surveyed</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Veeva (another eClinical company, keep in mind) found that 63 percent were using an RTSM system, up from about 43 percent in 2017. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G Clinical, generally, is looking to benefit from the increased public attention to the clinical trials process, and the flexibility that the pandemic has created for sponsors to get creative with clinical trial designs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic did encourage some innovation in this regard. Take, for example, the World Health Organization’s SOLIDARITY trial, which used an adaptive trial design in which multiple drugs could be tested at once. Drugs that showed no promise mid-way through the trial could be dropped (as hydroxychloroquine was in June 2020). The adaptive part, in short, allows for mid-trial tweaks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s not the traditional design of the gold-standard randomized controlled clinical trial, but it did glean a significant amount of knowledge in a short period of time. </span><a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMe2034294"><span style="font-weight: 400;">After seven months</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, three of four drugs tested showed no effect on mortality, whereas the fifth remdesivir, showed some limited promise. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9o43Rd0WAf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/the-health-data-transparency-movement-is-birthing-a-new-generation-of-startups/">The health data transparency movement is birthing a new generation of startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The health data transparency movement is birthing a new generation of startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/the-health-data-transparency-movement-is-birthing-a-new-generation-of-startups/embed/#?secret=9o43Rd0WAf" data-secret="9o43Rd0WAf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adaptive trial designs weren’t unheard of before the pandemic – the FDA had actually released guidance on adaptive clinical trials </span><a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/78495/download"><span style="font-weight: 400;">in 2019</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But the post-pandemic landscape might encourage more flexibility in this regard, and with it, increase a need for software that can be tweaked to accommodate such changes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think that we saw some regulatory hurdles reduced as part of this process that allows for more creativity in study design,” says Kelleher. “Probably the most important thing for us is our flexibility, we can make changes to studies very rapidly – to live studies.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4G Clinical and other RTSM software like it, are looking to hone tools that already exist within clinical trials – specifically software used to actually run them. It’s an area of research that the team itself has both a personal stake in, and strong industry knowledge. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kelleher was diagnosed with Multiple Sclerosis at the age of 23 (a disease to which there is still no definitive cure), and previously founded the Portland-based ACME business consulting. His co-founder Ed Tourtellotte, lost his wife to breast cancer around the same time. Neither have a background in pharmacology, but rather, the team is tackling drug development through streamlining clinical trial software. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By contrast, other companies aim to streamline clinical trial processes through A.I-based drug target identification, an especially hype-induced area of the space in which investment quadrupled to </span><a href="https://aiindex.stanford.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/2021-AI-Index-Report_Master.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$13.9 billion between 2019 and 2020</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Clinical trial management software may seem more mundane, but it’s still an essential part of running Phase III and most Phase II studies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tourtellotte has designed bespoke software systems for major drug developers, including Pfizer’s Impala system (used in 80 percent of Pfizer’s clinical trials for the past 20 years, says Kelleher) and another system Trident, which was sold </span><a href="https://www.outsourcing-pharma.com/Article/2010/10/20/BioClinica-to-launch-game-changing-IVR-IWR-platform"><span style="font-weight: 400;">to Bioclinica in 2009</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (along with Tourtoulette’s company, Tourtellotte Solutions). Trident was </span><a href="https://www.genengnews.com/topics/drug-discovery/gsk-to-use-bioclinica-tool-to-manage-clinical-trials/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">utilized by GlaxoSmithKlein</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for clinical trials in 2010. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At this point, the company has declined to confirm a total amount of funding, but in 2020, revenue grew 110 percent with just ten percent of its portfolio focused on COVID-19 related projects. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8MCKO4ME4t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/does-early-stage-health-tech-need-more-patient-capital/">Does early-stage health tech need more &#8216;patient&#8217; capital?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Does early-stage health tech need more &#8216;patient&#8217; capital?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/does-early-stage-health-tech-need-more-patient-capital/embed/#?secret=8MCKO4ME4t" data-secret="8MCKO4ME4t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171334</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
