<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 07:59:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Web Summit will hold RISE 2022 in Kuala Lumpur, launch a new event in Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/web-summit-will-hold-rise-2022-in-kuala-lumpur-launch-a-new-event-in-tokyo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/web-summit-will-hold-rise-2022-in-kuala-lumpur-launch-a-new-event-in-tokyo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 07:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kuala lumpur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web summit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Web Summit announced today that it will revive RISE, one of Asia’s largest tech conferences, in March 2022, moving it to Kuala Lumpur after five years in Hong Kong. It also announced a new event, called Web Summit Tokyo, that will launch in 2022, too. The flagship Web Summit event is currently taking place as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://websummit.com/">Web Summit </a>announced today that it will revive <a href="https://riseconf.com/">RISE</a>, one of Asia’s largest tech conferences, in March 2022, moving it to Kuala Lumpur after five years in Hong Kong. It also announced a new event, called Web Summit Tokyo, that will launch in 2022, too.</p>
<p>The flagship <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/the-summit" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="the-summit">Web Summit <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> event is currently taking place as an online conference.</p>
<p>In November 2019, Web Summit announced it was postponing RISE to 2021 amid the pro-democracy demonstrations in Hong Kong. Of course, this year has seen a series of other major event cancellations due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H34gZTwHyy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/15/rise-conference-2020-2021/">Web Summit cancels next year&#8217;s Rise conference over tension in Hong Kong</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Web Summit cancels next year&#8217;s Rise conference over tension in Hong Kong&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/15/rise-conference-2020-2021/embed/#?secret=H34gZTwHyy" data-secret="H34gZTwHyy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Web Summit is planning for the 2022 edition of RISE to be in-person, and has signed a new partnership with Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation. In a press statement, Web Summit and RISE co-founder and chief executive officer Paddy Cosgrave said, &#8220;This is not a goodbye to Hong Kong. We hope to return to the city in the future with a brand new event.&#8221;</p>
<p>Web Summit Tokyo, which will take place in September 2022, as part of its global expansion, which will also include an event in Brazil Rio de Janeiro or Porto Alegre are currently being considered as the location.</p>
<p>Web Summit has already announced plans to hold its flagship event as an in-person conference in November 2021 in Lisbon, Portugal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/web-summit-will-hold-rise-2022-in-kuala-lumpur-launch-a-new-event-in-tokyo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bolt unveils its fourth-generation scooter</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/bolt-unveils-its-fourth-generation-scooter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/bolt-unveils-its-fourth-generation-scooter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 07:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bolt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scooter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081891</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bolt is better known for its ride-hailing service. But the company also operates an electric scooter service in 45 cities across Europe. Designed by the company’s in-house hardware team, the new model focuses on safety. As you can see on the photo, it’s a big scooter that weighs 19kg — that’s more than an average [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://bolt.eu/en/">Bolt</a> is better known for its ride-hailing service. But the company also operates an <a href="https://bolt.eu/en/scooters/">electric scooter service</a> in 45 cities across Europe. Designed by the company’s in-house hardware team, the new model focuses on safety.</p>
<p>As you can see on the photo, it’s a big scooter that weighs 19kg — that’s more than an average bike. It has a battery with a 40km range and it is primarily made of aluminum.</p>
<p>The company says it should last up to 60 months thanks to a modular design. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/mtakso" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="mtakso">Bolt <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> can replace parts without having to replace the scooter altogether.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Behind the scenes, you’ll find built-in sensors to detect accidents and unsafe riding. If you fall or if you brake sharply, Bolt can be alerted. The scooter also recognizes unsafe riding patterns. Combined with audio and visual warnings, it should educate riders about what you’re supposed to do and not do.</p>
<p>On the integrated dashboard, you can receive alerts telling you that you’re riding in a pedestrian area, or in a low-speed area. You can also see if you’re allowed to park in this area. Bolt plans to turn on front light blinking when you enter a pedestrian or low-speed area.</p>
<p>Like most modern e-scooter models, Bolt can swap the battery without having to move the entire scooter. It is much more efficient to recharge detachable batteries than scooters themselves.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, Bolt unveiled plans to double-down on scooters. It plans to operate a scooter service in more than 100 cities in 2021. There could be as many as 130,000 electric scooters and electric bikes in European cities. Let’s see if the company delivers on its ambitious 2021 roadmap.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2081907" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2081907" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="676" class="size-full wp-image-2081907" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg 1965w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg?resize=768,507 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg?resize=680,449 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg?resize=1536,1015 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Bolt_4_scooter_2b.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2081907" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Bolt</p></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WEm1WycHbJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/how-four-european-cities-are-embracing-micromobility-to-drive-out-cars/">How four European cities are embracing micromobility to drive out cars</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How four European cities are embracing micromobility to drive out cars&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/how-four-european-cities-are-embracing-micromobility-to-drive-out-cars/embed/#?secret=WEm1WycHbJ" data-secret="WEm1WycHbJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/bolt-unveils-its-fourth-generation-scooter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081891</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PhonePe raises $700 million, becomes a separate entity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/phonepe-raises-700-million-becomes-a-separate-entity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/phonepe-raises-700-million-becomes-a-separate-entity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PhonePe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PhonePe, the crown jewel in Flipkart’s acquisition by Walmart, is &#8220;partially&#8221; spinning off, the Bangalore-based financial services firm said on Thursday. To kick off its new journey, the firm said it has secured $700 million in a new financing round. This round, the name of which was not disclosed, was led by Walmart with participation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/phonepe" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="phonepe">PhonePe, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> the crown jewel in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/20/walmart-flipkart-deal-done/">Flipkart’s acquisition by Walmart</a>, is &#8220;partially&#8221; spinning off, the Bangalore-based financial services firm said on Thursday. To kick off its new journey, the firm said it has secured $700 million in a new financing round.</p>
<p>This round, the name of which was not disclosed, was led by <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/walmart" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="walmart">Walmart <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> with participation from some existing investors, PhonePe said. The new round gave PhonePe, which was founded by three former <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/flipkart" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="flipkart">Flipkart <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> employees, a post-money valuation of $5.5 billion.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s announcement is a big boost to the confidence investors are showing on PhonePe. The startup had been engaging with investors for new capital for several quarters and, in at least one instance, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/03/google-and-walmarts-phonepe-establish-dominance-in-indias-mobile-payments-market-as-whatsapp-pay-struggles-to-launch/">struggled to raise funds at a $3 billion valuation earlier this year</a>, TechCrunch reported earlier. It had hoped to raise about $1 billion at a valuation as high as $10 billion last year, however, according to people familiar with the matter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The partial spin-off, which had been in the works for more than a year, means that Flipkart&#8217;s stake in PhonePe will reduce from 100% to 87%. &#8220;This partial spin-off gives PhonePe access to dedicated long-term capital to pursue our vision of providing financial inclusion to a billion Indians,&#8221; said Sameer Nigam, founder and chief executive of PhonePe, in a statement.</p>
<p>Flipkart will remain PhonePe’s majority shareholder, and the &#8220;two businesses will retain their close collaboration,&#8221; PhonePe said.</p>
<p>PhonePe, which means &#8220;on the phone&#8221; in Hindi, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/walmarts-phonepe-zips-past-google-pay-in-india-as-upi-tops-2-billion-monthly-transactions/">currently leads the mobile payments market in India</a>, by some metrics. In October, it surpassed Google Pay to become the top UPI payments app. UPI is a four-year-old payments infrastructure built by India’s largest banks. It is the most popular way people transact money digitally in India. PhonePe reported 835 million UPI transactions in October, ahead of Google Pay, which processed about 820 million transactions that month.</p>
<p>“As Flipkart Commerce continues to grow strongly serving the needs of Indian customers, we are excited at the future prospects of the group. This move will help PhonePe maximize its potential as it moves to the next phase of its development, and it will also maximize value creation for Flipkart and our shareholders,” said Kalyan Krishnamurthy, CEO of Flipkart Group, in a statement.</p>
<p>In a recent report to clients, analysts at Bernstein identified PhonePe as one of the startups in India that could file for an IPO in within three years. PhonePe&#8217;s &#8220;reliance on parent Flipkart has shrunk, from 50% of monthly transactions to less than 1% today. PhonePe was first to launch on UPI and has extended into new use cases including travel booking, bill payments, financial services etc. The company has also launched Switch which allows users to switch between PhonePe and other apps like food, grocery delivery etc. (Super App),&#8221; they wrote.</p>
<p>PhonePe, which has amassed over 100 million monthly active users, could look to expand outside of India, the analysts wrote in the report, which was obtained by TechCrunch.</p>
<p>PhonePe and Google Pay today also compete with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/paytm" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="paytm">Paytm, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which is backed by SoftBank and Alibaba. Paytm, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/24/paytm-1-billion/">privately valued at $16 billion last year when it raised $1 billion</a>, has shifted its attention to cater to merchants in recent quarters as UPI currently offers no way for companies to make any money on its platform.</p>
<p>At an event in Bangalore late last year, Sajith Sivanandan, managing director and business head of Google Pay and Next Billion User Initiatives, said current local rules in India have forced Google Pay to operate without a clear business model in the country.</p>
<p>If that wasn&#8217;t a challenge enough, WhatsApp, which is the most popular smartphone app in India with over 400 million users in the world&#8217;s second largest market, began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/whatsapp-receives-approval-to-expand-its-payments-service-in-india/">rolling out its payments service in the country last month</a>. At stake is India’s mobile payments market, which is estimated to reach $1 trillion by 2023, according to Credit Suisse.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/phonepe-raises-700-million-becomes-a-separate-entity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082354</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Food robotics startup Karakuri unveils automated canteen, plus $8.4M investment led by firstminute</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/food-robotics-startup-karakuri-unveils-automated-canteen-plus-8-4m-investment-led-by-firstminute/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/food-robotics-startup-karakuri-unveils-automated-canteen-plus-8-4m-investment-led-by-firstminute/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Hoberman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hoxton Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karakuri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week I witnessed for myself how a new kind of robot really could — as sci-fi has been telling us for many years — create and serve us food. Today, Karakuri, a food robotics startup, unveils its first automated canteen to make meals: the &#8220;DK-One” robot. It’s also revealing a $8.4 million (£6.3million) investment, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last week I witnessed for myself how a new kind of robot really could — as sci-fi has been telling us for many years — create and serve us food. Today, <a href="https://karakuri.com/">Karakuri</a>, a food robotics startup, unveils its first automated canteen to make meals: the &#8220;DK-One” robot. It’s also revealing a $8.4 million (£6.3million) investment, led by <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/firstminute-capital">firstminute capital</a>, which includes funding from Hoxton Ventures, Taylor Brothers, Ocado Group and the UK’s government-backed Future Fund. It has now closed a total of £13.5m in funding.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/karakuri" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="karakuri">Karakuri’s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> robotic system has been initially designed to make breakfast bowls. But the technology will end up being employed in a large array of scenarios, including restaurants, canteens, buffets, hotels and supermarkets. Posibly even tending vertical farms. It’s particular strength is in being able to create extremely tailor-made combinations of food, putting &#8216;personalized nutrition’ within practical reach. Remember those movies where the food is tailored by a robot? That.</p>
<p>The post-Covid world is also highly likely to embrace this technology due to the robot&#8217;s inherent cleanliness and efficiency, compared to human-made food. That said, Karakuri is not positioned to replace humans but to augment them, taking on the boring and repetitive tasks which typically see kitchen staff have far more itinerant careers due to the sheer pressure of low-level jobs where a robot would be far more suitable.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The DK-One robot is Karakuri’s first pre-production machine which uses the latest in robotics, sensing and control technologies. It’s capable of creating high quality hot and cold meals, which maximize nutritional benefits, restaurant performance and minimize food waste.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Vesx0iFc5U?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Post-COVID restrictions, further on-customer-site trials of the DK-One are expected to take place in the first half of 2021.</p>
<p>The DK-One robot zips around a circular enclosure at a rate of knots, each time measuring accurate portion sizes as determined by an app, where the customer can tailor to their tastes. It means anyone ordering something would be able to track the ingredients, nutrients, calories, and quantity of literally every meal.</p>
<p>Up to 18 ingredients can be dispensed per installation, with each ingredient temperature controlled. It will dispense of any ingredient type including wet, dry, soft, or hard food onto plates, bowls, or a range of meal containers</p>
<p>Because it’s so accurate it, therefore, reduces food waste around portions and allows for real-time data on ingredients. The thin margins restaurateurs typically have could be improved by using such a robot in repetitive tasks, and means employees can be tasked with more complex and fruitful and fulfilling work. It’s also easily integrated into existing commercial kitchens.</p>
<p>Barney Wragg, CEO and co-founder of Karakuri, said in a statement: “This will be the first time we can use a pre-production machine to demonstrate the DK-One’s commercial and nutritional benefits in the real world and thus demonstrate our vision for the future of food.”</p>
<p>Karakuri was founded by Simon Watt and Wragg, two longtime friends and colleagues who previously worked together at ARM. In April 2018 the Founders Factory venture studio invested in Karakuri and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/brent-hoberman" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="brent-hoberman">Brent Hoberman <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> joined the board as Chairman and is also listed as a co-founder.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/food-robotics-startup-karakuri-unveils-automated-canteen-plus-8-4m-investment-led-by-firstminute/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082271</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AutoX becomes China&#8217;s first to remove safety drivers from robotaxis</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/autox-removes-safety-drivers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/autox-removes-safety-drivers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 03:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AutoX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MediaTek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Momenta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shenzhen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Residents of Shenzhen will see truly driverless cars on the road starting Thursday. AutoX, a four-year-old startup backed by Alibaba, MediaTek and Shanghai Motors, is deploying a fleet of 25 unmanned vehicles in downtown Shenzhen, marking the first time any autonomous driving car in China tests without safety drivers or remote operators on public roads. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Residents of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/shenzhen-eb7c" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="shenzhen-eb7c">Shenzhen <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> will see truly driverless cars on the road starting Thursday. AutoX, a four-year-old startup backed by Alibaba, MediaTek and Shanghai Motors, is deploying a fleet of 25 unmanned vehicles in downtown Shenzhen, marking the first time any autonomous driving car in China tests without safety drivers or remote operators on public roads.</p>
<p>The cars, meant as robotaxis, are not yet open to the public, an <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/autox-ac12" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="autox-ac12">AutoX <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The milestone came just five months after AutoX <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/autonomous-vehicle-startup-autox-lands-driverless-testing-permit-in-california/">landed a permit from California</a> to start driverless tests, following in the footsteps of Waymo and Nuro.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It also indicates that China wants to bring its smart driving industry on par with the U.S. Cities from Shenzhen to Shanghai are competing to attract autonomous driving upstarts by clearing regulatory hurdles, touting subsidies and putting up 5G infrastructure.</p>
<p>As a result, each city ends up with its own poster child in the space: AutoX and Deeproute.ai in Shenzhen, Pony.ai and WeRide in Guangzhou, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/momenta-ai" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="momenta-ai">Momenta <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> in Suzhou, Baidu&#8217;s Apollo fleet in Beijing, to name a few. The autonomous driving companies, in turn, work closely with traditional carmakers to make their vehicles smarter and more suitable for future transportation.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have obtained support from the local government. Shenzhen is making a lot of rapid progress on legislation for self-driving cars,&#8221; said the AutoX representative.</p>
<p>The decision to remove drivers from the front <em>and</em> operators from a remote center appears a bold move in one of China&#8217;s most populated cities. AutoX equips its vehicles with its proprietary vehicle control unit called XCU, which it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/autox-and-fiat-chrysler-are-teaming-up-on-a-robotaxi-for-china/">claims</a> has faster processing speed and more computational capability to handle the complex road scenarios in China’s cities.</p>
<p>&#8220;[The XCU] provides multiple layers of redundancy to handle this kind of situation,&#8221; said AutoX when asked how its vehicles will respond should the machines ever go rogue.</p>
<p>The company also stressed the experience it learned from &#8220;millions of miles&#8221; driven in China&#8217;s densest city centers through its 100 robotaxis in the past few years. Its rivals are also aggressively accumulating mileage to train their self-driving algorithms while banking sizable investments to fund R&amp;D and pilot tests. AutoX itself, for instance, has raised <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/autox-ac12">more than $160 million</a> to date.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DSspKZwJmN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/momenta-profile/">How China&#8217;s first autonomous driving unicorn Momenta hunts for data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How China&#8217;s first autonomous driving unicorn Momenta hunts for data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/13/momenta-profile/embed/#?secret=DSspKZwJmN" data-secret="DSspKZwJmN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/autox-removes-safety-drivers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082324</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google faces complaint from NLRB alleging surveillance of employees and other labor violations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-nlrb-labor-complaint/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-nlrb-labor-complaint/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 02:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The National Labor Relations Board today issued a complaint against Google after investigating the firing of several employees last November. The complaint alleges Google violated parts of the National Labor Relations Act by surveilling employees, and generally interfered with, restrained and coerced employees in the exercise of their rights guaranteed by Section 7 of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The National Labor Relations Board today issued a complaint against <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> after investigating the firing of several employees last November. The complaint alleges Google violated parts of the National Labor Relations Act by surveilling employees, and generally interfered with, restrained and coerced employees in the exercise of their rights guaranteed by <a href="https://www.nlrb.gov/about-nlrb/rights-we-protect/the-law/interfering-with-employee-rights-section-7-8a1">Section 7 of the National Labor Relations Act</a>.</p>
<p>The NLRB also alleges Google discouraged &#8220;its employees from forming, joining, assisting a union or engaging in other protected, concerted activities,&#8221; the complaint states.</p>
<p>&#8220;This complaint makes clear that workers have the right to speak to issues of ethical business and the composition of management,&#8221; Laurence Berland, one of the fired Google employees, said in a statement. &#8220;This is a significant finding at a time when we’re seeing the power of a handful of tech billionaires consolidate control over our lives and our society. Workers have the right to speak out about and organize, as the NLRB is affirming, but we also know that we should not, and cannot, cleave off ethical concerns about the role management wants to play in that society.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ex-Googlers Berland and Kathryn Spiers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/03/fired-google-workers-will-file-federal-complaint-alleging-the-company-wrongfully-terminated-them/">previously filed a federal complaint with the NLRB arguing</a> Google fired them for organizing, which is a protected activity. They had organized around a variety of topics, including Google’s treatment of its temporary, vendor and contractor workers, Google’s alleged retaliation against employees who organized, the company’s work with Customs and Border Protection and more.</p>
<p>Additionally, in November 2019, Google put Rebecca Rivers and Berland on leave for allegedly violating company policies. At the time, Google said one had searched for and shared confidential documents that were not pertinent to their job, and one had looked at the individual calendars of some staffers. Following a protest in support of the two, Rivers, Berland, Duke and Waldman were fired.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>&#8220;Google has always worked to support a culture of internal discussion, and we place immense trust in our employees,&#8221; a Google spokesperson said in a statement to TechCrunch. &#8220;Of course employees have protected labor rights that we strongly support, but we have always taken information security very seriously. We’re confident in our decision and legal position. Actions undertaken by the employees at issue were a serious violation of our policies and an unacceptable breach of a trusted responsibility.”</div>
</div>
<p>This comes shortly after the <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/y3zav5/google-contractors-say-their-work-is-being-shipped-to-poland-after-unionizing">NLRB issued a formal complaint against Google contractor HCL</a>, alleging the company repeatedly violated the rights of unionized workers. Moving forward, Berland and Spiers are hoping the NLRB prosecutes the case against Google and seeks reinstatement and damages for them. But the next step is for the complaint to head to the desk of an administrative judge.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-nlrb-labor-complaint/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081843</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neuroglee gets $2.3 million to develop digital therapeutics for neurodegenerative diseases</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 01:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alzheimer's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital therapeutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eisai Co.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kuldeep Singh Rajput]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuroglee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081612</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are now about 50 million people with dementia globally, a number the World Health Organization expects to triple by 2050. Alzheimer’s is the leading cause of dementia and caregivers are often overwhelmed, without enough support. Neuroglee, a Singapore-based health tech startup, wants to help with a digital therapeutic platform created to treat patients in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are now about <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/dementia">50 million people with dementia globally</a>, a number the World Health Organization expects to triple by 2050. Alzheimer’s is the leading cause of dementia and caregivers are often overwhelmed, without enough support.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.neuroglee.com/">Neuroglee</a>, a Singapore-based health tech startup, wants to help with a digital therapeutic platform created to treat patients in the early stages of the disease. Founded this year to focus on neurodegenerative diseases, Neuroglee announced today it has raised $2.3 million in pre-seed funding.</p>
<p>The round was led by Eisai Co., one of Japan’s largest pharmaceutical companies, and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/kuldeep-singh-rajput" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="kuldeep-singh-rajput">Kuldeep Singh Rajput, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> the founder and chief executive officer of predictive healthcare startup Biofourmis.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="v72UnpZCK0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/softbank-vision-fund-2-leads-100-million-series-c-in-digital-therapeutics-company-biofourmis/">SoftBank Vision Fund 2 leads $100 million Series C in digital therapeutics company Biofourmis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank Vision Fund 2 leads $100 million Series C in digital therapeutics company Biofourmis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/softbank-vision-fund-2-leads-100-million-series-c-in-digital-therapeutics-company-biofourmis/embed/#?secret=v72UnpZCK0" data-secret="v72UnpZCK0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Neuroglee’s prescription digital therapy software for Alzheimer’s, called NG-001, is its main product. The company plans to start clinical trials next year. NG-001 is meant to complement medication and other treatments, and once it is prescribed by a clinician, patients can access its cognitive exercises and tasks through a tablet.</p>
<p>Neuroglee founder and CEO Aniket Singh Rajput (brother of Kuldeep) told TechCrunch that its first target markets for NG-001 are the United States and Singapore, followed by Japan. NG-001 needs to gain regulatory approval in each country, and it will start by seeking U.S. Food and Drug Administration clearance.</p>
<p>Once it launches, clinicians will have two ways to prescribe NG-001, through their healthcare provider platform or an electronic prescription tool. A platform called Neuroglee Connect will give clinicians, caregivers and patients access to support and features for reimbursement and coverage.</p>
<p>The software tracks patients’ progress, such as the speed of their fingers and the time it takes to complete an exercise, and delivers personalized treatment programs. It also has features to address the mental health of patients, including one that shows images that can bring up positive memories, which in turn can help alleviate depression and anxiety when used in tandem with other cognitive behavioral therapy techniques.</p>
<p>For caregivers and clinicians, NG-001 helps them track patient progress and their compliance with other treatments, like medications. This means that healthcare providers can work closely with patients even remotely, which is especially important during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="q52wGcJb9I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/11/as-alzheimers-costs-soar-startups-like-neurotrack-raise-cash-to-diagnose-and-treat-the-disease/">As Alzheimer&#8217;s costs soar, startups like Neurotrack raise cash to diagnose and treat the disease</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As Alzheimer&#8217;s costs soar, startups like Neurotrack raise cash to diagnose and treat the disease&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/11/as-alzheimers-costs-soar-startups-like-neurotrack-raise-cash-to-diagnose-and-treat-the-disease/embed/#?secret=q52wGcJb9I" data-secret="q52wGcJb9I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081612</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Govtech intelligence platform, The Atlas for Cities, bought by Government Executive Media Group</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/govtech-intelligence-platform-the-atlas-for-cities-bought-by-government-executive-media-group/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/govtech-intelligence-platform-the-atlas-for-cities-bought-by-government-executive-media-group/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atlas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san diego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Atlas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Atlas for Cities, the 500 Startups-backed market intelligence platform connecting tech companies with state and local governments, has been acquired by the Growth Catalyst Partners-backed publishing and market intelligence company Government Executive Media Group. The San Diego-based company will become the latest addition to a stable of publications and services that include the Route Fifty, publication [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://the-atlas.com/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://the-atlas.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1607028721887000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE_FPsTYrUC3MU6Ns3T0TJPi1fPRg">The Atlas for Cities</a>, the 500 Startups-backed market intelligence platform connecting tech companies with state and local governments, has been acquired by the Growth Catalyst Partners-backed publishing and market intelligence company <a href="https://www.govexec.com/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.govexec.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1607028721887000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFC6fvvq--NrcZeCsPL1jBF7APcCQ">Government Executive Media Group.</a></p>
<p>The San Diego-based company will become the latest addition to a stable of publications and services that include the <em>Route Fifty,</em> publication for local government and the defense-oriented intelligence service, DefenseOne.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/atlas-4d10" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="atlas-4d10">Atlas <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> provides peer-to-peer networks for state and local government officials to share best practices and is a marketing channel for the startups that want to sell services to those government employees. Through The Atlas, government officials can talk to each other, find case studies for best practices around tech implementations, and post questions to crowdsource ideas.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Government contractors can use the site to network with leadership and<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> receive buyer intent data to inform their strategy in the sector, all while getting intelligence about the problems and solutions that matter to state and local jurisdictions across the nation. </span></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“<a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/the-atlas-marketplace-co" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="the-atlas-marketplace-co">The Atlas <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> delivers on GEMG’s promise to look for companies that complement and supplement the full suite of offerings that we provide to our partners to reach decision makers across all facets of the public sector,” said Tim Hartman, CEO of Government Executive Media Group, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Led by Ellory Monks and Elle Hempen, The Atlas for Cities launched in 2019 and is backed by financing from individual investors and the 500 Startups accelerator program. It now counts 21,000 government officials across 3,400 cities on its platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;State and local governments in the United States spend $3.7 trillion per year. That&#8217;s almost 20% of GDP,&#8221; said Elle Hempen, co-founder of The Atlas. &#8220;Our mission to increase transparency and access for local leaders has the opportunity to transform this enormous, inefficient market and enable tangible progress on the most important issues of our times.&#8221;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/govtech-intelligence-platform-the-atlas-for-cities-bought-by-government-executive-media-group/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082209</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google shutting down Poly 3D content platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-shutting-down-poly-3d-content-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-shutting-down-poly-3d-content-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D modeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual effects]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google is almost running out of AR/VR projects to kill off. The company announced today in an email to Poly users that they will be shutting down the 3D-object creation and library platform &#8220;forever&#8221; next year. The service will shut down on June 30, 2021 and users won&#8217;t be able to upload 3D models to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/google" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="google">Google <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is almost running out of AR/VR projects to kill off.</p>
<p>The company announced today in an email to <a href="https://poly.google.com/">Poly</a> users that they will be shutting down the 3D-object creation and library platform &#8220;forever&#8221; next year. The service will shut down on June 30, 2021 and users won&#8217;t be able to upload 3D models to the site starting April 30, 2021.</p>
<p>Poly was introduced as a 3D creation tool optimized for virtual reality. Users could easily create low-poly objects with in-VR tools. The software was designed to serve as a lightweight way to create and view 3D assets that could in turn end up in games and experiences, compared to more art and sculpting-focused VR tools like Google&#8217;s Tilt Brush and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> (now Adobe&#8217;s) Medium software.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Google has already discontinued most of the company&#8217;s AR/VR plays, including most notably their Daydream mobile VR platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hpTAFjUkce"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/google-wakes-up-from-its-vr-daydream/">Google wakes up from its VR daydream</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google wakes up from its VR daydream&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/google-wakes-up-from-its-vr-daydream/embed/#?secret=hpTAFjUkce" data-secret="hpTAFjUkce" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The AR/VR industry&#8217;s initial rise prompted plenty of 3D-centric startups to bet big on creating or hosting a library of digital objects. As investor enthusiasm has largely faded and tech platforms hosting AR/VR content have shuttered those products, it&#8217;s less clear where the market is for this 3D content for the time being.</p>
<p>Users that have uploaded objects to Poly will be able to download their data and models ahead of the shutdown.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ySuSbznRDL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/01/google-launches-poly-a-home-for-the-worlds-3d-objects-built-for-creators/">Google launches Poly, a home for the world&#8217;s 3D objects built for creators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google launches Poly, a home for the world&#8217;s 3D objects built for creators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/01/google-launches-poly-a-home-for-the-worlds-3d-objects-built-for-creators/embed/#?secret=ySuSbznRDL" data-secret="ySuSbznRDL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-shutting-down-poly-3d-content-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082031</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hulu officially launches its co-viewing feature, Watch Party</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/hulu-officially-launches-its-co-viewing-feature-watch-party/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/hulu-officially-launches-its-co-viewing-feature-watch-party/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watch party]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hulu&#8217;s social viewing feature, Watch Party, has now launched to all on-demand subscribers, the company announced today. The co-viewing feature was first introduced during the earlier days of the pandemic in 2020, allowing Hulu users to watch shows together from different locations, as well as chat and react to what they&#8217;re watching in a group [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/hulu" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="hulu">Hulu&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> social viewing feature, Watch Party, has now launched to all on-demand subscribers, the company <a href="https://press.hulu.com/news/2020/12/02/hulu-watch-party-holiday-season/">announced</a> today. The co-viewing feature was first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/hulu-launches-a-new-watch-party-feature-for-virtual-viewing-parties-and-chat/">introduced</a> during the earlier days of the pandemic in 2020, allowing Hulu users to watch shows together from different locations, as well as chat and react to what they&#8217;re watching in a group chat interface on the side of the screen.</p>
<p>Initially, the feature was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/hulu-launches-a-new-watch-party-feature-for-virtual-viewing-parties-and-chat/">only made available to Hulu&#8217;s &#8220;No Ads&#8221; subscribers</a> before being tested with Hulu&#8217;s ad-supported subscribers in a more limited capacity. To celebrate the Season 2 premiere of Hulu Original &#8220;Pen15,&#8221; the company had offered the Watch Party experience to its ad-supported customers for 10 days, starting on September 18.</p>
<p>In November, Hulu began testing the Watch Party feature <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/hulu-tests-its-social-viewing-feature-watch-party-with-election-news-live-streams/">with election news live streams</a> &#8212; the first time it had offered co-viewing with its live content.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WfQz17EYb6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/hulu-tests-its-social-viewing-feature-watch-party-with-election-news-live-streams/">Hulu tests its social viewing feature, Watch Party, with election news live streams</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hulu tests its social viewing feature, Watch Party, with election news live streams&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/hulu-tests-its-social-viewing-feature-watch-party-with-election-news-live-streams/embed/#?secret=WfQz17EYb6" data-secret="WfQz17EYb6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Today, Hulu says Watch Party is no longer in a &#8220;test&#8221; phase, and is now officially available to both sets of on-demand customers, including those on its commercial-free and ad-supported plans alike.</p>
<p>At launch, Watch Party works across thousands of on-demand titles from Hulu&#8217;s library. This includes not only Hulu&#8217;s own original content but also other licensed and broadcast programs like &#8220;The Golden Girls,&#8221; &#8220;This Is Us,&#8221; &#8220;Family Guy&#8221; and &#8220;The Bachelorette&#8221; &#8212; all of which Hulu said had been popular titles for Watch Party during the testing period.</p>
<p>To use Watch Party, you&#8217;ll look for the new Watch Party icon that appears on a title&#8217;s detail page on Hulu.com. This will provide a link that you can then share with up to seven other Hulu subscribers, age 18 or older. The experience doesn&#8217;t require a browser plugin, but works directly on the Hulu website itself.</p>
<p>As the program plays, users can chat and react with emoji in the group chat window, or even pause the viewing experience if they need to take a quick break. This won&#8217;t pause the stream for other viewers, as with some other co-watching experiences &#8212; instead, the user can rejoin the group and stay behind others or they can use a &#8220;Click to Catch Up&#8221; button in the chat window to get back in sync.</p>
<p>Co-watching has been a popular pandemic activity as people looked for ways to stay connected with friends and family when they couldn&#8217;t spend time in person. In addition to Hulu, Amazon Prime Video <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/29/amazon-prime-video-introduces-watch-party-a-social-coviewing-experience-included-with-prime/">launched</a> co-viewing and <a href="https://variety.com/2020/digital/news/twitch-watch-parties-amazon-prime-video-titles-1234576194/">Twitch launched </a>its own Watch Parties. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/14/scener-now-lets-you-co-watch-hbo-or-netflix-in-a-virtual-theater-with-up-to-20-people/">HBO teamed up with Scener</a>, Plex <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/plex-launches-a-co-watching-experience-for-its-on-demand-library-and-users-personal-media/">launched</a> Watch Together and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/how-instagram-co-watching-works/">Instagram</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/facebook-introduces-a-co-viewing-experience-in-messenger-watch-together/">Facebook</a> rolled out co-viewing too. Netflix users still have to use third-party tools, however.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rl1CVHAola"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/how-instagram-co-watching-works/">Instagram launches Co-Watching of posts during video chat</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram launches Co-Watching of posts during video chat&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/how-instagram-co-watching-works/embed/#?secret=rl1CVHAola" data-secret="rl1CVHAola" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/hulu-officially-launches-its-co-viewing-feature-watch-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082197</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salesforce slumps 8.5% as its post-Slack selloff continues</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/salesforce-slumps-8-5-as-its-post-slack-selloff-continues/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/salesforce-slumps-8-5-as-its-post-slack-selloff-continues/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shares of Salesforce traded lower today, despite the company hosting a multi-hour keynote that included a buffet of Marc Benioff. What&#8217;s going on? Essentially, since the Salesforce-Slack deal reached the ears of the public, shares of the CRM giant have fallen, while shares of the enterprise social upstart have risen sharply. That Slack did well [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shares of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/salesforce" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="salesforce">Salesforce <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> traded lower today, despite the company hosting a multi-hour keynote that included a buffet of Marc Benioff.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s going on? Essentially, since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">the Salesforce-Slack deal</a> reached <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/slacks-stock-climbs-on-possible-salesforce-acquisition/">the ears of the public</a>, shares of the CRM giant have fallen, while shares of the enterprise social upstart have risen sharply.</p>
<p>That <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/slack" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="slack">Slack <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> did well since news of the deal broke is not a surprise. Salesforce is paying more for the company than it had been worth, the premium to its prior value constituting its argument that Slack&#8217;s investors should approve the deal. This is standard in corporate takeovers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AJ4OizvH0n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/embed/#?secret=AJ4OizvH0n" data-secret="AJ4OizvH0n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But what to make of Salesforce&#8217;s value declines? Let&#8217;s first calculate how much ground the company has lost on the stock market.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s happened to Salesforce&#8217;s stock from November 25th, when the deal initially leaked during the day, to today. We&#8217;re calculating the daily change between the preceding day&#8217;s close and the listed day&#8217;s final price:</p>
<ul>
<li>November 25: -5.4% (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/slacks-stock-climbs-on-possible-salesforce-acquisition/">deal leaks midday</a>)</li>
<li>November 27: +0.33%</li>
<li>November 30: -0.74%</li>
<li>December 1: -1.8% (deal is announced after-hours)</li>
<li>December 2: -8.52%</li>
</ul>
<p>Salesforce saw its share price fall from around $264 before the deal became known to $220.78 at the end of regular trading today. The loss in value works out to 16.5%. From a different perspective, Salesforce lost around $18.7 billion in value today alone.</p>
<p>Those swings constitute a summary rejection of the deal by investors, I&#8217;d say, or of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-beats-growth-expectations-as-investors-digest-the-slack-acquisition/">Salesforce&#8217;s recently stated guidance</a>, which was inclusive of the deal. Salesforce has lost more value than the transaction is worth, which feels notable.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u0bFG4f7A1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-beats-growth-expectations-as-investors-digest-the-slack-acquisition/">Salesforce beats growth expectations as investors digest the Slack acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce beats growth expectations as investors digest the Slack acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-beats-growth-expectations-as-investors-digest-the-slack-acquisition/embed/#?secret=u0bFG4f7A1" data-secret="u0bFG4f7A1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>My gut says that investors are worried that Salesforce is overpaying for Slack, and that potential synergies between the two won&#8217;t amount to as much as the two companies&#8217; CEOs imagine. But I wanted to ask my colleague Ron Miller about the situation, to see if he could add anything to the <em>why isn&#8217;t Wall Street liking this combo more</em> question. Here is his take:</p>
<p>While Wall Street appears to be taking an initial dislike to the deal &#8212; it is a big gaudy number &#8212; over time I think they should come to understand it better. Slack will give Salesforce the social piece it has been longing for since the days of Enterprise 2.0. They initially tried to build it themselves with Chatter, but that never quite caught on. Ten years later, they finally have their social component.</p>
<p>Benioff&#8217;s instincts about what his company needs are usually on target, and while he may have overpaid for this bauble, the ability to tie his company&#8217;s products together under Slack&#8217;s communications and work integration umbrella proved too attractive to resist.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget in spite of the fact that Microsoft Teams is making headway, mostly by giving it away for free with Office 365 subscriptions, Slack remains the darling of the developer class. And as long as Salesforce finds a way for it to maintain its independence, the marriage could work out. At the very least, it deserves a chance to prove that it can.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/salesforce-slumps-8-5-as-its-post-slack-selloff-continues/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082162</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Apple announces its best apps of 2020</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/daily-crunch-apple-announces-its-best-apps-of-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/daily-crunch-apple-announces-its-best-apps-of-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple releases its annual best apps list, a self-driving truck startup raises $350 million and the BioNTech/Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine gets emergency approval in the United Kingdom. This is your Daily Crunch for December 2, 2020. The big story: Apple announces its best apps of 2020 There were different winners — all selected by App Store [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/apple" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="apple">Apple <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> releases its annual best apps list, a self-driving truck startup raises $350 million and the BioNTech/Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine gets emergency approval in the United Kingdom. This is your Daily Crunch for December 2, 2020.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Apple announces its best apps of 2020</strong></p>
<p>There were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/apple-releases-its-best-of-2020-app-store-winners-and-most-downloaded-apps-of-the-year/">different winners</a> — all selected by App Store editors — for different devices. Home workout app Wakeout! was named the iPhone App of the Year, Disney+ was the Apple TV App of the Year and the productivity app Fantastical was the Mac App of the Year. As for the iPad App of the Year, it went to perhaps the most obvious choice: Zoom.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As far as user popularity goes, Apple said that Zoom was the biggest free iPhone app, followed by TikTok and Disney+ (which must qualify as free on a technicality), while the most popular free iPhone game was Among Us.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/loons-stratospheric-balloons-are-now-teaching-themselves-to-fly-better-thanks-to-google-ai/">Loon’s stratospheric balloons are now teaching themselves to fly better thanks to Google AI</a> — Alphabet’s Loon has been using algorithmic processes to optimize the flight of its stratospheric balloons for years, but the company is now deploying a new navigation system.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/apples-magsafe-duo-charger-is-now-available/">Apple’s MagSafe Duo charger is now available</a> — The MagSafe Duo appeared yesterday on Apple’s own store and has delivery estimates as soon as this week.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/google-news-showcase-paywalled-stories/">Google says its News Showcase will add free access to paywalled stories</a> — So far, Google News Showcase has launched in countries including Germany, Brazil, Argentina, Canada, France, U.K. and Australia.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/self-driving-trucks-startup-tusimple-raises-350m-from-u-s-rail-retail-and-freight-giants/">Self-driving trucks startup TuSimple raises $350M from US rail, retail and freight giants</a> — TuSimple was one of the first autonomous trucking startups to emerge in what has become a small-yet-bustling industry.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/virta-healths-behavioral-diabetes-treatment-service-is-now-worth-over-1-billion/">Virta Health’s behavioral diabetes treatment service is now worth over $1B</a> — Virta aims to reverse the presence of type 2 diabetes and other chronic metabolic conditions by changing a user&#8217;s diet and exercise.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/space-perspective-raises-7m-for-its-plan-to-ferry-tourists-to-the-edge-of-space/">Space Perspective raises $7M for its plan to ferry tourists to the edge of space</a> — Spaceship Neptune is designed to carry up to eight passengers on a six-hour journey that will include two hours spent at the upper edge of Earth’s atmosphere.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/from-surviving-to-thriving-as-a-hardware-startup/">From surviving to thriving as a hardware startup</a> — Six strategies from Minut CEO Nils Mattisson.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/a-roundup-of-recent-unicorn-news/">A roundup of recent unicorn news</a> — So much for a December news slowdown.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/the-uk-approves-the-biontech-pfizer-covid-19-vaccine-for-emergency-use/">The U.K. approves the BioNTech/Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine for emergency use</a> — The U.K. is the first country to approve the vaccine for widespread use.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/discovery-will-launch-its-own-streaming-service-on-january-4/">Discovery will launch its own streaming service on January 4</a> — Discovery is the latest media company to launch a standalone streaming service, and the latest to adopt the simple naming strategy of just adding a plus sign.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/">Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)</a> — Includes lots of good books for tech and business readers, plus my recommendation for the non-new, non-tech, yet extremely good novel &#8220;Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/daily-crunch-apple-announces-its-best-apps-of-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082205</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everyone has an opinion on the $27.7B Slack acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/everyone-has-an-opinion-on-the-27-7b-slack-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/everyone-has-an-opinion-on-the-27-7b-slack-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bret Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce-Slack deal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When the Salesforce-Slack deal was officially announced on Tuesday afternoon, and the number appeared, it was kind of hard to believe. Salesforce had shelled out more than $27 billion to buy Slack and bring it into the Salesforce family of products. The company sees a key missing piece in Slack, and that could explain why [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">Salesforce-Slack deal was officially announced</a> on Tuesday afternoon, and the number appeared, it was kind of hard to believe. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/salesforce" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="salesforce">Salesforce <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> had shelled out more than $27 billion to buy Slack and bring it into the Salesforce family of products. The company sees a key missing piece in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/slack" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="slack">Slack, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and that could explain why it was willing to spend such an astonishing amount of money to get it.</p>
<p>With Slack, Salesforce now has what CEO Marc Benioff called the interface to everything, something he says that the company has thought about for years. In 2010, they tried building it themselves with Chatter, a social tool that never really caught on in a big way. With Slack they finally have it.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve always had the vision of the social enterprise at Salesforce for more than a decade. Oh, we&#8217;ve had Dreamforces entirely dedicated to the vision of what a collaborative interface, a high production interface with applications and an ecosystem would look like wrapped on top of our Customer 360,&#8221; Benioff said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He added that ironically in a building right next door to Salesforce Park you&#8217;ll find Slack headquarters. They won&#8217;t have to go far to collaborate (or you know, they can just use Slack).</p>
<h2>From Chatter to Slack</h2>
<p>Neeraj Agrawal, general partner at Battery Ventures, says that Benioff has had an interest in enterprise social going back years, and this is his way of finally delivering. &#8220;Remember Chatter? Benioff was dead on with this trend. He <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/06/25/its-official-microsoft-confirms-it-has-acquired-yammer-for-1-2-billion-in-cash/">lost Yammer to Microsoft</a> (when Microsoft acquired it for $1.2 billion) about 7-8 years ago, and then launched Chatter. It was a huge bet, but didn’t work. Slack is really Chatter 2.0,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Chuck Ganapathi, CEO and co-founder at Tact.ai, was product lead on the Chatter product at Salesforce in the 2009 time frame. He wrote in a soon-to-be-published blog post he shared with TechCrunch that it failed for a lot of reasons, but mostly because at its core, Salesforce was still a bunch of database guys and enterprise social was a very different animal.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="G3E7rVS2Z3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/as-slack-acquisition-rumors-swirl-a-look-at-salesforces-six-biggest-deals/">As Slack acquisition rumors swirl, a look at Salesforce&#8217;s six biggest deals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As Slack acquisition rumors swirl, a look at Salesforce&#8217;s six biggest deals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/30/as-slack-acquisition-rumors-swirl-a-look-at-salesforces-six-biggest-deals/embed/#?secret=G3E7rVS2Z3" data-secret="G3E7rVS2Z3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Some of the issues were technical &#8212; Salesforce is a database-centric company, founded by Oracle alums on a relational DB foundation. DB applications and unstructured communication applications like Chatter or Slack represent completely different branches of computer science with little overlap,&#8221; he wrote. Because of that, he felt that they lacked the expertise to build the application correctly, and it never really caught on, with so many similar products in the market at the time.</p>
<p>But Benioff never lost interest in the concept of incorporating social into the Salesforce platform. It just took another 10 years or so and a bushel of money to make it happen.</p>
<h2>A good match or not?</h2>
<p>Leyla Seka, a partner at Operator Capital, who formerly ran the AppExchange at Salesforce, sees good things ahead with a combined Slack and Salesforce. &#8220;Salesforce and Slack together will offer a powerful duo of applications that will help companies work more effectively together. I think that COVID-19 has shown us how critical it is to get employees the data they need to do their job, but also the community they need to thrive at their job. The marriage of Salesforce and Slack promises to do just that,&#8221; Seka told me.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Be8IVr1LHF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/with-hyperforce-salesforce-lets-you-move-your-data-to-any-public-cloud/">With Hyperforce, Salesforce lets you move your data to any public cloud</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With Hyperforce, Salesforce lets you move your data to any public cloud&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/with-hyperforce-salesforce-lets-you-move-your-data-to-any-public-cloud/embed/#?secret=Be8IVr1LHF" data-secret="Be8IVr1LHF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Brent Leary, principal analyst at CRM Essentials, was knocked out by the price tag, but says it shows that Salesforce is not afraid to go after what it wants, even if it has to pay a hefty price to get it. &#8220;This goes to show Salesforce has absolutely no fear in them when it comes to this deal. They are willing to throw down the big bucks on this acquisition because they see a huge payoff by adding this piece into their platform,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>As for Slack, he sees it as a way for them to take the fast track to the enterprise big leagues. &#8220;And for Slack they go from competing with AMOSS (Adobe, Microsoft, Oracle, SAP, Salesforce) to joining one of them, and the company that really made the most sense for them to team up with,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Laurie McCabe, an analyst and founder at SMB Group, agrees with Leary&#8217;s take, saying Salesforce doesn&#8217;t hesitate when it thinks the value is there. &#8220;In this case, Slack gives them a strong collaboration offering that will help them compete more effectively against Microsoft’s growing cloud portfolio, which of course includes CRM and Teams,&#8221; she said.</p>
<h2>Show me the money</h2>
<p>Battery&#8217;s Agrawal believes this deal is all about generating revenue, and it was willing to pay a premium to move the needle in billion-dollar chunks. The end game he believes is about catching Microsoft, or at the very least getting to $1 trillion (with a T, folks) in market cap.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that investors are not showing signs, initially at least, of liking this deal, with the stock down over 8% today and 16.5% since the rumor of Salesforce&#8217;s interest in Slack surfaced last week before the Thanksgiving holiday. That translates into more than $18 billion in lost market cap &#8212; probably not the reaction they were hoping for. But Salesforce is big enough that it can afford to play a long game, and reach its financial goals with the help of Slack.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9gpWOekdIV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/slacks-stock-climbs-on-possible-salesforce-acquisition/">Slack’s stock climbs on possible Salesforce acquisition</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Slack’s stock climbs on possible Salesforce acquisition&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/slacks-stock-climbs-on-possible-salesforce-acquisition/embed/#?secret=9gpWOekdIV" data-secret="9gpWOekdIV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;To get to a market cap of $1 trillion, Salesforce now has to take MSFT head on. Until now, the company has mostly been able to stay in its own swim lane in terms of products. [&#8230;] To get to a trillion dollars in market cap, Salesforce needs to try to grow in two massive markets,&#8221; Agrawal said. Those would be either knowledge worker/desktop (see <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/01/salesforce-buys-word-processing-app-quip-for-750m/">the 2016 Quip acquisition</a>) or cloud (see <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/with-hyperforce-salesforce-lets-you-move-your-data-to-any-public-cloud/">the Hyperforce announcement</a>). Agrawal says chances are the company&#8217;s best bet is the former, and it was willing to pay top dollar to get it.</p>
<p>&#8220;The deal will help Salesforce maintain a 20%+ growth rate over the next few years,&#8221; he said. Ultimately, he sees it moving the revenue needle, which should eventually drive market cap higher and help achieve those goals.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that Salesforce president and CEO <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/person/bret-taylor" target="_blank" data-type="person" data-entity="bret-taylor">Bret Taylor <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said while they intend to integrate Slack deeply into the Salesforce product family, they recognize the power and utility of Slack as a standalone product and they don&#8217;t intend to do anything that would mess with that.</p>
<p>&#8220;Fundamentally, we want to make sure that Slack remains as a kind of technology-agnostic platform. We know that Slack is used by millions and millions of people every day to connect every tool under the sun. The most remarkable thing is just how many customers have also just integrated their own custom internal tools as well into this is really kind of the central nervous system for the teams that use it, and we would never want to change that,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to judge a deal this large until we have some hindsight and see how well the two companies have meshed, how well they can incorporate Slack into the Salesforce ecosystem, while allowing that independence Taylor alluded to. If they can find a way to walk that line and Slack becomes that wrapper, that operating system, that glue that holds the Salesforce ecosystem together, it will be a good deal, but if Slack stops innovating and withers under the weight of its corporate overlords, then it might not be money well spent.</p>
<p>Time will tell which is the case.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iK7LtPqecI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/">Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Salesforce buys Slack in a $27.7B megadeal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/salesforce-buys-slack/embed/#?secret=iK7LtPqecI" data-secret="iK7LtPqecI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/everyone-has-an-opinion-on-the-27-7b-slack-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082156</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sketchy wants to replace boring textbooks with ‘Pixar-like’ videos</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/sketchy-medical-series-a-tcg-reach-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/sketchy-medical-series-a-tcg-reach-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reach Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Chernin Group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2081901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Studying for med school is tough. What if it was more Pixar-like? Sketchy, a visual learning platform, takes complex material that a med student might need to memorize for an exam, and puts the information in an illustrated scene. For example, it uses a countryside kingdom to explain the coronavirus, or a salmon dinner to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Studying for med school is tough. What if it was more Pixar-like?</p>
<p><a href="https://sketchy.com/">Sketchy</a>, a visual learning platform, takes complex material that a med student might need to memorize for an exam, and puts the information in an illustrated scene. For example, it uses a countryside kingdom to explain the coronavirus, or a salmon dinner to explain Salmonella. The goal is for a student to be able to mentally go back to the scene while taking an exam, walk through it and retrieve all of the information.</p>
<p>While Sketchy’s strategy might seem odd, it’s actually well-known. The &#8220;memory palace&#8221; technique matches objects to concepts for easier memorization. So far, Sketchy has more than 30,000 paid subscribers and is on track to hit $7 million in revenue this year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>To charge this growth and break into new content verticals, Sketchy is taking venture capital on for the first time in its seven-year history. Last month, the <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20200924005067/en/Leading-Online-Education-Startup-SketchyMedical-Secures-30-Million-Investment-From-TCG">team announced</a> that it has raised a $30 million Series A led by <a href="https://tcg.co/">The Chernin Group</a> (TCG). Today, some of those shares were sold in a secondary transaction <a href="https://www.reachcapital.com/">Reach Capital,</a> which now accounts for $3 million of the financing.  It’s a big combined investment for a company that has been bootstrapping since birth &#8212; and the deal could help us see where online education is heading.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NIkRbOwkV4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/edtech-investors-are-panning-for-gold/">Edtech investors are panning for gold</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Edtech investors are panning for gold&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/edtech-investors-are-panning-for-gold/embed/#?secret=NIkRbOwkV4" data-secret="NIkRbOwkV4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The capital comes as Sketchy itself looks to grow past a content service for med students, and into an education platform tackling information in critical fields, from legal to nursing. With the new money, Sketchy plans to build an in-house animation studio and hire more artists and doctors, some of whom are currently consultants.</p>
<h2><strong>The story</strong></h2>
<p>A big part of Sketchy’s magic, and effectiveness, comes from the fact that all of its founding team have experience in medicine.</p>
<p>The company began in 2013 when then-med students Saud Siddiqui and Andrew Berg were in desperate need of a better study solution for microbiology. To liven up their studying, Berg and Siddiqui began weaving characters into stories to try to memorize concepts &#8212; and after a few good test scores, they started creating stories for their classmates.</p>
<p>“Neither Saud or I were artists, so they were pretty bad,” Berg said. As demand continued, the duo put their scraggly sketches on YouTube. Eventually, Siddiqui and Berg roped in classmate Bryan Lemieux, a good artist, to tell the stories with them. Eventually Bryan brought on his twin brother, Aaron, and the founding team was born.</p>
<p>Fast-forward to today: Siddiqui and Berg have finished their residencies in emergency medicine, while the Lemieux brothers chose to leave medicine. All have moved full-time to the company after trying to balance both jobs. Still, the knowledge from working in the field continues to be useful.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s name has evolved: born as SketchyMedical, it has since rebranded to just Sketchy. While the team chose the name to nod toward its focus on art, the name also has negative connotations. Expect a rebrand in the future.</p>
<p>Despite this, the company claims that it is used by a third of med students in the United States. The majority of its revenues come from 12-month subscriptions for students looking to prep for med school exams like Step 1, and Step 2.</p>
<p>While B2C is a promising business model for many reasons (it’s always easier to convince a human to pay instead of a entire, red-tape-bound institution), the company has also posted promising B2B growth. So far, 20% of its revenue comes from direct contracts it has with medical schools. The founders said that they will pursue both growth methods for now, but based on the price of med school (and student debt crisis), it would be great to see them grow through school contracts so students don&#8217;t have to face the brunt of costs.</p>
<h2><strong>Beyond the coronavirus </strong></h2>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/reach-capital" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="reach-capital">Reach Capital’s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Jennifer Carolan, an investor in Sketchy, said that Sketchy’s product market fit with med students is a “strong signal that their content is worth it.” Even with competitors such as Picorize and Medcomic, she’s confident that Sketchy’s product is defensible and can expand into new verticals. Part of the reason the firm approached Sketchy to invest in them is because of low customer acquisition costs, <a href="https://reachcapital.medium.com/sketchy-5b57affb5ad4">Carolan notes in a blog post. </a></p>
<p>That said, unlike most edtech companies, which have enjoyed surging new user demand thanks to remote learning, Sketchy didn’t have a huge COVID-19 boom.</p>
<p>“We weren&#8217;t one of those people that hadn&#8217;t found product market fit and then exploded after COVID,” said Berg. “We’ve always been there and been growing.”</p>
<p>So the real trigger for today’s fundraise wasn’t COVID-19 momentum, but instead, a push to capitalize its sustained growth into more digital curriculum verticals.</p>
<p>Long-term, think of Sketchy as joining a chorus of startups, including Top Hat Jr and Newsela, that want to replace textbook publishers. In a remote world, live, moving content is more rapidly losing value, and upstarts are trying to replace them with more effective and engaging content.</p>
<p>“One of the challenges is just to make sure we don&#8217;t go too fast,” Siddiqui said. “We want to keep that degree of quality we’ve maintained for so many years, and do it at scale.”</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s note: The original version of this story stated that Sketchy had raised $32 million. This is incorrect. The company raised $30 million along with a secondary transaction from Reach Capital. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cj6RkYOzGa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/equity-dive-edtechs-2020-wakeup-call/">Equity Dive: Edtech’s 2020 wakeup call</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Equity Dive: Edtech’s 2020 wakeup call&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/26/equity-dive-edtechs-2020-wakeup-call/embed/#?secret=cj6RkYOzGa" data-secret="cj6RkYOzGa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/sketchy-medical-series-a-tcg-reach-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2081901</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon&#8217;s Fire TV Cube adds support for two-way video calls via a connected TV</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/amazons-fire-tv-cube-adds-support-for-two-way-video-calls-via-a-connected-tv/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/amazons-fire-tv-cube-adds-support-for-two-way-video-calls-via-a-connected-tv/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fire TV Cube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon in September announced it was bringing video calling support to its Fire TV platform. Today, the company says two-way video calling is now available with its Fire TV Cube devices (2nd gen.). The new feature will allow customers to pair a third-party webcam with their Fire TV Cube in order to make and receive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amazon" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="amazon">Amazon <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> in September <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/amazon-redesigns-fire-tv-introduces-new-fire-tv-stick-and-low-cost-fire-tv-stick-lite/">announced</a> it was bringing video calling support to its Fire TV platform. Today, the company says <a href="https://amazonfiretv.blog/two-way-video-calling-with-fire-tv-cube-649648f92562">two-way video calling is now available</a> with its Fire TV Cube devices (2nd gen.). The new feature will allow customers to pair a third-party webcam with their Fire TV Cube in order to make and receive video calls from their TVs to any other Alexa device with a screen.</p>
<p>That means customers could call other Alexa owners who have a Fire TV Cube of their own, an Echo device with a screen like the Echo Show or even just the Alexa app installed on a smartphone or tablet.</p>
<p>For the feature to work, Amazon says the third-party video cams will need to meet certain minimum requirements, including UVC support, 720p resolution and 30 frames per sec (fps). Amazon, however, recommends that a better experience will be had with cameras with 1080p resolution and 60-90 degree field of view (FOV). It advises against 4K webcams.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company also says a better experience will be had with a field of view from six to 10 feet away from the TV, but not greater than 12 feet.</p>
<p>The webcams themselves are connected to the Fire TV Cube via a Micro USB to USB adapter.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dZEqNQWoEN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/amazon-redesigns-fire-tv-introduces-new-fire-tv-stick-and-low-cost-fire-tv-stick-lite/">Amazon redesigns Fire TV, introduces new Fire TV Stick and low-cost Fire TV Stick Lite</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon redesigns Fire TV, introduces new Fire TV Stick and low-cost Fire TV Stick Lite&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/amazon-redesigns-fire-tv-introduces-new-fire-tv-stick-and-low-cost-fire-tv-stick-lite/embed/#?secret=dZEqNQWoEN" data-secret="dZEqNQWoEN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Amazon recommends the <a class="cm jj" href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Widescreen-Calling-Recording-Desktop/dp/B006JH8T3S/ref_=FTV_Blog_videocalling" rel="noopener">Logitech C920</a>, <a class="cm jj" href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-C922x-Pro-Stream-Webcam/dp/B01LXCDPPK?ref_=FTV_Blog_videocalling" rel="noopener">Logitech C922x</a>, <a class="cm jj" href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-960-000637-HD-Webcam-C310/dp/B003PAIV2Q/ref_=FTV_Blog_videocalling" rel="noopener">Logitech C310</a>, <a class="cm jj" href="https://www.amazon.com/AUKEY-Streaming-Microphone-Widescreen-Recording/dp/B072MMH33F/ref_=FTV_Blog_videocalling" rel="noopener">Aukey PC-LM1E</a> or <a class="cm jj" href="https://www.amazon.com/Microphone-Wansview-Correction-Streaming-Conference/dp/B088D3VXC6/ref_=FTV_Blog_videocalling" rel="noopener">Wansview 101JD </a>webcams for those interested in trying the new feature.</p>
<p>Once connected, users will need to open the Alexa app on their phone to enable the messaging and calling options, if they had not already, and import their contacts.</p>
<p>To place a call, Alexa owners can say things like &#8220;Alexa, call Julie&#8217;s Echo,&#8221; for example. They can then control the call experience with voice commands like &#8220;Alexa, video on,&#8221; &#8220;Alexa, volume up,&#8221; &#8220;Alexa, answer&#8221; and &#8220;Alexa, end call,&#8221; among others.</p>
<p>Video chat support has been one of the key features for smart screens, like Amazon&#8217;s Echo Show, but it makes sense to bring support for video calls to the living room&#8217;s big screen, too, where possible. But unlike competitors in this space, Amazon doesn&#8217;t have an ecosystem of communication apps to leverage here, the way that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/google-finally-brings-group-calling-to-the-nest-hub-max/">Google Nest Hub Max</a> has with Google Meet and Duo, or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/10/facebooks-video-calling-portal-devices-add-whatsapp-login-new-features-and-content/">how Facebook Portal</a> can reach family and friends on Facebook and WhatsApp. That could potentially limit adoption for the feature, as it requires the other user is plugged into the Amazon ecosystem as well.</p>
<p>Amazon says the new Fire TV Cube feature enabling support for the two-way video calls will begin to roll out today.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KFCdcakTZ9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/google-finally-brings-group-calling-to-the-nest-hub-max/">Google finally brings group calling to the Nest Hub Max</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google finally brings group calling to the Nest Hub Max&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/google-finally-brings-group-calling-to-the-nest-hub-max/embed/#?secret=KFCdcakTZ9" data-secret="KFCdcakTZ9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/amazons-fire-tv-cube-adds-support-for-two-way-video-calls-via-a-connected-tv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082150</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump&#8217;s odd new attack on Section 230 is probably doomed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/trump-section-230-ndaa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/trump-section-230-ndaa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 22:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Section 230]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump administration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trump&#8217;s crusade against a key internet law known as Section 230 tends to pop up in unlikely places. His Twitter feed on Thanksgiving, for one. Or at times you&#8217;d think the nation would be hearing from its leader on the matter at hand: a worsening pandemic that&#8217;s killed nearly 270,000 people in the United States. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Trump&#8217;s crusade against a key internet law known as Section 230 tends to pop up in unlikely places. His Twitter feed <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1332175155104247808">on Thanksgiving</a>, for one. Or at times you&#8217;d think the nation would be hearing from its leader on the matter at hand: a worsening pandemic that&#8217;s killed nearly 270,000 people in the United States.</p>
<p>His latest threat to the law, which is widely regarded as the foundation for the modern internet, is unlikelier still. Now, Trump wants to veto the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA), a bill that allocates military funds each year, if it doesn&#8217;t somehow &#8220;terminate&#8221; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/23/the-consequences-of-indecency/">Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">&#8230;..Therefore, if the very dangerous &amp; unfair Section 230 is not completely terminated as part of the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA), I will be forced to unequivocally VETO the Bill when sent to the very beautiful Resolute desk. Take back America NOW. Thank you!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1333965375839621120?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In a tweet, Trump mysteriously called the law a &#8220;serious threat to our National Security &amp; Election Integrity&#8221; and claimed that only big tech companies benefit from it, which is not true. Big tech&#8217;s lobbying group made the opposite argument in response to the president&#8217;s new threat.</p>
<p>&#8220;Repealing Section 230 is itself a threat to national security,&#8221; Internet Association Interim President and CEO Jon Berroya said in a statement. &#8220;The law empowers online platforms to remove harmful and dangerous content, including terrorist content and misinformation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 230, which protects internet companies from liability for the content they host, is currently at the center of a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/section-230-hearing-big-tech/">complex bipartisan reform effort</a> — one that&#8217;s nowhere near a consensus, much less an agreement that Section 230 should be scrapped outright.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ymyKTfWGVA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/section-230-hearing-big-tech/">Section 230 will be on the chopping block at the next big tech hearing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Section 230 will be on the chopping block at the next big tech hearing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/section-230-hearing-big-tech/embed/#?secret=ymyKTfWGVA" data-secret="ymyKTfWGVA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>President Trump&#8217;s threat to block the NDAA stakes out a deeply unpopular position. The sweeping defense budget bill includes all kinds of funding for popular programs that benefit U.S. troops and veterans, making a veto of the bill if the terms of a totally unrelated demand aren&#8217;t met a strange gamble indeed. The fact that Trump&#8217;s latest anti-230 tactic comes during a lame duck session gives his threat even less bite.</p>
<p>In light of that, most of Congress has gone about business as usual so far. But close Trump ally Sen. Josh Hawley (R-MO) did signal his support for Trump&#8217;s position on Wednesday. &#8220;The NDAA does NOT contain any reform to Section 230 but DOES contain Elizabeth Warren’s social engineering amendment to unilaterally rename bases &amp; war memorials w/ no public input or process,&#8221; <a href="https://twitter.com/HawleyMO/status/1334205058494377986">Hawley tweeted</a>. &#8220;I cannot support it.&#8221;</p>
<p>If history is any lesson, Trump isn&#8217;t afraid to make an empty threat, eventually pivoting to something else that catches his attention. But Section 230 — previously a fairly arcane piece of legislation that attracted little mainstream attention — has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/trump-twitter-executive-order-social-media/">rankled Trump</a> for the better part of the year, even inspiring an executive order back in May.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fv9SnLFVx7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/trump-twitter-executive-order-social-media/">Going to war with Twitter, Trump threatens critical social media legal protections</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Going to war with Twitter, Trump threatens critical social media legal protections&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/28/trump-twitter-executive-order-social-media/embed/#?secret=fv9SnLFVx7" data-secret="fv9SnLFVx7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That executive order gets at the real reason behind Trump&#8217;s ire: He believes that social media companies, Twitter in particular, have unfairly censored him. While Twitter has continued to allow Trump to remain on its platform even as he flaunts the rules, the company now limits the reach of his most dangerous or misleading tweets — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/trump-tweet-steal-election-vote-by-mail/">false claims</a> about the election results, for example — and pairs them with warning labels.</p>
<p>Paradoxically, if Trump got his way, an outright repeal of Section 230 would open online platforms to an insurmountable level of legal liability, either sinking social media companies outright or forcing them to severely restrict their users&#8217; speech.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s possible that the president could dig his heels in, pushing the defense spending bill into President-elect Biden&#8217;s term. But it&#8217;s more likely that Trump will back off of his unusual demand, which so far has yet to attract much support <a href="https://twitter.com/nanditab1/status/1334220269788000257">or even acknowledgement</a> from his own party. At the moment, Congress is preoccupied with work on a second pandemic stimulus bill that would offer more financial support to the country.</p>
<p>Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR), who co-authored Section 230, remains unworried that a repeal could get stuffed into the multi-hundred-billion-dollar defense bill in the eleventh hour.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;d like to start for the Blazers, but it’s not going to happen either,&#8221; Wyden told TechCrunch. &#8220;It is pathetic that Trump refuses to help unemployed workers, while he spends his time tweeting unhinged election conspiracies and demanding Congress repeal the foundation of free speech online.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KHISy7OxjF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/with-absurd-timing-fcc-announces-intention-to-revisit-section-230/">With &#8216;absurd&#8217; timing, FCC announces intention to revisit Section 230</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With &#8216;absurd&#8217; timing, FCC announces intention to revisit Section 230&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/with-absurd-timing-fcc-announces-intention-to-revisit-section-230/embed/#?secret=KHISy7OxjF" data-secret="KHISy7OxjF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/trump-section-230-ndaa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082117</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter now supports hardware security keys for iPhones and Android</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/twitter-now-supports-hardware-security-keys-for-iphones-and-android/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/twitter-now-supports-hardware-security-keys-for-iphones-and-android/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 20:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Access Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief information security officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Identification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multi-factor authentication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yubikey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter said Wednesday that accounts protected with a hardware security key can now log in from their iPhone or Android device. The social media giant rolled out support for hardware security keys in 2018, allowing users to add a physical security barrier to their accounts in place of other two-factor authentication options, like a text [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/twitter" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="twitter">Twitter <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said Wednesday that accounts protected with a hardware security key can now log in from their iPhone or Android device.</p>
<p>The social media giant rolled out support for hardware security keys in 2018, allowing users to add a physical security barrier to their accounts in place of other two-factor authentication options, like a text message or a code generated from an app.</p>
<p>Security keys are small enough to fit on a keyring but make certain kinds of account hacks near impossible by requiring a user to plug in the key when they log in. That means hackers on the other side of the planet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/google-data-two-factor-security/">can&#8217;t easily break into your account</a>, even if they have your username and password.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>But <a href="https://twitter.com/jcmi/status/1197649884645511168?s=20">technical limitations</a> meant that accounts protected with security keys could only log in from a computer, and not a mobile device.</p>
<p>Twitter solved that headache in part by <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/engineering/en_us/topics/infrastructure/2019/webauthn.html">switching to the WebAuthn protocol</a> last year, which paved the way for bringing hardware security key support to more devices and browsers.</p>
<p>Now anyone with a security key set up on their Twitter account can use that same key to log in from their mobile device, so long as the key is supported. (A ton of security keys exist today that work across different devices, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/yubico-reveals-new-yubikey/">YubiKeys</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/05/google-opentitan-secure-chip/">Google&#8217;s Titan key</a>.)</p>
<p>Twitter — and other companies — have long recommended that high-profile accounts, like journalists, politicians and government officials, use security keys to prevent some of the more sophisticated attacks. Twitter explains how to set up two-factor authentication (and security keys) <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/managing-your-account/two-factor-authentication">here</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Twitter rolled out hardware security keys to its own staff to prevent a repeat of its July cyberattack that saw hackers break into the company&#8217;s internal network and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/twitter-hacker-admin-scam/">abuse an &#8220;admin&#8221; tool</a>, which the hackers then used to hijack high-profile accounts to spread a cryptocurrency scam.</p>
<p>In the wake of the attack, Twitter hired <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/twitter-ciso-rinki-sethi/">Rinki Sethi</a> as its new chief information security officer, and famed hacker Peiter Zatko, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/decrypted-apple-facebook-privacy-mudge-zero-day/">known as Mudge</a>, as the company&#8217;s head of security.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e0BfzCWXsr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/decrypted-apple-facebook-privacy-mudge-zero-day/">Decrypted: Apple and Facebook&#8217;s privacy feud, Twitter hires Mudge, mysterious zero-days</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Decrypted: Apple and Facebook&#8217;s privacy feud, Twitter hires Mudge, mysterious zero-days&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/decrypted-apple-facebook-privacy-mudge-zero-day/embed/#?secret=e0BfzCWXsr" data-secret="e0BfzCWXsr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/twitter-now-supports-hardware-security-keys-for-iphones-and-android/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082092</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helping big banks out-Affirm Affirm and out-Chime Chime gives Amount a $681 million valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/helping-big-banks-out-affirm-affirm-and-out-chime-chime-gives-amount-a-681-million-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/helping-big-banks-out-affirm-affirm-and-out-chime-chime-gives-amount-a-681-million-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 20:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amount]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capitalone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hanaco Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hsbc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QED]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amount, a new service that helps traditional banks compete in a digital world, has raised $81 million from none other than Goldman Sachs as it looks to help legacy fintech players compete with their more nimble digital counterparts. The company, which spun out from the startup lending company Avant in January of this year, has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.amount.com/">Amount</a>, a new service that helps traditional banks compete in a digital world, has raised $81 million from none other than Goldman Sachs as it looks to help legacy fintech players compete with their more nimble digital counterparts.</p>
<p>The company, which spun out from the startup lending company Avant in January of this year, has already inked deals with <span style="font-weight: 400;">Banco P</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">opular,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> HSBC, Regions Bank</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">TD Bank to power their digital banking services and offer products like point-of-sale lending to compete with challenger banks like Chime and lenders like Affirm or Klarna.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most banks are looking for resources and infrastructure to accelerate their digital strategy and meet the demands of today’s consumer,” said Jade Mandel, a vice president in Goldman Sachs&#8217; growth equity platform, GS Growth, who will be joining the board of directors at Amount, in a statement. “Amount enables banks to navigate digital transformation through its modular and mobile-first platform for financial products. We’re excited to partner with the team as they take on this compelling market opportunity.&#8221;</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Complementing those customer-facing services is a deep expertise in fraud prevention on the back-end to help banks provide more loans with less risk than competitors, according to chief executive Adam Hughes.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the combination of these three services that led Goldman to take point on a new $81 million investment in the company, with participation from previous investors <span style="font-weight: 400;">August Capital, Invus Opportunities and Hanaco Ventures</span> &#8212; giving Amount a post-money valuation of $681 million and bringing the company&#8217;s total capital raised in 2020 to a whopping $140 million.</p>
<p>Think of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/amount" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="amount">Amount <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> as a white-labeled digital banking service provider for Luddite banks that hadn&#8217;t upgraded their services to keep pace with demands of a new generation of customers or the COVID-19 era of digital-first services for everything.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/bank-3cdc" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="bank-3cdc">Banks <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> pay a pretty penny for access to Amount&#8217;s services. On top of a percentage for any loans that a bank processes through Amount&#8217;s services, there&#8217;s an up-front implementation fee that typically averages at $1 million.</p>
<p>The hefty price tag is a sign of how concerned banks are about their digital challengers. Hughes said that they&#8217;ve seen a big uptick in adoption since the launch of their buy-now-pay-later product designed to compete with the fast growing startups like <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/affirm" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="affirm">Affirm <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/klarna" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="klarna">Klarna <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>.</p>
<p>Indeed, by offering banks these services, Amount gives Klarna and Affirm something to worry about. That&#8217;s because banks conceivably have a lower cost of capital than the startups and can offer better rates to borrowers. They also have the balance sheet capacity to approve more loans than either of the two upstart lenders.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “Amount has the wind at its back and the industry is taking notice,” said Nigel Morris, the co-founder of Capital One and an investor in Amount through the firm QED Investors. “The latest round brings Amount’s total capital raised in 2020 to nearly $140 million, which will provide for additional investments in platform research and development while accelerating the company’s go-to-market strategy. QED is thrilled to be a part of Amount’s story and we look forward to the company’s future success as it plays a vital role in the digitization of financial services.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FT Partners served as advisor to Amount on this transaction.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/helping-big-banks-out-affirm-affirm-and-out-chime-chime-gives-amount-a-681-million-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082109</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 20:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2020]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2078170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2020 was a tough year for all of us, but a strong one for books (how often do you get to say that?). Sales are up, driven by lockdowns, boredom, and the need for escape. Yet, 2020 also felt like a watershed year for media in general, a time when we started to deeply question the value of real-time communications driven by fear. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome to TechCrunch&#8217;s 2020 Holiday Gift Guide! Need help with gift ideas? We&#8217;re here to help! We&#8217;ll be rolling out gift guides from now through the end of December. </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><em>You can find our other guides right here. </em></a><em>This is Part 1 of the Best Books gift guide. Part 2 with even more selections will be posted shortly.</em></p>
<p>2020 was a tough year for all of us, but a strong one for books (how often do you get to say that?). Sales are up, driven by lockdowns, boredom and the need for escape. Yet, 2020 also felt like a watershed year for media in general, a time when we started to deeply question the value of real-time communications driven by fear.</p>
<p>Books are no guaranteed antidote to the daily grind of the information economy, but they do provide room for readers and authors to breathe, to take stock of where we are and where we are going. Not in the moment, but of the moment. Whether that means escaping into the lives of fictional characters on another planet, or understanding the lives of others on our very own, books provide the material that can help us rethink all that’s going on and what happens next.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>So I’m delighted to share nine book recommendations from my fellow TechCrunch writers as well as a few VCs on what to read in 2020. Some books are a few weeks old, others a few years, but they all made an impact on the lives of their reviewers this year as we confronted one of the most challenging times in recent memory.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</i></p>
<h2 id="Dark Mirror: Edward Snowden and the Surveillance State by Barton Gellman">Dark Mirror: Edward Snowden and the Surveillance State by Barton Gellman</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/316047/dark-mirror-by-barton-gellman/">Penguin Random House</a>, 2020, 448 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Zack Whittaker, Cybersecurity Editor at TechCrunch</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078171" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?w=447" alt="" width="447" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg 1684w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?resize=197,300 197w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?resize=768,1168 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?resize=447,680 447w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?resize=1010,1536 1010w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?resize=1347,2048 1347w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Dark-Mirror.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 447px) 100vw, 447px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Dark Mirror&#8221; tells the story of how its author, Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist Barton Gellman, became embroiled in reporting one of the biggest leaks of highly classified documents in a generation, thanks to former NSA contractor turned whistleblower Edward Snowden.</p>
<p>Gellman was one of only a handful of people given a copy of the cache of “top secret” documents swiped by Snowden in 2013. The documents revealed the enormous scale of the U.S. government’s surveillance capabilities — and those of its allies. The book is written largely in first-person, and it shines a brand new light on the Snowden disclosures and published stories that followed, the mistakes that were made, as well as new revelations that were never previously told.</p>
<p>You learn more about Snowden, his character and temperament, how he collected thousands of classified documents from right under the NSA’s nose, how he came to “meet” Gellman for the first time, and what motives led the whistleblower to go public.</p>
<p>You also follow how Gellman sourced, vetted and fact-checked some of the most significant findings from the documents — with help from researchers Ashkan Soltani and Julie Tate — from revealing the PRISM slides, to the jaw-dropping moment that Gellman recounted telling a Google engineer how the NSA was secretly siphoning off data from its private data center links. Gellman spares no detail of his years-long journey in covering the documents, and isn’t one to shy away from revealing his own struggles — not least trying to protect the cache from spies both at home and abroad, and fearing that he too could become a target.</p>
<p>Gellman brings a fresh perspective and hindsight on the narrative you might have followed in the aftermath of the scandal, and fills in the blanks during a period of time that had the world in turmoil. And yet seven years after the first of many stories broke, &#8220;Dark Mirror&#8221; continues to spill in every chapter details never known before. His storytelling is exquisite, even if you’ll never want to use the internet again after reading it.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$20 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1594206015/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1594206015&amp;linkId=392ab0ef81517ff837cd112246e801b3">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="The Color of Money: Black Banks and the Racial Wealth Gap by Mehrsa Baradaran">The Color of Money: Black Banks and the Racial Wealth Gap by Mehrsa Baradaran</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674237476">Belknap Press</a> (Harvard University Press), 2017, 384 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Liz Sisson, Chief Operating Officer of Urban Us</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078173" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Color-of-Money.jpg?w=454" alt="" width="454" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Color-of-Money.jpg 907w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Color-of-Money.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Color-of-Money.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Color-of-Money.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Color-of-Money.jpg?resize=454,680 454w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Color-of-Money.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px" /></p>
<p>Anyone who manages money, invests in others’ livelihoods or lives in America should read &#8220;The Color of Money: Black Banks and the Racial Wealth Gap&#8221; by Mehrsa Baradaran, an associate dean and professor at the University of California-Irvine and a fellow at the Roosevelt Institute.</p>
<p>Baradaran’s 2017 book explores the past efforts to create economic inclusion in the United States, how they have not succeeded and how any real attempts to improve the wealth gap would need to improve access to capital, among other solutions.</p>
<p>The book digs into financial institutions and policies that are responsible for creating and maintaining racial inequalities in the United States. Baradaran covers the racial wealth gap and its relation to banking as well as the history, political theories, policies and people who maintained the longstanding racist institutions with access to capital and therefore wealth. The book also addresses the idea that wealth is not the same as equality.</p>
<p>A median white family in America has 13 times more wealth than that of a median Black family. &#8220;The Color of Money&#8221; explains through history and an examination of government policies such as redlining and GI Bills as well as discriminatory behaviors why that wealth gap continues, and why it tripled between 1984 and 2009.</p>
<p>Baradaran teaches the reader about the long history of financial institutions, such as community banking, Black banks, mortgage lending and government programs (e.g. CDFI, CRA, GSE, OMBE and FDIC) that have played a role in these systems. She also investigates the limitations of capitalism due to segregation and exploitation during the Reconstruction era, the Great Migration, the New Deal era, Jim Crow and throughout the neoliberal, trickle-down, small government and war on drugs policies of the 1970s, 80s, 90s and beyond.</p>
<p>The book introduces the philosophies of many leaders, from Frederick Douglass to Martin Luther King Jr., and Presidents Nixon and Reagan, who argued that financial prosperity through Black capitalism (banking, ownership, boot straps and entrepreneurship) was the answer to equality. The author argues these ideas are not magic bullets to fix centuries of poverty and abysmal economic opportunity due to discriminatory government, banking policies and generally resource-poor communities. The book breaks down the stereotypes of self-help dogma that tout “save more, don’t spend so much or pull yourself up” and rejects the idea that those who are not wealthy just need more financial literacy or mentorship. “Self-help microfinance cannot overcome macro inequality and systemic racism.”</p>
<p>Deploying capital and creating economic opportunity in VC and in startups means it’s important to understand the racial wealth gap and the history of banking, credit and capital in the United States. As a society, we should constantly be learning from our past mistakes to ensure we are making better and equitable decisions for the future. &#8220;The Color of Money&#8221; is a necessary work that pushes us to correct those past wrongs.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $15 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0674237471/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0674237471&amp;linkId=1d7358bae7e334fdc70e88808f1564e2">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="The Death of the Artist: How Creators Are Struggling to Survive in the Age of Billionaires and Big Tech by William Deresiewicz">The Death of the Artist: How Creators Are Struggling to Survive in the Age of Billionaires and Big Tech by William Deresiewicz</h2>
<p><a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250125514">Henry Holt and Co.</a> (Macmillan), 2020, 368 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Danny Crichton, TechCrunch Managing Editor</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078176" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?w=447" alt="" width="447" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg 1684w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?resize=197,300 197w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?resize=768,1168 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?resize=447,680 447w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?resize=1010,1536 1010w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?resize=1347,2048 1347w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Death-of-the-Artist.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 447px) 100vw, 447px" /></p>
<p>The internet has completely upended the production of art (often labeled as “content” in the capitalist jargon du jour). When it first came to wide attention, the internet seemed like an invention of infinite promise for creatives — a medium of open expression and a network of new human connections that offered faster and broader access to the most brilliant minds of the world. Old barriers crumbled, and cyberspace would be the new basis for an ambitious era of art.</p>
<p>Along the way, the internet also decimated the economic foundations of the modern art world, and despite the media’s obsession with platforms like Kickstarter, Patreon and Substack, has done almost nothing to underwrite the old middle-class careers that were once available to artists.</p>
<p>William Deresiewicz, the famed essayist of &#8220;<a href="https://theamericanscholar.org/the-disadvantages-of-an-elite-education/">The Disadvantages of an Elite Education</a>&#8221; and a book on how colleges produce &#8220;<a href="https://billderesiewicz.com/books/excellent-sheep/">Excellent Sheep</a>,&#8221; turns his attention to the creator market and the economics of art. He’s both an observer and a participant, having left his decade-long teaching stint at Yale to go full freelancer. For the book, he interviewed about 150 creators across a range of fields, from painting and sculpture to writers and illustrators, and what he finds is, perhaps unsurprisingly, depressing.</p>
<p>In short, the economics of art today are terrifying. Platforms like Spotify pay a pittance for art, and the so-called “mid-list” works of artists are increasingly valueless. The internet may have millions of creators bopping around, but few of those people are getting paid, and an extremely small number are getting paid well. Like in so many other knowledge fields, there is an extreme superstar effect on the internet where a handful of artists can have all while almost all other artists have none.</p>
<p>While the descriptions of the salaries and lack of benefits offers some of the emotional heft of the book, Deresiewicz goes on to explore the history of the funding of the arts, from Renaissance patrons to the modern world of grant and foundation money, attempting to place our current predicament into context. He manages to critique everyone, from artists who refuse to adapt to the capitalistic structures of today to the art schools that profit off the indebtedness of their students. I was expecting a polemic, and got a reasonable slice of analysis instead.</p>
<p>It’s an eye-opening book, but necessarily incomplete. For the reality is, there are too many humans who want to produce art, and too few consumers who want to pay to observe and enjoy it. That supply and demand mismatch isn’t going away anytime soon. While the author has some interesting ideas about copyright and intellectual property commons and what not, the reality is that the plight of the artist is most definitely not a problem that has been solved by Silicon Valley technologists.</p>
<p>Most of the book isn’t revolutionary, but in many ways, few economics are for art. &#8220;The Death of the Artist&#8221; reminds us that the consumer choices we make do influence the kind of art we get — and the future prognosis isn’t good.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$20 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1250125510/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1250125510&amp;linkId=9e1d31410db0b10531aaa89d72f65f38">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="A Woman of No Importance: The Untold Story of the American Spy Who Helped Win World War II by Sonia Purnell">A Woman of No Importance: The Untold Story of the American Spy Who Helped Win World War II by Sonia Purnell</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/558307/a-woman-of-no-importance-by-sonia-purnell/">Penguin Random House</a>, 2019, 368 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Ron Miller, TechCrunch enterprise reporter</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078180" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?w=451" alt="" width="451" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg 1696w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?resize=768,1159 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?resize=451,680 451w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?resize=1018,1536 1018w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?resize=1357,2048 1357w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/A-Woman-of-No-Importance.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 451px) 100vw, 451px" /></p>
<p>When you look back at World War II, you no doubt have heard about the male leaders and generals on all sides of the conflict. These are the people history typically remembers, but you don’t usually hear about the unsung heroes who operated in the shadows doing the hard work that wins wars.</p>
<p>One such person is a woman named Virginia Hall.</p>
<p>Author Sonia Purnell tells her remarkable story in the ironically titled &#8220;A Woman of No Importance.&#8221; As it turns out, Hall was incredibly important, and she single-handedly helped organize the resistance in Nazi-occupied France, moving stealthily around the country, constantly on the run from the Gestapo and French authorities, while somehow maintaining contact and passing valuable information to England.</p>
<p>She did all this not only as a woman in a world that didn’t take women seriously, remarkably, she also accomplished this with only one leg. Hall lost one of her legs in a hunting accident and used a wooden prosthetic, making her even more conspicuous for the authorities who were constantly on her trail.</p>
<p>Hall, who grew up in Baltimore, traveled overseas as a girl and developed a fondness for France. Even after the hunting accident, she drove an ambulance in France when the Germans attacked in 1940, simply wanting to help. Later, after returning to London, she somehow talked her way into a new spy network that was being formed by the English government. They lacked personnel who knew France and had contacts, so they took a chance on her. She rewarded them richly with a body of work that would help change the war. Later, she would work for the precursor to the CIA, the Office of Strategic Services, when America joined the war.</p>
<p>Among her accomplishments was building a network of spies, safe houses and supply routes. She quietly helped organize French resistance and, once in place, made sure they had money, weapons, food and training. She once engineered a daring escape of her colleagues, who were being held captive by Nazi authorities in a well-guarded prison camp. She climbed over the rugged Pyrenees mountains through deep snow to safety in Spain when she had to escape the country.</p>
<p>In spite of these accomplishments and many more, she of course had to deal with overt sexism along the way, and Purnell tells how she was often required to report to men who were inferior in every sense. Often she just went her own way, bypassing the system and simply getting the job done.</p>
<p>While there were awards and accolades after the war, she mostly ignored them and seemed content to be a person who operated in the background. She later worked for the CIA, where again she had to deal with sexism and a general lack of respect for her accomplishments.</p>
<p>Hall should be a figure who is remembered and revered by history — a role model for all, a woman whose dogged persistence, intelligence and savvy helped win the war. I couldn’t put this book down, constantly astonished by her feats of daring and bravery, and by the fact that such an amazing person could have been lost to history if not for this impeccably researched book.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $16 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735225311/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0735225311&amp;linkId=37a74c423e77ffbe040ad810b69976ab">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Shoe Dog: A Memoir by the Creator of Nike by Phil Knight">Shoe Dog: A Memoir by the Creator of Nike by Phil Knight</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/Shoe-Dog/Phil-Knight/9781501135927">Scribner</a> (Simon &amp; Schuster), 2016, 400 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Nicole Quinn, partner at Lightspeed Venture Partners</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078184" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?w=453" alt="" width="453" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Shoe-Dog.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px" /></p>
<p>I was a competitive sprinter for many years. It’s how I cleared my head and maintained equilibrium, so the book I recommend to founders is &#8220;Shoe Dog,&#8221; Phil Knight’s story of how he started his career selling low-cost running shoes and turned it into a $160 billion empire.</p>
<p>I remember reading &#8220;Shoe Dog&#8221; for the first time shortly after it was published, under the arches at the Knight Management Center at Stanford, where I had just finished my degree while also working on my own startup. That building was named after Phil Knight, who received his MBA from Stanford and had <a href="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/newsroom/school-news/nike-founder-phil-knight-give-105-million-stanford-gsb">donated $105 million</a> to the university.</p>
<p>One of the things I like about this book is that Knight was one of the first to discover the power of influencer marketing — most famously Nike’s connection with Michael Jordan in the 1980s. The deal was a partnership of equals between an up-and-coming company and a rising superstar, and it completely transformed the worlds of both sports shoes and celebrity endorsements.</p>
<p>Knight’s account of that partnership taught me to never take my own partnerships for granted. I consider myself lucky to work with influencers like Gwyneth Paltrow and Lady Gaga on Lightspeed portfolio companies Goop and Haus Laboratories, respectively. By treating these as true partnerships of value and respect, we can aspire to achieve what Nike and Jordan did with theirs.</p>
<p>&#8220;Shoe Dog&#8221; also drove home for me the incredible importance of word-of-mouth marketing. Knight writes about what happened when his first full-time employee, Jeff Johnson, walked around in a pair of Blue Ribbon Tigers: “People kept stopping him and pointing at his feet and asking where they could buy some neat shoes like those.”</p>
<p>When we analyzed Calm and Cameo to join our portfolio, we looked closely at their potential for generating word of mouth and were impressed with both. As in the early days of Nike, word of mouth is still one of the leading indicators of a brand with staying power.</p>
<p>Knight’s book also teaches us about the power of thinking globally. Back in 1980, Knight was already plotting to use Nike’s foothold in Japan to expand into China. Today, many strong U.S. brands still underperform in other countries. One of the key reasons Lightspeed has opened offices in China, India, Israel and London is to offer insights and advice for companies that seek a more global footprint.</p>
<p>Finally, &#8220;Shoe Dog&#8221; has made me grateful for all the funding options we have today for startups. Back in the early 1970s, when Knight was trying to build Nike into a global brand, IPOs weren’t necessarily a celebration. They were often the only way organizations could raise the capital they needed to reach the next level. “If we didn’t go public, we risked losing everything,” Knight writes. He didn’t want to do an IPO, but it was his only option to scale the company.</p>
<p>That’s a different universe <a href="https://marker.medium.com/the-counterintuitive-case-for-companies-to-stay-private-b929ab5cfbce">than the one we live in now</a>, with all the different investment rounds and funds available to startups today, which allow companies to take as long as they need before filing for a public offering, assuming they decide to take that path.</p>
<p>These are just some of the reasons why I recommend &#8220;Shoe Dog.&#8221; It perfectly captures the entrepreneurial spirit I see in the people and companies I work with each day and inspires me to help them follow in Knight’s footsteps.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $11<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1501135929/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1501135929&amp;linkId=13b4ac496bcc499bf905a7ac3032e473"> from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="The Information: A History, a Theory, a Flood by James Gleick">The Information: A History, a Theory, a Flood by James Gleick</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/60765/the-information-by-james-gleick/">Vintage</a> (Penguin Random House), 2011, 544 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Danny Crichton, TechCrunch Managing Editor</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078187" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg?w=472" alt="" width="472" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg?resize=104,150 104w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg?resize=208,300 208w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg?resize=768,1106 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg?resize=472,680 472w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg?resize=1066,1536 1066w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/The-Information.jpg?resize=35,50 35w" sizes="(max-width: 472px) 100vw, 472px" /></p>
<p>Information — what it is, when’s it true and what’s it for — has been one of the most persistent themes in tech the past few years. There are now dozens of works on misinformation, algorithmic propaganda and “fake news” trying to help us wade through the epistemology of the modern world. Yet, this isn’t the first time that humans have gone through an information revolution, nor is it likely to be the last.</p>
<p>James Gleick wrote &#8220;The Information&#8221; almost a decade ago, but the book feels more relevant than ever. In it, he provides a full historical overview of what we mean by information, how it gets organized and how it gets transmitted from person to person. It’s an absolutely fascinating lens to view history by, and represents one of the best examples of the power of synthesis to redefine our perspective on the world.</p>
<p>What’s all here? The invention of the alphabet and the dictionary. The use of drums and flares to signal danger and communicate over distances. The telegraph and the telephone. The development of mathematics and particularly the mathematics of information theory. Quantum and classical computing. All wrapped up into an overarching narrative about the human need for more knowledge and understanding of the universe. You also get to meet a cast of luminaries along the way, including some of the most brilliant minds in physics, mathematics and computer science.</p>
<p>Gleick focuses mostly on the theory and the invention of the technologies themselves, with occasional digressions into the social ramifications of these communications technologies. I would have liked more of the latter, as one pattern you notice with each wave of communications technology is that there are distinct short, medium and long-term changes that each induces. Given how much acceleration around information we have had the past decade or two, it’s quite palpable to observe just how much more change is to come that’s already been set in motion.</p>
<p>In short, &#8220;The Information&#8221; is a deeply researched and enticing historical journey, one that encourages us to contextualize the overwhelming changes happening in our world.</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $16 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1400096235/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1400096235&amp;linkId=beaa5fe053e961ccb472747b03d8b81e">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Lifespan: Why We Age—and Why We Don’t Have To by David A. Sinclair with Matthew D. LaPlante">Lifespan: Why We Age—and Why We Don’t Have To by David A. Sinclair with Matthew D. LaPlante</h2>
<p><a href="https://lifespanbook.com">Atria Books</a> (Simon &amp; Schuster), 2019, 459 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Alex Iskold, managing partner of 2048 Ventures</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078188" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?w=451" alt="" width="451" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?resize=768,1159 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?resize=451,680 451w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?resize=1018,1536 1018w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?resize=1357,2048 1357w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lifespan.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 451px) 100vw, 451px" /></p>
<p>David Sinclair, professor of genetics at Harvard Medical School, dedicated his life to the research of aging. The central idea of &#8220;Lifespan,&#8221; his latest book, is that humans aren’t actually programmed by nature to age and die. Instead, Sinclair argues that heart disease, Alzheimer’s, cancer and other major causes of death are all manifestations of one single disease — aging. He then explains how cutting-edge science in coming decades will help substantially slow down, and eventually reverse aging, enabling people to live to 150 years old and beyond.</p>
<p>The book contains a fascinating mix of Sinclair’s research, practical advice on anti-aging, implications for healthcare and medicine, philosophy of anti-aging and mind-bending societal implications of substantially longer lifespan</p>
<p><strong>Price:</strong> $15 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0008380325/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0008380325&amp;linkId=60811f0626d96fa3e64584f941c07294">from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell by Susanna Clarke">Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell by Susanna Clarke</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/us/jonathan-strange-mr-norrell-9781635576726/">Bloomsbury</a>, 2005, 864 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Anthony Ha, TechCrunch senior writer</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078190" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jonathan-Strange-and-Mr-Norrell.jpg?w=392" alt="" width="392" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jonathan-Strange-and-Mr-Norrell.jpg 600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jonathan-Strange-and-Mr-Norrell.jpg?resize=86,150 86w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jonathan-Strange-and-Mr-Norrell.jpg?resize=173,300 173w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jonathan-Strange-and-Mr-Norrell.jpg?resize=392,680 392w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jonathan-Strange-and-Mr-Norrell.jpg?resize=29,50 29w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" /></p>
<p>I’ve had a copy of &#8220;Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell&#8221; on my shelf for years, but I never felt motivated enough to start the (literally) thousand-page tome until its author, Susanna Clarke, <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/09/14/susanna-clarkes-fantasy-world-of-interiors">was profiled a few months ago in The New Yorker</a>.</p>
<p>Boy, do I feel dumb for waiting. The novel is an absolute pleasure from beginning to end, and as soon I’d started it, I found myself trying to steal free time to read another 10 pages (or 50, or 100 …)</p>
<p>The novel takes place in an alternate England where magic is real — or so we’re told. By 1806, when the story opens, faeries have disappeared, and the only magicians are “theoretical,” spending their time researching magical history rather than casting real spells.</p>
<p>Gilbert Norrell, a rather stodgy and reclusive scholar of the magical arts, changes all that. When challenged by The Learned Society of York Magicians, Mr. Norrell reveals his powers by bringing an entire cathedral’s work of statues to life. He then proceeds to London, where he hopes to revive the practice of English magic. Eventually, he trains an equally talented magician named Jonathan Strange — Strange is younger, more dashing and more impulsive, and the pair’s friendship soon turns into a rivalry.</p>
<p>That’s just the barest outline of the story, which encompasses everything from the Napoleonic wars, the cost of bringing your loved ones back from the dead and the history of a mysterious figure known as the Raven King. &#8220;Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell&#8221; fully justifies its length — if anything, it packs an entire trilogy’s worth of plot into a fast-paced single volume.</p>
<p>Beyond the pleasure of finding out what happens next, I luxuriated in the opportunity to spend time with the characters and world that Clarke created. Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell seem like real people, while its alternate history (often revealed in playful footnotes) feels like real history.</p>
<p>And, more than any novel I can recall, &#8220;Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell&#8221; makes magic seem like something indescribably strange — not just a writerly trick or trope, but a hidden layer of reality that only a talented magician (or writer) can reveal.</p>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$10<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0765356155/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0765356155&amp;linkId=1a0e2ecb86cef904f36e771fce711ba7"> from Amazon</a></p>
<h2 id="Exhalation: Stories by Ted Chiang">Exhalation: Stories by Ted Chiang</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/538034/exhalation-by-ted-chiang/">Knopf</a> (Penguin Random House), 2019, 368 pages<br />
<b>Recommended by Danny Crichton, TechCrunch Managing Editor</b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2078193" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exhalation.jpeg?w=446" alt="" width="446" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exhalation.jpeg 459w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exhalation.jpeg?resize=98,150 98w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exhalation.jpeg?resize=197,300 197w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exhalation.jpeg?resize=446,680 446w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Exhalation.jpeg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 446px) 100vw, 446px" /></p>
<p>We ran an experimental book club on the short story collection &#8220;Exhalation,&#8221; which explores a variety of themes about connection, humanity and a nice bit of time warp. Chiang has a preternatural ability to devise interesting plot devices and extend them into beautiful fractals of thinking and reflection. Definitely read the book, and check out our story-by-story discussion from earlier this year on TechCrunch:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/reading-ted-chiangs-the-merchant-and-the-alchemists-gate/">Reading Ted Chiang’s The Merchant and the Alchemist’s Gate</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/can-a-time-machine-offer-us-the-meaning-of-life/">Can a time machine offer us the meaning of life?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/29/what-is-our-meaning-in-life-in-a-world-of-technology/">What is our meaning in life in a world of technology?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/15/can-we-debate-free-will-versus-destiny-in-four-pages/">Can we debate free will versus destiny in four pages?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/16/with-the-development-of-generalized-ai-whats-the-meaning-of-a-person/">With the development of generalized AI, what’s the meaning of a person?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/23/how-do-we-connect-a-child-to-technology/">How do we connect a child to technology?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/27/with-better-recall-of-our-photos-and-videos-will-our-ability-to-forgive-disappear/">With better recall of our photos and videos, will our ability to forgive disappear?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/29/why-you-cant-overlook-the-small-details-in-the-pursuit-of-innovation/">Why you can’t overlook the small details in the pursuit of innovation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/08/what-is-the-purpose-of-belief-in-a-world-of-innovation/">What is the purpose of belief in a world of innovation?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/08/if-we-could-see-alternate-realities-would-we-want-to-take-a-look/">If we could see alternate realities, would we want to take a look?</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Price: </strong>$15<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1101972084/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=techcrunchgg-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1101972084&amp;linkId=b55e3e51ce673e04ba97129532daf384"> from Amazon</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2020/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/gift-guide-2020-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2078170</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Discovery will launch its own streaming service on January 4</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/discovery-will-launch-its-own-streaming-service-on-january-4/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/discovery-will-launch-its-own-streaming-service-on-january-4/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 20:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A&E networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animal Planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discovery networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discovery-Channel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2082057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Discovery is the latest media company to launch a standalone streaming service — and the latest to adopt the simple naming strategy of just adding a plus sign — with discovery+, set to launch in the United States on January 4, 2021. While Discovery doesn&#8217;t have the name recognition of (say) Disney/Disney+, it&#8217;s pitching the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/discovery-inc" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="discovery-inc">Discovery <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is the latest media company to launch a standalone streaming service — and the latest to adopt the simple naming strategy of just adding a plus sign — with discovery+, set to launch in the United States on January 4, 2021.</p>
<p>While Discovery doesn&#8217;t have the name recognition of (say) Disney/Disney+, it&#8217;s pitching the service as &#8220;the definitive streaming service for the best real life entertainment in the world,&#8221; with 55,000 episodes at launch drawn from Discovery networks like HGTV, Food Network, TLC, ID, OWN, Travel Channel, Discovery Channel and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/animal-planet" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="animal-planet">Animal Planet <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a>. It&#8217;s also struck a deal with A&amp;E Networks to feature content from A&amp;E, The History Channel and Lifetime.</p>
<p>And of course there will be original programming, including several &#8220;90 Day Fiancé&#8221; spinoffs, the U.S. premiere of the BBC series &#8220;A Perfect Planet,&#8221; a topiary competition series (with Martha Stewart as lead judge) called &#8220;Clipped,&#8221; a Kevin Hart travel show with the working title &#8220;Route 66&#8221; and much more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Discovery+ also has a first look deal with Magnolia Network, a joint venture with &#8220;Fixer Upper&#8221; stars Chip and Joanna Gaines. And it will feature original content from Discovery-backed digital media company Group Nine, whose brands include The Dodo, NowThis and Thrillist.</p>
<p>While the big U.S. launch isn&#8217;t happening until January, discovery+ actually launched in the United Kingdom and Ireland through a deal with Sky last month, and the company plans to launch across 21 markets in 2021. For European viewers, the service will be the streaming home of the Olympics, starting with next year&#8217;s event in Tokyo.</p>
<p>In the U.S., discovery+ will cost $4.99 per month, or $6.99 per month to go ad-free. Discovery is also announcing a partnership with <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/verizon" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="verizon">Verizon <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> to offer up to 12 months (depending on the plan) of free discovery+ access to select wireless and home internet subscribers. (Verizon owns TechCrunch.)</p>
<p>In a statement, Discovery president and CEO David Zaslav said:</p>
<blockquote><p>We have been working methodically the past two years to bring all of our strategic advantages to the launch of discovery+, including distribution and advertising partnerships around the world, a world-class offering of quality brands, authentic personalities and the largest content library at launch, as well as a broad slate of exclusive programming. With discovery+, we are seizing the global opportunity to be the world’s definitive product for unscripted storytelling, providing households and mobile consumers a distinct, clear and differentiated offering across valuable and enduring lifestyle, and real life verticals.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oK5EpHb5ge"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/group-nine-brian-sugar-interview/">PopSugar co-founder says pandemic will create &#8216;a huge windfall&#8217; for digital media</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;PopSugar co-founder says pandemic will create &#8216;a huge windfall&#8217; for digital media&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/group-nine-brian-sugar-interview/embed/#?secret=oK5EpHb5ge" data-secret="oK5EpHb5ge" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/discovery-will-launch-its-own-streaming-service-on-january-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2082057</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
