<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:58:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Amazon partners with Seraphim on AWS accelerator for space startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/amazon-partners-with-seraphim-on-aws-accelerator-for-space-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/amazon-partners-with-seraphim-on-aws-accelerator-for-space-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seraphim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seraphim Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon will soon be a big part of the space economy in the form of its Kuiper satellite internet constellation, but here on Earth its ambitions are more commonplace: get an accelerator going. They&#8217;ve partnered with space-focused VC outfit Seraphim Capital to create a 4-week program with (among other things) a $100,000 AWS credit for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon will soon be a big part of the space economy in the form of its Kuiper satellite internet constellation, but here on Earth its ambitions are more commonplace: <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/publicsector/announcing-aws-space-accelerator-startups/">get an accelerator going</a>. They&#8217;ve partnered with space-focused VC outfit Seraphim Capital to create a 4-week program with (among other things) a $100,000 AWS credit for a carrot.</p>
<p>Applications are open now for the AWS Space Accelerator, with the only requirement that you&#8217;re aiming for the space sector and plan to use AWS at some point. 10 will be accepted; you have until April 21 to apply.</p>
<p><a href="https://seraphim.vc/aws/accelerator/">The program sounds fairly straightforward</a>: a &#8220;technical, business, and mentorship&#8221; deal where you&#8217;ll likely learn how to use AWS properly, get some good tips from the AWS Partner Network and other space-focused experts on tech, regulations, and security, then rub shoulders with some VCs to talk about that round you&#8217;re putting together. (No doubt Seraphim&#8217;s team gets first dibs, but there doesn&#8217;t appear to be any strict equity agreement.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Selected startups may receive up to $100,000 in AWS Activate credit,&#8221; the announcement says, which does hedge somewhat, but probably legal made them put that in.</p>
<p>There are a good amount of space-focused programs out there, but not nearly enough to cover demand — there are a lot of space startups! And they often face a special challenge of being highly technical, have customers in the public sector, and need rather a lot of cash to get going compared with your average enterprise SaaS.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll understand more about the program once the first cohort is announced, likely not for at least a month or two.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/amazon-partners-with-seraphim-on-aws-accelerator-for-space-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132359</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LinkedIn confirms it&#8217;s working on a Clubhouse rival, too</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-confirms-its-working-on-a-clubhouse-rival-too/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-confirms-its-working-on-a-clubhouse-rival-too/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Clubhouse&#8217;s list of competitors is growing. LinkedIn has now confirmed it&#8217;s also testing a social audio experience in its app which would allow creators on its network to connect with their community. Unlike the Clubhouse rivals being built by Facebook and Twitter, LinkedIn believes its audio networking feature will be differentiated because it will be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Clubhouse&#8217;s list of competitors is growing. LinkedIn has now confirmed it&#8217;s also testing a social audio experience in its app which would allow creators on its network to connect with their community. Unlike the Clubhouse rivals being built by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/facebooks-clubhouse-rival-looks-a-lot-like-clubhouse-right-now/">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/twitter-spaces-arrives-on-android-ahead-of-clubhouse/">Twitter</a>, LinkedIn believes its audio networking feature will be differentiated because it will be connected with users&#8217; professional identity, not just a social profile. In addition, the company has already built out a platform that serves the creator community, which today has access to tools like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/20/linkedin-stories/">Stories</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/11/linkedin-debuts-linkedin-live-a-new-live-video-broadcast-service/">LinkedIn Live video broadcasting</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/111414">newsletters</a> and more.</p>
<p>And just today, LinkedIn formalized some of its efforts in this area with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-adds-creator-mode-video-profiles-and-in-partnership-with-microsoft-new-career-training-tools/">launch a new &#8220;Creator&#8221; mode</a> that lets anyone set their profile as one that can be followed for updates, like Stories and LinkedIn Live videos, for example.</p>
<p>This focus on creators puts LinkedIn on competitive footing in terms of expanding its own Clubhouse rival, compared with other efforts by Facebook, Twitter, <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/03/19/telegram-voice-features-ios-update/">Telegram</a>, or <a href="https://twitter.com/BobbyAllyn/status/1376974352994856961">Discord</a> &#8212; all of which have their own audio-based networking features in various stages development at this time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Though Twitter&#8217;s Clubhouse rival, Twitter Spaces, is already live in beta testing, its full set of creator tools have yet to arrive. In fact, it was only last month that Twitter <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/111414">announced</a> its plans for a larger creator subscription platform via a new &#8220;Super Follow&#8221; feature, for instance. And it only this year entered the newsletter space via an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">acquisition</a>. Facebook, meanwhile, has historically offered a number of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/creators">creator-focused features</a>, but has just recently gotten invested <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/29/22255876/facebook-newsletter-tools-independent-journalists-writers-substack-revue">in tools like newsletters</a>.</p>
<p>LinkedIn says its development of an audio-based networking feature came about because its members and creatives have been asking for more ways to communicate on its platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re seeing nearly 50% growth in conversations on LinkedIn reflected in stories, video shares, and posts on the platform,&#8221; a LinkedIn spokesperson said, when confirming its audio feature&#8217;s development. &#8220;We’re doing some early tests to create a unique audio experience connected to your professional identity. And, we&#8217;re looking at how we can bring audio to other parts of LinkedIn such as events and groups, to give our members even more ways to connect to their community,&#8221; they said.</p>
<p>As a result of creators&#8217; interest in this space, the company moved quickly to develop its own Clubhouse-like feature, where there&#8217;s a stage showcasing the room&#8217;s speakers and a set of listeners below. There are also tools to join and leave the room, react to comments, and request to speak, according to screenshots of the interface first discovered in the LinkedIn Android app by reverse engineer<a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1376856556533379075"> Alessandro Paluzzi</a>.</p>
<p>Note that Paluzzi populated the user interface with his own profile icon, shown in the image <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1376856556533379075">he tweeted</a>. That is not part of the LinkedIn mockup. Instead, LinkedIn shared its own conceptual UX mockup of its in-room experiences with TechCrunch, which shows a more fleshed out example of how the feature may look at launch.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2132351" style="width: 339px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2132351" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2132351" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?w=329" alt="" width="329" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg 1230w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?resize=73,150 73w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?resize=145,300 145w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?resize=768,1588 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?resize=329,680 329w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?resize=743,1536 743w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?resize=990,2048 990w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Concept-Mock.LinkedIn.jpg?resize=24,50 24w" sizes="(max-width: 329px) 100vw, 329px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2132351" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> LinkedIn</p></div></p>
<p>LinkedIn believes that because the audio experience will be connected with users&#8217; professional identities, they&#8217;ll feel comfortable speaking, commenting and otherwise engaging with the content, the company told TechCrunch. It will also be able to leverage its existing investment in moderation tools built for other features &#8212; like LinkedIn Live &#8212; to help to address any concerns over inappropriate or harmful discussions, like those that <a href="https://www.protocol.com/moderation-clubhouse-building-community">have</a> <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/z3vkde/clubhouse-app-misinformation-problem">already</a> <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2020/12/the-murky-world-of-moderation-on-clubhouse">plagued</a> <a href="https://www.communitysignal.com/why-has-clubhouse-been-plagued-by-trust-and-safety-issues/">Clubhouse</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our priority is to build a trusted community where people feel safe and can be productive,&#8221; a spokesperson noted. &#8220;Our members come to LinkedIn to have respectful and constructive conversations with real people and we’re focused on ensuring they have a safe environment to do just that,&#8221; they said.</p>
<p>Plus, LinkedIn says that audio networking makes for a natural extension of other areas, like Groups and Events &#8212; areas for networking that have continued to grow, and particularly during the pandemic.</p>
<p>In 2020, some 21 million people attended an event on LinkedIn, and overall LinkedIn sessions increased by 30% year-over-year. The company&#8217;s 740 million global members also last year built community, had conversations, and shared knowledge, with 4.8 billion connections made.</p>
<p>Like many companies which saw a pandemic boost, LinkedIn believes the pandemic only accelerated the natural progression towards online networking, remote work, and virtual events, which were already in place before lockdowns. For example, LinkedIn says that more than 60% of its members were working remotely by the end of 2020, versus 8% before the pandemic. LinkedIn believes the shift will stick, as more than half the world&#8217;s workforce is expected to <a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2020-07-14-gartner-survey-reveals-82-percent-of-company-leaders-plan-to-allow-employees-to-work-remotely-some-of-the-time">continue working from home</a> at least some of the time, even after the pandemic comes to an end.</p>
<p>That leaves room for new forms of online networking to grow, as well, including audio experiences.</p>
<p>LinkedIn doesn&#8217;t yet have an exact timeframe for its launch of the audio networking feature, but says it will begin beta testing soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-confirms-its-working-on-a-clubhouse-rival-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132216</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Google starts testing its cookie alternative</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/daily-crunch-google-starts-testing-its-cookie-alternative/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/daily-crunch-google-starts-testing-its-cookie-alternative/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 22:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google tries out new ad targeting technology, PayPal adds cryptocurrency support and Substack raises additional funding. This is your Daily Crunch for March 30, 2021. The big story: Google starts testing its cookie alternative Google announced today that it has begun rolling out a new technology called Federated Learning of Cohorts (FLoC) in a developer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google tries out new ad targeting technology, PayPal adds cryptocurrency support and Substack raises additional funding. This is your Daily Crunch for March 30, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Google starts testing its cookie alternative</strong></p>
<p>Google <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-starts-trialling-its-floc-cookie-alternative-in-chrome/">announced</a> today that it has begun rolling out a new technology called Federated Learning of Cohorts (FLoC) in a developer trial. FLoC is meant to serve as an alternative to personally identifiable cookies (which are being phased out by Google and other platforms), with Google analyzing your web browsing behavior and grouping you with other people who have similar interests, for ad-targeting purposes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The trial is starting out in a number of geographies, including the United States — but not in Europe, where there are concerns about compliance with Europe&#8217;s GDPR privacy regulations.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/youtube-tests-hiding-dislike-counts-on-videos/">YouTube tests hiding dislike counts on videos</a> — The company says it will run a “small experiment” with different designs that hide dislike counts, but not the &#8220;dislike&#8221; button itself.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ballot-counting-for-amazons-historic-union-vote-starts-today/">Ballot counting for Amazon’s historic union vote starts today</a> — Amazon&#8217;s warehouse in Bessemer, Alabama has become ground zero for one of the most import labor efforts in modern American history.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/paypals-new-feature-allows-u-s-consumers-to-check-out-using-cryptocurrency/">PayPal’s new feature allows US consumers to check out using cryptocurrency</a> — The feature expands on PayPal’s current investments in the cryptocurrency market.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/celebrity-video-request-site-cameo-reaches-unicorn-status-with-100m-raise/">Celebrity video request site Cameo reaches unicorn status with $100M raise</a> — Cameo has been building a good deal of steam in recent years, but it also got a major boost amidst the pandemic.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/substack-confirms-65m-raise-promises-to-rapidly-expand-its-financial-backing-of-newly-independent-writers/">Substack confirms $65M raise, promises to ‘rapidly’ expand its financial backing of newly independent writers</a> — Substack did not provide material new growth metrics, instead saying that it has “more than half a million people” paying for writers on its network.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nft-art-marketplace-superrare-closes-9-million-series-a/">NFT art marketplace SuperRare closes $9M Series A</a> — SuperRare launched its art platform in 2018, since then it has differentiated by maintaining a closed early access platform, closely curating the art that&#8217;s sold.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/">The Tonal EC-1</a> — Remember our deep dives into the history, businesses and growth of Patreon, Niantic, Roblox, Kobalt and Unity? We&#8217;re bringing the format back with an in-depth, multi-part look at fitness startup Tonal.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/">Is Substack really worth $650M?</a> — More thoughts on Substack&#8217;s finances.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/console-game-china-pulled-ecommerce/">A trove of imported console games vanish from Chinese online stores</a> — A handful of grey market videogame console vendors on Taobao stopped selling and shipping this week.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/applications-for-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021-are-now-open/">Applications for Startup Battlefield at TC Disrupt 2021 are now open</a> — TechCrunch is on the hunt for game-changing and ground-breaking startups from around the globe to feature in Startup Battlefield during TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 this fall.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/daily-crunch-google-starts-testing-its-cookie-alternative/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132319</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Maps adds COVID-19 travel guidance for over 300 airports worldwide</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/apple-maps-adds-covid-19-travel-guidance-for-over-300-airports-worldwide/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/apple-maps-adds-covid-19-travel-guidance-for-over-300-airports-worldwide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple inc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has updated its native Maps app with more helpful information designed to assist with travel while mitigating the spread of COVID-19. Apple Maps on iPhone, iPad and Mac will now show COVID-19 health measure information for airports when searched via the app, either through a link to the airport&#8217;s own COVID-19 advisory page, or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has updated its native Maps app with more helpful information designed to assist with travel while mitigating the spread of COVID-19. Apple Maps on iPhone, iPad and Mac will now show COVID-19 health measure information for airports when searched via the app, either through a link to the airport&#8217;s own COVID-19 advisory page, or directly on the in-app location card itself.</p>
<p>The new information is made available through a partnership with the Airports Council International and provides details on COVID-19 safety guidelines in effect at over 300 airports worldwide. The type of information provided includes requirements around COVID-19 testing, mask usage, screening procedures and any quarantine measures in effect, and generally hopes to help make the process of traveling while the global pandemic continues easier, and as vaccination programs and other counterefforts are set to prompt a global travel recovery.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Wctir5AE0f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/apple-maps-updated-with-covid-19-vaccination-locations-in-the-u-s/">Apple Maps updated with COVID-19 vaccination locations in the US</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple Maps updated with COVID-19 vaccination locations in the US&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/apple-maps-updated-with-covid-19-vaccination-locations-in-the-u-s/embed/#?secret=Wctir5AE0f" data-secret="Wctir5AE0f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Earlier this month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/apple-maps-updated-with-covid-19-vaccination-locations-in-the-u-s/">Apple also added COVID-19 vaccination locations within the U.S. to Apple Maps</a>, which can be found when searching either via text, with Siri, or using the &#8220;Find nearby&#8221; location-based feature. Last year, the company added testing sites in various locations around the world and added COVID-19 information modules to cards for other types of businesses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JqnjuUCgmD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/will-the-pandemic-spur-a-smart-rebirth-for-cities/">Will the pandemic spur a smart rebirth for cities?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will the pandemic spur a smart rebirth for cities?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/will-the-pandemic-spur-a-smart-rebirth-for-cities/embed/#?secret=JqnjuUCgmD" data-secret="JqnjuUCgmD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/apple-maps-adds-covid-19-travel-guidance-for-over-300-airports-worldwide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Free Extra Crunch membership included with TC Early Stage tickets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/free-extra-crunch-membership-included-with-tc-early-stage-tickets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/free-extra-crunch-membership-included-with-tc-early-stage-tickets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Travis Bernard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 20:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch Early Stage is coming up this week, and all attendees can get three months of free access to Extra Crunch as a part of a ticket purchase. Extra Crunch is our members-only community focused on founders and startup teams, and it features over 100 exclusive articles per month.  Head here to buy your ticket [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch Early Stage is coming up this week, and all attendees can get three months of free access to Extra Crunch as a part of a ticket purchase. Extra Crunch is our members-only community focused on founders and startup teams, and it features over 100 exclusive articles per month. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/#tickets"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Head here to buy your ticket to TC Early Stage</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extra Crunch unlocks access to our weekly investor surveys, private market analysis, and in-depth interviews with experts on fundraising, growth, monetization and other core startup topics. Get feedback on your pitch deck through Extra Crunch Live, and stay informed with our members-only Extra Crunch newsletter. Other benefits include an improved TechCrunch.com experience and savings on software services from AWS, Crunchbase and more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about Extra Crunch benefits </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and buy your TC Early Stage tickets </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/#tickets"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<h2><b>What is TC Early Stage? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TC Early Stage is a two-day virtual event where early-stage founders can take part in highly interactive group sessions with top investors and ecosystem experts. This includes everything from fundraising and operations to product lifecycle and recruiting.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The event will take place April 1-2, and we’d love to have you join. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">View the event agenda </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/announcing-the-agenda-for-tc-early-stage-operations-fundraising/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and purchase tickets </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-1/#tickets"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you buy your TC Early Stage pass, you will be emailed a link and unique code to claim the free trial of Extra Crunch.</span></p>
<h2><b>Already bought your TC Early Stage ticket?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Existing pass holders will be emailed with information on how to claim the free three months of Extra Crunch membership. All new ticket purchases will receive information over email immediately after the purchase is complete.</span></p>
<h2><b>Already an Extra Crunch member?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re happy to extend a free three months of access to existing users. Please contact <a href="mailto:extracrunch@techcrunch.com">extracrunch@techcrunch.com</a>, and mention that you are an existing Extra Crunch member who bought a ticket to TC Early Stage. </span></p>
<h2><b>What if I buy a ticket to both Early Stage 1 and 2?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You get six months of free access. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/free-extra-crunch-membership-included-with-tc-early-stage-tickets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131499</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon acquires Indian retail startup Perpule</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/amazon-acquires-indian-retail-startup-perpule/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/amazon-acquires-indian-retail-startup-perpule/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 20:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DotPe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dukaan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jio Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khatabook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OkCredit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reliance Retail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon has acquired a startup in India that is helping offline stores go online, the e-commerce group’s latest attempt to make inroads in the world’s second most populous nation where brick and mortar continue to drive more than 95% of sales. The American e-commerce group said on Tuesday evening that it has acquired Perpule, a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon has acquired a startup in India that is helping offline stores go online, the e-commerce group’s latest attempt to make inroads in the world’s second most populous nation where brick and mortar continue to drive more than 95% of sales.</p>
<p>The American e-commerce group said on Tuesday evening that it has acquired <a href="https://www.perpule.com">Perpule</a>, a four-year-old startup. A regulatory filing showed Amazon Technologies paid $14.7 million to acquire the Indian startup in an all-cash deal. The company is expected to spend an additional $5 million or so to compensate Perpule’s employees.</p>
<p>Perpule, which had raised $6.36 million (per insight platform Tracxn), offers a mobile payments device (point of sale machine) to offline retailers to help them accept digital payments and also establish presence on various mini app stores including those run by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/04/google-policy-cut-india-paytm-mini-app-store/">Paytm</a>, PhonePe and Google Pay in India.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Perpule has built an innovative cloud-based POS offering that enables offline stores in India to better manage their inventory, checkout process and overall customer experience,&#8221; an Amazon spokesperson said in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to have the Perpule team join us to focus on providing growth opportunities for businesses of all sizes in India while raising the bar of the shopping experience for Indian customers.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WkkKtYHNDX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/from-indias-richest-man-to-amazon-and-100s-of-startups-the-great-rush-to-win-neighborhood-stores/">From India&#8217;s richest man to Amazon and 100s of startups: The great rush to win neighborhood stores</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From India&#8217;s richest man to Amazon and 100s of startups: The great rush to win neighborhood stores&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/from-indias-richest-man-to-amazon-and-100s-of-startups-the-great-rush-to-win-neighborhood-stores/embed/#?secret=WkkKtYHNDX" data-secret="WkkKtYHNDX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Founded in late 2016, the Indian startup’s first product was focused on helping customers avoid queues at superchains such as Shoppers Stop, Spar Hypermarket and Big Bazaar. But the product, said Abhinav Pathak in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MtUc4r8ReSY">a recent interview</a>, wasn’t scaling, which is when Perpule pivoted.</p>
<p>The Bangalore-based startup &#8212; which counts Prime Venture Partners, Kalaari Capital and Raghunandan G (founder of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/zolve-raises-15-million-for-its-cross-border-neobank-aimed-at-global-citizens/">neobank Zolve</a>) among its investors &#8212; has further expanded in recent years, launching products like StoreSE, which enables a business to support group ordering.</p>
<p>Last year, it also expanded geographically, bringing its <a href="https://www.thejakartapost.com/news/2020/07/09/indian-retail-tech-start-up-perpule-expands-market-to-sea.html">offerings to Southeast Asian markets</a> including Indonesia, Malaysia, Thailand, Singapore and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Amazon has aggressively <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/26/amazon-launches-smart-stores-in-india-to-win-mom-and-pop/">engaged with physical stores in India</a> in recent years, using their vast presence in the nation to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/18/amazon-india-kirana-neighborhood-stores/">expand its delivery network</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/18/amazon-india-kirana-neighborhood-stores/">warehouses</a> and even just relying on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/23/amazon-begins-selling-items-from-neighborhood-stores-in-india-amid-facebooks-deal-with-jio/">their inventory to drive sales</a>.</p>
<p>The company’s push into physical retail comes as Flipkart, and Reliance Jio Platforms (backed by Facebook and Google), which last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/google-invests-4-5-billion-in-indias-reliance-jio-platforms/">raised over $20 billion</a>, also race to capture this market. The acquisition of Perpule comes less than a week after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/google-dotpe-india-27-5-million-investment/">Google backed DotPe</a>, a startup that offers several similar products.</p>
<p>These neighborhood stores offer all kinds of items, are family run and pay low wages and little to no rent. Because they are ubiquitous — there are more than 30 million neighborhood stores in India, according to industry estimates — no retail giant can offer a faster delivery. On top of that, their economics are often better than most of their digital counterparts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xqPdJ3dm5j"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/22/facebooks-5-7-billion-bet-on-indian-giant-jio-spells-trouble-for-amazon-and-flipkart/">Facebook’s $5.7 billion bet on Indian giant Jio spells trouble for Amazon and Flipkart</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook’s $5.7 billion bet on Indian giant Jio spells trouble for Amazon and Flipkart&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/22/facebooks-5-7-billion-bet-on-indian-giant-jio-spells-trouble-for-amazon-and-flipkart/embed/#?secret=xqPdJ3dm5j" data-secret="xqPdJ3dm5j" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/amazon-acquires-indian-retail-startup-perpule/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132225</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Applications for Startup Battlefield at TC Disrupt 2021 are now open</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/applications-for-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021-are-now-open/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/applications-for-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021-are-now-open/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neesha A. Tambe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Applications for Startup Battlefield are now open! Founders, this past year has been challenging in ways words can&#8217;t encompass. But you are persevering and now is the time to show the world what you have been working on. TechCrunch is on the hunt for game-changing and ground-breaking startups from around the globe to feature in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn">Applications</a> for Startup Battlefield are now <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn"><strong>open</strong></a>! Founders, this past year has been challenging in ways words can&#8217;t encompass. But you are persevering and now is the time to show the world what you have been working on. TechCrunch is on the hunt for game-changing and ground-breaking startups from around the globe to feature in Startup Battlefield during <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> this fall. Startups will be competing for a $100,000 equity-free prize, the eyes of investors from around the world and global media coverage on the most famous stage in tech media.</p>
<p><strong>Eligibility &amp; Application. </strong>Startup Battlefield highlights early-stage companies from all geographies, in any industry. Startups should have an MVP. Founders simply need to apply here. Every application is reviewed by a member of the TechCrunch editorial team. TechCrunch takes ZERO fees — the application and participation/training program for selected companies is free. TC does not take equity in any company.</p>
<p><strong>Training. </strong>Startups selected to pitch will engage in intensive training over several weeks with the Startup Battlefield team. Founders will perfect their pitches, finesse their business models and hone their presentation skills. Founders will have access to master classes from experts on how to build, market and scale the startups.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Pitch. </strong>About 25 startups will be selected to pitch on the main stage at TechCrunch Disrupt 2021. Each founder will present for six minutes, with a live demo, followed by a Q&amp;A with our esteemed panel of judges. Judges like Kristin Green, Aileen Lee, Alfred Lin, Susan Lyne and more. After the first round, the top set of companies will pitch again in the final round in front of a fresh panel of judges. The judges will pick the winner who will receive the Disrupt cup and the $100,000 equity-free prize money.</p>
<p><strong>Disrupt. </strong> Startup Battlefield founders are the VIPs of TC Disrupt. Founders get access to private events, complimentary event tickets, exhibition space on the virtual show floor, access to CrunchMatch and a private Startup Battlefield reception with members of the Startup Battlefield alumni community. Battlefield founders will also get access to future TC events and a free subscription to Extra Crunch.</p>
<p>Launch your startup this September. Step into the spotlight. Apply <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn">now</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/applications-for-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021-are-now-open/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NFT art marketplace SuperRare closes $9 million Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nft-art-marketplace-superrare-closes-9-million-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nft-art-marketplace-superrare-closes-9-million-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ashton kutcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chamath Palihapitiya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Collaborative Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consensys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dapper Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Benioff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark cuban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national basketball association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naval ravikant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Velvet Sea Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The NFT ecosystem is having an explosive moment and the startups that were ready to run with it are getting lots of cash to continue capturing that momentum. SuperRare, an NFT art platform that has garnered tens of millions in new sales in recent weeks, has just raised millions from investors. The $9 million Series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The NFT ecosystem is having an explosive moment and the startups that were ready to run with it are getting lots of cash to continue capturing that momentum.</p>
<p><a href="https://superrare.co/">SuperRare</a>, an NFT art platform that has garnered tens of millions in new sales in recent weeks, has just raised millions from investors. The $9 million Series A round was led by Velvet Sea Ventures and 1confirmation. Other investors participating in the round include Collaborative Fund, Shrug Capital, Third Kind, SamsungNext, Ashton Kutcher and Guy Oseary’s Sound Ventures, Mark Cuban, Marc Benioff, Naval Ravikant and Chamath Palihapitiya, among others.</p>
<p>In an <a href="https://medium.com/superrare/superrare-raises-9m-to-build-the-future-of-art-collecting-e2b3ded227e8">announcement</a> of the raise, the team called the crypto art scene a &#8220;global phenomenon.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>SuperRare launched its art platform in 2018, since then it has differentiated by maintaining a closed early-access platform that more closely curates the art they sell. Everything on the platform is a single-edition 1/1 sale. The team has said they plan to launch the site widely next year. The company earns a 3% transaction fee on art sales on the platform in addition to a 15% gallery fee for primary sales. One unique facet of the platform is that creators can continue to earn on a piece&#8217;s appreciating value following with 10% commissions on secondary sales.</p>
<p>While NFT art sales have taken off in recent weeks, there are still many structural issues facing their mainstream adoption largely due to scalability issues with Ethereum&#8217;s mainnet, which SuperRare operates on. Plenty of firms are building layer-two infrastructure that improves speed and cuts down on energy usage and transaction fees. Today, ConsenSys launched a platform called Palm featuring artists Damien Hirst as the platform&#8217;s first artist drop.</p>
<p>After a lengthy crypto winter, blockchain startups are coming back with a vengeance amid a surge in startup investing, a surge in enthusiasm around NFTs and a surge in bitcoin prices. Today, NBA Top Shot maker Dapper Labs announced in had raised $305 million in venture funding.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gOlSLLfdBy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/consenysys-launches-a-more-energy-efficient-nft-ecosystem-with-a-project-from-artist-damien-hirst-as-its-first-drop/">ConsenySys launches a more energy-efficient NFT ecosystem with a project from artist Damien Hirst as its first drop</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ConsenySys launches a more energy-efficient NFT ecosystem with a project from artist Damien Hirst as its first drop&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/consenysys-launches-a-more-energy-efficient-nft-ecosystem-with-a-project-from-artist-damien-hirst-as-its-first-drop/embed/#?secret=gOlSLLfdBy" data-secret="gOlSLLfdBy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nft-art-marketplace-superrare-closes-9-million-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YouTube tests hiding dislike counts on videos</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/youtube-tests-hiding-dislike-counts-on-videos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/youtube-tests-hiding-dislike-counts-on-videos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[like button]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[YouTube announced today it will begin testing what could end up being a significant change to its video platform: It&#8217;s going to try hiding the dislike count on videos from public view. The company says it will run a &#8220;small experiment&#8221; where it will try out a few different designs where dislike counts are no [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">YouTube announced today it will begin testing what could end up being a significant change to its video platform: It&#8217;s going to try hiding the dislike count on videos from public view. The company says it will run a &#8220;small experiment&#8221; where it will try out a few different designs where dislike counts are no longer shown, however none will see the &#8220;dislike&#8221; button itself removed entirely.</p>
<p>The company announced the tests on <a href="https://twitter.com/YouTube/status/1376942493481193475">Twitter</a>, but then explains further in a <a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/104325801?hl=en">community forum post</a> that the goal is not to remove the ability for users to signal they disliked a video &#8212; creators will still have access to the video&#8217;s like and dislike count from YouTube Studio and dislikes will still help power YouTube&#8217;s recommendation algorithms.</p>
<p>Instead, YouTube says that the idea to try hiding dislikes is based on creator feedback.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve heard from creators that the public dislike counts can impact their well-being and may motivate a targeted campaign of dislikes on a creator’s video,&#8221; the announcement reads. &#8220;So, we&#8217;re testing designs that don’t include the visible like or dislike count in an effort to balance improving the creator experience, while still making sure viewer feedback is accounted for and shared with the creator.&#8221;</p>
<p>Of course, there can be a sort of mob mentality that accompanies the use of the Like and Dislike buttons on YouTube. But seeing the dislike count can also help to signal to others when videos are clickbait, spam or misleading, which can be helpful.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Creators, you&#39;ll still be able to see the exact number of likes and dislikes in YouTube Studio. For viewers, if you&#39;re in the experiment, you can still like or dislike a video to share feedback with creators and help tune the recommendations you see on YouTube.</p>
<p>&mdash; YouTube (@YouTube) <a href="https://twitter.com/YouTube/status/1376942493481193475?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>YouTube showed off one potential design being tested that simply shows the same button layout but instead of a number of dislikes, the word &#8220;Dislike&#8221; appears underneath the thumbs down icon.</p>
<p>There will be no way to opt out of the test if you see the changes appear when you&#8217;re logged into YouTube &#8212; you&#8217;ll only be able to share feedback, the company notes.</p>
<p>To be clear, however, YouTube isn&#8217;t yet committed to removing the dislike count for everyone at this time. The feedback from this test will help inform YouTube as to if, when or how it will release designs like this more broadly.</p>
<p>YouTube wouldn&#8217;t be the first to experiment with removing metrics from a social app. Instagram<a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/12/2/20983760/instagram-removing-likes-authenticity"> has also been testing removing the number of positive engagements (Likes)</a>, in order to make the experience feel more authentic and less about chasing clout. And Facebook this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/facebook-redesigns-pages-with-a-more-simplified-layout-and-no-like-button/">removed the &#8220;Like&#8221; button from Facebook Pages</a>, in favor of the more accurate &#8220;Followers&#8221; measurement. However, in the case of removing just the dislike count and not the likes, viewers may misunderstand a video&#8217;s true popularity.</p>
<p>The company told TechCrunch the tests will run globally over the next few weeks on Android and iOS while it gathers feedback from a handful of designs.</p>
<p><em>Updated 3/30/21, 6 pm et to add details about launch. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Az7HGWdyIu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/extra-crunch-members-get-unlimited-access-to-12m-stock-images-for-99-per-year/">Extra Crunch members get unlimited access to 12M stock images for $99 per year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Extra Crunch members get unlimited access to 12M stock images for $99 per year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/extra-crunch-members-get-unlimited-access-to-12m-stock-images-for-99-per-year/embed/#?secret=Az7HGWdyIu" data-secret="Az7HGWdyIu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/youtube-tests-hiding-dislike-counts-on-videos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132174</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Substack confirms $65M raise, promises to &#8216;rapidly&#8217; expand its financial backing of newly independent writers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/substack-confirms-65m-raise-promises-to-rapidly-expand-its-financial-backing-of-newly-independent-writers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/substack-confirms-65m-raise-promises-to-rapidly-expand-its-financial-backing-of-newly-independent-writers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 18:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Substack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon Substack, a paid-newsletter startup, confirmed that it has raised $65 million, as initially reported by Axios. TechCrunch dug into the math behind the financing here. As anticipated, a16z led the new financing. What&#8217;s in store from the now Series B-backed company? Product work. The company wrote that it intends to &#8220;rapidly&#8221; expand its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This afternoon <a href="https://substack.com/">Substack</a>, a paid-newsletter startup, confirmed that it has raised $65 million, as initially reported <a href="https://www.axios.com/substack-andreessen-horowitz-newsletter-36cb98ea-a7b3-43b1-883a-fa45586eaad4.html">by Axios</a>. TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/">dug into the math</a> behind the financing here. As anticipated, a16z led the new financing.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s in store from the now Series B-backed company? Product work. The company <a href="https://blog.substack.com/p/investing-in-writers">wrote</a> that it intends to &#8220;rapidly&#8221; expand its Substack Pro program, which pays writers for a year to assist them in launching their own minipublication; Substack takes a larger cut of Pro user earnings during their first year, reverting to its usual split the next.</p>
<p>The Substack Pro model has <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/22338802/substack-pro-newsletter-controversy-jude-doyle">attracted controversy</a> in recent days, with some writers &#8212; both on Substack and not &#8212; criticizing the startup for opacity in whom it pays via its Pro program; some <a href="https://doyles.substack.com/p/in-queers-we-trust-all-others-pay">have argued</a> that Substack is subsidizing anti-trans writers in particular.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is motoring ahead on building out its infrastructure regardless, stating in its note that it intends to spend some of its new capital on creating &#8220;increasingly powerful subscription-publishing tools,&#8221; and &#8220;a support infrastructure for independent writers.&#8221; More tooling and more assistance could prove key to enticing more writers from their current employers &#8212; or Substack rivals &#8212; to its platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j83G5vdKaq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/">Is Substack really worth $650M?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Is Substack really worth $650M?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/embed/#?secret=j83G5vdKaq" data-secret="j83G5vdKaq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company also wrote that it plans to boost its community building and local news efforts.</p>
<p>Substack did not provide material new growth metrics, instead saying that it has &#8220;more than half a million people&#8221; paying for writers on its network; that figure is unchanged from a January figure <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-08/substack-newsletters-are-unbundling-the-news-industry">that Bloomberg reported</a>.</p>
<p>As Facebook and Twitter build out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/twitter-is-already-working-on-integrating-newsletters-on-its-site-following-revue-acquisition/">their own newsletter efforts</a>, and rival startups like <a href="https://trypico.com/">Pico</a> and <a href="https://ghost.org/">Ghost</a> offer related services, the paid-media space is a hot market today. At issue is more than the future homes for a handful of well-known writers with large audiences. The various tech companies competing in the space are each wagering that the long tail for paid writing is long, and that individuals of many profile sizes will be able to attract and hold a paid audience.</p>
<p>After what feels like decades in which online writing was devalued to commodity prices, we&#8217;re startling to find ourselves in a world where various well-financed companies are competing for our pens.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/substack-confirms-65m-raise-promises-to-rapidly-expand-its-financial-backing-of-newly-independent-writers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132107</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimus Ride partners with Polaris to commercialize electric autonomous vehicles</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/optimus-ride-partners-with-polaris-to-commercialize-electric-autonomous-vehicles/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/optimus-ride-partners-with-polaris-to-commercialize-electric-autonomous-vehicles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autonomous Vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microtransit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[optimus ride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polaris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ride hailing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Autonomous, electric mobility service provider Optimus Ride announced a partnership with powersports vehicle manufacturer Polaris to bring fully autonomous GEM electric vehicles to market. The two will introduce a new line of Polaris GEM low-speed vehicles that will be engineered to fully integrate Optimus Ride&#8217;s autonomous software and hardware suite. The microtransit vehicles are expected [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Autonomous, electric mobility service provider Optimus Ride announced a partnership with powersports vehicle manufacturer Polaris to bring fully autonomous GEM electric vehicles to market. The two will introduce a new line of Polaris GEM low-speed vehicles that will be engineered to fully integrate Optimus Ride&#8217;s autonomous software and hardware suite.</p>
<p>The microtransit vehicles are expected to come to market during the second half of 2023, when they&#8217;ll be deployed in geofenced, localized environments, such as corporate and academic campuses and mixed-use developments.</p>
<p>The Polaris GEMs aren&#8217;t the only electric autonomous vehicles on the roads. Big companies like Alphabet&#8217;s Waymo, Uber, Ford, Motional and GM subsidiary Cruise are all investing in autonomous vehicles to be used for either delivery or ride-hailing services on city streets. But Optimus Ride CEO Sean Harrington sees a market advantage in starting in a localized, geofenced environment, then, once the tech is safe and developed, expanding it outward.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div>&#8220;Microtransit is a great starting point for autonomy and it will be the place where AVs will start to penetrate,&#8221; Harrington told TechCrunch. &#8220;The concentration of short trips in a low-speed, localized environment means you can most rapidly deploy autonomous mobility solutions and deliver an exceptional experience. Whereas with a robotaxi, the technology challenge is unbounded.&#8221;</div>
<p>Optimus Ride has already deployed about 30 Polaris GEM vehicles, which have been retrofitted with Optimus Ride autonomous technology, for commercial ride-hailing operations in Brooklyn, Boston, California, Washington, D.C. and Northern Virginia, or as part of testing. There&#8217;s a testing site near its headquarters at the Boston Seaport, and there&#8217;s a closed track environment, called Union Point, in South Weymouth, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>In the near future, they&#8217;ll be continuing to expand current partnerships, like with real estate giant Brookfield Properties in Washington, D.C., as well as into new markets. Harrington specifically hinted at academic campuses as a next step.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2132133" style="width: 1991px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2132133" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2132133 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg" alt="" width="1981" height="1321" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg 1981w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/optimus-polaris-announcement-2-blank.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1981px) 100vw, 1981px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2132133" class="wp-caption-text">Polaris GEMs are deployed at the Brooklyn Navy Yard to transfer workers on a fixed microtransit route. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Optimus Ride</p></div></p>
<p>The GEMs provide visitors, residents and workers a combination of fixed route and on-demand mobility around the sites and in some cases out to regional transit hubs and neighboring areas.</p>
<p>&#8220;In D.C., at our Brookfield campus, we have the Opti Ride app that allows users to schedule rides and reserve a seat on the shuttle,&#8221; said Harrington. &#8220;Then in the Brooklyn Navy Yard, for example, we run on a fixed schedule and a fixed route.&#8221;</p>
<p>The microtransit vehicles, which drive at speeds less than 25 miles per hour, can currently seat four passengers, with a safety operator in the front row. Harrington says once they remove the steering wheel and brake pedals with the next generation of GEMs, the vehicles will accommodate six passengers.</p>
<p>Both the current set of GEMs and the next generation operate at Level 4 autonomy, which means they can operate without the need of a human operator. Despite the constraints of the geofenced environment, Harrington says the vehicles can fully interact with their environments.</p>
<p>&#8220;It has a complete perception stack leveraging lidar and computer vision, as well as situational awareness, classifying and tracking objects, full planning and motion control algorithms that allow the vehicle to safely operate within a given environment,&#8221; said Harrington. &#8220;The benefit of the geofence is that we can develop HD maps for those locations and be deterministic about everything we expect to see from a traffic standpoint. Being constrained in a specific environment means high safety and performance levels quickly, rather than an unbounded vehicle expected to operate in all conditions, anywhere.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xCHU0H7Ky3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/maas-transit-the-business-of-mobility-as-a-service/">MaaS transit: The business of mobility as a service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MaaS transit: The business of mobility as a service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/maas-transit-the-business-of-mobility-as-a-service/embed/#?secret=xCHU0H7Ky3" data-secret="xCHU0H7Ky3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/optimus-ride-partners-with-polaris-to-commercialize-electric-autonomous-vehicles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132077</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arm announces the next generation of its processor architecture</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/all-hail-armv9-arm-launches-the-next-generation-of-its-processor-architecture/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/all-hail-armv9-arm-launches-the-next-generation-of-its-processor-architecture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DSP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exynos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[image-processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nvidia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SOC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arm today announced Armv9, the next generation of its chip architecture. Its predecessor, Armv8, launched a decade ago and while it has seen its fair share of changes and updates, the new architecture brings a number of major updates to the platform that warrant a shift in version numbers. Unsurprisingly, Armv9 builds on v8 and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.arm.com/">Arm</a> today announced Armv9, the next generation of its chip architecture. Its predecessor, Armv8, launched a decade ago and while it has seen its fair share of changes and updates, the new architecture brings a number of major updates to the platform that warrant a shift in version numbers. Unsurprisingly, Armv9 builds on v8 and is backward compatible, but it specifically introduces new security, AI, signal processing and performance features.</p>
<p>Over the last five years, more than 100 billion Arm-based chips have shipped. But Arm believes that its partners will ship over 300 billion in the next decade. We will see the first Armv9-based chips in devices later this year.</p>
<p>Ian Smythe, Arm&#8217;s VP of Marketing for its client business, told me that he believes this new architecture will change the way we do computing over the next decade. &#8220;We&#8217;re going to deliver more performance, we will improve the security capabilities [ … ] and we will enhance the workload capabilities because of the shift that we see in compute that&#8217;s taking place,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The reason that we&#8217;ve taken these steps is to look at how we provide the best experience out there for handling the explosion of data and the need to process it and the need to move it and the need to protect it.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That neatly sums up the core philosophy behind these updates. On the security side, Armv9 will introduce Arm&#8217;s confidential compute architecture and the concept of Realms. These Realms enable developers to write applications where the data is shielded from the operating system and other apps on the device. Using Realms, a business application could shield sensitive data and code from the rest of the device, for example.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2132120" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2132120" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2132120" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png" alt="" width="1024" height="517" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png 1131w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png?resize=768,388 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png?resize=680,343 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/arm_future_v9.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2132120" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Arm</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re doing with the Arm Confidential Compute Architecture is worrying about the fact that all of our computing is running on the computing infrastructure of operating systems and hypervisors,&#8221; Richard Grisenthwaite, the chief architect at Arm, told me. &#8220;That code is quite complex and therefore could be penetrated if things go wrong. And it&#8217;s in an incredibly trusted position, so we&#8217;re moving some of the workloads so that [they are] running on a vastly smaller piece of code. Only the Realm manager is the thing that&#8217;s actually capable of seeing your data while it&#8217;s in action. And that would be on the order of about a 10th of the size of a normal hypervisor and much smaller still than an operating system.&#8221;</p>
<p>As Grisenthwaite noted, it took Arm a few years to work out the details of this security architecture and ensure that it is robust enough &#8212; and during that time Spectre and Meltdown appeared, too, and set back some of Arm&#8217;s initial work because some of the solutions it was working on would&#8217;ve been vulnerable to similar attacks.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2132100" style="width: 703px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-30-101359.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2132100" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2132100" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-30-101359.png" alt="" width="693" height="435" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-30-101359.png 693w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-30-101359.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-30-101359.png?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-30-101359.png?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-30-101359.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 693px) 100vw, 693px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2132100" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Arm</p></div></p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, another area the team focused on was enhancing the CPU&#8217;s AI capabilities. AI workloads are now ubiquitous. Arm had already introduced its Scalable Vector Extension (SVE) a few years ago, but at the time, this was meant for high-performance computing solutions like the Arm-powered Fugaku supercomputer.</p>
<p>Now, Arm is introducing SVE2 to enable more AI and digital signal processing (DSP) capabilities. Those can be used for image processing workloads, as well as other IoT and smart home solutions, for example. There are, of course, dedicated AI chips on the market now, but Arm believes that the entire computing stack needs to be optimized for these workloads and that there are a lot of use cases where the CPU is the right choice for them, especially for smaller workloads.</p>
<p>&#8220;We regard machine learning as appearing in just about everything. It&#8217;s going to be done in GPUs, it&#8217;s going to be done in dedicated processors, neural processors, and also done in our CPUs. And it&#8217;s really important that we make all of these different components better at doing machine learning,&#8221; Grisenthwaite said.</p>
<p>As for raw performance, Arm believes its new architecture will allow chip manufacturers to gain more than 30% in compute power over the next two chip generations, both for mobile CPUs but also the kind of infrastructure CPUs that large cloud vendors like AWS now offer their users.</p>
<p>&#8220;Arm’s next-generation Armv9 architecture offers a substantial improvement in security and machine learning, the two areas that will be further emphasized in tomorrow&#8217;s mobile communications devices,&#8221; said Min Goo Kim, the executive vice president of SoC development at Samsung Electronics. &#8220;As we work together with Arm, we expect to see the new architecture usher in a wider range of innovations to the next generation of Samsung’s Exynos mobile processors.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cdej6v3Qo2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/arm-ceo-simon-segars-discusses-ai-data-centers-getting-acquired-by-nvidia-and-more/">Arm CEO Simon Segars discusses AI, data centers, getting acquired by Nvidia and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Arm CEO Simon Segars discusses AI, data centers, getting acquired by Nvidia and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/arm-ceo-simon-segars-discusses-ai-data-centers-getting-acquired-by-nvidia-and-more/embed/#?secret=cdej6v3Qo2" data-secret="cdej6v3Qo2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/all-hail-armv9-arm-launches-the-next-generation-of-its-processor-architecture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132066</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google starts trialing its FLoC cookie alternative in Chrome</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-starts-trialling-its-floc-cookie-alternative-in-chrome/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-starts-trialling-its-floc-cookie-alternative-in-chrome/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tracking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web browsers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google today announced that it is rolling out Federated Learning of Cohorts (FLoC), a crucial part of its Privacy Sandbox project for Chrome, as a developer origin trial. FLoC is meant to be an alternative to the kind of cookies that advertising technology companies use today to track you across the web. Instead of a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google today announced that it is rolling out <a href="https://web.dev/floc/">Federated Learning of Cohorts</a> (FLoC), a crucial part of its <a href="https://www.privacysandbox.com/">Privacy Sandbox project</a> for Chrome, as a developer origin trial.</p>
<p>FLoC is meant to be an alternative to the kind of cookies that advertising technology companies use today to track you across the web. Instead of a personally identifiable cookie, FLoC runs locally and analyzes your browsing behavior to group you into a cohort of like-minded people with similar interests (and doesn&#8217;t share your browsing history with Google). That cohort is specific enough to allow advertisers to do their thing and show you relevant ads, but without being so specific as to allow marketers to identify you personally.</p>
<p>This &#8220;interest-based advertising,&#8221; as Google likes to call it, allows you to hide within the crowd of users with similar interests. All the browser displays is a cohort ID and all your browsing history and other data stay locally.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2131299" style="width: 867px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131299" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2131299" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png" alt="" width="857" height="708" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png 857w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png?resize=150,124 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png?resize=300,248 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png?resize=768,634 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png?resize=680,562 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/google_cohorts.png?resize=50,41 50w" sizes="(max-width: 857px) 100vw, 857px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131299" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The trial will start in the U.S., Australia, Brazil, Canada, India, Indonesia, Japan, Mexico, New Zealand and the Philippines. Over time, Google plans to scale it globally. As we learned earlier this month, Google is not running any tests in Europe because of <a href="https://www.adexchanger.com/platforms/google-will-not-run-floc-origin-tests-in-europe-due-to-gdpr-concerns/">concerns around GDPR</a> and other privacy regulations (in part, because it&#8217;s unclear whether FLoC IDs should be considered personal data under these regulations).</p>
<p>Users will be able to opt out from this origin trial, just like they will be able to do so with all other Privacy Sandbox trials.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, given how FLoC upends many of the existing online advertising systems in place, not everybody loves this idea. Advertisers obviously love the idea of being able to target individual users, though Google&#8217;s <a href="https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/2021-01-privacy-sandbox/">preliminary data</a> shows that using these cohorts leads to similar results for them and that advertisers can expect to see &#8220;at least 95% of the conversions per dollar spent when compared to cookie-based advertising.&#8221;</p>
<p>Google notes that its own advertising products will get the same access to FLoC IDs as its competitors in the ads ecosystem.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KfIoUclonx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/3-adtech-and-martech-vcs-see-major-opportunities-in-privacy-and-compliance/">3 adtech and martech VCs see major opportunities in privacy and compliance</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 adtech and martech VCs see major opportunities in privacy and compliance&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/3-adtech-and-martech-vcs-see-major-opportunities-in-privacy-and-compliance/embed/#?secret=KfIoUclonx" data-secret="KfIoUclonx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But it&#8217;s not just the advertising industry that is eyeing this project skeptically. Privacy advocates aren&#8217;t <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/03/googles-floc-terrible-idea">fully sold on the idea either</a>. The EFF, for example, argues that FLoC will make it easier for marketing companies that want to fingerprint users based on the various FLoC IDs they expose, for example. That&#8217;s something Google is addressing with its Privacy Budget proposal, but how well that will work remains to be seen.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, users would probably prefer to just browse the web without seeing ads (no matter what the advertising industry may want us to believe) and without having to worry about their privacy. But online publishers continue to rely on advertising income to fund their sites.</p>
<p>With all of these divergent interests, it was always clear that Google&#8217;s initiatives weren&#8217;t going to please everyone. That friction was always built into the process. And while other browser vendors can outright block ads and third-party cookies, Google&#8217;s role in the advertising ecosystem makes this a bit more complicated.</p>
<p>&#8220;When other browsers started blocking third-party cookies by default, we were excited about the direction, but worried about the immediate impact,&#8221; Marshall Vale, Google&#8217;s product manager for Privacy Sandbox, writes in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;Excited because we absolutely need a more private web, and we know third-party cookies aren&#8217;t the long-term answer. Worried because today many publishers rely on cookie-based advertising to support their content efforts, and we had seen that cookie blocking was already spawning privacy-invasive workarounds (such as fingerprinting) that were even worse for user privacy. Overall, we felt that blocking third-party cookies outright without viable alternatives for the ecosystem was irresponsible, and even harmful, to the free and open web we all enjoy.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that FLoC, as well as Google&#8217;s other privacy sandbox initiatives, are still under development. The company says the idea here is to learn from these initial trials and evolve the project accordingly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BsNp1a5TBC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/staying-ahead-of-the-curve-on-googles-core-web-vitals/">Staying ahead of the curve on Google&#8217;s Core Web Vitals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Staying ahead of the curve on Google&#8217;s Core Web Vitals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/staying-ahead-of-the-curve-on-googles-core-web-vitals/embed/#?secret=BsNp1a5TBC" data-secret="BsNp1a5TBC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-starts-trialling-its-floc-cookie-alternative-in-chrome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ballot counting for Amazon&#8217;s historic union vote starts today</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ballot-counting-for-amazons-historic-union-vote-starts-today/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ballot-counting-for-amazons-historic-union-vote-starts-today/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 17:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unionizing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132070</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vote counting begins today in the historic effort to unionize Amazon’s Bessemer, Alabama fulfillment center. The warehouse &#8212; which opened exactly a year ago to meet ramping up demand as COVID-19 bore down on the U.S. &#8212; has become ground zero for one of the most important labor efforts in modern American history. Voting began [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Vote counting begins today in the historic effort to unionize Amazon’s Bessemer, Alabama fulfillment center. The warehouse &#8212; which opened exactly a year ago to meet ramping up demand as COVID-19 bore down on the U.S. &#8212; has become ground zero for one of the most important labor efforts in modern American history.</p>
<p>Voting began by mail on February 8, after Amazon repeatedly attempted to delay the vote or force workers to submit ballots in-person, in spite of pandemic restrictions. Things have gotten predictably heated in the days and weeks leading up to yesterday’s official deadline. Though even by the standards of Amazon’s aggressive public relations strategy, thing went surprisingly far.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is extraordinary and revealing. One of the most powerful politicians in the United States just said she’s going to break up an American company so that they can’t criticize her anymore. <a href="https://t.co/Nt0wcZo17g">https://t.co/Nt0wcZo17g</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Amazon News (@amazonnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/amazonnews/status/1375529101931520007?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In particular, the e-commerce giant leveraged Twitter feeds as part of an aggressive anti-union strategy. The company simultaneously sought to bolster its image of existing working conditions while confronting progressive/leftist politicians like Vermont Senator Bernie Sanders, who played a key role in pushing the company toward the $15/hour warehouse minimum wage it now celebrates.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2021/3/28/22354604/amazon-twitter-bernie-sanders-jeff-bezos-union-alabama-elizabeth-warren">According to reports</a>, the company’s scorched-earth approach against Sanders and fellow New England Senator Elizabeth Warren were spurred on from the top. Founder Jeff Bezos &#8212; who will abdicate his CEO position later this year &#8212; was said to have encouraged the offensive. Employees at the companies were said to have flagged the offending tweets internally for suspicious activity. Those tickets were reportedly closed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8lpsW7A50s"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/amazon-goes-on-the-offensive-ahead-of-next-weeks-union-vote-counting/">Amazon goes on the offensive ahead of next week’s union vote counting</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon goes on the offensive ahead of next week’s union vote counting&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/amazon-goes-on-the-offensive-ahead-of-next-weeks-union-vote-counting/embed/#?secret=8lpsW7A50s" data-secret="8lpsW7A50s" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>After antagonist tweets and denying widespread and longstanding reports about Amazon workers peeing in bottles over fears of falling behind on quotas, the Amazon News Twitter reverted to a more positive approach. It has however, continued activity around the vote, including <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/30/amazon-loses-effort-to-install-camera-to-watch-ballot-box-in-union-vote.html">a bid to install video cameras</a> for monitoring boxes carrying ballots &#8212; a bid the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) has since rejected.</p>
<p>While the vote counting kicks off today, don’t expect immediate results. The process is a methodical and deliberate one. Among other things, there are processes in place for either side to object. It’s clear from Amazon’s recent behavior that the company is well aware that this is far more consequential than the 6,000 or so workers currently employed by the Bessemer location. If the company prevails, it will position the decision as validation of its working conditions. If workers vote to unionize, meanwhile, this could well start a chain reaction across the company.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2130857" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2130857" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2130857" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg" alt="A truck passes as Congressional delegates visit the Amazon Fulfillment Center after meeting with workers and organizers involved in the Amazon BHM1 facility unionization effort" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg 1581w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GettyImages-1231538431.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2130857" class="wp-caption-text">BIRMINGHAM, AL &#8211; MARCH 05: A truck passes as Congressional delegates visit the Amazon Fulfillment Center after meeting with workers and organizers involved in the Amazon BHM1 facility unionization effort, represented by the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union on March 5, 2021 in Birmingham, Alabama. Workers at Amazon facility currently make $15 an hour, however they feel that their requests for less strict work mandates are not being heard by management. (Photo by Megan Varner/Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>This week, workers at Amazon’s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-germany-strike-idUSKBN2BK0GU">Germany facilities are going on strike</a> for four days, following a similar move in Italy last week.</p>
<p>“It’s not just workers in Alabama, it’s workers everywhere who are saying to Jeff Bezos that enough is enough. No matter what language they speak, Amazon workers around the globe will not stand for the working conditions they’ve been forced to endure for too long,” Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU) President Stuart Applebaum said in a statement.</p>
<p>The NLRB oversees the vote counting. If workers vote to unionize, Bessemer workers will join the RWDSU. The organization has also seen its share of pushback from Amazon. As the company told TechCrunch last week:</p>
<blockquote><p>Stuart Appelbaum, Chief Disinformation Officer of RWDSU, in an attempt to save his long declining union, is taking alternative facts to a whole new level. But our employees are smart and know the truth—starting wages of $15 or more, health care from day one, and a safe and inclusive workplace. We encourage all of our employees to vote.</p></blockquote>
<p>Ballots have been sent to the NLRB’s Birmingham offices. There are a number of grounds on which either side can contest the results. These include everything from signatures to whether the person who cast a vote is, in fact, an eligible employee of Amazon. Even after votes are counted, things are likely to drag on. Court battles seem a likely outcome, moving forward. From there, things could ultimately stretch on for weeks or months.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7BpuGeRs06"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/the-future-of-gig-work-could-involve-unions-and-co-ops/">The future of gig work could involve unions and co-ops</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The future of gig work could involve unions and co-ops&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/the-future-of-gig-work-could-involve-unions-and-co-ops/embed/#?secret=7BpuGeRs06" data-secret="7BpuGeRs06" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The battle is a high stakes one that has made unusual political allies from opposite sides of the aisle. There aren’t too many events that have united politicians ranging from Marco Rubio on one side and Sanders, Warren and Joe Biden on the other. That goes double for something as traditionally divisive as labor unions.</p>
<p>“This campaign has already been a victory in many ways,” Appelbaum said in a statement issued late last week. “Even though we don’t know how the vote will turn out, we believe we have opened the door to more organizing around the country.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dtdaXXB2Fo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/07/amazon-warehouse-workers-begin-historic-vote-to-unionize/">Amazon warehouse workers to begin historic vote to unionize</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon warehouse workers to begin historic vote to unionize&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/07/amazon-warehouse-workers-begin-historic-vote-to-unionize/embed/#?secret=dtdaXXB2Fo" data-secret="dtdaXXB2Fo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ballot-counting-for-amazons-historic-union-vote-starts-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132070</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ConsenSys launches a more energy-efficient NFT ecosystem with a project from artist Damien Hirst as its first drop</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/consenysys-launches-a-more-energy-efficient-nft-ecosystem-with-a-project-from-artist-damien-hirst-as-its-first-drop/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/consenysys-launches-a-more-energy-efficient-nft-ecosystem-with-a-project-from-artist-damien-hirst-as-its-first-drop/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consensys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseph lubin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national basketball association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The NFT craze has been an intriguing moment for digital artists who have seen great leaps in how tech has allowed them to create their work, but not as much progress in shifting how they profit off of it. Though crypto&#8217;s early adopter artists have seemed to gain the most attention thus far, more institutionally [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The NFT craze has been an intriguing moment for digital artists who have seen great leaps in how tech has allowed them to create their work, but not as much progress in shifting how they profit off of it.</p>
<p>Though crypto&#8217;s early adopter artists have seemed to gain the most attention thus far, more institutionally present artists are dipping their feet into the token world. One of the bigger barriers has been the environmental concerns tied to the Ethereum blockchain, which required intense energy usage to mint new artwork, tied to incredibly high transaction fees, something that has invited controversy for early artists because of climate change concerns.</p>
<p>There have been a number of blockchain products to emerge in recent months that promise the benefits of Ethereum with greater speed, lower costs and lower energy usage, most notably Dapper Labs&#8217; Flow blockchain, which powers their NBA Top Shot product. Today, we saw the debut of a new &#8220;layer-two&#8221; entrant from <a href="https://consensys.net/">ConsenSys</a>, called Palm, which operates as a sidechain on Ethereum&#8217;s main network but will be supported via the popular crypto wallet MetaMask.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As part of Palm&#8217;s launch, the artist Damien Hirst announced he will be launching an NFT project, his first, called &#8220;The Currency Project,&#8221; on the platform&#8217;s <a href="https://palm.io/">Palm NFT Studio</a>.</p>
<p>Ethereum has already committed to transitioning to a more energy-efficient proof-of-stake consensus structure, but it&#8217;s unclear how quickly that&#8217;s going to happen. The network currently relies on a proof-of-work system (as does bitcoin), which use an energy-intensive manner of prioritizing where the next block in a chain is mined that gets more intensive as a network sees more traffic. It&#8217;s a reason why crypto mining operations have had to consistently invest in the latest hardware to maintain an edge and use more power. Proof-of-work does away with most of that, instead choosing nodes on the network to mine the next block based on reputation or their existing stake. There are some real security tradeoffs that have required workarounds though plenty in the crypto community aren&#8217;t quite satisfied with the compromises, though proponents argue that environmental concerns should take precedent.</p>
<p>In a press release, the team behind Palm says the ecosystem is &#8220;99% more energy-efficient than proof-of-work systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>Unlike Dapper Labs&#8217; Flow, Palm benefits from its interconnectedness with the community of Ethereum developers, something that was present in today&#8217;s announcement that showcased several industry partnerships including Nifty. The news arrived alongside details this morning of Dapper Labs&#8217; monster $305 million fundraise that will give the company backing to build on the momentum of Top Shot, which has given the broader NFT space the wave of enthusiasm it&#8217;s currently experiencing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZG5GmxRWwo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/">The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/embed/#?secret=ZG5GmxRWwo" data-secret="ZG5GmxRWwo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Yv24TYvz72"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nba-top-shot-maker-dapper-labs-is-now-worth-2-6-billion-thanks-to-half-of-hollywood-the-nba-and-michael-jordan/">NBA Top Shot maker Dapper Labs is now worth $2.6 billion thanks to half of Hollywood, the NBA, and Michael Jordan</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NBA Top Shot maker Dapper Labs is now worth $2.6 billion thanks to half of Hollywood, the NBA, and Michael Jordan&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/nba-top-shot-maker-dapper-labs-is-now-worth-2-6-billion-thanks-to-half-of-hollywood-the-nba-and-michael-jordan/embed/#?secret=Yv24TYvz72" data-secret="Yv24TYvz72" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/consenysys-launches-a-more-energy-efficient-nft-ecosystem-with-a-project-from-artist-damien-hirst-as-its-first-drop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132046</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s Area 120 launches Stack, an app that digitizes personal docs and extracts key information</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-launches-stack-an-app-that-digitizes-personal-docs-and-extracts-key-information/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-launches-stack-an-app-that-digitizes-personal-docs-and-extracts-key-information/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Area 120]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ocr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google&#8217;s in-house incubator, Area 120, is today releasing its latest project called Stack, an app that will help you digitize your documents, receipts and other papers you have lying around the house, and then automatically save them to Google Drive. The app will also helpfully suggest a name for your scans and the right category [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google&#8217;s in-house incubator, Area 120, is today releasing its latest project called <a href="https://stack.area120.com/">Stack</a>, an app that will help you digitize your documents, receipts and other papers you have lying around the house, and then automatically save them to Google Drive. The app will also helpfully suggest a name for your scans and the right category &#8212; or &#8220;stack,&#8221; as it&#8217;s called.</p>
<p>At launch, Stack can handle scanning a range of differently sized documents &#8212; like bills, shopping receipts or even IDs &#8212; which are then turned into PDFs and organized, while important information from within the file is detailed using AI technology.</p>
<p>The idea for Stack comes from <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedregal/">Christopher Pedregal</a>, who previously co-founded the edtech startup Socratic, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/16/google-discloses-its-acquisition-of-mobile-learning-app-socratic-as-it-relaunches-on-ios/">acquired by Google back in 2018. </a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Pedregal notes that, at Socratic, they had taken advantage of Google&#8217;s computer vision and language understanding technologies to make learning easier for high school students. While at Google, he began to think about how those same technologies could be put to work for better organizing documents. To experiment with the idea, he teamed up with Matthew Cowan. The two first worked together on <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/ai-machine-learning/google-cloud-announces-document-ai-platform">DocAI</a>, a team in Google Cloud that was developing AI technology that could analyze billions of documents.</p>
<p>They realized that they could also apply DocAI&#8217;s enterprise technology to users&#8217; personal documents, which led to the creation of Stack.</p>
<p>With the Stack app, initially available for Android, users can take a photo of a document and the app will automatically name it and &#8220;stack&#8221; it into the correct category &#8212; like Bills, Banking, House, IDs, Immigration, Insurance, Legal, Medical, Pet, Receipts, Tax, Travel, Vehicles and Work.</p>
<p>Users can add multiple pages when scanning a document, and Stack will OCR all the pages in a document, so that the full text of the document is searchable. Users can also star their most important scans for quicker access.</p>
<p>While the ability to quickly digitize documents by photographing them isn&#8217;t new &#8212; Microsoft has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/02/microsoft-debuts-office-lens-a-document-scanning-app-for-ios-and-android/">offered Office Lens</a> for years, for example &#8212;  Stack will also be able to identify key information from within the documents, like the &#8220;due date&#8221; on a bill, the &#8220;total amount due&#8221; or &#8220;account number.&#8221; It can then pull that info out to make it easier to find later on.</p>
<p>The app additionally allows users to search through the full text of the documents, not just the title, to find information they need. To keep the items protected, Stack&#8217;s documents can be secured by either your fingerprint or face scan, similar to how <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246465/google-drive-privacy-screen-face-touch-id-apple-now-available">Google Drive works</a> today. And Drive users can have all their scans automatically synced over to Google Drive.</p>
<p>Google says the app is currently available on Android, as a free download with no in-app purchases. Based on user feedback, Google will decide whether to bring Stack to more platforms, like iOS.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XxUhzr2Cko"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/to-solve-all-the-small-things-look-to-everyday-little-ai/">To solve all the small things, look to everyday Little AI</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To solve all the small things, look to everyday Little AI&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/to-solve-all-the-small-things-look-to-everyday-little-ai/embed/#?secret=XxUhzr2Cko" data-secret="XxUhzr2Cko" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-launches-stack-an-app-that-digitizes-personal-docs-and-extracts-key-information/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Volkswagen really is becoming &#8216;Voltswagen&#8217; in the US [UPDATE: Bad April Fool&#8217;s joke from VW]</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/volkswagen-really-is-becoming-voltswagen-in-the-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/volkswagen-really-is-becoming-voltswagen-in-the-u-s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EVs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volkswagen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volkswagen Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vw]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UPDATE: Per the Wall Street Journal, this is actually not happening and was instead an April Fool&#8217;s joke gone wrong. VW USA still has not responded to requests for comment, but VW Europe told the publication that it was in fact a joke. The release announcing the news remains live on VW&#8217;s official U.S. media [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Per the Wall Street Journal, this is actually not happening and was instead an April Fool&#8217;s joke gone wrong. VW USA still has not responded to requests for comment, but VW Europe told the publication that it was in fact a joke. The release announcing the news remains live on VW&#8217;s official U.S. media site with no indication that it&#8217;s not in fact true. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-volkswagen-name-idUSKBN2BM2YJ">Reuters is now reporting the same, citing three unnamed sources</a>.]</em></p>
<p>Automaker Volkswagen wants you to know it&#8217;s serious about electric vehicles — so serious, in fact, that it&#8217;s officially rebranding around a pun in the U.S. The company revealed in a press release that it&#8217;s changing its name from &#8220;Volkswagen of America&#8221; to &#8220;Voltswagen of America&#8221; in <a href="https://media.vw.com/en-us/releases/1499#images">a press release today</a>. News this could happen leaked late Monday, but many speculated it might be an April Fool&#8217;s joke that got out a bit early, but the automaker seems serious about switching the official brand from May 2021 onward given the official release on its newsroom.</p>
<p>Voltswagen (neé Volkswagen) says that the reason behind the change is to firmly demonstrate its commitment to &#8220;future-forward investment in e-mobility,&#8221; which said more simply, implies that it&#8217;s super serious about its electric drivetrain plans. In a more literal sense, &#8216;Volkswagen&#8217; is actually from the German for &#8220;the people&#8217;s car,&#8221; which suggests that Voltswagen is a car for … volts?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sort of, but not really, says VW (hey that still works!):</p>
<p>&#8220;We have said, from the beginning of our shift to an electric future, that we will build EVs for the millions, not just millionaires,&#8221; explained VW CEO and President Scott Keogh in the release announcing the swap. &#8220;This name change signifies a nod to our past as the peoples’ car and our firm belief that our future is in being the peoples’ electric car.”</p>
<p>This announcement comes just as Volkswagen has begun shipping its all-electric SUV, the ID.4, in the U.S. It ha a price tag of $33,995, before either federal and tax incentives, so that is indeed on the more affordable side of the existing U.S. electric vehicle market, with even more options set to come for cost-conscious consumers in the future as the company spurs its commitments of lowering emissions by achieving one million global EV sales by 2025, and playing host to a lineup of over 70 models across VW and its sub-brands worldwide by 2029.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3vso7kfIgR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/the-2021-volkswagen-id-4-ticks-all-the-boxes-except-one/">The 2021 Volkswagen ID. 4 ticks all the boxes, except one</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The 2021 Volkswagen ID. 4 ticks all the boxes, except one&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/the-2021-volkswagen-id-4-ticks-all-the-boxes-except-one/embed/#?secret=3vso7kfIgR" data-secret="3vso7kfIgR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Voltswagen branding will include use of a higher blue tone on the VW logo for all-electric vehicles, while gas cars will retain the more traditional dark blue look. The actual word &#8220;Voltswagen&#8221; will be used on EVs in addition to the initials logo, with the icon graphic itself will be the sole branding on gas cars in the U.S. going forward.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/volkswagen-really-is-becoming-voltswagen-in-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132007</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HighRadius raises $300M, triples valuation to $3.1B for AI-powered fintech software</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/highradius-raises-300m-triples-valuation-to-3-1b-for-ai-powered-fintech-software/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/highradius-raises-300m-triples-valuation-to-3-1b-for-ai-powered-fintech-software/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HighRadius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2132028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HighRadius, which has developed AI-powered fintech software, announced Tuesday it has raised $300 million in a Series C funding round led by D1 Capital and Tiger Global. The round values Houston-based HighRadius at $3.1 billion, triple its valuation of “more than $1 billion” at the time of its $125 million Series B in January of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HighRadius</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has developed AI-powered fintech software, announced Tuesday it has raised $300 million in a Series C funding round led by D1 Capital and Tiger Global.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round values Houston-based HighRadius at $3.1 billion, triple its valuation of “more than $1 billion” at the time of its $125 million Series B in January of 2020. With this latest financing, HighRadius has raised $475 million in funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Existing backers ICONIQ Growth and Susquehanna Growth Equity also participated in the round along with a slew of high-profile CEOs, including Snowflake Chairman and CEO Frank Slootman; Snowflake CFO Michael Scarpelli; Procore Technologies CEO Tooey Courtemanche and Airtable co-founder and CEO Howie Liu.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">HighRadius said it will use the new capital “to fuel product innovation and expand global go-to-market reach.”</span></p>
<p>At the beginning of 2020, HighRadius had more than 400 customers, including over 200 of the Forbes Global 2000 such as Walmart, Nike and Procter &amp; Gamble, and claimed to process more than $1 trillion in transactions per year.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the HighRadius platforms for order-to-cash and treasury management help more than 600 clients, including more than 200 of the Forbes Global 2000, &#8220;optimize their working capital.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2006, HighRadius may not technically be a “startup” in the literal sense of the word. It has, however, notably only taken external capital in recent years. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company describes itself as a “SaaS provider for integrated receivables, such as credit, cash application, EIPP, collections, deductions, and payments.” In other words, the platform aims to automate routing receivables and payments processes (such as predicting invoice payment dates, for example) across a variety of functions via AI and machine learning. Its white-labeled software is integrated into its partners’ offerings.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">John Curtius, partner at Tiger Global Management, said HighRadius is &#8220;in the opening innings of defining the next big software market for the Office of the CFO.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HYuPsjRbiX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/ai-fintech-products-are-operating-at-scale-and-investor-interest-is-maturing/">AI fintech products are operating at scale and investor interest is maturing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AI fintech products are operating at scale and investor interest is maturing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/ai-fintech-products-are-operating-at-scale-and-investor-interest-is-maturing/embed/#?secret=HYuPsjRbiX" data-secret="HYuPsjRbiX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/highradius-raises-300m-triples-valuation-to-3-1b-for-ai-powered-fintech-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2132028</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Duo goes passwordless</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/duo-goes-passwordless/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/duo-goes-passwordless/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Access Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authentication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multi-factor authentication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security token]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[svp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work Applications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Duo, the authentication service Cisco acquired for $2.35 billion in 2018, today announced its plans to launch a passwordless authentication service that will allow users to log in to their Duo-protected services through security keys or platform biometrics like Apple&#8217;s Face ID or Microsoft&#8217;s Windows Hello. The infrastructure-agnostic service will go into public preview in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://duo.com/">Duo</a>, the authentication service Cisco <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/16/ciscos-2-35-billion-duo-acquisition-front-and-center-at-earnings-call/">acquired for $2.35 billion in 2018</a>, today <a href="https://duo.com/blog/duos-passwordless-authentication-is-coming">announced</a> its plans to launch a <a href="https://duo.com/duo-presents-passwordless">passwordless authentication service</a> that will allow users to log in to their Duo-protected services through security keys or platform biometrics like Apple&#8217;s Face ID or Microsoft&#8217;s Windows Hello. The infrastructure-agnostic service will go into public preview in the summer.</p>
<p>&#8220;Cisco has strived to develop passwordless authentication that meets the needs of a diverse and evolving workforce and allows the broadest set of enterprises to securely progress toward a passwordless future, regardless of their IT stack,&#8221; said Gee Rittenhouse, SVP and GM of Cisco’s Security Business Group. &#8220;It’s not an overstatement to say that passwordless authentication will have the most meaningful global impact on how users access data by making the easiest path the most secure.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re using Duo or a similar product today, chances are that you are using both passwords and a second factor to log into your work applications. But users are notoriously bad about their password hygiene &#8212; and to the despair of any IT department, they also keep forgetting them.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the standard two-factor authentication scheme, the second factor is basically an extra moat around your password. Passwordless is essentially another form of two-factor authentication, but instead of passwords, it relies on cryptographic key pairs, be that with the help of a hardware security key or biometric authentication.</p>
<p>Duo&#8217;s passwordless service relies on the <a href="http://webauthn.guide/">Web Authentication standard,</a> which ensures that your data is stored locally and not on a centralized server, too.</p>
<p>According to Duo&#8217;s <a href="https://duo.com/resources/ebooks/the-2020-duo-trusted-access-report">own data</a>, we have now reached a point where the hardware is ready for passwordless, with 80% of mobile devices now offering support for biometrics.</p>
<p>&#8220;Passwordless is a journey requiring incremental changes in users and IT environments alike, not something enterprises can enable overnight,&#8221; said Wolfgang Goerlich, advisory chief information s<span class="il">ecurity</span> officer, <span class="il">Duo</span> s<span class="il">ecurity</span> at Cisco. &#8220;<span class="il">Duo</span> can help enterprises transition their environments and workforces securely and minimize user friction while simultaneously increasing trust in every authentication.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1irW2Wdxx1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/13/why-blaming-the-intern-wont-save-startups-from-cybersecurity-liability/">Why &#8216;blaming the intern&#8217; won&#8217;t save startups from cybersecurity liability</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why &#8216;blaming the intern&#8217; won&#8217;t save startups from cybersecurity liability&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/13/why-blaming-the-intern-wont-save-startups-from-cybersecurity-liability/embed/#?secret=1irW2Wdxx1" data-secret="1irW2Wdxx1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RPOcDa94Rb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/16/ciscos-2-35-billion-duo-acquisition-front-and-center-at-earnings-call/">Cisco&#8217;s $2.35 billion Duo acquisition front and center at earnings call</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cisco&#8217;s $2.35 billion Duo acquisition front and center at earnings call&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/16/ciscos-2-35-billion-duo-acquisition-front-and-center-at-earnings-call/embed/#?secret=RPOcDa94Rb" data-secret="RPOcDa94Rb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/duo-goes-passwordless/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tonal EC-1</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 15:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tonal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back in the halcyon days of 2019, we piloted a new format for Extra Crunch we dubbed the EC-1. Modeled after the Form S-1 filing that late-stage startups submit to the SEC as part of the IPO process, EC-1s are authoritative, deep analyses into growth-stage startups. We profiled and analyzed a number of companies like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Back in the halcyon days of 2019, we piloted a new format for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/">Extra Crunch</a> we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ec1/">dubbed the EC-1</a>. Modeled after the Form S-1 filing that late-stage startups submit to the SEC as part of the IPO process, EC-1s are authoritative, deep analyses into growth-stage startups. We profiled and analyzed a number of companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/patreon-ec-1/">Patreon</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/the-niantic-ec-1/">Niantic</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/11/roblox-ec1/">Roblox</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/09/kobalt-ec1/">Kobalt</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/17/how-unity-built-the-worlds-most-popular-game-engine/">Unity</a>, looking at everything from their product design, to their customer relations, to their events strategy and to the changing economics of music licensing.</p>
<p>They were very popular and we had huge ambitions for the series, but then 2020 hit, COVID-19 swept in, and suddenly our ability to travel and meet with a dozen executives in-person at a company was curtailed — there was also just a wee bit of breaking news to cover as well! We didn’t want to cut back on quality, so we bided our time.</p>
<p>Well, with some level of normality finally kicking in, we’re excited to restart this series in 2021. We have nearly 10 EC-1s in the works right now, and I am excited to introduce our first EC-1 profile of this new batch — a company that has truly skyrocketed amidst that dark pandemic year.</p>
<p><b>Tonal</b> is a unique entrant in the upscale fitness market, using a proprietary blend of hardware, software and content to bring comprehensive strength training to the home in as small and efficient of a package as possible. Sales have zoomed the past year as gyms shut down worldwide, and the company has been pelted by interest from both customers and investors.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2132021" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2132021" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2132021" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dylan_standing_incline_chest_press.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dylan_standing_incline_chest_press.png 1350w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dylan_standing_incline_chest_press.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dylan_standing_incline_chest_press.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dylan_standing_incline_chest_press.png?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dylan_standing_incline_chest_press.png?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Dylan_standing_incline_chest_press.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2132021" class="wp-caption-text">Tonal Device. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tonal</p></div></p>
<p>That success today, though, occludes a lengthy process of iteration over years against the droning negativity of most VCs who never expected a corporate enterprise infrastructure founder to be capable of building a popular consumer hardware device. Tonal is not just a story of willpower, but also an example of how much effort it takes to build a major startup, from product design and launch strategy to careful marketing and building the moats to protect itself from competition in a ferocious market.</p>
<p>TechCrunch’s writer and analyst for this EC-1 is <b>JP Mangalindan</b>. Mangalindan has been covering technology for years now, previously serving as chief tech correspondent for our corporate sister site Yahoo Finance and also publishing across a plethora of other tech publications. He brings a wealth of insight not just into startups and Tonal, but the wider fitness market as well. The lead editor for this package was <b>Danny Crichton</b>, the copy editor was <b>Richard Dal Porto</b> and illustrations were created by <b>Nigel Sussman</b>.</p>
<p><i>Tonal had no say in the content of this analysis and did not get advance access to it. Mangalindan has no financial ties to Tonal or other conflicts of interest to disclose.</i></p>
<p>The Tonal EC-1 comprises four main articles representing about 10,600 words and a reading time of about 43 minutes. Let’s get started:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Part 1: Origin Story</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/">How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech</a>” (3,200 words/13 minutes) — We start with the history of Tonal, the multiyear effort to raise VC funds and iterate on a product while reinventing the definition of strength-training equipment.</li>
<li><b>Part 2: Product launch</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-launch/">Millions of dollars and 3.5 years, and it all came down to this</a>” (2,800 words/11 minutes) — Explores the tradeoffs and tactics Tonal used to launch its product, a launch that as a hardware company, it couldn’t afford to mess up.</li>
<li><b>Part 3: Community building</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-community/">Building online communities for fun, profit and product</a>” (2,200 words/9 minutes) — Analyzes Tonal’s early forays into community building and how it uses community to improve its products while also retaining customers for its critical subscription business.</li>
<li><b>Part 4: Competitive landscape and future</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-future/">Can Tonal become the luxury fitness market champion?</a>” (2,400 words/10 minutes) — Evaluates the keen competition confronting Tonal in this market and analyzes the company’s next steps to continue its successful growth.</li>
</ul>
<p>We’re always iterating on the EC-1 format. If you have questions, comments or ideas, please send an email to TechCrunch Managing Editor Danny Crichton at <a href="mailto:danny@techcrunch.com">danny@techcrunch.com</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uD9J7B7up6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/">How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How a homegrown experiment became one of the fastest-growing companies in fitness tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1-origin/embed/#?secret=uD9J7B7up6" data-secret="uD9J7B7up6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tonal-ec1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131243</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
