<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 02:55:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>SaaS Labs raises $42 million for its business automation platform, acquires CallPage and Atolia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/saas-labs-raises-42-million-for-its-business-automation-platform-acquires-callpage-and-atolia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/saas-labs-raises-42-million-for-its-business-automation-platform-acquires-callpage-and-atolia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 02:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SaaS Labs has raised $42 million in a new financing round, less than three months after closing its previous funding, and acquired two startups as it looks to aggressively grow its automation platform that serves sales and support teams at small and medium-sized businesses. Sequoia Capital India led SaaS Labs’ Series B round. Base 10 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SaaS Labs has raised $42 million in a new financing round, less than three months after closing its previous funding, and acquired two startups as it looks to aggressively grow its automation platform that serves sales and support teams at small and medium-sized businesses.</p>
<p>Sequoia Capital India led SaaS Labs’ Series B round. Base 10 Partners and Eight Roads Ventures, two existing backers, as well as entrepreneurs Anand Chandrasekaran, Allison Pickens, Michael Stoppelman, and Amit Agarwal participated in the round. The new funding follows California and Noida-headquartered startup&#8217;s $18 million Series A raise in October.</p>
<p>For big businesses and enterprises, scores of tools exist to bring more efficiency in their sales and support operations. But the same isn’t true of small and medium-sized businesses. That was the learning Gaurav Sharma walked away with at his previous venture, called HelloSociety, in the US. (The firm was acquired by The New York Times.)</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259866" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“SMBs are very underloved and underserved if you look at the software offerings they have at their fingertips,” he told TechCrunch in an interview. Enterprises, in comparison, “have access to awesome tools to improve the productivity of their agents,” he said.</p>
<p>For the last six years, <a href="https://www.saaslabs.co">SaaS Labs</a> has been building AI-powered tools that are “equally powerful” to empower sales and support teams at smaller firms. These offerings are no-code solutions, removing the need of having an IT team to deploy it.</p>
<p>“These tools are also very affordable and integrate seamlessly with other business stacks and on-premise hardware solutions that small businesses rely on,” he said.</p>
<p>The challenge over 15 million sales and support agents face today is that they have to manually update their call logs and CRM tools that are not designed to offer real-time updates to their managers. This creates a gap in their communication channels, where no intervention can happen in real-time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2259868" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259868" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2259868 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/justcall-offering.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="630" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/justcall-offering.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/justcall-offering.jpg?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/justcall-offering.jpg?resize=300,189 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/justcall-offering.jpg?resize=768,484 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/justcall-offering.jpg?resize=680,428 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/justcall-offering.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259868" class="wp-caption-text">Dashboard of JustCall, a SaaS Labs offering that allows SMBs to set up a cloud-based contact center for sales or support teams within minutes. (Image credits: SaaS Labs)</p></div></p>
<p>“Chaos starts happening when you’ve a five-person team that is doing customer communication. So these teams can use our offering called JustCall.io, for instance, which integrates with over 100 other business tools. JustCall, which has a database of over 100 million calls to work through, uses machine learning to access the quality of the calls and whether the playbook or workflow is being followed. Managers then can only looks at the calls that have been poorly graded instead of trying to sift through every call,” he said.</p>
<p>The startup has amassed over 6,000 customers globally. It typically sees a small business join the platform by paying as little as $25 a month and overtime happily move to paying tens of thousands of dollars annually as their businesses grow.</p>
<p>Over 70% of these customers are based in the U.S. today, and 10% in the UK. Some of its customers include Grab, GoStudent, Booksy, HelloFresh.</p>
<p>The startup, which has been profitable for years, said it grew its revenue by 2.5 times last year.</p>
<p>On Thursday, it also announced two acquisitions – Poland-based CallPage, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/31/callpage-lets-you-call-your-website-visitors/">callback automation tool for sales teams</a> to connect with their leads instantly, and France-based Atolia, a productivity and collaboration tool. (Their teams will join Saas Labs as full-time employees.) Sharma said these acquisitions are helping SaaS Labs broaden its product offerings and also deepen its footprints in various markets.</p>
<p>A portion of the new funds will be deployed to acquire many more startups, said Sharma.</p>
<p>“While we are well-capitalized, this round gives us the firepower needed to double down on what&#8217;s working, hire great talent globally, launch innovative products, focus on brand marketing and get aggressive with strategic M&amp;As. As SMBs continue to adopt software to modernize different functions like sales, support, and marketing, etc. within their business, we are confident that SaaS Labs will be able to capture that opportunity and grow 30x in the coming 5-7 years.”</p>
<p>He is looking to take SaaS Labs public within the next four to five years, he said.</p>
<p>“SaaS Labs is building a multi-channel customer communication platform for small and medium businesses. Through a suite of products, it offers an experience that marries the efficiency of digital and the intimacy of offline communication channels,” said Tejashwi Sharma, MD at Sequoia Capital India, in a statement.</p>
<p>“Its flagship product JustCall, for example, has been able to drive deep impact. Customers, on average, reported time savings of 12 hours a week per agent on manual tasks while customer satisfaction improved by 30%. Sequoia Capital India is thrilled to partner with Gaurav and the team as they build the future of customer communication,” he added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/saas-labs-raises-42-million-for-its-business-automation-platform-acquires-callpage-and-atolia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259866</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YC alum Dropee, a Malaysia B2B wholesale platform, lands $7M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/yc-alum-dropee-a-malaysia-b2b-wholesale-platform-lands-7m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/yc-alum-dropee-a-malaysia-b2b-wholesale-platform-lands-7m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 02:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B2B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dropee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wholesale]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another startup focused on SMEs in Southeast Asia has announced a funding round. Dropee, a Malaysia-based B2B wholesale platform that also offers financial services, like working capital loans, to SMEs, said today it has closed a Series A round totaling $7 million. The Y Combinator alum raised $3 million in equity and $4 million in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Another startup focused on SMEs in Southeast Asia has announced a funding round. <a href="https://www.dropee.com/">Dropee</a>, a Malaysia-based B2B wholesale platform that also offers financial services, like working capital loans, to SMEs, said today it has closed a Series A round totaling $7 million. The <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/dropee">Y Combinator alum</a> raised $3 million in equity and $4 million in debt, led by returning investor Vynn Capital. Other participants included HCL Capital, Resolution Venture and LKF Capital, along with returning investors Brama One Ventures.</p>
<p>Operational in Malaysia, Singapore and Indonesia, Dropee plans to introduce new financing products for wholesalers and retailers over the next 12 months by working with strategic partners, including regional banks and non-banking financial institutions. It has now raised a total of $8.7 million.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HN2jS5n4Wm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/jakarta-based-sme-financial-platform-koinworks-scoops-up-108m-series-c/">Jakarta-based SME financial platform KoinWorks scoops up $108M Series C</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259283" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jakarta-based SME financial platform KoinWorks scoops up $108M Series C&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/jakarta-based-sme-financial-platform-koinworks-scoops-up-108m-series-c/embed/#?secret=HN2jS5n4Wm" data-secret="HN2jS5n4Wm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Launched 5 years ago, Dropee focuses primarily on food and beverages and fast-moving consumer goods. The startup says it is used by over 80,000 SMEs, mainly small retail stores, to buy wholesale inventory through its marketplace, and now totals more than $100 million in annualized transaction value. Its marketplace is integrated with a SaaS e-commerce platform that automates payment collection, tracks orders and sales and manages offline-to-online orders.</p>
<p>Lennise Ng, CEO of Dropee, said the startup was created because she and one of her co-founders came “from family businesses that are involved in B2B trading on fast-moving consumer goods products for over two generations.” That gave them a close-up look at inefficiencies in the wholesale trading space across Southeast Asia. Dropee was created to make the process more efficient.</p>
<p>For example, the platform makes product recommendations through its AI-based smart catalog: each B2B consumer sees a personalized selection of best-selling goods, complementary products and campaigns based on their business needs. SMEs can also order directly from its wholesale marketplace or an assigned sales agent, allowing wholesalers real-time transparency and allowing orders to process more quickly.</p>
<p>Dropee began offering financial products in November 2020, including up to 60 days credit financing for invoices and supply chain. “It can be challenging for traditional wholesalers to extend longer credit terms to SMEs, especially during the pandemic,” Ng said. She added that credit financing for retailers helps increase the number of immediate inventory purchases. To gauge creditworthiness and loan terms, Dropee uses multiple variables captured through its platform, including an SME’s transaction data to lifetime value per business network.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new round of financing will be used to expand Dropee’s supply chain financing, with plans to work with more brands and wholesalers across Southeast Asia to extend credit term payments for SME retailers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Vq6yzUwftC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/southeast-asian-startups-to-watch-in-2022/">Southeast Asian startups to watch in 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Southeast Asian startups to watch in 2022&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/southeast-asian-startups-to-watch-in-2022/embed/#?secret=Vq6yzUwftC" data-secret="Vq6yzUwftC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/yc-alum-dropee-a-malaysia-b2b-wholesale-platform-lands-7m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259283</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Play Games for PC, which brings Android games to Windows, enters beta testing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/google-play-games-for-pc-which-brings-android-games-to-windows-enters-beta-testing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/google-play-games-for-pc-which-brings-android-games-to-windows-enters-beta-testing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google today will begin rolling out a limited beta test of its newly announced Google Play Games for PC product in three overseas markets: Hong Kong, South Korea, and Taiwan. The Google Play Games PC application, which was announced last month during The Game Awards event, allows people to play Google Play games on Windows [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google today will begin rolling out a limited beta test of its newly <a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/12/09/google-play-games-windows/">announced</a> Google Play Games for PC product in three overseas markets: Hong Kong, South Korea, and Taiwan. The Google Play Games PC application, which was announced last month during <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OS4m2O3V93o">The Game Awards event</a>, allows people to play Google Play games on Windows PCs, in addition to currently supported platforms like mobile, tablet and ChromeOS. The new PC support will include both laptops and desktops, Google said, and players will be able to pick up from where they left off when switching from another device, like their Android phone, over to their computer.</p>
<p>The company had previously announced the first markets to gain access to the PC app, which was expected to arrive in early 2022. However, an exact date had not yet been given.</p>
<p>After gaining access to the beta, testers will be able to try out popular mobile games like &#8220;Mobile Legends: Bang Bang,&#8221; &#8220;Summoners War,&#8221; &#8220;State of Survival: The Joker Collaboration,&#8221; and &#8220;Three Kingdoms Tactic,&#8221; which already reach hundreds of millions of players worldwide each month. In total, beta testers will have access to more than 25 games, Google says.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259463" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The new PC app lets users browse through the catalog, then download and play games on a larger screen, while also taking advantage of their mouse and keyboard inputs. Users&#8217; gameplay progress, meanwhile, swill sync between devices, and they&#8217;ll continue to early Play Points when gaming on the PC, Google today noted.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TqkKjtp34Jg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>The PC app&#8217;s launch follows a recent move from Microsoft to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/microsoft-starts-testing-android-apps-on-windows-11/">bring Android apps to Windows 11</a>, which included a partnership with Amazon and its own Amazon Appstore, as demand for cross-platform gameplay has heated up. But the Google Play Games for PC app isn&#8217;t being built in partnership with Microsoft &#8212; it&#8217;s Google&#8217;s own app, which it built in-house and distributes. It&#8217;s also not a game streaming service. Players will download the games to their computer in order to play.</p>
<p>As the beta version goes to launch, Google says it will publish more details for Android developers that will help them optimize their existing games to be compatible with Windows PCs, so they&#8217;ll be able to take advantage of the expanded access the PC app will provide. Google had said last month that, with the launch of a Windows app, Google Play games could reach a gaming ecosystem of 2.5 billion monthly active users, across platforms.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Timed alongside this news at 4 PM PT today, Google will launch <a href="https://developer.android.com/games/playgames">a developer website</a> for those interested in participating in the beta where they can express interest and opt-in to receive updates as the beta continues.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/google-play-games-for-pc-which-brings-android-games-to-windows-enters-beta-testing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259463</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Electric rail vehicle startup Parallel Systems raises a $49.55M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/daily-crunch-electric-rail-vehicle-startup-parallel-systems-raises-a-49-55m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/daily-crunch-electric-rail-vehicle-startup-parallel-systems-raises-a-49-55m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 23:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for January 19, 2022! What a news roundup we have for you today: China’s changing venture landscape, the power of passwords, no-code startups, and why women are still raising paltry sums compared to men. Please enjoy! – <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2><strong>The TechCrunch Top 3</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/tiktok-bytedance-dissolves-strategic-investment-arm/">China’s corporate venture landscape hits regulatory wall</a>: Chinese tech giant ByteDance dissolved its strategic investment team, it became known today. The news comes as other sources reported that the country’s government may require larger internet firms to get approval before making investments. If that comes to bear, the ByteDance news could prove more harbinger than one-off, perhaps reducing the total capital available to startups in the country.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-arent-female-founders-getting-a-bigger-piece-of-the-pie-theories-abound/">Funding for women founders continues to disappoint</a>: New data indicates that less than 2% of VC funding last year went to all-women teams. The dollar amount rose as the larger venture landscape grew, but the data was still more than desultory. What’s going on? TechCrunch explored the question.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/when-will-vcs-hit-the-brakes/">When will VCs hit the brakes</a>? The boom in venture capital activity that the world recorded last year, and appears to be still afoot today, is increasingly in contrast to falling valuations for public tech companies. The rising dissonance between public concern and private enthusiasm has us wondering when VCs might slow their roll just a bit.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Startups/VC</strong></h2>
<p>The biggest piece of startup news today is that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/1password-series-c-funding/">1Password raised a massive $620 million round at a valuation of $6.8 billion</a>. The new funding was led by Iconiq Growth, and saw participation from a murderers’ row of venture capital firms.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259734" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Putatively a Series C, the investment comes after the company raised a huge $200 million Series A and a similarly large $100 million Series B. Companies waiting to raise capital and then raising a big check is rare, but not so rare that we don’t occasionally see the news event double up. Such was the case today: Dovetail, which, after raising a modest amount since its birth and only burning half the funds, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dovetail-raises-63m-to-grow-its-researcher-focused-software-business/">raised a massive $63 million Series A, it announced today</a>.</p>
<p>1Password, of course, is a password manager, while Dovetail is building researcher-focused software for corporate teams.</p>
<p>Before we turn to venture capital rounds, let’s chat about some fund news:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/the-berserk-pace-of-fintech-investing-outshines-the-global-vc-boom/">The pace of fintech investing is pretty insane</a>: The venture capital domain is awash in superlative numbers, enormous sums, titanic tallies and big rounds. But perhaps the single biggest niche, or at least the one that seems to make the most noise, is fintech. So we dug into that category to find out more.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/israels-viola-ventures-hits-250m-for-its-new-fund-appoints-yael-alroy-as-partner/">Viola Ventures closes $250M</a>: The Israeli tech scene has been more than busy in recent years, evidence of which can be found in that Viola’s latest fund was “oversubscribed and reached its hard cap,” TechCrunch reports. The firm now has $1.25 billion under management.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/inflection-raises-40-million-for-its-second-crypto-focused-fund/">It turns out you can raise a small crypto fund</a>: As crypto funds reach the billion-dollar mark and often soar right past that figure, it’s almost nice to find a smaller capital pool. Inflection raised a blockchain-focused fund worth just under $41 million, and our own Romain Dillet took a peek. (And speaking of crypto, POAP, or the “proof of attendance protocol” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/web3-proof-of-attendance-startup-raises-10m-to-mint-shared-memories-as-nfts/">just raised $10 million</a>, while <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/tom-bradys-buzzy-celebrity-nft-startup-autograph-banks-170m-from-silicon-valleys-top-crypto-investors/">something involving Tom Brady and NFTs raised $170 million</a>.)</li>
</ul>
<p>And now, the day’s deluge of new capital rounds from a bevy of startups:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/former-spacex-engineers-bring-autonomous-electric-rail-vehicle-startup-out-of-stealth/">$49.55M for autonomous electric rail transit</a>: Parallel Systems, founded by a crew of former SpaceX folks, wants to “build autonomous battery-electric rail vehicles.” It just came out of stealth. Decarbonization is hot. Autonomy is hot. Transit is hot. So it’s not a surprise that the company just landed eight figures of capital.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/lattice-raises-175m-more-at-a-3b-valuation-for-its-people-management-platform/">HR tech firm Lattice raises $175M at a $3B valuation:</a> The new round, a Series F, will go to build out its people-management service. Given that we’re in a never-ending pandemic and the work landscape has been forever shifted, it’s not a huge surprise that folks are lining up to fund Lattice’s work.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/a16z-avenir-and-google-back-south-african-mobile-games-publisher-carry1st-in-20m-round/">South African mobile games company lands $20M</a>: Meet Carry1st, a social games publisher that just landed eight figures. The round indicates that the African continent’s fruitful 2021 fundraising cycle is persisting into the new year, and marks a16z’s first investment in a startup with an African HQ.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/filmhub-backed-by-6-8m-from-a16z-and-others-helps-filmmakers-get-their-work-streamed/">Filmhub is like the DistroKid for movies</a>: If you make a movie and want to have it land on streaming channels, you might need some help. Filmhub just raised $6.8 million to help filmmakers get their work onto “more than 100 streaming channels,” TechCrunch reports.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/softrs-series-a-is-a-reminder-that-the-no-code-boom-continues/">Softr raises on the strength of the no-code market</a>: Softr’s product lets folks build apps from data sets – today Airtable, with more on the way – and intends to create a marketplace of templates and extensions in the future. It just landed $13.5 million to keep at it. TechCrunch covered its seed round <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/softr/">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>And to close us out, Revolut is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/revolut-launches-stock-trading-in-the-us/">launching stock trading in the United States</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/a-hard-rain-is-coming-for-uks-crypto-boom/">there could be rainy days ahead for crypto in the U.K</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Why Microsoft’s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2259527" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259527" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259527" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg" alt="Microsoft's Xbox One video game console and Activision Blizzard's Call of Duty: Modern Warfare video game arranged in Denver, Colorado, U.S., on Tuesday, Jan. 18, 2022. Microsoft Corp. agreed to buy Activision Blizzard Inc. in a $68.7 billion deal, uniting two of the biggest forces in video games to create the worlds third-biggest gaming company. Photographer: Michael Ciaglo/Bloomberg via Getty Images" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237816149.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259527" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Michael Ciaglo / Bloomberg / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Risk is an essential part of gambling, so it may be improper to describe Microsoft’s planned purchase of Activision Blizzard as a “bet.”</p>
<p>Considering that Microsoft has a market cap over $2 trillion, purchasing a gaming company that pumps out titles like Call of Duty, Guitar Hero and Candy Crush for $68 billion isn’t exactly fraught with danger.</p>
<p>According to Box CEO Aaron Levie, the move solidifies Redmond’s entry into AR/VR gaming.</p>
<p>“If you believe VR and immersive computing is the future — whether for consumer or business use cases — Activision helps Microsoft build a flywheel of content and technology that gets more users on board to this future.”</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mbdJnbXFgg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/">Why Microsoft&#8217;s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Microsoft&#8217;s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/embed/#?secret=mbdJnbXFgg" data-secret="mbdJnbXFgg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2><strong>Big Tech Inc.</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/google-lobbies-for-new-privacy-shield/">Google wants easier trans-Atlantic data flow</a>: Google has been making noise on regulatory issues lately, including the issue of GDPR rules regarding Google Analytics, and <a href="https://www.axios.com/apple-urges-caution-senate-antitrust-bills-3a6a3ae7-10e4-43a5-aab5-6e8cada7c619.html?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=editorial&amp;utm_content=politics-apple">also on antitrust rulings</a>. The company is expanding its public blogging efforts as it also lobbies directly.</li>
<li>And, to close our news for the day, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/instagram-launches-early-test-of-creator-subscriptions-in-the-u-s/">Instagram, part of the larger Meta corporation, is building subscriptions for creators</a>. Which, now that it has built it, feels somewhat inevitable.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>TechCrunch Experts</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/daily-crunch-electric-rail-vehicle-startup-parallel-systems-raises-a-49-55m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259734</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto.com CEO admits hundreds of customer accounts were hacked</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/crypto-com-ceo-admits-hundreds-of-customer-accounts-were-hacked/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/crypto-com-ceo-admits-hundreds-of-customer-accounts-were-hacked/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anita Ramaswamy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 23:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Damon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crypto.com CEO Kris Marszalek said around 400 customer accounts have been compromised in a hack in an interview with Bloomberg TV on Wednesday. His confirmation of the breach comes after multiple Crypto.com users alleged their funds had been stolen – complaints that had until now been met with vague responses from the company.  While Marszalek [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crypto.com CEO Kris Marszalek said around 400 customer accounts have been compromised in a hack </span><a href="https://twitter.com/BloombergLive/status/1483841347824099330"><span style="font-weight: 400;">in an interview with Bloomberg TV</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on Wednesday. His confirmation of the breach comes after multiple Crypto.com users alleged their funds had been stolen – complaints that had until now been met with vague responses from the company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Marszalek did not provide details as to how the hack occurred, he told Bloomberg TV that the exchange was back online “about 13-14 hours” after the incident and that all the impacted accounts were reimbursed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marszalek’s statement marks the first official acknowledgment by Crypto.com that a hack did, in fact, occur. Crypto.com first paused withdrawals on its platform on Sunday after noting </span><a href="https://twitter.com/cryptocom/status/1483050866894868484"><span style="font-weight: 400;">via Twitter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that a “small number of users [are] reporting suspicious activity on their accounts.” It also asked customers to reset their two-factor authentication out of “an abundance of caution.”</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259797" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company then reassured users numerous times in its communications that customer funds were safe, drawing speculation that Crypto.com would cover any customer losses incurred. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The losses may amount to $15 million worth of ETH, blockchain security provider PeckShield tweeted on Monday. PeckShield claimed in the tweet that about half of the funds were being sent to Tornado Cash to be “washed.” Tornado Cash </span><a href="https://twitter.com/TornadoCash"><span style="font-weight: 400;">says</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it provides “non-custodial anonymous transactions” on the Ethereum blockchain, meaning it can hide where crypto is being sent. Another analyst from blockchain data firm OXT Research </span><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/crypto-com-breach-may-be-worth-up-to-33m-suggests-onchain-analyst"><span style="font-weight: 400;">speculated</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the hack may actually have cost the exchange $33 million. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When asked about the scope of the losses, Marszalek told Bloomberg TV that Crypto.com was still working on a post-mortem of the incident that would be posted on the company’s blog “in the next couple of days.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Crypto.com is </span><a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/exchanges/crypto_com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the world’s fourth-largest crypto exchange</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it has been pushing hard into U.S. markets in recent months, with stunts including viral advertisements featuring actor Matt Damon and a $700 million purchase of the naming rights to the Los Angeles Lakers and Clippers Arena. It calls itself the “fastest-growing” crypto exchange and </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/17/crypto-com-500-million-fund-web3/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">expanded its venture capital arm</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to $500 million to back early-stage startups in the space earlier this week; the fallout regarding this week&#8217;s hack could threaten to stall some of its stateside growth.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/crypto-com-ceo-admits-hundreds-of-customer-accounts-were-hacked/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259797</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Accessible hiring practices to solve for The Great Resignation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/accessible-hiring-practices-to-solve-for-the-great-resignation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/accessible-hiring-practices-to-solve-for-the-great-resignation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 21:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[americans with disabilities act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inclusion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With so many organizations reevaluating their commitment to diversity, equity and inclusion, recruiters need to identify access as a key ingredient for developing a workplace that welcomes all.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Meagan Taylor</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dequesystems">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/meaganltaylor/">Meagan Taylor</a>, a project manager at <a href="https://www.deque.com/">Deque Systems</a>, is passionate about dismantling systemic barriers to capital and opportunity, including on the web.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Yay, no errors, warnings, or alerts! --></p>
<p>Employees across industries are quitting their jobs. One recent study reported that <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/14/1-in-4-workers-quit-their-job-this-year-according-to-new-report.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">one in four</a> people quit their job this year. Whether we want to chalk it up to career moves that were delayed due to the uncertain pandemic economy, a reevaluation of work environments, or a revolt against unsatisfactory employers, one thing is certain: It’s a job seeker’s market, with more than <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/jolts.nr0.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10 million</a> job openings as of November.</p>
<p>Many of these job seekers have disabilities, as these employees were disproportionately impacted by COVID-related layoffs – March to April 2020 saw a <a href="https://www.nga.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/SEED_Memo.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20%</a> reduction in workers with disabilities. With so many organizations already reevaluating their commitment to diversity, equity and inclusion, recruiters need to identify access as a key ingredient for developing a workplace that welcomes <em>all</em>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259542" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Not only is deploying accessible hiring practices the right thing to do – and a requirement under the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) – but it could also help mitigate widespread labor shortages, connecting companies to a large, talented pool of applicants.</p>
<p>But before developing strategies for reaching applicants with disabilities, there are some myths and misconceptions to confront.</p>
<p><strong>Myth:</strong> We’d have to lower our hiring standards if we want to include people with disabilities.</p>
<p><strong>Facts:</strong> People with disabilities often <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10869-018-9602-5#ref-CR56" target="_blank" rel="noopener">outperform</a> others. What’s more, companies inclusive to people with disabilities see <a href="https://www.accenture.com/t20181029T185446Z__w__/us-en/_acnmedia/PDF-89/Accenture-Disability-Inclusion-Research-Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28%</a> greater annual revenue as a result of increased innovation that develops inclusive products to capture new markets.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Myth:</strong> Employees with disabilities will have a higher rate of absence than others.</p>
<p><strong>Facts:</strong> People with disabilities often track equal or better attendance rates. They also have lower <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs10672-008-9063-5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">turnover rates</a>, a problem that&#8217;s greatly impacted productivity in 2021.</p>
<p><strong>Myth:</strong> Accommodations will be too expensive.</p>
<p><strong>Facts:</strong> First, <a href="https://askjan.org/topics/costs.cfm?csSearch=2546498_1">56%</a> of accommodations have zero cost. And of those that do incur a cost, 50% cost less than $500. Add in the increased profits and shareholder returns expected from disability-inclusive hiring, and organizations can only expect to gain.</p>
<p>Once organizations realize the positive impact of a culture of accessibility, they can begin exploring ways to hire candidates with disabilities using these guidelines from Loule Gebremedhin and Jennifer Stark of <a href="https://www.disabilityrightsca.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disability Rights California</a>, a public advocacy organization advancing the rights of Californians with disabilities.</p>
<h2>Phase 1: Recruitment</h2>
<h3>Look in the mirror</h3>
<p>Before even embarking on the recruitment process, organizations need to look inward. It’s not just a matter of realizing the facts and accepting people with disabilities as competent employees. It’s about valuing the expertise and experience of employees with disabilities and creating an environment that supports their professional growth.</p>
<p>Set clear goals by asking questions: What is our current culture around disabilities? Are we prepared to accommodate growth and retention? How does an equitable hiring process connect to our bigger goals?</p>
<p>Part of this internal review should focus on benefits. It’s no secret that great benefits can often be the deal-maker or -breaker for any candidate as they weigh opportunities. For people with disabilities, the stakes are higher. For many, a comprehensive physical and mental healthcare plan is a top consideration in selecting an employer.</p>
<p>Remote work is another important benefit. We’ve all witnessed the advantages of working from home this year, from a lower commute time/cost, greater flexibility around childcare and higher productivity. People with disabilities saw these advantages, too, along with the ability to design a personal work environment that meets their needs — for example, people with low vision can dictate how much light they need in the room to best support them.</p>
<h3>Prepare the application</h3>
<p>Next, recruiters need to revise job descriptions and applications to ensure they’re disability-friendly. Rather than talking about <em>how</em> a job needs to get done, reframe descriptions to focus on the end skills needed to accomplish goals (e.g., strong oral communication versus the ability to effectively communicate). <a href="https://production-askearn-org.s3.amazonaws.com/EARN_Explainer_Job_Descriptions_Checklist_ab47437635.pdf">This guide</a> from the Employee Assistance and Resource Network can help develop descriptions.</p>
<p>Locating and filling out job applications is a top challenge for people with disabilities, with many digital applications not meeting accessibility requirements. This not only diminishes the number of applicants with disabilities, but can also open organizations to legal risk under the ADA. Training and tools that help developers produce accessible sites and forms supporting the application process are easy ways to ensure all qualified candidates have equal access while simultaneously maintaining compliance.</p>
<h2>Phase 2: Interviews</h2>
<h3>Proactively accommodate</h3>
<p>People with disabilities are accustomed to requesting accommodations – but what if they didn’t have to? An interview process that offers accommodations upfront confirms to job seekers that accessibility matters to the organization (and it’s also required under the ADA).</p>
<p>For example, for in-person interviews, consider whether a person in a wheelchair could easily get to the location. For virtual interviews, double-check that your meeting platform has automated captioning switched on at the very least. Even better if you’ve got a live captioner or ASL provider available.</p>
<h3>Train hiring managers</h3>
<p>Hiring managers’ <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w21560" target="_blank" rel="noopener">biases</a> are at the core of the low employment rates for people with disabilities. Organizations can play an active role in building awareness and mitigating bias by implementing training around basic disability etiquette and ethical, ADA-compliant questioning. Including people with disabilities on hiring panels can also increase mindfulness of disabilities.</p>
<h2>Phase 3: Offers</h2>
<p>When it’s time to hire employees with disabilities, organizations need to take steps to provide an offer that’s both competitive and meets candidates’ needs.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ensure compensation is on par with similar roles across the industry</strong> – Remember that people with disabilities are often unfairly paid less, with some policies still in place allowing workers with disabilities to be paid <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/09/17/912840482/u-s-agency-urges-end-to-below-minimum-wage-for-workers-with-disabilities" target="_blank" rel="noopener">less than minimum wage</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Create a system for providing accommodations </strong>– Ensure potential employees know they can request accommodations and have a policy for responding to and meeting requests. The <a href="https://askjan.org/info-by-role.cfm#for-employers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Job Accommodation Network</a> can help provide insight into which accommodations to provide.</li>
<li><strong>Build mentoring and retention programs</strong> – Offer specialized mentoring, education, and networking opportunities to support growth and leadership.</li>
</ul>
<p>Over the past year, organizations have made great strides in considering diversity, equity and inclusion in the workplace. Accessibility is part of this equation and needs to be seen as such for organizations to meet their overarching goals.</p>
<p>Beyond doing the right thing, fostering a hiring process that seeks candidates with disabilities and provides an environment in which they can thrive can help mitigate current staffing gaps, power innovation, and support a strong organizational culture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/accessible-hiring-practices-to-solve-for-the-great-resignation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259542</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Podcasts introduces new &#8216;Listen With&#8217; collections to help users discover shows</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/apple-podcasts-introduces-new-listen-with-collections-to-help-users-discover-shows/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/apple-podcasts-introduces-new-listen-with-collections-to-help-users-discover-shows/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 20:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple Podcasts is rolling out a new &#8220;Listen With&#8221; editorial franchise to give users a new way to discover podcasts. The company says Listen With helps users discover new shows by sharing those that popular artists, authors, filmmakers, journalists, influencers and other podcasters are listening to. Each collection includes a few shows and quotes about why [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple Podcasts is rolling out a new &#8220;Listen With&#8221; editorial franchise to give users a new way to discover podcasts. The company says Listen With helps users discover new shows by sharing those that popular artists, authors, filmmakers, journalists, influencers and other podcasters are listening to. Each collection includes a few shows and quotes about why they were selected to be featured. The collections are curated by Apple&#8217;s editorial team and are now available in the United States and Canada and can be found in the &#8220;Browse&#8221; section of the Apple Podcasts app.</p>
<p>The first collection is with Jay Shetty, who is an author, life coach and former monk. In his collection, Shetty recommends &#8220;A Slight Change of Plans&#8221; with Maya Shankar from Pushkin Industries; &#8220;Anything goes with Emma Chamberlain&#8221; from Ramble; &#8220;How I Built This with Guy Raz&#8221; from NPR; &#8220;We Can Do Hard Things with Glenn Doyle&#8221; from Cadence13 and Oprah’s &#8220;SuperSoul.&#8221;</p>
<p>Listen With is Apple&#8217;s third editorial franchise. The company launched its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/apples-new-editorial-franchise-apple-podcasts-spotlight-to-highlight-interesting-creators/">&#8220;Spotlight&#8221;</a> editorial franchise last year to highlight rising podcast creators in the United States. The editorial team at Apple selects new podcast creators to feature every month and give them prominent screen real estate in the Apple Podcasts app and promote them across social media and elsewhere. Apple also has a &#8220;Kids &amp; Family&#8221; collection curated in partnership with Common Sense Media.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259693" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In addition to launching Listen With, Apple also shared insights on podcasts subscriptions, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/apple-unveils-podcast-subscriptions-and-a-redesigned-apple-podcasts-app/">launched</a> in April 2021. The company revealed that launching a subscription grows the total audience of a podcast. Apple notes that the total audience increased for the top 50 subscriptions with existing audiences on Apple Podcasts in the four weeks after their subscription launch. The company also said that among the best-performing creators, more than 10% of listeners have signed up for a subscription. Since the launch of Apple Podcasts Subscriptions, one in five subscriptions enjoy an adoption rate of more than 10%.</p>
<p>Apple has been working to expand its podcasts platform and it&#8217;s clearly not the only one to do so. For instance, <a href="https://podnews.net/article/spotify-bigger-than-apple">Spotify has</a> <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-10/spotify-agrees-to-buy-podcast-ad-tech-company-for-235-million">spent</a> over $800 million on podcast companies, like Anchor, the Ringer, Gimlet Media, and Megaphone. SiriusXM, meanwhile, has bought podcast management and analytics platform Simplecast, ad tech platform AdsWizz, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/spotify-buying-podcast-hosting-and-ad-company-megaphone-for-235m/">and podcast app Stitcher</a>. On the other hand, Amazon <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/amazon-acquires-podcast-network-wondery/">has acquired</a> the podcast network Wondery.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/apple-podcasts-introduces-new-listen-with-collections-to-help-users-discover-shows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259693</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Mayht, a small startup, is taking on the world of speaker goliaths</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/mayht-vs-goliath/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/mayht-vs-goliath/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 20:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forward One]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayht]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speakers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are many ways of spinning up a startup, but it takes a particularly brave set of founders to take on a deeply entrenched industry with a small number of incumbents who have the market all sown up. You&#8217;d have to be a special flavor of bold to take on internet search for example &#8212; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are many ways of spinning up a startup, but it takes a particularly brave set of founders to take on a deeply entrenched industry with a small number of incumbents who have the market all sown up. You&#8217;d have to be a special flavor of bold to take on internet search for example &#8212; where the name of the leading company is literally synonymous with searching for something on the internet. The world of speakers is similar; the technology has barely moved in the past hundred years, and only a handful of manufacturers create almost every single speaker element that plays the sweet dulcet tones of Shania Twain into the ether around you.</p>
<p>Plenty of startups think they can put a dent in this world, and every year, I see dozens of pitches for companies that are &#8220;making speakers better&#8221; in various ways. And every year, it falls flat. Yes, innovations are happening, but core speaker technology rarely moves in a way that could be described as truly innovative. At CES this year, I got to talking with the team of <a href="https://www.mayht.com/">Mayht</a>, which might just be the exception to that general rule.</p>
<p>The company has created speakers that are pointing in opposite directions of each other, with motors that move the speaker elements apart at the same time &#8212; creating a similar motion to you clapping your hands. That means that the speakers are perfectly balanced. The company claims the impact is more bang for the buck, and that the more-compact speakers can be more energy efficient in use, and smaller to ship and store. The speaker tech is interesting, but what really piqued my interest was how a small rag-tag bunch of innovators from the Netherlands is planning to shake things up.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259521" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Mayht is a technology company. Early on in its journey, it realized that in the world of speaker tech, there&#8217;s not much point in going head-to-head against the behemoths in the space. Armed with a handful of patents and some cool reference speakers (i.e. prototypes they can show off to potential partners), the company is hoping to build what is essentially an outsourced R&amp;D arm. They are the skunkworks that creates new and interesting tech, before licencing it to the well-known speaker brands out there. I decided to take a closer look at the little Dutch startup, and how it is taking on one of the most well-entrenched industries in consumer electronics.</p>
<p>In this interview, I talk with the Mayht team and its investors to figure out what the special sauce is when you&#8217;re a scrappy David in a world of Goliaths.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been working on this speaker technology since 2016. In the first couple of years we were just creating prototypes, but now we got a lot of stuff that is really close to mass production &#8212; or in mass production. We&#8217;re not a manufacturer of drivers, we just defend the technology and we license it,&#8221; explains Mattias Scheek, CEO at Mayht. &#8220;We can finally show our technology in different kinds of applications &#8212; from soundbars to small subwoofers to small voice-assistant speakers. We believe the latter, in particular, will really disrupt the market. If say, an Echo Dot can have the same sound as the Sonos One, or a soundbar. Or if a speaker without a subwoofer can have the same sound as something that does have one. It makes a big change in the market. We are finally able to show those things to the public.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company claims it has invented a new generation of speaker drivers. Whereas a typical speaker driver has a membrane, it can make limited movement, because the whole motor structure is behind the membrane. Mayht&#8217;s innovation is to put the motor structures at the sides of the membrane. That means more movement, and more displacement. You see a similar thing in automobile engines: A &#8220;bigger&#8221; engine can work in one of two ways &#8212; either you make each cylinder bigger, which means that more gas and air mixture can explode and create power. Or you make the stroke longer. Mayht is applying the same idea to speakers here. Speakers need to be smaller in a lot of different applications &#8212; the company suggests smart home speakers like the Google Mini and Alexa&#8217;s speakers, but also in vehicle tech, where space is at a premium. The company also claims that its speaker tech reduces rattle:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2259570" style="width: 250px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mayht-speaker.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259570" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259570" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mayht-speaker.gif" alt="" width="240" height="268" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2259570" class="wp-caption-text">Mayht&#8217;s speaker technology puts the motors on the side of the membranes. The theory is that this makes the speakers balanced, and able to displace a lot more air than a comparable-sized speaker with a traditional design. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mayht</p></div></p>
<p>The company doesn&#8217;t have many kind words for the current generations of smart speakers &#8212; while adding voice controllability, mesh Wi-Fi, great design, power management and great user experience were all meaningful innovations, the speaker tech itself is pretty underwhelming.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s exactly the same story for all the manufacturers &#8212; Bang &amp; Olufsen, Bose, Sony. Every company uses the same technology and the same drivers because they essentially come from the same factories. There are three or four major manufacturers and all those different speaker brands take their drivers from those manufacturers. It&#8217;s not strange that there is no innovation in that field,&#8221; laments Scheek. &#8220;Because the manufacturers themselves don&#8217;t really develop drivers, they are not pushed to make higher-quality tech. They may move the needle by 1 or 2% but not to change the complete architecture of the driver. Doing so would mean changing their whole manufacturing setup, which is just a huge risk for those companies.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2259587" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259587" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259587" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="673" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg 5985w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg?resize=300,197 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg?resize=768,505 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg?resize=680,447 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg?resize=1536,1009 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg?resize=2048,1346 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/DSC07569.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2259587" class="wp-caption-text">Taking apart a Sonos One shows you that underneath all the fancy technology is&#8230; some pretty underwhelming-looking speaker elements. (<strong>Image Credits:</strong> Haje Kamps <a href="https://blog.bolt.io/sonos-one/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for a Bolt teardown</a>)</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;The speaker companies are not rewarded to really, truly innovate. From a cost perspective, they have to perform for the best quality with the lowest level of cost. And so there&#8217;s no incentive for speaker manufacturers to really think out of the box to bring out something really new and innovative,&#8221; explains Max van den Berg, Mayht&#8217;s chief commercial officer. &#8220;To put this into perspective, we&#8217;ve spoken to around 45 speaker companies globally since the start of this company. None of them have seen anything like this before &#8212; this is truly disruptive innovation.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company raised a total of €4 million in its most recent round, led by <a href="https://www.forward.one/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forward One</a>; I caught up with the partner who spearheaded the investment, to figure out why it felt confident to put its money behind a company that from the outside seems like it is facing an uphill battle.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think the team makes Mayht special. The two founding brothers have been working with speakers since they were seven years old really impressed me,&#8221; said Frederik Gerner, partner at Forward One, a South Africa-based venture capital firm that is investing in hardware startups. &#8220;Their story on how they want to disrupt the speaker industry just makes so much sense! It&#8217;s a massive and still-growing market that has been operating for decades on the same technology, and it&#8217;s ready for disruption. Hardware is a real means to create a step-change in many industries, and we see the need for high-tech hardware innovation as more achievable and more important than ever.&#8221;</p>
<p>Building out a factory to out-manufacture the existing speaker element manufacturers would be a fools&#8217; errand &#8212; one that the company is cleverly side-stepping by taking a licencing approach instead, building a very lean, engineering-focused team, and raising relatively small amounts of money. Mayht currently has 20 employees, 70% or so of whom are on the engineering side. The company also made the shrewd move of stacking its advisory board with strategically powerful folks who can add a tremendous amount of leverage, and may just be the key to building this type of company going forward.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have some very experienced people in our advisory board who are really active in the team. There are two people who formerly worked at Philips in the licensing department. One of them actually led the licensing department and made that side of Philips a huge business. He&#8217;s really helping us with the licensing structure, but also with how you handle [patent] litigation. He&#8217;s also an incredible deal-maker,&#8221; explains Scheek.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2259665" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259665" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259665" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093912.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2259665" class="wp-caption-text">A Mayht speaker prototype next to a (much larger) Sonos speaker. The company claims the two speakers have the same sound volume and quality. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mayht</p></div></p>
<p>The company highlights the importance of building a company that fits well with the type of startup you are building. For example, Mayht also added Piet Coelewij, who was the managing director and VP of Global Operations for Sonos for five years, to its advisory board. It also highlights the company&#8217;s chief commercial officer, Max van den Berg, who was the marketing manager for personal audio for Sony in the mid 1990s, and continued in senior executive positions within Sony for several decades after that. &#8220;Having the right people in the room really helps open doors,&#8221; Scheek mentions in what might be the understatement of the year.</p>
<p>The company created a brand that it&#8217;s hoping to use to co-brand with other companies; a shrewd move that solves a significant branding problem. Most people don&#8217;t know who made the speaker elements inside their speakers &#8212; and why would they care. But there are predicates in other industries; unless you&#8217;re a very special kind of nerd, most people don&#8217;t care who made the processors inside their computers &#8212; not until Intel decided to pick up the fight and create the &#8220;Intel inside&#8221; campaign when AMD started nipping at its heels. Mayht is taking a sheet from the same playbook, and trademarked the Heartmotion brand. It hopes that it can convince its licensees to co-brand their speakers. &#8220;Sonos powered by Heartmotion&#8221; &#8212; that sort of thing.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah, so our technology brand for licensing would be Heartmotion. We called it that because the speaker looks like a pumping heart,&#8221; says Scheek. &#8220;Our goal is to have that on every product, and that our partners that use our technology will use it as part of the marketing on the box of the product.&#8221;</p>
<p>By minimizing the size and weight of the speaker tech, the company has a couple of clever talking points at its disposal. For car and RV makers, it means that they can cram more sound into smaller spaces &#8212; such as door panels and dashboards &#8212; without compromising on sound output. Those are obvious, but I was particularly impressed by how Mayht is tapping into a number of marketing messages that work particularly well in the current climate, where (finally!) people are starting to show some interest in greener tech. Packaging smaller speakers that have big performance and low energy consumption has a number of perhaps unexpected impacts. One example is the company&#8217;s prototype speaker that is clad in <a href="https://www.powerfoyle.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Powerfoyle light-harvesting tech</a>, which means <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/mayht-and-powerfoyle/">it&#8217;s possible to create a Bluetooth speaker that just keeps on going</a>. Energy consumption aside, smaller form factors mean less weight and less shipping volume, which has a ton of second-hand environmental benefits.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2259664" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259664" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259664" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/20220104_093346.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2259664" class="wp-caption-text">Mayht&#8217;s Heartmotion prototype speaker lineup. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mayht</p></div></p>
<p>Between Mayht&#8217;s licencing-first business model backed by a patent portfolio strategy, a great founder story, an advisory board staffed with a who&#8217;s-who of licensing and audio experts, and the willingness to move slow enough to get things right the first time around, the company is slowly positioning itself for an interesting 2022. The team hopes it is well resourced as it&#8217;s gearing up for a year of execution after many years of research and setting the stage.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is the year of getting our products into consumers&#8217; hands, and I am excited to see that happen. We&#8217;ve been working on it while staying under the radar for quite some time. It&#8217;s been really strange &#8212; the industry knows that this is amazing, but the consumer hasn&#8217;t experienced it yet. For us, this is the year of the big reveal. In addition to working with our partners to get this to the consumer, we are going to do something ourselves&#8230;&#8221; Sheek trails off, itching to tell me the details, but remembering the recorder is running. &#8220;We&#8217;re going to announce it quite soon &#8212; in Q2 of this year. I can&#8217;t tell you much, but we are working on a reference product that the consumer can buy directly from us. We want consumers to experience this, so we are making a limited edition speaker for people to try.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company told me it isn&#8217;t really planning to make much money on its own product; this is really a mass-produced sample to help build brand awareness.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are building a product with the [3-inch] T3 driver ourselves because the whole industry is really starting to move once you prove yourself. We made a lot of prototypes over the past years,&#8221; explains van den Berg. The problem is that it takes a bit of time to design a new product, and the big speaker brands take their time in doing so. To really hit the ground running, the company is taking a risk and taking matters into its own hands. &#8220;We feel [third-party designed speakers] are a bit of a longer process; they need time to make decisions. Most likely, their products will be on the market by the end of 2022 or in early 2023. In the meantime, we think it&#8217;s very important that we announce this technology to the consumers. We don&#8217;t want to be a competitor of anybody out there, but we think what we are doing is cool, and we are excited to release a limited edition product; a beautiful Bluetooth speaker powered by Heartmotion.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/mayht-vs-goliath/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259521</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Microsoft&#8217;s $2T+ market cap makes its $68B Activision buy a cheap bet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 20:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wth a market cap just over $2 trillion, Microsoft has vast resources to invest in the most logical parts of its business.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Even though consumer gaming constitutes a small fraction of its overall business, Microsoft&#8217;s announcement yesterday of its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/18/microsoft-acquire-activision-blizzard/">all-cash $69 billion deal</a> to buy Activision Blizzard proves that the technology corporation takes the sector plenty seriously.</p>
<p>It is easy to think that Microsoft should have invested the money into other, perhaps more lucrative businesses in its portfolio. But with a market cap just over $2 trillion (a number so large it&#8217;s hard to wrap your head around), Microsoft has vast resources to invest in the most logical parts of its business.</p>
<p>Even if this $70 billion bet doesn’t pay out, Microsoft will come out on the other side fairly unscathed. That kind of financial power gives a company myriad options, even if it involves making one of the largest acquisitions in tech history.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s not forget that this deal comes on the heels of Microsoft&#8217;s acquisition of speech-to-text company Nuance last spring <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/microsoft-is-acquiring-nuance-communications-for-19-7b/">for $20 billion</a>. That deal that is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/cma-microsoft-nuance/">stuck in regulatory limbo</a> in the U.K., which begs the question: Given it size and scope, could regulators end up taking a close look at the Activision Blizzard deal, what could be perceived as a gaming market land grab?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Even if this $70 billion bet doesn’t pay out, Microsoft will come out on the other side fairly unscathed.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>With that in mind, we&#8217;re examining this deal&#8217;s financial viability to see whether Microsoft might have been better off putting those resources into the enterprise/business side of the house, or if its resources are simply so vast that the company doesn&#8217;t have to consider the sort of tradeoffs most companies must make when it comes to an M&amp;A of this magnitude.</p>
<h2>Digging into the portfolio</h2>
<p>Although Microsoft is reporting earnings next week, we can still see the breakdown of how the company makes the majority of its money from its <a href="https://news.microsoft.com/2021/10/26/microsoft-cloud-strength-drives-first-quarter-results-4/#:~:text=%E2%80%94%20October%2026%2C%202021%20%E2%80%94%20Microsoft,%2420.2%20billion%20and%20increased%2027%25" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most recent report,</a> disclosed October 26, 2021. In that earnings digest, the Redmond, Washington-based software giant reported over $45 billion in revenue, with its Intelligent Cloud division accounting for $17 billion of the total, and its Productivity and Business Processes group good for $15 billion more.</p>
<p>The consumer side of the house produced more than $13 billion in top line, but gaming was just a portion of that division’s results that includes certain Windows and Surface incomes, along with search and advertising.</p>
<p>In spite of the differential in scale between the company’s entertainment work and its enterprise income, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella called out gaming in its <a href="https://www.fool.com/earnings/call-transcripts/2021/10/27/microsoft-msft-q1-2022-earnings-call-transcript/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earnings report call</a> with analysts, praising its growth:</p>
<blockquote><p>And in gaming, revenue increased 16% at 14% in constant currency, ahead of expectations. Better-than-expected console supply, and continued strong demand resulted in Xbox hardware revenue growth of 166% and 162% in constant currency. Xbox content and services revenue increased 2% and was relatively unchanged in constant currency against a strong prior-year comparable. Segment gross margin dollars increased 10% and 8% in constant currency. Gross margin percentage decreased roughly one point year over year, driven by sales mix shift to gaming hardware.</p></blockquote>
<p>Clearly, the company sees gaming as an important growth driver. How does that fit into the recent deal announcement? Not merely in terms of the company stacking accretive gaming revenues, with Constellation Research analyst Holger Mueller viewing the transaction as a way to grow related incomes via Windows and Azure cloud services.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-microsofts-2t-market-cap-makes-its-78b-activision-buy-a-cheap-bet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259507</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web3 &#8216;Proof of attendance&#8217; startup raises $10M to mint shared memories as NFTs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/web3-proof-of-attendance-startup-raises-10m-to-mint-shared-memories-as-nfts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/web3-proof-of-attendance-startup-raises-10m-to-mint-shared-memories-as-nfts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A.Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advancit Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delphi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sound ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Chernin Group]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If blockchains are immutable records of our digital history, what kinds of history do we want to inscribe on them? Predictably, most records thus far have been transaction data, but as entrepreneurs expand their ambitions for NFTs, startups are aiming to tie those asset transactions to real world events and interactions. POAP, which stands for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If blockchains are immutable records of our digital history, what kinds of history do we want to inscribe on them? Predictably, most records thus far have been transaction data, but as entrepreneurs expand their ambitions for NFTs, startups are aiming to tie those asset transactions to real world events and interactions.</p>
<p><a href="https://poap.xyz/">POAP</a>, which stands for Proof Of Attendance Protocol, wants to dial deeper into the idea of using NFT&#8217;s to create internet communities, with a protocol that helps build more active communities and award individual participation like taking part in an event. POAP is organized around badges as the visual signifier of their protocol. In the real world, a user could scan a QR code to received an NFT memento that could unlock admission to an online community and earn them future drops.</p>
<p>Plenty of this functionality exists elsewhere across Ethereum projects made possible by some of the underlying features of the blockchain which allows developers to create &#8220;snapshots&#8221; of active wallets which have been linked to the project at a given time. The POAP ecosystem also includes a number of other tools including Etheruem-backed polling, raffle contest mechanics and private chat verification tech.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259629" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup announced this week that they&#8217;ve raised a $10 million Seed round led by Archetype and Sapphire Sport with additional participation in the funding from Sound Ventures, The Chernin Group and Advancit Capital. A host of crypto native funds also invested including Collab Currency, 1KX, Libertus Capital, Red Beard Ventures, 6th Man Ventures, Delphi Digital and A Capital.</p>
<p>POAP <a href="https://decrypt.co/83614/ethereum-badge-app-poap-is-scaling-back-to-move-forward">met some challenges in 2021</a> as NFT community growth accelerated and the number of people looking to tap into their platform created an overwhelming influx of spam that brought the platform to a crawl. In a blog post, the company says it plans to use its new funding to invest in its application and platform layers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XhenvXjdrL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/tom-bradys-buzzy-celebrity-nft-startup-autograph-banks-170m-from-silicon-valleys-top-crypto-investors/">Tom Brady&#8217;s buzzy celebrity NFT startup Autograph banks $170M from Silicon Valley&#8217;s top crypto investors</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tom Brady&#8217;s buzzy celebrity NFT startup Autograph banks $170M from Silicon Valley&#8217;s top crypto investors&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/tom-bradys-buzzy-celebrity-nft-startup-autograph-banks-170m-from-silicon-valleys-top-crypto-investors/embed/#?secret=XhenvXjdrL" data-secret="XhenvXjdrL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/web3-proof-of-attendance-startup-raises-10m-to-mint-shared-memories-as-nfts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259629</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dovetail raises $63M to grow its researcher-focused software business</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dovetail-raises-63m-to-grow-its-researcher-focused-software-business/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dovetail-raises-63m-to-grow-its-researcher-focused-software-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arun mathew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dovetail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rich Wong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Australian user research software company Dovetail announced today that it has closed a $63 million Series A led by Accel. The company has now raised just over $70 million in total, and it added its new capital at a valuation that it describes as &#8220;north&#8221; of $700 million. As you can tell by the numbers, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Australian user research software company <a href="https://dovetailapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dovetail</a> announced today that it has closed a $63 million Series A led by <a href="https://www.accel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Accel</a>. The company has now raised just over $70 million in total, and it added its new capital at a valuation that it describes as &#8220;north&#8221; of $700 million.</p>
<p>As you can tell by the numbers, this is no ordinary Series A. Instead, it&#8217;s a late-stage investment of sorts by Accel, a venture capital firm that has a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/05/how-one-vc-firm-wound-up-with-no-code-startups-as-part-of-its-investing-thesis/">history of making large investments</a> into technology companies that have raised little capital or self-funded until they raise, later in life, a large check.</p>
<p>Given that the Dovetail round is not our standard Series A fare, let&#8217;s take moment and talk through the deal, starting with the company&#8217;s early history and what&#8217;s it&#8217;s building.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259520" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>Boostrapping(ish) Dovetail</h2>
<p>TechCrunch spoke with Dovetail co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/humphreybc?originalSubdomain=au" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Benjamin Humphrey</a> about the capital raise, turning the clock back to the start of the company itself. Per Humphrey, after a stint in the Bay Area working for a technology company, the New Zealander joined Atlassian in Australia, where he stayed for a multi-year tenure. After that, he co-founded Dovetail without the intention of raising venture capital, instead planning to build the company along the lines of Buffer and Basecamp, well-known technology firms that have pursued a more self-funded approach to growth.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s focus on building software for the user research market might sound niche, but Dovetail found enough traction in its early days to scale to a team of six with around a half-million dollars in annual revenue under its own power. At that point, however, Humphrey said, venture investors were approaching the firm, so Dovetail raised a modest round of around AUD$5 million back in 2019.</p>
<p>One of its investors, Felicis, wanted to put more capital into the company toward the end of 2020. Dovetail, its CEO said, didn&#8217;t need the money, so it raised a seed-1 round at a valuation north of $100 million, a price indicative of the position it had in the market. (Lesson: Being profitable-ish and growing is the real startup sweet spot when it comes to fundraising.)</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s it, until today. Per new investors Rich Wong and Arun Mathew of Accel, Dovetail had burned only half of its total fundraising before they got the chance to invest.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Software companies don&#8217;t tend to grow sans material burn in today&#8217;s market, which means that customers were showing up to buy what Dovetail is building.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s Dovetail selling?</h2>
<p>The Accel duo described what Dovetail is building as a sort of new category, namely the &#8220;system of record for user research.&#8221;</p>
<p>Humphrey put it in more prosaic terms, describing Dovetail&#8217;s product to TechCrunch as a productivity tool for researchers. Engineers have GitHub and designers have Figma, he said, noting that user researchers need their own software. Silicon Valley and the larger startup scene, he added, has done much work building tooling for the &#8220;D&#8221; in R&amp;D, but far less on the &#8220;R&#8221; part of the equation.</p>
<p>Dovetail&#8217;s product is software that allows customers to collect user feedback data from NPS (net promoter score) surveys, audio, video and text answers, which are then tagged by teams, machine-analyzed and shared across an organization. The goal, Humphrey said, is to build a relational database for companies to store their institutional knowledge about customers so that they can make faster decisions.</p>
<p>As an example, he said that when a product manager (PM) leaves a company, they take with them quite a lot of knowledge. This means that new PMs will have to race around asking questions of the company to get up to speed, instead of having that knowledge stored and secure. Dovetail could help companies hold onto the data and knowledge from research, making them both accessible and more permanent.</p>
<h2>Growth</h2>
<p>I&#8217;m still learning about what Dovetail does, so expect more over time as we explore the research software market. But what I can say today is that Dovetail is growing like a weed. Per Humphrey, the company tripled its revenue and customers last year. All self-serve, with the company only hiring its first acount executive a few months ago. That&#8217;s <em>actual</em> product-led growth.</p>
<p>Product-led growth, the idea that one&#8217;s actual service or good will draw in customers, is essentially a rebrand of the concept of product-market fit (PMF) &#8212; or is perhaps a more pure version of what PMF should mean. Regardless, the relatively young company is looking to match its 2021 growth rate this year, per its investors &#8212; or at least get close. And that&#8217;s why it is nearly a unicorn already.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll harangue Humphrey for growth data later this year, as he likely won&#8217;t be ringing our phone in the next months with new capital news.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dovetail-raises-63m-to-grow-its-researcher-focused-software-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259520</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: How do I successfully expand my company to the US?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dear-sophie-how-do-i-successfully-expand-my-company-to-the-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dear-sophie-how-do-i-successfully-expand-my-company-to-the-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L-1 visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m an entrepreneur in Guatemala and would like to come to the United States to expand my tech company. What is the best way to do that?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/dear-sophie-do-we-need-a-visa-to-explore-the-us-market/">Dear Sophie: Do we need a visa to explore the US market?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/dear-sophie-with-the-h-1b-lottery-looming-how-should-we-approach-overseas-hiring/">Dear Sophie: With the H-1B lottery looming, how should we approach overseas hiring?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">​​Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch+ members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><!-- Yay, no errors, warnings, or alerts! --></p>
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>I’m an entrepreneur in Guatemala and would like to come to the United States to expand my tech company. </strong></p>
<p><strong>What is the best way to do that?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Groundbreaking Guatemalan</strong></p>
<p>Dear Groundbreaking,</p>
<p>What fantastic news that you’re looking to tackle the U.S. market. In a recent <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/106-how-to-set-up-your-company-for-immigration-success/">podcast</a> (which is actually trending in your country the last several weeks!), I discussed my take on how to best establish a startup for immigration success. Whether a founder wants to make their way to the United States – or if they’re already here and want to start a venture of their own – we discussed the details. There are even options for companies that are newly formed with limited funding.</p>
<p>It’s important to know your options when setting up your company in the United States. This knowledge enables your company to successfully sponsor you, your founding team, and other prospective hires for visas and green cards if needed – prospective investors will also feel more comfortable investing in your company. Super important, right?! Before you get too deep into your plans, I recommend you consult both a corporate attorney and an immigration attorney to assist you in your efforts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>LLC versus Delaware C-corp</h2>
<p>One of the first decisions you’ll need to make is how to structure your company in the U.S. A business or corporate attorney will be able to help you make this decision. In general, both corporations and LLCs are able to sponsor individuals for a U.S. visa or green card.</p>
<p>What I typically see in the startup ecosystem are that most VCs prefer investing in a C corporation created in Delaware (Delaware C-corp). That’s primarily because Delaware laws protect investors, and Delaware C-corps can distribute two or more classes of stock and stock options to employees, investors, and board members.</p>
<p>There is no U.S. residency or citizenship requirement to set up a Delaware C-corp, and it can be done within a day. For more info on this topic, <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/039-startup-law-with-attorney-lindsey-mignano/">listen to my chat</a> about startup law with my good friend and trusted colleague <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindsey-mignano-477a0167/">Lindsey Mignano</a>, founding partner of <a href="https://www.smithshapourian.com/">Smith Shapourian Mignano</a>, a corporate law firm based in San Francisco that focuses on startups.</p>
<p>Also, talk to your business attorney about the ownership structure of these entities as well. For example, one possibility is that your Guatemalan company could own your U.S.-based company. However, most investors prefer to invest in a parent company based in the United States, so you could consider setting up your U.S. company to own your company in Guatemala. However, if you’ve already distributed shares in your company in Guatemala, this could be a cumbersome process that might best wait until you’re ready for a funding round. Then, you could do what’s called a Delaware flip — and you should definitely have your corporate attorney advise you on doing that.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/dear-sophie-how-do-i-successfully-expand-my-company-to-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259449</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Disney&#8217;s streaming biz reorg includes an international content hub, plans to double Disney+ footprint</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/disneys-streaming-biz-reorg-includes-an-international-content-hub-plans-to-double-disney-footprint/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/disneys-streaming-biz-reorg-includes-an-international-content-hub-plans-to-double-disney-footprint/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 18:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asia pacific]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob Chapek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disney channel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[espn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the walt disney company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Disney announced today it plans on expanding its direct-to-consumer streaming business to more global markets and is creating a new International Content and Operations group to aid in this push. The group will be headed by nearly 25-year Disney veteran Rebecca Campbell, who will focus on local and regional content production for Disney&#8217;s streaming services, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Disney announced today it plans on expanding its direct-to-consumer streaming business to more global markets and is creating a new International Content and Operations group to aid in this push. The group will be headed by nearly 25-year Disney veteran <a href="https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/leaders/rebecca-campbell/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rebecca Campbell</a>, who will focus on local and regional content production for Disney&#8217;s streaming services, while also overseeing Disney&#8217;s international teams. The new role will report directly to Disney CEO Bob Chapek. The company also today offered an update on its current streaming footprint and 2023 forecast for Disney+.</p>
<p>As of the end of fiscal 2021, Disney says it had 179 million total subscriptions across Disney+, ESPN+ and Hulu. It plans to more than double the number of countries Disney+ is available in to over 160 by its fiscal 2023.</p>
<p>Though the new international content group is new, Disney says it already has more than 340 local and regional titles in various stages of production and development for its streaming services. That number will grow over time, as Campbell, who previously served as chairman of International Operations and Direct-to-Consumer, will focus on expanding the international content pipeline. In her expanded role, she&#8217;ll also continue to overseas teams in Asia Pacific, EMEA, India and Latin America.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259536" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The creation of the International Content and Operations group gives Disney a fourth home for content creation, alongside its Studios Content, General Entertainment Content and Sports Content groups, Disney says. This addition highlights the importance of establishing an expanded global footprint in streaming to better compete with streamers like Netflix, which is still trying to figure out how to win subscribers in some markets, like India, where it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/struggling-to-win-subscribers-netflix-cuts-prices-in-india/">recently had to cut prices</a>. HBO Max has also had its eye on gaining an international footprint, with <a href="https://pressroom.warnermedia.com/us/media-release/hbo-max/hbo-max-launch-first-european-countries-october-26">recent launches</a> in parts of Europe.</p>
<p>In addition to the new international content hub, Disney has also reorganized other parts of its streaming business.</p>
<p>The company promoted Joe Earley, previously EVP, Marketing &amp; Operations for Disney+, as the new president of Hulu. He&#8217;ll report to Michael Paull, who has been promoted to the newly created role of president, Disney Streaming, which will be accountable for Disney+, Hulu, ESPN+ and Star+ globally. Paull&#8217;s prior role as head of Disney+ has yet to be filled. In his new position, he reports to Disney Media &amp; Entertainment Distribution (DMED) Chairman, Kareem Daniel.</p>
<p>&#8220;Disney’s direct-to-consumer efforts have progressed at a tremendous pace in just a few short years, and our organization has continued to grow and evolve in support of our ambitious global streaming strategy,&#8221; Chapek said, in a <a href="https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/the-walt-disney-company-creates-international-content-group-to-expand-pipeline-of-local-content-and-continue-to-grow-its-global-direct-to-consumer-business/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> announcing the organizational changes. &#8220;Rebecca has played a vital role in orchestrating our global platform expansion, and I’m excited that she will be leading our new International Content group, bringing her expertise and talent to oversee the growing pipeline of original local and regional content for our streaming services while continuing to lead our international operations. Likewise, with a relentless focus on serving consumers, Kareem has developed an industry-leading team of seasoned executives who are uniquely equipped to take our streaming business into Disney’s next century.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/disneys-streaming-biz-reorg-includes-an-international-content-hub-plans-to-double-disney-footprint/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259536</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As its data flows woes grow, Google lobbies for quickie fix to EU-US transfers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/google-lobbies-for-new-privacy-shield/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/google-lobbies-for-new-privacy-shield/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 18:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data retention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dutch dpa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU-US Privacy Shield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gina Raimondo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kent Walker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noyb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safe harbor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schrems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the legal uncertainty in Europe clouding use of US cloud services cranks up, Google has responded by firing up its lobbying engines to call for US and European lawmakers to get a move on and come up a new rubberstamp to grease transatlantic data flows as usual as the bloc&#8217;s regulators finally start to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As the legal uncertainty in Europe clouding use of US cloud services cranks up, Google has responded by firing up its lobbying engines to call for US and European lawmakers to get a move on and come up a new rubberstamp to grease transatlantic data flows as usual as the bloc&#8217;s regulators finally start to find their banhammers.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/austrian-dpa-schrems-ii/">Last week</a>, Austria&#8217;s data protection authority decided that a local website&#8217;s use of Google Analytics to have breached the bloc&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) over the risk of US intelligence agencies being able to access site users&#8217; personal data.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/its-time-for-a-new-eu-us-data-transfer-framework/">blog post </a>calling for &#8220;a new EU-US data transfer framework&#8221;, Google&#8217;s Kent Walker flags this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/austrian-dpa-schrems-ii/">decision </a>before seeking to downplay its significant &#8212; writing that Google has offered its eponymous analytics service to business for 15 years and &#8220;never once received the type of demand the DPA speculated about&#8221;, before adding: &#8220;We don&#8217;t expect to receive one because such a demand would be unlikely to fall within the narrow scope of the relevant law.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259393" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s a reassuring-sounding soundbite by Google&#8217;s (and its parent Alphabet&#8217;s) chief lawyer and president of global affairs.</p>
<p>The problem is, legally speaking, it&#8217;s irrelevant &#8212; as it&#8217;s roughly the equivalent of Walker saying &#8216;waaa, EU law is not fair!&#8217;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">protections to customers of <a href="https://twitter.com/Google?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Google</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Microsoft?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Microsoft</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/AWS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@AWS</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Apple</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Meta?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Meta</a> (&#8230;) once their data is processed by US industry &#8211; otherwise your customers will sooner or later be gone, just like people don&#39;t trust Russian or Chinese &quot;cloud&quot; providers.. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f610.png" alt="😐" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TimeToLobbyTheUScongress?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TimeToLobbyTheUScongress</a> (2)</p>
<p>&mdash; Max Schrems <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f1ea-1f1fa.png" alt="🇪🇺" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@maxschrems) <a href="https://twitter.com/maxschrems/status/1483795305225240582?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 19, 2022</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The lack of rights and redress for foreigners whose information gets scooped up by US authorities &#8212; or is <em>at risk of getting scooped up</em> &#8212; as a result of sweeping US surveillance laws (such as FISA 702), which apply broadly to electronic service providers like Google, is in stark conflict with the EU&#8217;s data protection framework which requires that an &#8220;essentially equivalent&#8221; level of protection applies to EU people&#8217;s information if it&#8217;s exported outside the bloc.</p>
<p>The key point is Europeans&#8217; personal data must be effectively shielded from the risk of unauthorized access/misuse &#8212; NB: data doesn&#8217;t <em>actually</em> have to have been grabbed by the NSA for any laws to apply! &#8212; in order for the level of protection wrapping exported data to be considered legally adequate.</p>
<p>This is not a blanket ban on personal data transfers out of the EU to third countries because EU law leaves open the possibility that, where there are risks, so called &#8220;supplementary measures&#8221; may be applied to these kinds of transfers to raise the level of protection to the required standard.</p>
<p>These special measures could be additions at a legal, organization or procedural level (e.g. contract clauses, data retention policies); or, indeed, specific technical measures (like data localization; or true end-to-end encryption with zero access to the data via a third country-based provider or any of their subsidiaries) &#8212; or, for added assurance, a blend of several layered add-ons.</p>
<p>Google claims it had applied enough such extras to boost the level of data protection in the Austrian case.</p>
<p>However the DPA disagreed &#8212; finding Google&#8217;s claimed supplements did not cut the mustard, for all Walker&#8217;s claims of &#8220;<a href="https://services.google.com/fh/files/misc/safeguards_for_international_data_transfers.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-analytics-onclick="{&quot;event&quot;:&quot;page interaction&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;in-article links&quot;,&quot;action&quot;:&quot;link click&quot;,&quot;label&quot;:&quot;https://services.google.com/fh/files/misc/safeguards_for_international_data_transfers.pdf&quot;}">extensive supplementary measures</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s notable that his sentence immediately qualifies that claim &#8212; saying the measures apply &#8220;practical and effective protection of data to any reasonable standard&#8221;.</p>
<p>So, essentially, Google&#8217;s lobbying sleight of hand there seeks to replace <em>actual</em> EU legal standards over personal data transfers with a <em>Google-defined</em> &#8220;reasonable&#8221; standard (which has already been found unreasonable by at least two EU data supervisors&#8230; ).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s evident that rather than Google change its business practices &#8212; say, by offering Google Analytics users data localization plus encryption key escrow via an EU-based third party, plus some robust contractual clauses about challenging access requests &#8212; the tech giant is resorting to loudly yelling for lawmakers to &#8216;fix&#8217; its legal headache with a quickie data transfer pact.</p>
<p>The problem for Google is that the legal conflict between US surveillance law and EU data protection law isn&#8217;t something that can be quickly and quietly papered over anymore.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qnJCTvrCV2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/no-quick-fix-for-transatlantic-data-transfers-says-ec/">No quick fix for transatlantic data transfers, says EC</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;No quick fix for transatlantic data transfers, says EC&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/no-quick-fix-for-transatlantic-data-transfers-says-ec/embed/#?secret=qnJCTvrCV2" data-secret="qnJCTvrCV2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The European Commission has tried doing that before, and while the Safe Harbor (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/06/europes-top-court-strikes-down-safe-harbor-data-transfer-agreement-with-u-s/">RIP</a>) arrangement for transatlantic data transfers stood for around 15 years before the EU&#8217;s top court struck it down, the replacement Privacy Shield only managed about four before the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/europes-top-court-strikes-down-flagship-eu-us-data-transfer-mechanism/">court struck again</a>, even more definitively.</p>
<p>EU lawmakers are unlikely to want a third bullseye &#8212; even if they are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/11/eu-us-privacy-shield-is-dead-long-live-privacy-shield/">keen on (and still in talks about) a replacement Privacy Shield</a> to grease EU-US commerce.</p>
<p>The so-called &#8216;Schrems II&#8217; CJEU decision that shattered the EU-US Privacy Shield did not close the door to personal data exports entirely but the court was careful to seek to pre-empt the risk of non-compliant-business-as-usual by underscoring that data flows must be assessed on a case by case basis and notified in advance to DPAs which &#8212; the court also made clear &#8212; can&#8217;t just sit on their hands and do in fact have a legal duty to suspend risky transfers.</p>
<p>The ruling also reiterated that EU-<em>US</em> transfers specifically are risky &#8212; hence blasting Privacy Shield (and Safe Harbor) to smithereens.</p>
<p>This is why US cloud services are so clearly in the frame.</p>
<p>The lack of a federal privacy law in the US which can offer an equivalent to EU&#8217;s GDPR is the underlying problem. And that essentially means the missing piece is also substantial reform of US surveillance laws &#8212; something that&#8217;s provided impossible to achieve so far (even regarding <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/16/senate-fisa-section-702-cloture-vote-wyden-paul/">warrantless spying on US citizens</a>, let alone foreigners).</p>
<p>In the meanwhile, more enforcements against non-compliant data transfers are looming.</p>
<p>If the Austrian&#8217;s decision over a single, local website&#8217;s use of Google Analytics risks sounding like small fry, around a hundred similar complaints were filed across the bloc <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/18/eu-websites-use-of-google-analytics-and-facebook-connect-targeted-by-post-schrems-ii-privacy-complaints/">back in August 2020</a>, by European privacy campaigner noyb &#8212; also targeting use of Facebook Connect &#8212; so scores of similar decisions are pending.</p>
<p>Which means a potential pipeline of problems for Google in Europe over tools like Google Analytics&#8230;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LygCi8Myar"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/18/eu-websites-use-of-google-analytics-and-facebook-connect-targeted-by-post-schrems-ii-privacy-complaints/">EU websites&#8217; use of Google Analytics and Facebook Connect targeted by post-Schrems II privacy complaints</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EU websites&#8217; use of Google Analytics and Facebook Connect targeted by post-Schrems II privacy complaints&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/18/eu-websites-use-of-google-analytics-and-facebook-connect-targeted-by-post-schrems-ii-privacy-complaints/embed/#?secret=LygCi8Myar" data-secret="LygCi8Myar" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://edpb.europa.eu/news/news/2021/edpb-establishes-cookie-banner-taskforce_en">Last fall</a> the European Data Protection Board set up a taskforce to co-ordinate the response to this flotilla of complaints. So where one DPA has found use of Google Analytics breaches the GDPR others are likely to follow shortly.</p>
<p>(Note for example the Dutch DPA &#8212; which issued <a href="https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/nl/onderwerpen/internet-telefoon-tv-en-post/cookies#hoe-kan-ik-bij-google-analytics-de-privacy-van-mijn-websitebezoekers-beschermen-4898">emergency guidance</a> last week warning that use of Google Analytics &#8220;may soon not be allowed&#8221;. In an FAQ section of its website where it makes the warning &#8212; under the topic of &#8220;how can I protect the privacy of my website visitors with Google Analytics&#8221; &#8212; the regulator also wrote: &#8220;The AP [itself] is currently investigating two complaints about the use of Google Analytics in the Netherlands. Upon completion of that investigation, in early 2022, the AP will be able to say whether Google Analytics is now allowed or not.&#8221;)</p>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/edps-decision-european-parliament-covid-19-test-website/">another notable recent decision</a>, the European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS) reprimanded the European Parliament over the presence of Google Analytics and Stripe in the code of a COVID-19 test booking website that had been built for it by a third party supplier. Again, use of Google Analytics was found to breach the regulation given the problem of US data transfers &#8212; although the website provider had also failed to properly implement cookie consents so there were multiple compliance problems in that case. And while the Parliament escaped a fine (on procedural grounds) the regulatory hot water led it to yank Google Analytics long before the decision landed.</p>
<p>So how many other European entities will now be looking increasingly uneasily at their website plug-ins? (After all, alternatives to tools like Google Analytics which don&#8217;t require schlepping data to the US do already exist. So the old &#8216;no one got sacked for installing US tech calculus may start to shift.)</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s blog prefers to spin the possibility that it&#8217;s about to lose a whole bunch of European customers into a typical Big Tech projection that the doom will rain down mercilessly as a nuclear storm &#8212; seeking to whip up fear among lawmakers over the impact on small businesses of them not &#8220;aligning&#8221; the literal law with Google&#8217;s preferred way of doing business.</p>
<h2>Case by case</h2>
<p>What&#8217;s clear is that the regulatory noose is tightening when it comes to Chapter V of the GDPR &#8212; and that has major implications for many US tech giants as their services often involve transferring user data outside the bloc.</p>
<p>The legal risks are varied, though, since data flows are now being analyzed on a case by case basis.</p>
<p>Which is also why having a top-level transfer deal is so sought for &#8212; since it massively simplifies compliance issues involved in exporting EU users&#8217; data.</p>
<p>In another case, Facebook has been spectacularly successful at fending off regulatory action against its EU-US data transfers for literally years, thanks to its forum shopping and deep pockets to splash money on lawyers. But its data flows are<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/"> surely operating on borrowed time</a> &#8212; after a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/facebook-told-it-may-have-to-suspend-eu-data-transfers-after-schrems-ii-ruling/">preliminary suspension order by Ireland in 2020</a>; and Facebook&#8217;s subsequent failure to block it in the Irish courts.</p>
<p>Ireland&#8217;s regulator agreed it would &#8220;swiftly&#8221; finalize a decision on those EU-to-US flows <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/">over a year ago</a>.</p>
<p>Nor is it only Google and Facebook on the hook here.</p>
<p>Since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/eu-bodies-use-of-us-cloud-services-from-aws-microsoft-being-probed-by-blocs-privacy-chief/">May</a>, the EDPS has been investigating EU institutions&#8217; cloud contracts with AWS and Microsoft over similar compliance concerns.</p>
<p>If the EU&#8217;s chief data supervisor concludes those US cloud services are also unable to adequately protect Europeans&#8217; data it could essentially order that alternative services be found to take their place.</p>
<p>And that could then kick off a snowball of service switching, given the EDPS&#8217; steering role as the EU&#8217;s top data supervisor.</p>
<p>So Google is quite right that the data flows issue could have multiple impacts.</p>
<p>A finding of compliance problems with those US cloud contracts is not certain, though &#8212; because, one again, each data transfer is different. And it&#8217;s possible that adequate supplementary measures are being applied in those cases.</p>
<p>AWS, for example, survived a legal challenge related to use of its service in France <a href="https://iapp.org/news/a/why-this-french-court-decision-has-far-reaching-consequences-for-many-businesses/">last year</a>. In that case the website (Doctolib) had been hosted by AWS in the EU (with data centers in France and Germany). But as the EU entity (AWS Sarl) is a subsidiary of US-based AWS, which is subject to US law, the legal challenge concerned its extraterritorial effects &#8212; and the potential for US authorities to obtain data from an EU-based subsidiary via the US-based parent regardless of the data not leaving the EU.</p>
<p>The extraterritorial reach of US law creates an extra layer of compliance headaches for even those US cloud giants that <em>do</em> offer data localization via an EU subsidiary. (Or, to put it another way, data localization alone still may not be enough.)</p>
<p>In the Doctolib case, the French court ruled that the data <em>was</em> sufficiently protected owing to a series of applied supplementary measures &#8212; both legal and technical &#8212; and also based on their assessment of the specifics of the data transfers and procedures put in place.</p>
<p>Specifically, the data being processed by AWS was not considered by the court to be health data (which attracts a very high level of compliance requirements) as it was more limited in scope (related to booking vaccine appointments).</p>
<p>Additionally, the data retention had been limited to three months; data was encrypted and the key held by a trusted third party in the EU (not by AWS Sarl). And, furthermore, a contract between Doctolib and AWS Sarl included a clause setting out a specific procedure in the event of an access request by a foreign authority &#8212; including a guarantee that AWS Sarl would challenge any general access request from a public authority.</p>
<p>So, in other words, a full package of measures had been applied &#8212; and were, in the end, found to be sufficient by the French court.</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s Walker is therefore quite right when he writes that the CJEU&#8217;s July 2020 ruling &#8220;did not impose an inflexible standard&#8221;.</p>
<p>Compliance with EU-US data flows post-Schrems II has been demonstrated to be possible &#8212; and indeed available. Just not, per recent regulatory decisions, if you&#8217;re using Google Analytics&#8230;</p>
<h2>Spinning for time</h2>
<p>Despite what is clearly a major problem for Google in Europe, in his blog post, Walker seeks to spin the compliance issue as more an existential crisis for its customers (&#8220;publishers and small businesses&#8221;) &#8212; and even for the &#8220;open, global internet&#8221; as a whole &#8212; warning that the Austrian decision &#8220;may portend broader challenges&#8221; and suggesting &#8220;hundreds of billion euros&#8221; of damage could be done to Europe’s economy if lawmakers don&#8217;t figure out how to stop the regulatory banhammers from falling.</p>
<p>Yet given that other US services have found ways to comply with Schrems II that&#8217;s clearly plain wrong &#8212; as well as terrible hubris.</p>
<p>It is also hypocrisy. If Google was once synonymous with the open web, as a small, garage-based startup building a better search engine, the rapacious adtech giant &#8212; whose business is under investigation in both the EU and the US on multiple fronts, spanning antitrust, consumer protection and privacy charges, to name a few &#8212; that it&#8217;s turned into is a lot more walled garden than open web these days.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Instead of taking the necessary steps to adapt its business processes to respect EU law &#8212; by developing supplementary measures that are actually deemed sufficient by regulators &#8212; Google has reached down to rattle its sabre, pointing to its market power in a bid to scare legislators into aligning their pesky rules with how it mints money.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Businesses in both Europe and the U.S. are looking to the European Commission and the U.S. Department of Commerce to quickly finalize a successor agreement to the Privacy Shield that will resolve these issues,&#8221; pens Walker, before trumpeting that: &#8220;The stakes are too high &#8212; and international trade between Europe and the U.S. too important to the livelihoods of millions of people &#8212; to fail at finding a prompt solution to this imminent problem.&#8221;</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s motivation in penning the blog post likely has more than half eye on cooling the nerves of shareholders who may be spooked by regulatory enforcements. Hence repeat suggestions that a fix is about to materialized with talk of governments &#8220;finaliz[ing]&#8221; a &#8220;revised agreement&#8221; that can be &#8220;a durable framework&#8221; (i.e. that won&#8217;t just get shot down again by the CJEU in a few years).</p>
<p>There is a very half-hearted and passing mention to US surveillance reform too, with Walker claiming: &#8220;We have long <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/digital-security-and-due-process-new-legal-framework-cloud-era/" data-analytics-onclick="{&quot;event&quot;:&quot;page interaction&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;in-article links&quot;,&quot;action&quot;:&quot;link click&quot;,&quot;label&quot;:&quot;https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/digital-security-and-due-process-new-legal-framework-cloud-era/&quot;}">advocated</a> for government transparency, lawful processes, and surveillance reform.&#8221;</p>
<p>But his loudest call is for a quick fix &#8212; with the Google president segueing instantly from the topic of surveillance reform to redouble his push for the quickest of fixes (&#8220;we urge quick action&#8221;), and further pressing: &#8220;At this juncture, we urge both governments to take a flexible and aligned approach to resolving this important issue.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is unfortunate phrasing since, technically speaking, the EU is not a &#8220;government&#8221;. But since Google&#8217;s grasp of the detail of EU data protection compliance has been found wanting we should not be surprised that it doesn&#8217;t really understand EU governance either.</p>
<p>TechCrunch contacted the European Commission with questions about the negotiations towards Google&#8217;s sought for quickie replacement data transfer deal.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for the EU&#8217;s executive cautioned that &#8220;some time&#8221; is needed given the &#8220;complexity&#8221; involved in trying to &#8220;strike a balance between privacy and national security&#8221;, as they put it &#8212; emphasizing that any replacement arrangement must be &#8220;fully compliant with the requirements set by the EU court&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Securing a new arrangement for safe transatlantic data flows is a priority for us and our U.S. partners,&#8221; they told us, adding that &#8220;negotiations have intensified in the past months, with discussions at technical and political level&#8221; &#8212; which they specified have included regular contacts between commissioner Reynders and his counterpart, US Secretary for commerce, Gina Raimondo (with the last one taking place in mid-December).</p>
<p>&#8220;Only an arrangement that is fully compliant with the requirements set by the EU court can deliver the stability and legal certainty stakeholders expect on both sides of the Atlantic,&#8221; they also told us, adding: &#8220;These negotiations take some time, given also the complexity of the issues discussed and the need to strike a balance between privacy and national security.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked about replacements that companies seeking legal certainly in the meanwhile can make use of, the spokesperson said only [emphasis ours]: &#8220;Until we find a sustainable solution with the US, other tools for international data transfers such as the Standard Contractual Clauses can still be used <strong><em>under certain conditions</em></strong>. That is one of the reasons why we adopted modernised Standard Contractual Clauses in June 2021.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jMpaJPsdtK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/eu-puts-out-final-guidance-on-data-transfers-to-third-countries/">EU puts out final guidance on data transfers to third countries</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EU puts out final guidance on data transfers to third countries&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/eu-puts-out-final-guidance-on-data-transfers-to-third-countries/embed/#?secret=jMpaJPsdtK" data-secret="jMpaJPsdtK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZrFcI2zSXa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/clouds-gather-over-us-cloud-services-after-cjeu-ruling/">Legal clouds gather over US cloud services, after CJEU ruling</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Legal clouds gather over US cloud services, after CJEU ruling&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/clouds-gather-over-us-cloud-services-after-cjeu-ruling/embed/#?secret=ZrFcI2zSXa" data-secret="ZrFcI2zSXa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/google-lobbies-for-new-privacy-shield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tom Brady&#8217;s buzzy celebrity NFT startup Autograph banks $170M from Silicon Valley&#8217;s top crypto investors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/tom-bradys-buzzy-celebrity-nft-startup-autograph-banks-170m-from-silicon-valleys-top-crypto-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/tom-bradys-buzzy-celebrity-nft-startup-autograph-banks-170m-from-silicon-valleys-top-crypto-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arianna Simpson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[athlete]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bolt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Derek Jeter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DraftKings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eddy cue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Floyd Mayweather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ilya Fushman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katie Haun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Kardashian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kleiner Perkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Damon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFL players association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicole Quinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger woods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tom brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tony hawk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Velvet Sea Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259481</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Autograph, an NFT agency co-founded by athlete Tom Brady with a particularly deep bench of star power, has banked new funding from crypto investors who hope the platform can bring a new generation of celebrities and their fans into the fold of crypto collectibles. The startup tells TechCrunch it has closed a $170 million Series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://autograph.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Autograph</a>, an NFT agency co-founded by athlete Tom Brady with a particularly deep bench of star power, has banked new funding from crypto investors who hope the platform can bring a new generation of celebrities and their fans into the fold of crypto collectibles.</p>
<p>The startup tells TechCrunch it has closed a $170 million Series B round led by Andreessen Horowitz and Kleiner Perkins with participation from Katie Haun&#8217;s new fund and Lightspeed partner Nicole Quinn. This comes on the heels of a Series A round co-led by 01A and Velvet Sea Ventures that closed this past July. The raise adds three new members to the board, including Haun, a16z&#8217;s Arianna Simpson and Kleiner Perkins&#8217;s Ilya Fushman.</p>
<p>They join an expansive board with some major names, including Brady, Apple&#8217;s Eddy Cue, FTX&#8217;s Sam Bankman-Fried and artist Abel Tesfaye, also known as The Weeknd.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259481" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ptkv9AOPh8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/katie-haun-is-splitting-off-from-a16z-to-launch-her-own-crypto-fund/">Katie Haun is splitting off from a16z to launch her own crypto fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Katie Haun is splitting off from a16z to launch her own crypto fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/katie-haun-is-splitting-off-from-a16z-to-launch-her-own-crypto-fund/embed/#?secret=ptkv9AOPh8" data-secret="ptkv9AOPh8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Autograph is essentially an agency go-between for celebrity athletes and entertainers looking to find a personal presence in the incredibly noisy NFT world. Celebrity NFT drops have been a mixed bag since the crypto collectibles skyrocketed to popularity early last year. While some have come into the space with thoughtful projects that reward their fans, there have been a multitude of ridicule-generating cash grabs.</p>
<p>Crypto has generally been a tough place for discerning celebrities to make a dent or earn a buck without losing some of their cultural capital. Matt Damon received a fair share of ridicule this month for appearing in a corny crypto ad campaign. Earlier this week Kim Kardashian and Floyd Mayweather were named in lawsuit brought by disgruntled investors who had backed a token that the two had earlier endorsed.</p>
<p>While fellow NFT unicorn Dapper Labs has inked partnerships with a handful overarching American sports league players associations, including the NFL Players Association and the NBA&#8217;s Player Association, Autograph seems to be more focused on the individual athletes and the cult of personality built around them outside the context of the teams they play on or leagues they are part of. Autograph has a handful of early partners largely in the sports world, but the names represent some of the most famous athletes in their respective sports, including Brady, Tiger Woods, Simone Biles, Derek Jeter, Naomi Osaka, Usain Bolt, Wayne Gretzky and Tony Hawk.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Autograph&#8217;s aim seems to be in building out an onramp to the space where triple-A listers can dip their toes into crypto influencing in a more highly curated environment.</p>
<p>In July, Autograph announced a partnership with DraftKings, though the startup tells TechCrunch it has been working with a number of marketplaces. Autograph has been primarily serving up its NFTs on the Polygon blockchain, which taps into Ethereum&#8217;s infrastructure but uses significantly less energy per transaction, a fact that&#8217;s likely important to celebrities who may be wary to open themselves up to environmental critiques of blockchain technologies.</p>
<p>Outside the sports world, Autograph has done drops with The Weeknd, Slam Magazine and officially-licensed NFTs for the horror series Saw.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="40OeSqtB0C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/draftkings-shares-plans-for-launch-of-nft-collectibles-marketplace/">DraftKings shares plans for launch of NFT collectibles marketplace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DraftKings shares plans for launch of NFT collectibles marketplace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/draftkings-shares-plans-for-launch-of-nft-collectibles-marketplace/embed/#?secret=40OeSqtB0C" data-secret="40OeSqtB0C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/tom-bradys-buzzy-celebrity-nft-startup-autograph-banks-170m-from-silicon-valleys-top-crypto-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259481</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram launches early test of creator subscriptions in the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/instagram-launches-early-test-of-creator-subscriptions-in-the-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/instagram-launches-early-test-of-creator-subscriptions-in-the-u-s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram is giving creators more ways to make money with today&#8217;s launch of Instagram Subscriptions. The feature, which was spotted hitting the App Store back in November, is now officially in early testing with a small group of U.S. creators who will be able to offer their followers paid access to exclusive Instagram Live videos [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram is giving creators more ways to make money with today&#8217;s launch of Instagram Subscriptions. The feature, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/08/instagrams-creator-subscriptions-nearing-launch-app-store-listing-reveals/">spotted hitting the App Store</a> back in November, is now officially in early testing with a small group of U.S. creators who will be able to offer their followers paid access to exclusive Instagram Live videos and Stories. Subscribers will also receive a special badge that will help them to stand out in the comments section and creators&#8217; inboxes.</p>
<p>At launch, only 10 total U.S. creators have gained access to the new feature, as Instagram considers this an &#8220;alpha&#8221; test meant to allow for feedback from fans and creators alike, which it will then iterate upon.</p>
<p>Currently, the list of alpha creators includes actor and influencer <a href="https://www.instagram.com/alanchikinchow/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@alanchikinchow</a>; basketball player <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sedona._/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@sedona._</a>; astrologer <a href="https://www.instagram.com/alizakelly/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@alizakelly</a>; dancer/actress/model <a href="https://www.instagram.com/kelseylynncook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@kelseylynncook</a>; digital creator <a href="https://www.instagram.com/elliottnorris/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@elliottnorris</a>; Olympic silver medalist <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jordanchiles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jordanchiles</a>; gymnast and creator <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jackjerry/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jackjerry</a>; spiritual coach and artist <a href="https://www.instagram.com/bunnymichael/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@bunnymichael</a>; XR creator <a href="https://www.instagram.com/donalleniii/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@donalleniii</a>; and digital creator <a href="https://www.instagram.com/lonnieiiv/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@lonnieiiv</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259398" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Through the Subscriptions product, creators can choose their own price point for access to their exclusive content. There are eight price points to choose from, starting at $0.99 per to month to as much as $99.99 per month, depending on how much a creator believes their content is worth. Most creators will likely start toward the bottom of that range, at price points like $0.99, $1.99, $2.99, $4.99 or maybe even $9.99 per month, before experimenting with higher pricing like $19.99, $49.99 or $99.99 per month.</p>
<p>Once subscribed, users will be able to access prior subscriber-only content, like Stories saved as Highlights, for example. They&#8217;ll be alerted to exclusive broadcasts, where they&#8217;ll be able to engage more deeply with the creators as the viewing audience will be, naturally, smaller. In subscriber-only Stories, indicated with a purple ring, creators may share things like behind-the-scenes content, special polls and more. Subscriber badges, also purple, will help fans stand out in the comments of public content, and will help them to be identified in creators&#8217; message request folders in the inbox.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2259429" style="width: 554px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259429" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2259429" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg?w=544" alt="" width="544" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg?resize=768,960 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg?resize=544,680 544w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/instagram-subscriptions-1.jpeg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 544px) 100vw, 544px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259429" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<p>Although <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1412465982656991233" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there had been reports</a> that Instagram was developing technology that would prevent creators&#8217; exclusive content from being screenshot, Instagram told us there isn&#8217;t any such technology available during this initial test phase. However, resharing the content is a violation of its terms and creators are being encouraged to report anyone screenshotting or recording their content.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>There&#8217;s also no dedicated section for Subscriptions in creators&#8217; analytics dashboards during the early tests. But creators will be able to access their total estimated earnings from subscriptions, total subscribers, new subscriptions and cancellations from their Subscriptions Settings. They aren&#8217;t able to export subscriber lists, or any sort of data, but Instagram says it hopes to build tools that would allow creators to connect with subscribers &#8220;off-platform&#8221; in the future.</p>
<p>For fans, signing up for a subscription to their favorite creators&#8217; content takes place via traditional in-app purchases across iOS and Android. And for now, Instagram is not taking a cut of the creators&#8217; revenues.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are the same as all of Meta &#8212; we&#8217;re not taking any rev share until at least 2023,&#8221; noted Instagram co-head of Product, Ashley Yuki. &#8220;Our main goal here is that we help creators make a living&#8230;We&#8217;re trying to think of all the ways that we can build monetization products where that&#8217;s possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>Of course, Instagram isn&#8217;t just trying to help creators make a living. It&#8217;s also trying to shore up its platform against the threat of competition, namely from TikTok, which has attracted a growing number of creators looking to reach a younger, Gen Z following. It&#8217;s also seen other large tech rivals, like YouTube and Snapchat, try to appeal to TikTok users with similar short-form video products, like Instagram&#8217;s TikTok clone called Reels. Meanwhile, even Twitter has launched its own creator initiative with its Super Follow platform, and numerous startups are working on services that allow creators to consolidate, track and monetize their following in new ways.</p>
<p>The activity in this space is a reflection of the size of the market. The creator economy is <a href="https://influencermarketinghub.com/creator-earnings-benchmark-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimated</a> to be a little over $100 billion dollars, and growing. Even if Instagram (and Facebook) defer collecting their cut of creator transactions for a year, Meta sees it as a small investment in ensuring a larger piece of that pie going forward.</p>
<p>Despite the competitive landscape, Instagram believes its strength will come from the fact that it&#8217;s <em>not</em> a new product.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the biggest differentiators here for creators and for fans is just the convenience of the fact that you actually know how to use all these things already. You&#8217;re already on Instagram. And we hear a lot [about] the friction of having to do the &#8216;click out.&#8217; It might seem like a small thing. But in those moments, it can be the difference between having someone jump over your subscription or not,&#8221; explained Yuki. &#8220;The convenience of just having it all where the conversation and connection is already happening, we think is going to be one of the strongest points of this for both creators and for fans,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Instagram Subscriptions is only one way Meta has been working to help creators monetize. Last year, Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/creators/earn-money-with-subscriptions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rebranded</a> Facebook Fan Subscriptions to just &#8220;Subscriptions,&#8221; and allowed creators to download their subscribers&#8217; emails. Facebook creators can also use personalized links to promote their subscriptions. And across Facebook and Instagram, creators can participate in Meta&#8217;s <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/07/investing-1-billion-dollars-in-creators/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$1 billion bonus program</a>.</p>
<p>In time, it seems likely that Facebook and Instagram Subscriptions could merge. If that came to be, fans would also be able to sign up on Facebook or Instagram &#8212; including via the websites, where no App Store commissions would need to be paid. And those subscriptions could carry over to the respective mobile apps. Yuki didn&#8217;t discount the idea, when asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;In this alpha, that&#8217;s not implemented yet. But that&#8217;s something that we could definitely consider for the future,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg also touted the launch on his Facebook profile today, noting Subscriptions would &#8220;help creators earn more by offering benefits to their most engaged followers like access to exclusive Lives and Stories.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m excited to keep building tools for creators to make a living doing creative work and to put these tools in more creators&#8217; hands soon,&#8221; he wrote.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/instagram-launches-early-test-of-creator-subscriptions-in-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259398</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Israel&#8217;s Viola Ventures hits $250M for its new fund, appoints Yael Alroy as partner</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/israels-viola-ventures-hits-250m-for-its-new-fund-appoints-yael-alroy-as-partner/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/israels-viola-ventures-hits-250m-for-its-new-fund-appoints-yael-alroy-as-partner/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immunai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IronSource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outbrain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payoneer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viola group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viola Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Viola Ventures, an Israeli VC, has closed its sixth fund of $250 million. It now has $1.25 billion in assets under management, largely early-stage tech companies. Viola says the fund was oversubscribed and reached its hard cap. With the new fund, Viola Ventures will invest in 25-30 early-stage (seed and A round) companies, in its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.viola-group.com/fund/violaventures/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Viola Ventures</a>, an Israeli VC, has closed its sixth fund of $250 million. It now has $1.25 billion in assets under management, largely early-stage tech companies. Viola says the fund was oversubscribed and reached its hard cap.</p>
<p>With the new fund, Viola Ventures will invest in 25-30 early-stage (seed and A round) companies, in its core verticals such as fintech, vertical AI and deep tech, digital health, next-gen enterprise infrastructure, SaaS 3.0, web3 and cybersecurity.</p>
<p>Viola Ventures has invested in numerous startups, including ironSource, Payoneer, Redis, Verbit, Outbrain, Pagaya, Lightricks and Immunai.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259539" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>2021 was a bumper year for Israeli tech. Tech firms <a href="https://startupnationcentral.org/news/start-up-nation-central-summarizes-2021-a-record-breaking-year-for-israeli-tech-25-billion-raised-and-an-unprecedented-number/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised</a> $25.6 billion (representing 136% growth in equity investments over 2020) and 22 tech companies went public with a cumulative market cap of over $84 billion.</p>
<p>Viola Ventures says eight of its portfolio companies reached unicorn status. IronSource went public at a valuation of $11 billion. Pagaya has announced its public listing at an $8.5 billion valuation.</p>
<p>Danny Cohen, general partner at Viola Ventures, said: “It’s not only important to invest in high-performing companies but to invest in them early. Our track record proves that we know how to identify outstanding teams, aggressively be the first money, and then support them to unicorn status and beyond. We are confident that our sixth fund will help grow the next generation of market leaders.”</p>
<p>The fund recently promoted <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yaelalroy/?originalSubdomain=il" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yael Alroy</a>, a principal at the fund, to partner and appointed a dedicated partner from the executive search industry, Jeff Shapiro.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/israels-viola-ventures-hits-250m-for-its-new-fund-appoints-yael-alroy-as-partner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259539</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The berserk pace of fintech investing outshines the global VC boom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/the-berserk-pace-of-fintech-investing-outshines-the-global-vc-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/the-berserk-pace-of-fintech-investing-outshines-the-global-vc-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cb insights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It appears that what is true for the venture capital market is also true for the fintech market, but in a more exaggerated form. Fintech is like most venture, but simply more extreme.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/data-show-2021-was-a-bonkers-record-setting-year-for-venture-capital/">global startup fundraising boom</a> has lifted nearly every sector you can name: Edtech took off during the pandemic, software in general got a lift, and even more risky and long-term wagers like space tech and biotech are seemingly doing well in today’s risk-on startup fundraising market.</p>
<p>But no single category or niche in startup land has done better than financial technology, or fintech.</p>
<p>Around the world, fintech startups have raised simply astounding amounts of capital, with geographies like Latin America, Africa, North America, and more seeing neobanks, payments companies, new consumer-facing lending services, cryptocurrency on-ramps from the traditional banking world, trading apps, and other sub-sectors raising tectonic rounds from investors hungry to get their own capital to work in the craze.</p>
<h2>No surprises</h2>
<p>Global venture funding reached a record $621 billion in 2021, according to the <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/reports/CB-Insights_Venture-Report-2021.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CB Insights 2021 State of Venture Report</a>. That’s more than double 2020&#8217;s total of $294 billion.</p>
<p>In 2021, global fintech funding jumped to a new record of $131.5 billion across 4,969 deals. That compares to $49 billion across 3,491 deals in 2020. As you can see, the pace at which capital was invested into fintech startups in 2021 grew much more rapidly than total deal count, leading to larger rounds on average. The CB Insights data that we’re citing here also helps put the pace of fintech investing into context compared to its peer startup groups, with financial technology companies raising one in every five venture capital dollars last year, or some 21%.</p>
<p>The fevered pace at which fintech startups attracted external capital continued: In the fourth quarter of 2021, fintech funding reached $34.9 billion – second only to Q2 2021, which saw funding total $36.6 billion. Deal flow was similar – 1,256 in Q4 compared to 1,224 in Q2.</p>
<p>To make those numbers a bit more understandable to our monkey brains, in the fourth quarter inclusive of weekends, holidays, and other non-working periods, some 14 fintech deals were announced <em>every day</em>, worth $387,777,777 every 24 hours. That’s pretty fucking rapid.</p>
<p><img class="breakout wp-image-2259445 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-10.50.05-AM-1.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>The fintech venture market is so big, in fact, that its outlines mirror those of the venture capital market itself. The United States, for example, led in fintech funding in Q4, as it did in total venture capital dollars in the year. The U.S. was followed by Asia and Europe in fintech investment – with $18.2 billion invested in U.S. fintechs, compared to $8.2 billion and $5.6 billion in Asia and Europe, respectively.</p>
<p>While still lagging globally, Latin America came in at an impressive fourth place with $1.9 billion in funding in fintech startups. (Note: In Q3, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/why-latams-fintech-boom-is-more-than-hype-and-superlative-venture-investment/">LatAm fintechs</a> reaped $4.2 billion in funding; smaller numbers tend to be more variable quarter-to-quarter.)</p>
<p>But those are just the top-line figures. What happened on an individual round basis? Let’s talk about it.</p>
<h2>Average deal size</h2>
<p>Average and median fintech deal sizes reached new records last year. The average fintech startup round in 2021 was $32 million, up sharply – nearly double! – from $18 million in 2020. Meanwhile, the median deal size was $5 million, compared to $4 million in 2020, a more modest increase of 20%.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/the-berserk-pace-of-fintech-investing-outshines-the-global-vc-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259440</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inflection raises $40 million for its second crypto-focused fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/inflection-raises-40-million-for-its-second-crypto-focused-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/inflection-raises-40-million-for-its-second-crypto-focused-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inflection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercury Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2259494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early-stage venture firm Inflection has raised a new fund to invest into the “open economy”, as the firm says in its investment thesis. With that term, the firm means that it plans to cover all things crypto, web3 and blockchain with its new $40.7 million fund. Limited partners in the Mercury Fund include Accolade Partners, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Early-stage venture firm <a href="https://www.inflection.xyz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Inflection</a> has raised a new fund to invest into the “open economy”, as the firm says in its <a href="https://www.inflection.xyz/thesis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">investment thesis</a>. With that term, the firm means that it plans to cover all things crypto, web3 and blockchain with its new $40.7 million fund.</p>
<p>Limited partners in the Mercury Fund include Accolade Partners, Evanston Capital, Isomer, Hutt Capital, Multiple Capital, Christian Angermeyer&#8217;s Presight Partners, Galaxy Digital, DCG, Rockaway, Marc Andreessen, Chris Dixon, Bo Shao and Erik Voorhees.</p>
<p>Inflection plans to write the first VC check for new crypto projects — the investment could range from $0.5 million to $1.5 million. While the firm has put together a traditional fund denominated in USD, it plans to deploy its capital in different ways. In addition to traditional equity rounds, Inflection also plans to buy tokens in private sales but also bet on some cryptocurrencies by buying publicly listed crypto assets.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2259494" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Inflection has been around for a few years already. It hasn’t disclosed the size of its initial fund, but it has been fully invested already. Some of the investments from fund 1 include popular automated market maker <a href="https://balancer.fi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Balancer</a>, decentralized Git platform <a href="https://radicle.xyz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Radicle</a> and privacy-focused Notion alternative <a href="https://anytype.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anytype</a>.</p>
<p>Inflection has already started investing with its new Mercury Fund as well. Portfolio companies include <a href="https://unstoppable.fi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unstoppable Finance</a>, <a href="https://violet.co" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Violet</a>, <a href="https://www.defined.fi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Defined</a> and <a href="https://beta.catalog.works" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Catalog</a>. Interestingly, Inflection defines the open economy as five different verticals — open money, open finance, open data, open media and open orgs. Here&#8217;s what it looks like in a chart:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2259495" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2259495" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2259495" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-5.51.02-PM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="709" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-5.51.02-PM.png 1048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-5.51.02-PM.png?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-5.51.02-PM.png?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-5.51.02-PM.png?resize=768,532 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-5.51.02-PM.png?resize=680,471 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-19-at-5.51.02-PM.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2259495" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Inflection</p></div></p>
<p>While the Inflection team is still relatively small with only four full-time team members, the firm doesn’t plan to just sign checks. “We run nodes, govern crypto networks, write code and scale DAOs,” the Inflection team writes on its website. It&#8217;s interesting to see how crypto-native VC firms differ from traditional VC funds in this description.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Alexander Lange is the founder and general partner of the firm. Jonatan H. Luther-Bergquist acts as the head of research for the firm. Both of them are based in Germany. John Zannos, venture partner, as well as the firm’s operational team members are based in Boston, Massachusetts. Inflection primarily invests in Europe and the U.S. but has a global mandate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/inflection-raises-40-million-for-its-second-crypto-focused-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2259494</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why aren&#8217;t female founders getting a bigger piece of the pie? Theories abound</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-arent-female-founders-getting-a-bigger-piece-of-the-pie-theories-abound/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-arent-female-founders-getting-a-bigger-piece-of-the-pie-theories-abound/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anita Ramaswamy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female founders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PitchBook Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serial entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2257869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Less than 2% of venture capital funding went to all-female founding teams in 2021, marking a five-year low, new data from PitchBook shows. All-female founding teams did receive 83% more funding in 2021 in absolute dollars compared to the year prior, but that’s likely because U.S. startups overall raked in a record amount of cash [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Less than 2% of venture capital funding went to all-female founding teams in 2021, marking a five-year low, </span><a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/articles/female-founders-dashboard-2021-vc-funding-wrap-up" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">new data from PitchBook shows</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. All-female founding teams did receive 83% more funding in 2021 in absolute dollars compared to the year prior, but that’s likely because U.S. startups overall raked in a record amount of cash last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, the rising tide did not lift all boats. The share of funding all-female founding teams earned was down for the second year in a row, </span><a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/articles/the-vc-female-founders-dashboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">according to PitchBook</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how is it that despite the recent boom in startup funding, the venture capital industry is actually becoming an even tougher place for women to raise money?</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2257869" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Venture investor Del Johnson hosted a Twitter Spaces conversation last week that fostered discussion about whether and why all-female founding teams appear uniquely disadvantaged in the fundraising process &#8212; despite that the </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">number of women in venture capital has increased in recent years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">One theory shared by <span style="font-weight: 400;">Johnson </span>is that &#8220;male power brokers [are] more likely to select or fund the women VCs who share their own patriarchal biases, a</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">nd keep out the many women who don’t share those views,&#8221; he told TechCrunch in a written message. In short, women VCs are just as inclined to favor male founders as their male peers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Serial entrepreneur Gentry Lane, who was part of the discussion and spoke with TechCrunch afterward, similarly believes that the venture industry is inherently biased against women. How else explain that while top VCs have been more accessible than ever because of Zoom and online interactions, the share of funding going to all-female founders is dropping and not rising? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s &#8220;systemic misogyny,&#8221; says Lane, who is the CEO and founder of venture-backed national security software company ANOVA Intelligence.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet there were other theories surfaced in the Twitter Spaces conversation. VCs are more comfortable hosting events dedicated to helping underrepresented founders than actually funding them, suggested some of the participants. Instead of writing checks, investors engage in so-called virtue signaling, observed these frustrated entrepreneurs.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Lane also suggested that <span style="font-weight: 400;">VCs&#8217;s enduring focus on presentations and pitch decks rather than &#8220;normal, human conversation&#8221; continues to negatively impact underrepresented founders, who typically have less experience in the former categories.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment stage could also play a role, discussion participants noted, as much of the increase in venture funding overall in 2021 was driven by later-stage rounds, </span><a href="https://www.kauffmanfellows.org/journal_posts/female_founders_hire_more_women" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">which tend to be dominated by male founders</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>While speculation abounds, there was a silver lining in that PitchBook report. To wit, the PitchBook data shows that VC-backed companies with at least one female founder captured over 25% of last year’s total venture deals by count, representing 17.6% of overall deal value. Founding teams with both men and women accounted for the vast majority of those deals.</p>
<p>Shriya Nevatia of accelerator program On Deck cited the PitchBook data as a reason for optimism, pointing out the recent increase in the percentage of deals with at least one female founder <a href="https://twitter.com/shriyanevatia/status/1481860548618764289" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in a tweet yesterday</a>. Wrote Nevatia: &#8220;This is sooo much closer to 50% &#8212; up from 11.8% in 2008 &#8212; that&#8217;s quite fast!!&#8221;</p>
<p>She then tweeted: &#8220;We <em>ARE</em> making progress, keep it up yall.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/why-arent-female-founders-getting-a-bigger-piece-of-the-pie-theories-abound/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2257869</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
