<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 13:10:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Placer.ai, a location analytics startup, finds $100M at a $1B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/placer-ai-a-location-analytics-startup-finds-100m-at-a-1b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/placer-ai-a-location-analytics-startup-finds-100m-at-a-1b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 13:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Array Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fifth Wall Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeffrey Katzenberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[josh buckley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lachy Groom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Product Hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the walt disney company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web traffic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many of us are moving around these days a lot less than we used to &#8212; because of Covid, we&#8217;re working from home instead of an office; and we are traveling and going out less. Now, as we shift back into more &#8220;normal&#8221; behavior, a startup that&#8217;s helping to better understand where and how we [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Many of us are moving around these days a lot less than we used to &#8212; because of Covid, we&#8217;re working from home instead of an office; and we are traveling and going out less. Now, as we shift back into more &#8220;normal&#8221; behavior, a startup that&#8217;s helping to better understand where and how we are getting around has picked up a significant round of funding. <a href="https://www.placer.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Placer.ai</a>, which has built a platform to track and understand footfall in a variety of venues, has raised $100 million, funding that it will be using to continue expanding its platform. Placer has confirmed that the round values it at $1 billion.</p>
<p>The round is coming from an interesting mix of strategic and financial investors. It&#8217;s being led by Josh Buckley, the CEO of Product Hunt; with participation from WndrCo (Disney/Dreamworks&#8217; supremo Jeffrey Katzenberg&#8217;s investment firm), Lachy Groom, MMC Technology Ventures LLC, Fifth Wall Ventures, and Array Ventures; and a swathe of real estate names including J.M. Schapiro (CEO of Continental Realty Corp), Eliot Bencuya and Jeff Karsh of Tryperion Partners, Daniel Klein of Klein Enterprises/Sundeck Capital, and Majestic Realty.</p>
<p>Today, Placer has around 1,000 customers across real estate and property, retail, consumer packaged goods, and municipalities &#8212; some of the names include JLL, Regency Centers, Taubman, Planet Fitness, BJ’s Wholesale Club, and Grocery Outlet &#8212; which are using it to determine anonymized crowd movement, size and sentiment to help with their decision making and strategic planning.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256646" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The plan is to invest both in building out that user base further, and in the platform itself, by bringing in more physical and digital datasets &#8212; for example vehicle traffic, planned construction data, web traffic and purchase data to augment the 50+ data sets that it aggregates today &#8212; which in turn will lead to more use cases for Placer&#8217;s technology.</p>
<p>Given how much our movements have been curtailed in the last couple of years, it&#8217;s somewhat ironic that a company whose currency is physical presence in open places would be growing, much less raising money on the back of its potential. In actual fact, Noam Ben-Zvi, Placer&#8217;s CEO and co-founder, tells me that business has been stronger in recent years than ever before.</p>
<p>Growth has largely coming in two areas. First, people were still shopping, and going to other places, so existing customers were using it to figure out how, where and why people were moving around when they were (indeed Placer.ai created a <a href="https://www.placer.ai/the-square/recovery-dashboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recovery dashboard</a> to track specifically around this idea and how it related to Covid-19). Over time, that core business has gotten smarter.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been around for five years working with early adopters giving us feedback,&#8221; Ben-Zvi said. &#8220;They pass us known information about their properties and we can use that to retrain and calibrate our models so they get more accurate.&#8221; A lot of this to date has been about historical data but now the company is shifting into providing more predictive insights as well, he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Second, the pandemic gave rise to a new set of reasons to need this kind of data, whether it was to determine crowds at testing or vaccination sites, or because the changing economy was precipitating real estate dealmaking, or something else. This meant new customers were, for example, using Placer&#8217;s tools for M&amp;A due diligence, or to help determine interesting opportunities for investment.</p>
<p>Interestingly, he notes that one salient point that Placer has determined is that even with the rise of virtual experiences, physical is not quite dead yet. &#8220;Everywhere the rebound is impressively fast,&#8221; he noted. This is in marked contrast to when the pandemic first descended on the world in early 2020. &#8220;When Covid hit we were concerned. We froze our hiring, and waited since some of our customers weren&#8217;t even opening anymore.&#8221;</p>
<p>A lot of the data that Placer is able to pass on to customers &#8212; who essentially construct their own parameters for searching using a self-service tool &#8212; has traditionally been out of their reach despite their best efforts. Katzenberg&#8217;s previous work in the entertainment industry gave him first-hand experience of those black holes in consumer behavior and sentiment, which is one reason why he has gravitated to a company building technology to solve that now.</p>
<p>&#8220;Placer provides instant, simple and actionable insights to questions we&#8217;ve been asking as operators for over 30 years. The pace of innovation, the unique trust that the company has developed, and the massive market demand all point to the magnitude and scale of what this team can achieve,” said Katzenberg in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have long felt like the disruption Placer can bring is massive, but the market demand has far exceeded our initial expectations,&#8221; added Josh Buckley. “We see a powerful opportunity to continue partnering with Placer to improve the way decisions are made in the physical world, fundamentally improving the way these businesses and organizations operate.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/placer-ai-a-location-analytics-startup-finds-100m-at-a-1b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256646</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Headspace Health acquires AI-powered mental health and wellness company Sayana</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/headspace-health-acquires-ai-powered-mental-health-and-wellness-company-sayana/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/headspace-health-acquires-ai-powered-mental-health-and-wellness-company-sayana/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ginger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Headspace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Headspace Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mergers and acquistions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Headspace Health has acquired Sayana, an AI-powered mental health and wellness company, for an undisclosed amount. Headspace Health says the acquisition of the San Francisco-based company will expand its ability to provide personalized self-care to its users. The acquisition comes as Headspace and Ginger merged last year to form Headspace Health, which is valued at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.headspace.com/health">Headspace Health</a> has acquired <a href="https://www.sayana.app/">Sayana</a>, an AI-powered mental health and wellness company, for an undisclosed amount. Headspace Health says the acquisition of the San Francisco-based company will expand its ability to provide personalized self-care to its users. The acquisition comes as Headspace and Ginger <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/headspace-and-ginger-are-merging-to-form-headspace-health/">merged last year</a> to form Headspace Health, which is valued at $3 billion. The merger brought Ginger&#8217;s therapy and coaching offerings together with Headspace&#8217;s mindfulness and meditation services.</p>
<p>Founded in 2018 and backed by Y Combinator in 2020, Sayana leverages chat-based sessions with an AI persona that encourages users to track their moods. The app personalizes users&#8217; experiences based on their mood trends and suggests self-care and breathing exercises. The company&#8217;s sleep app helps users get restful sleep sessions based on their mood and sleep patterns.</p>
<p>Headspace Health CEO Russel Glass told TechCrunch in an interview that Sayana&#8217;s apps will continue to operate for a period of time while Headspace Health integrates their core capabilities into the Headspace and Ginger experience. Once the integration is complete, the company will turn off Sayana as a separate experience and move users over into Headspace Health.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256176" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Sayana created a unique, member-driven experience and as we think about the future of what we&#8217;re trying to do, it fits elegantly into the Headspace Health vision of a world where you can support the full continuum of care, regardless of where somebody is in the mental health continuum,&#8221; Glass said. &#8220;One of the things we&#8217;ve seen during the pandemic is just how many people continue to need support, so we have to keep focused on innovation. We have to ensure that we can automate parts of the mental health continuum and deliver personalized self-care content to people that have a need, and that&#8217;s where this acquisition is so exciting.&#8221;</p>
<p>Headspace Health is focused on creating an integrated experience to offer mental health help ranging from prevention to clinical care, all from one platform that is backed by AI and data science. With the addition of Sayana, Headspace Health plans to advance its capability to personalize experiences by offering help and services based on users&#8217; check-ins.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256209" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256209" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2256209" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png" alt="" width="1024" height="610" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png 6016w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png?resize=300,179 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png?resize=768,458 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png?resize=680,405 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png?resize=1536,915 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png?resize=2048,1220 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/sayana_sc_white.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256209" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Headspace Health</p></div></p>
<p>Glass stated that Headspace and Ginger are already leveraging AI to support their team of behavioral health coaches, therapists and psychiatrists to ensure quality interactions with users, comprehensive tracking of services and close collaboration among care providers. He outlined that adding Sayana&#8217;s capability to understand a user&#8217;s needs in a completely automated way via a robust chatbot experience will destigmatize experiences and offer more personalized and effective care.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As part of the acquisition, Sayana founder and CEO Sergey Fayfer is joining Headspace Health and is taking on a product leadership role within the company.</p>
<p>“Since our inception, we’ve been on a mission at Sayana to put accessible self-care in everyone’s pocket,” Fayfer said in a statement. “We’re thrilled to bring together our technology, engineering and design expertise to help advance Headspace Health’s efforts to democratize high-quality, affordable mental healthcare around the world.”</p>
<p>In terms of the future, Glass says Headspace Health plans to continue to expand to meet the growing needs of care for mental health. The company&#8217;s goal is to be the most accessible and comprehensive platform by reducing the cost of care as much as possible. He outlined that Headspace Health will continue to innovate to ensure that it can reduce the cost of care, while keeping the quality of care as high as possible. Glass noted that this is going to require Headspace Health to be aggressive in terms of how it thinks about both inorganic growth strategies and organic growth strategies.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will continue to focus on the employer landscape. You&#8217;ll see us continuing to announce new health plan and provider partnerships, there will be a number of those in the coming months,&#8221; Glass said. &#8220;We&#8217;ll continue to focus on youth as an expansion area for us. You&#8217;ll continue to see us innovate. We&#8217;re spending a lot on research and development and will continue to be acquisitive as we see opportunities to add platforms like Sayana to our platform over time.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/headspace-health-acquires-ai-powered-mental-health-and-wellness-company-sayana/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256176</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jakarta-based investment app Pluang raises $55M led by Accel</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/jakarta-based-investment-app-pluang-raises-55m-led-by-accel/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/jakarta-based-investment-app-pluang-raises-55m-led-by-accel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fractional trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pluang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stocks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256033</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jakarta-based investment app Pluang announced that it has raised $55 million led by Accel. This is a follow-on to its Series B and brings that round’s total to $110 million. The funding will be used to make Pluang available in more Southeast Asian countries, increase its asset classes and on hiring.  Pluang’s last round of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Jakarta-based investment app <a href="https://pluang.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pluang</a> announced that it has raised $55 million led by Accel. This is a follow-on to its Series B and brings that round’s total to $110 million. The funding will be used to make Pluang available in more Southeast Asian countries, increase its asset classes and on hiring.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Pluang’s last round of funding was a <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/pluang-receives-over-us3m-in-funding-led-by-go-ventures-300915718.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$3 million Series A in 2019</a>.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Other participants in the newest round include Trung Nguyen, Andy Ho, Aleksander Leonard Larsen, and Jeffrey Zirlin, founders of Axie Infinity founders; Alexa von Tobel, former Learnvest CEO); Pismo CTO Daniela Binatti; Monzo COO Sujata Bhatia; <a href="http://Public.com"><span class="s1">Public.com</span></a> co-CEOs Jannick Malling and Leif Abraham; FalconX CEO Raghu Yarlagadda; Flink CEO Sergio Jimenez (Flink CEO), The Chainsmokers and BRI Ventures. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/indonesian-savings-and-investment-app-pluang-gets-20m-in-pre-series-b-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Existing investors</a> Square Peg, Go-Ventures and Openspace Ventures also contributed.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256033" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p class="p1">Launched in 2019, Pluang started with gold and has since grown its range of asset classes, so investors can diversify their holdings and decrease risk. Investments can start as low as IDR 10,000 (or less than $1 USD) in gold, indexes, mutual funds and crypto assets. The app is also launching a new features that will users to invest in fractional U.S. stocks.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">“Affordability is an incredibly important thing to address for our new retail investors,” said co-founder and co-CEO Claudia Kolonas.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yd9peV8GCj"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/bibit-raises-another-growth-round-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-this-time-for-65m/">Bibit raises another growth round led by Sequoia Capital India, this time for $65M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bibit raises another growth round led by Sequoia Capital India, this time for $65M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/bibit-raises-another-growth-round-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-this-time-for-65m/embed/#?secret=yd9peV8GCj" data-secret="yd9peV8GCj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p1">Pluang is integrated in Indonesian super apps like Gojek, DANA, Tokopedia and Bukalapak, and now claims 3.5 million registered users in Indonesia, and says that from January 2020 to November 2021, it marked 22x growth in monthly transacting users and 28.5x growth in users with an active balance.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">Indonesia has high rates of savings and relatively low rates of retail investing, but that is quickly changing.</p>
<p>Other investment apps focused on Southeast Asia include Indonesia-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/two-months-after-its-series-a-pintu-gets-35m-in-new-funding-led-by-lightspeed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pintu</a>, robo-advisor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/bibit-raises-another-growth-round-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-this-time-for-65m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bibit</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/28/ajaib-raises-65m-series-a-extension-led-by-ribbit-capital-increasing-the-rounds-total-to-90m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ajaib</a> and Singapore-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investment-app-syfe-raises-29-6m-series-b-led-by-returning-investor-valar-ventures/">Syfe</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hukilF0TBt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/southeast-asian-startups-to-watch-in-2022/">Southeast Asian startups to watch in 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Southeast Asian startups to watch in 2022&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/southeast-asian-startups-to-watch-in-2022/embed/#?secret=hukilF0TBt" data-secret="hukilF0TBt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Kolonas said the new interest in investment is driven by the country’s high rates of smartphone penetration and savings per capita. “Because of this, there are millions of potential first-time investors just starting to establish money management habits and practices that were previously impossible where they live. Until very recently, most of the asset classes that can be accessed through Pluang were only available to the privileged and wealthy while most others were faced with low financial literacy and very limited investing options.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Like many other investment apps in Indonesia, Pluang includes financial literacy features, which Kolonas said it is “laser-focused on” improving. The new funding will enable Pluang to “provide the tools, resources and education necessary to set our users up for long-term wealth creation.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In a statement to TechCrunch, Accel partner Ethan Choi said Pluang is Accel’s fourth investment in consumer-focused investment apps globally, after the United States’ <span class="s1">Public.com</span>, Europe’s Trade Republic and Latin America’s Flink. “We were looking for the leader in Southeast Asia,” he said, adding that “after meeting Claudia and Richard [Chua, Pluang’s other co-founder and co-CEO], we were deeply impressed by the traction they have achieved on minimal capital and the fact that they were the only player that had the licenses and product to offer multiple asset classes including equities, indexes, and crypto &#8211; which we believe is critical to building a big business in the region.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="F6zZBCtVJg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/28/ajaib-raises-65m-series-a-extension-led-by-ribbit-capital-increasing-the-rounds-total-to-90m/">Ajaib raises $65M Series A extension led by Ribbit Capital, increasing the round&#8217;s total to $90M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ajaib raises $65M Series A extension led by Ribbit Capital, increasing the round&#8217;s total to $90M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/28/ajaib-raises-65m-series-a-extension-led-by-ribbit-capital-increasing-the-rounds-total-to-90m/embed/#?secret=F6zZBCtVJg" data-secret="F6zZBCtVJg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/jakarta-based-investment-app-pluang-raises-55m-led-by-accel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256033</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newcomer aggregator Ecommerce Brands snags $40M in equity, debt to deploy eCaaS model</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/newcomer-aggregator-ecommerce-brands-snags-40m-in-equity-debt-to-deploy-ecaas-model/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/newcomer-aggregator-ecommerce-brands-snags-40m-in-equity-debt-to-deploy-ecaas-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bearing Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cart.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Brands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Jacobsen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Bickenbach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ecommerce Brands aims to differentiate itself from the crowded aggregator space by being the technology force for DTC brands to scale while operators focus on running their businesses.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.ecommercebrands.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ecommerce Brands</a> is one of the newest consumer brand aggregators to emerge in a crowded space and aims to integrate with Cart.com to support the backend needs of brands as they scale.</p>
<p>The Atlanta-based company officially kicked off in September 2021, helmed by founder and CEO Mark Bickenbach, who previously served as a business unit president of The Home Depot and CFO of its website, and board chairman Jim Jacobsen, former CEO of RTIC Outdoors and co-founder of Cart.com.</p>
<p>Today, it announced a $40 million investment, with $10 million in equity led by Bearing Ventures, and $30 million in debt.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256389" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2256392" style="width: 496px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256392" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2256392" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?w=486" alt="Mark Bickenbach, Ecommerce Brands" width="486" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg 1654w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?resize=107,150 107w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?resize=214,300 214w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?resize=768,1075 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?resize=486,680 486w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?resize=1097,1536 1097w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?resize=1463,2048 1463w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/IMG_5018.jpg?resize=36,50 36w" sizes="(max-width: 486px) 100vw, 486px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256392" class="wp-caption-text">Mark Bickenbach, founder and CEO of Ecommerce Brands. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ecommerce Brands</p></div></p>
<p>Cart.com, a Houston-based company providing end-to-end e-commerce services, brought in its own funding round, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/e-commerce-as-a-service-platform-cart-com-picks-up-98m-to-give-brands-scaling-tools/">$98 million Series B</a> last August for its software, services and infrastructure for businesses to scale online.</p>
<p>Bickenbach told TechCrunch that Ecommerce Brands plans to acquire direct-to-consumer brands, integrate them on Cart.com and grow them in revenue and profitability, something that previously would have only been done on marketplaces.</p>
<p>“Direct-to-consumer brands are limited in a number of ways, including scaling their operations and technology,” he said. “They run on thinner margins and focus on a single channel, so if you are trying to cover the fixed costs of business, putting money across channels is hard to do. That is where we see the opportunity to take a business, add the technology and let the operators deal with running a business.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He believes that is what differentiates his company from the e-commerce aggregators acquiring successful brands from the likes of Amazon and Shopify.</p>
<p>Overall, e-commerce aggregators have gained traction across the world in the past few years, with successful companies securing billions of venture-backed capital in recent years. Most recently we saw Merama in Latin America become a unicorn after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/e-commerce-aggregator-merama-gets-its-horn-after-just-12-months-in-business/">raising $60 million</a>, while Beijing-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/chinese-amazon-aggregator-nebula-brands-raises-50m-led-by-l-catterton/">Nebula Brands took in $50 million</a>.</p>
<p>Before them was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/18/gravitiq-throws-its-hat-into-crowded-e-commerce-aggregator-ring/">Gravitiq</a>, focused on healthcare brands, and Heyday’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/heyday-raises-555m-to-buy-up-and-scale-more-d2c-brands-on-the-amazon-marketplace-universe/">$555 million Series C</a>. The big name in aggregators, Thrasio, announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/thrasio-the-amazon-aggregator-raises-1b-in-fresh-funding-at-a-valuation-of-up-to-10-billion/">$1 billion in October</a>, while Perch grabbed a large investment of <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/softbanks-vision-fund-2-leads-775m-investment-in-perch-sets-new-record-for-fastest-company-to-achieve-profitable-unicorn-status-in-the-us-301299324.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$775 million</a> in May.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the new funding will be used to acquire the businesses and get them moving on Cart.com for their back-end operations. Ecommerce Brands also will be building out its own tools to manage growth and operations, while also doing some hiring in the area of supply chain. Bickenbach expects those new tools to be ready by March.</p>
<p>Ecommerce Brands has since acquired five brands, together with annual gross sales of more than $150 million. It is mainly looking at businesses that are EBITDA positive.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RAr95Nzmv2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/5-predictions-for-the-future-of-e-commerce/">5 predictions for the future of e-commerce</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 predictions for the future of e-commerce&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/5-predictions-for-the-future-of-e-commerce/embed/#?secret=RAr95Nzmv2" data-secret="RAr95Nzmv2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/newcomer-aggregator-ecommerce-brands-snags-40m-in-equity-debt-to-deploy-ecaas-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256389</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BigPanda gets its horn after securing $190M in fresh capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/bigpandas-gets-its-horn-after-securing-190m-in-fresh-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/bigpandas-gets-its-horn-after-securing-190m-in-fresh-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 13:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advent International]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AIOps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assaf Resnick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BigPanda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[databases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elik Eizenberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Noeth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[incident management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company’s technology transforms huge volumes of IT data into actionable insight and automates incident management so IT operations teams can be proactive about their response processes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">AIOps leader <a href="http://bigpanda.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BigPanda</a> is now valued at $1.2 billion following a new Series D round of $190 million led by Advent International.</p>
<p>Joining Advent in the round are Insight Partners and other existing investors. The latest round gives the company $317 million in total funding, according to Crunchbase data.</p>
<p>Assaf Resnick, BigPanda co-founder and CEO, told TechCrunch the company is cementing its leadership in AIOps event correlation and automation. The company’s technology transforms huge volumes of IT data into actionable insight and automates incident management so IT operations teams can be proactive about their response processes.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256488" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It’s been a while since we checked in on BigPanda — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/27/bigpanda-wants-to-bring-order-to-it-alerts-madness/">nearly eight years to be exact,</a> and much has changed since the company came out of stealth in 2014.</p>
<p>Thanks in part to the global pandemic, the digital transformation has penetrated every part of our life, Resnick said. More people trust automated workflow now, including for IT operations. However, people are now in charge of 80% of keeping a business running, but with all of the data flowing, it is nearly impossible to keep up, he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CvPWRWTsJx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/27/bigpanda-wants-to-bring-order-to-it-alerts-madness/">BigPanda Wants To Bring Order To IT Alerts Madness</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BigPanda Wants To Bring Order To IT Alerts Madness&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/10/27/bigpanda-wants-to-bring-order-to-it-alerts-madness/embed/#?secret=CvPWRWTsJx" data-secret="CvPWRWTsJx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Recognizing that pace of innovation and how companies were spending more of their mission critical resources on putting out fires, Big Panda decided to go after additional funding to meet that demand. The company was finishing up its third quarter, which Resnick said was strong, and looking at the fourth quarter when it was decided to go for additional funding.</p>
<p>“The pipeline and market were accelerating beyond what we initially thought,” he added. “When looking at the total available market, we realized our customers were 1% of the market, and with current digital transformation being faster than two years ago, we didn’t have enough people to keep up with the data.”</p>
<p>At the same time, BigPanda was at the beginning of a relationship with Advent, and it made sense to take on the $190 million, which Resnick said “lets us hit the gas on our go-to-market acceleration.”</p>
<p>Even before the new round, the company was seeing good traction in the market. Its 2021 sales grew by 155%, while the fourth quarter set a record for number of new customers added in a single quarter with nearly two times the growth since 2019. BigPanda not only grew its footprint with existing customers last year, but also saw a five-time year-over-year increase in deals valued at over $1 million. Its team also doubled over the past two years.</p>
<p>Much of the company’s current go-to-market strategy is concentrated in North America, but the new funding will provide an outlet for a more international focus, he said. The company already has an office in London and will be investing more there as it also targets mid-market companies.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The funding will also go toward increasing the size of its machine learning, product and R&amp;D teams, while also giving it some capital for strategic acquisition opportunities.</p>
<p>As part of the investment, Advent partner Eric Noeth will join BigPanda’s board of directors while former VMware chief operating officer Sanjay Poonen joins as a strategic advisor.</p>
<p>Noeth said that in talks with other investors and companies in the space, BigPanda’s name kept rising to the surface, especially as more companies leveraged technology, but did not have the manpower to manage all of the data events coming through.</p>
<p>“It is remarkable to find a company with such adoration from a group of competitors and customers,” he added. “AIOps is having a watershed moment. COVID changed technology so much, but now you have a massive tailwind around digital, and that is still in early innings. Most impressive is the cross sectors of customers that all have the same problem of automating and mediating issues quickly. That tangible use case has been a powerful driver for BigPanda.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Resnick and Noeth both say that the scarcity of talent problem is also hitting company chief information officers, whose job, they say, is shifting to be more like a chief technology officer while also retaining the task of keeping the lights on without getting in the way of innovation and velocity.</p>
<p>“Data is growing exponentially, even if there was not a scarcity of talent, it wouldn&#8217;t make sense to invest more money and talent there,” Resnick added. “You have to turn to automation.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UBOKKK3FBB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/24/stop-creating-self-fulfilling-prophecies-how-to-apply-ai-to-small-data-problems/">Stop creating self-fulfilling prophecies: How to apply AI to small data problems</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Stop creating self-fulfilling prophecies: How to apply AI to small data problems&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/24/stop-creating-self-fulfilling-prophecies-how-to-apply-ai-to-small-data-problems/embed/#?secret=UBOKKK3FBB" data-secret="UBOKKK3FBB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/bigpandas-gets-its-horn-after-securing-190m-in-fresh-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256488</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public appoints first independent board members, details 2021 user growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/public-appoints-first-independent-board-members-details-2021-user-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/public-appoints-first-independent-board-members-details-2021-user-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning, Public, an investment app for the American market, announced the appointment of two new board members. The startup also provided some details regarding its growth in the COVID era, a period that generated strong results for a number of services that allowed users to save and invest. Public has added Jessica Neal, former [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning, <a href="https://public.com/">Public</a>, an investment app for the American market, announced the appointment of two new board members. The startup also provided some details regarding its growth in the COVID era, a period that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/fintechs-savings-and-investing-boom-isnt-just-a-domestic-affair/">generated strong results</a> for a number of services that allowed users to save and invest.</p>
<p>Public has added <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeneal/">Jessica Neal</a>, former chief talent officer at Netflix and present-day venture partner at TCV to its board, along with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrisbrummerlaw">Dr. Christopher J. Brummer</a>, a professor at Georgetown, member of the Fannie Mae board of directors, and adviser to Paradigm, a firm that invests in crypto-focused companies. (Paradigm recently <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/citadel-securities-to-receive-first-outside-investment-11641905101?mod=djemalertNEWS">made the news</a> for taking part in a deal with Sequoia to invest in trading firm Citadel Securities.)</p>
<p>TechCrunch spoke with Public co-CEOs Leif Abraham and Jannick Malling about the board additions. Broadly, the two appointments align with Abraham&#8217;s view of what his company focused on last year, namely scaling its business operations and its human capital. Neal fits neatly on the human side of that work, while Brummer&#8217;s <a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/faculty/chris-brummer/">work on fintech and crypto regulatory matters</a> slots him into the operational side of Public&#8217;s business.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256384" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The savings and investing boom</h2>
<p>TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/17/saving-not-spending-is-the-new-hotness-in-fintech/">spilled much ink</a> covering <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/08/fintechs-uneven-new-reality-has-helped-some-startups-harmed-others/">the 2020 and 2021 savings and investing boom</a>. Citizens of many countries turned to equities and crypto trading and investing services in droves as global savings rates rose, and the markets proved more volatile than in previous years.</p>
<p>The trend was most commonly viewed through the lenses provided by Coinbase and Robinhood. Both went public in 2021, giving the market insight into their economics, and how broad consumer demand is for crypto and equity investing and trading products. (Public has supported equities and crypto assets <a href="https://medium.com/the-public-blog/introducing-crypto-on-public-211fe0b2dfab">since last October</a>.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="82ZN4ki3Gj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/as-investing-apps-boom-public-doubles-down-on-its-social-focus/">As investing apps boom, Public doubles down on its social focus</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As investing apps boom, Public doubles down on its social focus&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/as-investing-apps-boom-public-doubles-down-on-its-social-focus/embed/#?secret=82ZN4ki3Gj" data-secret="82ZN4ki3Gj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Public rode the same wave of consumer demand for financial management products and services, raising a mountain of capital in quick order. For example, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/social-stock-trading-services-public-raises-65m-series-c/">announced its $65 million Series C in December 2020</a>, only to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/as-expected-stock-trading-service-public-raises-220m-at-unicorn-valuation/">raise $220 million more in February 2021</a>. Suddenly worth more than $1 billion, the new unicorn earned its place in our mental landscape for companies to track in the consumer fintech market.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Other firms mirrored Public&#8217;s rapid-fire fundraising cadence. Chicago-based M1 Finance is a good example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/14/m1-finance-closes-45m-series-c-mere-months-after-it-raised-its-33m-series-b/">having raised</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/m1-finance-raises-another-rapid-fire-round-after-scaling-its-aum-to-more-than-3-5b/">successive rounds</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/m1-finance-raises-150m-in-softbank-led-series-e-boosts-valuation-to-1-45b/">last year</a> as its assets under management, or AUM, scaled rapidly.</p>
<p>But while M1 was willing to share AUM numbers as it grew, and the fact that it was targeting a roughly 1% revenue result for each dollar it helped manage, Public is still conservative regarding what it will share on the growth front.</p>
<p>The company did disclose that it saw &#8220;funded accounts&#8221; grow by 700% last year. But on the revenue front its CEOs were more coy, saying in a statement that their goals this year include &#8220;expanding [their] platform’s capabilities,&#8221; in ways that will include &#8220;new areas of monetization.&#8221;</p>
<p>That Public is being more quiet about revenue than user growth is not a huge surprise. Recall that Public <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/trading-app-public-drops-payment-for-order-flow-in-favor-of-tips/">made the choice to stop collecting payment for order flow</a> (PFOF) revenue last year, setting up a clear contrast to Robinhood&#8217;s largest top-line generator. The company at the time said that it would instead accept tips from its users.</p>
<p>Public&#8217;s strong fundraising history gave it the room to avoid a monetization focus last year, but 2022 will likely become a proving ground for the company to build out its revenue model. In conversation with TechCrunch, Abraham and Malling were clear that they were content with their choice to not collect PFOF incomes. Why? In their view, transactional revenue streams are inherently volatile, and as they want to position Public as more of an investing application than a trading platform, collecting incomes based on the pace at which users bought and sold securities was a bit counter to their ethos.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="seZLmbAwgB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/crypto-volatility-continues-to-flummox-wall-street/">Crypto volatility continues to flummox Wall Street</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crypto volatility continues to flummox Wall Street&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/crypto-volatility-continues-to-flummox-wall-street/embed/#?secret=seZLmbAwgB" data-secret="seZLmbAwgB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Still, the company is a business, and one with material aspirations. The two CEOs are bullish on the scale of their market &#8212; that Public has a big TAM, to use venture-speak &#8212; implying that their choice to focus on building out community features and scaling their company&#8217;s technology will bear fruit as the company onboards more users.</p>
<p>On that front, one of the more interesting facts regarding Public is its customer acquisition is about half organic. And the company said that it wasn&#8217;t seeing its customer acquisition costs rise as it grew. That fact grants credence to the idea that there are still Americans in the market for an investing and trading home.</p>
<p>TechCrunch asked how horizontal the company will go, given that many fintech products with a consumer focus wind up working to become financial super apps. Public&#8217;s leaders said that they don&#8217;t want to build a bank.</p>
<p>So Public is sticking to its guns, focusing on building a community-focused investing service. Let&#8217;s see how it works to grow its revenue per user this year now that it has attracted an audience of users at scale.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/public-appoints-first-independent-board-members-details-2021-user-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wordle is being punished by app stores for choosing the open web</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/wordle-is-being-punished-by-app-stores-for-choosing-the-open-web/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/wordle-is-being-punished-by-app-stores-for-choosing-the-open-web/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Owen Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 12:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wordle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Owen Williams Contributor Fascinated by how code and design is shaping the world, Owen is a technology columnist that previously wrote for OneZero, The Next Web and works as a UX Manager by day. If you&#8217;ve been on Twitter lately, you&#8217;ve probably noticed your timeline drowning in grey, green and yellow squares. Those posts are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Owen Williams</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Fascinated by how code and design is shaping the world, Owen is a technology columnist that previously wrote for OneZero, The Next Web and works as a UX Manager by day.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">If you&#8217;ve been on Twitter lately, you&#8217;ve probably noticed your timeline <a href="https://twitter.com/ow/status/1479882667311067142">drowning in grey, green and yellow squares</a>. Those posts are thanks to <a href="https://www.powerlanguage.co.uk/wordle/">Wordle</a>, a free word game that gives you six tries or fewer to guess the correct word for the day.</p>
<p>The game is absolutely everywhere, growing from a handful of users to hundreds of thousands in a matter of weeks, despite being both free to play and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/03/technology/wordle-word-game-creator.html">originally built by a software engineer in Brooklyn, Josh Wardle, for his partner</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">i promise to never make a Wordle tweet again but uh…Wordle 203 2/6</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256543" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e9.png" alt="🟩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e8.png" alt="🟨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e8.png" alt="🟨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2b1b.png" alt="⬛" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2b1b.png" alt="⬛" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e9.png" alt="🟩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e9.png" alt="🟩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e9.png" alt="🟩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e9.png" alt="🟩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f7e9.png" alt="🟩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&mdash; Owen Williams <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/26a1.png" alt="⚡" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@ow) <a href="https://twitter.com/ow/status/1479882667311067142?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Wordle stands out in a world of in-app purchases and loot boxes because it&#8217;s free to play, has no advertising at all, and most importantly, <a href="https://www.powerlanguage.co.uk/wordle/">is played on a simple website</a>, rather than requiring an app to be downloaded from Apple&#8217;s App Store or Google Play.</p>
<p>The choice to make Wordle a web app, rather than something downloaded from a store makes sense, given that it was developed as a passion project rather than by a business, and it&#8217;s a simple, fun game that isn&#8217;t really designed to make money.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A side effect of that choice, however, is that Wordle is suddenly being ripped off in app stores by other developers who smell a quick way to make money off of unsuspecting users that either don&#8217;t care or don&#8217;t know any better.</p>
<p>Part of Wordle&#8217;s charm is that the posts of colorful squares you see everywhere don&#8217;t really feel like advertising; there&#8217;s no link back to the game or cheesy copy trying to convince you to install it: you&#8217;re on your own to find it via a quick Google search.</p>
<p>As a result, the average iPhone or Android owner is likely to assume Wordle is an app and head right to their respective app store to find it—which is exactly what I did when I first discovered it, only to find a dead end when I started playing a month ago before realizing I should just Google it.</p>
<p>Now, however, opportunistic developers have smelled this and are <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878752/wordle-app-store-review-copies-advertisements-in-app-purchase">creating almost exact clones of Wordle</a> in order to generate money where Wardle has eschewed doing so. One developer, <a href="https://twitter.com/zachshakked">Zach Shakked</a>, cloned the game in its entirety down to the exact game play and user interface, called it Wordle, and uploaded it to Apple&#8217;s App Store, <a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/wordle-the-app/id1604016922">charging $30-per-year to play a game that was intended to be free</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">This guy shamelessly cloned Wordle (name and all) as an F2P iOS game with in-app purchases and is bragging about how well it&#39;s doing and how he&#39;ll get away with it because Josh Wardle didn&#39;t trademark it. So gross. <a href="https://t.co/kIs8BypuRA">pic.twitter.com/kIs8BypuRA</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Andy Baio (@waxpancake) <a href="https://twitter.com/waxpancake/status/1480990948972658689?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 11, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Shakked <a href="https://twitter.com/waxpancake/status/1480990948972658689">bragged on Twitter</a> about how many users he was converting to paid customers as well as running ads against the search term &#8220;Wordle&#8221; on the App Store. After widespread backlash, however, Shakked removed the game from sale, and late on Tuesday<a href="https://twitter.com/zachshakked/status/1481129425706143746"> published a lengthy apology and partial justification</a> for his actions via Twitter.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In the past, we&#8217;ve seen cloning behavior like this play out on app stores with viral games like </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://venturebeat.com/2014/03/30/threes-vs-2048-when-rip-offs-do-better-than-the-original-game/">Threes</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> and </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/16/5416774/apple-and-google-fighting-flappy-bird-clones">Flappy Bird</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, both of which were cloned by developers and rejigged </span><em style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">slightly </em><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">with extra fees or advertising on top in the hope of fooling a few users and making a quick buck.</span></p>
<p>Wordle is facing a threat we haven&#8217;t seen play out yet: the game&#8217;s developer is essentially being punished by app stores for choosing to build using open web technologies, rather than a native app. Not only is this type of behavior allowed by the Apple App Store, there&#8217;s little recourse—because as far as Apple is concerned, Wordle doesn&#8217;t exist, given it wasn&#8217;t built a native app.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no way for a developer of a fully functional, capable web app like Wordle to claim their name in the App Store, nor is there a way for them to list their website to get users to the right place and defend themselves from copycats. Google actually does allow developers to <a href="https://chromeos.dev/en/publish/pwa-in-play">upload some kinds of progressive web apps to the Play Store</a>, though at time of writing Wardle doesn&#8217;t appear to have chosen to do this. If he wanted to defend his game on the Play Store when a clone does appear there, he&#8217;d at least have a choice to do so.</p>
<p>It <em>could </em>be argued that Wardle didn&#8217;t trademark Wordle—let alone invent the actual gameplay given that it&#8217;s <a href="https://twitter.com/jherskowitz/status/1481015729944252418">based on a 70&#8217;s gameshow</a>—but that isn&#8217;t the point: because Wordle is a web-based, it&#8217;ll continually open itself up to clones until Wardle develops an official app.</p>
<p>Apple has a longstanding history of intentionally ignoring or degrading open web technologies that could compete with its incredibly successful, lucrative, closed app store. Progressive web apps (PWA), a set of standards that allow websites to function similarly to native apps, are only half-heartedly supported, broken, or plain ignored on iOS and iPadOS.</p>
<p>Web push, a standard that allows websites to send push notifications to users, <a href="https://caniuse.com/push-api">has been ignored by Apple for years with no explanation</a> despite support in almost every competing browser, including the desktop version of Safari. When Apple doesn&#8217;t ignore standards that would allow web apps to compete on an even playing field, it can intentionally delay them for years, <a href="https://infrequently.org/2021/04/progress-delayed/">a practice documented in this long, exhausting list by Alex Russell, an engineer at Google</a>.</p>
<p>The inability to claim a name and link to a website, rather than build a native app, is by design for this reason: Apple doesn&#8217;t want users to go to the web. Instead, the company intentionally harms the open web for its own gain to the detriment of users of its own App Store who might be tricked into paying for something that could be free, if only they&#8217;d searched the web instead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/wordle-is-being-punished-by-app-stores-for-choosing-the-open-web/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256543</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web3Auth secures $13M from Sequoia India to simplify crypto onboarding and authentication</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/web3auth-secures-13m-to-drive-mass-adoption-of-web3-apps-and-wallets-through-non-custodial-authentication-infrastructure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/web3auth-secures-13m-to-drive-mass-adoption-of-web3-apps-and-wallets-through-non-custodial-authentication-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto wallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[torus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Web3 is seen as the future of the internet because it allows people to control their own data and digital assets, but crypto developers have been learning from the past when it comes to onboarding new users. The current state of crypto onboarding is unwieldy and unnecessarily prolonged due to the seed phrase, a series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Web3 is seen as the future of the internet because it allows people to control their own data and digital assets, but crypto developers have been learning from the past when it comes to onboarding new users.</p>
<p>The current state of crypto onboarding is unwieldy and unnecessarily prolonged due to the seed phrase, a series of words created by the crypto wallet to regain access. On a technical level, seed phrases have contributed to the loss of nearly 20% of all bitcoins in circulation, roughly equivalent to the GDP of Hungary, according to Singapore-based crypto infra startup <a href="https://web3auth.io/">Web3Auth</a>, formerly known as <a href="https://tor.us/index.html">Torus</a>. The lengthy passwords that users are asked to store in a safe place can be a significant barrier to entry for non-technical users who are used to simple “forgot password?” workflows on nearly every traditional internet platform. There have also been security issues when it comes to platforms holding control of a user’s private keys.</p>
<p>Web3Auth, a non-custodial key infrastructure solution for Web3 apps and wallets, wants to solve these problems by leveraging social accounts and devices that mainstream users already own to enable users to manage their keys intuitively.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2254392" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“Users use keys as accounts to trade, hold assets, or just interact with blockchains, so control and security of those keys are important,” chief executive officer and co-founder Zhen Yu Young told TechCrunch. “Non-custodial wallets help you manage your key, spanning from solutions as simple as writing a phrase on a paper to more secure methods.”</p>
<p>Web3Auth is powered by the Torus Network, an open-source, non-custodial, distributed key management network. Web3Auth builds on this infrastructure to make Web3 authentication — including password-less auth, SMS auth, or other OAuth methods like Google, Twitter, Discord and Reddit – in apps and wallets simple and intuitive to use.</p>
<p><a href="http://web3auth.io/">Web3Auth</a> announced today it has closed a $13 million Series A led by <a href="https://india.sequoiacap.com/">Sequoia Capital India.</a> This round included participation from <a href="https://www.usv.com/">Union Square Ventures</a>, <a href="https://multicoin.capital/">Multicoin Capital</a>, <a href="https://ftx.com/">FTX</a>, Bitcoin.com, <a href="https://darma.capital/">DARMA Capital</a>, <a href="https://chainstry.com/">Chainstry</a>, <a href="https://www.hashed.com/">Hashed</a>, <a href="https://www.kosmos.vc/">KOSMOS Capital</a>, Kyros Ventures, LD Capital, Minted Labs, P2P Capital, Phoenix VC, Staking Facilities, YBB Capital, Moonwhale Ventures and Decentralab.</p>
<p>The fresh capital brings its total raised to $15 million since its inception in 2019. It will accelerate expansion into decentralized gaming, NFTs, and social applications and advance its mission to eliminate seed phrases and make blockchain authentication decentralized and accessible to all with the Series A funding. The company also plans to increase its headcount, Young told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2255510" style="width: 1469px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255510" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2255510 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/web3auth.png" alt="" width="1459" height="584" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/web3auth.png 1459w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/web3auth.png?resize=150,60 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/web3auth.png?resize=300,120 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/web3auth.png?resize=768,307 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/web3auth.png?resize=680,272 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/web3auth.png?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1459px) 100vw, 1459px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255510" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Web3Auth</p></div></p>
<p>Web3Auth’s authentication infrastructure is designed to make it easy for developers to build familiar login flows such as single sign-on with Google and Twitter, eliminating the need for users to directly interface with vulnerable public-private key pairs. It is also designed to give more advanced users the ability to connect the wallet or key management system.</p>
<p>“We designed Web3Auth to bypass the UX obstacles holding back mainstream crypto adoption. True to our focus on accessibility, we wanted Web3Auth to meet users wherever they are. Intuitive and familiar login flows are needed if we want to onboard the next wave of mainstream users into crypto,” said Young. “We’re encouraged that some of the best investors in the world care deeply about usability and accessibility in crypto. We’re extremely grateful for their support, and we’re going to use it to catapult Web3 into the future.”</p>
<p>In 2021, more than 300 applications and wallets selected Web3Auth to secure over four million users’ private keys. Its users have increased 30 times since the same time last year, Young noted.</p>
<p>“Our main users are Web3 wallets and applications. Many popular wallets in the ecosystems, such as Binance Extension, Kepler, Kukai, Skyweaver and Kash, are powered by Web3Auth”  in their core flows to boost conversion rates, reduce loss and support tickets, Young told TechCrunch. “On the application side, the NFT and gaming applications utilizing Web3Auth that are particularly popular include Skyweaver, Rarible MyCryptoHeros, and others.”</p>
<p>Young pointed out similar platforms like <a href="https://magic.link/">Magic Link</a>, which provides key management through a different infrastructure like AWS Cloud HSM to store user keys, and <a href="https://www.fireblocks.com/">Fireblock</a>’s underlying infrastructure that utilizes multi-party computation (MPC)/threshold cryptography. They’re, however, more enterprise and internal-facing authentication relative to the Torus platform being more external, Young said, adding that a similar analogy could be Okta and Auth0 in the web 2.0 authentication space.</p>
<p>“We think that the non-custodial nature of Web3, which allows users to control their own data and destiny, is a huge step forward in bringing power back to the users. This makes the data more portable and safer while continuing to enable existing login product features, giving users the best both worlds. Sequoia Capital India is excited to partner with a team and a product that is concentrating on making crypto more accessible not by adding more bells and whistles but by addressing a long-standing problem at its most fundamental level,” Anandamoy Roychowdhary, principal of Sequoia India.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ml4B3E4cfU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/hong-kong-based-fintech-xanpool-raises-27m-for-its-decentralized-payment-network/">Hong Kong-based fintech XanPool raises $27M for its decentralized payment network</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hong Kong-based fintech XanPool raises $27M for its decentralized payment network&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/hong-kong-based-fintech-xanpool-raises-27m-for-its-decentralized-payment-network/embed/#?secret=Ml4B3E4cfU" data-secret="Ml4B3E4cfU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kMBDc6jD6g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/identity-platform-auth0-raises-120m-series-f-round-at-1-92b-valuation/">Identity platform Auth0 raises $120M Series F funding round at $1.92B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Identity platform Auth0 raises $120M Series F funding round at $1.92B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/14/identity-platform-auth0-raises-120m-series-f-round-at-1-92b-valuation/embed/#?secret=kMBDc6jD6g" data-secret="kMBDc6jD6g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="khJpZmSC6G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/crypto-infrastructure-provider-fireblocks-raises-310m-triples-valuation-to-2-2b-in-five-months/">Crypto infra startup Fireblocks raises $310M, triples valuation to $2.2B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crypto infra startup Fireblocks raises $310M, triples valuation to $2.2B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/crypto-infrastructure-provider-fireblocks-raises-310m-triples-valuation-to-2-2b-in-five-months/embed/#?secret=khJpZmSC6G" data-secret="khJpZmSC6G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/web3auth-secures-13m-to-drive-mass-adoption-of-web3-apps-and-wallets-through-non-custodial-authentication-infrastructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254392</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lime&#8217;s new e-bike has a swappable battery that also works with its scooters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/lime-new-e-bike-swappable-battery-works-with-scooters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/lime-new-e-bike-swappable-battery-works-with-scooters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255824</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lime is finally making good on its promise to deliver its Gen4 e-bike to the streets after first announcing plans to introduce the new hardware last March. The new bikes will have a swappable battery that&#8217;s interchangeable with Lime&#8217;s latest generation of e-scooters. The micromobility operator launched Wednesday 250 of its new bikes in Washington, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Lime is finally making good on its promise to deliver its Gen4 e-bike to the streets after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/lime-unveils-new-ebike-as-part-of-50-million-investment-to-expand-to-more-25-cities/">first announcing plans to introduce the new hardware last March</a>. The new bikes will have a swappable battery that&#8217;s interchangeable with Lime&#8217;s latest generation of e-scooters.</p>
<p>The micromobility operator launched Wednesday 250 of its new bikes in Washington, D.C., where it plans to gradually replace the full fleet of 2,500 e-bikes by April, according Russell Murphy, senior director of corporate communications. Lime will continue to launch in cities globally, swapping out older generations for the new model in each city over the next year.</p>
<p>This move is part of a $50 million investment the company has directed towards the development the new e-bike and its expansion to another 25 cities in North American, Europe, Australia and New Zealand.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255824" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The last generation of Lime e-bikes can be found in 50 markets globally, including London, Seattle, Paris, Denver and <a href="https://www.live5news.com/2022/01/11/bike-share-industry-giant-coming-charleston/">soon Charleston, South Carolina</a>. Lime had initially aimed to launch the Gen4 e-bike in the summer of 2021, but had to delay save for a few pilots last autumn due to supply chain issues, said Murphy.</p>
<p>The swappable battery is the most notable feature of Lime&#8217;s new green-and-white bike, which matches the appearance of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/lime-plans-for-modes-beyond-bikes-and-scooters-in-2021/">Lime&#8217;s latest Gen4 scooter.</a></p>
<p>&#8220;This is a potential leap forward for the industry,&#8221; Murphy told TechCrunch. &#8220;If you have one battery between vehicle types, you can operate a more streamlined multimodal fleet.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lime expects the battery upgrade to lead to improved unit economics. Since vehicles won&#8217;t have to be taken in to charge, there will be fewer operational tasks, which tend to be one of the highest costs associated with running a shared micromobility business. At the same time, by only needing to swap out the battery, there will be more vehicles on the street for longer, providing better reliability to riders and a higher potential for earning revenue, said Murphy.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;It will also mean one team can do every charge task instead of having one charge team for bikes and one for scooters,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The new e-bike will also have an improved motor that will help riders climb hills more easily, a phone holder that charges smartphones, a new handlebar display that matches that of the Gen4 scooter and an automatic two-speed transmission that allows for a smoother start, rather than having to pedal a bit to get the motor going.</p>
<p>Lime&#8217;s plans to continue scaling its e-bikes are in line with the company&#8217;s stated goals to refresh a significant portion of its fleet, move into more cities and develop new technologies to win additional city requests for proposal. In November, the micromobility giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/lime-raises-523-million-as-it-prepares-to-go-public/">closed a $523 million raise in convertible debt and term loan financing</a>, which is potentially the company&#8217;s last funding round before it plans to go public this year.</p>
<p>As Lime preps itself for public markets, it&#8217;s working on strengthening its considerable hold on the industry by becoming more operationally efficient and getting its hardware on point, and the introduction of this upgraded e-bike reinforces that. Meanwhile, as Lime tries to scoop up every permit it can get its hands on, competitor Spin, which is owned by Ford, shared plans last week to <a href="https://www.spin.app/blog-posts/spin-forwardhttps://www.spin.app/blog-posts/spin-forward">lay off a quarter of its staff</a> as part of its restructuring process to exit open permit markets. Spin is now winding down operations in a few U.S. markets, all markets in Germany and Portugal and could shut down in Spain as early as February.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sw27Ik10hN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/27/micromobility-in-2022-refined-mature-and-packed-full-of-tech/">Micromobility in 2022: Refined, mature and packed full of tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Micromobility in 2022: Refined, mature and packed full of tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/27/micromobility-in-2022-refined-mature-and-packed-full-of-tech/embed/#?secret=sw27Ik10hN" data-secret="sw27Ik10hN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/lime-new-e-bike-swappable-battery-works-with-scooters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255824</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TravelPerk adds $115M to equity and debt Series D, discloses unicorn valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/travelperk-series-d-unicorn/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/travelperk-series-d-unicorn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avi Meir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barcelona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Booking.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Click Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kayak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kinnevik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NexTravel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TravelPerk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SME-focused business travel booking platform, TravelPerk, has topped up the $160 million in equity and debt it raised last in a Series D last April with an additional $115M &#8212; closing out the round at $275M. TravelPerk said its business is now being valued at $1.3BN &#8212; meaning it&#8217;s achieved coveted &#8216;unicorn&#8217; status. In total, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SME-focused business travel booking platform, <a href="https://www.travelperk.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TravelPerk</a>, has topped up the $160 million in equity and debt it raised last <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/travelperk-raises-160m-in-equity-and-debt-after-a-year-of-derailed-business-trips/">in a Series D last April </a>with an additional $115M &#8212; closing out the round at $275M.</p>
<p>TravelPerk said its business is now being valued at $1.3BN &#8212; meaning it&#8217;s achieved coveted &#8216;unicorn&#8217; status.</p>
<p>In total, it has raised $409M since being founded back in 2015.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256643" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company declined to disclose a valuation when it took in the earlier slice of equity and debt last year so the Barcelona-based startup is sounding more confident going into 2022 vs Spring 2021.</p>
<p>That said, it&#8217;s not clear how much of the $115M tranche is equity vs debt &#8212; a spokeswoman for the startup declined to provide a break down or a clear answer when we asked, saying only: &#8220;This round is a mix of equity and debt funding.&#8221;</p>
<p>The final tranche of the D round was led by US VC firm General Catalyst, a new investor in the business, along with existing backer Kinnevik.</p>
<p>Another investor in this slice of the Series D, Gillian Tans, ex-chairwoman and CEO of Booking.com &#8212; who is investing in a  personal capacity &#8212; is joining the board of directors alongside Joel Cutler, an early investor in Stripe, Airbnb, and Kayak.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Tans said: “I have been working in the travel industry for many years, and TravelPerk is the one company that never ceases to surprise me. It has solidified its leadership position over the last two years in challenging times for the travel industry, emerging stronger than ever. They are innovative and have been able to anticipate and address their customers’ changing needs through major acquisitions, new market entries, and product designs. I’m honored to be joining as an investor and the Board of Directors at TravelPerk and to help the company reach a global leadership position.”</p>
<p>General Catalyst MD Joel Cutler added in another supporting statement: “Hybrid and remote working is undoubtedly here to stay but a Zoom call will never be able to replicate the benefits of in-person, face-to-face interaction. We have no doubt that business travel will continue to grow and thrive in the years ahead, with TravelPerk as the clear leader in the space, and we’re thrilled to be participating in this funding round.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s certainly been a tough couple of years for the travel sector generally &#8212; and for work trips in particular &#8212; given the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic which has led to scores of conference cancelations and accelerated tools and tech around virtual meetings, which offer a low friction, low cost alternative to business travel for physical meetings.</p>
<p>In person industry events did start to pick up again last year &#8212; with major tech conferences such as the GSMA&#8217;s Mobile World Congress, Web Summit and CES (earlier this year) taking place in some capacity &#8212; but it&#8217;s typically been with vastly reduced attendance vs pre-pandemic years.</p>
<p>Streaming continues to be a popular choice for workers and employers to avoid the risk and hassle associated with pandemic era business travel.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RR7AjJMW3I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/22/as-exhibitors-mull-attendance-amid-omicron-ces-organizers-stand-firm/">As exhibitors mull attendance amid omicron, CES organizers stand firm</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As exhibitors mull attendance amid omicron, CES organizers stand firm&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/22/as-exhibitors-mull-attendance-amid-omicron-ces-organizers-stand-firm/embed/#?secret=RR7AjJMW3I" data-secret="RR7AjJMW3I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Despite obvious demand-side challenges for business travel, TravelPerk has continued to present a bullish front throughout this period &#8212; operating a no layoffs policy and splashing out on a number of acquisitions aimed at tooling up for COVID-19-triggered changes to how people are travelling for work.</p>
<p>It has also managed to tap investors to continue backing its platform as it reconfigures its feature mix to support changing business travel needs.</p>
<p>TravelPerk said the Series D will be used to double down on product development &#8212; with a focus on building tools for an era of hybrid working. Albeit, it&#8217;s focus is on trying to expand the portion of physically co-located working that&#8217;s going on.</p>
<p>A recent feature, added to TravelPerk&#8217;s platform in November, is an events organizing tool aimed at nudging customers to plan and book in-person get togethers, such as for an offsite, a party or a meeting of new starters. &#8220;TravelPerk Events enables remote and hybrid teams to connect in real life,&#8221; runs its marketing spiel for the tool.</p>
<p>“As time goes by, it is clear that there won’t be a replacement for the human touch. We are seeing data on our platform and we are feeling it ourselves,&#8221; argues CEO Avi Meir in a statement. “While some technologies are focused on virtual interactions, TravelPerk is building the technology that will help us get together in real life.”</p>
<p>The startup is also ploughing money into developing what it bills as &#8220;sustainable&#8221; travel solutions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.travelperk.com/blog/travelperk-acquires-susterra-to-usher-in-the-era-of-sustainable-business-travel/">Last fall</a> TravelPerk acquired a UK-based corporate responsibility consultancy, called Susterra, to beef up its ability to offer tools for customers to calculate a travel-related carbon footprint.</p>
<p>It was already offering carbon offsetting to try to grease bookings in spite of the existential challenge posed by climate change &#8212; which will require massive, swift global reductions in carbon emissions if humanity is to avoid environmental catastrophe, thereby presenting an obvious challenge to travel industry growth.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, TravelPerk is doing the opposite of talking down its growth prospects.</p>
<p>It said expanding in the US is another focus for the Series D &#8212; a market that became its largest <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/business-trip-platform-travelperk-buys-yc-backed-rival-nextravel/">a year ago</a> when it acquired US-based rival NexTravel.</p>
<p>It also plans to use the funding to double down on growth in its other large market: Europe.</p>
<p>Since 2019 (so pre-pandemic), TravelPerk said its business has grown 4x in terms of annualised revenue. It also said it has doubled its customer acquisition rate &#8212; albeit a considerable chunk of recent onboarding is likely to have come from acquisitions over this period.</p>
<p>As well as buying US-based NexTravel at the start of last year, it also picked up the UK&#8217;s Click Travel <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/travelperk-buys-uk-based-click-travel-in-latest-pandemic-purchase/">last summer</a>, at the time the largest business travel platform in the country.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z0CauBXBtd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/travelperk-raises-160m-in-equity-and-debt-after-a-year-of-derailed-business-trips/">TravelPerk raises $160M in equity and debt after a year of derailed business trips</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TravelPerk raises $160M in equity and debt after a year of derailed business trips&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/travelperk-raises-160m-in-equity-and-debt-after-a-year-of-derailed-business-trips/embed/#?secret=Z0CauBXBtd" data-secret="Z0CauBXBtd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/travelperk-series-d-unicorn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256643</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MTN Uganda introduces overdraft facility as it step-ups competition in digital lending space</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/mtn-uganda-introduces-overdraft-facility-as-it-step-ups-competition-in-digital-lending-space/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/mtn-uganda-introduces-overdraft-facility-as-it-step-ups-competition-in-digital-lending-space/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 10:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cameroon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital lenders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M-Pesa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rwanda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Safaricom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west africa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Africa’s mobile-money sector remains the most active of any region in the world according to GSM Association (GSMA), an umbrella body representing the interests of players in the telecommunications industry. The report shows that registered mobile money accounts in Africa stood at slightly over half a billion in 2020, a 12-percentage point growth from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Africa’s mobile-money sector remains the most active of any region in the world according to GSM Association (GSMA), an umbrella body representing the interests of players in the telecommunications industry. The <a href="https://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GSMA_State-of-the-Industry-Report-on-Mobile-Money-2021_Full-report.pdf">report</a> shows that registered mobile money accounts in Africa stood at slightly over half a billion in 2020, a 12-percentage point growth from the previous year. The value of transactions hit $495 billion, up 23-percentage points.</p>
<p>East Africa accounts for the bulk of Africa’s mobile money transactions followed by West Africa. The GSMA report shows that the value of transactions in West Africa had the highest growth after increasing by 46 percentage points to $178billion (the second highest value after East Africa’s).</p>
<p>Fundamentally, mobile money enables users to send and receive money, as well as to pay utility bills — but in advanced situations like it is across Africa, the wallet turns subscribers’ phone numbers into a sort of proxy for bank accounts.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256645" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As it grows, mobile money has come to be a launchpad for digital lenders, who use customers’ mobile money transaction history to determine the amount of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/fintechs-in-africa-continue-to-overshadow-all-other-startups-in-funding-gained/">instant credit to extend to borrowers</a> &#8212; monies that are then directly deposited into customers’ mobile money wallets.</p>
<p><strong>MTN Uganda&#8217;s mobile overdraft credit</strong></p>
<p>Innovative products grounded on mobile money include the newly-launched <a href="https://www.mtn.co.ug/mtn-momo/faqs/">MoMoAdvance</a>, an overdraft loan by MTN Uganda, the country’s biggest telco, and a subsidiary of the MTN Group &#8212; whose other affiliated companies have operations in southern, west and central regions of Africa.</p>
<p>MoMoAdvance was launched following a pilot program that started late 2020, and it allows MTN’s customers to overdraw on its MoMo (mobile money) wallet. Users will be charged an access fee of 2.75% of the amount borrowed, and a daily interest of 0.5% on the outstanding balance for a maximum of 45 days.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“MTN MoMoAdvance will offer the MTN MoMo customers the convenience of transacting beyond their MoMo wallet balance and pay back later… we believe that it will give them the convenience to transact seamlessly beyond their wallet balances during times of need then pay back later,” <a href="https://www.mtn.co.ug/mtn-momo-uganda-launches-momoadvance-an-overdraft-facility-that-enables-customers-transact-beyond-their-momo-wallet-balances/">said</a> MTN Mobile Financial Services, general manager, Stephen Mutana.</p>
<p>MoMoAdvance borrows heavily from a similar overdraft product, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/17/mobile-overdraft-facility-fuliza-outshines-silicon-valley-backed-lending-apps-in-kenya/">Fuliza, by Kenya’s biggest telco, Safaricom</a>, which was launched in January 2019, and allows subscribers to complete transactions even when they have insufficient funds in their M-Pesa mobile wallets.</p>
<p>The overdraft services are based on a borrowing limit that is defined by a customer&#8217;s transaction history, while the overdrawn amount and accrued interest are deducted from the customers’ wallets anytime they are topped up. Fuliza has grown in popularity over the last three years among M-Pesa users, with Safaricom now giving out about $12 million worth of overdraft loans every day.</p>
<p>Fuliza is offered in partnership with KCB and NCBA, both of which are Kenyan banks with a regional presence. MTN Uganda also partnered with NCBA for its MoMoAdvance credit, and it is now likely that the bank will establish such partnerships in other East African countries Rwanda and Tanzania, where it already has operations.</p>
<p>The mobile-money overdraft products are providing a competitive edge to telcos as lending apps continue to enter African markets. The apps have stepped up competition for telco-owned mobile lending services like MoKash by MTN Uganda and M-Shwari by Safaricom – which allow customers to borrow short-term loans and pay back within 30 days.</p>
<p>Such innovative and easily accessible digital lending services have made credit accessible to a majority of people in Africa, who were previously cut out by formal financial institutions for lack of a banking history. However, most of the emerging digital lenders charge predatory interests, often attributed to the high-risk environment that they work in. This is as the regulatory environment gradually adapts to formalize the sector, eventually leading to better pricing for users while shielding the service providers from losses.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/mtn-uganda-introduces-overdraft-facility-as-it-step-ups-competition-in-digital-lending-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256645</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Outlines showers your home with recyclable options</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/outlines/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/outlines/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 08:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cpg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Impact Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The sign of a true entrepreneur is someone who can look around and go &#8220;wait a minute, there must be a better way.&#8221; That approach worked well for Outlines&#8216; founders, who are tackling the unsexy but pretty serious recycling issue of shower curtain liners. The company just closed a $1 million pre-seed lead by Social Impact [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The sign of a true entrepreneur is someone who can look around and go &#8220;wait a minute, there <em>must be a better way.</em>&#8221; That approach worked well for <a href="https://livingoutlines.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Outlines</a>&#8216; founders, who are tackling the unsexy but pretty serious recycling issue of shower curtain liners. The company just closed a $1 million pre-seed lead by <a href="https://social-impact-capital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Social Impact Capital</a> to make sure that the giant water-splash-stopping sheets of plastic that are present in most of the 128 million households in the U.S. get sustainably recycled, rather than putting them in landfills.</p>
<p>&#8220;I moved to New York from London about six years ago. Like all New Yorkers I moved into like an old apartment that required me to have like a shower liner &#8212; one of those plastic shower curtains. Coming from Europe, like I was very used to a door or a plexiglass screen on the shower, or a separate shower unit. I was caught in this constant dilemma; I would pick up my shower liner, three or four months would go by it would get slimy and gross,&#8221; Outlines co-founder Luke Barkley Young explains. &#8220;I was in this really awkward position where I&#8217;d want to get a new one, but I had this plastic-guilt of throwing it away. I was used to being able to recycle everything, and I just hated this constant pain point.&#8221;</p>
<p>Long story short, Young and his co-founder Megan Murphy set out to solve the problem in a rather elegant way. The pair developed a shower curtain system where the top of the curtain, the weights and the shower curtain hooks are made from sturdy, long-lasting materials, and the shower liner itself is made from easy-to-recycle plastic. The company developed a business model where it can take the shower liner in return and recycle it responsibly, as it ships out replacement shower liners on a regular rotation.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256256" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company started as a project called &#8220;Drip,&#8221; where the duo found 2,500 early adopter customers who, in addition to being early paying customers, gave a lot of feedback about their needs as consumers. After a while, the company decided that there was almost certainly a sustainable market there, and spun up the Outlines company to explore that direction further.</p>
<p>Of course, a single-product company rarely makes a great investment opportunity, so I pressed the founding team on what might happen next in their product portfolio.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256528" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256528" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2256528" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="475" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg 4240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg?resize=150,70 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg?resize=300,139 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg?resize=768,356 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg?resize=680,315 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg?resize=1536,713 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg?resize=2048,950 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Clever.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256528" class="wp-caption-text">Outlines&#8217; shower curtain liner is full of clever details, including ensuring that all parts of the liner itself are recyclable, moving the weights and the metal clips to the parts of the curtain that are not designed to be refreshed. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Outlines</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We haven&#8217;t decided fully on what our second product will be. What we are interested in is bringing to market links to a much larger audience. We have a couple of ideas. Things like loofahs, potty scrubbers, dish scrubbers, these things that just by the sheer nature of what they do, are possible products for us. Nobody wants to clean their dishes with the same dish scrubber forever,&#8221; explained Young. &#8220;So we are working to really understand our customer base, to determine what we should release next. We definitely hope to do that in the first half of 2022.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On the one hand, the cynic in me is wondering &#8220;wait, we are giving VC funding to shower curtains, now?&#8221; but on the other hand, if 10% of households in the U.S. replace their shower curtain liners once every other year, that&#8217;s still 6 million sheets of plastic that need to be dealt with every year, somehow. Ensuring that it&#8217;s recycled responsibly doesn&#8217;t seem so bad. Still, I found myself wondering if a washable shower liner wouldn&#8217;t make more sense than shipping recyclable sheets of plastic around.</p>
<p>&#8220;First of all, shipping in general &#8212; especially in the United States &#8212; is becoming less carbon-intensive. So if you look at all the major couriers, they are adding more electric vehicles to their fleet. So carbon cost of shipping things back and forth is reducing, which is far superior to constantly shipping new stuff from the Far East where typically these plastic products are made. Also, when you do recycle in the U.S., there&#8217;s a lot more legislation and regulation around how recycling can happen versus overseas. The other point on this is when we throw items away they go to landfills. As they decompose, they actually release methane, which is a far more heavy greenhouse gas than CO<sub>2</sub> from shipping back and forward,&#8221; Young argues. He further explains that washable solutions aren&#8217;t really an option: &#8220;Reusable, washable plastics would be a dream, but there are two problems with that. First of all, a lot of plastic-based materials that are waterproof, like polyester, when you put them in your washing machine, the friction of that actually really releases millions of microplastics. Municipal water systems just cannot get them out of the water supply. And then if you were to use a natural fiber, they&#8217;re covered in what&#8217;s called a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Durable_water_repellent" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Durable Water Repellent (DWR)</a>. Over time, because of the heat of a shower, it actually corrodes off. When that happens, your shower liner doesn&#8217;t work. So for this use case, plastic is by far the best material to use.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company today announced it raised its $1 million round, and I wondered what&#8217;s possible now that wasn&#8217;t possible before they closed the round.</p>
<p>&#8220;We just closed the round of $1 million before our launch, which was very exciting. We&#8217;ve done a ton of development up until this point, both in the product and the design of the product, the website and the entire online experience. But we&#8217;re really excited about investing in our digital tools. The first part is a part of responsible replenishment, it&#8217;s all about serving you a plan that is highly personalized to your needs. Obviously what we&#8217;re trying to do with that isn&#8217;t ensure that we&#8217;re not sending you more than you need, but you&#8217;re also receiving enough so that you&#8217;re not standing next to mold every single morning,&#8221; explains Murphy. &#8220;We are investing in that piece to make sure that we are as smart as possible, and that we&#8217;re creating something that&#8217;s genuinely valuable to you as a customer. We are also really excited about further product development. As Luke said, we are already beginning work on the second product, but this is a big category with lots of space for innovation. So we are investing in future product development, to make sure that we&#8217;re rolling out new products at a relatively quick pace.&#8221;</p>
<p>You can learn more about Outlines at <a href="https://livingoutlines.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LivingOutlines.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/outlines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256256</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigeria&#8217;s SeamlessHR raises $10M to expand HR and payroll solutions across Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/nigerias-seamlesshr-raises-10m-to-expand-hr-and-payroll-solutions-across-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/nigerias-seamlesshr-raises-10m-to-expand-hr-and-payroll-solutions-across-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AXA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Capria Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embedded finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HR software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PWC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SeamlessHR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sterling Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tlcom Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Africa’s appetite for cloud computing software continues to increase as connectivity and bandwidth opportunities push boundaries. Per reports, the continent’s cloud computing industry coupled with the Middle East is expected to grow to $31.4 billion in 2026 from $14.2 billion last year. SeamlessHR, a Nigeria-based company that wants to help African businesses “leverage the continent’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Africa’s appetite for cloud computing software continues to increase as connectivity and bandwidth opportunities push boundaries. Per reports, the continent’s cloud computing industry coupled with the Middle East </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is expected</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to grow to $31.4 billion in 2026 from $14.2 billion last year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://seamlesshr.com/">SeamlessHR</a>, a Nigeria-based company that wants to help African businesses “leverage the continent’s greatest asset: abundant human capital” with its cloud-based human resources (HR) and payroll software, has raised $10 million in Series A funding for its next phase of growth and regional expansion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pan-African venture capital firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/tlcom-capital-closes-71m-africa-fund-with-plans-to-back-12-startups/">TLcom Capital</a> led the round. New investor Capria Ventures and existing investors Lateral Frontier Ventures, Enza Capital and Ingressive Capital participated.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256522" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s eponymous product is a cloud-based, end-to-end HR software that helps businesses manage and streamline their entire human resource processes and workflow.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its product suite includes an HR management system, performance and competency management, HR analytics, leave management, payroll management and recruitment management.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CEO <a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/dr-emmanuel-okeleji-722077b">Emmanuel Okeleji</a> and CTO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dejjy">Deji Lana</a> didn’t build SeamlessHR from the get-go</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It was four years after several iterations of Insidify, an aggregator site for job seekers and</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a review site for companies that they started SeamlessHR in 2018.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The natural client for our job sites was the HR,” CEO Okeleji told TechCrunch on a call. “So we thought, ‘how can we help HR to become more productive and successful so that they can run a better, more profitable company and hire more people in the process?’”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The founder also said one of the reasons for the pivot from Insidify to SeamlessHR was because the former wasn’t profitable and lacked the flexibility to scale across Africa. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With SeamlessHR, both goals could </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be accomplished and a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> year after launching SeamlessHR’s MVP, revenues picked up and was 10 times more than Insidify’s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Initially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the company signed a couple of smaller companies to build its reputation. But over time, it began to focus on bigger clients and signed up a bank as its first main enterprise customer. The company said that</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its enterprise-grade solution caters to various companies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They range from businesses with 100 employees or fewer to large enterprises with more than 10,000 employees; and from</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> multinationals and banks such as PwC, AXA and Sterling Bank to startups and investment firms like Flutterwave and TGI Group.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over 100,000 employees from these organizations use SeamlessHR monthly. “We have the largest aggregation of medium-to-very large companies in Africa,” Okeleji remarked.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Four years in, SeamlessHR is now rich with human resources and payroll data after handling salaries for several hundreds of companies. Sitting on top of such data provides leverage to build out more vertical products; for this reason, SeamlessHR will venture into launching embedded finance products for employees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s how it will work: Say a company is using SeamlessHR for its 5,000 employees; any one of them can tap into the platform’s earned wage access where they can get their salaries up until the point they’ve worked. It’s a typical salary structure in markets such as the U.S. but rarely used in markets like Nigeria.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In Africa, the innovation that allows people to access credit from their jobs doesn’t happen</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And an HR payroll software is well-positioned to lead that innovation because we use finance, technology and HR to help people convert their employment into collateral to access safe credit,” stated the CEO, who believes the company’s cash advances will appeal more to employees than “predatory” loans offered by some lending companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Africa’s payroll and HR management market has witnessed the emergence of newer companies such as YC-backed <a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/08/14/workpay-raises-seed-funding-kepple-africa-yc/">Workpay</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/nigerias-digital-payroll-platform-bento-expands-to-kenya-rwanda-and-ghana-to-enter-six-other-african-markets-in-2022/">Bento</a>. They help businesses with salary disbursement, taxes and pension, carving out a niche for themselves in a market that appears to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be dominated by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> SeamlessHR</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Building an HR solution in Africa requires more workaround than in developed markets, where most small businesses can afford to pay for software. The opportunity in Africa </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">primarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> lies with large corporates, not SMEs. They have higher purchasing power and a greater need for HR solutions; they make up the bulk of SeamlessHR’s customers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SeamlessHR has also eaten into the market share of legacy and “on-premise” systems like SAP and Oracle, commonly used by large companies </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">locally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Companies now know they can do without hiring employees who need certifications to manage software and concentrate on setting and onboarding cloud-based software solutions capable of serving their</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> needs, albeit cheaper. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Localization of software also plays a part in SeamlessHR replacing these legacy systems in Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TLcom Capital partner Andreata Muforo said of the investment, “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The strong execution shown by Emmanuel and his team is a vital ingredient required to build</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">a successful business and as they expand their products to include embedded finance and launch their</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">solutions to new markets, we’re proud to partner alongside them and strengthen their push to unlock more value within Africa’s B2B space.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company says its new funding will further strengthen its position as “Africa’s leading cloud HR and payroll platform</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.” Okeleji, who had a brief stint as an investment banker and practised as a doctor, said on the call that SeamlessHR would take its business south of the continent with South Africa as operating hub, thus hiring more staff. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company currently has a presence in Nigeria and Kenya; it’ll also use the funds to expand further in the East African country and surrounding markets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Product-wise, SeamlessHR plans to build out its embedded finance offerings and provide </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">additional</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> functionalities, especially around artificial intelligence, data analytics and machine learning.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Okeleji mentioned that SeamlessHR would move beyond human resources and payroll at some point into other departments that make organizations tick. He also hinted at the possibility of SeamlessHR scaling beyond Africa into other global markets, referencing the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/freshworks-aims-for-nearly-9-billion-valuation-in-us-ipo/">recent strides made by India’s Freshworks</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are building software solutions to optimize HR now, but in the future, we’ll go to other areas beyond HR. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And we </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are positioned</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to build a global SaaS company because SaaS products can travel the world faster than, say, fintech</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re beating global players in our local market and while we are not distracting ourselves now, we know we can play this game globally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/nigerias-seamlesshr-raises-10m-to-expand-hr-and-payroll-solutions-across-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256522</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>App Annie: Global app stores&#8217; consumer spend up 19% to $170B in 2021, downloads grew 5% to 230B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/app-annie-global-app-stores-consumer-spend-up-19-to-170b-in-2021-downloads-grew-5-to-230b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/app-annie-global-app-stores-consumer-spend-up-19-to-170b-in-2021-downloads-grew-5-to-230b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 08:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile device]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Weather Channel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256377</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Consumer spending on mobile apps reached $170 billion in 2021, according to App Annie&#8217;s newly released &#8220;State of Mobile 2022&#8243; report, out today, which offers a comprehensive look at the app economy across iOS, Google Play and third-party Android app stores in China. That figure is up 19% year-over-year, which is down just one percentage [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Consumer spending on mobile apps reached $170 billion in 2021, according to App Annie&#8217;s newly released &#8220;<a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/insights/market-data/state-of-mobile-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">State of Mobile 2022&#8243; report</a>, out today, which offers a comprehensive look at the app economy across iOS, Google Play and third-party Android app stores in China. That figure is up 19% year-over-year, which is down just one percentage point from the growth rate the firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">reported in its prior annual report</a>. Growth in app downloads, however, dipped a bit more. Though today&#8217;s consumers are installing more apps than ever &#8212; 230 billion were downloaded in 2021, setting another record &#8212; the growth rate itself is slowing.</p>
<p>In January 2021, App Annie reported year-over-year download growth of 7% during 2021, which has now dropped to just 5% in 2021.</p>
<p>Download growth today is being driven largely by emerging markets like India, as well as Pakistan, Peru, the Philippines, Vietnam, Indonesia and Egypt.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256377" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2256423" style="width: 2890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256423" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256423 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png" alt="" width="2880" height="1800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png?resize=2048,1280 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/SOM22Summary.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2880px) 100vw, 2880px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256423" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>What&#8217;s also clear is that consumers are spending more time in apps &#8212; even topping the time they spend watching TV in some cases.</p>
<p>The report noted the average American watches 3.1 hours of TV per day, for example, but over the course of the past year, they spent 4.1 hours on their mobile device. And they&#8217;re not even the world&#8217;s heaviest mobile users. In markets like Brazil, Indonesia and South Korea, users surpassed 5 hours per day in mobile apps in 2021.</p>
<p>Across the top 10 markets analyzed in the study, the average time spent in apps topped 4 hours, 48 minutes in 2021 &#8212; up 30% from 2019. This included the averages from Brazil, Indonesia, South Korea, Mexico, India, Japan, Turkey, Singapore, Canada, the U.S., Russia, the U.K., Australia, Argentina, France, Germany and China combined.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><img class="wp-image-2256436 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.13.35-PM.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Much of this time was spent in social, photo and video apps, which accounted for 7 out of every 10 minutes spent on mobile in the past year. These categories, plus entertainment apps, also appeal to Gen Z users, particularly in the U.S.</p>
<p>Here in the U.S., Gen Z&#8217;s most-used apps included Instagram, TikTok, Snapchat and Netflix. Millennials meanwhile preferred Facebook, Messenger, Amazon and WhatsApp. Gen X, which has now been lumped into the Baby Boomer demographic (ack!), used The Weather Channel, Amazon Alexa, NewsBreak and Ring.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256444" style="width: 1714px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256444" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256444 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1704" height="1522" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg 1704w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg?resize=150,134 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg?resize=300,268 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg?resize=768,686 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg?resize=680,607 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1372 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.15.56-PM.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1704px) 100vw, 1704px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256444" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>This increased time spent in apps has had a direct impact on consumer spending. In the U.S., the COVID-19 pandemic&#8217;s lingering effects have forced users to shop, work, learn, game and entertain themselves from home over the past year. This led to &#8220;phenomenal&#8221; growth in consumer spending, App Annie said, as the market added $43 billion in 2021, or $10.4 billion more than 2020, equating to 30% year-over-year growth &#8212; higher than the global average.</p>
<p>At the high end of consumer spending, there were 233 apps and games that pulled in more than $100 million in 2021, and 13 titles that generated over $1 billion. This is up 20% from 2020, when there were then 193 apps and games topping the $100 million mark, and only 8 titles making over $1 billion annually.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256449" style="width: 1652px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256449" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256449 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1642" height="1518" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg 1642w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg?resize=150,139 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg?resize=300,277 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg?resize=768,710 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg?resize=680,629 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1420 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.18.06-PM.jpg?resize=50,46 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1642px) 100vw, 1642px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256449" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>Outside the consumer spending that included paid apps, subscriptions and in-app purchases, the broader mobile app market topped $295 billion in 2021, up 23% year-over-year, despite fears from marketers over Apple&#8217;s privacy changes and IDFA crackdown. In 2022, the market is expected to grow to $350 billion, aided by big events including the Beijing Olympics and the U.S. mid-terms.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256447" style="width: 1394px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256447" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256447 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1384" height="1542" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg 1384w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg?resize=135,150 135w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg?resize=269,300 269w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg?resize=768,856 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg?resize=610,680 610w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg?resize=1379,1536 1379w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.16.47-PM.jpg?resize=45,50 45w" sizes="(max-width: 1384px) 100vw, 1384px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256447" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>New mobile app releases also grew in 2021, as publishers launched 2 million new apps and games, bringing the total number of apps and games ever released across the App Store and Google Play to 21+ million. Of course, older apps and games have since been removed over the years either by the publishers themselves or the app stores during cleanups. Currently, there are 5.4 million &#8220;live&#8221; apps and games available on the app stores, 1.8 million of which are on iOS and 3.6 million on Google Play.</p>
<p>Google Play also accounted for 77% of all the new releases last year, while games made up 15% of all releases across both stores, the report noted.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256450" style="width: 1106px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256450" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2256450 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1096" height="1552" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg 1096w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg?resize=106,150 106w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg?resize=212,300 212w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg?resize=768,1088 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg?resize=480,680 480w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg?resize=1085,1536 1085w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.17.56-PM.jpg?resize=35,50 35w" sizes="(max-width: 1096px) 100vw, 1096px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256450" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>App Annie&#8217;s full report took a deep dive into individual app categories, as well, including gaming, finance, retail, video streaming, food &amp; drink, health &amp; fitness, social, travel, dating and more.</p>
<p>Among the highlights from its findings:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Gaming</strong>: An additional $16 billion in gaming consumer spend was added in 2021, bringing the total spend to $116 billion.</li>
<li><strong>Finance</strong>: Finance app downloads in India topped 1 billion in 2021, driving the category&#8217;s 28% year-over-year increase in downloads to 5.9 billion worldwide.</li>
<li><strong>Shopping</strong>: Time in shopping apps reached over 100 billion hours spent globally in 2021, up 18% year-over-year. Countries with the fastest growth include Indonesia, Singapore and Brazil (52%, 46% and 45%, respectively).</li>
<li><strong>Video Streaming</strong>: Total hours spent watching video streaming apps grew 16% worldwide since pre-pandemic levels. But China saw declines as users shifted to short-form apps TikTok and Kwai. Netflix is on track to top 1 million downloads in more than 60 countries in 2022.</li>
<li><strong>Food &amp; Drink</strong>: Sessions in food &amp; drink apps reached 62 billion in 2021. Several regions drove growth in Q4, including the U.S. (42% year-over-year), Russia (154% YoY), Turkey (75% YoY) and Indonesia (over 9x growth).</li>
<li><strong>Health &amp; Fitness</strong>: Worldwide downloads of health &amp; fitness apps surpassed pre-COVID levels in 2021, despite a slight softening from a pandemic-induced high in 2020 in most countries. The top five meditation apps worldwide saw 27% year-over-year growth in consumer spending.</li>
<li><strong>Social</strong>: Time spent in the top 25 livestreaming apps outpaced the social market year-over-year by a factor of 9 &#8212; year-over-year growth of 40% compared to all social apps at 5%. Global spend in the top 25 livestreaming apps in 2021 grew 6.5x from 2018 and 55% year-over-year. TikTok saw year-over-year growth rates as high as 75%.</li>
<li><strong>Travel</strong>: Downloads of travel apps rebounded by 20% in H2 driven by sharp increases from July-December 2021. H2 downloads hit 1.95 billion globally, nearing pre-pandemic levels of 2.08 billion H2 2019.</li>
<li><strong>Dating</strong>: Worldwide consumer spending on dating apps topped $4 billion in 2021, a 95% increase since 2018. Growth was primarily driven by the U.S., Japan, China and the U.K. Tinder led the market with $1.35 billion in worldwide consumer spending in 2021.</li>
</ul>
<p>The report also listed the top apps and games worldwide and by individual countries by both downloads and consumer spending. Globally, the top five most downloaded apps in 2021 were Google Meet, Instagram, TikTok, Microsoft Teams and InShot. By consumer spend, the list was YouTube, Tinder, Tencent Video, Disney+ and TikTok.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256452" style="width: 1794px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256452" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256452 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1784" height="982" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg 1784w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg?resize=300,165 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg?resize=768,423 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg?resize=680,374 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg?resize=1536,845 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.42-PM.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1784px) 100vw, 1784px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256452" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>Top games by download included Project Makeover, acquapark.io, WormsZone.io, DOP 2: Delete One Part and Bridge Race. By spending, the list was led by Honour of Kings, Fantasy Westward Journey, Candy Crush Saga, Homescapes and Empires &amp; Puzzles.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256453" style="width: 1772px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256453" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256453 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1762" height="962" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg 1762w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg?resize=150,82 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg?resize=300,164 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg?resize=768,419 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg?resize=680,371 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg?resize=1536,839 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-4.20.52-PM.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1762px) 100vw, 1762px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256453" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>The full report is <a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/insights/market-data/state-of-mobile-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/app-annie-global-app-stores-consumer-spend-up-19-to-170b-in-2021-downloads-grew-5-to-230b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256377</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Refyne raises $82 million to help workers get faster access to wages</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/refyne-tiger-global-earned-wage-access-india/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/refyne-tiger-global-earned-wage-access-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 06:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DST Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earned wage access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refyne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RTP Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Refyne has raised a new financing round, just seven months after securing its previous funding, as the Bengaluru-based startup scales its platform that helps workers access their earned salaries in real time. Tiger Global led Refyne’s $82 million Series B funding, the two said Wednesday. Existing backers QED Investors, partners of DST Global, RTP Global, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Refyne has raised a new financing round, just seven months after securing its previous funding, as the Bengaluru-based startup scales its platform that helps workers access their earned salaries in real time.</p>
<p>Tiger Global led Refyne’s $82 million Series B funding, the two said Wednesday. Existing backers QED Investors, partners of DST Global, RTP Global, Jigsaw VC and XYZ Capital also participated in the new round, which takes the one-and-a-half-year-old startup’s all-time raise to $106 million.</p>
<p>Refyne did not disclose how it was valued in the new round, but its co-founder and chief executive Chitresh Sharma told TechCrunch in an interview that the valuation has surged 6.5 times since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/refyne-raises-20-1-million-to-help-workers-in-india-get-faster-access-to-wages/">the Series A in June</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256548" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Refyne is building what is known in the industry as an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/earned-wage-access/">earned wage access platform</a>, where a link is established between reward and work. The startup works with employers to enable their workers to access their earned salaries in real time. An employee with the partnered firm can log into Refyne and see how much they have earned in a week and withdraw a fraction of it anytime they wish, for instance.</p>
<p>It’s not rare for people to run out of cash between their paychecks. In that moment, they either take a loan from friends and family, or go to a bank or, in an alarmingly high number of cases, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/google-cracks-down-on-personal-loan-apps-in-india-following-abuse-and-outcry/">approach loan sharks</a>. Refyne is serving clients who hire both white-collar and blue-collar workers, so for many of them, a bank loan is unlikely an option.</p>
<p>The idea &#8212; which has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/wagely-an-indonesian-earned-wage-access-and-financial-services-platform-raises-5-6m/">put to test in several markets</a> &#8212; appears to be showing signs of a market fit in India, the world&#8217;s second-most populous nation. More than 150 firms &#8212; including Practo, TeamLease, Tenon, Shadowfax, Rebel Foods, Acko, BlackBuck, Arti Group and Cafe Coffee Day &#8212; are working with Refyne today to enable the service for their over 700,000 employees, Sharma said.</p>
<p>Its clients today operate in a wide range of categories, a factor that Sharma said requires Refyne to employ different strategies to best serve each. “For manufacturing sector, we have an on-ground team that goes for orientation and induction. Seventy percent of our effort goes before deploying. For companies that are geographically distributed, given the COVID times, we also do a lot of Zoom orientation.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2256559" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256559" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256559 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/refyne-tiger-global-chitresh-sharma-apoorv-kumar.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/refyne-tiger-global-chitresh-sharma-apoorv-kumar.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/refyne-tiger-global-chitresh-sharma-apoorv-kumar.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/refyne-tiger-global-chitresh-sharma-apoorv-kumar.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/refyne-tiger-global-chitresh-sharma-apoorv-kumar.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/refyne-tiger-global-chitresh-sharma-apoorv-kumar.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/refyne-tiger-global-chitresh-sharma-apoorv-kumar.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256559" class="wp-caption-text">Chitresh Sharma (left) and Apoorv Kumar co-founded Refyne. <strong>Image Credits: </strong>Refyne</p></div></p>
<p>In a statement, Alex Cook, a partner at Tiger Global, said: “We believe Refyne will be the preferred partner for large employers that want to offer Earned Wage Access. We are excited to support Chitresh, Apoorv and the Refyne team, as they work to improve financial wellness for the Indian workforce.”</p>
<p>The platform, which supports 12 languages and is compatible with any human resource management system and enterprise resource planning service, has had a “significant impact on retention for the clients, and in helping employers hire faster,” Sharma said, adding that the startup was the first and the largest player in the space. That has added responsibility on Refyne to make the market aware of EWA and quash some misconceptions, he said.</p>
<p>“Some people confuse us with other forms of credit products such as payday lenders. So most of our effort will be in ensuring that the category is well-known while we continue to expand our growth numbers,” he said.</p>
<p>Sharma said the startup is working continually to improve its service and building data sets to understand how people behave to help better evaluate and project their creditworthiness. “Current credit scoring looks at people’s past behavior to determine their future.”</p>
<p>The startup aims to serve 3 million workers by the end of the year and is also hiring in several roles.</p>
<p>“The support and confidence that global investors such as Tiger Global have shown us is a testament to our mission,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/refyne-tiger-global-earned-wage-access-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256548</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Despite blockchain gaming&#8217;s play-to-earn angle, I prefer to pay</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axie Infinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can't get that hyped about blockchain gaming — I want to have fun, not monetize my experience.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If there&#8217;s one thing that venture capitalists have taught me, it&#8217;s that aligned incentives can kick ass.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a phrase you&#8217;ll hear often if you spend time with professional private market investors. But if I summon my collegiate years, the phrase is really just the economic principle that individuals respond to incentives, restated in a slightly more targeted fashion.</p>
<p>In the land of venture capital, the idea works out as follows: Individuals respond to incentives, so you want to ensure that everyone at a company, for example, has <em>aligned </em>incentives.</p>
<p>This is why startups often offer a dusting of equity to employees, giving them a tiny slice of ownership in the overall project. This <em>aligns</em> employee incentives toward aggregate corporate success, something that employers want because they are in the game of paying people as little as they can while still hitting human capital quality benchmarks and not having too much employee churn.</p>
<p>There are less crassly capitalistic reads of why venture capitalists allow startups to sell equity to employees at below-market rates through options. I don&#8217;t buy them. Investors like return, and they optimize for it, thanks to their own incentive structure.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ataFpxlSbr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/">Blockchain gaming survey: 7 investors discuss regulation, opportunities and NFT hype</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Blockchain gaming survey: 7 investors discuss regulation, opportunities and NFT hype&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/embed/#?secret=ataFpxlSbr" data-secret="ataFpxlSbr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>VCs have a good gig. They take money from existing capital pools, invest it in work that others are doing, and then get a cut of deal profits while also ripping a few hundred bips per year of their total investing vehicle. Here again, we see aligned incentives, with venture capitalists profiting when <em>their</em> backers profit. Teamwork.</p>
<p>I drag you through all of that to explain that the concept of aligned incentives is marrow-deep in the startup and venture capital worlds, something that can, at times, blind folks to other ways of doing business.</p>
<p>Games, for example. Crypto games in particular.</p>
<p>You see, the crypto community and its myriad backers are pretty hot on crypto games. Here, it seems, is a place where incentives can be aligned in a new, exciting manner, translating gaming into related economic activity. All the fun of games, but with aligned economic incentives! What could go wrong?</p>
<h2>Play to earn?</h2>
<p>Through the lens of aligned incentives, the concept of play-to-earn games on a blockchain excites venture capitalists. Users will play the game, generating both fun and economic activity. The user gets some of the value, and the company the rest. Everyone is happy, and the game can go on making money forever, right?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain gaming survey: 7 investors discuss regulation, opportunities and NFT hype</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karan Bhasin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axie Infinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC investor survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPG]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s still a haze of uncertainty surrounding blockchain games, so we reached out to several active investors in to get a clearer picture of where opportunities exist today and what they see on the horizon.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The video-game industry has always been on the bleeding edge, but blockchain gaming is still widely viewed as emerging technology.</p>
<p>In October 2021, Valve banned all blockchain-related games from its Steam platform. Meanwhile, within Axie Infinity, an NFT-based online game, new players are paying hundreds of dollars to acquire mythical pets and love potions.</p>
<p>There’s still a haze of uncertainty surrounding blockchain games, so we reached out to several active investors in the space to get a clearer picture of where opportunities exist today and what they see on the horizon. We asked them to share the advice they&#8217;re giving their portfolio companies, along with their thoughts on how future regulation might impact the industry.</p>
<p>Interestingly, at least one investor noted that growth wasn&#8217;t a key consideration: &#8220;We tell our companies to really think about the missing pieces, particularly in gaming infrastructure,&#8221; said Banafsheh Fathieh, head of investments, Americas at Prosus Ventures. &#8220;What are the pain points we can alleviate for users and builders? Growth is less of a focus now, utility is incredibly important at this stage.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We surveyed:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonbackman/?originalSubdomain=fi">Anton Backman</a>, principal, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenrick/?originalSubdomain=sg">Kenrick Drijkoningen</a>, general partner, <a href="https://www.playventures.vc/">Play Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/banafsheh-b-fathieh-97629469/">Banafsheh Fathieh</a>, head of investments, Americas, <a href="https://www.prosus.com/ventures">Prosus Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshchapmanb/">Josh Chapman</a>, managing partner, <a href="https://www.konvoy.vc/">Konvoy Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardthai/?originalSubdomain=vn">Eddie Thai</a>, general partner, <a href="https://vietnam.500.co/">500 Startups</a> and general partner, <a href="https://ascendvietnam.com/">Ascend Vietnam Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/beryl-chavez-li-832baa4b/?originalSubdomain=ph">Beryl Li</a>, co-founder, <a href="https://yieldguild.io/">Yield Guild Games</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajulgarg/?originalSubdomain=in">Rajul Garg</a>, founder and managing partner, <a href="https://leo.capital/">Leo Capital</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h2 class="p1">Anton Backman, principal, and Kenrick Drijkoningen, general partner, Play Ventures</h2>
<p><strong>What was your initial reaction on hearing about Steam’s ban on blockchain games?</strong></p>
<p>It was not an entirely unexpected move from Steam. Incumbents tend to be more wary of adapting new business models and gaming is no different. As a fledgling space, NFTs are beridden with projects of varying quality and we believe Steam wants to do some quality assurance and wait until the situation stabilizes before allowing blockchain games en masse. Interestingly enough, at the time of writing (Nov 14) MIR4, a crypto-enabled MMORPG on Steam, is running at 88,000 concurrent users. Seems that there’s still a gray area in terms of how these games are classified.</p>
<p><strong>What advice have you been giving your portfolio companies to grow? What sort of guidance and assistance do blockchain gaming companies seek from you?</strong></p>
<p>We typically act as a sparring partner for founders in strategy-related matters. With blockchain gaming companies we have mostly assisted the teams in navigating the technology stack, i.e., what blockchains and/or scaling solutions to consider, as well as token economic design. In our view it’s key to embrace a crypto native approach of building and experimenting with the product while also involving your community in the process.</p>
<p><strong>How do you view the regulatory environment for blockchain gaming? Is the uncertainty making you reconsider your strategy?</strong></p>
<p>No. It’s not the first time innovation has outpaced regulation and we see it as a natural reaction to new consumer behavior and ways of building companies. Similarly, Uber fought an uphill battle with regulators before eventually democratizing the taxi medallion system and providing an outsized improvement for end users of taxi services. This doesn’t mean that companies and projects should build products that are against the law but rather engage in healthy discussion with regulators as the adoption of their products increases.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254571</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harry&#8217;s files paperwork for fresh $139.9M financing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/harrys-files-paperwork-for-fresh-139-9m-financing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/harrys-files-paperwork-for-fresh-139-9m-financing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[razor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tehmina Haider]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Harry’s goal since birth was to target incumbents in the global shave market, which is forecasted to reach $22.5 billion by 2030.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Yay, no errors, warnings, or alerts! --></p>
<p>A year after the FTC blocked <a href="https://www.harrys.com/en/us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Harry’s</a> from getting acquired by Edgewell Personal Care, the direct-to-consumer razor startup raised $155 million in Series E financing to give it a $1.7 billion valuation. Now, months later, Harry’s filed paperwork indicating that it has raised another nine-figure cash tranche.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1556308/000155630822000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEC filings</a> show that Harry’s has raised $139.9 million in a new financing event. The same filing listed the co-founders alongside Zola’s co-founder Shan-Lyn Ma, Addition Capital founder Lee Fixel, Campbell Soup Co. CEO Mark Clouse, politician Helena Foulkes, Zoom chief diversity officer Damien Hooper-Campbell, as well as Harry’s chief financial officer Jeff Lipkin and chief counsel Jack Sarno.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256504" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Harry’s, through a spokesperson, said, “we are not commenting at this moment.”</p>
<p>The new funding gives the company just over $791 million in total known funding since the company was founded in 2013, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/harrys" target="_blank" rel="noopener">according to Crunchbase data.</a></p>
<h2>From acquisition target to brand incubator</h2>
<p>Harry’s has been quite active over the past year. It recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/harrys-acquisition-d2c-deodorant-lume/">acquired</a> Lumē, <a href="https://lumedeodorant.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a direct-to-consumer brand</a> created to help control all-over body odor, in an undisclosed deal. Early in 2021, it launched its Headquarters hair care line. In a previous interview with TechCrunch, Tehmina Haider, Harry’s chief growth officer, spoke to the company’s focus on acquiring businesses with “demonstrated product fit and consumer love.”</p>
<p>“The idea about M&amp;A for Harry’s is we want to be a multi-category CPG company and build a family of CPG brands,” she said. “We want to create more and better things for consumers, and we are looking for brands aligned with that mission, are positioned in a way we can be helpful and are brands serving unmet needs.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Whether or not this is a plan to help it eventually enter the public markets is unclear, but it does help that the late-stage DTC company has some precedent to look to.</p>
<p>Casper, which recently left the public markets after its rocky debut, taught investors and the public about the limits of DTC companies, while <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/warby-parker-makes-it-clear-that-direct-listings-are-unicorn-friendly/">Warby Parker’s direct listing gave the same cohort some hope. </a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/caspers-return-to-private-life-isnt-a-canary-for-dtc-companies-going-public/">As our own Alex Wilhelm puts it</a>, DTC companies that want to go public either need to “grow quickly enough that losses feel secondary, leading to share-price appreciation and the ability to self-fund growth as needed” or find a way to trim losses if growth slows. In other words, it may not appear as SaaS growth, but it could appear as value growth.</p>
<p>Regardless of if it goes down the public market path or not, Harry’s goal since birth was to target incumbents in the global shave market, which is forecasted to reach <a href="https://www.psmarketresearch.com/market-analysis/razor-market" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$22.5 billion by 2030.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/harrys-files-paperwork-for-fresh-139-9m-financing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256504</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: After clinching $12.3B valuation, Brex hires Meta exec as chief product officer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/daily-crunch-after-clinching-12-3b-valuation-brex-hires-meta-exec-as-chief-product-officer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/daily-crunch-after-clinching-12-3b-valuation-brex-hires-meta-exec-as-chief-product-officer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fertilis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justworks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em><br />
<!-- Yay, no errors, warnings, or alerts! --></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for January 11, 2022! Today we have new venture funds, spyware news, Brex raising (again), and more. We’re back to 100% of last year’s startup and technology news pace, so we do hope you are rested up. It’s going to be a hectic, busy year. – <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-admin/twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2><strong>The TechCrunch Top 3</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/poland-nso-pegasus-election/">Cybersecurity matters to democracy</a>: Spyware built by the infamous NSO Group was “used to spy on three critics of the Polish government,” according to Citizen Lab, TechCrunch reports. The result of the allegations is that there are now questions regarding Poland’s 2019 parliamentary elections. This is not the last time we’ll see this sort of story around the world.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/turos-s-1-filing-shows-that-unicorns-can-slingshot-out-of-the-pandemic/">Turo’s business roars back in 2021</a>: Car-rental unicorn Turo has filed to go public, so TechCrunch dug into the numbers. The gist is that after a pretty flat 2020, Turo’s business posted strong growth and improved revenue quality during the first three quarters of 2021. We should get more updated numbers in time. (For you IPO fans out there, recall that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/20/justworks-files-to-take-its-smb-focused-hr-themed-saas-business-public/">HR software firm Justworks will debut later this week</a>.)</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/brex-confirms-12-3b-valuation-hires-meta-exec-to-serve-as-its-chief-product-officer/">Brex confirms $300M raise</a>: The race to control the corporate spend market was a key theme last year, and 2022 is starting on a similar note, with well-known market competitor Brex confirming that it raised nine figures in a Series D-2 round that values the former startup at $12.3 billion. We expect Ramp, Brex’s rival, to announce more capital by the time you read this brief, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/ramp-raises-300m-at-a-3-9b-valuation-makes-its-first-acquisition/">given how last year went</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Startups/VC</strong></h2>
<p>Kicking off our startup coverage today, a few notes before we get into the individual bulletins. First, the SPAC boom has left the public market littered with formerly private companies that combined with blank-check entities and then lost half their value. SPACs failed to get enough private companies public last year to cut the number of unicorns, and the lackluster post-combination results <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/the-spac-boom-was-a-failure-yeah/">add up to a general failure</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256445" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>And Kleiner Perkins has joined a16z and Norwerst in announcing more than 10 figures worth of new capital. The venture capital firm, now in its 50th year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/kleiner-perkins-starts-off-50th-year-with-1-8b-in-two-new-funds/">just closed $1.8 billion across two funds</a>. Founders, that sound you just heard was the starting gun.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/locket-an-app-for-sharing-photos-to-friends-homescreens-hits-the-top-of-the-app-store/">Locket shoots to the top of app stores</a>: Today Sarah Perez added me on a new social service, leading to us trading selfies and dog pics back and forth. The app? Locket, which is tearing up the mobile application charts. Read on for what it does and why it’s popular.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/orbit-fabs-on-orbit-fuel-shuttle-will-top-up-astroscales-servicing-satellites/">In-orbit refueling</a>: This story is the coolest. Darrell Etherington, our in-house space expert, writes that “Orbit Fab has teamed with Astroscale to provide on-orbit refueling services to the latter company’s geostationary servicing spacecraft.” This is a solution to a problem that most folks don’t think about. But if we want low-flying satellites to stay, well, afloat, they will at times need more fuel. And it looks like the tech to do so is getting close to maturity.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/back-market-reaches-5-7b-valuation-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/">Back Market puts more points on the board for France</a>: French startups had a pretty good 2021, and Back Market is helping the country’s upstart tech scene start this year on solid footing. The company “operates a marketplace of refurbished electronics devices” and just closed a $510 million Series E that values it at $5.7 billion. Last year it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/back-market-raises-another-335-million-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/">raised $335 million</a>, for reference.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/fertilis-ivf-cell-culture-funding/">IVF tech is hot</a>: If you haven’t had a chance to visit the shores of infertility, you might not be aware of just how complicated the in-vitro fertilization (IVF) process is. It’s complex. The good news for would-be parents is that startups like Fertilis, an Australian company, are raising capital to make the ordeal a bit more likely to result in a live birth.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/novo-the-smb-neobank-nabs-90m-at-a-700m-valuation/">Novo proves that there is still capital in the market for neobanks</a>: Sure, Chime has yet to go public, much to our chagrin, but a lack of exits in the neobanking space is not slowing investors down. Novo, a neobank aimed at SMBs, just closed $90 million at a $700 million valuation.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/fast-charge-ev-battery-maker-storedot-pulls-in-80m-led-led-by-vietnams-vinfast/">StoreDot raises capital for super-fast battery charging</a>: EVs are great, but they are still a bit slow to recharge. While gas-powered cars are not great for the air we breathe, they are incredibly good at onboarding fuel. StoreDot is busy closing a round that could be worth up to $80 million for like, <em>very</em> fast battery topping-up.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/gostudent-raises-340m-series-d-funding-round-as-it-pushes-into-international-markets/">Online tutoring is big business (outside of China)</a>: Sure, the Chinese government <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/">drop-kicked its domestic edtech market</a>, but that doesn’t mean that tutoring is kaput as a business type around the world. Evidence of that? GoStudent just closed a $340 million Series D less than a year after it closed a $244 million Series C.</li>
</ul>
<p>We’re low on time, but there was so much more: This <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-admin/ises-6-2m-pre-series-a/">African e-commerce company</a> just closed a Series A, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/mostly-ai-raises-25-million-to-further-commercialize-synthetic-data-in-europe-and-the-u-s/">Mostly AI landed $25 million</a>, and Qonto – also in the business banking space like Novo! – <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/business-banking-startup-qonto-raises-552-million-at-5-billion-valuation/">raised more than half a billion</a>. It’s <em>busy</em> out there.</p>
<p>And just to squeeze in one more thing, <a href="https://twitter.com/ron_miller">Ron Miller</a> has a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tupu-io-wants-to-help-women-thrive-in-tech-jobs-through-mentorship/">great story up on a group that is helping women in tech thrive through mentorship</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2255889" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255889" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255889" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg" alt="Exclamation mark ,3D render against an orange background." width="1024" height="619" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=768,464 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=680,411 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255889" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=ShadowPix" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ShadowPix <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Startups grow fast, and when you’re building one, it can be easy to lose track of what’s working — and what’s not.</p>
<p>One way to track how well your business is doing is to look at the big-picture numbers, but Karen Peacock, CEO of Intercom, has a warning: Averages can be dangerously misleading.</p>
<p>“If Jeff Bezos walks into a bar with 100 people, suddenly, on average, the net worth of each individual in that bar is over a billion dollars. Is that useful? Would that lead you to take the right actions? No — averages hide true insights.”</p>
<p>Peacock explains how founders can assess where their business’ strengths lie and where they need to work harder, including how to gauge revenue health and use customer segmentation to find “leaks in the bucket.”</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZpSeR1VcW7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/dont-trust-averages-how-to-assess-and-strengthen-the-health-of-your-business/">Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/dont-trust-averages-how-to-assess-and-strengthen-the-health-of-your-business/embed/#?secret=ZpSeR1VcW7" data-secret="ZpSeR1VcW7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2><strong>Big Tech Inc.</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/apple-to-allow-third-party-app-payment-options-in-south-korea/">Apple to allow third-party payment options in South Korea</a>: A change in the wind? Perhaps. News that Apple will change its in-app payment rules in South Korea – it didn’t have a choice – could lead other countries to similar rulings. For Apple, focused on preserving a large slice of the iOS economy for itself, it’s bad news.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/edps-decision-european-parliament-covid-19-test-website/">The EU sanctions itself over privacy errors</a>: Here’s a fun one – insert the Spider-Man pointing at Spider-Man meme – the “European Union’s chief data protection supervisor has sanctioned the European Parliament for a series of breaches of the bloc’s data protection rules,” <a href="https://twitter.com/riptari">Natasha Lomas</a> writes. At least they are consistent!</li>
<li>And finally today, the Indian government will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/vodafone-idea-india-government/">now own just under 36% of Vodafone Idea</a>, “to save the third-largest telecom operator in the country from collapsing.” Wild!</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>TechCrunch Experts</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend software consultants who have expertise in UI/UX, website development, mobile development and more! If you’re a software consultant, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/daily-crunch-after-clinching-12-3b-valuation-brex-hires-meta-exec-as-chief-product-officer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256445</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s what happened when Mercedes-AMG got its hands on the all-electric EQS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/first-drive-2022-mercedes-amg-eqs-and-2022-mercedes-amg-sl/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/first-drive-2022-mercedes-amg-eqs-and-2022-mercedes-amg-sl/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roberto Baldwin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auto tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes EQS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes-AMG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First, there was the dense fog. Then there was the snow. But inclement weather couldn&#8217;t put a damper on the AMG iterations of Mercedes&#8217; flagship EV or its latest generation SL. Performance, luxury, comfort, and technology all hit the mark even when the AMG team gets their hands on the Mercedes EQS and the latest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">First, there was the dense fog. Then there was the snow. But inclement weather couldn&#8217;t put a damper on the AMG iterations of Mercedes&#8217; flagship EV or its latest generation SL.</p>
<p>Performance, luxury, comfort, and technology all hit the mark even when the AMG team gets their hands on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/all-the-tech-crammed-into-the-2022-mercedes-benz-eqs/">Mercedes EQS</a> and the latest SL Roadster.</p>
<p>At its core, the 2022 Mercedes AMG SL Roadster still has a glimmer of the soul that enveloped the original 300 SL Roadster introduced in the late 1950s. Where that vehicle was the top-down transportation of choice of Hollywood&#8217;s golden era elite, it&#8217;s easy to imagine Clooney, Mirren, and Run the Jewel&#8217;s Killer Mike rolling into an event behind the wheel of this newest convertible.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256366" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2256467" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256467" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256467 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg" alt="The new Mercedes-AMG SL Roadster" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256467" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG SL 63 4Matic+ <strong>Image credit</strong>: Mercedes-Benz</p></div></p>
<p>And while the Bondish AMG SL Roadster has roots in last century, the AMG EQS is Ironman. It&#8217;s all about all today&#8217;s tech being used to accomplish a goal &#8212; while like the Roadster &#8212; doing so in style.</p>
<p>Both the AMG SL Roadster and AMG EQS are new vehicles and while they share much of the same technology at their core, there is a stark difference.</p>
<p>The menacing roar of the SL is replaced in the EQS by a composed set of sounds. The EQS has instant EV torque, the SL&#8217;s impressive displacement and turbos are no match for the EVs launch potential.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Mercedes will build handcrafted engines for its AMG lineup until the bitter end. There is no handcrafted electric motor in the AMG EQS. The signature of a technician will not show up on a battery pack. Meanwhile, the amount of filth spewed into the air by the EQS is merely a fraction of what the V8 roadster will put into our atmosphere over its lifetime.</p>
<h2>2022 Mercedes AMG EQS</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2256468" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256468" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256468 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg" alt="The new Mercedes-AMG EQS" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256468" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG EQS 53 4MATIC+ at a charging station. <strong>Image credit</strong>: Mercedes</p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s a concern with a vehicle that&#8217;s built to be luxury-first that it could be slightly ruined by receiving the performance treatment. If a sedan&#8217;s main purpose is to pamper the driver and passengers, stiffening up the ride and remapping the accelerator so that every little tap results in a neck snap, it&#8217;s really no longer accomplishing its goal.</p>
<p>EQS fans that also want to go faster, relax. That hasn&#8217;t happened here. The AMG EQS — the first electric AMG to land in the United States — deftly combines what&#8217;s great about the electric luxury sedan with some tuning by the AMG team.</p>
<p>With a power increase of up to 751 horsepower and 752-pound feet of torque (a jump of ​​133 horsepower and 69-pound feet of torque over the EQS580), the luxury electric sedan feels decidedly quicker than its non-AMG counterpart. An internal being slammed into your spine 3.4 seconds from zero to 60 quicker.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not just the two electric motors that got an upgrade. Tweaks to the cooling system, wiring, and battery management system of the 107.8-kWh capacity pack on the AMG variant also allow the vehicle in Sport and Sport Plus mode to stay at peak performance longer. During my drive from Palm Springs to Los Angeles, I never felt a loss of power after multiple acceleration tests.</p>
<p>That increase also comes with new acceleration-coupled sounds in the vehicle called the AMG sound experience. I&#8217;m a fan of these EV noises. While artificial, they do recreate the audible experience of sudden bursts of speed.</p>
<p>The power increase is accompanied by AMG ride control air suspension with active dampeners. Throw in the 4Matic+ all-wheel-drive system and rear-wheel steering of up to nine degrees and attacking hairpin turns at speed a controlled and impressive experience considering the size and heft of the vehicle. There is some body roll, but it&#8217;s far less than what I&#8217;ve experienced on the regular EQS.</p>
<p>In addition to all those performance hardware and software tweaks and the new Sport Plus, there&#8217;s another new mode that luck would have it, I was able to test. As we climbed higher into the mountains during the drive, and the road transformed from black to gray, to snow-covered white, I was able to use that AMG Slippery mode. Which worked wonderfully in the ice and snow and any loss of traction was short-lived and more likely the result of the AMG EQS rolling on Michelin Pilot Sport EV summer tires.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256472" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256472" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256472 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg" alt="Mercedes AMG EQS electric vehicle" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256472" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG EQS encounters snowy roads. <strong>Image credit</strong>: Roberto Baldwin</p></div></p>
<p>When choosing the wheels for this drive program Mercedes was clearly expecting dry roads and if not sunny weather, at least dry weather. Mother Nature had other plans. With winter or even all-season rubber, the AMG EQS would have made even those nervous about driving on frozen water more at ease.</p>
<p>Inside, other than a few AMG flourishes here and there, it&#8217;s the same EQS with the latest MBUX infotainment system and its enormous 56-inch Hyperscreen that includes a 12.3 instrument cluster, 17.7 -inch touchscreen display, and 12.3-inch passenger display. All standard in the AMG trim level. The display also includes the Zero Layer interface, which presents a map with widgets of features that appear as needed.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256474" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256474" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256474 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg" alt="The new Mercedes-AMG " width="2000" height="1039" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=300,156 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=768,399 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=680,353 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=1536,798 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256474" class="wp-caption-text">Interior of Mercedes-AMG EQS 53 4MATIC+ shows the expansive infotainment system. Image credit: Mercedes</p></div></p>
<p>The crown jewel of MBUX — the voice assistant — continues to evolve. &#8220;Hey Mercedes&#8221; along with the Zero Layer interface are essentially the standard by what other automakers should strive to accomplish in the vehicle. A robust voice-powered navigation feature coupled with a more focused screen.</p>
<p>On more than a few occasions, I realized that instead of looking for a feature, I&#8217;d ask the vehicle to do what I wanted. Other items, like media controls that in previous generation Mercedes required multiple taps to skip to the next song, were presented readily in the Zero Layer interface hovering over the navigation.</p>
<p>Like with the SL Roadster, the combination of voice assistant and Zero Layer make for an improved infotainment experience although, I&#8217;m still puzzled why Mercedes made the screen so wide it&#8217;s actually blocked by the steering wheel. Sure they moved all the widgets over, but it&#8217;s still an odd decision beyond the ability to say, &#8220;hey, look how big we made that display.&#8221;</p>
<h2>2022 Mercedes AMG SL</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2256478" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256478" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256478 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg" alt="Mercedes AMG EQS electric vehicle" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256478" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG SL on a foggy section of the test drive.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Roberto Baldwin</p></div></p>
<p>While the balance of luxury versus performance errs on the side of speed and handling thanks to up to 577 horsepower and 590 pound-feet of torque on the AMG SL 63 variant, even at slow speeds (thanks to the previously mentions fog), the AMG SL delivers a rich top-down experience.</p>
<p>Mercedes will sell two versions of the vehicle, the AMG SL 55 Roadster with 469 horsepower and 516 pound-feet of torque and the more powerful 63 variant mentioned above. Both are outfitted with the automaker&#8217;s all-wheel-drive 4Matic+ system powered by handcrafted 4.0-liter V8 Biturbo engines.</p>
<p>The result of all that displacement coupled with turbos is impressive and well-mannered power that reacts instantly either from a standstill or while passing slower vehicles. The AMG SL 63 might be the more powerful vehicle, but the AMG SL 55 is likely the better call since there are very few instances where all that extra horsepower and torque are even usable.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256479" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256479" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256479 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg" alt="Mercedes AMG SL" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256479" class="wp-caption-text">Interior shot of Mercedes-AMG SL<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Roberto Baldwin</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s also the least powerful SL Roadster you&#8217;ll be able to buy of this generation. Mercedes has no plans to release a non-performance version of the roadster. Instead, as with all other Mercedes, it&#8217;s decided to make sure that this vehicle, when not blasting through canyons, is as smooth and luxurious as any other Mercedes. During my tests, I can say that they&#8217;re about 85% there.</p>
<p>On everyday suburban and urban roads, the AMG SL Roadster offers up a nearly glassy ride, but its performance underpinnings are a gentle reminder that this is not an S-Class. You&#8217;re going to feel some of the bumps, holes and ruts in the road. The bright side to that is impressive handling that even on rain-slicked roads, kept the wheels firmly planted to the asphalt with just the slightest bit of oversteer that only appeared when you really pushed the vehicle. Steering is tight and responsive without feeling twitchy and the inclusion of the rear-wheel steering creates the impression of a smaller vehicle both on backroads and while tooling around town.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256477" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256477" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256477 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg" alt="Mercedes-AMG SL 63 4Matic+ touchscreen" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256477" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG SL 63 4Matic+ 11.9-inch touchscreen display can be tilted back and forth. <strong>Image credit</strong>: Mercedes</p></div></p>
<p>Inside, Mercedes has also outfitted the SL with the latest version of its MBUX infotainment system complete with the Zero Layer option. As an extra bonus, because of potential sun glare, the 11.9-inch touchscreen display can be tilted back and forth from 12 to 32 degrees. The reflections of the sun are also why the 12.3-inch instrument cluster has an integrated visor. Sadly neither was needed during my overcast and foggy drive.</p>
<p>With the SL Roadster, Mercedes has built a proper convertible sports car that&#8217;s filled with its latest technology. Neither sides of the vehicle, performance, and tech, contradict the other. It&#8217;s a symbiotic relationship. Essentially, it&#8217;s the James Bond of cars. A nod to the past with a wild side that&#8217;s already ready with the latest gizmo to complete the mission while dressed in a tuxedo.</p>
<p>After driving the AMG EQS and SL vehicles back to back over two days, it&#8217;s interesting to see the beginning of the transition of AMG vehicles. The performance arm of Mercedes, like the automaker itself, is poised to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/mercedes-benz-to-build-eight-battery-factories-in-push-to-become-electric-only-automaker-by-2030/">go fully electric by 2030</a>.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s most striking is thinking about the future, I&#8217;ve driven the first generation SL 300 Roadster. At the time of its launch, it was like something from outer space. At some point in the near future, the automaker might introduce another AMG SL and if Mercedes continues to refine its EV technologies at the pace it&#8217;s doing so right now, it&#8217;ll likely be just as groundbreaking and electric.</p>
<p>Also, it&#8217;ll have no problem driving in snow even with the top down.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/first-drive-2022-mercedes-amg-eqs-and-2022-mercedes-amg-sl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256366</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
