<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 21:33:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Nigeria lifts ban on Twitter, says the social media giant has met some conditions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/nigeria-lifts-ban-on-twitter-says-the-social-media-giant-has-met-some-conditions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/nigeria-lifts-ban-on-twitter-says-the-social-media-giant-has-met-some-conditions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 21:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2257021</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Nigerian government has lifted the suspension of Twitter operations, more than months after it first declared a crackdown on the social media giant in the country. The news was made known via local press today. Kashifu Inuwa Abdullahi, the director-general of Nigeria&#8217;s tech agency, National Information Technology Development Agency (NITDA) made the announcement via [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Nigerian government has lifted the suspension of Twitter operations, more than months after it first declared a crackdown on the social media giant in the country. The news was made known via local press today.</p>
<p>Kashifu Inuwa Abdullahi, the director-general of Nigeria&#8217;s tech agency, National Information Technology Development Agency (NITDA) made the announcement via a statement. He was put in charge, as chairman, of the committee &#8212; Technical Committee Nigeria-Twitter Engagement &#8212; set up by the Nigerian government to oversee talks between the West African nation and Twitter after the ban.</p>
<p>In the statement, the chairman said that the approval was given following a memo written by the country&#8217;s minister of communications and digital economy to the president, Muhammadu Buhari. The statement also revealed that the ban will be lifted effective immediately by midnight, January 13, 2022.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2257021" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“The Federal Government of Nigeria (FGN) directs me to inform the public that President Muhammadu Buhari, GCFR, has approved the lifting of the suspension of Twitter operation in Nigeria effective from 12am tonight, 13th January 2022,&#8221; the statement read. “The approval was given following a memo written to the President by the Honourable Minister of Communications and Digital Economy, Prof Isa Ali Ibrahim. In the Memo, the Minister updated and requested the President’s approval for the lifting based on the Technical Committee Nigeria-Twitter Engagement’s recommendation.”</p>
<p>Abdullahi also noted in the statement that Twitter has agreed to set “a legal entity in Nigeria during the first quarter of 2022.” It was one of the three requests, out of ten, Nigeria said Twitter had failed to meet in order to reinstate the company’s operations in the country. Nigeria&#8217;s information minister Lai Mohammed made this announcement in August last year.</p>
<p>The other requests in addition to setting up a local office were paying taxes locally and cooperating with the Nigerian government to regulate content and harmful tweets. Nigeria&#8217;s government said the social media platform only reached an agreement on seven requests.</p>
<p>TechCrunch reached out to Twitter for comment but has not received any as of press time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><em>More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/nigeria-lifts-ban-on-twitter-says-the-social-media-giant-has-met-some-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2257021</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact checkers write open letter urging YouTube to get serious about Covid misinformation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/youtube-covid-misinformation-fact-checkers-letter/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/youtube-covid-misinformation-fact-checkers-letter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 21:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deception]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fact checking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frances Haugen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online disinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politifact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transcription services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A group of more than 80 prominent fact checking organizations around the world is pressing YouTube to take action against Covid misinformation, which still prevails on the platform now two years into the pandemic. &#8220;As an international network of fact-checking organizations, we monitor how lies spread online — and every day, we see that YouTube [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A group of more than 80 prominent fact checking organizations around the world is pressing YouTube to take action against Covid misinformation, which still prevails on the platform now two years into the pandemic.</p>
<p>&#8220;As an international network of fact-checking organizations, we monitor how lies spread online — and every day, we see that YouTube is one of the major conduits of online disinformation and misinformation worldwide,&#8221; the coalition of fact checkers wrote in an <a href="https://www.poynter.org/fact-checking/2022/an-open-letter-to-youtubes-ceo-from-the-worlds-fact-checkers/">open letter published on Poynter</a>. &#8220;This is a significant concern among our global fact-checking community.&#8221;</p>
<p>The collection of fact checking organizations that signed the letter spans the globe, including U.S.-based groups like Politifact, the Washington Post Fact-checker and Poynter&#8217;s MediaWise alongside Africa&#8217;s Dubawa and Africa Check, India&#8217;s Fact Crescendo and Factly and many more organizations from countries including Indonesia, Israel and Turkey.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256964" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The group notes that health-related misinformation has long found fertile ground on the video-sharing site, including content encouraging cancer patients to fight their conditions with unscientific treatments.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the last year, we have seen conspiracy groups thriving and collaborating across borders, including an international movement that started in Germany, jumped to Spain and spread through Latin America, all on YouTube,&#8221; the letter states. &#8220;Meanwhile, millions of other users were watching videos in Greek and Arabic that encouraged them to boycott vaccinations or treat their COVID-19 infections with bogus cures.&#8221;</p>
<p>The letter also highlights the particular dangers of misinformation spreading in non-English language videos. Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen called attention to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/">parallel concerns on that platform</a>, which also does not invest evenly in content moderation outside of English-speaking countries. The fact checking group encourages YouTube to &#8220;provide country- and language-specific data, as well as transcription services that work in any language&#8221; to push back against the flow of misinformation in languages beyond English, which the company focuses its moderation methods on.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uCzxpLrfqi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/senate-judiciary-tech-hearing-algorithms-twitter-youtube-facebook/">The next tech hearing targets social media algorithms — and YouTube, for once</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The next tech hearing targets social media algorithms — and YouTube, for once&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/senate-judiciary-tech-hearing-algorithms-twitter-youtube-facebook/embed/#?secret=uCzxpLrfqi" data-secret="uCzxpLrfqi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The fact checkers don&#8217;t just present problems — they posed solutions as well, pointing out that the company should create far more transparency around its misinformation and disinformation policies and support independent researchers who specialize in those issues. The group also urges YouTube to step up its efforts to debunk misinformation and provide immediate context on-platform, two tactics that could be accomplished by deepening its work with fact checking organizations.</p>
<p>While Facebook and Twitter have long faced intense public scrutiny for the spread of misinformation on their platforms, YouTube often manages to fly under the radar. Its recommendation algorithm has played an active role in promoting dangerous claims in recent years, but because like TikTok the platform is video and not text-based it&#8217;s generally more difficult for researchers to study and lawmakers holding tech accountability hearings to wrap their heads around.</p>
<p>&#8220;YouTube is allowing its platform to be weaponized by unscrupulous actors to manipulate and exploit others, and to organize and fundraise themselves,&#8221; the group wrote. &#8220;Current measures are proving insufficient.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ulaVojkdqY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/google-youtube-climate-change-denial-ban/">Google and YouTube say they won&#8217;t allow ads or monetized content pushing climate denial</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google and YouTube say they won&#8217;t allow ads or monetized content pushing climate denial&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/google-youtube-climate-change-denial-ban/embed/#?secret=ulaVojkdqY" data-secret="ulaVojkdqY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Zn38NQDBOm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/youtube-will-now-ban-content-with-vaccine-misinformation/">YouTube will now ban content with vaccine misinformation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;YouTube will now ban content with vaccine misinformation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/youtube-will-now-ban-content-with-vaccine-misinformation/embed/#?secret=Zn38NQDBOm" data-secret="Zn38NQDBOm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/youtube-covid-misinformation-fact-checkers-letter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The metaverse will be filled with &#8216;elves&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/the-metaverse-will-be-filled-with-elves/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/the-metaverse-will-be-filled-with-elves/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 21:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avatar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The most dangerous part of the metaverse will be agenda-driven artificial agents that look and act like other users but are actually simulated personas controlled by AI.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Louis Rosenberg</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/louisbrosenberg">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/louis-rosenberg-025851132/">Louis Rosenberg</a> is a pioneer of virtual and augmented reality and CEO of <a href="https://unanimous.ai/staff-item/louis-rosenberg-phd/">Unanimous AI</a>. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Some say the metaverse is nothing but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/the-irrational-exuberance-of-web3/">marketing hype</a>, while others insist it will transform society. I fall into the latter camp, but I’m not talking about cartoon worlds filled with avatars like many are pitching.</p>
<p>Instead, I believe the <em>true metaverse</em> – the one that will change society &#8212; will be an <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/12/28/future-augmented-reality-will-inherit-the-earth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">augmentation layer on the real world,</a> and within 10 years it will be the foundation of our lives, impacting everything from shopping and socializing to business and education.</p>
<p>I also believe that a corporate-controlled metaverse is dangerous to society and requires aggressive regulation. That’s because the platform providers will be able to <a href="https://bigthink.com/the-future/metaverse-augmented-reality-danger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">manipulate consumers</a> in ways that will make social media seem quaint. Most people resonate with concerns around data collection and privacy, but they overlook what will be the most dangerous technology in the metaverse – artificial intelligence.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256343" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The most dangerous part of the metaverse: agenda-driven artificial agents that look and act like other users but are actually simulated personas controlled by AI.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</span></p>
<p>In fact, if you ask people to name the core technologies of the metaverse, they’ll usually focus on the eyewear and maybe mention the graphics engines, 5G or even blockchain. But those are just the nuts and bolts of our immersive future – the technology that will pull the strings in the metaverse, creating (and manipulating) our experience, is AI.</p>
<p>Artificial intelligence will be just as important to our virtual future as the headsets that get all the attention. And the most dangerous part of the metaverse will be agenda-driven artificial agents that look and act like other users but are actually simulated personas controlled by AI. They will engage us in “conversational manipulation,” targeting us on behalf of paying advertisers without us realizing they aren’t real.</p>
<p>This is especially dangerous when the AI algorithms have access to data about our personal interests and beliefs, habits and temperament, all while monitoring our emotional state by reading our facial expressions and vocal inflections.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If you think targeted ads in social media are manipulative, it’s nothing compared to the conversational agents that will engage us in the metaverse. They will pitch us more skillfully than any human salesperson, and it won’t just be to sell us gadgets – they will push political propaganda and targeted misinformation on behalf of the highest bidder.</p>
<p>And because these AI agents will look and sound like anyone else in the metaverse, our natural skepticism to advertising will not protect us. For these reasons, <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/12/04/the-metaverse-needs-aggressive-regulation/">we need to regulate</a> AI-driven conversational agents, especially when they have access to our facial and vocal affects, enabling our emotions to be used against us in real time.</p>
<p>If we don’t regulate this, ads in the form of AI-driven avatars will sense when you’re skeptical and change tactics in mid-sentence, quickly zeroing in on the words and images that impact <em>you</em> personally. As I <a href="https://futurism.com/artificial-intelligence-isnt-intelligence-manipulating-humanity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote in 2016</a>, if an AI can learn to beat the world’s best chess and Go players, learning to sway consumers to buy things (and believe things) that aren’t in our interest is child’s play.</p>
<p>But of all the technologies headed our way, it’s what I call the “elf” that will be the most powerful and subtle form of coercion in the metaverse. These “electronic life facilitators” are the natural evolution of digital assistants like Siri and Alexa, but they won’t be disembodied voices in the metaverse. They’ll be anthropomorphized personas customized for each consumer.</p>
<p>The platform providers will market these AI agents as virtual life coaches and they will be persistent throughout your day as you navigate the metaverse. And because the metaverse will ultimately be an augmentation layer upon the real world, these digital elves will be with you everywhere, whether you are shopping or working or just hanging out.</p>
<p>And just like the marketing agents described above, these elves will have access to your facial expressions and vocal inflections along with a detailed data history of your life, nudging you toward actions and activities, products and services, even political views.</p>
<p>And no, they won’t be like the crude chatbots of today, but embodied characters you’ll come to think of as trusted figures in your life – a mix between a familiar friend, helpful adviser and caring therapist. And yet, your elf will know you in ways no friend ever could, for it will be monitoring all aspects of your life down to your blood pressure and respiration rate (via your trusty smartwatch).</p>
<p>Yes, this sounds creepy, which is why platform providers will make them cute and non-threatening, with innocent features and mannerisms that seem more like a magical character in your own “life adventure” than a human-sized assistant following you around. This is why I use the word “elf” to describe them, as they might appear to you as a fairy hovering over your shoulder or maybe a gremlin or alien – a small anthropomorphic character that can whisper in your ear or fly out in front of you to draw attention to things in your augmented world it wants you to focus on.</p>
<p>This is where it gets especially dangerous &#8212; without regulation, these life facilitators will be hijacked by paying advertisers, targeting you with greater skill and precision than anything on today’s social media. And unlike ads of today, these intelligent agents will be following you around, guiding you through your day, and doing it with a cute smile or giggly laugh.</p>
<p>To help convey what this will be like, both positive and negative, I’ve written a short narrative, <a href="https://medium.com/predict/metaverse-2030-ee59e4d4010d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Metaverse 2030</a>, that portrays how AI will drive our immersive lives by 2030 and beyond.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the technologies of VR, AR and AI have the potential to enrich and improve our lives. But when combined, these innovations become especially dangerous, as they all have one powerful trait in common – they can make us believe that computer-generated content is authentic, even if it’s an agenda-driven fabrication. It’s this powerful ability for digital deception that should make us fear an AI-enabled metaverse, especially when controlled by powerful corporations that sell third-party access to its users for promotional purposes.</p>
<p>I raise these concerns in the hope that consumers and industry leaders will push for <a href="https://bigthink.com/the-future/metaverse-dystopia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">meaningful regulation</a> before the problems become so ingrained in the technology of the metaverse that they’re impossible to undo.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/the-metaverse-will-be-filled-with-elves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256343</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FCC proposes stricter requirements for reporting data breaches</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/fcc-proposes-stricter-requirements-for-reporting-data-breaches/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/fcc-proposes-stricter-requirements-for-reporting-data-breaches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 21:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carriers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2257024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Federal Communications Commission is the next US regulator hoping to hold companies more accountable for data breaches.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jon Fingas</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jon Fingas is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/24/tesla-will-disable-in-dash-video-games-while-its-cars-are-in-motion/">Tesla will disable in-dash video games while its cars are in motion</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/23/mercks-covid-19-antiviral-pill-is-the-second-authorized-by-the-fda/">Merck&#8217;s COVID-19 antiviral pill is the second authorized by the FDA</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The Federal Communications Commission is the next US regulator hoping to hold companies <a href="https://www.engadget.com/ftc-rules-that-health-apps-must-notify-consumers-if-their-data-is-breached-114043312.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">more accountable for data breaches</a>. Chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel has <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/chair-rosenworcel-circulates-new-data-breach-reporting-requirements" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">shared</a> a rulemaking proposal that would introduce stricter requirements for data breach reporting. Most notably, the new rules would require notifications for customers affected by &#8220;inadvertent&#8221; breaches — companies that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/microsoft-power-apps-data-exposed-report-covid-19-api-configuration-165453736.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">leave data exposed</a> would have to be just as communicative as victims of cyberattacks.</p>
<p>The requirements would also scrap a mandatory one-week waiting period for notifying customers. Carriers, meanwhile, would have to disclose reportable breaches to the FCC in addition to the FBI and Secret Service.</p>
<p>Rosenworcel argued the tougher rules were necessary to account for the &#8220;evolving nature&#8221; of breaches and the risks they posed to victims. People ought to be protected against larger and more frequent incidents, the FCC chair said — that is, regulations need to catch up with reality.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2257024" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The FCC didn&#8217;t say when the proposal might come up for a vote, although the FCC&#8217;s next open meeting is slated for January 27th. There&#8217;s no guarantee the Commission will greenlight the new requirements. It won&#8217;t be surprising if the rulemaking moves forward, however. While companies are now more likely to disclose breaches, there have been multiple high-profile incidents where those firms took too long to alert customers or <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-27-ny-attorney-general-sues-dunkin-cyberattacks.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">didn&#8217;t notify them at all</a>. The new measures could cut that wait time, giving people a better chance of securing their data and preventing fraud.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on<a href="https://www.engadget.com/fcc-data-breach-reporting-requirements-204349123.html"> Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/fcc-proposes-stricter-requirements-for-reporting-data-breaches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2257024</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unicorn exits augur poorly as Justworks delays IPO, citing &#8216;market conditions&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/unicorn-exits-augur-poorly-as-justworks-delays-ipo-citing-market-conditions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/unicorn-exits-augur-poorly-as-justworks-delays-ipo-citing-market-conditions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 20:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Justworks' IPO delay indicates that the enthusiasm gap between private markets and their public analog is wide.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Justworks, a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/20/justworks-files-to-take-its-smb-focused-hr-themed-saas-business-public/">venture-backed software startup focused on the HR market</a> for small and medium-sized businesses, announced earlier today that it would delay its IPO. In a statement to TechCrunch, Justworks said that it &#8220;decided to delay its IPO due to market conditions at this time.&#8221;</p>
<p>An IPO delay is just that, a public debut pushed back. But Justworks&#8217; decision to put its public offering on temporary hiatus comes on the heels of rapid declines in the value of recent technology debuts employing traditional IPOs, SPACs and direct listings. Even more, Justworks&#8217; now-delayed IPO follows a selloff in the value of software and technology shares more generally.</p>
<p>Is there something bigger afoot than one company&#8217;s stumble?</p>
<h2>Reading the tea leaves</h2>
<p>The Justworks IPO delay is the latest data point in what could be a worsening exit market for unicorns. Otherwise, we wouldn&#8217;t make a fuss.</p>
<p>Why? Sometimes when a private company wants to go public, it finds that public-market investors are not willing to buy its shares at the price it had in mind. By taking more time, the IPO hopeful can tidy up its numbers, perhaps answering some of its critics head-on with results or business tweaks. Once the company has tuned its performance and image, it can try to float once again.</p>
<p>Such a private-public disconnect can stem from a gap between a company&#8217;s results, what it thinks they are worth, and the public market&#8217;s view of the particular firm in question. Alternatively, a similar disconnect can arise from the public markets simply being on a different page regarding valuations than the private markets. Our read of the Justworks news is that it&#8217;s likely dealing with at least the latter issue, and perhaps the former as well.</p>
<p>The possibility of a gap between how private investors value growth-focused tech companies and how the stock market values those companies matters because of how many richly valued tech startups need to find an exit in the coming year. In bad news for those companies, a number of factors likely made Justworks&#8217; IPO timing difficult, hinting that other unicorns could also struggle to exit in today&#8217;s investing climate.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/unicorn-exits-augur-poorly-as-justworks-delays-ipo-citing-market-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256966</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dorm Room Fund returns to campus with new $10.4 million fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/dorm-room-fund-returns-to-campus-with-new-10-4-million-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/dorm-room-fund-returns-to-campus-with-new-10-4-million-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 20:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dorm Room Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emerging fund managers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dorm Room Fund, a venture capital operation that launched to invest in student-led startups, has raised a new $10.4 million fund, per SEC filings. The filing marks Dorm Room Fund’s largest fund to date, and its first that appears to include investors beyond First Round Capital, the firm that first launched the student-focused operation in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.dormroomfund.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dorm Room Fund</a>, a venture capital operation that launched to invest in student-led startups, has raised a new $10.4 million fund, <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1899115/000090571822000094/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">per SEC filings.</a> The filing marks Dorm Room Fund’s largest fund to date, and its first that appears to include investors beyond First Round Capital, the firm that first launched the student-focused operation in 2012. The SEC filing indicates that the fundraise is still ongoing. Both firms declined to comment.</p>
<p>Dorm Room Fund’s original vision was tied to First Round Capital’s bet that early-stage investing could be led by students, for students. In 2012, First Round Capital thus allocated a portion of its assets under management &#8212; a  $3 million capital pool &#8212; to be managed by a group of students. Today, Dorm Room Fund continues to still only invest in companies where at least one person on the founding team is a student or recent graduate.</p>
<p>Dorm Room Fund has made 326 investments to date, in startups such as Brooklinen and Snackpass &#8212; as well as venture firm Harlem Capital Partners. On its website, the operation says it writes $40,000 SAFE notes into the startups it backs &#8212; and has teams in New York City, San Francisco, Boston and Philadelphia.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256996" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>While the operation&#8217;s focus is largely in the United States, we have some signals its checkwriting focus may be broadening: Dorm Room Fund’s latest investment, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/dorm-room-fund/recent_investments" target="_blank" rel="noopener">per Crunchbase</a>, was in a pre-seed round for Alima, a Mexico City-based company that wants to make product procurement easier for businesses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0qj8Eca1iB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/18/more-than-another-check-founders-need-activation-energy/">More than another check, founders need activation energy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;More than another check, founders need activation energy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/18/more-than-another-check-founders-need-activation-energy/embed/#?secret=0qj8Eca1iB" data-secret="0qj8Eca1iB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For Dorm Room Fund, which had been noticeably quieter in its investment activity over the past few years, fresh capital could give a boost to its student-focused operations. As the larger investing world gets more competitive, investors are incentivized to find talent sooner and sooner &#8212; either through in-house accelerators, non-dilutive programming or, in this case, a carved out microfund explicitly for aspiring entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>The strategy may feel especially relevant today, but there is precedent. Similar to Dorm Room Fund, General Catalyst launched Rough Draft Ventures as a play to get more access to student networks. Contrary Capital, another student-focused venture capital firm, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/contrary-capitals-20m-fund-ii-is-all-about-community-first-investments/">recently announced a $20 million fund</a> &#8212; its second investment vehicle to date. In 2019, First Round made another move in favor of early talent: it supported the Graduate Fund, a pre-seed fund that targets recent graduates of undergraduate or master’s programs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/16/new-pre-seed-fund-powered-by-first-round-capital-will-target-recent-graduates/">but that operates independently. </a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Dorm Room Fund appears to have been gearing up for a refresh of sorts. In 2018, the team launched a CRM for founders raising a seed round, but a year later the firm’s CEO Rei Wang left their post to launch The Grand, a learning and development platform to help people navigate change. That same year, <a href="https://dormroomfund.medium.com/announcing-the-new-ceo-and-coo-of-dorm-room-fund-460e66eb6351" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the team hired Molly Fowler,</a> who previously worked in politics and urban planning, to be the new chief executive. It also brought on Chauncey Hamilton as its inaugural COO, who was previously the chief of staff to First Round partner Rob Hayes. With new leadership, Dorm Room Fund has seemed to convince a cadre of LPs that its longtime focus deserves fresh capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FzITpzAOfb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/08/startup-accelerators-definition-of-value-add-is-due-for-a-refresh/">Startup accelerators’ definition of &#8216;value add’ is due for a refresh</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startup accelerators’ definition of &#8216;value add’ is due for a refresh&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/08/startup-accelerators-definition-of-value-add-is-due-for-a-refresh/embed/#?secret=FzITpzAOfb" data-secret="FzITpzAOfb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/dorm-room-fund-returns-to-campus-with-new-10-4-million-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256996</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Magic Leap grants healthcare startups access to its new AR headset ahead of mid-2022 release</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/magic-leap-grants-healthcare-startups-access-to-its-new-ar-headset-ahead-of-mid-2022-release/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/magic-leap-grants-healthcare-startups-access-to-its-new-ar-headset-ahead-of-mid-2022-release/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 19:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magic Leap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ahead of a planned enterprise release later this year, Magic Leap has provided a group of healthcare companies with early access to its second-generation augmented reality headset.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Igor Bonifacic</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Igor Bonifacic is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/chinas-change-5-probe-finds-on-site-evidence-of-water-on-the-moons-surface/">China&#8217;s Chang&#8217;e-5 probe finds on-site evidence of water on the Moon&#8217;s surface</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/the-entry-level-2022-polestar-2-will-have-an-epa-estimated-range-of-270-miles/">The entry-level 2022 Polestar 2 will have an EPA-estimated range of 270 miles</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Ahead of a planned enterprise release later this year, Magic Leap has provided a group of healthcare companies with <a href="https://www.magicleap.com/en-us/news/news/magic-leap-announces-health-technology-early-access-program-participants-for-magic-leap-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">early access</a> to its second-generation augmented reality headset. One of the companies, <a href="https://sentiar.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1"><ins>SentiAR</ins></a>, offers software that allows doctors to see a 3D model of a patient’s heart while they’re operating them. Another company, Brainlab, wants to make its Mixed Reality Viewer software available on Magic Leap 2.</p>
<p>That Magic Leap is making its latest wearable available to digital healthcare startups first isn’t surprising; CEO Peggy Johnson said as much would happen <a href="https://www.engadget.com/magic-leap-2-release-date-peggy-johnson-interview-160326037.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1"><ins>last April</ins></a>. &#8220;Augmented reality may transform healthcare more than any other industry, at least in the near term,&#8221; she said at the time, noting also that the company would focus on enterprise customers at launch.</p>
<p>Magic Leap has famously struggled since its emergence as one of Silicon Valley’s most hyped startups. In 2019, it came out that the company had reportedly only sold <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-12-06-magic-leap-6000-headsets-sold-report.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><ins>6,000</ins></a> units of its $2,300 <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-01-magic-leap-hands-on-one-creator-edition-mixed-reality.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><ins>Magic Leap One Creator Edition</ins></a>headset through the first six months that the device was available. It subsequently spent months laying off employees before a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/magic-leap-raises-350-million-puts-layoffs-on-hold-034824726.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1"><ins>$350 million investment</ins></a> gave it a new shot of life.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256973" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/magic-leap-2-early-access-program-192759568.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/magic-leap-grants-healthcare-startups-access-to-its-new-ar-headset-ahead-of-mid-2022-release/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256973</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple releases iOS 15.2.1 to patch iPhones and iPads against HomeKit flaw</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/apple-ios-ipad-homekit-flaw/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/apple-ios-ipad-homekit-flaw/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 19:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HomeKit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS 15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portable Media Players]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Touchscreens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has fixed a security vulnerability in iOS and iPadOS that could be exploited via HomeKit to launch persistent denial of service (DoS) attacks. The technology giant released iOS 15.2.1 and iPadOS 15.2.1 on Wednesday to patch the so-called &#8220;doorLock&#8221; flaw, which was disclosed earlier this month by security researcher Trevor Spiniolas. The bug affects iPhones [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple/?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAMwMwcRkMyaATka8BRCt76S9VdoYfJ2YpVe_Z5mS2iWLyCMVnJ0GH2VoV88NhEHXb9uunkyeLxpMtQWSUFgBKO5dw6R9uW-z7TOscctAmyzT7hQ_4hzSb6s3Emuo_ckgtySx8gfyDoJOkdxRubNNPK8RVmjlx8OJXbTqalkn1pPE">Apple</a> has fixed a security vulnerability in iOS and iPadOS that could be exploited via HomeKit to launch persistent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ddos/">denial of service</a> (DoS) attacks.</p>
<p>The technology giant<a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT213043"> released iOS 15.2.1 and iPadOS 15.2.1</a> on Wednesday to patch the so-called &#8220;doorLock&#8221; flaw, which was disclosed earlier this month by <a href="https://trevorspiniolas.com/doorlock/doorlock.html">security researcher Trevor Spiniolas</a>. The bug affects iPhones and iPads running iOS 14.7 through iOS 15.2 and is triggered via HomeKit, Apple&#8217;s smart home platform that lets Apple users configure, communicate with, and control their smart home devices</p>
<p>To exploit the bug, an attacker would need to change the name of a HomeKit device to a string larger than 500,000 characters. When that string loads on a user&#8217;s iPhone or iPad, the device&#8217;s software would be thrown into a denial of service (DoS) state, requiring a forced-reset to unfreeze. But once the device reboots and the user signs back into the iCloud account linked to HomeKit, the bug is triggered again.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256928" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Even if a user doesn’t have any devices added on HomeKit, an attacker could create a spoof Home network and trick a user into joining via a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/phishing/">phishing</a> email. Worse, Spiniolas warned that attackers could leverage the doorLock vulnerability to launch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ransomware/">ransomware</a> attacks against iOS users, locking devices into an unusable state and demanding a ransom payment to set the HomeKit device back to a safe string length.</p>
<p>Spiniolas said that Apple pledged to fix the issue in a security update last year, but this was pushed back until &#8220;early 2022,&#8221; prompting Spiniolas to disclose the bug fearing the delay poses a &#8220;serious risk&#8221; to users.</p>
<p>&#8220;Despite them confirming the security issue and me urging them many times over the past four months to take the matter seriously, little was done,&#8221; he wrote. &#8220;Status updates on the matter were rare and featured exceptionally few details, even though I asked for them frequently.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Apple’s lack of transparency is not only frustrating to security researchers who often work for free, it poses a risk to the millions of people who use Apple products in their day-to-day lives by reducing Apple’s accountability on security matters.&#8221;</p>
<p>The update can be downloaded now and is available for the iPhone 6s and later, all iPad Pro models, iPad Air 2 and later, iPad 5th generation and later, iPad mini 4 and later, and iPod touch (7th generation).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/apple-ios-ipad-homekit-flaw/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256928</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HomeValet launches its $499 Smart Box to keep your grocery deliveries cold and packages secure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/homevalet-launches-its-499-smart-box-to-keep-your-grocery-deliveries-cold-and-packages-secure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/homevalet-launches-its-499-smart-box-to-keep-your-grocery-deliveries-cold-and-packages-secure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 18:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distribution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inhome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HomeValet, a D.C. Metro area-based startup that has developed a temperature-controlled smart box for grocery deliveries, is now releasing its smart home product to the public and expanding its partnership with Walmart. The company had previously piloted its Smart Box with Walmart in 2021 as a way for grocery delivery customers to keep their fresh [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.homevalet.co">HomeValet</a>, a D.C. Metro area-based startup that has developed a temperature-controlled <a href="https://www.homevalet.co/smart-box/">smart box</a> for grocery deliveries, is now releasing its smart home product to the public and expanding its partnership with Walmart. The company had previously piloted its Smart Box with Walmart in 2021 as a way for grocery delivery customers to keep their fresh and frozen items cold while also ensuring their deliveries remained secure until they could retrieve them.</p>
<p>Now, the Smart Box will now be offered to Walmart&#8217;s InHome grocery delivery subscribers in select markets starting this month, the company says. It will also be offered to general consumers who can <a href="https://www.homevalet.co/preorder/">pre-order</a> the box with a down payment of $50. The full product costs $499 for InHome subscribers &#8212; so it&#8217;s a bit of an investment. (Financing is available through Affirm.)</p>
<p>However, the box could make sense for people who want the convenience of placing grocery orders online but aren&#8217;t able to be at home when those items are delivered.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256829" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2256929" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256929" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256929" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_Comp_03_BaseModelT-copy.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256929" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> HomeValet</p></div></p>
<p>This is one of the major roadblocks to grocery delivery adoption among consumers. Because fresh and frozen items need to be put away fairly soon after delivery, many people opt to order groceries via curbside pickup or just shop the stores as usual. The issue also complicates the logistics of grocery delivery, as shoppers want their groceries delivered at certain times of day when they can be home &#8212; like after work or on weekends. This leads to ebbs and flows of delivery requests throughout the days and weeks, instead of allowing the retailer itself to determine the best time to route and deliver certain orders.</p>
<p>Walmart&#8217;s solution to this problem, so far, has been its InHome delivery service. This grocery subscription service, which the retailer said last week<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/04/walmart-to-expand-inhome-grocery-delivery-to-30-million-u-s-households-in-2022/"> would be available to 30 million households by year-end,</a> allows Walmart employees to enter the home through a smart lock system and put groceries away in the fridge and freezer on the customer&#8217;s behalf. These deliveries are recorded via vest-worn cameras for security purposes.</p>
<p>But not all customers will be comfortable with having unknown people enter their homes. (Or they can&#8217;t allow this for some other reason &#8212; like having a big dog who doesn&#8217;t like visitors, perhaps!)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This is where the HomeValet Smart Box system could come in. Instead of having the Walmart delivery staff enter their home, the delivery driver would be able to access the smart box and place the groceries inside.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256932" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256932" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256932" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="486" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg 5000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?resize=768,549 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?resize=680,486 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?resize=1536,1097 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?resize=2048,1463 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Smart-Box_TopDown_02-3-Zone-Pantry-Fridge-Freezee.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256932" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> HomeValet</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The HomeValet system itself is an internet-connected box with an uncooled side for pantry and other non-grocery items as well as a temperature-controlled cooler side with sections for both fresh and frozen items. (The sections are configurable by the end user, too.)</p>
<p>The Smart Box also ships with a companion mobile app that alerts you to deliveries and records video of the courier placing your order inside the box via its included Sony IMX322 camera, which records in 1080p.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256923" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256923" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256923" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/App_holding-phone-mock.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="507" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/App_holding-phone-mock.jpeg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/App_holding-phone-mock.jpeg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/App_holding-phone-mock.jpeg?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/App_holding-phone-mock.jpeg?resize=768,572 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/App_holding-phone-mock.jpeg?resize=680,507 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/App_holding-phone-mock.jpeg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256923" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> HomeValet</p></div></p>
<p>From the app, customers are able to lock and unlock the box, as needed, and adjust the temperature remotely. The box can also automatically unlock for deliveries before they arrive if integrated with a supported retailer&#8217;s system, like Walmart&#8217;s InHome. (The app requires a paid subscription).</p>
<p>The Smart Box is powered by a standard 110-volt outlet and can be anchored to the ground if desired. The box is a sizable 120 pounds and sports dimensions of 50.86&#8243; x 25.37&#8243; x 26.56&#8243;. (An earlier version had a UV light for sanitization but the current system&#8217;s specs doesn&#8217;t mention this feature.)</p>
<p>HomeValet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/walmart-partners-with-smart-box-maker-homevalet-for-grocery-delivery-pilot/">piloted its Smart Box system with Walmart</a> customers in May 2021 in Northwest Arkansas and ran additional tests in parts of Indiana, Minnesota, and in the D.C. Metro area. The company is now making the system available to InHome shoppers first.</p>
<p>Walmart InHome customers serviced by stores in Florida &#8212; a smart place to start, given the climate &#8212; will be getting the first shipments of the box in Feb. 2022. InHome customers can purchase the box at the launch price of $499 plus a $10/mo subscription service, with 6 months free included.</p>
<p>The box will then ship to other pre-order customers in August 2022 in limited quantities, followed by expanded shipments in Nov. 2022. These customers will pay a different MSRP to be released at a later date.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/homevalet-launches-its-499-smart-box-to-keep-your-grocery-deliveries-cold-and-packages-secure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Omnichannel customer messaging platform Superchat raises $15.6M round led by Blossom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/omnichannel-customer-messaging-platform-superchat-raises-15-6m-round-led-by-blossom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/omnichannel-customer-messaging-platform-superchat-raises-15-6m-round-led-by-blossom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 18:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Lim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While last year’s WhatsApp outage is still sending shivers down the spine of its 2 billion users, the same is also true for the millions of businesses now using it to connect with their customers. As we now know, messaging across all platforms is a new area from which many startups are emerging. One of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While last year’s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/04/facebook-instagram-and-whatsapp-hit-by-outage" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WhatsApp outage</a> is still sending shivers down the spine of its 2 billion users, the same is also true for the millions of businesses now using it to connect with their customers. As we now know, messaging across all platforms is a new area from which many startups are emerging.</p>
<p>One of the most recent is <a href="https://en.superchat.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Superchat</a>, which is building an all-in-one messaging platform for small and medium-sized businesses to contact their customers. And these things are needed: According to some <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/RightNow/2011-customer-experience-impact-report/6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">surveys</a> 78% of customers giving up on a transaction because of a negative experience. And European companies <a href="https://www.majorel.com/future-customer/expert-view/why-bad-customer-service-is-expensive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lose</a> €13 billion in revenues a year over bad customer service.</p>
<p>Superchat has now raised $15.6 million in a Series A round led by London-based VC <a href="https://www.blossomcap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blossom Capital</a>, with participation from <a href="https://www.468cap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">468 Capital</a>. That means the startup has now raised a total of $18.8 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256903" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Alex Lim, managing partner at Blossom Capital, said: “Superchat has built a platform that empowers small and medium-sized businesses to leverage the benefits of digital channels and provide the very best service to even the most discerning customers. The founders and the team understand the unique pain points being felt by companies, many of which are still relying on email and phone calls despite the significant shift to digital seen in the wake of the pandemic.”</p>
<p>The startup says it pulls in conversations from WhatsApp, Facebook, Instagram, Google Business, Telegram, webchat, email, and SMS – into a single inbox for the business. By doing this companies get data insights into their customers, helping them boost sales etc. All team members can see and reply to messages.</p>
<p>Founded by Yilmaz Köknar and Mika Hally, the platform has largely worked for customers in Germany to date.</p>
<p>Köknar said: “Today’s customers want and expect to be able to contact businesses wherever, and whenever suits them… this can prove to be a logistical nightmare for the companies, and results in poor experiences for the customers. No one wins within the current status quo, but with Superchat, everyone does.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Superchat is up against a number of well-funded players in this sphere including Rake, Messagebird, Smooch and others, so it will be interesting to see how it fairs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/omnichannel-customer-messaging-platform-superchat-raises-15-6m-round-led-by-blossom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256903</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wordle is tech born of love that asks nothing in return</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/josh-wardle-interview-wordle/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/josh-wardle-interview-wordle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 17:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andy baio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloudflare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guardian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Wardle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kevin o'connor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kickstarter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSCHF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Years Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wordle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The internet loves an unlikely success story, and as we approached the new year, one came around the corner to delight us with a simple idea, and a short game to play it out: Wordle, where you guess a five-letter word in six tries, and then laugh and cry with others as you share your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The internet loves an unlikely success story, and as we approached the new year, one came around the corner to delight us with a simple idea, and a short game to play it out: <a href="https://www.powerlanguage.co.uk/wordle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wordle</a>, where you guess a five-letter word in six tries, and then laugh and cry with others as you share your results and the grid charting your attempts.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a breath of fresh air in the tech industry, as we discussed with the game&#8217;s creator, Josh Wardle: no mobile app. Only one word every 24 hours. No advertising. No registration required. And you can even play it if your internet connection drops.</p>
<p>But perhaps, even more delighting than the game itself, is the origin story.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256733" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The short version is that British-raised New York resident Josh Wardle, who used to work at Reddit and is now a software engineer at Brooklyn art collective <a href="https://mschf.xyz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mschf</a>, originally built Wordle last year <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/01/03/technology/wordle-word-game-creator.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for his partner</a>, a word puzzle enthusiast, for them to play together.</p>
<p>Hosting it on a website he&#8217;s had for years as a home for his other creative efforts (<a href="http://powerlanguage.co.ul" target="_blank" rel="noopener">powerlanguage.co.uk</a>, back from his time in England), Wardle casually shared the game with family. Then he showed it to a few well-placed friends. But virality, as we know, doesn&#8217;t take much to get rolling when the stars are aligned. It was in the blink of an eye that all hell broke loose.</p>
<p>Over the space of weeks, the game grew from fewer than 1,000 to 2 million players.</p>
<p>“What I built [at the start] is the game that everyone is playing today,&#8221; he said in an interview with TechCrunch. &#8220;It was definitely not the intention when I started.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That rapid growth has surprised Wardle. At his day job at Mschf &#8212; the collective known for stunts like Lil Nas X&#8217;s controversial &#8220;<a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/mschf-lil-nas-x-satan-shoes-caa-drop-viral-1235038051/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blood shoes</a>&#8221; &#8212; he says he occasionally finds himself &#8220;going down the rabbit hole&#8221; on Twitter looking at what people are saying about his creation.</p>
<p>But Wardle&#8217;s not an impresario, nor at this point particularly entrepreneurial (we mean that in a good way &#8212; he&#8217;s just natural in his approach), and that&#8217;s leading to some unexpected outcomes.</p>
<p>People have suspected, and we&#8217;ve now confirmed, that Wardle has been getting approached by investors who want to take Wordle to the next level. (Sidenote: <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Wardle&#8217;s employer Mschf is backed by VCs like Founders Fund. So that could be an interesting template for one direction to go. Or not.) But Wardle isn&#8217;t trying to turn a profit on Wordle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;I don’t want Wordle to be my full-time job, but I don’t want to invest in it or do any of that stuff. I’m very happy with where it’s at,&#8221; Wardle told TechCrunch. &#8220;I think that if [venture funding] were to happen, it would be more in the context of being an artist with a patron or something like that.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">While Wardle</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> considers what to do, if anything at all, his runaway game has found a ton of traction with other less salubrious types: numerous developers have started <a href="https://twitter.com/zachshakked/status/1480912762620547072" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cloning it,</a> taking advantage of Wordle&#8217;s static place on the web and building apps to profit off the interest. </span></p>
<p>While Wardle himself has not really had much of a chance to consider how or if to defend his IP, others have <a href="https://twitter.com/waxpancake/status/1480990948972658689?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">taken up his cause</a>, and now Apple <a href="https://twitter.com/sethsandler/status/1481067821186826248?s=21" target="_blank" rel="noopener">appears to be taking down Wordle clone apps</a> independently of any appeals from Wordle&#8217;s creator.</p>
<p>At the same time, ironically, Wardle’s also getting accused of stealing the Wordle concept from others. The host of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lingo_(British_game_show)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lingo</a>, a gameshow in the U.K., has been <a href="https://twitter.com/adilray/status/1478635246237241345" target="_blank" rel="noopener">publicly railing</a> about how he has given Lingo no credit, considering that the game “looks like ours, works like ours, smells like ours and basically is OURS.”</p>
<p>But Wardle didn&#8217;t build the game for money or viral fame. When you consider the impetus for making Wordle, and how few iterations it&#8217;s had since then, all of this seems to be missing the point.</p>
<p>&#8220;I feel smart when I get a Wordle, even though I made the game,&#8221; Wardle told us. &#8220;It&#8217;s about the journey, especially on days like today where I&#8217;m like really stumped and I like have to think about it.&#8221; (The answer on the day we talked was &#8220;query&#8221;, which is quite perfect.) &#8220;It&#8217;s hard enough that it will hit, like, that sense of accomplishment that feels good.&#8221;</p>
<p>We sat down with Josh Wardle to hear more about his reasons for keeping it simple, and what he&#8217;s thinking about next.</p>
<p>+++++++++++++</p>
<p><em>[This interview has been condensed for clarity]</em></p>
<p><strong>TC: Something that people love about Wordle is that you can only play once a day &#8212; it’s not comparable to past viral games like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/02/01/developer-behind-flappy-bird-the-impossible-game-blowing-up-the-app-store-says-he-just-got-lucky/">Flappy Bird</a>, which was eventually deleted by its developer because it got too addictive. How intentional were you about building a game that, by nature, can only take up a few minutes of your day?</strong></p>
<p>JW: My partner and I play a lot of The New York Times word games, and they follow that one-a-day model. One thing that is interesting to reflect on, though, is that Wordle could be one a day, but if everybody was getting a different word on that day &#8212; if the word was random but you could still only play one &#8212; it wouldn&#8217;t have caught on the way it has. Right? It’s something about the fact that it’s one puzzle, and everybody is solving it. In terms of games like Flappy Bird, I’m just kind of suspicious of apps and games that want your endless attention &#8212; like, I worked in Silicon Valley. I know why they do that. With Wordle, actually, I kind of deliberately did what you’re not meant to do if growth is your goal. And bizarrely, I think, those things have led to growth. But obviously, a ton of it is luck, and being in the right place at the right time. I think people have an appetite for things that transparently don’t want anything from you. I think people quite like it that way, you know?</p>
<div class="c-message_actions__container c-message__actions" role="group">
<div class="c-message_actions__group" role="group" aria-label="Message shortcuts" data-qa="message-actions"><strong style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">You built this for you and your partner to play together, so how did the game go from that to viral sensation?</strong></div>
</div>
<p>Back in the U.K. over the summer, I shared it with my family, and they loved it so much that it derailed the family group chat, so we had to splinter off and create a Wordle channel. There wasn’t the emoji grids at that point, so you’d just come into the chat and say “I got the word in three” or whatever. I introduced it to a few friends in the states, and Andy Baio shared it on his <a href="https://waxy.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog</a>. Then, a New York Times newsletter author included it as a footnote around Thanksgiving, like, “Hey, I’ve been enjoying this thing,” and that somehow led to it getting really popular in New Zealand, and then Australia, and then a Guardian journalist in Australia wrote about it, and that’s the first time I remember logging in the next day and seeing that 80,000 people had played the previous day. One of the early adopters in New Zealand came up with the emoji grid idea and was manually typing them out to share her results on Twitter, so I decided to integrate it into the app itself, and obviously that’s had a huge impact.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			 I think people have an appetite for things that transparently don’t want anything from you. I think people quite like it that way, you know?					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p><strong>You’re now seeing millions of people playing it, all off your Power Language site. How have you handled that traffic?</strong></p>
<p>It’s incredibly simple. It’s literally just a website and some JavaScript that downloads, and once it’s downloaded, it never needs to do anything again, like your phone could go offline and you could continue to play it. So there’s no backend. There’s some shortcomings to the way I did it, like right now, I have people looking at the source code, and they discover all the words are there and they can examine those things. But if I had to be scaling a backend, you know, every time you submitted a guess you had to go to a server, that would have been a huge headache. So because I just built it for my partner and me, I built it as simply as possible. For the people who look in the source for the solution, I’ve seen &#8212; which I quite like &#8212; on Twitter, people are saying it’s like if you’re doing the puzzle section in the newspaper, you can turn the puzzle upside down and read the answers. It’s more about like, who are you cheating if you’re doing that? You can open an incognito browser and take the puzzle again today if you really want, you know? It’s very low stakes.</p>
<p>[Originally the site was hosted by an independent company] and for a while there, I was waking up in the morning, hoping fewer people would have played because I was worried I was gonna hit my bandwidth limit. After Wordle went viral, close to the end of December, I still had enough breathing room where I had 100 gigabytes of bandwidth to play with. Then one of my good ex-Reddit friends, Kevin O&#8217;Connor [now the VP of Engineering at Kickstarter] helped me put Cloudflare in front of my website; then more recently, we migrated the hosting to Amazon S3, which can scale indefinitely as long as I&#8217;m happy to pay for it.</p>
<p><strong>So many venture capitalists are playing Wordle and posting their results on Twitter. Have any VCs reached out to you? What do you think about what some of them must be thinking, that this might have potential as an enterprise rather than just a fun game?</strong></p>
<p>I’ve had a few people reach out in that very diplomatic and warm VC style. [Laughs.] I haven’t had any conversations yet. I don’t even know &#8212; I’ve never been in this position before, and I don’t know what that conversation would look like when I’m giving this thing away for free. I like giving it away for free &#8212; part of the point is it’s free.</p>
<p><strong>Are you going to respond to them and see what happens?</strong></p>
<p>I think I’d be foolish not to, right? It seems like a unique opportunity. I don’t want Wordle to be my full-time job, but I don’t want to invest in it or do any of that stuff. I’m very happy with where it’s at. But given that I work in tech, and I’ll probably continue working in tech, it seems like one of those things where it’s good to meet these people and at least have a discussion.</p>
<p>I’m fortunate enough to be in a position where it does cost me a bit to keep the servers up to run Wordle, but I can afford to do that.</p>
<p>It’s not like I think that everyone needs to give away the things they create online for free, it was just that because that’s how I started this, it’s made it easier for me to continue it this way. I made something that felt really authentic to me, and now when people are asking like, “Do you want to monetize it? Why aren’t you doing X, Y and Z?”</p>
<p>It’s really easy for me to say… No, I was really happy with it when it was just my partner and me playing together. It’s really easy to get seduced by all that stuff, but I try and instead be like… I was happy then, and I think I’ll be happy in the future if that’s where it ends. If at the end of the day with Wordle, it’s just her and me playing again, I think I’ll be totally happy for that to be the outcome.</p>
<p><strong>We noticed you did two pretty cool projects when you worked at Reddit, “<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/reddit-button-n357841" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Button</a>” and “<a href="https://www.newsweek.com/reddit-place-internet-experiment-579049" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Place</a>.” What drives you to create these?</strong></p>
<p>My background is in art, and I’m just interested in making interesting things. The business side of things is not super interesting to me at all, and I can’t imagine anyone paying… like, the things that I’m interested in making are very weird or like not conventional, I think, and don’t really make sense as businesses. I think that if [venture funding] were to happen, it would be more in the context of being an artist with a patron or something like that.</p>
<p><strong>So many people on the internet are making memes and art around Wordle &#8212; do you have any favorites?</strong></p>
<p>I really like the creative interpretations of the emoji grids. There’s an account I started following recently that does green and yellow <a href="https://twitter.com/wordleinpaint" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Paint style pictures</a>. I saw someone who <a href="https://twitter.com/traceyfanclub/status/1479935207562092545" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cross-stitches</a> her Wordle results, which is quite awesome. So it’s those things &#8212; that people enjoy and care enough about this thing that it gives them inspiration, and they want to express it, and it makes them feel good creatively. That’s really an amazing compliment. I like to create things myself, so seeing people respond to something I’ve made in that way feels amazing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">but what if i cross stitch every single one of my wordle results <a href="https://t.co/g312E8WrCC">pic.twitter.com/g312E8WrCC</a></p>
<p>&mdash; abcdefghijklmnopqrs_uvwxyz <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1faa1.png" alt="🪡" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f3db.png" alt="🏛" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@traceyfanclub) <a href="https://twitter.com/traceyfanclub/status/1479935207562092545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><strong>It feels like chatter about the game is especially big on Twitter. Why?</strong></p>
<p>One thing I will say is that the majority of players are not actually posting their results on Twitter. There’s an account called <a href="https://twitter.com/WordleStats" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wordle Stats</a> that looks at Twitter, then collects all the grids people share, then posts it the next day and says, “Okay, 30% of people got it in four,” and I think it was two days ago that it collected 100,000-something, whereas at that time, close to 2 million people played Wordle.</p>
<p>There are Wordles being shared in WhatsApp groups, like my family group. For some people, Twitter is that family WhatsApp group. But the vast majority of people playing are off Twitter. I think they’re playing it with their friends and family. It’s hard for some families to see each other because of COVID, and sometimes it’s hard to come up with a topic of conversation. But Wordle is just such a low-effort way to check in, and sometimes you just post your result, sometimes you can respond to others’, but it’s this really comforting way of letting other people know that you’re thinking about them. It’s a shared experience.</p>
<p><strong>Why is your website called “powerlanguage”?</strong></p>
<p>That’s just a username I’ve used online for a long time, which originates from mishearing someone. Someone was berating my friends and me in my youth. We were being told off for swearing at each other. I thought he said, “power language.” In retrospect, he was saying “foul language,” and I misheard it, but I was so delighted by the idea of swearing being called “power language” and just kind of ran with it in a way you do when you’re 16 or whatever.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			 I was really happy with it when it was just my partner and me playing together. [&#8230;] If at the end of the day with Wordle, it’s just her and me playing again, I think I’ll be totally happy for that to be the outcome.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p><strong>What do you think of all the Wordle clones? Would you ever want to make an app?</strong></p>
<p>People have asked me about the app thing a lot &#8212; one response is I don’t have the skills, and I’d have to invest the time to learn how to do it, which I could do, but it would be an investment of my time. And again, if I’m building a game for my partner… We can use a website every day. It’s not a problem. If my goal was to make Wordle my business or to monetize it, I can see why it would make sense, but then I would have to wrestle with a bunch of things like… Would I send you a push notification? I would definitely have to think about the contract I’m establishing with the player. Do you really want me to notify you? Is this the best way? Why don’t you just forget about Wordle for a little bit?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ijcnuxrrjb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/wordle-is-being-punished-by-app-stores-for-choosing-the-open-web/">Wordle is being punished by app stores for choosing the open web</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wordle is being punished by app stores for choosing the open web&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/wordle-is-being-punished-by-app-stores-for-choosing-the-open-web/embed/#?secret=Ijcnuxrrjb" data-secret="Ijcnuxrrjb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>I will say, I did have one really nice thing happen to me where there was someone who built a game called Wordle on the App Store years ago, and it suddenly started getting a lot of traffic and downloads. He Googled it, found The New York Times article, and reached out to me on Twitter and was like, “Hey, I really like how you’re approaching this. I got some money from people downloading the app and I want to donate it, where should I donate it?” I need to get back to him, but he was like, “I think I would want it to go to a charity focused on literacy or something,” which I thought was amazing.</p>
<p>As far as the clones, I mean, there are some subtle things with Wordle that actually make it work. I actually put quite a lot of effort in &#8212; the solutions list, I actually invested a fair amount of time filtering those. A big one for me was if there were a bunch of five-letter words you’ve never heard of, and if the solution was one of those words, I think that feels bad for people.</p>
<p><strong>The Ringer reported that “<a href="https://www.theringer.com/2022/1/7/22870249/what-to-do-when-playing-the-word-game-wordle-isnt-enough-solve-it" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FARTS</a>” will never be a Wordle solution. Is there a reason for that? </strong></p>
<p>There is a reason for that, but I know part of the joy of discovering Wordle and playing it over a number of times… I know why it’s not included, but I don’t want to state that. I want to let people kind of discover it themselves. It’s an exercise to the reader. <em>(Note: We think we figured it out.)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/josh-wardle-interview-wordle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256733</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Do we need a visa to explore the US market?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/dear-sophie-do-we-need-a-visa-to-explore-the-us-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/dear-sophie-do-we-need-a-visa-to-explore-the-us-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While sightseeing in the U.S., we’d like to explore the feasibility of expanding our business in there. Do we need to get a special visa to do that?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/dear-sophie-with-the-h-1b-lottery-looming-how-should-we-approach-overseas-hiring/">Dear Sophie: With the H-1B lottery looming, how should we approach overseas hiring?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/">Dear Sophie: Will the H-1B lottery be based on the highest wages?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">​​Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch+ members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>My husband and I plan to visit our daughter during her spring break. (She’s an F-1 international student at a U.S. university.) In between spending time with our daughter and sightseeing, we’d like to explore the feasibility of expanding our business in the United States. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Do we need to get a special visa to do that?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Multitasking Mom</strong></p>
<p>Dear Multitasking,</p>
<p>Thank you for reaching out to me before your trip! Conducting business activities while in the United States on a tourist visa is one of the most common mistakes that founders make. I mention this and a few other situations in my <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/105-immigration-pitfalls-for-startup-founders/">podcast episode</a> on immigration pitfalls that startup founders should avoid. Doing business while in visitor status can jeopardize your ability to live and work in the United States or to enter the U.S. in the future.</p>
<p>To answer your question, yes, you will need either a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/b-1-visa-visitors-business/">B-1 business visitor visa</a> or <a href="https://esta.cbp.dhs.gov/esta/">ESTA</a> (Electronic System for Travel Authorization) Visa Waiver Program if you are not a citizen of either Canada or Bermuda. Citizens of Canada and Bermuda do not need a visa to visit the U.S. for certain business visitor activities for less than 180 days.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Before I dive into the specifics of B-1 visas and ESTA, the Visa Waiver Program, as it relates to business, let me just say that it’s never too early to meet with an immigration attorney to discuss your long-term goals and immigration options. I recommend that international founders such as you and your husband talk with an immigration lawyer even before you make your first business-related trip to the United States.</p>
<p>Immigration issues will matter for you both and any international talent you hire should you decide to expand your business here. What’s more, your reasons for coming to the U.S., the visa you obtain, what you say to U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) officers when you arrive in the U.S., what you do while you’re in the U.S., and when you leave could all affect future visits or stays in the U.S.</p>
<h2>B-1 Business Visitor Visa<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/dear-sophie-do-we-need-a-visa-to-explore-the-us-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256404</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI-powered transcription platform DeepScribe raises $30M to unburden doctors from tedious data entry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/ai-powered-transcription-platform-deepscribe-raises-30m-to-unburden-doctors-from-tedious-data-entry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/ai-powered-transcription-platform-deepscribe-raises-30m-to-unburden-doctors-from-tedious-data-entry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 17:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeepScribe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DeepScribe, an AI-powered medical transcription platform, has raised $30 million in Series A funding led by Nina Achadjian at Index Ventures, with participation from Scale.ai CEO Alex Wang, Figma CEO Dylan Field and existing investors Bee Partners, Stage 2 Capital and 1984 Ventures. The company&#8217;s latest round of funding follows its $5.2 million seed round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.deepscribe.ai/?utm_source=adwords&amp;utm_campaign=Search+-+Branded+(General)&amp;utm_medium=ppc&amp;utm_term=deepscribe&amp;hsa_ver=3&amp;hsa_grp=96566457506&amp;hsa_acc=9515316564&amp;hsa_ad=496407464360&amp;hsa_src=g&amp;hsa_tgt=kwd-880077634062&amp;hsa_kw=deepscribe&amp;hsa_cam=9508509494&amp;hsa_mt=p&amp;hsa_net=adwords&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAlfqOBhAeEiwAYi43F7w0-C5O7W5UoMkNLKx-V3h6TWg8R34X7TAv6EjY0rPuMFl_iJW53xoCyCEQAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DeepScribe</a>, an AI-powered medical transcription platform, has raised $30 million in Series A funding led by Nina Achadjian at Index Ventures, with participation from Scale.ai CEO Alex Wang, Figma CEO Dylan Field and existing investors Bee Partners, Stage 2 Capital and 1984 Ventures. The company&#8217;s latest round of funding follows its $5.2 million seed round <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/05/13/2229163/0/en/Medical-Prodigy-DeepScribe-Lands-5-2M-Seed-Funding-for-Life-Changing-AI-Assistant.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> in May 2021. DeepScribe was founded in 2017 by Akilesh Bapu, Matthew Ko and Kairui Zeng with the aim of unburdening doctors from tedious data entry and allowing them to focus on their patients.</p>
<p>In 2019, DeepScribe launched its ambient voice AI technology that summarizes natural patient-physician conversations. The idea for DeepScribe was prompted by Bapu and Ko&#8217;s own experiences. Bapu&#8217;s father was an oncologist and he saw the toll that documentation had on his father&#8217;s work/life balance. On the other hand, Ko saw how the burden of clinical documentation was impacting patients&#8217; perception of care when he was the care coordinator for his mother when she was diagnosed with breast cancer.</p>
<p>After being frustrated with the care his mother was receiving, Ko turned to Bapu and his father for help. The pair then began to understand the importance of clinical documentation and realized that recent breakthroughs in artificial intelligence and natural language processing were not being used to remedy the situation. They then decided to create a platform that would address the problem.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256775" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;After researching products in the space, we wondered why with over 75% of providers using documentation tools in the space, they were still spending nearly half their day writing notes,&#8221; Ko told TechCrunch in an email. &#8220;After testing the products, our thesis was that the existing products in the space were not solving the problem, as they still required the physician to summarize the conversation. Speech-to-text solutions were only capable of translating exactly what you say to text on a computer screen. What doctors wanted and what would really solve the problem was an ambient AI that would be able to intelligently understand and summarize a natural patient conversation. With this insight, we set out to build what is now DeepScribe, the world&#8217;s first ambient AI scribe.&#8221;</p>
<p>Once a physician starts the application, DeepScribe records, summarizes and integrates the conversation into the physician&#8217;s health record system of choice. The application records patient exams while it listens and prepares clinical notes. DeepScribe then uploads the notes directly into the fields of Electronic Health Records (EHR), enabling physicians to review and sign their fully prepared notes in the appropriate EHR fields.</p>
<p>The application is compatible with small talk and only includes the medically relevant information in the conversation. The company also notes that the AI-scribe continuously gets smarter by listening and learning about a physician&#8217;s conversation style, preferred phrasing and writing preferences.</p>
<p>Over the past 18 months, DeepScribe has scaled to more than 400 physicians around the United States and processed over half a million patient-physician conversations. DeepScribe says its platform saves physicians an average of three hours a day and costs around one-sixth the cost of human medical scribes. To date, the company has saved physicians over 2.5 million minutes of documentation. In terms of reliability, DeepScribe says physicians encounter less than one correction per note on average after 20 days of usage.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company says this latest investment will accelerate DeepScribe’s growth, as it plans to continue to improve and transform medical documentation workflows and healthcare overall. DeepScribe aims to deploy its technology to multiple large health systems, grow its engineering team and get its AI in the hands of more physicians.</p>
<div>&#8220;While there are many things on our roadmap, what excites us the most are the possibilities outside of pure summarization,&#8221; Ko said. &#8220;We believe that voice will be the building blocks for the future of medicine and holds the ability to transform the diagnosis and treatment of care as we know it. We hope to leverage the data that we are harvesting through the delivery of our service to go beyond providing efficiencies for the physician and to begin improving outcomes for patients.&#8221;</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/ai-powered-transcription-platform-deepscribe-raises-30m-to-unburden-doctors-from-tedious-data-entry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256775</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canalys: Worldwide PC shipments soared in 2021 to 341 million units</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/canalys-worldwide-pc-shipments-soared-in-2021-to-341-million-units/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/canalys-worldwide-pc-shipments-soared-in-2021-to-341-million-units/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 16:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canalys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lenovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PC market share]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It would be easy to think PC sales dropped worldwide last year amid chip shortages, but that conventional thinking would be wrong. As it turns out, Canalys reports that PC shipments grew 15% year over year in 2021 and were up 27% over 2019, with a whopping 341 million units sold. While the fourth-quarter numbers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It would be easy to think PC sales dropped worldwide last year amid chip shortages, but that conventional thinking would be wrong. As it turns out, Canalys reports that PC shipments grew 15% year over year in 2021 and were up 27% over 2019, with a whopping 341 million units sold.</p>
<p>While the fourth-quarter numbers were up just 1% over the previous year, 2021 was still the best year since 2012, according to the firm.</p>
<p>As Canalys senior analyst Ishan Dutt pointed out, PCs had a great year in spite of chip supply issues, and he sees PCs as firmly entrenched as part of our work and leisure lives, with it becoming the norm to have multiple PCs in the same home in developed areas of the world.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256782" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;For the market to post double-digit growth over an impressive 2020, despite the constant cloud of supply constraints, speaks volumes about how strong PC demand has been over the last 12 months. Taking a long-term view, the most important developments in 2021 were the large increases in PC penetration and usage rates,&#8221; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The big winners in 2021 were the Big 3 PC makers: Lenovo, HP and Dell, with Apple coming in fourth. It&#8217;s worth noting that while everyone had a good year, as the chart below shows, Apple had the largest growth number year-over-year at 28.3%, while Acer was second with 21.8% growth in spite of being fifth overall in terms of shipment numbers.</p>
<p>In terms of market share, Lenovo and HP were the clear winners with 24.1% and 21.7%, respectively. Dell was third with 17.4% with Apple fourth with 8.5%</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256784" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256784" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256784" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-12-at-10.36.46-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="Canalys PC shipments chart for 2021 organized by PC manufacturer" width="680" height="618" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-12-at-10.36.46-AM.jpg 1274w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-12-at-10.36.46-AM.jpg?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-12-at-10.36.46-AM.jpg?resize=300,273 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-12-at-10.36.46-AM.jpg?resize=768,698 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-12-at-10.36.46-AM.jpg?resize=680,618 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-12-at-10.36.46-AM.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256784" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Canalys</p></div></p>
<p>Although chip shortages are expected to persist into the new year, and there is speculation that the education market may be saturated, Canalys still believes that 2022 will be a strong year for PC sales. In fact, Canalys analyst Rushabh Doshi said the market would likely have been bigger in 2021 if not for the supply issues.</p>
<p>&#8220;The primary reason why we are in a shortage situation is that demand is outstripping supply. It is [definitely true] that had the supply situation been better, the PC industry would have grown faster, and be [even bigger],&#8221; Doshi told me.</p>
<p>He sees a market that will continue to expand into the future. &#8220;Looking at an unconstrained view, the demand for better and faster PCs is now more pronounced than ever, not just in work, but also at home. With the importance of PCs reinforced in the past two years, we believe that the growth is here to stay,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/canalys-worldwide-pc-shipments-soared-in-2021-to-341-million-units/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256782</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data show 2021 was a bonkers, record-setting year for venture capital</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/data-show-2021-was-a-bonkers-record-setting-year-for-venture-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/data-show-2021-was-a-bonkers-record-setting-year-for-venture-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 16:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cb insights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchBase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256762</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With a history of venture capital activity setting records in recent years, you may not feel like last year was all too special. It was.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Venture capitalists went hard in 2021.</p>
<p>Data collected from a number of sources indicates that last year set venture capital records around the world. From dollars invested to deal volume, sectors and geographies posted their strongest performance and excelled on essentially every continent.</p>
<p>Today’s startup boom, from a venture capital perspective, is a wide-ranging and incredibly expensive enterprise.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>With a history of venture capital activity setting records in recent years, you may not feel like last year was all too special. It was. The total value of capital disbursed, and the pace at which those funds were put to work, is different than prior years and preceding eras.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220370 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-red-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>The good news from that fact is that we’re seeing venture capital tallies rise across more markets than we did in previous startup boom cycles. This means that more founders in more places are raising capital, even if traditional hot spots like Silicon Valley and the larger U.S. market retain much of their historical heft.</p>
<p>Next week, The Exchange will dig into sectors, trends and particular regions of the world. Today, we’re talking big, high-level numbers and just how much busier last year was for the venture set. With <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/venture-trends-2021/">data from CB Insights</a>, <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/global-vc-funding-unicorns-2021-monthly-recap/">Crunchbase News </a>and a <a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/reports/q4-2021-pitchbook-nvca-venture-monitor-first-look">first look from PitchBook</a> regarding a coming data set, we have plenty of numbers to parse.</p>
<p>So take a walk with us through what could be the most insane and busy year we’ll ever see for venture capitalists. (Unless, of course, 2022 manages to out-crazy last year. Don’t write off that possibility entirely; <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1481257794842079232" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we’re off to a busy start</a>.)</p>
<h2>A record year ‘round the world</h2>
<p>The top-line figures are astounding.</p>
<p>CB Insights reports that venture investment reached $621 billion in 2021, up 111% from 2020 levels. Recall that 2020 was effectively tied with 2018 as the largest year for global venture investment &#8212; until 2021 came and took its crown.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/data-show-2021-was-a-bonkers-record-setting-year-for-venture-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256762</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram, still benefiting from TikTok&#8217;s ban in India, again became the top app by downloads in Q4</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/instagram-still-benefitting-from-tiktoks-ban-in-india-again-become-the-top-app-by-downloads-in-q4/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/instagram-still-benefitting-from-tiktoks-ban-in-india-again-become-the-top-app-by-downloads-in-q4/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 16:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple-app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensor tower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram is benefiting from TikTok&#8217;s ban in India, and has now reclaimed the top spot in terms of total global downloads as of the fourth quarter of 2021. According to new data published by app intelligence firm Sensor Tower, Instagram just had its best quarter since at least 2014, with app installs up 10% over [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram is benefiting from TikTok&#8217;s ban in India, and has now reclaimed the top spot in terms of total global downloads as of the fourth quarter of 2021. According to <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/q4-2021-data-digest" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new data</a> published by app intelligence firm Sensor Tower, Instagram just had its best quarter since at least 2014, with app installs up 10% over Q3. The Meta-owned photo and video sharing app was also the first Meta app to take the No. 1 position on the top downloads chart since WhatsApp held that spot back in Q4 2019.</p>
<p>In fact, Q4 2021 was only the second time in the past two years that TikTok wasn&#8217;t the No. 1 app by worldwide downloads, the firm says.</p>
<p>The only other time TikTok dropped from its top position during that time was at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, when Zoom beat TikTok to become the No. 1 app by downloads in Q2 2020.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256772" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2256788" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256788" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256788" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="545" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg 1646w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=300,241 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=768,616 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=680,545 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=1536,1232 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/global-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256788" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<p>Instagram&#8217;s move to the top of the global (non-game) app market comes from an increase in installs from Android users, specifically. For the second quarter in a row, Meta-owned apps claimed both the No. 1 and No. 2 spots on the chart of the top Google Play apps by worldwide downloads. Instagram was No. 1 in the quarter, followed by Facebook. TikTok, meanwhile, was No. 3.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256786" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256786" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256786" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="541" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg 1648w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=300,238 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=768,610 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=680,541 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=1536,1221 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/google-play-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256786" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<p>On the chart showing the most downloaded apps on the Apple App Store, things look a lot different.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here, TikTok and YouTube continue to hold the No. 1 and No. 2 positions, respectively &#8212; spots they&#8217;ve held since Q2 2020. In Q4, TikTok surpassed 50 million App Store installs for the eighth straight quarter in a row, Sensor Tower says.</p>
<p>The rest of the top five was rounded out by Meta&#8217;s apps with WhatsApp (No. 3), Instagram (No. 4) and Facebook (No. 5). Meanwhile, an unusual appearance by China&#8217;s National Anti-Fraud Center app took the No. 6 spot, after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/instagram-bonuses-reels-tiktok/">being promoted by in a state-sponsored campaign.</a> The rest of the list is filled out with the typical selection of social, chat and entertainment apps.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256787" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256787" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256787" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="530" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg 1714w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=300,234 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=768,599 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=680,530 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=1536,1197 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/app-store-downloads-q4-2021.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256787" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<p>As an interesting side note, the quarter also saw Twitter reaching the top 20 most downloaded apps on the App Store for the first time since Q1 2020, and the fourth time since the start of 2020 when adoption jumped 34% quarter-over-quarter &#8212; growth that has mostly continued since. (Perhaps the flurry of product development activity is finally starting to pay off?</p>
<p>While TikTok is the No. 1 app by downloads in both the App Store and Google Play in the U.S., its fall from No. 1 globally can be at least partially attributed to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/29/india-bans-tiktok-dozens-of-other-chinese-apps/">India&#8217;s decision to ban the app</a> in the country back in June 2020, along with others from Chinese firms, over &#8220;national security&#8221; concerns.</p>
<p>Sensor Tower told TechCrunch that, since the ban, Instagram has seen a steady increase in the share of its global downloads coming from India.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256785" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256785" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256785" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="532" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png 1700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png?resize=300,235 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png?resize=768,601 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png?resize=680,532 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png?resize=1536,1202 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tiktok-download-share.png?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256785" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<p>For example, in Q2 2020, approximately 21% of Instagram&#8217;s downloads were from India, and that share increased to 39% by Q4 2021. And when looking at the full-year totals, around 25% of Instagram&#8217;s downloads came from India in 2020, which then grew to about 36% in 2021.</p>
<p>Instagram has been working to address the TikTok threat by shifting its app&#8217;s focus to video and promoting its TikTok clone, known as Reels. The company in 2021 began <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/instagram-bonuses-reels-tiktok/">offering huge bonuses to creators</a> posting on Reels &#8212; some payouts were as high as $10,000 &#8212; in an effort to regain traction in the face of the growing competition.</p>
<p>Though Instagram won the recent quarter, Sensor Tower data indicates TikTok was still the top app by global downloads for the full year (2021) across both app stores, followed by Facebook then Instagram.</p>
<p>For what it&#8217;s worth, rival firm App Annie <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/app-annie-global-app-stores-consumer-spend-up-19-to-170b-in-2021-downloads-grew-5-to-230b/">shows</a> a slightly different set of rankings. It also has TikTok at the top by worldwide downloads, but sees it followed by Instagram then Facebook. The takeaway here is that Facebook and Instagram were likely close in terms of downloads, and the two companies&#8217; different methodologies for download estimates saw them ending up with different figures as a result.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/instagram-still-benefitting-from-tiktoks-ban-in-india-again-become-the-top-app-by-downloads-in-q4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256772</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Would you marry your investors?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/would-you-marry-your-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/would-you-marry-your-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[due diligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, a podcast about the business of startups, where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines. This is our Wednesday show, where we niche down to a single topic and dive deep. This week Natasha and Mary Ann and Alex came together to talk about the changing nature of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/49d3812b-9d8a-4b49-a04f-b33609618d52?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Equity</a>, a podcast about the business of startups, where we unpack the numbers and nuance behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is our Wednesday show, where we niche down to a single topic and dive deep. This week <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/bayareawriter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mary Ann</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex</a> came together to talk about the changing nature of due diligence in the startup market.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256456" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The chat was loosely <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/3-views-how-due-diligence-will-change-in-2022/">centered around a piece that the three of us wrote</a> as 2021 was coming to a close, but the conversation quickly broadened to include a host of factors that are impacting how startups fundraise and build today.</p>
<p>Mary Ann talked about the power of FOMO, and how that particular social factor is impacting how startups raise. Natasha brought up the importance of back-channeling, and how founders talk to one another. And Alex tried to tease out the difference in how funds of various sizes will approach doing their own diligence, or letting others take on the work.</p>
<p>It was all very good fun! You can read the original backing piece on TC+ <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/3-views-how-due-diligence-will-change-in-2022/">here</a>, and we&#8217;re back Friday!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>,</i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i> Spotify </i></a><i>and all the casts.</i></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/would-you-marry-your-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256456</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jitterbit acquires low-code service PrimeApps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/jitterbit-acquires-low-code-service-primeapps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/jitterbit-acquires-low-code-service-primeapps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citizen developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jitterbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mulesoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[primeapps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[API transformation company Jitterbit today announced that it has acquired PrimeApps, a Turkey-based low-code application development service. Jitterbit plans to combine its API platform with PrimeApps to build an end-to-end platform that will make it easier for non-technical users to build business apps, something that &#8212; almost by default &#8212; includes integrating different data sources. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">API transformation company <a href="https://www.jitterbit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jitterbit</a> today announced that it has acquired <a href="https://www.primeapps.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PrimeApps</a>, a Turkey-based low-code application development service. Jitterbit plans to combine its <a href="https://www.jitterbit.com/platform/ipaas" target="_blank" rel="noopener">API platform</a> with PrimeApps to build an end-to-end platform that will make it easier for non-technical users to build business apps, something that &#8212; almost by default &#8212; includes integrating different data sources. This new platform is scheduled to become available in April 2022.</p>
<p>The two companies did not disclose the financial details of the transaction. Jitterbit CEO George Gallegos would only say that he believes it&#8217;s &#8220;a great deal compared to the billion-dollar opportunity.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jitterbit is on a bit of an acquisition spree. Last November, the company also acquired Wevo, an enterprise integration platform-as-a-service (iPaaS) provider that focuses on Latin America, while last May, it picked up eBridge, another iPaaS service that focuses on enabling data integration between on-premises and cloud e-commerce and CRM systems. In part, these moves were made possible by private equity firm Audax&#8217;s <a href="https://www.jitterbit.com/press-release/audax-private-equity-announces-investment-in-jitterbit-inc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2020 investment</a> in the company.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256668" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The Jitterbit team recently identified this opportunity of layering a no-code/low-code service on top of its platform. As Gallegos noted, from the beginning, the company had focused on automating business processes. Often, the result of these integrations and new workflows is a user experience that a developer then has to create. &#8220;We just saw this coming up over and over &#8212; and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve been looking for either building or finding someone like, in this case, PrimeApps, which was a wonderful combination that was a great fit [&#8230;],&#8221; Gallegos said. &#8220;This was key to accelerating our ability to deliver this capability to our customers in the market to allow them to have one end-to-end solution.&#8221;</p>
<p>PrimeApps never took any outside funding since it was founded by Serdar Turan <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/primeapps" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in 2015</a>. Its 25 employees will all join Jitterbit. &#8220;We were already looking for ways to expand our footprint globally. But it&#8217;s not easy &#8212; it&#8217;s tough,&#8221; Turan said. &#8220;When Jitterbit approached us &#8212; and they were already pretty big in their area &#8212; they were completing what we were missing wonderfully. I saw the opportunity and now we join forces around growing together.&#8221;</p>
<p>The PrimeApps brand is going away as part of this deal, Turan said, and the service will be fully merged into Jitterbit, with its customers moving to the new platform over time.</p>
<p>As Jitterbit&#8217;s Gallegos noted, the company so far competed with the likes of MuleSoft and Boomi in the iPaaS business. These don&#8217;t offer the kinds of end-to-end solution that Jitterbit now offers with the integration of PrimeApps, though I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if we saw them make similar moves in the near future, too.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The promise of low-code development is now starting to come to life. By joining <span class="il">Jitterbit</span>, we are becoming a first-mover that will help usher in this revolution, which will dramatically change how work gets done,” said Turan. &#8220;With <span class="il">Jitterbit</span>’s advanced iPaaS and API management solutions, our platform will empower citizen developers, who are closest to their customers, to create new digital experiences that solve business challenges rapidly without having to rely on an army of IT engineers.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/jitterbit-acquires-low-code-service-primeapps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256668</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Merit grabs $50M Series B to expand digital credentials platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/merit-grabs-50m-series-b-to-expand-digital-credentials-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/merit-grabs-50m-series-b-to-expand-digital-credentials-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rose park advisors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When we think about identity in the digital world, it usually involves a username and password, but Merit (originally called Sigma) wants to help governments issue digital credentials that link back to a government license database with the goal of bringing an end to flimsy paper cards. Today the company announced a hefty $50 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When we think about identity in the digital world, it usually involves a username and password, but <a href="http://merits.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Merit</a> (originally called Sigma) wants to help governments issue digital credentials that link back to a government license database with the goal of bringing an end to flimsy paper cards.</p>
<p>Today the company announced a hefty $50 million Series B. Rose Park Advisors led the round with participation from prior investors a16z, Bow Capital and Govtech Fund, along with new investors Experian Ventures, Spike Ventures, InState Capital, Collier Fund, Metaplanet Holdings and other individual investors. Merit has now raised $80 million, according to the company.</p>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Tomer Kagan said that idea is to create a verifiable online digital identity. A driver&#8217;s license is proof that the state gives you the right to drive, but one that is delivered in the analog form of a plastic card. Merit wants to change that by moving these credentials into the digital realm and linking them to a government database.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256694" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;You need to be empowered to share information about yourself with a third party that is programmatically verifiable, meaning it is just known to be true because I am passing along something that was given to me by an organization that you can verify came from that organization. So what we did is we built a platform over the last five years that actually handles this by allowing organizations to connect to other databases,&#8221; Kagan explained.</p>
<p>The company spent the last five years working with various governments to build connectors to these licensing databases to allow third parties to access the data and have it update automatically. So if you are a plumbing company, you can display your employees&#8217; plumbing credentials on the company website and have them update automatically when the license is renewed (or show that it wasn&#8217;t).</p>
<p>One of the higher-profile examples of this was a project Merit put in place last summer after the tragic <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/news-event/miami-building-collapse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">collapse of a building in Miami</a>. In just one month, the company built a system for verifying which vendors and personnel were allowed onto the site, a project that involved verifying the identities of more than 16,000 people, according to the company.</p>
<p>For now, at least, the company has to work directly with each government entity that it makes a deal with. Each project requires its own workflow and connectors, but Kagan said that each project also builds on the next, so it&#8217;s not like starting from scratch with each new customer.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Today, the company has around 70 employees with plans to get to around 100 by the end of the year. As he adds personnel, Kagan said that he has thought a lot about how to build a diverse and inclusive company.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our non-engineering teams look pretty diverse today. But of course, like everywhere else, we&#8217;re always trying to increase, for example, our female representation in engineering. What&#8217;s really helped is that we&#8217;re fully remote. Getting out of the Bay Area has actually been really helpful in terms of diversity hiring,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Kagan said that fundraising during the pandemic was a pretty stressful exercise, and he had to convince some investors that his company&#8217;s business model, selling services to the government, was a viable strategy. Some investors wouldn&#8217;t invest in companies that deal primarily with government contracts by policy, but in the end, he raised $50 million, so there were plenty of investors willing to go that route.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/merit-grabs-50m-series-b-to-expand-digital-credentials-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256694</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google offers not to put News Showcase into search results in Germany as antitrust probe rolls on</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/google-news-showcase-fco-offers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/google-news-showcase-fco-offers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreas Mundt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyright law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Markets Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[German Federal Cartel Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Showcase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search results]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the latest bit of regulatory woe for Big Tech in Europe, Google is trying to settle a German antitrust investigation into its news licensing product by offering not to expand the display of News Showcase &#8220;story panels&#8221; into general search results. The German Federal Cartel Office (FCO) announced today that the company has proposed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the latest bit of regulatory woe for Big Tech in Europe, Google is trying to settle a German antitrust investigation into its news licensing product by offering not to expand the display of News Showcase &#8220;story panels&#8221; into general search results.</p>
<p>The German Federal Cartel Office (FCO) <a href="https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/Pressemitteilungen/2022/12_01_2022_Google_News_Showcase.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced today</a> that the company has proposed several measures in response to its antitrust concerns &#8212; which also include taking steps to put clear blue water between News Showcase contracts and ongoing negotiations with publishers related to copyright licensing obligations around so called neighbouring rights for news.</p>
<p>Under EU and German law Google must pay copyright fees to news publishers for displaying snippets of their content &#8212; following a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/european-parliament-votes-for-controversial-copyright-reform/">2019 EU copyright reform</a> which was transposed into German law in May 2021.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256681" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Unilateral attempts by German lawmakers &#8212; around a decade ago &#8212; to force Google to pay licensing fees to local publishers for displaying snippets of their content in Google News were easily thwarted by the tech giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/06/21/google-makes-google-news-in-germany-opt-in-only-to-avoid-paying-fees-under-new-copyright-law/">switching to an opt-in model</a> for the aggregator in the market.</p>
<p>Ultimately it&#8217;s taken a pan-EU directive &#8212; combined with local antitrust intervention &#8212; to force Google&#8217;s hand on this issue so it can&#8217;t simply change how it operates to circumvent payments.</p>
<p>Although the tech giant&#8217;s compliance with EU copyright law remains a work in progress, to put it mildly. (Its activity in the region on this front has already attracted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/">a fine of over half a billion dollars in France</a>, for instance, where Google&#8217;s approach to news licensing also remains under close regulatory watch.)</p>
<p>Germany is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/in-latest-big-tech-antitrust-push-germanys-fco-targets-google-news-showcases-fine-print/">scrutinizing Google&#8217;s negotiations with local news publishers</a> &#8212; as well as, as of today, extracting operational concessions from it on how it operates News Showcase.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The FCO said it&#8217;s concerned that if Google integrates News Showcase into general search results, as Google has previously said it intends to, it will result in the company self-preferencing its own services or &#8220;impeding services offered by competing third parties&#8221;.</p>
<p>It also has focus on whether the News Showcase contractual terms &#8220;unreasonably disadvantage&#8221; the participating publishers &#8212; including by making it &#8220;disproportionately difficult for them to enforce their general ancillary copyright when participating in Google News Showcase&#8221;.</p>
<p>The regulator also said it is reviewing Google&#8217;s conditions for access to Google’s News Showcase service &#8212; to examine whether non-discriminatory access is ensured for publishers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s likely no accident that just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/germany-fco-google-decision/">last week the FCO confirmed its ability to apply special measures</a> to Google&#8217;s business, under powers to tackle digital market giants which were passed by local lawmakers at the start of last year. That shrinks the time frame for regulatory action and squeezes how much room Google has to try to wiggle around any FCO orders.</p>
<p>Similar <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/">Big Tech-focused copyright reforms are underway in the U.K.</a>, too. While ex ante rules for gatekeeping giants are well on their way to being adopted at an EU level (aka, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/23/ep-imco-dma-vote/">Digital Markets Act</a>). So the operational leash for Big Tech in Europe is only set to shorten.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m6xvWb6MeY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/germany-fco-google-decision/">Germany&#8217;s antitrust probe of Google products steps up a gear</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Germany&#8217;s antitrust probe of Google products steps up a gear&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/germany-fco-google-decision/embed/#?secret=m6xvWb6MeY" data-secret="m6xvWb6MeY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As well as offering not to expand the showcasing of licensed content to general search results in Germany, the FCO said today that Google has &#8220;already changed some of the practices under examination and declared its willingness to address any remaining ambiguities and concerns by modifying the Showcase contracts and providing clarifying statements&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;In particular, Showcase contracts are to be clearly separated from the ongoing negotiations regarding other ancillary copyright payments between Google and the publishers or their collecting societies,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>The tech giant announced the global<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/google-to-pay-out-1b-to-publishers-to-license-content-for-new-google-news-showcase/"> News Showcase</a> product back in October 2020 &#8212; when it said it would pay participating publishers $1 billion collectively to licence their news content to appear in so-called &#8220;story panels&#8221; (see below examples from <a href="https://news.google.com/news-showcase/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google&#8217;s product marketing</a>) across Google products.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256726" style="width: 2368px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256726" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2256726 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png" alt="" width="2358" height="1182" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png 2358w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png?resize=768,385 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png?resize=680,341 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png?resize=1536,770 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png?resize=2048,1027 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screenshot-2022-01-12-at-12.39.36.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2358px) 100vw, 2358px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256726" class="wp-caption-text">Screengrab: Natasha Lomas/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>At the time Google was facing rising legal requirements in a number of jurisdictions over remuneration for displaying news content (Australia came up with its own legislative template targeting Google and Facebook to pay for news reuse in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/31/australia-now-has-a-template-for-forcing-facebook-and-google-to-pay-for-news/">August 2020</a>, for example).</p>
<p>So the News Showcase gambit always looked like a naked attempt by Google to limit a looming revenue hit while simultaneously leveraging its market power to generate as much upside for its ad-monetizing internet content business as possible.</p>
<p>Closed-door commercial deals for News Showcase offered Google the chance to dangle a carrot of licensing payments and play publishers off against each other &#8212; pressuring them to agree to its terms and shrink legally mandated licensing fees.</p>
<p>Initially, Google said content licensed under News Showcase would appear in story panels on the Google News app on mobile devices. It went on to expand where participating publishers&#8217; content appeared to include its News aggregator product on the desktop and a personalized content feed on mobile devices, called Google Discover.</p>
<p>Evidently, it hoped to be able to further expand where across its online real-estate the licensed content appears &#8212; including by adding News Showcase into search results.</p>
<p>However, in Europe, where Google&#8217;s search engine remains dominant, its plan quickly landed it in regulatory hot water over competition concerns.</p>
<p>As its name suggests, the News Showcase product provides the prospect of raised visibility for participating publishers by featuring their content to Google users across a number of touchpoints &#8212; including giving mobile users the ability to follow publishers so that more of their content gets threaded into personalized feeds. So there is a strong incentive for publishers to cut deals with Google &#8212; giving it leverage over content licensing negotiations.</p>
<p>For example, publishers may feel incentivized to cut deals with Google for News Showcase in order not to miss out on the prospect of extra traffic being sent their way (especially if competitors have already cut deals) &#8212; putting commercial pressure on them to agree to broad licensing terms that might waive or reduce copyright-based licensing fees.</p>
<p>The problem for Google is that European competition regulators have not been taken in by its attempt to use a proprietary news display product and commercial terms to smudge copyright compliance by co-mingling News Showcase negotiations and contacts with legally required licensing fees &#8212; and have instead listened to publisher complaints that Google is not playing fair. (The FCO probe, for example, was opened following a complaint filed by the collecting society Corint Media.)</p>
<p>Issuing a hefty sanction last summer, the French competition watchdog said Google had sought to unilaterally impose its global news licensing product in negotiations with publishers — pushing for the legal neighbouring right to be incorporated as “an ancillary component with no separate financial valuation”.</p>
<p>Its investigation continues &#8212; but has already landed Google with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-592m-in-france-for-breaching-antitrust-order-to-negotiate-news-copyright-fees/">a $592 million fine for breaching an earlier order</a>.</p>
<p>Germany hasn&#8217;t issued any sanctions yet, but with the FCO flush with new powers to tackle abusive digital giants, the threat is clearly there. Hence Google&#8217;s alacritous offer of tweaks to how it operates the News Showcase product in Germany (the FCO only began probing the T&amp;Cs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/in-latest-big-tech-antitrust-push-germanys-fco-targets-google-news-showcases-fine-print/">last summer</a>).</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s dominance in Europe in the market for general search means the company has faced a number of antirust enforcements in recent years &#8212; both at an EU and national level. But it&#8217;s fair to say that EU Member States&#8217; competition watchdogs have been quickest to respond to news publishers&#8217; concerns.</p>
<p>Germany was one of the first markets to get News Showcase which has likely fed the FCO&#8217;s relatively quick scrutiny of the product. Although France was faster to transpose the EU copyright reform into national law &#8212; and its competition watchdog has been keenly focused on Google&#8217;s compliance with the neighbouring right requirement, and with the detail of how it has negotiated fees with news publishers over reuse of their content.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/google-france-antitrust-news-litigation-settlement-offer/">December</a>, the French regulator announced Google had made a series of commitments around negotiating in good faith &#8212; which it proposed should apply for a period of five years.</p>
<p>France&#8217;s watchdog is consulting on Google&#8217;s proposal until the end of this month &#8212; after which it will make a decision whether to accept them or require additional measures.</p>
<p>The German FCO is also now consulting locally on Google&#8217;s operational offers around News Showcase.</p>
<p>In a statement, Bundeskartellamt president Andreas Mundt said: “Google has proposed measures to respond to our competition concerns relating to Google News Showcase. The company no longer plans to include Showcase content in the general search results. The conditions for participating in Google News Showcase are not intended to prevent publishers from enforcing their general ancillary copyright. Access to Google News Showcase is based on objective criteria. We rely on the assessment of the market players affected to ensure that the measures proposed by Google are effective. In view of the wide variety of interests the publishers may have we are thus conducting broader consultations in the sector.”</p>
<p>He further noted that the regulator is keeping a close eye on how Google negotiates with publishers over copyright fees, adding:<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> “Parallel to the Google News Showcase proceeding we are closely monitoring the negotiations on ancillary copyright fees.”</span></p>
<p>In yet another recent regulatory intervention triggered by publisher (and adtech) complaints, Google&#8217;s plan to deprecate support for third-party tracking cookies and move to a suite of new ad targeting technologies (aka Privacy Sandbox) is under close supervision of the U.K.&#8217;s competition watchdog &#8212; and that process has also led Google to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/26/cma-google-privacy-sandbox-revisions/">propose a series of commitments in order to be allowed to proceed</a>.</p>
<p>Separately last summer, France&#8217;s competition watchdog hit Google with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/france-fines-google-268m-for-adtech-abuses-and-gets-interoperability-commitments/">a $268 million fine for self preferencing its adtech</a> &#8212; leading to yet another behavioral offer from the tech giant, in that case a set of interoperability commitments.</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> A Google spokesperson has now sent this statement on its News Showcase proposals in Germany:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Google News Showcase is the kind of licensing programs that had been demanded for years by publishers as well as policy makers. We are glad that more than 700 publications globally are already part of Showcase, with more than 90 publications in Germany alone. These are new services that bring value to consumers and we’re happy to work with the German competition authority on finding the right approach efficiently. We have already made some changes and proposed further measures for improvement and are looking forward to any further feedback. At the same time we continue this important work together with our publishing partners in order to support quality journalism in Germany and beyond.”</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3xadcUeb3x"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/google-france-antitrust-news-litigation-settlement-offer/">Google offers behavioral pledges on news payments in France to try to end costly antitrust litigation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google offers behavioral pledges on news payments in France to try to end costly antitrust litigation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/google-france-antitrust-news-litigation-settlement-offer/embed/#?secret=3xadcUeb3x" data-secret="3xadcUeb3x" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MQTOwA7zW8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/26/cma-google-privacy-sandbox-revisions/">Google agrees with UK&#8217;s CMA to deeper oversight of Privacy Sandbox</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google agrees with UK&#8217;s CMA to deeper oversight of Privacy Sandbox&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/26/cma-google-privacy-sandbox-revisions/embed/#?secret=MQTOwA7zW8" data-secret="MQTOwA7zW8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/12/google-news-showcase-fco-offers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256681</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
