<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 21:50:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Netflix to acquire German visual effects studio behind &#8216;Stranger Things&#8217; and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/netflix-to-acquire-german-visual-effects-studio-behind-stranger-things-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/netflix-to-acquire-german-visual-effects-studio-behind-stranger-things-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 20:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acquisition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netflix is acquiring Munich-based visual effects studio Scanline VFX for an undisclosed amount. The company expects the deal to close in the first quarter of 2022, subject to regulatory approvals and closing conditions. Scanline has done work on several Netflix originals, including &#8220;Stranger Things&#8221; and &#8220;Cowboy Bebop.&#8221; The studio has also provided special effects for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Netflix is acquiring Munich-based <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/bringing-more-vfx-magic-to-our-members-with-scanline-vfx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">visual effects studio Scanline VFX</a> for an undisclosed amount. The company expects the deal to close in the first quarter of 2022, subject to regulatory approvals and closing conditions. Scanline has done work on several Netflix originals, including &#8220;Stranger Things&#8221; and &#8220;Cowboy Bebop.&#8221; The studio has also provided special effects for many Marvel and DC titles.</p>
<p>Founded in 1989, Scanline has offices in Vancouver, Montreal, Los Angeles, London, Munich, Stuttgart and Seoul. For Netflix, Scanline has worked on &#8220;Stranger Things 4,&#8221; &#8220;Blood Red Sky,&#8221; &#8220;Slumberland,&#8221; &#8220;The Gray Man,&#8221; &#8220;The Adam Project&#8221; and &#8221; Don&#8217;t Look Up.&#8221; Outside of Netflix, the studio has provided special effects for &#8220;Game of Thrones,&#8221; &#8220;Black Widow,&#8221; &#8220;Black Panther,&#8221; &#8220;Captain Marvel,&#8221; &#8220;Iron Man 3,&#8221; &#8220;Captain America: The Winter Soldier,&#8221; &#8220;Zack Snyder&#8217;s Justice League,&#8221; &#8220;Joker&#8221; and more.</p>
<p>In terms of upcoming projects, Scanline is working on &#8220;The Batman,&#8221; &#8220;The Flash,&#8221; &#8220;Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom,&#8221; &#8220;Black Adam&#8221; and &#8220;Moonfall.&#8221; Netflix says that going forward, Scanline will continue to operate as a standalone business and work with its current clients.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238227" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Netflix&#8217;s vice president of studio operations, Amy Reinhard, says Scanline is known for its complex, photorealistic effects and expertise in virtual production. In a <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/bringing-more-vfx-magic-to-our-members-with-scanline-vfx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a>, Reinhard outlined that Netflix plans to invest in Scanline’s pipeline, infrastructure and workforce and &#8220;continue to support the work that Scanline’s Eyeline Studios is doing in virtual production to push the boundaries of what is visibly possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ll also continue to rely on many other studios around the world for our VFX needs so we can continue to ensure that our creators have access to the world&#8217;s most innovative tech, and continue to bring the most compelling and cutting-edge storytelling to our members,&#8221; Reinhard stated.</p>
<p>Netflix&#8217;s acquisition of Scanline comes amid the streaming giant&#8217;s push toward in-house production. In 2018, Netflix acquired Albuquerque Studios and announced last year that it planned to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/netflix-commits-1-billion-to-make-new-mexico-home-to-one-of-the-worlds-largest-studios/">invest $1 billion</a> in production spending to expand the studio and include an additional 300 acres to make it home to one of the largest studios. The proposed expansion and $150 million in capital expenditures will add 10 new stages, post-production services, mills, backlots and training facilities, wardrobe suites, a commissary and more.</p>
<p>The streaming giant&#8217;s latest acquisition comes as it recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/28/netflix-acquires-its-first-games-studio-oxenfree-developer-night-school/">purchased its first games studio,</a> Night School Studio, in September for an undisclosed amount. The independent game developer is known for its narrative-driven titles like &#8220;Oxenfree&#8221; and was founded in 2014 by Sean Krankel, a former senior game designer at Disney Interactive, and Adam Hines, who was a lead writer at Telltale Games.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/netflix-to-acquire-german-visual-effects-studio-behind-stranger-things-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238227</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roku customers report streaming issues after 10.5 update</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/roku-customers-report-streaming-issues-after-10-5-update/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/roku-customers-report-streaming-issues-after-10-5-update/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 20:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple tv app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hbo now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hisense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Radio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Football League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nfl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sharp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sling TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Westinghouse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A number of Roku customers are experiencing problems with their Roku TVs following the Roku OS 10.5 update. According to reports published to Roku&#8217;s own customer forums and other sites, like Reddit, impacted Roku TV owners say many of their streaming apps &#8212; like HBO Max, Disney+, Amazon Prime Video, Paramount+ and others, no longer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A number of Roku customers are experiencing problems with their Roku TVs following the <a href="https://newsroom.roku.com/news/2021/09/roku-os-10-5-offers-easy-access-to-content-/-qrfhin6-1632009402" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Roku OS 10.5 update</a>. According to reports published to Roku&#8217;s own <a href="https://community.roku.com/t5/Roku-Device-Features-Settings-Updates/OS-10-5-Roku-TV-experiencing-loading-channel-issues/td-p/738115/highlight/true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">customer forums</a> and other sites, like Reddit, impacted Roku TV owners say many of their streaming apps &#8212; like HBO Max, Disney+, Amazon Prime Video, Paramount+ and others, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Roku/comments/qyxplo/i_feel_roku_owes_me_money_since_im_now_paying_for/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">no longer work</a> while others have more intermittent issues, like Netflix.</p>
<p>Some are also experiencing problems with their <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Roku/comments/qz5whm/frozen_screen_and_broken_remote_with_new_update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">screens being frozen</a> and their Roku remote no longer functioning, they said, but it&#8217;s unclear for now if these are a related or separate issue.</p>
<p>Roku says it&#8217;s aware of the problem and working to resolve it.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238123" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>While the 10.5 update began rolling out in October, Roku tends to update its streaming players first followed by its Roku TV devices. That means many of the impacted customers only recently received the update, as they own a Roku TV, leading to the flood of consumer complaints when the update resulted in favorite streaming apps not working. In addition, the issues impact Roku Ultra devices, as well.</p>
<p>Though the issue began to blow up on the Roku forums last week, some users said <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Roku/comments/qygyez/customer_support_offers_absolutely_no_support_105/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they&#8217;ve been dealing with</a> a non-functional TV for multiple weeks, leading them to purchase a Chromecast or Fire TV stick instead.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://community.roku.com/t5/Roku-Device-Features-Settings-Updates/OS-10-5-Roku-TV-experiencing-loading-channel-issues/td-p/738115/highlight/true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an 18-page thread</a> on Roku&#8217;s community forums, users reported issues with Westinghouse, TCL, Sharp and Hisense TVs, among other devices. There are <a href="https://community.roku.com/t5/Roku-Device-Features-Settings-Updates/bd-p/device-settings-config" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many other threads as well</a>, with dozens of responses. Customers with both hardwired and wireless network connections are impacted, according to consumer complaints. A few users said rebooting their TV <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Roku/comments/qwbwwy/tcl_roku_tv_has_strong_wifi_connection_but_all/?utm_medium=android_app&amp;utm_source=share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">or router</a> worked, but others said they tried that, as well as a factory reset, without any resolution.</p>
<p>Roku has been aware of the problem for some time, as a Roku forum <a href="https://community.roku.com/t5/forums/recentpostspage/post-type/message/user-id/108737" target="_blank" rel="noopener">moderator has been writing back</a> to forum posters since at least last week, asking for information about their devices like the serial number, Roku device model, device ID and software OS version.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With no official fix yet available, Roku has been forced to roll back the update for some of its users by downgrading their devices to software version 10.0.0. But this option hasn&#8217;t been automatically deployed to all customers. Instead, forum members said a Roku representative had privately <a href="https://community.roku.com/t5/Roku-Device-Features-Settings-Updates/OS-10-5-Roku-TV-experiencing-loading-channel-issues/td-p/738115/page/10" target="_blank" rel="noopener">messaged</a> them with instructions after they shared their device information.</p>
<p>And, as of last week, users were <a href="https://community.roku.com/t5/Roku-Device-Features-Settings-Updates/OS-10-5-Roku-TV-experiencing-loading-channel-issues/m-p/740171/highlight/true#M25239" target="_blank" rel="noopener">being asked to private message</a> a Roku employee with their device information to receive the downgrade, indicating the fix is being handled on a one-off basis for the time being. This process is frustrating some Roku customers who think a broader rollback should be underway at this point.</p>
<p>The issues arrive at a time when many U.S. consumers will be taking time off from work over the Thanksgiving holidays &#8212; meaning they have a lot more time for watching TV. Tuning into NFL football, for example, is part of the Thanksgiving tradition, but livestreaming apps like Sling TV and Hulu are among those impacted by the software issues.</p>
<p>A representative for Roku was reached for comment this afternoon but didn&#8217;t yet have a statement available.</p>
<p>Later in the day, Roku shared the following comment with TechCrunch:</p>
<p><i><span data-removefontsize="true" data-originalcomputedfontsize="16">A small portion of users that have certain older Roku TV models or older Roku Ultra players are experiencing issues with the latest firmware update, OS 10.5. We are actively investigating and working to resolve this as quickly as possible, and will provide our customers with real-time updates [on our website at <a href="http://support.roku.com/contactus" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://support.roku.com/contactus&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1637698687667000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2vu8GeOoQ6fVVHwHsuboNJ" data-removefontsize="true" data-originalcomputedfontsize="16">support.roku.com/contactus</a> and on twitter at @RokuSupport.</span></i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/roku-customers-report-streaming-issues-after-10-5-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238123</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 must-have board slides for SaaS sales and revenue leaders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/5-must-have-board-slides-for-saas-sales-and-revenue-leaders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/5-must-have-board-slides-for-saas-sales-and-revenue-leaders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 20:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief revenue officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales numbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re responsible for driving revenue growth at your company, here's how you can make your portion of board meetings as engaging and impactful as possible.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Bill Binch</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/billbinch">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Bill Binch is an operating partner at global, technology-focused investment firm Battery Ventures. He previously was the chief revenue officer of Pendo, a Battery portfolio company.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">As a revenue leader at large and small technology companies, I’ve spent the last 15 years attending a lot of quarterly board meetings.</p>
<p>These meetings take countless hours to prepare for and can create a lot of stress. The prep and the practice can be draining, and, more importantly, distracting from your daily grind.</p>
<p>This is all necessary because the board meeting is such a high-stakes event. As a wise mentor once told me, no one ever gets a promotion from a board meeting, but people sure do get fired afterward.</p>
<p>So if you’re responsible for driving revenue growth at your company, how do you make your portion of these meetings as engaging and impactful as possible? I’ve got some hard-earned advice on that front, as well as suggestions for five must-have board slides — customized for leaders at B2B, software-as-a-service companies — that will help you give a great presentation and preserve your sanity.</p>
<h2>Size matters — and so does consistency</h2>
<p>I’ve been part of company board meetings where the deck was 30 slides, and I’ve also been in meetings where decks would be more than 150 slides. You’ll need to gauge what level of detail is right for your organization, but my general rule is to cut your slides until it hurts the narrative of the deck.</p>
<p>You should also strive for consistency. You’ll want to deliver the same sets of metrics and details in each quarterly meeting so that directors and executives can make apples-to-apples comparisons of key data.</p>
<p>One caveat: The world is evolving and the idea of &#8220;cohort data&#8221; is thriving. As businesses evolve and new models like consumption- or payment-based pricing become more common, you may need to adjust certain metrics over time, particularly if you are a B2B SaaS company.</p>
<h2>Deliver the goods</h2>
<p>From the delivery point of view, I’ll share a couple of ideas.</p>
<p>The first is fairly well known: Don’t present slides; present the story. Board members are skilled at thin slicing through data and composing their questions ahead of time. Don’t feel the need to present every nuance around your data — get to the point.</p>
<p>The other piece of advice here is to look ahead. First-time attendees at board meetings often lean toward giving a look at the past, which is probably not where you should be focusing most of your energy. Read through your presentation and see how much focuses on the future versus the past.</p>
<p>The majority of your deck should paint a picture of what you’re going to do, not what’s happened. The board has received a board flash from the CEO right after the quarter closed and has now read the deck. What you’re here to do is share the adjustments you’re making to lead the business forward.</p>
<p>Finally: Create an appendix. This allows your content — new initiatives, changes to go-to-market strategies and product topics — to stay front-and-center and not get bogged down by too much data. But having an appendix still allows the board to view more detailed, quarter-over-quarter changes.</p>
<h2>Focus on these five, must-have slides</h2>
<p>I traditionally build my &#8220;talk time&#8221; around five revenue-focused slides during a board presentation. Some versions of these slides have been in my board decks for the past decade. These are data-rich slides, so again, prepare to discuss the story they’re telling and not the data.</p>
<p>For example, your board members will notice if your sales velocity is speeding up and your average selling price is trending down. They can see that in your numbers, so you need to explain why that is happening.</p>
<h2>Slide #1: Headline reel</h2>
<p>After the cover page and agenda, I think every deck should start with the headline reel: the key results of what you achieved last quarter. Regardless of whether your quarter was good or bad, don’t make the board search through the deck to find the details.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/5-must-have-board-slides-for-saas-sales-and-revenue-leaders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237765</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creator-driven marketplace LTK now valued at $2B after raising $300M from SoftBank</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/creator-driven-marketplace-ltk-now-valued-at-2b-after-raising-300m-from-softbank/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/creator-driven-marketplace-ltk-now-valued-at-2b-after-raising-300m-from-softbank/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Influencer Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LTK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media influencers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When LTK launched in 2011, phrases like &#8220;influencer marketing&#8221; or &#8220;the creator economy&#8221; weren&#8217;t common, but fashion blogger Amber Venz Box faced the same struggles that internet personalities face today. How do you convert unpaid hours writing posts, shooting photos, editing videos and building a following into a viable career? Amber Venz Box started LTK [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When LTK launched in 2011, phrases like &#8220;influencer marketing&#8221; or &#8220;the creator economy&#8221; weren&#8217;t common, but fashion blogger Amber Venz Box faced the same struggles that internet personalities face today. How do you convert unpaid hours writing posts, shooting photos, editing videos and building a following into a viable career?</p>
<p>Amber Venz Box started LTK when she wanted a way to earn a commission from readers who bought the products she recommended, but now a decade later, the blogger-turned-founder has a $2 billion company on her hands. Previously branded as RewardStyle and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/06/liketoknow-it-app-launch-screenshots/">LIKEtoKNOW.it</a>, LTK helps social media influencers make their posts shoppable and houses them on a central marketplace, both on the web and on its app. Brands can also use the platform to connect with creator partners for upcoming marketing campaigns. The company reached this valuation after raising $300 million from SoftBank&#8217;s Vision Fund.</p>
<p>LTK caters to creators, brands and shoppers, who spend more than $3 billion on the platform each year, according to the company. The interface is reminiscent of Instagram Shop &#8212; you scroll through posts by creators who have curated their favorite products to share, only LTK predates Instagram&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/facebook-whatsapp-e-commerce-features/">pivot to e-commerce</a>. The company has been <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211122006289/en/LTK-the-Creator-Commerce%E2%84%A2-Platform-Raises-at-a-2-Billion-Valuation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">profitable for many years</a>, and with its new round of funding, plans to hire across the organization to grow the Texas-based company internationally. Currently, LTK has an international staff of 350, working with 5,000 retailers and more than 1 million brands.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238083" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“We believe LTK is helping to reimagine the concept of entrepreneurship by enabling people to make a living out of their hobbies and passions,” said Angela Du, Investment Director at SoftBank Investment Advisers, who will join the company’s board of directors when the transaction closes. “LTK&#8217;s innovative marketing platform empowers these creators to build their personal brands across the social universe and forge long-term, authentic relationships with their followers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The success and growth of LTK reiterates consumers&#8217; increasing interest in shopping through recommendations from the people they follow. Venz Box <a style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexandrasternlicht/2021/11/22/ltk-cofounder-amber-venz-box-now-one-of-americas-richest-self-made-women-after-softbank-fundraising/?sh=13de51de1939" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told Forbes</a> that more than 130 influencers have become self-made millionaires through LTK. These creators, mostly women, earn between 10% and 25% of sales &#8212; the brands and retailers on the platform set their own commission rate. Brands get the sale that the creator drives, and the creator earns a commission on top of that &#8212; LTK earns a transaction fee from these sales.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/creator-driven-marketplace-ltk-now-valued-at-2b-after-raising-300m-from-softbank/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238083</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FSD Africa expands insurtech accelerator program to Ghana and Nigeria</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/fsd-africa-expands-insurtech-accelerator-program-to-ghana-and-nigeria/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/fsd-africa-expands-insurtech-accelerator-program-to-ghana-and-nigeria/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Most people in Africa wish to utilize various insurance products but are often deterred by the associated high premiums. It is, therefore, not surprising that insurance penetration across the continent remains marginal, with reported premiums per capita being 11 times lower than the world average, according to a McKinsey study. But the market might soon [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Most people in Africa wish to utilize various insurance products but are often deterred by the associated high premiums. It is, therefore, not surprising that insurance penetration across the continent remains marginal, with reported premiums per capita being 11 times lower than the world average, according to a <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/middle-east-and-africa/africas-insurance-market-is-set-for-takeoff">McKinsey study</a>.</p>
<p>But the market might soon change as innovative products that run on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/insuretech-on-the-heels-of-a-fintech-boom-heats-up-in-africa/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">micropayment or pay-per-use frameworks emerge</a> under the support of institutions like the U.K.-funded Financial Sector Deepening (FSD) Africa.</p>
<p>FSD Africa is set to launch insurtech accelerator programs in Ghana and Nigeria next year to promote innovations that will drive the uptake of insurance in the two markets and beyond.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238088" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The planned launch of insurtech accelerator programs in the West African countries follows the introduction of the same in Kenya earlier this year, in partnership with Insurance Regulatory Authority, the country’s regulator, and cloud solution provider Tellistic Technology Services.</p>
<p>“At FSD Africa, we are committed to the growth of the insurance sector and are excited to be involved in grooming the next generation of insurance innovators. … The insurance industry has been slow to innovate compared to the rest of the financial sector, yet Africa is experiencing a huge protection gap,” FSD Africa&#8217;s director of risk, Kelvin Massingham, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“We are planning to launch the BimaLab Insurtech Accelerator Program in Ghana and Nigeria.&#8221;</p>
<p>FSD Africa is also planning to provide access to capital through venture funds and grants to early-stage insurtech startups, in addition to setting up an online platform where founders can brainstorm, share experiences, create partnerships, and gain technical support from different industry professionals.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The organization is working with eight insurance regulators including those of Ghana, Malawi, Nigeria, Rwanda and Tanzania to build an environment that bolsters insurtech innovation across the continent.</p>
<p>“It is really a peer learning and engagement platform for regulators primarily around regulating for innovation and things like creating insurtech and startup ecosystems, but also on wider issues like ESG (environmental, social and governance). And we&#8217;re excited to support the development of similar programs like this across the region,” Massingham said.</p>
<p>The new plans follow the graduation of the Kenya program’s second cohort last Friday. Over the 10-week program, participants were provided with knowledge and resources to develop and get their solutions ready for the market. Twelve startups were in the cohort, with Karopay and Motisure landing recognition for their innovations.</p>
<p>Motisure targets motorcycle (boda-boda) taxi commuters and riders with personal accident coverage for as low as 10 Kenyan shillings (about 9 U.S. cents) a day. Boda-bodas are a popular means of transport in East Africa, with 22 million rides served every day in Kenya alone.</p>
<p>Karopay’s edtech insurance product Bimashule ensures that students in rural Kenya have basic medical and personal accident insurance coverage, with premiums starting from less than $1 a month. It also comes with a school fee guarantee in the event of a guardian’s demise.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/fsd-africa-expands-insurtech-accelerator-program-to-ghana-and-nigeria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238088</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: The smart home starter kit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/smart-home-gift-guide-ideas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/smart-home-gift-guide-ideas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 19:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Belkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HomeKit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HomePod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lutron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart home devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart speakers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wi-fi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2234206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A year ago I accidentally turned my house into a smart home. What started out as an easy (and lazy, let&#8217;s be honest) way to switch off the radio in the kitchen without getting up from the couch quickly became an obsession to remotely control and automate as much of my house as possible. What [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A year ago I accidentally turned my house into a smart home. What started out as an easy (and lazy, let&#8217;s be honest) way to switch off the radio in the kitchen without getting up from the couch quickly became an obsession to remotely control and automate as much of my house as possible.</p>
<p>What makes a smart home? In my house the lights, outlets and window blinds can be controlled from my phone, at home or anywhere in the world, but you can extend it to other things, like air conditioners, sprinklers and garage door openers. Or thermostats, speakers, security cameras and just about anything electrical. And by adding smart home tech that can detect temperature, humidity or motion, you can automate your house to turn the light up at sunset, set the sprinklers on when the weather is dry, turn on the air conditioning when it&#8217;s warm or alert you if the doors open when you&#8217;re not at home.</p>
<p>The novelty of switching your living room lights off and off from your phone might quickly wear off, but it can be reassuring knowing that you can get a sense of what&#8217;s going on at home even when you&#8217;re not there — or automatically adjust the climate and lighting when you are.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2234206" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>You&#8217;re probably thinking, <em>is this guy serious? Why would I want even more of my home connected to the internet? </em>The Internet of Things (IoT) doesn&#8217;t have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/02/smart-home-hub-flaws-unlock-doors/">the best reputation</a> historically with security, but modern smart home devices can be certified to the far higher standards set by the Big Tech giants like Apple, Amazon and Google. That said, no technology is ever perfectly secure, though efforts to create a common secure smart home standard is paying off with Matter, a protocol endorsed by some of the biggest tech companies and smart home device makers.</p>
<p>It helps to join a smart home ecosystem that you&#8217;re comfortable with. I use a Mac and an iPhone, so <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/19/anybody-can-now-make-homekit-accessories/">Apple&#8217;s HomeKit</a> makes the most sense for me. Apple does not collect a ton of data like other smart home ecosystems and is probably a better fit for the privacy minded. For this guide we&#8217;ll focus on HomeKit but much will broadly apply if you use another ecosystem. For Android users, Google Home would make more sense, or Amazon Alexa if you&#8217;re so inclined. Many modern devices are compatible with other smart home platforms anyway, including newer standards like Thread. But for best results, pick an ecosystem and make sure the add-ons you&#8217;re buying are compatible.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re after convenience or routine — or like in my case you just want to tinker — there&#8217;s a lot you can do with what you already have but a lot more you can do without breaking the bank.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission. <em> Looking for more ideas? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/pages/gift-guide-2021/">Find our other gift guides here.</a></em></i></p>
<h2>First, you need (or may already have) a HomeKit hub</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2234227" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2234227" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2234227 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homepod.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="729" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homepod.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homepod.jpg?resize=150,107 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homepod.jpg?resize=300,214 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homepod.jpg?resize=768,547 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homepod.jpg?resize=680,484 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homepod.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2234227" class="wp-caption-text">A HomePod mini or Apple TV will work as a hub. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brian Heater/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>HomeKit devices rely on a hub to communicate with. It&#8217;s through this hub that your other smart home devices connect to the internet, letting you access your devices from your phone in the outside world. Good news if you have an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/the-new-apple-tv-4k-comes-with-a-new-siri-remote/">Apple TV</a> or a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/12/apple-discontinues-original-homepod-will-focus-on-mini/">HomePod</a> (or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/apple-homepod-mini-review-remarkably-big-sound/">HomePod mini</a>) since these will serve as your HomeKit hub out of the box and generally don&#8217;t require any configuration. If you have more than one of these devices in your home, they can all serve as failover hubs if one becomes unavailable.</p>
<p>Some tech, like Philips Hue or Samsung SmartThings, will require their own separate hub (sometimes called a bridge) before they will appear in your smart home. Hubs often connect directly into the router, so keep available ports and wireless range in mind.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Apple TV HD | Price: </strong>$150 from <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-tv/apple-tv-hd/32gb">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0933BY6P4/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B0933BY6P4&amp;linkId=610073289f7cce11a37b5e3172816e09">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.target.com/p/apple-tv-2nd-generation-hd-32gb/-/A-78265687">Target</a></li>
<li><strong>Apple TV 4K</strong> <strong>| Price: </strong>$180 from <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-tv/apple-tv-4k/32gb">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0933D3SN6/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B0933D3SN6&amp;linkId=209c38d77b42fe4ab6d9d1de31f1d0e5">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/apple-tv-4k-32gb-black/5901530.p?skuId=5901530">Best Buy</a></li>
<li><strong>HomePod Mini | Price:</strong> $100 from <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-homepod/homepod-mini">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/apple-homepod-mini-space-gray/6377587.p?skuId=6377587">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://www.target.com/p/apple-homepod-mini/-/A-81643195">Target</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Control your regular devices with smart plugs</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2236125" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2236125" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2236125 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wemo-smart-plug.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="687" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wemo-smart-plug.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wemo-smart-plug.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wemo-smart-plug.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wemo-smart-plug.jpg?resize=768,516 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wemo-smart-plug.jpg?resize=680,457 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wemo-smart-plug.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2236125" class="wp-caption-text">Smart plugs can be used to control regular devices with physical power switches. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Smart plugs are a great way of connecting conventional electrical and appliances to your smart home. A smart plug fits between your regular appliance plug and the wall outlet and can be told to switch on and off at your command. It&#8217;s worth noting that smart plugs only work with devices and appliances with a physical power switch that stays in place and won&#8217;t work with devices with an auto-shutoff switch, like a kettle. (You probably shouldn&#8217;t rely on a smart plug for anything mission critical, like medical equipment or big household appliances.)</p>
<p>WeMo Wi-Fi Smart Plugs by Belkin have a small form factor compared to other, bulkier smart plugs and work reliably. There&#8217;s also a physical button on the side, in case you want or need to toggle it by hand. Eve Energy plugs are a little more expensive and also come with power management features in the Eve app but no physical button for backup.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>WeMo Wi-Fi Smart Plugs | Price: </strong>$25 from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08CJGZZZ1/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08CJGZZZ1&amp;linkId=38599f9675333144e18ea868c4a300f0">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/wemo-wifi-smart-plug-white/6401021.p?skuId=6401021">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://www.belkin.com/us/smart-home/wemo/wemo-wifi-smart-plug/p/p-wsp080/">Belkin Store</a></li>
<li><strong>Eve Energy | Price:</strong> $40 from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08YHPN63H/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08YHPN63H&amp;linkId=ce5f7c0a2ffc534932888ba07a7ec4b2">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/eve-energy-smart-plug-power-meter-with-built-in-schedules-apple-homekit-bluetooth-and-thread-white/6469243.p">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://www.evehome.com/en-us/store#energy">Eve Store</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Smart bulbs will light your home the way you want it</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2236126" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2236126" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2236126 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homekit-smart-bulbs.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="813" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homekit-smart-bulbs.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homekit-smart-bulbs.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homekit-smart-bulbs.jpg?resize=300,238 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homekit-smart-bulbs.jpg?resize=768,610 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homekit-smart-bulbs.jpg?resize=680,540 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/homekit-smart-bulbs.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2236126" class="wp-caption-text">You may be better off finding smart bulbs that fit your existing fixtures, rather than the most recommended brand. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Just like regular bulbs, smart bulbs come in all shapes, sizes and colors so you&#8217;re likely going to need to find a brand that suits your lights and fixtures. You may also need to mix and match brands as you expand your smart home. Most bulbs are dimmable and some offer granular temperature controls to get the warmth of the room right. <a href="https://us-shop.nanoleaf.me/products/nanoleaf-essentials-lightstrips">Nanoleaf</a> also offers bulbs that connect to HomeKit over Wi-Fi. Philips Hue is a popular favorite but requires a separate hub to talk to your <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/02/apple-debuts-a-new-home-app-website-to-show-how-its-devices-work-in-a-smart-home/">Home app</a>. LIFX also has a <a href="https://www.lifx.com">broad range of bulbs</a> and an accompanying app offering a few more features. Furniture giant IKEA has a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/23/ikeas-smart-light-bulbs-will-work-with-amazon-alexa-apple-siri-and-google-assistant/">diverse range of smart bulbs</a>. A common criticism of smart bulbs is that they often aren&#8217;t as bright as regular filament or LED bulbs, so keep that in mind if your home is particularly prone to low light.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>LIFX Mini White | Price:</strong> $10 from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0865TRD5L/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B0865TRD5L&amp;linkId=c6afc8fd82e817daa16cbdd989c9fb2a">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/lifx-a19-650-lumens-wi-fi-smart-led-bulbs-work-with-homekit-alexa-hey-google-and-more-2-pack-white/6424995.p">Best Buy</a></li>
<li><strong>Nanoleaf Essentials A19 | Price:</strong> $15 from <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPE62ZM/A/nanoleaf-essentials-a19-bulb">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/nanoleaf-essentials-a19-smart-thread-bluetooth-led-bulbs-3pk-white-and-colors-white/6473062.p">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://nanoleaf.me/en-US/products/nanoleaf-essentials/">Nanoleaf</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Set the mood with smart strip lighting</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2236127" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2236127" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2236127 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/home-strip-lighting.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="685" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/home-strip-lighting.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/home-strip-lighting.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/home-strip-lighting.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/home-strip-lighting.jpg?resize=768,514 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/home-strip-lighting.jpg?resize=680,455 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/home-strip-lighting.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2236127" class="wp-caption-text">Strip lighting can be themed, colorful and animated. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Zack Whittaker/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Adding color light strips to your smart home can really brighten up a space. Smart light strips are like regular strip lighting for under cabinets and shelves, but they can be controlled from your phone. These adhesive-backed strips contain dozens or hundreds of LEDs that let you customize their color and brightness, and often also their patterns and animations to bring reactive light to your rooms. You&#8217;ll need to keep in mind that most will require a power source, more often than not a wall outlet if not USB — many modern television sets should have one spare. We like the Nanoleaf Essentials Lightstrip Starter Kit to start with, or LIFX&#8217;s Lightstrip also does a great job; there&#8217;s one in my living room.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Nanoleaf Essentials Lightstrip Starter Kit | Price: </strong>$50 from <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPE52ZM/A/nanoleaf-essentials-80-lightstrip-starter-kit">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/nanoleaf-essentials-smart-led-lightstrip-starter-kit-2m--80-white-and-colors-white/6473080.p">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://us-shop.nanoleaf.me/collections/5-0-essentials-all/products/nanoleaf-essentials-lightstrips">Nanoleaf</a></li>
<li><strong>LIFX Color Zones Lightstrip | Price: </strong>$100 from<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09211Y24Q/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B09211Y24Q&amp;linkId=04c4075bceeaf7abbf94fb4ebbb2b389"> Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/lifx-lightstrip-color-zones-120/6459598.p">Best Buy</a>, <a href="https://www.homedepot.com/p/LIFX-80-in-Smart-Light-Strip-Kit-40-in-Strip-Light-2-Pack-LZ3SK2MUS/316926074">Home Depot</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>You can retrofit some of your older tech</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2237421" style="width: 849px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2237421" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2237421 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SOMA.jpg" alt="" width="839" height="767" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SOMA.jpg 839w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SOMA.jpg?resize=150,137 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SOMA.jpg?resize=300,274 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SOMA.jpg?resize=768,702 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SOMA.jpg?resize=680,622 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/SOMA.jpg?resize=50,46 50w" sizes="(max-width: 839px) 100vw, 839px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2237421" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SOMA</p></div></p>
<p>One of the best things about smart homes is how much you can do with your existing fittings. There are a handful of window blinds and shades made by well-known brands like <a href="https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/fyrtur-blackout-roller-blind-wireless-battery-operated-gray-30417460/">IKEA</a> (with a separate hub) or baked-in like Lutron&#8217;s <a href="https://www.serenashades.com/applehomekit/">Serena</a> that are natively compatible with HomeKit. Or if you have existing blinds, there are options to let you retrofit your existing window blinds with a HomeKit-enabled controller.</p>
<p>My house has vertical blinds with a tilt handle you have to rotate to close the blinds and so we rely on <a href="https://www.somasmarthome.com/">Soma</a>, an Estonia-based smart home device maker, which makes a number of blind controllers that fit into existing chains or tilt mechanisms. You hook them up to your blinds, remove the peel from the adhesive on the device, stick the box to the wall and you&#8217;re done — no skills required. These controllers run on battery or can be powered through the stick-on solar panel or plugged into an outlet. These controllers connect to HomeKit through a separate Raspberry Pi-like hub, the <a href="https://www.somasmarthome.com/products/soma-connect-blinds-control-for-amazon-alexa-apple-homekit-google-home">Soma Connect</a>. While my experience with Soma has been flawless, others at TechCrunch report having troubles with it — consider our reviews here &#8220;mixed.&#8221;</p>
<p>Blinds are just one area that can be retrofitted to work with HomeKit. Other tech exists to connect garage doors, ceiling fans and even <a href="https://www.evehome.com/en-us/eve-thermo">radiators</a> to your smart home, too.</p>
<h2>Get automating your home with sensors</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2234247" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2234247" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2234247 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/eve-door.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/eve-door.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/eve-door.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/eve-door.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/eve-door.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/eve-door.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/eve-door.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2234247" class="wp-caption-text">Sensors allow you to set up more automations for your smart home. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Eve Home</p></div></p>
<p>Now you have your lights and blinds hooked up to your Home app, you can start to add sensors to the mix. Sensors can let you automate your home by detecting light, movement, temperature, or if a window or door opens, and then turning on fans when it gets warm or setting the lights only when someone is home at sunset before it gets dark. Some might want to use these for security. They can be useful for power saving by shutting off lights when no motion is detected and adjusting the temperature when the weather changes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ONVIS-Hygrometer-Thermometer-Temperature-Bluetooth/dp/B07KY6747N">Onvis Motion</a> is a great, cheap, entry-level motion detector that also packs in a thermostat and hygrometer, so you can instantly get the temperature and humidity of the room that it&#8217;s in. Weather stations are more expensive but pack in a lot more features. <a href="https://www.evehome.com/en-us/eve-door-window">Eve Door &amp; Window</a> are small stick-on battery-powered sensors that can trigger an alert or any other connected HomeKit device when a door or window is opened. And, if you&#8217;re after a privacy-friendly camera, Logitech&#8217;s Circle View <a href="https://www.logitech.com/en-us/products/cameras/circle-view-security-camera.961-000489.html">works exclusively</a> on HomeKit&#8217;s end-to-end encrypted video and doesn&#8217;t rely on a third-party cloud, if that&#8217;s a deal breaker for the privacy-minded.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Onvis Motion | Price:</strong> $30 from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07KY6747N/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07KY6747N&amp;linkId=e86d2c56890c443942d5f7573b1c4e81">Amazon</a></li>
<li><strong>Eve Door &amp; Window |</strong> <strong>Price: </strong>$40 from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08BDM47S2/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B08BDM47S2&amp;linkId=33ee2985bb718e4753bcd164936f6e0c">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HKFX2VC/B/eve-door-window-wireless-contact-sensor">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/eve-door-window-smart-contact-sensor-with-apple-homekit-bluetooth-and-thread-white/6434931.p">Best Buy</a></li>
<li><strong>Logitech Circle View | Price: </strong>$160 from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B085HKNBSX/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B085HKNBSX&amp;linkId=20d32c4f0a7cc9d3e46a220c4a641929">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HNRE2VC/A/logitech-circle-view-apple-homekit-enabled-security-camera">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.logitech.com/en-us/products/cameras/circle-view-security-camera.961-000489.html">Logitech</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Your Home app is your smart home dashboard</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2236128" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2236128" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2236128 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ios-homekit-screenshot.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="887" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ios-homekit-screenshot.jpg 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ios-homekit-screenshot.jpg?resize=150,130 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ios-homekit-screenshot.jpg?resize=300,260 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ios-homekit-screenshot.jpg?resize=768,665 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ios-homekit-screenshot.jpg?resize=680,589 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/ios-homekit-screenshot.jpg?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2236128" class="wp-caption-text">The Home app, which lets you control your HomeKit smart home from anywhere in the world. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>One of the benefits to picking one ecosystem and sticking with it: For the most part, the most important features of each device will be aggregated into one app. With HomeKit, that&#8217;s the Home app.</p>
<p>Your Home app consolidates your HomeKit-enabled smart home tech in one place and lets you connect your sensors to automate the rest of your home. With window sensors you can turn on all of your lights as soon as you open the door, and you can set your strip lighting to light up a hallway when a sensor detects motion between sunset and sunrise.</p>
<p>The Home app also packs in some automation features, like switching on fans or opening blinds at certain times of the day when you know it&#8217;s going to be bright outside or at a time you know you&#8217;ll want privacy. Most devices also come with a corresponding app, often with a lot more settings, features and the ability to update the device&#8217;s firmware.</p>
<p>And that is your starter HomeKit smart home!</p>
<h2>Some things to think about:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Wi-Fi network range is critical to a functioning smart home. HomeKit works on the 2.4 GHz wireless connection because it has a longer range than 5 GHz. There&#8217;s a good chance your router allows you to use both, but make sure you&#8217;re on the right network when setting up your HomeKit devices. Network coverage might be fine in a one-bedroom apartment, but larger homes may require Wi-Fi range extenders or a mesh network.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>If you have a router that&#8217;s set up for self-organizing networking, which lets you move seamlessly between the different Wi-Fi bands, you might want to switch that setting off since it can interfere with your smart home. Some routers may have a dedicated Wi-Fi network for IoT devices built in.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Sometimes things will break and it&#8217;s not always clear why. Sometimes it&#8217;s just a moment of poor connectivity, sometimes in the more frustrating cases you might need to reset your devices. Each device comes with its own scannable QR code for getting set up. Keep these codes safe since you&#8217;ll need them if you ever have to reset a device and especially helpful when you can&#8217;t easily access or scan your HomeKit devices.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>You can customize your Home screen and room backgrounds. <a href="https://homepaper.app/">HomePaper</a> is a simple app that does exactly that, and it&#8217;s designed to gradually fade the background so it&#8217;s not intrusive or make the device panels difficult to read. Home wallpapers don&#8217;t sync across your Apple devices, so you have to manually add wallpapers to each Home app.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/19/anybody-can-now-make-homekit-accessories/">Anybody can now make HomeKit accessories</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/18/apple-debuts-a-4-99-per-month-apple-music-voice-plan-designed-mainly-for-homepod-use/">Apple debuts $4.99 monthly Apple Music Voice plan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-tv-to-support-using-homepod-mini-as-speakers-among-other-updates/">Apple TV to support using HomePod Mini as speakers, among other updates</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-announces-icloud-with-privacy-focused-features/">Apple announces iCloud+ with privacy-focused features</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/gift-guide-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/gift-guide-2021-banner.jpg" alt="TechCrunch Gift Guide 2021" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/smart-home-gift-guide-ideas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234206</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voyager Space Holdings to acquire majority stake in Space Micro</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-space-micro/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-space-micro/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 18:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space micro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voyager Space Holdings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Voyager Space Holdings is continuing its trend of snapping up space companies by moving to acquire a majority stake in Space Micro, a manufacturer of orbital communications and digital subsystems for satellites. This is Voyager’s sixth acquisition since its founding in October 2019, as the company seeks to become a full-service space firm offering everything [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://voyagerspace.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Voyager Space Holdings</a> is continuing its trend of snapping up space companies by moving to acquire a majority stake in <a href="https://www.spacemicro.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Space Micro</a>, a manufacturer of orbital communications and digital subsystems for satellites.</p>
<p>This is Voyager’s sixth acquisition since its founding in October 2019, as the company seeks to become a full-service space firm offering everything from robotics to launch support to communications tech.</p>
<p>Previous acquisitions include X.O. Markets, the parent of commercial space service venture <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/voyager-space-holdings-sets-it-sights-on-space-stations-with-majority-stake-in-nanoracks/">Nanoracks</a>; Pioneer Astronautics, a company that conducts research into supporting human life in outer space; robotics startup Altius Space Machines; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-multi-launch-site-startup-the-launch-company/">The Launch Company</a>, a launch support company.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238132" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The acquisition strategy has turned Voyager Space into something of a powerhouse; despite being scarcely two years old, the company has already set its sights on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/">launching a commercial space station in 2027</a>. The plans, which were announced as part of a joint project with Nanoracks and Lockheed Martin, position Voyager to oversee financing and capital allocation for the project.</p>
<p>Whether Space Micro’s tech will be used on that station isn’t clear, but the investment will no doubt provide support for the subsystems manufacturer to scale operations and its product output.</p>
<p>“Today marks a huge step in our growth trajectory,” Space Micro co-founder and chair David Strobel said in a statement. “The satellite constellation market stands at the tipping point of explosive expansion and now, with the Voyager team and operational functions by our side, we will be prepared to scale our technologies to meet these market needs.”</p>
<p>Space Micro has built out a large portfolio of customers since its founding in 2002, including NASA, the U.S. Space Force, the U.S. Air Force and the German Space Agency. The company currently has more than 100 subsystems in orbit and has collectively racked up 2.7 million hours of spaceflight time.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company has provided tech for NASA’s Lunar Atmosphere Dust and Environment Explorer mission and its Transiting Explanet Survey Satellite. Space Micro also works with commercial companies, and was selected by Masten Space Systems earlier this year to provide transponders for the company’s XL-1 lunar lander.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/voyager-space-holdings-to-acquire-majority-stake-in-space-micro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NFT music rights startup Royal banks $55M investment led by a16z Crypto</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/nft-music-rights-startup-royal-banks-55m-investment-from-a16z-crypto/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/nft-music-rights-startup-royal-banks-55m-investment-from-a16z-crypto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 18:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Dixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katie Haun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naithan jones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenDoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paradigm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Less than three months after announcing a $16 million seed round led by Founders Fund and Paradigm, NFT music rights startup Royal has raised another major round of funding, banking a $55 million Series A from Andreessen Horowitz&#8217;s crypto investment arm. The startup partners with musicians and allows users to buy NFTs which represent collective [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Less than three months after announcing a $16 million seed round led by Founders Fund and Paradigm, NFT music rights startup <a href="https://royal.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Royal</a> has raised another major round of funding, banking a $55 million Series A from Andreessen Horowitz&#8217;s crypto investment arm.</p>
<p>The startup partners with musicians and allows users to buy NFTs which represent collective ownership in works from those artists. The effort is helmed by Justin Blau, an EDM artist who performs under the name 3LAU, and JD Ross, a co-founder of home-buying startup Opendoor. Royal represents a very early, but promising foray into NFT functionality outside the spheres of visual art and gaming.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="x5cmzfHtkC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/founders-fund-backs-royal-a-music-marketplace-planning-to-sell-song-rights-as-nfts/">Founders Fund backs Royal, a music marketplace planning to sell song rights as NFTs</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238085" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Founders Fund backs Royal, a music marketplace planning to sell song rights as NFTs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/founders-fund-backs-royal-a-music-marketplace-planning-to-sell-song-rights-as-nfts/embed/#?secret=x5cmzfHtkC" data-secret="x5cmzfHtkC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Last month, Blau gave away hundreds of NFTs through the platform, which held 50% of the streaming rights to his latest song. The startup says there have already been nearly $600,000 worth of secondary sales for those tokens, giving the new single an implied $6 million valuation. Crypto-friendly musicians like Blau have already banked millions from crypto holders looking to diversify their holding through NFTs while also backing projects that expand the market opportunity of the blockchain.</p>
<p>Boundary-pushing projects like Royal still have a delicate line to walk when it comes to advertising opportunities to grow alongside artists while staying compliant with securities laws.</p>
<p>This investment is notably being helmed by a16z Crypto co-lead Katie Haun who sits on the boards of Coinbase and NFT marketplace OpenSea. The firm already has a deep relationship with Royal&#8217;s executive team, having previously backed Ross&#8217;s last company Opendoor. Naithan Jones, a former Andreessen Horowitz partner who led the team&#8217;s Talent X Opportunity Fund, also joined Royal in September as the firm&#8217;s head of Growth.</p>
<p>Joining the round alongside a16z Crypto are a number of musical artists, including The Chainsmokers, Nas, Logic and Kygo. CAA and NEA’s Connect Ventures, Crush Music, Coinbase Ventures, Founders Fund and Paradigm also participated in the round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fle99HslaH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/crypto-vc-firm-paradigm-debuts-monster-2-5-billion-fund/">Crypto VC firm Paradigm debuts monster $2.5 billion fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crypto VC firm Paradigm debuts monster $2.5 billion fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/crypto-vc-firm-paradigm-debuts-monster-2-5-billion-fund/embed/#?secret=fle99HslaH" data-secret="fle99HslaH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/nft-music-rights-startup-royal-banks-55m-investment-from-a16z-crypto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238085</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU retail giant Schwarz Group snags security startup XM Cyber for $700 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/eu-retail-giant-schwarz-group-snags-security-startup-xm-cyber-for-700-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/eu-retail-giant-schwarz-group-snags-security-startup-xm-cyber-for-700-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 18:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schwarz group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xm cyber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Schwarz Group, an EU-based retail company, announced today that it has acquired Israeli security startup XM Cyber for $700 million. It may seem like a strange partnership, as Schwarz is best known as the owners of the Lidl and Kaufland supermarkets, but the company believes that extending into security will ultimately help benefit its retail [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://gruppe.schwarz/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Schwarz Group</a>, an EU-based retail company, announced today that it has acquired Israeli security startup <a href="https://xmcyber.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">XM Cyber</a> for $700 million. It may seem like a strange partnership, as Schwarz is best known as the owners of the Lidl and Kaufland supermarkets, but the company believes that extending into security will ultimately help benefit its retail business.</p>
<p>XM helps customers simulate what an attack could look like to expose flaws and openings in a company&#8217;s security posture with the goal of shutting down vulnerabilities before an actual cyberattack happens.</p>
<p>Christian Müller, chief information officer at Schwarz Group, says that adding a security piece to the portfolio is essential, especially as more shopping moves online. &#8220;Finding and closing security gaps from an attacker’s perspective is a disruptive approach to the way organizations can proactively protect their networks. XM Cyber&#8217;s solution builds on our strong IT security to further protect our customers, partners and ourselves as a company,&#8221; Müller said in a statement.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238042" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Meanwhile, XM Cyber CEO and co-founder Noam Erez sees the advantages of being part of a large corporation, even if it lacks a technology focus. &#8220;For XM Cyber customers, this means that with the financial backing of Schwarz, we will be able to accelerate product innovation, scale and extend our global reach. For Schwarz customers, with their continued investment in their digital product range, the ability to secure suppliers, consumers and businesses is a key enabler in delivering on the promise of digital transformation,&#8221; Erez said.</p>
<p>Perhaps not surprisingly, Schwarz intends to let XM continue to operate as an independent entity under the terms of the deal and all 110 employees will keep their jobs, meaning that existing customers should likely see little change in how things operate.</p>
<p>Perhaps they will get the advantage of XM being part of the larger company as Erez says, so long as the parent company doesn&#8217;t make any significant changes behind the scenes, but some customers may also be put off by the company being owned by a non-tech entity. Time will tell on that front.</p>
<p>XM Cyber was founded in 2016 and raised $49 million, according to Crunchbase data. The most recent deal was a $17 million Series B in July led by Macquarie Capital.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/eu-retail-giant-schwarz-group-snags-security-startup-xm-cyber-for-700-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AutoCloud raises $4M to commercialize its OSS cloud visualization service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/autocloud-raises-4m-to-commercialize-its-oss-cloud-visualization-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/autocloud-raises-4m-to-commercialize-its-oss-cloud-visualization-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 18:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animo Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autocloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b capital group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moxxie Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncorrelated Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AutoCloud announced a $4 million seed round this morning. The cloud-focused startup&#8217;s investment was led by Animo Ventures, with participating checks from Uncorrelated Ventures, B Capital Group and Moxxie Ventures. AutoCloud is the commercial side of the CloudGraph open source project. The hybrid open source (OSS) and commercial combination is an increasingly popular startup method [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.autocloud.dev/">AutoCloud</a> announced a $4 million seed round this morning. The cloud-focused startup&#8217;s investment was led by <a href="https://animo.vc/">Animo Ventures</a>, with participating checks from <a href="https://uncorrelated.com/">Uncorrelated Ventures</a>, <a href="https://www.bcapgroup.com/">B Capital Group </a>and <a href="https://www.moxxie.vc/">Moxxie Ventures</a>.</p>
<p>AutoCloud is the commercial side of the <a href="https://www.cloudgraph.dev/">CloudGraph</a> open source project. The hybrid open source (OSS) and commercial combination is an increasingly popular startup method of attacking markets. Hashicorp <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/hashicorps-ipo-filing-reveals-a-growing-business-but-at-a-slower-pace/">recently went public</a> partially on the strength of its OSS core. This morning, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/jina-ai-raises-30m-for-its-for-its-neural-search-platform/">Jina.ai announced</a> a $30 million raise for its commercial and open source approach to neural search, for a more early-stage example.</p>
<p>CloudGraph is an OSS tool that ingests usage data from multiple cloud providers &#8212; think AWS, Azure, etc. &#8212; standardizes it, and makes it queryable using GraphQL (a technology that is itself seeing more use and positive opinion, per the <a href="https://2020.stateofjs.com/en-US/technologies/">State of Javascript 2020 report</a>).</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238041" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>AutoCloud sits atop CloudGraph, offering automated data ingestions, security compliance and cloud resource visualization. The company&#8217;s co-founder and CEO, <a href="https://twitter.com/tysonkunovsky">Tyson Kunovsky,</a> told TechCrunch that his company&#8217;s goal is akin to what Hashicorp and others have done, taking a piece of work that the large cloud platforms are doing poorly and improving the experience.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2238069" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2238069" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2238069 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="221" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg 3586w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?resize=150,111 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?resize=300,221 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?resize=768,567 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?resize=680,502 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?resize=1536,1133 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?resize=2048,1511 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AutoCloud_founders-1.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2238069" class="wp-caption-text">The AutoCloud founding team. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> AutoCloud</p></div></p>
<p>As with all OSS projects that may succeed, its goal is to offer something useful to the market as open code and build a commercial business atop what&#8217;s generally available. In the case of AutoCloud, that&#8217;s a SaaS model that will feature pricing tiers based on the number of assets tracked.</p>
<p>The startup is early, so we don&#8217;t have traditional traction metrics to cite &#8212; revenue growth, net dollar retention, that sort of thing. Kunovsky told TechCrunch that his firm has been largely focused on CloudGraph itself, but that hundreds of users of the OSS service found AutoCloud via the project&#8217;s readme and have signed up for its waitlist.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>AutoCloud intends to turn on its paid product before the end of 2021, which is mere weeks away. So, the next time that we talk to the company, we can harangue it about revenue growth and related metrics.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that Chicago-based AutoCloud is a standard startup of the day in that it has a team in multiple locations, including Argentina and Chile.</p>
<p>Kunovsky has big aspirations for the company. AutoCloud, he explained, wants to take things from the cloud command line and term them into a graphical user interface, or GUI. That&#8217;s no small task.</p>
<p>Given that AutoCloud has a multi-cloud approach to the market, it doesn&#8217;t seem <em>too</em> likely that Amazon or Microsoft or the Google cloud team will attack its market directly. But perhaps another cloud infra provider might noodle into its space in time. At that point, how strong the CloudGraph project has become on its own will be a key deciding point in whether AutoCloud can or cannot compete with more incumbent tech companies.</p>
<p>Regardless, add the AutoCloud round to your OSS scorecard. More when it inevitably raises again in the next quarter or two.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/autocloud-raises-4m-to-commercialize-its-oss-cloud-visualization-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238041</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Culture lands $25 million in seed funding to commercialize its cheesy vegan mozzarella</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/new-culture-lands-25-million-in-seed-funding-to-commercialize-its-cheesy-vegan-mozzarella/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/new-culture-lands-25-million-in-seed-funding-to-commercialize-its-cheesy-vegan-mozzarella/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 18:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ahren Innovation Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CPT Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Led by sales of cheddar and mozzarella, the U.S. cheese market alone was valued at $34.3 billion in 2019, and is projected to reach $45.5 billion by 2027, growing at a compound annual growth rate of 5.25%, according to Allied Market Research. By comparison, the vegan cheese industry is tiny, measuring around $1.2 billion in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Led by sales of cheddar and mozzarella, the U.S. cheese market alone was valued at $34.3 billion in 2019, and is projected to reach <a href="https://www.alliedmarketresearch.com/us-cheese-market" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$45.5 billion</a> by 2027, growing at a compound annual growth rate of 5.25%, according to Allied Market Research.</p>
<p>By comparison, the vegan cheese industry is tiny, measuring around $1.2 billion in size in 2019 and projected to reach <a href="https://www.alliedmarketresearch.com/vegan-cheese-market-A07197" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$4.4 billion</a> by 2027, per Allied&#8217;s findings.</p>
<p>That massive gap hasn&#8217;t stopped a syndicate of investors from plowing $25 million in seed funding into <a href="https://www.newculturefood.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New Culture</a>, a company that sells &#8220;cow cheese, without the cow.&#8221; On the contrary, its investors think the three-year-old, Bay Area-based startup can grow the market meaningfully through an animal-free mozzarella that, according to investor Steve Jurvetson, tastes, smells and stretches like milk cheese, unlike most vegan cheese, which he describes as &#8220;quite disgusting to date.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237873" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The missing ingredient, says Jurvetson, has been the casein protein of milk, which, until now, could only be had from milk. Meanwhile, New Culture says through a precision fermentation process, it is producing large amounts of casein protein. As an <a href="https://vegnews.com/2021/6/vegan-dairy-identical-cheese" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earlier report</a> in VegNews better describes it, New Culture, using giant fermentation tanks, is inserting DNA sequences into microbes that effectively instruct them to express the target proteins (alpha caseins, kappa caseins and beta caseins) after feeding on a sugar solution.</p>
<p>The company then collects the casein &#8212; which it blends with water, plant-based fats, vitamins and minerals &#8212; to make mozzarella.</p>
<p>The end product is healthier, says Jurvetson, noting that it&#8217;s both cholesterol and lactose-free. It&#8217;s also far better for the environment. Indeed, it requires an estimated <a href="https://www.watereducation.org/post/food-facts-how-much-water-does-it-take-produce" target="_blank" rel="noopener">56 gallons of water</a> to produce just one ounce of dairy-based cheese. (New Culture will also require far less land use, obviously.)</p>
<p>Note that you won&#8217;t find New Culture&#8217;s mozzarella in your neighborhood grocery store &#8212; not yet anyway. The plan is to first distribute its cheese through pizzerias around the country beginning next year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Eventually, says New Cultures co-founder and CEO, Matt Gibson &#8212; a New Zealander who studied genetics and microbiology and who previously founded and sold an education review site &#8212; the company could well make yogurts, ice cream and even milk, though he stressed that, for the foreseeable future, the focus is very much on mozzarella.</p>
<p>New Culture&#8217;s round was led by Ahren Innovation Capital and CPT Capital. Other new investors include ADM Ventures, Be8 Ventures, S2G Ventures, Marinya Capital and Future Ventures, run by Jurvetson and partner Maryanna Saenko.</p>
<p>Earlier backers also participated in the financing, including SOSV, Bee Partners, Mayfield, Bluestein Ventures and Evolv Ventures, which is the corporate venture arm of Kraft Heinz.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/new-culture-lands-25-million-in-seed-funding-to-commercialize-its-cheesy-vegan-mozzarella/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237873</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Riot Games&#8217; new esports president on NBA collaboration, its hit Netflix series and NFTs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/riot-games-new-esports-president-on-nba-collaboration-its-hit-netflix-series-and-nfts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/riot-games-new-esports-president-on-nba-collaboration-its-hit-netflix-series-and-nfts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Needham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Riot Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amid a spectacle staged during the Golden State Warriors versus Toronto Raptors game on November 21, Riot Games&#8217; new esports president John Needham sent League of Legends T-shirts parachuting down onto a packed stadium of sports fans while a cinematic trailer announced the return of one of the world’s largest esports tournaments to North America. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amid a spectacle staged during the Golden State Warriors versus Toronto Raptors game on November 21, Riot Games&#8217; new esports president John Needham sent League of Legends T-shirts parachuting down onto a packed stadium of sports fans while a cinematic trailer announced the return of one of the world’s largest esports tournaments to North America.</p>
<p>It was the culmination of a day when dozens of the global press were gathered to tour the state-of-the-art Chase Center in San Francisco, the venue where the 2022 League of Legends World Championship finals will be held next November.</p>
<p>“We haven’t been in North America with major international events since 2016 and haven’t been able to come back the past few years due to travel restrictions around COVID,” Needham told TechCrunch. “We’re just very excited to be doing live events again and want fans to know that they can expect a thrilling production the likes of the Super Bowl halftime show.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238015" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It’s been more than a decade since Riot held its first World Championships in 2011, known as Worlds. The multiplayer online battle game boasts more than 180 million monthly active players and 10 franchise League of Legends teams, each with NBA ownership ties. NBA all stars like <a href="https://bleacherreport.com/articles/2787665-stephen-curry-invests-in-esports-organization-tsm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steph Curry</a>, <a href="https://www.espn.com/esports/story/_/id/25080676/michael-jordan-invests-team-liquid-parent-company" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Michael Jordan and Magic Johnson</a> are team investors, along with others from the Golden State Warriors, Los Angeles Lakers, Houston Rockets, Cleveland Cavaliers, Milwaukee Bucks, Memphis Grizzlies, New York Knicks, Philadelphia 76ers, Washington Wizards and Charlotte Hornets.</p>
<p>With 73.8 million fans watching the Worlds finals in 2021, up from 46 million in 2020, according to Needham, League of Legends esports tournaments have become big business, drawing in major brands like Louis Vuitton, AXE by Unilever, Spotify, Bose, Mercedes-Benz, Red Bull and Coca-Cola.</p>
<p>“We partner with brands to bring value to our fans and have found that when we do there is a joint brand lifting that often occurs. Brands get access to our valuable, hard to reach Gen Z demographic while we gain credibility being partnered with them,” said Needham. “When Louis Vuitton created its first <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/league-of-legends/true-damage-skins" target="_blank" rel="noopener">digital fashion line</a> for us, it added to our fans’ game experience<em>. </em>These types of skins are so popular that they are the foundation of our business model and generate, by far, the most revenue for us.”</p>
<p>Riot’s massive fan base has also proven to be an asset in the company’s pursuit to become a global entertainment powerhouse.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On November 6, the trailer for Riot’s first Netflix series, Arcane, was played during the Worlds finals as nearly 74 million fans tuned in. It also did a promotion for <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/league-of-legends-jinx-fortnite-skin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arcane in Fortnite</a>, a game with more than <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/6/21249497/fortnite-350-million-registered-players-hours-played-april" target="_blank" rel="noopener">350 million registered players</a>, partially owned by Riot’s parent company, Tencent. Within days, Arcane shot to the top of Netflix charts, <a href="https://top10.netflix.com/tv/2021-11-14.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hitting the No. 2 spot</a> for the week of November 8, with more than 34 million viewers.</p>
<p>Having a bigger presence in Europe and Asia than in North America, Needham sees the 2022 Worlds tour as a way to create renewed interest in the game.</p>
<p>“We’ve had over 600 million players around the world who have enjoyed the League of Legends universe since inception. For those who have churned and are not currently playing the game, we hope to reactivate them as we canvas across North America, from Mexico City for the play-ins, to New York City for the quarter finals, to Toronto for the semifinals, to San Francisco for the finals.”</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2238019,2238020,2238021,2238022,2238215"]</p>
<h2></h2>
<p>Despite Riot’s interest in venturing onto new platforms, Needham says there are no plans to jump into the metaverse.</p>
<p>“We have a lot of partners who want to do NFTs with us that we’re analyzing right now, but there isn’t an NFT or blockchain strategy for us to talk about yet. Collectibles just haven’t been a big part of esports, not like traditional sports,” he said. “I want to see the NFT market mature a bit more before we dive in from an esports perspective.”</p>
<p>He added that Riot has no plans to partner with Netflix Gaming or Roblox, either.</p>
<p><em>Correction: Removed Fenty by Rihanna, as the brand is not an esports sponsor.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/riot-games-new-esports-president-on-nba-collaboration-its-hit-netflix-series-and-nfts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238015</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wave brings some science and sanity to the business of mental health</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/wave-pre-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/wave-pre-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 17:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hannah Grey VC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wave]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2236279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The kids aren&#8217;t alright. According to the founders of Wave, 75% of Gen Z is struggling with their emotional well-being. To be clear &#8212; not all of them are meeting the criteria for diagnosable mental health illnesses, but they do need a bit more than a firm handshake and a &#8220;keep going, son.&#8221; That&#8217;s the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The kids aren&#8217;t alright. According to the founders of <a href="https://www.wavelife.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wave</a>, 75% of Gen Z is struggling with their emotional well-being. To be clear &#8212; not all of them are meeting the criteria for diagnosable mental health illnesses, but they do need a bit more than a firm handshake and a &#8220;keep going, son.&#8221; That&#8217;s the market Wave is primarily going after with its digital platform, which is taking an inclusivity-first approach to making tools and techniques available to young adults.</p>
<p>The app is launching to a public test audience early next year, and with a broader launch to a wider group of consumers later in the year. The company&#8217;s founder is Dr. Sarah Adler, a Stanford Professor of Psychiatry and Clinical Psychologist. She is eager to tell the world about what the app will do, but is playing her cards a little guardedly until the app becomes available to the wider public. Adler has spent her career building innovative delivery models to increase access to care through user-centered design. She believes that data-informed, digital solutions paired with well-trained, lower-cost human capital, like health coaches, is the best way to deliver quality care at scale, especially for overlooked populations (think <a href="https://lgbta.wikia.org/wiki/GSRD" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GSRM</a> and BIPOC) traditionally left out of the conversation.</p>
<p>I asked Dr. Adler to give an example of the type of exercises the app would be able to provide.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2236279" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;One of the things that we fundamentally believe is and this comes from Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT), which is an evidence-based treatment for anxiety and depression. We believe that a lot of the poor decisions that we make in life, or the decisions that don&#8217;t make us feel really good, we do because of a lack of clarity about what&#8217;s important to us. A values clarification exercise is an exercise that you might do with your therapist if you have one, and you can afford to pay $250 an hour to do that. What we&#8217;ve done is we designed one that is much more engaging. It&#8217;s a video game-like experience where you&#8217;re going through a values clarification exercise, and at the end of it, we&#8217;ve evoked the emotion that we want to evoke neurochemically in your brain, the same way that you would do if you were sitting with me in a therapy session,&#8221; explains Dr. Adler. &#8220;When you have clarity on your values, you can start to piece together how to make decisions. What are the actions that I want to take, that are aligned with my greater values? Do I want to go out and binge drink with my friends tonight? By knowing my longer-term goals and values, I can reconcile my behaviors. That helps me make decisions.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company just announced it closed a $2 million pre-seed round late this summer. The round was led by <a href="https://www.hannahgrey.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hannah Grey VC</a>, with participation from <a href="https://www.k50ventures.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K50 Ventures</a>, <a href="https://tribecap.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tribe Capital</a>, <a href="https://www.av.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alumni Venture Group</a>, <a href="https://verissimo.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Verissimo Ventures</a>, <a href="https://conscience.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Conscience VC</a> and select strategic angels.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a ton of funding pouring into mental health, over $2.5 billion in 2020 alone, to build and scale products that aren’t backed in science, not deeply mired in inclusive user experience, and not showing repeatable outcomes,&#8221; says Dr. Adler. &#8220;At Wave we aren’t just interested in the business metrics: the downloads, sign-ups and pilots, we are building for tangible results, with measurable outcomes for people who traditionally can’t get care.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re not fighting social media. We&#8217;re trying to integrate it with it. We believe that in order to address and engage these users, we need to meet them where they are &#8212; especially true for a generation that&#8217;s entirely tied to their phones. We call it our digital ecosystem and it integrates all of the best evidence-based content with immersive experiences that borrow from the best video game technology. I don&#8217;t mean token economies; what I mean is what the video game industry has learned about how to keep people engaged with things they have to learn,&#8221; explains Dr. Adler. &#8220;We create these immersive experiences and deliver them in a way that keeps people coming back to use it. Ultimately, that helps them get better.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/wave-pre-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2236279</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM acquires 25% stake in electric boat company Pure Watercraft</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/gm-acquires-25-stake-in-electric-boat-company-pure-watercraft/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/gm-acquires-25-stake-in-electric-boat-company-pure-watercraft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 17:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric boats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pure Watercraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[General Motors has taken a 25% stake in Seattle-based electric boating company Pure Watercraft. GM&#8217;s move reflects a broadening interest in all things EV, including boats and other vehicles, and comes as part of the automaker’s commitment to invest $35 billion in electric and autonomous technology through 2025. Pure Watercraft makes all-electric outboard motor systems, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">General Motors has taken a 25% stake in Seattle-based electric boating company <a href="https://www.purewatercraft.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pure Watercraft</a>. GM&#8217;s move reflects a broadening interest in all things EV, including boats and other vehicles, and comes as part of the automaker’s commitment to invest $35 billion in electric and autonomous technology through 2025.</p>
<p>Pure Watercraft makes all-electric outboard motor systems, which it calls Pure Outboard, that can be used as a drop-in replacement for boats that would use a 25 to 50 horsepower gas-powered motor. The company has also partnered with major boat manufacturers to sell complete electric boats, including a pontoon barge, fishing boat and two rigid inflatable boats.</p>
<p>Pure Watercraft says its electric systems require zero maintenance compared to gas engines, in addition to eliminating fossil fuel pollution. The range is also likely to suit a pretty wide range of consumer use cases &#8212; the company notes on its website that Pure Outboard could support a nearly four-hour, 20-mile fishing trip with 15% charge to spare.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237997" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/22/pure-watercraft-ramps-up-its-electric-outboard-motors-with-a-23m-series-a/">a $23 million Series A</a> led by L37 last September to spin up production, nine years after the company was founded by CEO Andy Rebele. With this latest investment from GM, the two companies will co-develop and commercialize battery technology, “integrating GM technology into a variety of applications,” the automaker said in a statement.</p>
<p>This is just the latest signal that electric technologies are starting to move far beyond road vehicles or even aircraft, to transportation and mobility formats that have continued to be dominated by conventional gas propulsion. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/will-smith-kevin-durant-and-sean-diddy-combs-invest-in-electric-boat-startup-arc/">Ten-month-old electric watercraft startup Arc</a> has raised $7 million in total funding, including bringing on several new investors last month. Seattle startup <a href="https://www.zinboats.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zin Boats</a> is also developing an electric speedboat.</p>
<p>It’s also a noteworthy move for GM, which is already exploring ways to use its technology in other mobility industries, like rail and aerospace. Earlier this year, the company partnered with Wabtec to develop electric freight locomotives using hydrogen fuel and batteries. GM also announced a partnership with Liebherr-Aerospace to jointly develop a hydrogen fuel cell demonstration system for aircraft.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/gm-acquires-25-stake-in-electric-boat-company-pure-watercraft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237997</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Analogue&#8217;s Pocket retro gaming handheld console ships on December 13</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/analogues-pocket-retro-gaming-handheld-console-ships-on-december-14/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/analogues-pocket-retro-gaming-handheld-console-ships-on-december-14/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 17:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analogue pocket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retro gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2238016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Analogue, the retro gaming hardware company behind the excellent Nt Mini, Super Nt, Mega Sg and more, has announced a shipping date for its much-anticipated Analogue Pocket handheld: December 13. The portable console, which has support for Game Boy, Game Boy Color and Game Boy Advance cartridges out of the box, has been delayed due [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Analogue, the retro gaming hardware company behind the excellent Nt Mini, Super Nt, Mega Sg and more, has announced a shipping date for its much-anticipated <a href="https://www.analogue.co/pocket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Analogue Pocket handheld</a>: December 13. The portable console, which has support for Game Boy, Game Boy Color and Game Boy Advance cartridges out of the box, has been delayed due to COVID and supply constraints, but the company says all preorders will now ship out on December 13, with anticipated delivery dates between December 14 and December 30.</p>
<p>The Analogue Pocket looks to be a fantastic retro gaming experience, with a 3.5&#8243; LCD display that operates at a resolution of 1600&#215;1440, for a total display density of 615 PPI. In addition to supporting the range of Game Boy titles, it also works with adapters to support Game Gear, Neo Geo Pocket Color and Atari Lynx cartridges, too. On top of its gaming chops, the console has a built-in digital audio workstation called Nanoloop that acts as both synthesizer and sequencer for music creation.</p>
<p>Analogue&#8217;s major technical achievement, besides the hardware design, is the creation of FPGA chips that allow it to run natively the game cartridges it supports, just as they were originally intended &#8212; crucially not in emulation mode. This means it&#8217;s a reference quality gaming experience for purists, with screen modes to support replication of the original hardware experience for hardcore gamers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2238016" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>On top of everything else, the $199.99 Analogue Pocket also supports accessories like the Analogue Dock, which provides 1080p output to a connected TV, as well as support for connecting up to 4 8BitDo controllers for local multiplayer via wired or wireless connections. The console itself also offers up to 10 hours of gameplay via its internal battery, and USB-C charging.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/analogues-pocket-retro-gaming-handheld-console-ships-on-december-14/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2238016</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fractional lands $5.5 million to let friends (and strangers) invest in real estate together</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/fractional-lands-5-5-million-to-let-friends-and-strangers-invest-in-real-estate-together/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/fractional-lands-5-5-million-to-let-friends-and-strangers-invest-in-real-estate-together/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fractional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237702</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As teammates at buy now, pay later fintech Affirm, Stella Han and Carlos Treviño bonded over their shared background of growing up in real estate families. The mission of &#8220;pay at your own pace&#8221; at Affirm clashed with their firsthand experience of the taxing time commitment and high costs that comes with owning real estate; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Output copied to clipboard! --></p>
<p>As teammates at buy now, pay later fintech Affirm, <a href="https://twitter.com/hellastellah" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stella Han</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/rlostrevino?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Carlos Treviño</a> bonded over their shared background of growing up in real estate families. The mission of &#8220;pay at your own pace&#8221; at Affirm clashed with their firsthand experience of the taxing time commitment and high costs that comes with owning real estate; a contrast that eventually seeded the idea for Fractional.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.fractional.app/">Fractional</a>, a San Francisco-based startup, wants to make real estate ownership more accessible. The platform, which participated in Y Combinator’s Winter 2021 batch, helps people co-own investment properties with friends and strangers. It takes out some of the logistical challenges of finding property, and also removes financial barriers by allowing people to put smaller checks into a collective that will then invest into a property.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237702" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The vision has brought over 400 users to its beta, who have gone on to co-invest across 95 properties. It’s also brought millions in early funding to the team: Fractional announced today that it has raised $5.5 million in total funding at a $30 million valuation. Fractional&#8217;s seed round is led by CRV, but includes Y Combinator, Will Smith, Kevin Durant, Goodwater Capital, Unusual Ventures, Global Founders Capital, On Deck, Contrary Capital and Soma Capital.</p>
<p>Fractional divides the home ownership process into three main parts. First, the startup either matches together co-owners or onboards a friend group to kickstart the underwriting process, which blends well with the co-founder’s experience at Affirm. Then, it helps facilitate the purchase through legal and financial software services. Finally, it partners with property management companies and other services to make sure the co-owned homes stay in good shape (without the time commitment from its new co-owners).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ppnjnZKqma"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/community-is-the-new-ai/">Community is the new AI</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Community is the new AI&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/08/community-is-the-new-ai/embed/#?secret=ppnjnZKqma" data-secret="ppnjnZKqma" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While Fractional certainly alleviates some of the financial hurdles of real estate ownership, friends may stray away from getting into business with each other due to the sheer pressure it can put on a relationship. What if life circumstances cause one person to want to sell before others? Or another refuses to upgrade the kitchen?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Despite their backgrounds, the co-founders know that scaling access as a service within real estate is uniquely complex. So, Han and Treviño pooled together cash and bought a plot of land in Mexico to more closely understand the process. Treviño’s family owns a construction business in Mexico, so the duo was able to find an off-market deal for a good price and eventually build a retail storefront on the property. But, as Han recalls, &#8220;the process wasn&#8217;t super smooth&#8221; and they had to pay a lawyer about $750 an hour to understand the mechanics of the process.</p>
<p>“We had to hire a lawyer because I just wanted to make sure we had a good model between the two of us on how we make decisions, how we resolve conflicts.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2237706" style="width: 369px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2237706" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2237706" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg" alt="" width="359" height="479" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg 2448w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg?resize=768,1024 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg?resize=510,680 510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg?resize=1152,1536 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg?resize=1536,2048 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fractional-cofounders.jpg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2237706" class="wp-caption-text">Fractional co-founders Stella Han and Carlos Treviño. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fractional</p></div></p>
<p>CRV general partner Saar Gur thinks that the social networking layer of Fractional, &#8220;where new and experienced investors participate in a symbiotic environment,&#8221; is one of its distinguishing factors, according to a statement. &#8220;This also lets Fractional drive constant engagement on the platform beyond raw transactions and fuel their growth through organic word of mouth instead of aggressive paid marketing,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The rise of alternative investing, from NFT ownership to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/step-aside-nfts-aqua-thinks-modern-investors-should-dive-into-private-equity/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">private equity funds,</a> may trigger more adoption. Consumers are getting comfortable with the idea of diversifying their portfolios away from traditional public equities, and Fractional is a platform that capitalizes on one of the better-known asset classes out there &#8212; real estate.</p>
<p>Not Boring Capital’s Packy McCormick, who is an angel investor in Fractional, thinks the startup brings a highly scalable, high-margin business to a typically hard-to-scale, low-margin business.</p>
<p>“What&#8217;s been most impressive to me,&#8221; the investor and writer told TechCrunch, &#8220;is that in an industry that&#8217;s been very asset heavy &#8212; you need to buy a house and do construction and then sell it, or buy an asset and then let people invest &#8212; they&#8217;ve taken a pure software approach that doesn&#8217;t compromise the ease of the process and still gives people the hands-on feel of owning a house.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/fractional-lands-5-5-million-to-let-friends-and-strangers-invest-in-real-estate-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237702</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Walmart will be the first retailer to test Twitter&#8217;s new livestream shopping platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/walmart-will-be-the-first-retailer-to-test-twitters-new-livestream-shopping-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/walmart-will-be-the-first-retailer-to-test-twitters-new-livestream-shopping-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Live-Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livestream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Personette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter&#8217;s e-commerce initiatives now include livestream shopping and Walmart will be the first retailer to test the new platform. Over the past year, Walmart has invested in live shopping by hosting events across social platforms like TikTok and YouTube, and soon it will debut Twitter&#8217;s first-ever shoppable livestream. On November 28, Walmart will kick off [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter&#8217;s e-commerce initiatives now include livestream shopping and Walmart will be the first retailer to test the new platform. Over the past year, Walmart has invested in live shopping by hosting events across social platforms like TikTok and YouTube, and soon it will debut Twitter&#8217;s first-ever shoppable livestream. On November 28, Walmart will kick off a Cyber Deals live event on Twitter, where users will be able to watch a live broadcast, shop the featured products and join the conversation around the event by posting tweets.</p>
<p>The livestream will begin at 7 PM ET on November 28, 2021, and will allow Walmart customers to shop from Twitter as well as a number of other platforms, including Walmart.com/live, and the retailer&#8217;s Facebook, Instagram, TikTok and YouTube accounts. Musician-turned-creator Jason Derulo will host the livestream, where he&#8217;ll introduce the audience to deals in electronics, home goods, apparel, seasonal décor and more during a 30-minute variety show. Surprise special guests will also drop in, says Walmart.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2237960" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2237960" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2237960" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Walmart-Cyber-Deals-Shoppable-Livesteam.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2237960" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Walmart</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237880" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Walmart has been broadening its support for livestream shopping throughout 2021. It hosted its first shoppable livestream last December when it worked with TikTok <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/walmart-to-pilot-test-live-streamed-video-shopping-on-tiktok/">on its Holiday Shop-Along Spectacular event,</a> shortly after its planned investment in the video app fell through. (Walmart was interested in a deal for TikTok following Trump&#8217;s executive order that would have forced a sale of TikTok&#8217;s U.S. operations. But Trump&#8217;s order was blocked by the courts.)</p>
<p>That first TikTok live event proved successful, Walmart said at the time, having delivered 7x more views than had been anticipated. It also helped Walmart grow its TikTok follower base by 25%. Though the retailer didn&#8217;t detail the sales revenue the event delivered, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/walmart-to-host-a-new-live-stream-shopping-event-on-tiktok-following-successful-pilot/">ran a second TikTok livestream shopping event</a> just a few months later.</p>
<p>While Walmart&#8217;s bid for TikTok had signaled the retailer&#8217;s interest in live, social e-commerce, it saw potential outside of TikTok, as well. Over the past year, Walmart expanded livestream shopping tests to include other platforms. To date, Walmart has hosted more than 15 livestream events across five platforms, including its own website.</p>
<p>Those live commerce initiatives will now include Twitter, which is <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2021/watch--chat--shop--live-shopping-on-twitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">today revealing</a> its new livestream shopping platform to the public.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Twitter says the Walmart Cyber Deals livestream will serve as the initial test of Live Shopping on Twitter in the U.S.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2237959" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2237959" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2237959" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2237959" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>This new platform expands upon Twitter&#8217;s existing shopping products and livestream capabilities.</p>
<p>It will include a live broadcast that streams at the top of a Live Event page, followed by a Shoppable Banner and Shop Tab where the products shown in the livestream are featured. Twitter users will be able to toggle back and forth between the &#8220;Latest&#8221; tab and the &#8220;Shop&#8221; tab during the event as they preview the products. When consumers want to make a purchase, they&#8217;re directed to the retailer&#8217;s website within an in-app browser where the livestream will continue to be broadcast. That way, users won&#8217;t miss anything during checkout, Twitter says.</p>
<p>At the bottom of the Live Event page, there&#8217;s also a text box where consumers can tweet about the livestream with a suggested hashtag.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are honored to have Walmart onboard as the first-ever brand to host a Live Shopping event on Twitter. Walmart is renowned for bringing customers an immersive look into their products and we are excited to bring this experience onto Twitter with them, while helping them reach their business objectives,&#8221; said Sarah Personette, chief customer officer at Twitter, in a statement. &#8220;This is just the first of many Live Shopping events we hope brands will be able to bring to market, and we can’t wait for people to watch, chat, and shop &#8212; all through Twitter,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2237958" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2237958" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2237958" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/twitter-live-shopping-2.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2237958" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>The livestream shopping platform builds on Twitter&#8217;s<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/twitter-launches-u-s-e-commerce-pilot-that-lets-users-shop-from-profiles/"> earlier tests of a Shop Module</a>, launched in July, that gave brands, businesses and retailers a way to showcase their products directly on their Twitter profiles. The test was meant to better understand if there was demand for shopping on Twitter, and had included a handful of pilot partners like gaming retailer <a href="https://twitter.com/GameStop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GameStop</a> and travel brand <a href="https://twitter.com/ArdenCove" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arden Cove</a>, among others.</p>
<p>Walmart said it was interested in testing Twitter&#8217;s new capabilities because it consistently sees high returns across top- and middle-of-funnel content on Twitter&#8217;s platform, which makes it a natural next step for Walmart&#8217;s explorations into social commerce.</p>
<p>The new Twitter livestream event represents the start of a bigger push into live shopping over the 2021 holiday season for Walmart. The company says it has over 30 shoppable livestream events planned across eight social and media platforms, including BuyWith, BuzzFeed, Facebook, IGN, TalkShopLive, Tasty, Twitter and YouTube. (TikTok was not listed, but Walmart told us it&#8217;s working closely with the TikTok team on future shoppable livestreams.)</p>
<p>&#8220;Twitter continues to be an important platform for Walmart’s business and our customers,&#8221; said William White, chief marketing officer at Walmart U.S. &#8220;We’ve been focused on charting new territory in shoppable livestreams and are excited to celebrate an important milestone together with the first Livestream Shopping event on Twitter. We’re meeting customers where they are and making it easier to shop incredible deals and find inspiration through dynamic, interactive experiences. We look forward to continuing to bring engaging experiences to our customers that allow them to shop seamlessly while also being entertained,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Following the initial test of Live Shopping with Walmart, Twitter says it will start testing a new way to house merchant onboarding and product catalog management tools through an interface called the &#8220;Twitter Shopping Manager.&#8221; This will simplify the process of getting started with Shopping on Twitter, the company says. It also plans to make the <a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2021/twitter-shopping--testing-shoppable-profiles-on-twitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shop Module</a> available to more retailers over the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Twitter told TechCrunch it doesn&#8217;t take a cut of the e-commerce revenues delivered through Live Shopping nor are brands paying to be included. But offering live shopping on Twitter could entice more users to join the platform, which has historically struggled with growing consumer adoption.</p>
<p>The live event will be available on Twitter on iOS and desktop in the U.S., starting on November 28th at 7 PM ET/4 PM PT.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/walmart-will-be-the-first-retailer-to-test-twitters-new-livestream-shopping-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237880</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one founder built the gold standard in office guest sign-in, then shifted the business for COVID</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/how-one-founder-built-the-gold-standard-in-office-guest-sign-in-then-shifted-the-business-for-covid/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/how-one-founder-built-the-gold-standard-in-office-guest-sign-in-then-shifted-the-business-for-covid/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 16:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Envoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[larry gadea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The way COVID-19 has changed the way we work comes up a lot &#8212; founders have had to pivot and innovate to build companies during lockdown, but the workplace restrictions seemed to spark inspiration for this week&#8217;s guest, Larry Gadea, founder and CEO of Envoy. Envoy started in 2013 as a guest sign-in platform to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The way COVID-19 has changed the way we work comes up a lot &#8212; founders have had to pivot and innovate to build companies during lockdown, but the workplace restrictions seemed to spark inspiration for this week&#8217;s guest, Larry Gadea, founder and CEO of Envoy. Envoy started in 2013 as a guest sign-in platform to make offices safer and more efficient. Over the past 18 months, Envoy has created new products to solve for many of the new issues offices have as they adapt to the new and frequently changing office safety protocols. Larry talks about how remote work affected company culture, his work-life balance philosophy and how his leadership style has grown with the company.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScwCotybrbEFX8yli-thpevQ4E4rLOtITXUQl6htZpoTguSiA/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Take our listener survey</a> and let us know a bit about yourself and what you think of Found.</p>
<p>Connect with us:</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237972" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li>On <a href="https://twitter.com/found" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter</a></li>
<li>On<a href="https://instagram.com/foundpod" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Instagram</a></li>
<li>Via email: <a href="mailto:found@techcrunch.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found@techcrunch.com</a></li>
<li>Call us and leave a voicemail at (510) 936-1618</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/c0d6bf82-910d-4212-b61f-27abe823470b?dark=false&amp;show=true" width="100%" height="480px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/how-one-founder-built-the-gold-standard-in-office-guest-sign-in-then-shifted-the-business-for-covid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237972</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What happened to Paytm&#8217;s IPO valuation?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/what-happened-to-paytms-ipo-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/what-happened-to-paytms-ipo-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 16:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Paytm's IPO price was simply too high compared to its recent financial results. Trailing results matter as well, and Paytm's were just too weak to support its IPO price.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you weren&#8217;t paying close attention, you might have expected a different result from Paytm&#8217;s IPO. After all, the company is incredibly well funded <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/09/29/alibaba-increases-its-investment-in-indian-payments-and-commerce-firm-paytm/">by investors that you know by name</a>, and the Indian fintech giant has sufficiently scaled into a global brand.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>And yet.</p>
<p>After debuting last Thursday, Paytm has notched two double-digit declines, measured in percentage terms, during its first two days of trading. As far as going public is concerned, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/india-paytm-makes-market-debut/">seeing your share price fall 27%</a> and then 13% is about as bad as it can go.</p>
<p>So, what happened? To understand the lackluster Paytm IPO &#8212; technically the public offering from One 97 Communications, Paytm&#8217;s parent company &#8212; we&#8217;re going back to the company&#8217;s IPO filing, which we&#8217;ll augment with a new filing that dropped today containing a few more data points concerning its performance.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220367 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-grn-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>What we want to know is whether we can spot in the numbers enough reason to understand the company&#8217;s awful post-IPO performance. Was Paytm simply mispriced in its public debut? If so, we don&#8217;t have to spend as much time wondering if the larger Indian stock market is less than welcoming toward tech unicorns.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/author/manish-singh/">TechCrunch&#8217;s Manish Singh</a>, we also have some analyst numbers to lean up against for support. Into the breach!</p>
<h2>Paytm&#8217;s IPO filing</h2>
<p>To avoid this post going on for more words than you want to read, we&#8217;ll skip a deep dive into what Paytm offers the market. Let it suffice to say that it offers payments, bill pay and loans to the Indian market, among other efforts.</p>
<p>So how good of a business is fintech in India? Let&#8217;s take a peek at <a href="https://www.axiscapital.co.in/uploads/equity_documents/20210716104312_one_97_communications_limited__drhp.pdf">the company&#8217;s IPO filing</a>.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/what-happened-to-paytms-ipo-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237819</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GoDaddy says data breach exposed over a million user accounts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/godaddy-breach-million-accounts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/godaddy-breach-million-accounts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 16:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief information security officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoDaddy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private key]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2237929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Web hosting giant GoDaddy has reported a data breach, and warns that data on 1.2 million customers may have been accessed. In a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, GoDaddy&#8217;s chief information security officer Demetrius Comes said the company detected unauthorized access to its systems where it hosts and manages its customers&#8217; WordPress servers. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Web hosting giant GoDaddy has reported a data breach, and warns that data on 1.2 million customers may have been accessed.</p>
<p>In a filing <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1609711/000160971121000122/gddyblogpostnov222021.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with the Securities and Exchange Commission</a>, GoDaddy&#8217;s chief information security officer Demetrius Comes said the company detected unauthorized access to its systems where it hosts and manages its customers&#8217; WordPress servers. WordPress is a web-based content management system used by millions to set up blogs or websites. GoDaddy lets customers host their own WordPress installs on their servers.</p>
<p>GoDaddy said the unauthorized person used a compromised password to get access to GoDaddy&#8217;s systems around September 6. GoDaddy said it discovered the breach last week on November 17. It&#8217;s not clear if the compromised password was protected with two-factor authentication.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2237929" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The filing said that the breach affects 1.2 million active and inactive managed WordPress users, who had their email addresses and customer numbers exposed. GoDaddy said this exposure could put users at greater risk of phishing attacks. The web host also said that the original WordPress admin password created when WordPress was first installed, which could be used to access a customer&#8217;s WordPress server, was also exposed.</p>
<p>The company said that active customers had their sFTP credentials (for file transfers), and the usernames and passwords for their WordPress databases, which store all the user&#8217;s content, exposed in the breach. In some cases, the customer&#8217;s SSL (HTTPS) private key was exposed, which if abused could allow an attacker to impersonate a customer&#8217;s website or services.</p>
<p>GoDaddy said it&#8217;s reset customer WordPress passwords and private keys, and is in the process of issuing new SSL certificates.</p>
<p>The web host has more than 20 million customers worldwide. A spokesperson for GoDaddy did not immediately comment.</p>
<p><b>Read more:</b></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/25/web-host-hostinger-data-breach/">Hostinger says data breach may affect 14 million customers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/17/epik-website-bug-hacked/">Web host Epik was warned of a critical security flaw weeks before it was hacked</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/14/web-hosting-account-hacks/">Some of the biggest web hosting sites were vulnerable to simple account takeover hacks</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/godaddy-breach-million-accounts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2237929</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
