<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:31:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Five stories that shook up the enterprise in 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/five-stories-that-shook-up-the-enterprise-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/five-stories-that-shook-up-the-enterprise-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Levie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Selipsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Jassy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Box]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bret Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Benioff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starboard Value]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is often a mistaken impression that covering the enterprise is kind of dull when compared to the consumer side of the house, but having followed the space for a couple of decades now, I can tell you that nothing could be further from the truth. For one thing, there&#8217;s big money in the enterprise, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There is often a mistaken impression that covering the enterprise is kind of dull when compared to the consumer side of the house, but having followed the space for a couple of decades now, I can tell you that nothing could be further from the truth.</p>
<p>For one thing, there&#8217;s big money in the enterprise, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/20/oracle-snags-cerner-in-28b-mega-deal-to-make-a-big-move-into-healthcare/">Oracle buying Cerner</a> last week for $28 billion and shaking up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/20/oracle-joins-microsoft-in-spending-big-to-dominate-healthcare-vertical/">the healthcare vertical</a> while they were at it, or UiPath going from obscure startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/uipaths-meteoric-rise-from-unknown-startup-to-35b-rpa-juggernaut/">to $35 billion RPA juggernaut</a> earlier this year, before falling back a bit after going public.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s intrigue, like when activist investors try to force companies to make moves they normally wouldn&#8217;t want to make, and battles for control of the board like we saw <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/starboard-value-puts-box-on-notice-that-its-looking-to-take-over-board/">at Box this year</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252213" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>There&#8217;s drama, like the three-year battle among the biggest enterprise cloud infrastructure companies in the world for the $10 billion Department of Defense <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/pentagon-jedi-contract/">JEDI cloud contract</a>, a procurement process that had everything from lawsuits to repeated internal reviews to presidential interference.</p>
<p>So you can say a lot of things about the enterprise&#8230; but boring? Definitely not &#8212; and this year was no different. So I decided to close out 2021 with a look at five stories that rocked the enterprise. It&#8217;s hard to narrow 12 months of news down to the five biggest stories, but here are my choices.</p>
<h2>The Bezos-Jassy-Selipsky musical chairs at Amazon</h2>
<p>Perhaps the biggest news this year involved <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/jeff-bezos-will-no-longer-be-ceo-of-amazon-as-of-later-this-year/">Jeff Bezos deciding to step back</a> as CEO, taking on the chairman role. Now that in itself did not have a huge enterprise impact because Amazon is an e-commerce company, which doesn&#8217;t necessarily fall within my purview, but then there was what happened next.</p>
<p>That February day when Bezos made his announcement, he also indicated he had chosen his replacement, Amazon Web Services CEO Andy Jassy. He had helped <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/02/andy-jassys-brief-history-of-the-genesis-of-aws/">build the cloud infrastructure business at Amazon</a> into a massive business, surpassing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/cloud-infrastructure-market-hits-180b-run-rate-in-q3-as-even-chip-shortages-cant-slow-it-down/">a $64 billion run rate</a> in the most recent quarter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Replacing him wouldn&#8217;t be easy, but they turned to an old friend when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/tableau-ceo-adam-selipsky-is-returning-to-aws-to-replace-andy-jassy-as-ceo/">they hired Tableau CEO Adam Selipsky</a> to take over for Jassy. Selipsky had previously been at AWS from its inception until 2016, when he left to take over Tableau. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/03/aws-reinvent-2021-was-more-incremental-than-innovative/">Now it&#8217;s his job</a> to keep the train moving. He has momentum in his favor, but competition is getting ever more fierce, and it bears watching what happens next year under Selipsky&#8217;s leadership.</p>
<h2>Bret Taylor&#8217;s totally excellent week</h2>
<p>One of the other top stories involved Salesforce executive <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/30/bret-taylor-has-been-promoted-to-salesforce-co-ceo/">Bret Taylor getting a couple of big jobs</a> in the same week at the end of November, making for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/3-analysts-break-down-bret-taylors-pretty-sweet-week/">a pretty sweet week for him</a>. For starters he was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/jack-reportedly-stepping-down-from-twitter-ceo-role/">named chairman of the board at Twitter</a>. If that weren&#8217;t enough, he was also named co-CEO at Salesforce, where he had moved rapidly up the ladder since his company, Quip was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/01/salesforce-buys-word-processing-app-quip-for-750m/">acquired in 2016</a> for $750 million.</p>
<p>While Twitter had turmoil of its own with long-time CEO Jack Dorsey stepping down and Parag Agrawal taking over, the move to co-CEO at the CRM giant was clearly the bigger news from an enterprise perspective. While <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/salesforces-taylor-will-report-to-benioff-despite-co-ceo-title" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Information reported</a> that Taylor would still be reporting to company co-founder, chairman and co-CEO Marc Benioff, the promotion put Taylor in line to be Benioff&#8217;s heir apparent should Benioff decide to step back into the chairman role in the same way that Bezos did earlier this year. Another storyline to consider in 2022 is whether Salesforce revisits its desire to buy Twitter,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/24/why-salesforce-might-be-interested-in-twitter/"> a move it thought of making in 2016</a> before <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/14/salesforce-officially-walks-away-from-twitter-acquisition-for-real-this-time/">walking away</a>.</p>
<h2>Box-Starboard Value proxy fight</h2>
<p>Box <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/box-wins-proxy-board-battle-with-activist-investor-starboard-value/">beat back an attempt</a> by activist investor Starboard Value <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/activist-investor-starboard-value-makes-official-bid-for-box-board-seats-in-letter/">to take over the board</a>, a move that likely would have resulted in the removal of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/as-activist-investors-loom-whats-next-for-box/">co-founder and CEO Aaron Levie</a>, the sale of the company, or both. It was the culmination of months of drama and it made it a major enterprise story line for 2021.</p>
<p>Starboard Value, an activist investor, bought<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/starboard-value-takes-7-5-stake-in-box/"> a 7.5% stake</a> in the cloud content management company in 2019, which would grow to 8.8%, giving the firm considerable influence over the company. They remained quiet for a time, but last year they decided to make a move and put Box on notice that they wanted to take over the board, which resulted in a proxy battle.</p>
<p>Along the way, Box answered with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/kkr-hands-box-a-500m-lifeline/">a $500 million investment from KKR</a>, further angering Starboard, filed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/box-takes-fight-with-activist-investor-public-in-sec-filing/">a document with the SEC</a> pushing back against Starboard&#8217;s slate of board candidates and issued their<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/box-reports-earnings-early-to-give-shareholders-time-to-review-financials-ahead-of-board-vote/"> earnings report early</a> to give voters a chance to see their latest results. As luck would have it, the company scored two decent quarters following Starboard&#8217;s action and easily won the proxy battle, leaving the status quo for now. What happens in 2022? As I wrote, perhaps it&#8217;s time for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/after-a-proxy-fight-victory-its-time-for-box-to-make-some-bold-moves/">Box to make some bold moves</a>, and use some of KKR&#8217;s money to buy some adjacent functionality.</p>
<h2>DoD kills JEDI and announces new cloud initiative</h2>
<p>The $10 billion, decade-long <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/15/why-the-pentagons-10-billion-jedi-deal-has-cloud-companies-going-nuts/">JEDI cloud contract</a> has been drama-filled from the day it was announced in 2018. Over those years, I wrote <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/pentagon-jedi-contract/">more than 30 articles</a> on it, so when the Pentagon decided<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/nobody-wins-as-dod-finally-pulls-the-plug-on-controversial-10b-jedi-contract/"> to kill it finally this year</a>, that was big news.</p>
<p>From the start, conventional wisdom said that it was Amazon&#8217;s contract to win. There were complaints that the RFP was written with Amazon in mind, but in the end it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/25/in-a-victory-over-amazon-microsoft-wins-10b-pentagon-jedi-cloud-contract/">Microsoft that won the deal</a>. Amazon <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/amazon-asks-judge-to-set-aside-microsofts-10b-dod-jedi-cloud-contract-win/">went to court</a> though, stating that the previous president had directly interfered with the procurement process because of his personal dislike for Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos, who also happens to own The Washington Post newspaper. Amazon also argued that it should have won on merit.</p>
<p>Regardless, it succeeded in convincing a judge <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/13/judge-halts-microsoft-work-on-jedi-contract-after-aws-request/">to put the project on hold</a> in February 2020. It would never restart, and the DoD decided to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/19/pentagon-announces-new-cloud-initiative-to-replace-ill-fated-jedi-contract/"> move on to a new project</a> in July, stating that technology had changed since 2018 (which is true) and wisely deciding to go with a multi-vendor approach with its new initiative, instead <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/the-single-vendor-requirement-ultimately-doomed-the-dods-10b-jedi-cloud-contract/">of the winner-take-all approach</a> it had pursued with JEDI.</p>
<h2>Dell spins out VMware</h2>
<p>When <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/12/dell-buys-emc-for-67b-in-largest-deal-in-tech-history/">Dell bought EMC in 2015</a> for $67 billion (later amended to $58 billion), it was the largest deal in tech history, and another doozy of a story <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/dell-emc-deal/">to follow and write about</a> over the years. VMware was always the crown jewel of the deal, and so enterprise reporters like me kept a close eye on what Dell was going to do with it. For a long time it stood pat, but it was a huge story in the early part of the year when it announced it was spinning out the company in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dell-is-spinning-out-vmware-in-a-deal-expected-to-generate-over-9b-for-the-company/">a deal valued at $9 billion</a>.</p>
<p>It seemed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/should-dell-have-pursued-a-more-aggressive-debt-reduction-move-with-vmware/">a little light perhaps</a> given the amount of money <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/01/unpacking-how-dells-debt-load-and-vmware-stake-could-come-together/">that&#8217;s still on the books</a> for the EMC deal. What happens next year? Could someone <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/18/once-vmware-is-free-from-dell-who-might-fancy-buying-it/">make a run to acquire VMware</a> now that it&#8217;s free of Dell? Dell remains a major shareholder and still has plenty of debt left over from that EMC deal, so it is definitely something to watch in 2022.</p>
<p><em>It&#8217;s hard to choose just five because inevitably I&#8217;ve left out some worthy storylines. What would you have included? Leave a comment and let me know.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/five-stories-that-shook-up-the-enterprise-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252213</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best of TechCrunch 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/best-of-techcrunch-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/best-of-techcrunch-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alyssa Stringer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 19:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Better.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biometrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climate Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flamethrower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We asked our staff to vote on their favorite stories of the year, added evergreen content and our top TC+ articles for a well-rounded 2021 list. Enjoy!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Just when we thought things couldn’t get more unexpected than a pandemic that shut down the world in 2020, 2021 entered the chat.</p>
<p>As we started to navigate a “new normal,” we also started challenging the systems around us with advancements in crypto, web3, the metaverse and so much more.</p>
<p>When looking at our top-performing stories of the year, a lot stood out. Some stories were to be expected, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/microsoft-launches-google-wave/">product launches</a> and major outages (ahem, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">Facebook</a>). Others were deep analyses and interviews on different sectors of the industry. It was hard to narrow down a top 10.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252058" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Instead of spitting out a list of TechCrunch’s top-performing stories, we asked our staff to vote on their favorite stories of the year, added evergreen content and our top TC+ articles for a well-rounded 2021 list. Enjoy!</p>
<h2>Staff picks</h2>
<p><strong>1. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/28/eric-dean-wilson-interview/">Air conditioning is one of the greatest inventions of the 20th Century. It’s also killing the 21st</a></strong></p>
<p>What started as a small Twitter Spaces interview with about 180 listeners quickly (and very unexpectedly) turned into one of TechCrunch’s top-read stories of 2021. Danny’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/book-review/">book reviews</a> gained traction this year, but nothing piqued readers’ interests (see the comments for proof) quite like unpacking the modern-day air conditioner. Danny’s Spaces interview with Eric Dean Wilson focused on his book “After Cooling: On Freon, Global Warming, and the Terrible Cost of Comfort,” exploring the before, during and after story of A/C — and how damaging the comforts of cold, clean indoor air can actually be.</p>
<p><strong>2. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/onlyfans-porn-ban-is-cryptos-opportunity-of-a-lifetime/">OnlyFans’ porn ban is crypto’s opportunity of a lifetime</a></strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Twitter erupted when OnlyFans announced its ban on “sexually explicit content” in mid-August in an attempt to comply with its investors and banks. At the time, the decision left creators feeling betrayed, and experts questioned if OnlyFans could even survive the transition. Although the decision has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/onlyfans-suspends-decision-to-ban-explicit-content/">since been suspended</a>, the tech community’s immediate solution to the ongoing regulatory issues the porn industry faces was simple: crypto. For those of you new to the world of crypto, this real-world antidote will help you understand the “why” behind the push for cryptocurrencies. And for those of you well-versed on the topic, Lucas weighs both the opportunities and potential challenges crypto and porn face.</p>
<p><strong>3. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/elon-musk-said-it-was-not-a-flamethrower/">Elon Musk said it was &#8216;Not a Flamethrower&#8217;</a></strong></p>
<p>This is probably our “most 2021” headline. Many of us are — maybe a little too much — accustomed to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/30/elon-musk-shills-a-50-tesla-cyberwhistle-with-a-joke-about-whistleblowers/">Tesla CEO’s name in headlines</a> for wacky, meme-like behavior or commentary. But what makes this story interesting is the real-life dangers behind Musk’s money-spinning gag products. Musk sold a limited run of flamethrowers back in 2017 in an effort to raise awareness and funds for his startup, The Boring Company, which launched in 2016. However, Musk knew various countries had a ban on flamethrowers and thus labeled the product &#8220;Not a Flamethrower.&#8221; Problem solved? Not even close. TechCrunch contributor Mark Harris highlights an American who was incarcerated in Italy for the possession of Not a Flamethrower.</p>
<p><strong>4. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/medium-exodus-culture-memo/">Medium sees more employee exits after CEO publishes ‘culture memo’</a></strong></p>
<p>It’s safe to say this year brought much disruption to today’s corporate ecosystem. Not only are employees challenging work-life balance, the wealth gap and company culture, but they are also taking a stance on social and political initiatives. Natasha spoke with various former and current employees at Medium after CEO Ev Williams posted a &#8220;culture memo,&#8221; which ended up tripling churn at the company. However, after speaking to one engineer, Natasha found that there has been a long-standing “history of problematic issues at Medium, with a wave of departures that seem to be clearly triggered by the memo.” This article not only explores the downfall of Medium’s company culture but also how it relates to companies who sent out similar memos, like Coinbase and Basecamp.</p>
<p><strong>5. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/tiktok-just-gave-itself-permission-to-collect-biometric-data-on-u-s-users-including-faceprints-and-voiceprints/">TikTok just gave itself permission to collect biometric data on US users, including &#8216;faceprints and voiceprints&#8217;</a></strong></p>
<p>TikTok took off in the thick of the pandemic as many people in 2020 turned to the platform for their daily dose of viral videos, dances and trends while in quarantine. However, now more than ever, social media users are aware of data collection as growing concerns of privacy rights emerge. TikTok changed its privacy policy in June to allow the capture of users’ biometric data, which includes faceprints and voiceprints. At first glance, the new privacy policy is on par with many other social networks&#8217; use of data collection. But Sarah breaks down why the new policy is alarming, TikTok’s history with the U.S. government, past biometric privacy violation lawsuits and the policy update’s buggy rollout. This article is a good starting point for the ongoing data-privacy issues social media users face.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="breakout aligncenter wp-image-2252204 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg" alt="" width="3200" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg?resize=768,216 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg?resize=680,191 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg?resize=1536,432 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg?resize=2048,576 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-banner.jpg?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3200px) 100vw, 3200px" /></p>
<h2>Best evergreen</h2>
<p>With only a few days left in 2021, we looked back to see what we covered this year that we can continue to learn from in the future. NFTs aren’t going anywhere, yet, so that was at the top of our evergreen list, along with privacy laws, how Zoom effects your brain and how lessons in growth marketing from Cam Sinclair director of Ammo, a Perth-based growth marketing agency.</p>
<p><strong>1. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/27/if-you-havent-followed-nfts-heres-why-you-should-start/">If you haven’t followed NFTs, here’s why you should start</a></strong></p>
<p>This new(ish) wave of crypto has grown exponentially over the past year. When Cooper Turley wrote this article in February 2021, he said, “The estimated total value of crypto art has now passed $100 million according to cryptoart.io/data — just one vertical of a growing ecosystem of NFTs.” The estimated total value now, December 2021, is over $2 billion. If you don’t know much about NFT’s, this article is a great starting point.</p>
<p><strong>2. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/toolkit-nso-pegasus-iphone-android/">This tool tells you if NSO’s Pegasus spyware targeted your phone</a></strong></p>
<p>Are you concerned that your phone was targeted by NSO’s spyware? You probably shouldn’t be, but in July of 2021, a list was leaked that contained, “50,000 phone numbers of potential surveillance targets was obtained by Paris-based journalism nonprofit Forbidden Stories and Amnesty International and shared with the reporting consortium, including The Washington Post and The Guardian.” Zack writes about how Pegasus can be delivered and how you can tell if your phone has been targeted.</p>
<p><strong>3. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/new-york-city-biometrics-law/">New York City’s new biometrics privacy law takes effect</a></strong></p>
<p>In July of 2021, Zack also reported on a new biometric law taking effect in New York City. This law limits what businesses can do with the biometric data they collect. Zack says, “The move will give New Yorkers — and its millions of visitors each year — greater protections over how their biometric data is collected and used, while also serving to dissuade businesses from using technology that critics say is discriminatory and often doesn’t work.”</p>
<p><strong>4. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/this-is-your-brain-on-zoom/">This is your brain on Zoom</a></strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve all been working from home, faces seen by colleagues on endless video chats, so it was great to read Devin Coldewey’s breakdown of a study Microsoft conducted about how your brain needs a break. When discussing the study, Devin says, “During the meeting block with no breaks, people showed higher levels of beta waves, which are associated with stress, anxiety and concentration.” Here’s to scheduling meeting breaks in 2022!</p>
<p><strong>5. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/australian-growth-marketing-agency-ammo-helps-startups-calibrate-their-efforts/">Australian growth marketing agency Ammo helps startups calibrate their efforts</a></strong> <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"><br />
</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"><br />
TechCrunch Experts launched this year with the first focus being growth marketing. Anna Heim interviewed Cam Sinclair, Ammo’s director, and they talked about when companies are ready for growth marketing, mistakes to avoid when branding and more. Sinclair says, “At Ammo, we don’t measure time, we measure outcomes. At the start of every project we define what success looks like with the client. Every client is different, and we’re responsive to that.”</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="breakout aligncenter wp-image-2252205 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg" alt="" width="3200" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg?resize=768,216 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg?resize=680,191 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg?resize=1536,432 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg?resize=2048,576 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/best-2021-tc-plus-banner.jpg?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3200px) 100vw, 3200px" /></p>
<h2>TC+ Favorites</h2>
<p><strong>1. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/subscription-based-pricing-is-dead-smart-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-models/">Subscription-based pricing is dead: Smart SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based models</a></strong></p>
<p>Kyle Poyar, partner at OpenView, contributed this article about usage-based pricing models in January of 2021. Poyar says, “Usage-based pricing will be the key to successful monetization in the future.” The article continues with four tips to help companies with this model. While we don’t want to give all of the tips away in this summary, one of the tips that Poyar writes about is picking the right usage metric.</p>
<p><strong>2. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/nubanks-ipo-filing-gives-us-a-peek-into-neobank-economics/">Nubank’s IPO filing gives us a peek into neobank economics</a></strong></p>
<p>In November, Alex and Natasha wrote about Nubank’s IPO filing, focusing on the economics of neobanking and Nubank’s financial health. If you want to take a deeper dive into Nubank, you can read Marcella McCarthy and Danny Crichton’s TC-1 <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/nubank-ec1/">here</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">.</span></p>
<p><strong>3. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/how-does-former-better-com-ceo-vishal-garg-still-have-a-job/">How does former Better.com CEO Vishal Garg still have a job?</a></strong></p>
<p>Mary Ann was <em style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">busy</em><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> in the month of December, with one of her focuses being news from Better.com (</span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/better-com-lays-off-9-of-its-staff/">like when they laid off 9% of their staff</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">). While it would take a lot to shock Mary Ann and Alex, especially after </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/better-com-ceo-vishal-garg-apologizes-to-current-employees-for-blundering-the-execution-of-mass-layoffs/">this</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, they were surprised that Garg hadn’t been asked to completely step down. They said, “Some surmised that he had super-voting shares and thus could vote to keep himself in the role of CEO despite what others voted. But after digging into the S-4 filed by Better.com’s SPAC partner, Aurora Acquisition Corp., in November, we realized that is not the case.”</span></p>
<p><strong>4. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/how-should-saas-companies-deliver-and-price-professional-services/">How should SaaS companies deliver and price professional services?</a></strong></p>
<p>Roger Hurwitz, a founding partner at Volition Capital, contributed an article about how to charge for professional services and why that pricing may be different from other SaaS strategies. Hurwitz compares a three-year impact of two pricing strategies in this article.</p>
<p><strong>5. <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/5-critical-pitch-deck-slides-most-founders-get-wrong/">5 critical pitch deck slides most founders get wrong</a></strong></p>
<p>Jose Cayasso, co-founder and CEO of Slidebean, reviews “250 to 300 investor decks every single month” and uses this experience to teach others what the must-haves are for a slide deck. His first suggestion is a go-to-market slide, and he includes why and where in the deck it should appear with an example of one in the full article.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/best-of-techcrunch-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252058</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Year’s robolutions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/new-years-robolutions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/new-years-robolutions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 19:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Actuator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daniela rus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is always a strange week &#8212; that liminal space between the Christmas holiday and New Year. Romjul &#8212; or “Dead Week” &#8212; as they call it in Norway (thanks Haje). It’s a time for quiet and reflection on the year that was for some &#8212; and CES embargoes for others. We’re currently focused on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This is always a strange week &#8212; that liminal space between the Christmas holiday and New Year. Romjul &#8212; or “Dead Week” &#8212; as they call it in Norway (thanks Haje). It’s a time for quiet and reflection on the year that was for some &#8212; and CES embargoes for others. We’re currently focused on the latter, while trying to stay mindful of the former here at Actuator HQ.</p>
<p>We devoted much of the past few weeks to rounding up some of the year’s key trends in the space: delivery, warehouse/fulfillment and food prep. We’ve also spoken to a number of key people in the industry, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/raise-and-deliver/">CMU robotics head Matthew Johnson-Roberson and Boston Dynamics CEO Rob Playter</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/every-day-is-boxing-day/">OpenRobotics CEO Brian Gerkey</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/23/dinner-is-servoed/">iRobot CEO Colin Angle</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2252065" style="width: 809px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252065" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2252065" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/35606200100_740eb5157f_c.jpg" alt="" width="799" height="555" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/35606200100_740eb5157f_c.jpg 799w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/35606200100_740eb5157f_c.jpg?resize=150,104 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/35606200100_740eb5157f_c.jpg?resize=300,208 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/35606200100_740eb5157f_c.jpg?resize=768,533 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/35606200100_740eb5157f_c.jpg?resize=680,472 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/35606200100_740eb5157f_c.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2252065" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Paul Marotta/Getty Images for TechCrunch</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252064" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This week we’ve asked MIT CSAIL Director Daniela Rus to weigh in on the matter. She’s really gone above and beyond in her responses for this last Actuator of 2021, so I’m going to let her kick things off.</p>
<p><strong>What was the defining robotics/AI/automation trend of 2021?</strong> Regarding robotics and automation, the pandemic and subsequent labor shortages made it abundantly clear that there is a critical role for robots in the workplace. Industry has seen increased adoption of robots for manufacturing and logistics applications, where autonomy can deliver value, yet autonomy on the roadways in the form of a robotaxi is still a long way away. Research has made great strides on safer and more capable robots, with advancements in soft robot bodies and machine-learning powered robot brains.</p>
<p>In AI, we have seen heightened awareness about the challenges with today’s AI solutions. Industry has adopted many deep neural network applications that are enabling tools to augment work in a variety of fields. But it has also become clear that these methods require data availability, meaning massive data sets that have to be manually labeled and are not easily obtained in every field. The quality of that data needs to be very high, and if the data is biased or bad, the performance of the systems trained on this data will be equally bad. Furthermore, these systems are black boxes &#8212; there is no way for users of the systems to truly “learn” anything based on the AI’s innerworkings. There are also robustness problems as the trained models are often unstable, and we need to understand that the systems do not do “deep reasoning”, they mostly perform shallow pattern matching. The research community is working to address these challenges.</p>
<p><strong>What will 2022 bring for these categories?</strong> As we move forward into our rapidly changing world, I believe that robots and AI can help us unlock our human potential, as individuals and as a collective. While the past 60 years have defined the field of industrial robots and empowered hard-bodied machines to execute complex assembly tasks in constrained industrial settings, the next sixty years will usher in robots in human-centric environments to assist humans with physical tasks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While the industrial robots of the past 60 years have mostly been inspired by the human form, the next stage will be soft robots inspired by the animal kingdom: form and diversity modeled by our own built environment, with broad potential to mimic our natural state. While the industrial robots of the past 60 years are made of hard plastics and metal, I believe the next 60 years will bring us machines made of materials available to us naturally, or through engineered processes like wood, plastics, paper, ice or even food.</p>
<p>We will also see new ideas for AI, get more serious about AI and privacy, and address AI sustainability. It is important to remember that today’s greatest advances are due to decades-old ideas enhanced by vast amounts of data and computation. New technical ideas and funding to back them are needed to ensure progress. Additionally, we will understand more clearly the carbon footprint of machine learning and get more serious about Sustainable AI.</p>
<p>AI innovations can help optimize many of our activities to slow the impacts of warming: optimizing the electricity cost of technology, making transportation more efficient, monitoring and stopping deforestation, preserving biodiversity or ensuring there’s enough food to go around. But to do all that, AI systems must consume enormous amounts of energy. Current research estimates that training a large deep-learning model produces 626,000 pounds of carbon dioxide, equal to the lifetime emissions of five cars. We need to develop simpler models, which can drastically reduce the carbon footprint of AI.</p>
<p>The spread of robotics, automation and AI technologies has the potential to make people’s lives easier &#8212; but many of the roles that these technologies can play will displace work done by humans today. We will also focus efforts to anticipate and respond to the economic inequality this could create.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1961905" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1961905" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-1961905" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg" alt="Ford Marks 100th Anniversary Of Its Dearborn Truck Plant" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1041983056.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1961905" class="wp-caption-text">DEARBORN, MI &#8211; SEPTEMBER 27: A Ford Motor Company worker works on a Ford F-150 truck on the assembly line at the Ford Dearborn Truck Plant on September 27, 2018 in Dearborn, Michigan. The Ford Rouge Plant is celebrating 100 years as America&#8217;s longest continuously operating auto plant. The factory produced Eagle Boats during WW I and currently produces the Ford F-150 pickup truck. (Photo by Bill Pugliano/Getty Images)</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s going to be impossible to top Professor Rus’ words this week, but I would like to cap the year off with a couple of items that highlight what’s happened in the industry over the past year and &#8212; perhaps &#8212; give us a glimpse of where things are going. I will echo what a lot of people have already said in the pages of Actuator: It’s been a remarkable year for robotics. After spending many years covering the space and hearing people prognosticate on the eventually of robotics, the pandemic has seen many begin to be put into practice faster than many predicted.</p>
<p>Of course, I don’t think anyone was hoping that a pandemic would be how we got here, but, well, that’s how things go. And to echo Professor Rus’ statement, here’s hoping we’re able to address climate change concerns head on before it’s too late &#8212; and that we can address the inevitable displacement of human jobs. If we’re going to be deploying robots to improve the working conditions of some, it behooves us as a society to ensure that we’re able to support those whose jobs are made redundant as a result.</p>
<p>Roboticists will tell you about the dull, dirty and dangerous jobs they plan to replace, but there’s a far more difficult conversation around the impact that shift has on humans. It’s true right now that companies are having a difficult time filling roles &#8212; something automation can and will address. It’s also true that most of this technology is still in a collaborative stage that requires the involvement of human workers. But as the technology progresses and becomes more capable, is it invetible that we’re going to leave large swaths of the population behind because we’ve deemed the work they do as unskilled?</p>
<p>Looking at the trends for the past year, these are the key categories I’ve been following in the space:</p>
<ul>
<li>Warehouse/fulfillment</li>
<li>Transportation</li>
<li>Food delivery/prep</li>
<li>Farming/agriculture</li>
<li>Home</li>
<li>Medical/surgical</li>
<li>Manufacturing</li>
<li>Construction</li>
</ul>
<p>And in some ways, that’s really just the start. For instance, a couple of weeks ago we covered Petra, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/petra-emerges-from-stealth-with-30m-raised-for-tunnel-boring-robot-swifty/">a drilling company that raised $30 million</a> to bore through solid rock for infrastructural projects. The list of fields robotics is set to disrupt is long and growing. As we look forward to 2022, let’s consider how we handle such things, going forward. I’m excited to continue discussing these and other issues in Actuator going forward. Next week, however, we’re going to get much more myopic and focus on the robots of CES.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2251844" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2251844" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2251844" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/54351640762019_.pic_hd.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2251844" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Meituan&#8217;s food delivery drone seen landing on top of a pickup kiosk in Shenzhen / Photo: TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Thankfully, the big robotics news has slowed down a bit this Romjul (I only get to use my new word like once a year, so I’m making the most of it). Rita has a great story for you <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/meituan-food-drone-delivery-china/">about Meituan</a>, which is taking drone-based food delivery to Shenzhen. The Tencent-backed company has delivered 19,000 meals to 8,000 customers during its two-year pilot. As the piece notes, relatively lax regulations in the manufacturing hub are a big part of what brought it to Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Speaking of China, the country’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology has <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/China-tech/China-lays-out-path-to-become-robotics-powerhouse-by-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener">helped map out an ambitious five-year plan</a> aimed at increasing robotic adoption. That includes a planned 20% per year revenue increase, with a focus on manufacturing.</p>
<p>Happy New Year, and congrats on getting through this last one. Not everyone was so lucky. Here&#8217;s to sharing more robot news in 2022.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191371" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191371" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2191371" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191371" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Need a head start on your New Year&#8217;s resolution of subscribing to more free robotics newsletters? Have I got <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">some great news for you</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/new-years-robolutions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252064</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mercedes, BMW, more join list of companies opting-out of an in-person CES</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/mercedes-bmw-more-join-list-of-companies-opting-out-of-an-in-person-ces/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/mercedes-bmw-more-join-list-of-companies-opting-out-of-an-in-person-ces/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 19:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercedes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panasonic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two more auto giants have added their names to the growing list of big companies opting out of an in-person CES with less than a week remaining before kickoff. Yesterday, Mercedes confirmed that it would be skipping the physical event. &#8220;As the health and safety of our customers, partners, employees and guests are our highest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two more auto giants have added their names to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/more-companies-bow-out-of-in-person-ces-presence/">growing list of big companies</a> opting out of an in-person CES with less than a week remaining before kickoff. Yesterday, Mercedes confirmed that it would be skipping the physical event.</p>
<p>&#8220;As the health and safety of our customers, partners, employees and guests are our highest priority,” the company <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/mobile/ces-2022-amid-covid-surge-mercedes-amd-and-oneplus-drop-out-joining-microsoft-google-intel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said in a statement</a>. &#8220;Due to the large group of participants and the different country-specific regulations, a solid, safe and harmless planning for all participants is unfortunately not be feasible in the current situation. We deeply regret this decision but consider it necessary.&#8221;</p>
<p>Today, BMW followed suit, issuing <a href="https://www.bmwusanews.com/newsrelease.do?id=3878&amp;mid=" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a media release</a>, announcing a shift to a virtual press conference. The carmaker’s statement was short and sweet, noting, “For many years, the BMW Group has been presenting innovations at the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas. Due to the pandemic situation, the BMW Group will move all planned media activities at CES to a fully digital program livestreamed from Germany.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252222" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Lidar company Velodyne, meanwhile, issued a full press release about its decision this week, stating:</p>
<blockquote><p>Velodyne Lidar will not participate in person at CES 2022 due to the surge in COVID-19 infection rates. The health and safety of employees, partners and the public are the topmost priorities for Velodyne and were the primary factors in the company’s decision.</p></blockquote>
<p>Early today, IBM also confirmed its decision to extract itself from the in-person event in a statement to TechCrunch:</p>
<blockquote><p>Due to the evolving COVID conditions, and out of an abundance of caution, IBM will not participate on-site at CES in Las Vegas this year. We look forward to participating in the event virtually.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Also newly out is Panasonic, which had planned an in-person press conference for January 4. The company has shifted to a virtual event and will only <a href="https://mashable.com/article/ces-2022-covid-dropouts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have a limited presence</a> at the show.</p>
<p>Those companies join GM, Google, Microsoft, AMD, OnePlus, MSI, Lenovo, Intel, T-Mobile, AT&amp;T, Meta, Twitter, Amazon, Proctor &amp; Gamble, TikTok, Pinterest and a number of major media outlets, TechCrunch included. The decision to jump ship over mounting omicron concerns is likely an especially difficult one for startups, who rely on shows like CES to get noticed. I have, however, been contacted by a growing number of smaller companies who have made the difficult decision to stay home.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Over 2200 companies are confirmed to participate in person at CES 2022 in Las Vegas. Our focus remains on convening the tech industry and giving those who cannot attend in person the ability to experience the magic of CES digitally.</p>
<p>&mdash; CES (@CES) <a href="https://twitter.com/CES/status/1474187232730828801?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 24, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The Consumer Technology Association &#8212; which runs CES &#8212; has stood firm in its plans to go ahead with the show, which starts January 5 (with media days on the 3 and 4).</p>
<p>“CES 2022 will be in person on January 5-8 in Las Vegas with strong safety measures in place, and our digital access is also available for people that don’t wish to, or can’t travel to Las Vegas,” the org said in a statement issued December 22. “Our mission remains to convene the industry and give those who cannot attend in person the ability to experience the magic of CES digitally.”</p>
<p>On Christmas Day, the Las Vegas Review Journal ran<a href="https://www.reviewjournal.com/opinion/commentary-ces-will-and-must-go-on-in-las-vegas-2502202/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> an op-ed</a> from CTA head Gary Shapiro headlined “CES will and must go on in Las Vegas,” which accused media of “tell[ing] the story only through their lens of drama and big name companies.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/mercedes-bmw-more-join-list-of-companies-opting-out-of-an-in-person-ces/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252222</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The year the tide turned on ransomware</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-year-the-tide-turned-on-ransomware/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-year-the-tide-turned-on-ransomware/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitdefender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cd projekt red]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chainalysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colonial pipeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fujitsu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaseya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Years Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panasonic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qualys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year was rife with ransomware. 2021 witnessed the attack on IT software company Kaseya that knocked 1,500 organizations offline, the CD Projekt Red hack that saw threat actors make off with source code for games including Cyberpunk 2077 and The Witcher 3, and several high-profile attacks targeting big-name tech companies, from Olympus to Fujitsu and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This year was rife with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ransomware/">ransomware</a>. 2021 witnessed the attack on IT software company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/kaseya-hack-flood-ransomware/">Kaseya</a> that knocked 1,500 organizations offline, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/cd-projekt-red-hit-by-ransomware-attack-refuses-to-pay-ransom/">the CD Projekt Red hack</a> that saw threat actors make off with source code for games including Cyberpunk 2077 and The Witcher 3, and several high-profile attacks targeting big-name tech companies, from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/12/technology-giant-olympus-hit-by-blackmatter-ransomware/">Olympus</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/fujifilm-becomes-the-latest-victim-of-a-network-crippling-ransomware-attack/">Fujitsu</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/panasonic-data-breach/">Panasonic</a>.</p>
<p>It was also the year that hackers seized global attention by targeting critical infrastructure, hacking American oil pipeline system <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/colonial-pipeline/">Colonial Pipeline</a>, meat-processing giant JBS and Iowa New Cooperative, an alliance of farmers that sells corn and soy, to name just a few.</p>
<p>After the attacks led to prolonged shutdowns, inflated oil prices and ran the risk of food shortages, the U.S. government began to take notice — after years of inaction — and scored some rare wins in what once seemed like an unwinnable battle against the ransomware epidemic.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252122" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It began in April when the Department of Justice formed the Ransomware and Digital Extortion Task Force. The move, which followed what the DOJ described as the “worst year” for ransomware attacks, aimed to prioritize the “disruption, investigation, and prosecution of ransomware and digital extortion activity.” The task force declared its first victory two months later when the DOJ announced it had arrested 55-year-old Latvian national Alla Witte and charged her for her role in &#8220;a transnational cybercrime organization&#8221; that was behind <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/12/trickbot-spam-millions-emails/">TrickBot</a>, one of the most well-known and widely used banking trojans and ransomware tools.</p>
<p>An even bigger win came just days later when the DOJ announced it had seized $2.3 million in bitcoin that Colonial Pipeline paid to the DarkSide ransomware gang to reclaim its data. Since then, the U.S. government has offered <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/">a reward of up to $10 million</a> for information that helps identify or track down leaders of the notorious ransomware group.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Treasury Department announced sanctions against the Chatex cryptocurrency exchange for facilitating ransom transactions, just weeks after taking similar action against the Suex crypto exchange.</p>
<p>The biggest win for the Task Force came in October <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/08/us-charges-kaseya-hacker-and-seizes-6m-from-revil-ransomware-gang/">with its disruption of the notorious REvil ransomware gang</a>. Prosecutors announced they had charged a 22-year-old Ukrainian national linked to the gang that orchestrated the July ransomware attack against Kaseya, and said it had seized more than $6 million in ransom tied to another member of the notorious ransomware group.</p>
<p>The U.S. government’s efforts to target ransomware groups this year were applauded by many, particularly for its tactic of following the money. Chainalysis, a provider of blockchain transaction analysis software, lauded the Treasury’s action against Suex as a “big win” against ransomware operators, telling TechCrunch that dismantling the mechanisms for ransomware groups to cash out their cryptocurrency would be vital in slowing them down. Morgan Wright, chief security advisor at SentinelOne, said that without removing the main incentive — financial gain — ransomware gangs will continue to operate and expand.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">Read more on TechCrunch</h4>
		
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/ransomware-recovery-can-be-costly-and-not-just-because-of-the-ransom/">Ransomware recovery can be costly, and not just because of the ransom</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/cisa-iran-hackers-ransomware/">US says Iran-backed hackers are now targeting organizations with ransomware</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/fbi-ransomware-private-financial-extort/">FBI says ransomware groups are using private financial information to further extort victims</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/">US government offers $10M bounty for DarkSide ransomware hackers</a></li>
</ul>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>“Attackers will always have the advantage because they don’t have to follow the rules or the law. However, there are two approaches that could seriously impact the ability of transitional ransomware gangs to achieve their goals &#8212; removing the ability to use cryptocurrency for ransoms and machine speed responses to machine speed attacks,&#8221; said Wright.</p>
<p>The U.S. government also offered rewards for information on ransomware tactics, like the $10 million bounty for information on DarkSide, and the subsequent reward for intel on REvil. “With rewards this large, there’s a substantial incentive for these criminals to turn on one another. This action undermines trust across the ransomware as a service affiliate model,&#8221; Jake Williams, CTO at BreachQuest, told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>But some believe that while the government&#8217;s actions have undoubtedly scared off some, it&#8217;s unlikely to disincentive ransomware gangs that continue to reap the financial rewards.</p>
<p>&#8220;While I applaud law enforcement efforts to bring those responsible for ransomware attacks to justice, the likelihood of apprehension and jail time simply does not outweigh the large sums of money being made by these criminal groups,&#8221; said Jonathan Trull at Qualys, an IT security company. &#8220;Unfortunately, the battle against ransomware is an asymmetric one, meaning there simply is not enough law enforcement resources globally to deal with the volumes and complexity of investigations needed.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wright agreed, and was less than impressed by the U.S. government&#8217;s activity so far: &#8220;Arresting two people and recovering a few million dollars isn’t a victory over ransomware. This is more of a political statement to ’show’ something is being done about ransomware. $2.3 million isn’t even worthy of a rounding error when you look at the billions of dollars already lost.&#8221;</p>
<p>Similarly, many believe that these tactics will unlikely be enough to fend off the growing threat of ransomware as we enter the new year, particularly as threat actors adapt their own. Experts believe that the ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) model — in which operators lease out their ransomware infrastructure to others in return for a percentage of the ransom proceeds — will continue to thrive in 2022, making it more difficult for law enforcement to track down operators.</p>
<p>Others expect multi-staged attack chains — the breaches that start with a phish and lead to data theft and eventually ransomware — to become more prevalent, which could enable hackers to infiltrate even the most well-protected network infrastructures.</p>
<p>The latter will likely lead to the U.S. government collaborating more closely with the private sector in 2022, according to Trull. &#8220;Law enforcement alone is not going to turn the tide, in my opinion. It will need to be a combination of enforcement actions paired with dedicated efforts to harden systems, develop, and operationalize backups of key data and systems, and effective response from the private sector.&#8221;</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s clear that more action is needed, the U.S. government is making progress. While a handful of prosecutions has been mocked by some, it&#8217;s clearly had an impact &#8212; particularly on ransomware groups&#8217; ability to advertise and recruit potential partners. In the wake of this unwanted attention, ransomware was banned from several popular hacking forums, leading to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/fin7-fake-company-recruit-hacks/">one hacking group setting up a fake company</a> to lure unwitting IT specialists into supporting its continued expansion into the lucrative ransomware industry.</p>
<p>“Ransomware gangs are less welcome on certain cybercrime forums than they once were,&#8221; said Brett Callow, a ransomware expert and threat analyst at Emsisoft.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D7Xx6B8gfM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/six-things-we-learned-cybersecurity/">6 things in cybersecurity we didn&#8217;t know last year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;6 things in cybersecurity we didn&#8217;t know last year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/six-things-we-learned-cybersecurity/embed/#?secret=D7Xx6B8gfM" data-secret="D7Xx6B8gfM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-year-the-tide-turned-on-ransomware/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252122</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voyant raises $15M to scale production of its tiny, inexpensive lidar tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/voyant-raises-15m-to-scale-production-of-its-tiny-inexpensive-lidar-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/voyant-raises-15m-to-scale-production-of-its-tiny-inexpensive-lidar-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 17:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lidar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[up.partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voyant photonics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The future of lidar is uncertain unless, as Voyant hopes to do, its price and size are reduced to fractions of their current values. As long as lidars are sandwich-sized devices that cost thousands, they won&#8217;t be ubiquitous — so Voyant has raised some cash to bring its smaller, cheaper, more easily manufactured, yet still [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The future of lidar is uncertain unless, as Voyant hopes to do, its price and size are reduced to fractions of their current values. As long as lidars are sandwich-sized devices that cost thousands, they won&#8217;t be ubiquitous — so Voyant has raised some cash to bring its smaller, cheaper, more easily manufactured, yet still highly capable lidar to production.</p>
<p>When I wrote up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/16/voyant-photonics-raises-4-3m-to-fit-lidar-on-the-head-of-a-pin/">the company&#8217;s seed round back in 2019</a>, the goal was more or less to shrink lidar down from sandwich to fingernail size using silicon photonics. But the real challenge faced by nearly every lidar company is getting the price down. Between a strong laser, capable receptor and a mechanical or optical means of directing the beam, it just isn&#8217;t easy making something cheap enough that, like an LED or touchscreen, you can easily put several of them in a vehicle that costs less than $30,000.</p>
<p>CEO Peter Stern joined the company just as COVID was getting started, and they were looking for a way to turn a promising prototype developed by co-founders Chris Phare and Steven Miller into a working and marketable product. After going back to basics they ended up with a photonics-based frequency-modulated continuous wave (FMCW) system (just go with it for now) that could be manufactured at existing commercial fabs.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251603" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Every other system is filled with a lot of expensive stuff — our vision is a mass-produceable chip, like anything else,&#8221; he said, and noted the lack of a powerful precision laser as a huge savings to cost and space. &#8220;What people use as a laser source generally costs a lot, needs assembly and calibration, there are lens issues&#8230; our laser sources are basically out of date, slightly refurbished datacom lasers the size of sesame seeds. These things cost like $5 each, the laser path costs $30, something like that.&#8221;</p>
<p>This tiny scale is made possible by the FMCW method, used more often in radar. A continuous beam of light encoded with identifiable data patterns and constantly adjusting its frequency, this approach avoids many issues with traditional lidar methods. And the way Voyant does it, it&#8217;s cheap &#8212; possible to get under a hundred bucks with scale. All the optics, beam handling and sensing and so on is right there on the chip.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2252191" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252191" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2252191" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg" alt="" width="980" height="629" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg 980w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg?resize=768,493 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg?resize=680,436 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lidar-waveguides.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 980px) 100vw, 980px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2252191" class="wp-caption-text">Close-up of some of the waveguides found on the lidar chip. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Voyant Photonics</p></div></p>
<p>But they&#8217;re not going up against Velodyne or any of the upstart lidar companies duking it out in the automotive sector like Luminar and Baraja. &#8220;We&#8217;re too underfunded to take us through an automotive development cycle,&#8221; Stern said — and indeed it&#8217;s quite an expensive market to try to break into. &#8220;Because we&#8217;re cheaper, we see applications in robotics, mobility, industrial safety&#8230; anywhere someone wants to use a Velodyne puck, we can displace them for non-automotive purposes pretty quickly.&#8221;</p>
<p>You may very well think &#8220;wait, I have lidar on my phone — what&#8217;s different about this?&#8221; Certainly you can make lidar units at this scale and size, but their capabilities are extremely limited. Great for scanning your living room, but unreliable past a few meters or in sunshine or bad weather. Voyant isn&#8217;t going for cars, but its devices still have auto-grade specs: millimeter accurate out to a hundred meters, the sort of thing you want when you&#8217;re traveling 70 MPH.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AqTzzH8T8a"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/lidar-startup-aeva-raises-another-200m-ahead-of-its-debut-as-a-public-company/">Lidar startup Aeva raises another $200M ahead of its debut as a public company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lidar startup Aeva raises another $200M ahead of its debut as a public company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/lidar-startup-aeva-raises-another-200m-ahead-of-its-debut-as-a-public-company/embed/#?secret=AqTzzH8T8a" data-secret="AqTzzH8T8a" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The FMCW technique (also used in Aeva&#8217;s lidars) produce fewer points, leading to lower resolution, but it provides instantaneous doppler velocity. Knowing how fast the thing your beam hit is moving without having to expend extra scanning power or computation is arguably a big plus.</p>
<p>Another interesting leg up it has on the competition is in the unit&#8217;s ability to discern not just distance and velocity, but at least to a certain extent <em>material</em>. This uses a measure of polarization, a factor of the beam that is affected in different ways by different surfaces. So from a single data point, Voyant&#8217;s devices should be able to tell whether something is metal, asphalt, wood, skin, clothing or fur — among other things. That&#8217;s unbelievably useful for categorizing objects — if it has fur on it, it&#8217;s probably not a tree or a car, right?</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2252189" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252189" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2252189" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg" alt="Block diagram of the Lark lidar test kit." width="1024" height="568" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg?resize=768,426 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg?resize=680,377 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/lark-block.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2252189" class="wp-caption-text">Block diagram of the Lark lidar test kit. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Voyant Photonics</p></div></p>
<p>The $15.4 million A round was led by UP.Partners, with participation from LDV Capital and Contour Ventures. The company plans to use the money to move toward production by putting its development kits in the hands of partners. The &#8220;Lark&#8221; is the more traditional of the two, bouncing the laser signal off a galvo mirror, while the &#8220;Sparrow&#8221; unit uses a 2D beam steering technique that further reduces the need for mechanical components.</p>
<p>Stern said they&#8217;ll be making about 200 units for partners in 2022, and then will start taking commercial orders in 2023. By that time the automotive world may have taken note, but if Voyant&#8217;s strategy succeeds, it will have slipped a good piece of the industrial market out of reach of companies making larger, more expensive units.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/voyant-raises-15m-to-scale-production-of-its-tiny-inexpensive-lidar-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251603</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The best tech of CES 2012</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-best-tech-of-ces-2012/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-best-tech-of-ces-2012/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 17:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2022]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Consumer electronics are a bad metric for gauging the passage of time. And, frankly, Consumer Electronics Shows are considerably worse. I’ve attended well into the double digits of CES and have largely experienced them in similar manner: as a week-long flurry of news and shiny gadgets, filing news from trailers, press centers, hotel rooms and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Consumer electronics are a bad metric for gauging the passage of time. And, frankly, Consumer Electronics Shows are considerably worse. I’ve attended well into the double digits of CES and have largely experienced them in similar manner: as a week-long flurry of news and shiny gadgets, filing news from trailers, press centers, hotel rooms and convention center hallway floors in a sometimes quixotic attempt to define the year’s trends.</p>
<p>The halls of the Las Vegas Convention Center and its many satellite Expo Halls and hotel suites are thick with the ghosts of good intentions and forced obsolescence. That’s the nature of the category. Some of the devices that have become our daily drivers over the past decade debuted at CES, but more often than not, devices come and go &#8212; if they ever end up making it to store shelves in the first place.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/more-companies-bow-out-of-in-person-ces-presence/">CES 2022 will be a strange one</a> &#8212; a fact that has more to do with extenuating global circumstances than anything happening on the show floor (though, last I heard, one of the Backstreet Boys will still be on hand to show off home boxing equipment). Questions around the relevance of in-person conferences pre-dated COVID-19, of course &#8212; though CES has always felt like an exception, owing to the importance of being in the same room with the hardware being announced.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252172" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>After narrowly missing pandemic-related shutdowns in 2020, CES 2021 was a dry run for what an all-virtual future might look like. The results were…half-baked. CES 2012, on the other hand, had none of those issues. After a bit of dip in previous years (owing to a global recession), the show boasted its best-ever attendance of 153,000. The growth would continue over the next several years, as the event continued to take over Vegas, peaking again at around 182,000 in 2019, according to the CTA.</p>
<p>In 2012, CES still felt like something of a phone show in a way that no longer exists. Between Mobile World Congress the following month and the decision for many of the big companies to follow in Apple’s footsteps by announcing their flagships on their own time, CES isn’t the same epicenter of phone news it once was. Though that void has been quickly filled by other categories in the subsequent decade &#8212; including, most notably, automotive, which has moved front and center.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2026759" style="width: 4010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2026759" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2026759 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg" alt="" width="4000" height="2670" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-453573862.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2026759" class="wp-caption-text">Color-coded cables run into the radio unit of Sprint Corp. 8T8R equipment, the multiple antenna technology which combines eight-transmit and eight-receive radios at a cell site to boost the performance of Sprint&#8217;s LTE TDD 2.5 GHz spectrum, on a rooftop in Chicago, Illinois, U.S., on Wednesday, Aug. 13, 2014. Sprint reported its first quarterly profit in more than six years in July, with sales that topped analysts&#8217; estimates, after holding onto more subscribers than projected. Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg via Getty Images.</p></div></p>
<p>LTE was everywhere at<a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2012/"> CES 2012</a>, much like the 5G bombardment of a few years back. CNET even went so far as saucily calling the show <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/ces-2012-a-4g-orgy-but-android-ics-is-still-mia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a “4G Orgy”</a> in a headline. Five years after Sprint demoed Wimax in Vegas for the show, it was officially ready to jump ship and join the rest of the world in LTE-land. The<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/01/09/playstation-certified-xperia-s-sony/"> Sony Xperia S</a> grabbed headlines, as did the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/02/17/motorola-droid-4-review-this-keyboard-rocks-but-thats-about-it/">Droid 4</a>, Motorola’s valiant attempt to keep the physical keyboard alive five years after the first iPhone marked the beginning of the end of the BlackBerry’s reign.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_535698" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-535698" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-535698" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/lumia-900-8.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-535698" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>But the show truly belonged to one of two LTE-sporting Windows Phone devices announced at the show. The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/05/11/htc-titan-ii-review-sometimes-a-win-win-is-a-lose/">HTC Titan II</a> may have been the first device on the OS to sport the next-gen wireless technology, but the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/04/15/nokia-lumia-900-review-this-ones-a-no-brainer/">Nokia Lumia 900</a> captured attendees’ imaginations with a 4.3-inch AMOLED display, 8-megapixel rear-facing camera, 512MB of RAM and an eye-catching design.</p>
<p>A year prior, straight-talking CEO Stephen Elop <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/06/21/jumping-off-the-burning-platform-nokia-knew-it-was-stuck-on-wp7-when-it-signed-on/">compared the company’s woes</a> to a man standing on a burning platform in the middle of icy waters. The partnership with Microsoft was Nokia’s leap. A year later, Nokia would sell off its mobile division to Microsoft.</p>
<p>Like the Droid 4’s valiant &#8212; if ultimately doomed &#8212; attempt to hang onto the QWERTY keyboard, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/01/09/sony-intros-bloggie-live-bloggie-sport-pocket-cams-to-combat-camera-phones/">Sony’s Bloggie</a> was a last gasp for standalone blogging camcorders. This was a year after Cisco shut down its Flip Video business, after acquiring the then-red hot pocket camcorder in 2009 for $590 million. Leave it to Sony to say “screw it,” and attempt to squeeze the last few embers from a dying category.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_457776" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-457776" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-457776" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/acer.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="427" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/acer.jpg 640w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/acer.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/acer.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/acer.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><p id="caption-attachment-457776" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>And then there were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/10/01/remember-ultrabooks-yeah-that-was-a-good-time/">the ultrabooks</a>. If the category can be said to have had a moment, it was those five days in Las Vegas. By mid-year, the stories about the death of the category had already begun. Coined by Intel and announced at Computex 2011, the category was the latest thin-and-light classification &#8212; really, an attempt for PC-makers to offer their own take on the MacBook Air.</p>
<p>Intel offered strict guidance for the category, focused on things like thinness, weight and battery life. The category was, ultimately, cost-prohibitive and doomed by ever shifting goal posts of specs and the rise of smartphones and tablets.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_582745" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-582745" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-582745" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/517408197_3_o.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-582745" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>At CES 2012, desktop 3D printing was the future, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/01/09/makerbot-announces-their-latest-3d-printer-the-replicator/">MakerBot was front and center</a>. The NYC-based spinout of the RepRap open source project used the show to debut the Replicator. A significant improvement over its previous Thing-O-Matic system, the system sported a Star Trek-inspired name and felt like a major step toward a dream of a 3D printer in every home.</p>
<p>Pricing, technical limitations and the arrival of more advanced technology from companies like Formlabs damped the fortunes of many companies in the space, in what ultimately proved a fairly massive tech hype bubble. A year later, MakerBot was acquired by 3D printing giant Stratasys, which has focused on the technology for the educational market.</p>
<p>As always, CES brings plenty of concepts that seem destined to stay conceptual. The Samsung Smart Window is pretty much par for the course on that front. The transparent window display with touchscreen functionality captured the eye of many show goers in an era where everyone seemed to want everything to be a giant screen, but never seemed to make it much further than CES booth dressing. As a footnote, the company has since invested in an artificial smart window<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/18/a-smart-highlighter-and-artificial-window-are-among-samsungs-latest-c-lab-spinoffs/"> as part of its C-Lab initiative</a>, because, again, the consumer electronics industry is a weirdly cyclical one, for all of its talk about forward progress.</p>
<p>Ten years out, CES 2012 may appear more miss than hit. Certainly the most hyped products tend to be the ones that suffer the most in hindsight. We never made it to 3D printers and smart windows in every home, but hey, LTE had a pretty good run.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2022/?utm_source=internal&amp;utm_medium=footer-banner"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ces-2022-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about CES 2022 on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/the-best-tech-of-ces-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252172</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Not every creator economy startup is built for creators</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/not-every-creator-economy-startup-is-built-for-creators/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/not-every-creator-economy-startup-is-built-for-creators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 16:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fourthwall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patreon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The inherent tension within the creator economy lies between the promise of financial freedom and the realization this freedom comes at a cost.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ten years ago, if you were a scrappy kid somehow making a living off of YouTube ad revenue and brand deals, you were probably told you didn&#8217;t have a real job. Now, if monetizing your creative output is how you pay your rent, you&#8217;re part of the creator economy, a buzzy new industry.</p>
<p>An <a href="https://signalfire.com/blog/creator-economy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">often-cited landmark report</a> from the venture capital firm SignalFire says that creators are the fastest-growing type of small business. Despite the creator economy only really forming a decade ago, there are now 50 million people who consider themselves &#8220;creators,&#8221; and more American children want to be YouTube stars (29%) than astronauts (11%), per SignalFire. So it makes sense that more and more startups are cropping up to provide tools for creators &#8212; it&#8217;s an opportunity to cash in on a growing market, and savvy entrepreneurs want to make money.</p>
<p>As this market has expanded, I&#8217;ve written about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/a-bank-for-the-creator-economy-karat-raises-26m-in-series-a-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">credit card companies for creators</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/playground-launches-in-beta-to-help-creators-cultivate-community/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">community-building tools</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/cobalt-launches-from-beta-with-a-2-8m-seed-to-help-creators-launch-products/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">companies that help you design a product to sell,</a> among other ventures. But as my inbox teems with too many creator-focused startup pitches, products and opportunities to ever even consider, I&#8217;ve noticed a troubling trend &#8212; not all of these businesses are actually good for the creators they intend to serve. Some might actually be pretty predatory.</p>
<p>For example, if an all-in-one creator platform folds, what does that mean for creators who put all their eggs in that basket? How do major tech acquisitions impact the people who monetize on those platforms? As <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/7kb9mg/a-former-facebook-vp-thinks-investing-in-humans-is-the-future-of-vc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">venture capitalists invest in creators</a> as though they&#8217;re startups, how can those creators protect themselves from exploitative terms and conditions?</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Startups need to have a backup plan to make sure that if they don&#8217;t become the next Patreon, the creators who trusted them won&#8217;t be doomed.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</span></p>
<p>Startups need to have a backup plan to make sure that if they don&#8217;t become the next Patreon, the creators who trusted them won&#8217;t be doomed. I&#8217;ve started asking these questions to any startup that purports to be a &#8220;one-stop shop&#8221; or an &#8220;all-in-one solution&#8221; to the creator economy. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/18/fourthwall-raises-17m-for-its-all-in-one-creator-commerce-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fourthwall</a> had a good answer.</p>
<p>The company said that it has three months of emergency operating expenses set aside to ensure that if they were to fail, they could help transition creators to other platforms. Fourthwall also said it would make its platform open source if this were to happen. But regardless, this friction isn&#8217;t exactly helpful.</p>
<p>The inherent tension within the creator economy lies between the promise of financial freedom and the realization this freedom comes at a cost. As more startups aim to connect talent with brand deals, build monetization tools and develop new social platforms, creators need to know what to look out for to avoid a bad situation &#8212; and startups themselves need to think as though they&#8217;re in a creator&#8217;s shoes, understanding that if a creator trusts them with their business, then they have a moral and financial obligation not to screw it up.</p>
<h2>&#8220;A platform is not your friend&#8221;</h2>
<p>When Spotify <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/14/spotify-gimlet-anchor-340-million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bought</a> the popular podcast creation service Anchor in 2019, podcasters panicked. But Amanda McLoughlin, CEO of the independent podcast collective Multitude Productions, had seen massive acquisitions like this happen before. Since the early days of YouTube, McLoughlin has been a creator herself, so she&#8217;s seen the industry change from both creative and business perspectives. One defining moment in her early life as an internet creator was when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2006/10/09/google-has-acquired-youtube/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google bought YouTube</a> in 2006.</p>
<p>&#8220;Before 9 a.m., I got a dozen messages from friends and colleagues worried about what such a large and unexpected consolidation means for those of us trying to make a living in podcasting,&#8221; McLoughlin <a href="https://medium.com/@shessomickey/3-lessons-for-podcasters-from-someone-who-lived-through-youtubes-buyout-1beacbcfbcb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote at the time</a>. So she rehashed the lessons she learned from the YouTube acquisition: Diversify your income streams, don’t trust individual platforms too much and believe in your own value.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/not-every-creator-economy-startup-is-built-for-creators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249497</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yukai Engineering&#8217;s cute stuffed animal robot will nibble on your finger</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/yukai-engineerings-cute-stuffed-animal-robot-will-nibble-on-your-finger/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/yukai-engineerings-cute-stuffed-animal-robot-will-nibble-on-your-finger/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 16:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yukai Engineering, the maker of the Qoobo robotic cat tail pillow, has revealed a soft robot that nibbles on a user’s fingertip. They hopes the "somewhat pleasing sensation" will brighten your day.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/sidewalk-labs-products-will-be-folded-into-google-proper/">Sidewalk Labs products will be folded into Google proper</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/toyotas-latest-ev-concepts-include-sports-cars-and-a-pickup/">Toyota’s latest EV concepts include sports cars and a pickup</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">It wouldn’t be <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/ces%202022/" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1"><ins>CES season</ins></a> without at least a couple of offbeat robots showing up. Yukai Engineering, the maker of the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/qoobo/" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1"><ins>Qoobo robotic cat tail pillow</ins></a>, has revealed a soft robot that nibbles on a user’s fingertip. The company hopes the &#8220;somewhat pleasing sensation&#8221; will brighten up your day.</p>
<p><a href="https://hamham.ux-xu.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1"><ins>Amagami Ham Ham</ins></a> has an algorithm called a “Hamgorithm” that selects one of two dozen nibbling patterns, so you’ll never be sure exactly what you’ll feel when you shove your digit into the robot’s maw. Yukai designed the patterns — which include Tasting Ham, Massaging Ham and Suction Ham — to replicate the feeling of a baby or pet nibbling on one’s finger.</p>
<div id="outstreamPlayer-inArticle" class="basePlayer expandedPlayer playerCollapsed">
<div id="outstream-adText"></div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252162" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2021-12%2Fcdba0260-6981-11ec-9aff-8160bca77886&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=74c3df161ba047ab83e634599f46dda8054dc83f" alt="A soft robot called Amagami Ham Ham " data-uuid="aa34e227-1d5b-36f0-8aea-5f2488291e35" /><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Yukai Corporation</div>
</figure>
<p>“Amagami” means “soft biting” and “ham” means “bite” in Japanese. Yukai based the look of the robot on a character from Liv Heart Corporation’s Nemu Nemu stuffed animal series. There’ll be a couple of finger-munching models to choose from: Yuzu (Calico Cat) and Kotaro (Shiba Inu).</p>
<p>“Most people like the nibbling sensation but know they need to teach their children or pets to stop it, because kids and animals will otherwise bite them with full force eventually,&#8221; said Yukai Engineering CMO Tsubasa Tominaga, who invented the robot at a hackathon earlier this year. &#8220;Amagami Ham Ham is a robot that frees humankind from the conundrum of whether ‘to pursue or not to pursue’ the forbidden pleasure.”</p>
<p>Pricing hasn&#8217;t been determined, but Yukai and Liv Heart plan to run a crowdfunding campaign in the spring. In the meantime, those braving CES can check out Amagami Ham Ham at the show, and perhaps leave Yukai&#8217;s booth with a slightly more tender finger.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_GiQswlhps4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Among the other devices Yukai will show off at CES is Bocco Emo. The company has updated the original <a href="https://japanese.engadget.com/jp-2015-05-12-bocco-kickstarter.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">Bocco robot</a> to act as a smart medical device. Yukai says hospitals in Japan are using it to monitor patients&#8217; vitals (via connected sensors like pulse oximeters and thermometers) and notify nurses about a patient&#8217;s condition.</p>
<p>During a pilot period, Bocco Emo was used to inform patients&#8217; families about how they&#8217;re doing. It can also communicate with patients using sound effects, facial expressions and gestures while they wait for a nurse to arrive.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/yukai-engineering-amagami-ham-ham-soft-robot-finger-nibble-160043421.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/yukai-engineerings-cute-stuffed-animal-robot-will-nibble-on-your-finger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252162</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>African tech took center stage in 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/african-tech-took-center-stage-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/african-tech-took-center-stage-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4DX Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Algebra Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bankly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cairo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dfs lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dubai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edukoya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ejara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equinix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flutterwave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interswitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jetstream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jumia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klasha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lagos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LoftyInc Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MainOne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morocco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ozow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PalmPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam altman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sawari Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shuttlers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SVB Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swvl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TymeBank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uLesson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united arab emirates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vision Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voltron Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worldremit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zip]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two years ago, the African tech ecosystem saw newfound attention from global players that translated to the continent’s best year of receiving venture capital. From varying sources, it is estimated up to $2 billion went into African tech startups in 2019. With high-profile visits from the most famous Jacks (Ma and Dorsey), a long-awaited first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two years ago, the African tech ecosystem saw newfound attention from global players that translated to the continent’s best year </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> receiving venture capital. From varying sources, it is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/04/did-african-startups-raise-496m-1b-or-2b-in-2019/">estimated up to $2 billion </a>went </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">into African tech startups in 2019.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With high-profile visits from the most famous Jacks (Ma and Dorsey), a long-awaited first IPO by e-commerce giant Jumia and massive $100 million rounds, it was a sign of things to come for African tech.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But two months into 2020, the pandemic did an excellent job of lowering expectations as investment activities from local and international investors slowed down.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252098" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It wasn’t a bad year, though. African startups nearly raised $1.5 billion and saw a couple of fascinating exits: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/15/stripe-acquires-nigerias-paystack-for-200m-to-expand-into-the-african-continent/">Stripe-Paystack</a> and <a href="https://www.worldremit.com/en/news/worldremit-completes-sendwave-acquisition-and-appoints-two-executives">WorldRemit-Sendwave</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Entering 2021, the bullishness of African tech stakeholders returned &#8212; and why not? As businesses reopened globally and the pandemic drove people to adopt new habits in e-commerce, work, spending money, online delivery, and learning, venture capital into various industries </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was poised</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to increase </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">immensely,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and Africa would not be exempt.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Predictions </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were made</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on how much the continent’s startups would raise in December</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">AfricArena, a tech ecosystem accelerator, pegged <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/">deals to close between $2.25 billion and $2.8 billion</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Stephen Deng, the co-founder and partner of DFS Lab, a firm that invests in digital commerce startups, </span><a href="https://twitter.com/mrstephendeng/status/1388264008415727616?s=21"><span style="font-weight: 400;">serially compared </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">the 2016 Southeast Asia funding landscape to where Africa might be in 2021, at $3 billion.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7iv1q2O0bV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/">Venture capital investment in Africa predicted to reach a record high this year</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture capital investment in Africa predicted to reach a record high this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/venture-capital-investment-in-africa-predicted-to-reach-a-record-high-this-year/embed/#?secret=7iv1q2O0bV" data-secret="7iv1q2O0bV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These predictions weren’t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">entirely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> off the mark. In the end, information from the likes of <a href="https://thebigdeal.substack.com/p/the-bar-is-set-very-very-high-for">Maxime Bayen</a> and <a href="https://www.briterintelligence.com/overview">Briter Bridges</a> made 2019 numbers look like child’s play. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">2021 was when African tech reached an inflection point and took center stage as companies raised over $4 billion (more than they got in 2019 and 2020 combined)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From minting five unicorns to witnessing more million-dollar raises by female CEOs, we spotlight some of the events that shaped this pivotal moment in African tech.</span></p>
<h2>What’s a record year of funding without some unicorns?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attaining unicorn status &#8212; a privately held company with a valuation of $1 billion &#8212; is undoubtedly one of the vainest achievements for any startup, yet it remains the most coveted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Africa, the first two unicorns were <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/03/04/africa-roundup-goldman-backs-startup-african-internet-group-to-become-continents-1st-unicorn/">Jumia</a> (in 2016) and fintech giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/12/african-e-commerce-startup-jumias-shares-open-at-14-50-in-nyse-ipo/">Interswitch</a> (in 2019). </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Jumia went public on the NYSE in 2019, it ceased to be a unicorn and became a typical billion-dollar </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">publicly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> held company</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a similar case with Egyptian payments company Fawry. It <a href="https://www.menabytes.com/fawry-goes-public/">went public</a> on the Egyptian stock market (the first indigenous tech company to do so on African soil) in 2019. However, unlike Jumia, Fawry only reached a billion-dollar valuation a year after going public. So, it isn’t and technically wasn’t a unicorn.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interswitch was the continent’s sole unicorn until five more </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were minted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this year. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Four are fintechs: Flutterwave, OPay, Wave and Chipper Cash, while one is tech talent marketplace Andela</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Flutterwave got its horn in March at $1 billion; OPay in August at $2 billion; Wave and Andela the following month, at $1.7 billion and $1.5 billion, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">; Andela in September raised at a $1.5 billion valuation; Chipper Cash in November at $2 billion. Meanwhile, Interswitch, the sole unicorn between 2019 and 2021, is worth $1 billion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A couple of reasons are behind this sudden surge in unicorn numbers on the continent. More experienced founders exist and specific markets, particularly in the Big Four (Nigeria, South Africa, Egypt and Kenya), show a mix of matured but still open-for-disruption traits.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, sectors such as fintech keep opening up in ways never seen before and there’s a rush of foreign money from first-time investors in early and later stages, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">simultaneously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2>International investors participated from pre-seed to Series E stages</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While global investors have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">previously</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> invested in African startups, their activity seemed more prominent in 2021, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">probably</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> because of their participation across the board.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, investors such as Berlin-based VC firm Target Global and renowned investment firm and hedge fund Tiger Global cut checks across early and growth stages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Target invested in both Series A rounds of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/kuda-raises-25m-more-led-by-valar-to-become-the-neobank-for-every-african-on-the-planet/">Kuda </a>and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/tiger-global-backs-african-fintech-mono-in-15m-series-a-round/">Mono</a> (including the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/kuda-the-african-challenger-bank-raises-55m-at-a-500m-valuation/">Series B round</a> of the former). The European VC also led the pre-seed rounds of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/18/nigerias-kippa-gets-3-2m-pre-seed-for-its-small-business-finance-management-app/">Kippa</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/target-global-leads-3-5m-pre-seed-in-nigerian-online-learning-platform-edukoya/">Edukoya</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. On</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the other hand, Tiger </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">led <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/tiger-global-leads-3m-round-in-zambias-union54-for-its-card-issuing-api/">Union54’s seed round</a>, Mono’s Series A and later rounds in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/tiger-global-leads-42m-series-b-in-nigerian-credit-led-neobank-fairmoney/">FairMoney</a> and Flutterwave</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other deals where growth firms participated in early and growth stages included Sequoia in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/sequoia-leads-5m-pre-seed-in-egypts-1-month-old-digital-bank-telda/">Telda’s pre-seed</a>; Wave’s Series A, via stealthy wealth management fund Sequoia Heritage; and OPay’s Series C, via its subsidiary fund Sequoia Capital China.   </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="B33hbjBAMP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/12/faster-deals-less-diligence-the-african-startup-market-mirrors-its-larger-rivals/">Faster deals, less diligence: The African startup market mirrors its larger rivals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Faster deals, less diligence: The African startup market mirrors its larger rivals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/12/faster-deals-less-diligence-the-african-startup-market-mirrors-its-larger-rivals/embed/#?secret=B33hbjBAMP" data-secret="B33hbjBAMP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was also action from other investors, such as Dragoneer, FTX, Fidelity, SVB Capital and Sam Altman, who </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">got involved</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in single large deals for the first time. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was routine for other firms like Tencent as it invested in the growth rounds of uLesson, Ozow and TymeBank&#8211; and SoftBank, who, via its Vision Fund 2, led two of the continent’s many nine-figure rounds in 2021: unicorns Andela and OPay</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2>African startups raised more $100M+ rounds this year than ever before</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">OPay had one of the three nine-figure deals in 2019 after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/operas-africa-fintech-startup-opay-gains-120m-from-chinese-investors/">raising a $120 million Series B round</a>. Others included Andela’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/23/connecting-african-software-developers-with-top-tech-companies-nets-andela-100-million/">$100 million</a> and Interswitch’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/11/nigerias-interswitch-confirms-1b-valuation-after-visa-investment/">$200 million</a> deals</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">So imagine the surprise the following year when no nine-figure deal took place (</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as the continent didn’t produce any unicorn)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The draught didn’t last long, as Africa not only had its highest unicorn year but also recorded the most nine-figure rounds (11 from 10 startups) in a single year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s start with the unicorns: </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Flutterwave’s Series C <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/african-payments-company-flutterwave-raises-170m-now-valued-at-over-1b/">was $170 million</a>; OPay raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/african-fintech-opay-valued-at-2b-in-softbank-vision-fund-2-led-400m-funding/">$400 million</a> Series C; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/sequoia-heritage-stripe-and-others-invest-200m-in-african-fintech-wave-at-1-7b-valuation/">Wave</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/softbank-sinks-200m-into-andela-propels-company-into-unicorn-territory/">Andela</a> each picked up $200 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then Chipper Cash did the double: a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/30/africa-has-another-unicorn-as-chipper-cash-raises-100m-series-c-led-by-svb-capital/">$100 million Series C</a> and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/chipper-cash-gets-2b-valuation-with-150m-extension-round-led-by-ftx/">$150 million extension</a> for its unicorn round months later</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Others include TymeBank’s $180 million Series B, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/08/fidelity-visa-and-kingsway-back-south-african-fintech-jumo-in-120m-round/">Jumo</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/egyptian-fintech-mnt-halan-lands-120m-from-apis-partners-disruptech-and-others/">MNT-Halan’s</a> $120 million rounds, TradeDepot’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/tradedepot-raises-110m-from-ifc-novastar-to-extend-bnpl-service-to-merchants-across-africa/">$110 million</a> and MFS Africa’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/mfs-africa-gets-100m-after-series-of-investments-and-acquisitions-in-the-past-year/">$100 million</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only non-fintech deals were Andela and TradeDepot (although the latter has an embedded finance play)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Also, all but two deals were </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">solely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> equity-based: TradeDepot and MFS Africa raised a mix of equity and debt.</span></p>
<h2>A handful of local acquisitions and a monumental exit</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Digital payments gateway <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/mfs-africa-gets-100m-after-series-of-investments-and-acquisitions-in-the-past-year/">MFS Africa</a> is one of Africa’s few corporate investors and acquirers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Over the past five years, the company has made strategic bets across overlooked startup regions in Africa, investing in Julaya, Maviance and Numida. And </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in terms of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> acquisitions, Beyonic and, <a href="https://techcabal.com/2021/10/20/mfs-africa-acquires-baxi/">most recently, Baxi</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last year, the trend of seeing local companies buy each other played out and continued into 2021. Some interesting acquisitions include TLcom-backed Kenyan consumer experience platform Ajua <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/kenyas-ajua-acquires-wayawaya-to-consolidate-consumer-experience-play-in-africa-smes/">buying WayaWaya</a>; Nigerian bus booking and Techstars-backed Treepz expanding into Ghana and Ugabus after getting <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/mobility-startup-plentywaka-picks-up-1-5m-seed-acquires-ghanas-stabus/">Stabus</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/nigerian-maas-startup-treepz-closes-2-8m-seed-round-to-fund-east-african-expansion/">Ugabus</a>; and Flutterwave making a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/flutterwave-acquires-disha-a-creator-platform-that-planned-to-shutter-in-february/">foray into the creator economy space</a> with the Disha acquisition.</span></p>
<p>Others include Jiji’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/jiji-acquires-cars45-as-it-looks-to-build-a-future-outside-classifieds/">acquisition</a> of Cars45, Egypt’s B2B e-commerce platform MaxAB <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/maxab-the-egyptian-b2b-food-and-grocery-delivery-startup-raises-40m-for-expansion/">purchasing YC-backed Waystocap</a>, thus expanding into Morocco, and Cheki <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/nigerias-autochek-acquires-cheki-kenya-and-uganda-from-roam-africa/">selling its businesses in Kenya and Uganda</a> to Nigeria’s Autochek.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like the MFS Africa-Baxi deal &#8212; which both parties claimed to be the second-largest fintech acquisition in Africa after Stripe-Paystack &#8212; the other acquisitions listed </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were undisclosed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why African startups don’t disclose their acquisition figure is a topic for another day. Personally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, reporting such deals may not be appealing going forward (if they remain undisclosed) unless they involve international expansion plays.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Case in point: Nigerian healthtech Helium Health <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/nigerias-helium-health-acquires-uaes-meddy-in-rare-africa-gcc-deal/">acquiring UAE’s Meddy</a> (the first of its kind between sub-Saharan Africa and the GCC) and Australian BNPL player Zip <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/03/zip-acquisition-of-payflex-means-africa-is-ripe-for-bnpl-disruption/">buying up South Africa’s PayFlex</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And international expansion via acquisition gets more exciting when a figure </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is attached</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">; for instance, data center</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Equinix</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/equinix-is-acquiring-nigerias-mainone-for-320m-as-it-expands-into-africa/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> announced that it would </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">acquire</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Nigeria’s</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">MainOne</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/equinix-is-acquiring-nigerias-mainone-for-320m-as-it-expands-into-africa/">, for $320 million</a>. The news was the highlight for this year’s acquisition deals, not only for its size but also because MainOne is a female-led company, with <a href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/funke-opeke/">Funke Opeke</a> as its CEO.</span></p>
<h2>More female-led startups raised million-dollar rounds</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Funke Opeke is one of the very few founders to have come this far: running an African </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">tech company to the point of exit. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">She’s also </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">probably</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the only female founder on the continent to have raised nine figures </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">cumulatively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for her business</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Opeke’s experience is an outlier. In Africa and globally, funding doesn’t come easy for female-led companies. A report by Briter Bridges from the middle of this year looked at 1,100+ companies to have received VC money between 2013 and May 2021 (pegged at $20 million or less).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Per the report, only 3% of the $1.7 billion raised within this period went to all-female founding teams compared to 76% for all-male teams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, it’s great news when female-led startups raise a million dollars or more in Africa. And it indirectly contributes to how well the region performs, as we can attest to this year which recorded more than ten deals, signalling an improvement in VCs (both gender-focused and gender-agnostic) </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">sourcing for female-led teams to invest in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The female-led startups that raised a million dollars or more this year include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/16/nigerian-shared-mobility-startup-shuttlers-raises-1-5m-plans-pan-african-expansion/">Shuttlers</a>, </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/nigerian-fintech-of-the-unbanked-bankly-raises-2m-led-by-vault-and-flutterwave/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bankly</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/kenyas-lami-raises-1-8m-to-scale-api-insurance-platform-across-africa/">Lami</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/nigerian-fintech-okra-raises-3-5m-backed-by-accenture-ventures-and-susa-ventures/">Okra</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/backed-by-greycroft-klasha-gets-2-4m-to-improve-cross-border-commerce-in-africa/">Klasha</a>, <a href="https://disrupt-africa.com/2021/07/16/sa-lending-startup-akiba-digital-raises-1-1m-pre-seed-funding-for-scale/">Akiba Digital</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/cameroons-ejara-raises-2m-to-offer-crypto-and-investment-services-in-francophone-africa/">Ejara</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/kenyas-fintech-kwara-lands-4-million-in-seed-round-from-breega-softbank-to-build-neobank-for-credit-unions/">Kwara</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/target-global-leads-3-5m-pre-seed-in-nigerian-online-learning-platform-edukoya/">Edukoya</a>, <a href="https://reelfruit.com/reelfruit-raises-3-million-series-a-funding-to-expand-production-with-new-factory/">Reelfruit</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/ghanas-jetstream-lands-3m-to-build-the-digital-infrastructure-for-africas-trade-corridors/">Jetstream</a>.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PgporwrdiA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/mainone-ceo-funke-opeke-says-equinix-is-buying-her-company-for-the-right-price/">MainOne CEO Funke Opeke says Equinix is buying her company for the right price</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MainOne CEO Funke Opeke says Equinix is buying her company for the right price&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/mainone-ceo-funke-opeke-says-equinix-is-buying-her-company-for-the-right-price/embed/#?secret=PgporwrdiA" data-secret="PgporwrdiA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Local investors &#8212; and founders &#8212; stepped up their game</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/women-focused-pe-fund-alitheia-idf-raises-100-million-to-invest-in-gender-diverse-businesses-across-africa/">Alitheia IDF</a> is an investor in Reelfruit and Jetstream. The women-focused firm, led by principal partners Tokunboh Ishmael and Polo Leteka, has a $100 million private equity fund for gender-diverse businesses in Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s also one of the local funds that raised huge sums of money this year to write checks for African startups across different stages</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Others include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/16/ventures-platform-announces-first-close-of-its-40m-pan-african-fund/">Ventures Platform</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/loftyinc-capital-launches-third-fund-at-10m-for-a-more-diverse-portfolio-of-african-startups/">LoftyInc Capital</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/one-of-nigerias-high-profile-angel-investors-is-launching-a-fund-for-african-startups/">Voltron Capital</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/4dx-ventures-closes-second-fund-with-60m-adds-dikembe-mutombo-as-senior-advisor/">4DX Ventures</a>, all sub-Saharan-based VC firms with a pan-African strategy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Up north, investors such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/05/sawari-ventures-finally-closes-71m-fund-for-north-african-startups/">Sawari Ventures </a>and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/after-its-first-54m-fund-algebra-ventures-launches-another-90m-fund-for-startups-in-egypt/">Algebra Ventures</a> pulled their weight backing startups, particularly in Egypt, where startup innovation and investment has taken off </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">astronomically</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Local and Africa-focused investors also took up entire seed to Series A rounds of some companies in sub-Saharan Africa (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/nigerian-fintech-software-provider-appzone-raises-10m-to-expand-and-grow-engineering-team/">Appzone</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/nigerias-lender-payhippo-raises-3-million-in-seed-funding-to-extend-quick-loans-to-smes/">Payhippo</a>, to name a few), which rarely happened in previous years. Future Africa, Kepple Africa, Launch Africa, and others continued with their pace from 2020 and wrote many new and follow-on checks this year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We even noticed how active founders like Flutterwave CEO Olugbenga’ GB’ Agboola, Paystack founders Shola Akinlade and Ezra Olubi, and Chipper Cash founders Ham Serunjogi and Maijid Moujaled took part in some early-stage rounds too.</span></p>
<h2>Nigeria became the unicorn capital; Egypt, a powerhouse</h2>
<p>In November 2019, three fintech companies, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/11/nigerias-interswitch-confirms-1b-valuation-after-visa-investment/">Interswitch</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/17/operas-africa-fintech-startup-opay-gains-120m-from-chinese-investors/">OPay</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/12/palmpay-launches-in-nigeria-on-40m-round-led-by-chinas-transsion/">PalmPay</a>, raised a cumulative $360 million from American and Chinese investors. That announced Nigeria as Africa’s unofficial capital for fintech investment and digital finance startups.</p>
<p>Fintech opportunity in Nigeria is the largest on the continent. With over 40% of Nigerian adults having bank accounts and digital payments hitting more than $250 billion in 2019, it’s no surprise that the startups facilitating transactions for the unbanked (OPay) and providing gateways (Interswitch and Flutterwave) are now worth more than $1 billion.</p>
<p>The three companies, including Andela, started operations in Nigeria’s commercial city, Lagos, earning Nigeria the status of Africa’s unicorn capital in 2021.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a long time, Nigeria has been one of the three countries that receive the bulk of local and international venture capital, including Kenya and South Africa. The three countries present Africa’s most connected populace and growing economy; the perfect environment to attract foreign capital before others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But then Egypt stepped into the picture in 2017, and with time, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the North African country became part of the “Big Four” as the country began attracting venture capital eyeballs. And a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">fter </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">quietly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> spending the last couple of years at the rear, Egypt picked up </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">impressively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2020 and this year surpassed Kenya to become the region’s third most active investment region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As this <a href="https://www.theafricareport.com/149429/egypt-is-rapidly-rising-to-top-spot-in-africas-startup-ecosystem/">report</a> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">aptly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> put: “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seemingly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from nowhere, Egypt is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">suddenly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on the radar as a key African startup funding destination, highlighting the prospects for continental growth of the nascent sector.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Egypt also has bragging rights in producing the first SPAC deal on the continent. In July, Cairo and Dubai-based ridesharing company Swvl <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/egyptian-ride-sharing-company-swvl-plans-to-go-public-in-a-1-5b-spac-merger/">announced that it was going public via a merger</a> with Queen’s Gambit Growth Capital. It’s a deal that will value Swvl, one of the country’s success stories, at almost $1.5 billion once completed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With a large population and impressive GDP per capita, the North African country raised almost $600 million this year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. While it’s less than what Nigeria and South Africa raised at over $1.4 billion and $830 million, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">respectively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, some observers predict that Egypt will surpass South Africa by next year if it keeps up with its pace.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a few reasons behind this thinking. In Nigeria, South Africa and Kenya, fintech is the sector that receives the most funding. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The major sector is e-commerce and retail in Egypt, but the country is a hot spot for fintech, too, evident in holding the highest pre-seed rounds in both categories</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Rabbit’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/rabbit-a-20-minute-convenience-delivery-startup-in-egypt-comes-out-of-stealth-with-11m-pre-seed/">$11 million</a> and Telda’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/sequoia-leads-5m-pre-seed-in-egypts-1-month-old-digital-bank-telda/">$5 million</a> rounds).</span></p>
<p>When I wrote <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/how-fintech-and-serial-founders-drove-african-pre-seed-investing-to-new-heights-in-2020/">this piece</a> earlier this year, the largest pre-seed round at the time was Autochek’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/nigerias-autochek-raises-3-4m-for-car-sales-and-service-platform/">$3.4 million</a>. Rabbit’s eight-figure pre-seed is thrice that amount. Sources recently told TechCrunch that another Egyptian startup will close a pre-seed round that high next year.</p>
<p>Mindblowing pre-seed investments like these are one of the many indicators of how fast venture capital has picked up in Africa. The continent’s startups raised over $4 billion this year and minted five unicorns. No one knows what to expect in 2022, but there’s a nuanced sanguinity that we would see “more of everything” including some IPOs (I might be reaching here) so brace yourselves.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k5idJMW4MI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/">How African startups raised investments in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How African startups raised investments in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/how-african-startups-raised-investments-in-2020/embed/#?secret=k5idJMW4MI" data-secret="k5idJMW4MI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/african-tech-took-center-stage-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252098</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech-led biofuel startup Koko Networks launches new consumer goods business in Kenya</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/tech-led-biofuel-startup-koko-networks-launches-new-consumer-goods-business-in-kenya/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/tech-led-biofuel-startup-koko-networks-launches-new-consumer-goods-business-in-kenya/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 09:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koko Networks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Koko Networks, a Kenya-based bio-fuel technology enterprise, has extended its business to cover other fast-moving consumer goods through a new tech platform that will capitalize on its established distribution networks in low-income neighborhoods. Koko Club, its new business line, is selling the products directly to consumers through the dukas (small shops) that currently serve as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://kokonetworks.com/koko-fuel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Koko Networks</a>, a Kenya-based bio-fuel technology enterprise, has extended its business to cover other fast-moving consumer goods through a new tech platform that will capitalize on its established distribution networks in low-income neighborhoods.</p>
<p>Koko Club, its new business line, is selling the products directly to consumers through the dukas (small shops) that currently serve as the company’s agents for its bio-ethanol cooking fuel and stoves.</p>
<p>The Koko Club products, displayed in designated spaces within the agents&#8217; small shops, will only be sold to registered Koko Club members.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252110" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The shop owners (agents) are using Koko’s PoS system to sign up customers, capturing their biodata, and issuing them with an electronic card that they will use when buying products from any Koko Club shop.</p>
<p>The customer cards are linked to an e-wallet, similar to the one currently used to purchase Koko’s bio-fuel, and which can be topped up via mobile money and other technologies.</p>
<p>Koko Club is sourcing products directly from manufacturers and manage the inventory through a real-time management system that prevents stockouts, in addition to providing accurate market analytics.</p>
<p>With 35 SKUs under its portfolio, initially, Koko Club is keeping the prices of its products competitive by shortening the supply chains from manufacturer to consumers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“We are targeting low-income households by bringing them the benefits of better products, lower prices and convenience. This is in addition to making sure that we have the right assortment of products all the time,” Koko Networks co-founder and chief innovation officer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sagunsaxena/?originalSubdomain=ke" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sagun Saxena</a> told TechCrunch. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregmurraycleanstar/?originalSubdomain=ke" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Greg Murray</a> is the startup&#8217;s other co-founder and CEO.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2252112" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2252112" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2252112" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KokoClub.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="666" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KokoClub.jpeg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KokoClub.jpeg?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KokoClub.jpeg?resize=300,195 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KokoClub.jpeg?resize=768,500 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KokoClub.jpeg?resize=680,443 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/KokoClub.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2252112" class="wp-caption-text">Koko Club is a technology-enabled retail platform targeting consumers in low-income neighborhoods. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Koko Networks</p></div></p>
<p>Micro-retail outlets, which account for <a href="https://nextbillion.net/informal-retailers-mobile-solutions-emerging-markets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">80%</a> of Sub-Saharan Africa’s household retail trade, are important for supplying consumers with groceries and other household items.</p>
<p>These informal retailers are usually located within walking distance, making them convenient to shoppers, with the added advantage of extending credit lines to loyal buyers.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/05/marketforce-partners-with-cellulant-to-expand-in-five-new-markets-across-africa-as-it-races-to-cover-continent/">contributions of these informal merchants to economies</a>, therefore, cannot be ignored, as they account for the vast majority of trade in the retail sector across the continent.</p>
<p>These shops, however, continually suffer challenges, like stockouts, variability in earnings and inadequate financing, making it hard for them to grow.</p>
<p>These are some of the gaps that Koko Club is planning to bridge, especially on the issue of stockouts &#8212; seeing that the agents do not require capital to restock.</p>
<p>Modernizing informal trade is regarded as one of the strategies for unlocking credit and the potential of these small micro-retail outlets, as well as improving the lives of small business owners. Saxena said Koko Club’s business model gives manufacturers direct access to this market segment.</p>
<p>“Many of these manufacturers have armies of people that go into the neighborhoods to make sure that their products are being positioned properly and that these shops are styled. They even need to have people out there to figure out what prices the retailers are selling at,” he said.</p>
<p>“So, we take care of so much of that for them; we can tell them right now, exactly how many of their products are there and their price tags, and all that kind of information.”</p>
<p>The Koko Club idea was conceived mid 2020 but it wasn’t until the beginning of this year that the startup moved forward with its launch, riding on the success of its bioethanol fuel business, which was unveiled in 2019 as a cleaner, cheaper and safer alternative to charcoal and fuelwood.</p>
<p>Currently, there are over 300,000 households using Koko’s bioethanol fuel and stove (made in Koko’s plant in India), up from about 100,000 in March this year. These households are served by the more than 1,000 agents, who will now double up as Koko Club agents.</p>
<p>The Koko fuel business has in just over two years grown beyond Kenya’s capital Nairobi following a recent launch in the coastal city of Mombasa, with plans to enter Nakuru and Kisumu in the first half of 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/30/tech-led-biofuel-startup-koko-networks-launches-new-consumer-goods-business-in-kenya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252110</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We need to pay more attention to &#8216;age-tech&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/we-need-to-pay-more-attention-to-age-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/we-need-to-pay-more-attention-to-age-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 05:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Age tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agetech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caregiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elderly people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seniors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For the last two years, many of us have only been able to see our elderly relatives through screens, watching them grow older, trading physical distance for their safety. More than anything else, the pandemic has highlighted the vulnerabilities of aging people. The tech community — founders, investors, journalists — all need to pay more [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For the last two years, many of us have only been able to see our elderly relatives through screens, watching them grow older, trading physical distance for their safety. More than anything else, the pandemic has highlighted the vulnerabilities of aging people. The tech community — founders, investors, journalists — all need to pay more attention to “age-tech.”</p>
<p>“Age-tech” isn’t a niche sector, and aging populations aren’t limited to a few countries. According to a <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/ageing-and-health" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent World Health Organization report</a>, one in six people will be aged 60 years or older by 2030, while the number of people aged 80 years or older is expected to triple between 2020 and 2050, to 426 million.</p>
<p>“While this shift in distribution of a country’s population toward older ages — known as population aging — started in high-income countries (for example, in Japan 30% of the population is already over 60 years old), it is now low- and middle-income countries that are experiencing the greatest change,” the report said. “By 2050, two-thirds of the world’s population over 60 years will live in low- to middle-income countries.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252107" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The WHO report goes on to say “globalization, technological developments (e.g. in transport and communication), urbanization, migration and changing gender norms are influencing the lives of older people in direct and indirect ways. A public health response must take stock of these current and projected trends and frame policies accordingly.”</p>
<p>Tech giants have started tapping into the potential of this growing demographic, creating new services for their existing platforms and hardware. For example, earlier this month, Amazon <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/amazon-launches-its-19-99-per-month-alexa-together-elder-care-subscription-for-families/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">officially launched Alexa Together</a>, which turns Alexa devices into tools for caregivers with features that allow users to call out for help, an emergency helpline, fall detection, a remote assist option to help manage device settings and an activity feed so family members can see if someone has been less active than usual. Google, meanwhile, started <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/18/google-is-piloting-a-simpler-nest-hub-max-interface-at-retirement-homes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">piloting a simplified Nest Hub Max interface last year</a> at retirement homes in an effort to help residents feel less isolated during lockdowns.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MmZh8LmLdz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/amazon-launches-its-19-99-per-month-alexa-together-elder-care-subscription-for-families/">Amazon launches its $19.99 per month &#8216;Alexa Together&#8217; elder care subscription for families</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon launches its $19.99 per month &#8216;Alexa Together&#8217; elder care subscription for families&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/amazon-launches-its-19-99-per-month-alexa-together-elder-care-subscription-for-families/embed/#?secret=MmZh8LmLdz" data-secret="MmZh8LmLdz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>What I find more interesting, however, are startups that focus on age-tech. When I cover hardware events, it’s heartening to see the number of companies developing tech for aging people. Most of next week’s CES announcements are still embargoed, but I’ll be doing a round-up of age-tech startups at the event.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uJ7XIQeruZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/nobis-smart-lamp-alerts-caregivers-when-a-fall-is-detected/">Nobi’s smart lamp alerts caregivers when a fall is detected</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nobi’s smart lamp alerts caregivers when a fall is detected&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/nobis-smart-lamp-alerts-caregivers-when-a-fall-is-detected/embed/#?secret=uJ7XIQeruZ" data-secret="uJ7XIQeruZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>At the last CES in January 2021, one of the most interesting products was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/nobis-smart-lamp-alerts-caregivers-when-a-fall-is-detected/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nobi’s smart lamp</a>, an unobtrusive ceiling lamp that alerts caregivers when a fall or irregular movements are detected and automatically illuminates the floor when someone stands up to walk.</p>
<p>There were also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/startups-at-ces-showed-how-tech-can-help-elderly-people-and-their-caregivers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">several age-tech presentations</a>, including one by <a href="https://aarpinnovationlabs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AARP Innovation Lab,</a> the nonprofit’s startup accelerator program, which presented nine companies. Many focused on helping elderly people “age in place,” or stay in their homes instead of moving into nursing facilities. These include <a href="https://www.wheelpad.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wheel Pad</a>, whose accessible, modular work and home spaces fit into existing structures and sites; <a href="https://www.zibrio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zibrio</a>, a scale that can be used at home to predict if users are at a risk for fall; and <a href="https://www.fallcall.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FallCall Solutions</a>, which develops Apple Watch apps and wearables, including jewelry, to help family members and other caregivers check in on users.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nzTq0S64k2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/startups-at-ces-showed-how-tech-can-help-elderly-people-and-their-caregivers/">Startups at CES showed how tech can help elderly people and their caregivers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups at CES showed how tech can help elderly people and their caregivers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/17/startups-at-ces-showed-how-tech-can-help-elderly-people-and-their-caregivers/embed/#?secret=nzTq0S64k2" data-secret="nzTq0S64k2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But hardware can only go so far. Startups around the world are looking at the needs of caregivers, too. Caregiver burnout is a <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/9225-caregiver-burnout" target="_blank" rel="noopener">major problem</a>, but technology can help. For example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/caregiving-startup-homage-raises-10-million-series-b-to-enter-new-asian-markets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Homage</a>, operational in Singapore and Malaysia, plans to expand into five more countries over the next two years. To assess caregivers and help match them with patients, it builds a profile of each provider and also works with nurses to evaluate how they are able to perform essential tasks, like manual transfer techniques. All that data is used by its matching engine, which makes the process of finding caregivers faster for families and patients.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o8gGSEc1Qy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/caregiving-startup-homage-raises-10-million-series-b-to-enter-new-asian-markets/">Caregiving startup Homage raises Series B to enter new Asian markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Caregiving startup Homage raises Series B to enter new Asian markets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/17/caregiving-startup-homage-raises-10-million-series-b-to-enter-new-asian-markets/embed/#?secret=o8gGSEc1Qy" data-secret="o8gGSEc1Qy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Meanwhile in the United Kingdom, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/elderly-caretech-platform-birdie-gets-11-5m-series-a-led-by-index/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Birdie</a> is building software tools to support care providers, including ones that reduce administrative costs and enable real-time carer check-ins and medication-related notifications. The startup’s goal is to offer more personalized and preventative care so adults can live in their homes for longer as they age.</p>
<p>Changing family structures mean elderly people around the world have become increasingly isolated, and that’s a hard problem for technology to fix. But Papa, an on-demand senior assistance and companionship platform, shows that addressing loneliness among the elderly can translate into a promising business model. The Miami-based startup, which currently <a href="https://www.papa.com/pal-local-jobs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">operates in 27 states</a>, <a href="https://www.mobihealthnews.com/news/senior-care-platform-papa-scoops-150m-series-d-funding" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced last month</a> that it had raised $150 million in Series D funding, led by SoftBank Vision Fund 2, just seven months after a $60 million Series C.</p>
<p>Everyone deserves to reach the end of their lives not only in safety, but also in comfort and with dignity, and tech can be part of the solution to changing social dynamics that means aging people are often far from loved ones. One of my New Year’s resolutions is to cover more age-tech startups for TechCrunch; if you know of one I should pay attention to, please email me at shu@techcrunch.com.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/we-need-to-pay-more-attention-to-age-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252107</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Using public roads, trucking startup TuSimple completes 80-mile autonomous run</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/daily-crunch-110/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/daily-crunch-110/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 23:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello again friends, and welcome to Daily Crunch for December 29, 2021.</p>
<p>This is going to be the last Daily Crunch for the year, as the news machine seems to be winding down for its New Year&#8217;s nap. It&#8217;s been a pleasure putting these together while <a href="http://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex</a> has been AFK  — alas, my little sprint has come to an end. Alex should be back next week, and I&#8217;ll be moving on to help wrangle all the news from CES.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2252029" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Many thanks to the Daily Crunch team, and to all of you, for letting me hang out for a few days. Have a safe and wonderful new year!</p>
<p>—<a href="https://twitter.com/grg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Greg</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/tusimple-completes-its-first-driverless-autonomous-truck-run-on-public-roads/">TuSimple&#8217;s biggest test yet:</a></strong> Autonomous trucking company TuSimple says it has completed its first driverless test run on public roads, successfully completing an 80-mile trip with no human intervention. Will road-tripping kids of the future know the joy of convincing a truck driver to honk the horn?</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/six-things-we-learned-cybersecurity/">6 things in cybersecurity we didn&#8217;t know last year:</a></strong> Our security editor Zack Whittaker knows his stuff, so when he makes a big list of cybersecurity things that were new to him this year, I listen. Like, for example, that the biggest cost in a ransomware attack often isn&#8217;t the ransom itself.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/the-evtol-take-off-part-two-looking-ahead-to-2022/">eVTOLs in 2022:</a> </strong>Is 2022 the year in which eVTOLs finally … take off? Calling it a &#8220;make it or break it year&#8221; for electric aircraft that can hover and take off/land vertically, Aria Alamalhodaei has a great multipart look at the state of the industry and the challenges on the flight path ahead. Linked above is part two, here&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/top-evtol-trends-2021/">part one from earlier this month.</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/globalbees-joins-unicorn-club-for-its-thrasio-like-house-of-brands/">GlobalBees joins the unicorn club:</a> </strong>GlobalBees, an Indian company that specializes in acquiring/partnering with promising &#8220;digitally native brands&#8221; to help them grow, has raised $110 million in a round valuing it at $1.1 billion.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/southeast-asian-startups-to-watch-in-2022/">Southeast Asian startups to watch in 2022:</a></strong> &#8220;As someone who covers Southeast Asia startups and funding stories, the best word I can think of to describe 2021 is &#8216;whoa!'&#8221; writes Catherine Shu.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Dear Sophie: Will the H-1B lottery be based on the highest wages?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099516" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099516" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2099516 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg" alt="lone figure at entrance to maze hedge that has an American flag at the center" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2099516" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Dear Sophie,</p>
<p>I graduated in December, and I’m currently working on OPT for an early-stage biotech startup. I’m not sure how much my employer knows about the H-1B lottery process or if they are planning to put me in the lottery.</p>
<p>I heard that the next lottery will not select H-1B candidates based on the highest salaries paid. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/">What else should I know?</a></p>
<p>— Gifted Grad</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/28/samsungs-c-lab-class-features-a-diaper-sensor-smart-guitar-and-modular-robot/">Samsung’s C-Lab:</a></strong> One of my favorite parts of CES — which we&#8217;re regretfully skipping in-person this year — is how a number of huge companies use it as a way to exhibit the otherwise secret projects they&#8217;ve been tinkering on in their in-house incubators. Brian Heater has a list of Samsung&#8217;s latest side quests, which varies from pet recognition AI to diaper sensors.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/apple-foxconn-india/">Apple puts Foxconn plant on probation:</a></strong> Apple put operations at a 17,000-person factory in India on pause, following reports that hundreds of employees had to be treated for food poisoning. Apple says it has sent out independent auditors to evaluate the food safety and living conditions, with the local government also demanding action.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this article on TechCrunch+ from Miranda Halpern, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/23/10-growth-marketing-experts-share-their-2022-predictions-and-new-years-resolutions/">“10 growth marketing experts share their 2022 predictions and New Year’s resolutions.”</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/daily-crunch-110/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252029</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 views: How due diligence will change in 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/3-views-how-due-diligence-will-change-in-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/3-views-how-due-diligence-will-change-in-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 22:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[due diligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch’s Alex Wilhelm, Natasha Mascarenhas and Mary Ann Azevedo, the trio behind the Equity podcast, dive into what's in store for startup due diligence.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A few years ago, VCs were expected to perform extensive due diligence on startups. Investors dove into financials, called customers and vetted founders.</p>
<p>But power has now shifted toward the founders after a long run of investors holding more than half the power thanks to the commoditization of capital. The pace at which deals were done increased, and the time to reach what VCs love to call “conviction” fell sharply. This compressed diligence cycles, leading to less intrusive vetting.</p>
<p>The acceleration of venture capital and the burgeoning check sizes in the last few years has led to a decline in traditional due diligence. The full impact of private-market investors doing less preparatory diligence than in previous years and cycles will not become clear for some time.</p>
<p>But, in the meantime, we can see a few clear ripple effects: Inflating valuations can lead to unnecessary pressure, making startups rush product development and hiring, and faster checks can lead to an over-reliance on existing networks, exacerbating an already brutal gender fundraising gap. Throw in the concept of Tiger Global bringing pre-diligence to deal making, and preemption is becoming the norm, with venture players rapidly changing how they make decisions.</p>
<p>TechCrunch’s <a href="https://twitter.com/alex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alex Wilhelm</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Natasha Mascarenhas</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/bayareawriter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mary Ann Azevedo</a>, the trio behind <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=a19aebfa75654ba7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Equity podcast</a>, dive into what&#8217;s in store for startup due diligence.</p>
<h2>Natasha: Informalization will continue, so long live the back channel</h2>
<p>Back channeling has long existed in tech and all industries as a way for two parties to exchange information about a third in an informal, and hopefully illustrative way. In venture investing, back channeling can be used by an investor to gut check an entrepreneur they’re about to wire millions of dollars to — or vice versa, by the snappy founder who wants to make sure the money behind their money is stable. The process also helps stop predatory investors from winning deals, because, well, founders talk.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;Founders need to take their heads out of the clouds a bit and pay attention to what the investors can bring to the table.&#8221;							<cite>Mary Ann Azevedo</cite>
					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The venture market doesn’t appear to be slowing down, so I expect next year will bring an even greater focus on back channeling in the world of first-check fundraising. The broader argument behind the growing importance of back channeling is that the only way to keep up with fast checks is to offer more channels for gut checking.</p>
<p>Before, due diligence looked like a months-long process with back-to-back in-person meetings. But as founder friendliness becomes the norm, it’s more important than ever for entrepreneurs to assess the check writer, understand their options and have better navigation in this capital-rich environment.</p>
<p>Founders will need to build alliances with investors, customers and even other founders so they can help each other when it comes to fundraising. This may help getting an outside investor to write a check, but more interestingly, it may help entrepreneurs simply build better and learn how to ignore a lofty valuation from a well-vetted partner. In the background, <a href="https://twitter.com/irrvrntVC/status/1458897245491937284" target="_blank" rel="noopener">investors have to get comfortable </a>with the idea that a founder may have already pinged a portco before they pitch you — it’s one to two minutes of work that can save time, resources and a doomed relationship.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/3-views-how-due-diligence-will-change-in-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249888</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: Will the H-1B lottery be based on the highest wages?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 20:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dear Sophie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lottery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m currently working on OPT for an early-stage biotech startup. I heard that the next lottery will not select H-1B candidates based on the highest salaries paid. What else should I know?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/22/dear-sophie-whats-allowed-between-a-k-1-visa-and-a-green-card/">Dear Sophie: What’s allowed between a K-1 visa and a green card?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/dear-sophie-how-to-maneuver-the-latest-travel-bans-h-1b-alternatives/">Dear Sophie: How to maneuver the latest travel bans, H-1B alternatives</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>TechCrunch+ members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>I graduated in December, and I’m currently working on OPT for an early-stage biotech startup. I’m not sure how much my employer knows about the H-1B lottery process or if they are planning to put me in the lottery. </strong></p>
<p><strong>I heard that the next lottery will not select H-1B candidates based on the highest salaries paid. What else should I know?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Gifted Grad</strong></p>
<p>Dear Gifted,</p>
<p>It’s great that you’re thinking ahead to the lottery! I recently <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/103-a-futurists-lens-on-immigration-future-of-work-climate-change-and-more-with-jamais-cascio/">chatted about the future of immigration</a>, including work, climate change and more with <a href="https://medium.com/@cascio/facing-the-age-of-chaos-b00687b1f51d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">futurist and inventor of the BANI Framework Jamais Cascio</a>. This podcast sheds some light on the context of the global high-skilled immigration and future trends affecting the global labor market for the U.S. specifically.</p>
<p>For H-1B and other legal questions, as always, I recommend that your employer work with an experienced immigration attorney to guide you through the petition process.</p>
<h2>No wage-based H-1B lottery yet!</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/immigration/099-h-1b-planning-for-fy2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">H-1B lottery in March</a> will remain a random selection process, at least for now. In September, a federal district court judge invalidated a final rule issued by the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, which oversees U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), that would have changed the H-1B lottery from a random selection process to one that prioritized the highest wages. A wage-based selection process for the H-1B lottery would have disadvantaged cash-strapped early-stage startups and recent university graduates, who typically earn entry-level wages.</p>
<p>According to an analysis by the National Foundation for American Policy, a random H-1B lottery process makes international students and graduates 54% more likely to get selected to apply for an H-1B compared to a wage-based selection process.</p>
<p>However, the Biden administration has supported a wage-based H-1B lottery system, so the Department of Homeland Security might one day try again to push for the change.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>Registration for the lottery</h2>
<p>As you already know, the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/what-we-do/h-1b_speciality_occupations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">H-1B visa</a> requires an employer to sponsor you, so make sure to discuss sponsorship with your employer as soon as possible so that you both can prepare. If your company doesn’t already have an immigration attorney, they will need to engage one ASAP. The attorney will walk them through creating an online USCIS account to register you and any other candidates they’d like in the lottery. Your company will have to pay the $10 non-refundable fee to register each candidate.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/dear-sophie-will-the-h-1b-lottery-be-based-on-the-highest-wages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Founders First Capital Partners brings a different approach to diversity investing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/founders-first-capital-partners-brings-a-different-approach-to-diversity-investing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/founders-first-capital-partners-brings-a-different-approach-to-diversity-investing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 20:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders first capital partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Folsom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revenue based investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underrepresented founders]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kim Folsom came up through the engineering ranks in the 80s and 90s before founding the first of six companies, three of which successfully exited. Today, she is the founder and CEO at Founders First Capital Partners, a San Diego startup investment firm that uses a non-traditional approach to funding called revenue-based investment to invest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kimtfolsom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kim Folsom</a> came up through the engineering ranks in the 80s and 90s before founding the first of six companies, three of which successfully exited. Today, she is the founder and CEO at <a href="https://foundersfirstcapitalpartners.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Founders First Capital Partners</a>, a San Diego startup investment firm that uses a non-traditional approach to funding called <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/revenue-based-financing-the-next-step-for-private-equity-and-early-stage-investment/">revenue-based investment</a> to invest in historically underrepresented founders.</p>
<p>Unlike most Silicon Valley VC firms, Founders First isn&#8217;t looking for the next unicorn. Instead, Folsom seeks out founders from historically underrepresented backgrounds &#8212; women, people of color, LBGTQ, veterans &#8212; with solid ideas and decent, if not spectacular, revenue and growth who have had trouble getting external investment to help build their businesses.</p>
<p>She focuses on B2B companies, usually in tech, that have a product and some wraparound services to go with it that you could turn into recurring subscription revenue. And with the additional help from Founders, coaching and guidance transform the business into a recurring revenue growth engine.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251747" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Instead of buying equity in the startup with the hope that it exits at some point, Folsom wants to partner with these companies by lending them money, usually between $50,000 and $1 million, with an average investment of $300,000. As they succeed, she succeeds by getting paid back over time, based on monthly revenue with a profit cushion for her firm.</p>
<p>I sat down with Folsom last fall to discuss her career journey and why she decided to build a different kind of investment firm aimed at people who live and work in areas that are often invisible to Sand Hill Road.</p>
<h2>Startup dreams</h2>
<p>Folsom, who is a Black woman, came of age in the 80s as an engineer. She cut her teeth at firms like NCR, where she helped design automatic teller machines, which were cutting-edge technology in those early days of the IBM PC. But her goal was always to run a company, which she knew wouldn&#8217;t be possible at the corporations where she was working.</p>
<p>&#8220;I spent the [early part of my career] trying to figure out how I could learn enough at the various corporations I worked at so I could go out on my own. And in time, during the dot-com era in the mid-90s, I launched my first company, and I went on to launch six before launching Founders First,&#8221; she told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>She raised $30 million along the way, and learned what it takes to build a company &#8212; valuable intelligence she can share with the companies she funds today.</p>
<p>Folsom didn&#8217;t have many role models in the business world when she was starting; there were few women, and even fewer women of color, in engineering roles in the 1980s. Nor did she see women becoming leaders of large tech companies until the late 90s when Meg Whitman was named CEO of eBay and Carly Fiorina CEO at HP.</p>
<p>Even today, just 8.2% of CEOs at Fortune 500 companies are women, and women of color hold just 1% of CEO positions across the Fortune 1000, according to data from <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/8-2-of-fortune-500-ceos-are-women-according-to-the-2021-women-ceos-in-america-report-301400856.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Women Business Collaborative</a>.</p>
<p>As for women of color leading startups, there were few getting venture funding when she was starting, and today the numbers aren&#8217;t much better. Crunchbase found in the first half of 2021 <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/something-ventured-funding-to-black-startup-founders-quadrupled-in-past-year-but-remains-elusive/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just 1.2%</a> of $147 billion in venture funding went to Black founders. When you narrowed that data down to Black women founders, the number dropped to <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/something-ventured-black-women-founders/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a minuscule 0.34%</a>.</p>
<p>After her experience as a founder, she wanted to set up a firm that helped people who were usually left out of this process to make it easier for them to access sources of capital.</p>
<p>&#8220;The journey for diverse founders is the same &#8212; whether a woman, person of color, military veteran, LGBTQ or in a low and moderate income area &#8212; it&#8217;s tough to grow a business and get access to smart money such that you have a positive wealth creating outcome,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s why she launched Founders First in 2015.</p>
<h2>Giving back</h2>
<p>Folsom knew she had this wealth of experience as a startup founder who built companies, raised money and exited successfully, and she wanted to find a way to help others build businesses and get all the same advantages, especially people who were being left out of the venture financing world.</p>
<p>&#8220;Having gone through this with my own experience a few times, I felt I knew enough that I could try something, but I wanted to structure this in a way that leveraged what I knew about the market I was going to serve,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Folsom recognized<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> that exiting offered a reasonable way for both investors and founders to make money, but she also knew that the process wasn&#8217;t terribly efficient and didn&#8217;t work for everyone because there were many viable companies that just couldn&#8217;t meet the revenue and growth requirements of most conventional VC firms.</span></p>
<p>She decided that by using revenue-based funding instead of equity, she could build her firm around a new class of founders, and create a successful investment vehicle for her partners, while helping these founders grow into much more successful companies than they could have on their own.</p>
<p>&#8220;There wasn&#8217;t that perspective of unicorns in the dot-com era that there is today. But the path of getting to a unicorn company means you&#8217;re going to have to [ignore] a lot of really good companies that could have such a significant impact on markets,&#8221; Folsom said.</p>
<p>Rather than unicorns, Folsom says that she is looking to build “<a href="https://www.tbd.community/en/a/zebra-movement-starting-a-revolution" target="_blank" rel="noopener">zebras</a>.” In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/05/inside-the-effort-to-turn-startups-into-zebras-not-unicorns/">a 2019 story on Zebras Unite</a>, an organization building a community of zebra founders, zebras were described this way: “Because there are fewer financial incentives for investors to fund startups that are less focused on more traditional exit routes of either selling or going public, it can be hard to attract investors.&#8221;</p>
<p>Folsom says that is precisely why she is trying to help zebras because “they can have a significant impact and build wealth for both the community they serve, and the founders.”</p>
<h2>Funding the fund</h2>
<p>When she launched in 2015, Folsom struggled to find investment partners in spite of her impressive credentials. Initially, she says that most investors thought the idea of investing in diverse founders using the revenue-based model was too unorthodox and they didn&#8217;t want to take a chance. She started by investing her own money, then went to the people who had invested in her in the past.</p>
<p>&#8220;You know, when I started Founders First, and I said that I wanted to focus on funding diverse founders and I wanted to use a model that was more relevant for business owners, people thought I was crazy. So I had raised money in the past, and my early investors…were people largely who were betting on me and had bet on me in the past,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>She went through a proof of concept in 2017 with 10 companies, and when that worked, she began looking for a Series A. Before that happened though, in 2019 she secured <a href="https://foundersfirstcapitalpartners.com/founders-first-capital-partners-secures-unprecedented-100-million-credit-facility-from-community-investment-management-cim/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a $100 million credit facility</a> from Community Investment Management, an organization that promotes inclusion through lending, a company that would seem to be a perfect match for Folsom&#8217;s goals.</p>
<p>The firm scored a Series A totaling $11 million this year with a <a href="https://foundersfirstcapitalpartners.com/rockefellerfounderfirst/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$9 million chunk in March</a> from The Rockefeller Foundation and the Surdna Foundation, followed by an additional <a href="https://foundersfirstcapitalpartners.com/seriesa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$2 million in November</a> from W.K. Kellogg Foundation, Pivotal Ventures (a Melinda French Gates company), the Schultz Family Foundation and Arc Chicago, LLC.</p>
<p>She says that a growing awareness about institutional racism in the wake of George Floyd&#8217;s murder has definitely helped a firm like hers trying to increase diversity investing to raise capital. Yet, while the firm is based in San Diego, as were all her startups, she says that not one California institutional investor stepped up to participate in the round.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NN3PWCZYjE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/indy-vc-firm-sixty8-capital-launches-20m-fund-aimed-at-underrepresented-founders/">Indy VC firm Sixty8 Capital launches $20M fund aimed at underrepresented founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Indy VC firm Sixty8 Capital launches $20M fund aimed at underrepresented founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/indy-vc-firm-sixty8-capital-launches-20m-fund-aimed-at-underrepresented-founders/embed/#?secret=NN3PWCZYjE" data-secret="NN3PWCZYjE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How it works</h2>
<p>Folsom looks for companies that are beyond the ideation phase and are making some money already and with some potential to grow with the right tweaks to the business model. She says that the founders must have the right amount of experience, expertise and a commitment to growth. In addition, the founding team has to be open to surrounding themselves with new people who can help drive that growth.</p>
<p>She said that they evaluate investments in companies based upon the strength and predictability of their revenues, but never ask founders to put up personal credit or assets. The company&#8217;s revenue acts as collateral.</p>
<p>The funded company pays back the &#8220;loan&#8221; based on an agreed-upon cap amount over a specific term, usually three years. &#8220;For Founders First, that cap can be 1.35 to 2x over that term. The company makes monthly payments using a percentage of sales revenue. That percentage is agreed upon that can range between 2% and 10% [of revenue],&#8221; she explained.</p>
<p>As an example of a success story using this model, she offers <a href="https://www.klarinetsolutions.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Klarinet Solutions</a>, which provides managed services for Microsoft SharePoint and Office 365. The company had a mid-six-figure income that had been flat for three years prior to teaming up with Founders. Founders helped create new revenue streams, including recurring revenue, resulting in 2.5x revenue growth in two years, while doubling the size of its staff. <span style="letter-spacing: -0.1px; font-size: 1rem;"> </span></p>
<p>Folsom is trying to use her expertise and experience to help other companies like Klarinet get access to funding to help them grow and develop their businesses in areas that typically are left behind when it comes to tech funding.</p>
<p>She wants people to understand that helping diverse founders is not a zero-sum game, certainly not with all the capital out there right now looking for a home. She understands from a lifetime of experience that the current climate pushing diversity and inclusion could change quickly. Folsom says that she has seen opportunity windows open in the past, only to close after a year or two, and she&#8217;s hoping it&#8217;s different this time.</p>
<p>&#8220;The window opens for a year, 18 months or two years and then it closes, and [I&#8217;m hoping that] this time when the window&#8217;s open, it&#8217;s not just going to be a [few people] that come out of it on the other side. We&#8217;ve got to be able to make it such that thousands of people do.&#8221;</p>
<p>Perhaps as firms like Founders First proliferate to help historically underrepresented groups gain access to more investment dollars, it will help keep that window wide open, creating wealth and jobs across communities that have been left behind in the past.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/founders-first-capital-partners-brings-a-different-approach-to-diversity-investing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251747</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tumblr is at war with Apple over &#8216;mature&#8217; content on its app again</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/tumblr-ios-tags-ban-apple/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/tumblr-ios-tags-ban-apple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 19:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automattic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS App Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumblr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web traffic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hide your &#8220;Tony the Tiger&#8221;/&#8221;Eugene Levy&#8221; fan fiction &#8212; those phrases, along with hundreds of others, are now banned from Tumblr&#8217;s iOS app. Now, any personal blog that flags itself as &#8220;mature&#8221; is not accessible on the iOS app &#8212; users will see a pop-up explaining that the content has been hidden because of &#8220;potentially [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hide your &#8220;Tony the Tiger&#8221;/&#8221;Eugene Levy&#8221; fan fiction &#8212; those phrases, along with hundreds of others, are now banned from Tumblr&#8217;s iOS app.</p>
<p>Now, any personal blog that flags itself as &#8220;mature&#8221; is not accessible on the iOS app &#8212; users will see a pop-up explaining that the content has been hidden because of &#8220;potentially suggestive or explicit content.&#8221; Tumblr also said that certain posts will be hidden in the search function and on user&#8217;s dashboards &#8212; which shows recommended posts, as well as content from the users they&#8217;re following.</p>
<p>&#8220;In order for us to remain in Apple’s App Store and for our Tumblr iOS app to be available, we needed to make changes that would help us be more compliant with their policies around sensitive content,&#8221; Tumblr <a href="https://wip.tumblr.com/post/671184848292118528/an-update-on-the-tumblr-ios-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> in a blog post.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251910" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2251961" style="width: 656px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2251961" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2251961" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tumblr-censor-message.png?w=646" alt="" width="646" height="562" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tumblr-censor-message.png 646w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tumblr-censor-message.png?resize=150,130 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tumblr-censor-message.png?resize=300,261 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tumblr-censor-message.png?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 646px) 100vw, 646px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2251961" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tumblr</p></div></p>
<p>Tumblr users developed an <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1YG7E84Dvs2PyoKMgSgZFgEX0Kh0RtJqsazZsyVGY8dk/mobilebasic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unofficial crowdsourced list</a> of tags that the Tumblr app has banned on iOS in order to comply with these policies. Some of the banned tags make sense for a platform trying to scrub itself of sensitive content &#8212; &#8220;porn,&#8221; &#8220;drugs&#8221; and &#8220;sex&#8221; are banned, for instance. Others are incomprehensible (or troubling if you think about them for too long), like the aforementioned &#8220;Tony the Tiger&#8221; and &#8220;Eugene Levy.&#8221; Even tags with the numbers 69 and 420 are banned.</p>
<p>Many Tumblr users flock to the site to talk anonymously about their experiences, but some of these tag bans effectively censor those conversations. Several tags related to <a href="https://www.verywellhealth.com/what-is-stimming-in-autism-260034" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stimming</a>, a common coping practice for autistic people, are banned, along with tags like &#8220;depression,&#8221; &#8220;PTSD&#8221; and &#8220;bipolar.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We understand that these adjustments will impact how users are able to access potentially sensitive content while using our iOS app, and that can be frustrating,&#8221; a Tumblr spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;We are working on more thoughtful solutions which will be rolled out in the near future and we will keep the community updated as that work continues.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A former Tumblr iOS engineer who blogs on the site as sreegs <a href="https://sreegs.tumblr.com/post/671649355334336512/alright-lets-talk-about-apple-and-tumblrs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">explained</a> what might be causing this problem and its ineffective, bandaid-like solutions.</p>
<p>&#8220;If a reviewer [at Apple] runs your app and finds porn, your app is rejected and you’re told to correct the problem,&#8221; they <a href="https://sreegs.tumblr.com/post/671649355334336512/alright-lets-talk-about-apple-and-tumblrs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> in a blog post. The engineer said that this would happen about &#8220;once every five updates,&#8221; but once the offending post &#8212; provided to Tumblr via screenshot &#8212; was removed, the app would be good to go.</p>
<p>&#8220;Once in a while Tumblr would get a really persistent reviewer. It would take a handful of porn scrubs and re-submissions before they’d finally green-light an update,&#8221; sreegs wrote. The engineer thinks that this is similar to what&#8217;s happening on Tumblr&#8217;s iOS app now.</p>
<p>Tumblr has faced a years-long struggle with approval on the iOS App Store. In 2018, Tumblr&#8217;s iOS app was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/19/tumblr-booted-from-app-store-due-to-child-porn/">taken down</a> from the App Store after child sexual abuse material (CSAM) made its way through the app&#8217;s filtering technology. A month later, the platform reacted by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/03/tumblr-no-more-porn/">banning all porn</a> and other sexually explicit content, resulting in a near-immediate <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/tumblr-debuts-post-a-subscription-service-for-gen-z-creators/">29% monthly traffic decrease</a>. Since then, the platform&#8217;s web traffic has remained relatively stagnant.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2180381" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2180381" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2180381" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="308" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png 1938w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png?resize=150,68 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png?resize=300,136 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png?resize=768,348 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png?resize=680,308 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png?resize=1536,696 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tumblr-Monthly-Traffic.png?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2180381" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SimilarWeb</p></div></p>
<p>Of course, it&#8217;s a Sisyphean task to scrub a user-generated content platform of any adult content. But Apple&#8217;s standards for Tumblr seem particularly stringent.</p>
<p>&#8220;A little part of me also wants to be cynical and say that since Instagram and Twitter are so big, they can get away with more than Tumblr can,&#8221; the former Tumblr iOS engineer theorized. &#8220;Combine that with Tumblr’s history of blatantly allowing porn up until the end of 2018. I can’t prove it, of course, but if Tumblr has a reputation at Apple, it can’t be a good one.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the meantime, Tumblr content is being banned tag by tag, from #rule 34 to #long post.</p>
<p>Tumblr wrote on its <a href="https://changes.tumblr.com/post/671837799097532416/tuesday-december-28th-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Changes blog</a> yesterday that it&#8217;s reviewing the list of tags that can&#8217;t be accessed in the iOS app, and it expects this review process to pick up in January.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re working on a web-based toggle that would allow folks to opt into allowing sensitive content in the iOS app,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>Tumblr users often refer to the platform as a wasteland of the internet. The app itself once subtitled its iOS app as &#8220;<a href="https://unwrapping.tumblr.com/post/651763186035539968/hellsite-affectionate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hellsite (affectionate)</a>&#8221; in the App Store. So why do people keep using it?</p>
<p>&#8220;W<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">e’re busted enough that people assume the site is dead, so stuff like this has super easy workarounds,&#8221; a dedicated Tumblrite told TechCrunch. It&#8217;s not hard to find these workarounds if you search &#8220;tag ban,&#8221; on the site, but regular users know that the search function is very buggy anyway. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;I bet the broken search feature is actually coming in clutch here. Shit just doesn&#8217;t show up half the time, which means we can&#8217;t find it, but neither can Apple.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>But what Tumblr lacks in working iOS apps and search functions, it makes up for with its algorithm&#8230; or lack thereof. As platforms like TikTok, Twitter, YouTube, Facebook and Instagram <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/snap-tiktok-youtube-senate-hearing-congress/">face the Senate</a> to talk about the mysterious ways they serve content, Tumblr is making it work (define &#8220;work&#8221;) the old-fashioned way. It displays content from users you follow in reverse chronological order.</p>
<p>&#8220;I <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">honestly believe being a dumpster fire has fully worked in Tumblr’s favor at this point,&#8221; the avid Tumblr user said. &#8220;W</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">e’ve got no algorithm, so we still get to curate our experience exactly how we want.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BcSAE9aSsO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/tumblr-debuts-post-a-subscription-service-for-gen-z-creators/">Tumblr debuts Post+, a subscription service for Gen Z creators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tumblr debuts Post+, a subscription service for Gen Z creators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/tumblr-debuts-post-a-subscription-service-for-gen-z-creators/embed/#?secret=BcSAE9aSsO" data-secret="BcSAE9aSsO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pcjdzu7G5f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/tumblr-community-lash-out-post-plus-subscription/">Trouble in fandom paradise: Tumblr users lash out against its beta subscription feature</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Trouble in fandom paradise: Tumblr users lash out against its beta subscription feature&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/tumblr-community-lash-out-post-plus-subscription/embed/#?secret=pcjdzu7G5f" data-secret="pcjdzu7G5f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/tumblr-ios-tags-ban-apple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251910</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What 7 combined decades in tech taught us about perseverance and reinvention</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/what-7-combined-decades-in-tech-taught-us-about-perseverance-and-reinvention/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/what-7-combined-decades-in-tech-taught-us-about-perseverance-and-reinvention/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 16:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contractor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity in tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender gap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender parity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[major]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programmer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At a time when the tech workforce has a dire need for more skilled individuals — especially women — now is the time to enlist and empower this motivated group.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Michelle Boockoff-Bajdek</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/michellebb">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		As chief marketing officer at <a href="http://www.skillsoft.com/">Skillsoft</a>, Michelle Boockoff-Bajdek leads a global marketing organization focused on helping companies unlock the hidden value inside their greatest asset — their people.	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Betsy Veneziano</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Betsy Veneziano is an application support specialist at <a href="https://www.tylertech.com/">Tyler Technologies</a>. Throughout her career, she’s worked as a programmer for NASA and in multiple senior roles as an IT, product management and marketing leader.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Women in the workplace have historically been undervalued and underrepresented. That’s no secret, but it rings especially true in tech. In the United States alone, women make up <a href="https://www.catalyst.org/research/women-in-the-workforce-global/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">less than 40% of the global workforce</a> and only fill <a href="https://ncwit.org/resource/bythenumbers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25% of professional computing jobs</a>. Furthermore, a <a href="https://s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/skillsoft.com/prod/documents/SKS_Women-in-Tech-Report_FINAL.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new report</a> found that 45% of surveyed women in tech said men outnumber them at work at ratios of 4-to-1 or greater.</p>
<p>Between the two of us, we possess nearly 70 years of experience working in tech(!), and if you ask us to recount our journeys, we’re likely to recall both great and not-so-great memories. For instance, one of us distinctly remembers being told by an eighth grade math teacher that she wasn’t good enough to take algebra. But in a fortuitous act of youthful defiance, she elected to major in math before landing her first post-grad job as a programmer for a NASA contractor. This would go on to launch a thriving, 50+ year career in tech.</p>
<p>A few decades later, the other remembers serving as the only woman on her company’s leadership team, often feeling isolated and alone. Again, defying the status quo, she instead used this as a catalyst to build a platform focusing on advancing women in the workplace, helping to identify and bring more female leaders to the table.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251686" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>What these stories illustrate — and what the two of us agree about — is this: While many organizations and allies are making a more concentrated effort to help women progress in their careers and thrive in a male-dominated tech world, much of the onus on driving change and making improvements rests squarely on our shoulders as women. Women are resilient, and they are showing a fresh perspective, energy and dedication to ensure they rebound and regain influence, power and capital after being disproportionately affected by the pandemic.</p>
<p>Whether you’re a woman considering a career in tech or a seasoned professional, we all share in this mission and have a role to play in mitigating the gender gap and supporting one another.</p>
<p>Here are a few things that have worked for us over the years:</p>
<h2>Acknowledge the challenges and face them head-on</h2>
<p>If you like country music, you’ve likely heard the song, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_uHXS36LKNE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“Same Boat,”</a> with the chorus singing, “We’re all in the same boat, fishing in the same hole … ” Well, we may be fishing in the same hole — or, in the case of the past two years, riding out the same storm — but we’re still in very different boats.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Hiring women returning from a career break can bolster existing talent pools, and these &#8220;returners&#8221; are often highly motivated, educated and more than qualified to take on a variety of roles.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Skillsoft’s <a href="https://s3.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/skillsoft.com/prod/documents/SKS_Women-in-Tech-Report_FINAL.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2021 Women in Tech report</a> shows that women, particularly those in technical fields, continue to face many of the challenges in the workplace that have long existed. The largest percentage cites their biggest issue as lack of equity in pay, followed by work and life balance, lack of opportunities and lack of training.</p>
<p>Additionally, in the United States during the pandemic, 34% of men working remotely with children at home received a promotion compared to 9% of women in the same situation, and 26% of men received a pay raise compared to just 13% of women, according to a <a href="https://www.qualtrics.com/blog/inequitable-effects-of-pandemic-on-careers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study</a> by Qualtrics and The Boardlist.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Yes, the gender gap faced by women has shown slight signs of improvement in recent years, but this is a reminder that the road to equality is long and winding. It’s essential to remain persistent and not lose sight of your aspirations in the face of adversity. Even if you were an average student, you may soon find yourself in a meeting and realize you’re one of the smartest people there.</p>
<p>Learn from your mistakes, and when things are not going your way, find a way that works. This held true in the 1960s, and it still does today.</p>
<h2>Don’t be afraid of reinvention</h2>
<p>Life throws curve balls. For many women, taking a hiatus from work to have and care for children (or others, like aging parents) is inevitable. From personal experience, it can be difficult finding an employer willing to take a chance on women returning to the workforce. That’s why being persistent and willing to reinvent yourself is so important.</p>
<p>Maintain a mindset of curiosity throughout your career. That’s critical to ensure you’re able to adapt and pivot in any given situation. Perhaps after leaving the workforce, your previous position in product marketing is no longer there, or maybe you’ve reached a certain point in your career and no longer enjoy the work. Are your existing skillsets transferable to another role? Are there skills you’ve learned along the way — or could acquire — that allow you to shift to another path, such as development?</p>
<p>While pivoting and reinventing your career can be daunting, it can also pay major dividends in the long term.</p>
<p>For organizations, embracing this approach is good business. Hiring women returning from a career break can bolster existing talent pools, and these &#8220;returners&#8221; are often highly motivated, educated and more than qualified to take on a variety of roles. They want to put their best foot forward and bring mature and diverse perspectives, many of which they may have gained during their hiatus.</p>
<p>At a time when the tech workforce has a dire need for more skilled individuals — especially women — now is the time to enlist and empower this motivated group.</p>
<h2>Master the most important skill of all: Flexibility</h2>
<p>Change can be disruptive, but embracing and adapting to change can open a new world of possibilities. In order to come out ahead, it’s important to not just survive organizational change, but understand and learn how to thrive in it.</p>
<p>For example, several years ago one of us led a team that was bringing a new product to market that was tremendously exciting. Her company, however, decided to go a different route and bought a business that was already successful in this space. She could have worried about her job (and did, briefly), but instead, realized that the company needed help moving customers from the existing product to the acquired one. So she raised her hand, let them know that she could help and was subsequently assigned to the new team.</p>
<p>She’s now been with this company for nearly 20 years.</p>
<p>On the flip side, if an organization is asking such a drastic change of an employee, they must also provide the tools and resources needed for them to be successful in their new role. Here’s where creating a culture of learning, in which every employee is given the opportunity to develop new skills and capabilities, comes into play.</p>
<p>We all aspire to something bigger, to finding our place in — and contributing to — the world. Women&#8217;s careers are journeys made up of diverse and interwoven learning experiences that build leadership, power, influence, grit and resilience. We’ve made some good choices and faced some tough challenges during our combined 70-plus years in the tech workforce.</p>
<p>What have we learned? What you do with those learning lessons and how you build your story of perseverance, resilience and success as a female in technology is what matters most.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/what-7-combined-decades-in-tech-taught-us-about-perseverance-and-reinvention/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251686</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 things in cybersecurity we didn&#8217;t know last year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/six-things-we-learned-cybersecurity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/six-things-we-learned-cybersecurity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Bureau of Investigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MetroMile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spyware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Treasury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251824</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The past 12 months in cybersecurity have been a rough ride. In cybersecurity, everything is broken — it&#8217;s just a matter of finding it — and this year felt like everything broke at once, especially toward the end of the year. But for better or worse, we end the year knowing more than we did [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The past 12 months in cybersecurity have been a rough ride. In cybersecurity, everything is broken — it&#8217;s just a matter of finding it — and this year felt like everything broke at once, especially toward the end of the year. But for better or worse, we end the year knowing more than we did before.</p>
<p>Here we look back at the year that&#8217;s been, and what we learned along the way.</p>
<h3 id="Ransomware costs businesses because of downtime, not ransom payments">1. Ransomware costs businesses because of downtime, not ransom payments</h3>
<p>The scourge of file-encrypting malware continues. Ransomware this year alone forced entire towns offline, blocked paychecks and caused fuel shortages, as entire company networks were held for ransom in exchange for millions of dollars in cryptocurrency payments. The U.S. Treasury <a href="https://www.fincen.gov/news/news-releases/ransomware-trends-bank-secrecy-act-data-between-january-2021-and-june-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimates</a> that ransomware operators are likely to make more from ransom payments in 2021 than they did during the past decade. But research shows that the businesses <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/ransomware-recovery-can-be-costly-and-not-just-because-of-the-ransom/">face the most losses</a> through lost productivity and the often-arduous task of cleaning up after a ransomware attack — including incident response and legal support.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251824" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h3 id="The FTC can order mobile spyware makers to notify their victims">2. The FTC can order mobile spyware makers to notify their victims</h3>
<p>SpyFone became the first-ever spyware maker <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/spyfone-ftc-stalkerware/">to be banned in the U.S.</a> following an order from the Federal Trade Commission in September. The FTC accused the &#8220;stalkerware&#8221; app maker of creating the stealthy malware to allow stalkers and domestic abusers real-time access to data, such as messages and location history, on their victims&#8217; phones but without their knowledge. The FTC also ordered SpyFone to delete all of the data it had &#8220;illegally&#8221; collected and, for the first time, notify those whose <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2021/12/ftc-finalizes-order-banning-stalkerware-provider-spyware-business?es_id=c3ee559ee1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">phones were hacked</a> by its software.</p>
<h3 id="Cybersecurity VC funding doubled in size compared to last year">3. Cybersecurity VC funding doubled in size compared to last year</h3>
<p>It was a record-breaking year for cybersecurity VC funding. By August, investors had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/cybersecurity-vc-funding-surges-to-a-record-11-5b-in-2021/">poured $11.5 billion in total venture funding</a> during the first half of 2021. That&#8217;s more than double the $4.7 billion spent during the same period a year earlier. The biggest raises include a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/transmit-security-raises-543m-series-a-to-kill-off-the-password/">$543 million Series A</a> for Transmit Security and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/lacework-lands-525m-investment-as-revenue-grows-300/">$525 million Series D</a> for Lacework. Investors said a boon in cloud computing, security consulting and risk and compliance helped fuel the investments.</p>
<h3 id="A third of all legal demands for Microsoft user data are served with gag orders">4. A third of all legal demands for Microsoft user data are served with gag orders</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that tech companies are some of the biggest holders of user data, and — less surprisingly — a frequent target of government data requests that seek information for criminal investigations. But Microsoft <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/microsoft-gag-orders/">this year warned</a> of the growing trend of the government attaching secrecy orders to search warrants, gagging the company from telling its users when their data is subject to an investigation.</p>
<p>Microsoft said one-third of all legal orders come with secrecy provisions, many of which are &#8220;unsupported by any meaningful legal or factual analysis,” according to the company&#8217;s consumer security chief Tom Burt. Microsoft said secrecy orders were endemic across the entire tech industry.</p>
<h3 id="The FBI was allowed to hack into private networks to clean up after a cyberattack">5. The FBI was allowed to hack into private networks to clean up after a cyberattack</h3>
<p>In April, the FBI launched a first-of-its-kind operation to remove backdoors in hundreds of U.S. company email servers left behind by hackers weeks earlier. China was ultimately blamed for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-says-china-backed-hackers-are-exploiting-exchange-zero-days/">the mass exploitation</a> of vulnerabilities in Microsoft&#8217;s Exchange email software, which the hackers used to attack thousands of company email servers around the U.S. to steal contact lists and mailboxes. The hacks left thousands of servers vulnerable, forcing companies to scramble to fix the flaws, but the patches didn&#8217;t remove a backdoor left behind, allowing the hackers to return and easily regain access.</p>
<p>A federal court in Texas <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/fbi-launches-operation-to-remotely-remove-microsoft-exchange-server-backdoors/">authorized the operation</a> allowing the FBI to exploit the same vulnerabilities as the hackers to remove the backdoors, fearing they could be further exploited by bad actors. Other countries have carried out similar &#8220;hack and patch&#8221; operations to take out botnets before, but this is the first known time the FBI effectively cleaned up private networks after a cyberattack.</p>
<h3 id="Fraudsters are targeting car insurance sites for unemployment benefit scams">6. Fraudsters are targeting car insurance sites for unemployment benefit scams</h3>
<p>Several car insurance companies were targeted this year for an unlikely, but an increasingly common, scam. Metromile said <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/metromile-website-bug-hacker/">a bug in its website</a> used for storing insurance quotes was misused to obtain driver license numbers. Then, months later, Geico said it too was targeted and had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/geico-driver-license-numbers-scraped/">driver license numbers scraped</a>.</p>
<p>Geico&#8217;s data breach notice blamed scammers who used the stolen license numbers &#8220;to fraudulently apply for unemployment benefits in your name.&#8221; Turns out that many U.S. states need a driver&#8217;s license before you can apply for state unemployment benefits — hence why the car insurance companies were targeted.</p>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/ransomware-recovery-can-be-costly-and-not-just-because-of-the-ransom/">Ransomware recovery can be costly, and not just because of the ransom</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/microsoft-gag-orders/">Microsoft says a third of its government data requests have secrecy orders</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/fbi-launches-operation-to-remotely-remove-microsoft-exchange-server-backdoors/">FBI launches operation to remove backdoors from hacked Microsoft Exchange servers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/cybersecurity-vc-funding-surges-to-a-record-11-5b-in-2021/">Cybersecurity VC funding surges to a record $11.5B in 2021</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/spyfone-ftc-stalkerware/">FTC bans spyware maker SpyFone, and orders it to notify hacked victims</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/metromile-website-bug-hacker/">Metromile says a website bug let a hacker obtain driver license numbers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/geico-driver-license-numbers-scraped/">Geico admits fraudsters stole customers’ driver’s license numbers for months</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/six-things-we-learned-cybersecurity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251824</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fiverr rolls out new Pinterest-like personalized discovery feature</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/fiverr-rolls-out-new-pinterest-like-personalized-visual-discovery-feature/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/fiverr-rolls-out-new-pinterest-like-personalized-visual-discovery-feature/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiverr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelancers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketplace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2251665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freelance marketplace Fiverr is rolling out an interactive Pinterest-like mobile experience aimed at enabling users to engage with a constantly updated feed of visual content curated specifically for them. The company says the new feature, which is called &#8220;Inspire,&#8221; was specifically designed to help inspire new projects and help users uncover freelancers on the marketplace. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Freelance marketplace <a href="https://www.fiverr.com/?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc-brand&amp;utm_campaign=G_CA_Brand&amp;utm_term=one-fiverr_(exact)&amp;utm_content=AdID%5e553699614849%5eKeyword%5efiverr%5ePlacement%5e%5eDevice%5ec&amp;caid=342920080&amp;agid=26557560640&amp;ad_id=553699614849&amp;kw=fiverr&amp;lpcat=br_general&amp;show_join=true&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAiKuOBhBQEiwAId_sK7TZwzTKQYv5wb4s_2r_Syjp0SA8A2WyGl_aA2qOJs2Jz81XhQv8CxoCLGcQAvD_BwE&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fiverr</a> is rolling out an interactive Pinterest-like mobile experience aimed at enabling users to engage with a constantly updated feed of visual content curated specifically for them. The company says the new feature, which is called &#8220;Inspire,&#8221; was specifically designed to help inspire new projects and help users uncover freelancers on the marketplace. Users can interact with the content by &#8220;liking&#8221; it in their feed and adding it to a mood board or list within the app in order to reference it later.</p>
<p>Fiverr says the new feature also aims to help users discover various services and capabilities that may be beneficial to their business or project needs. Content within the feed is curated based on users&#8217; recent searches and purchases. The company notes that by using native endless exploration, users are not only exposed to content that is highly personal and relevant to them but also content that can be complementary to what they’ve previously looked at.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to see what kind of inspiration and ideas come from this new experience and to continue commemorating and recognizing the hard work of talented freelancers everywhere,&#8221; said Liron Markus, the vice president of product at Fiverr, in a statement.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2251665" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2251678" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2251678" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2251678" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/fiverr-inspire.gif" alt="" width="500" height="504" /><p id="caption-attachment-2251678" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Fiverr</p></div></p>
<p>This latest news comes as Fiverr recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/fiverr-acquires-stoke-talent-for-95m-adding-freelance-management-tools-for-employers-to-its-platform/">acquired</a> Stoke Talent, which lets companies manage their freelance teams, for $95 million. Stoke’s toolset includes features to onboard new freelancers; employers can also pay them through the platform and accordingly track their overall freelance budgets. In October, Fiverr<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/fiverr-is-acquiring-online-learning-company-creativelive/"> acquired</a> Seattle-based online learning company CreativeLive for an undisclosed amount. CreativeLive is an entrepreneurial learning platform where users can attend courses on video, photography, design, business, marketing and more.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<p>Earlier this year, Fiverr expanded<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/fiverr-subscriptions/"> beyond project-based payments</a> with the launch of three- or six-month subscriptions. Through this feature, sellers on Fiverr can offer to provide a defined set of work each month. The buyer or seller can cancel at any time without having to pay fees on the remaining months of the subscription.</p>
</div>
<p>Fiverr is now headquartered in New York, but was founded in Tel Aviv in 2010. It’s publicly traded on the NYSE and is valued at $6.3 billion. Fiverr says more than four million customers bought services from freelancers on its platform across more than 160 countries in its latest fiscal year. Its marketplace covers specialties in more than 500 categories and nine verticals, such as graphic design, digital marketing, programming, video and animation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/fiverr-rolls-out-new-pinterest-like-personalized-visual-discovery-feature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2251665</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
