<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:48:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Despite blockchain gaming&#8217;s play-to-earn angle, I prefer to pay</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axie Infinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2252964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can't get that hyped about blockchain gaming — I want to have fun, not monetize my experience.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If there&#8217;s one thing that venture capitalists have taught me, it&#8217;s that aligned incentives can kick ass.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a phrase you&#8217;ll hear often if you spend time with professional private market investors. But if I summon my collegiate years, the phrase is really just the economic principle that individuals respond to incentives, restated in a slightly more targeted fashion.</p>
<p>In the land of venture capital, the idea works out as follows: Individuals respond to incentives, so you want to ensure that everyone at a company, for example, has <em>aligned </em>incentives.</p>
<p>This is why startups often offer a dusting of equity to employees, giving them a tiny slice of ownership in the overall project. This <em>aligns</em> employee incentives toward aggregate corporate success, something that employers want because they are in the game of paying people as little as they can while still hitting human capital quality benchmarks and not having too much employee churn.</p>
<p>There are less crassly capitalistic reads of why venture capitalists allow startups to sell equity to employees at below-market rates through options. I don&#8217;t buy them. Investors like return, and they optimize for it, thanks to their own incentive structure.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ataFpxlSbr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/">Blockchain gaming survey: 7 investors discuss regulation, opportunities and NFT hype</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Blockchain gaming survey: 7 investors discuss regulation, opportunities and NFT hype&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/embed/#?secret=ataFpxlSbr" data-secret="ataFpxlSbr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>VCs have a good gig. They take money from existing capital pools, invest it in work that others are doing, and then get a cut of deal profits while also ripping a few hundred bips per year of their total investing vehicle. Here again, we see aligned incentives, with venture capitalists profiting when <em>their</em> backers profit. Teamwork.</p>
<p>I drag you through all of that to explain that the concept of aligned incentives is marrow-deep in the startup and venture capital worlds, something that can, at times, blind folks to other ways of doing business.</p>
<p>Games, for example. Crypto games in particular.</p>
<p>You see, the crypto community and its myriad backers are pretty hot on crypto games. Here, it seems, is a place where incentives can be aligned in a new, exciting manner, translating gaming into related economic activity. All the fun of games, but with aligned economic incentives! What could go wrong?</p>
<h2>Play to earn?</h2>
<p>Through the lens of aligned incentives, the concept of play-to-earn games on a blockchain excites venture capitalists. Users will play the game, generating both fun and economic activity. The user gets some of the value, and the company the rest. Everyone is happy, and the game can go on making money forever, right?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/despite-blockchain-gamings-play-to-earn-angle-i-prefer-to-pay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2252964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain gaming survey: 7 investors discuss regulation, opportunities and NFT hype</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karan Bhasin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axie Infinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC investor survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roblox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPG]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2254571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s still a haze of uncertainty surrounding blockchain games, so we reached out to several active investors in to get a clearer picture of where opportunities exist today and what they see on the horizon.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The video-game industry has always been on the bleeding edge, but blockchain gaming is still widely viewed as emerging technology.</p>
<p>In October 2021, Valve banned all blockchain-related games from its Steam platform. Meanwhile, within Axie Infinity, an NFT-based online game, new players are paying hundreds of dollars to acquire mythical pets and love potions.</p>
<p>There’s still a haze of uncertainty surrounding blockchain games, so we reached out to several active investors in the space to get a clearer picture of where opportunities exist today and what they see on the horizon. We asked them to share the advice they&#8217;re giving their portfolio companies, along with their thoughts on how future regulation might impact the industry.</p>
<p>Interestingly, at least one investor noted that growth wasn&#8217;t a key consideration: &#8220;We tell our companies to really think about the missing pieces, particularly in gaming infrastructure,&#8221; said Banafsheh Fathieh, head of investments, Americas at Prosus Ventures. &#8220;What are the pain points we can alleviate for users and builders? Growth is less of a focus now, utility is incredibly important at this stage.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We surveyed:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonbackman/?originalSubdomain=fi">Anton Backman</a>, principal, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenrick/?originalSubdomain=sg">Kenrick Drijkoningen</a>, general partner, <a href="https://www.playventures.vc/">Play Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/banafsheh-b-fathieh-97629469/">Banafsheh Fathieh</a>, head of investments, Americas, <a href="https://www.prosus.com/ventures">Prosus Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshchapmanb/">Josh Chapman</a>, managing partner, <a href="https://www.konvoy.vc/">Konvoy Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardthai/?originalSubdomain=vn">Eddie Thai</a>, general partner, <a href="https://vietnam.500.co/">500 Startups</a> and general partner, <a href="https://ascendvietnam.com/">Ascend Vietnam Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/beryl-chavez-li-832baa4b/?originalSubdomain=ph">Beryl Li</a>, co-founder, <a href="https://yieldguild.io/">Yield Guild Games</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajulgarg/?originalSubdomain=in">Rajul Garg</a>, founder and managing partner, <a href="https://leo.capital/">Leo Capital</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<h2 class="p1">Anton Backman, principal, and Kenrick Drijkoningen, general partner, Play Ventures</h2>
<p><strong>What was your initial reaction on hearing about Steam’s ban on blockchain games?</strong></p>
<p>It was not an entirely unexpected move from Steam. Incumbents tend to be more wary of adapting new business models and gaming is no different. As a fledgling space, NFTs are beridden with projects of varying quality and we believe Steam wants to do some quality assurance and wait until the situation stabilizes before allowing blockchain games en masse. Interestingly enough, at the time of writing (Nov 14) MIR4, a crypto-enabled MMORPG on Steam, is running at 88,000 concurrent users. Seems that there’s still a gray area in terms of how these games are classified.</p>
<p><strong>What advice have you been giving your portfolio companies to grow? What sort of guidance and assistance do blockchain gaming companies seek from you?</strong></p>
<p>We typically act as a sparring partner for founders in strategy-related matters. With blockchain gaming companies we have mostly assisted the teams in navigating the technology stack, i.e., what blockchains and/or scaling solutions to consider, as well as token economic design. In our view it’s key to embrace a crypto native approach of building and experimenting with the product while also involving your community in the process.</p>
<p><strong>How do you view the regulatory environment for blockchain gaming? Is the uncertainty making you reconsider your strategy?</strong></p>
<p>No. It’s not the first time innovation has outpaced regulation and we see it as a natural reaction to new consumer behavior and ways of building companies. Similarly, Uber fought an uphill battle with regulators before eventually democratizing the taxi medallion system and providing an outsized improvement for end users of taxi services. This doesn’t mean that companies and projects should build products that are against the law but rather engage in healthy discussion with regulators as the adoption of their products increases.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/blockchain-gaming-survey-7-investors-discuss-regulation-opportunities-and-nft-hype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2254571</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harry&#8217;s files paperwork for fresh $139.9M financing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/harrys-files-paperwork-for-fresh-139-9m-financing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/harrys-files-paperwork-for-fresh-139-9m-financing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[razor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tehmina Haider]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Harry’s goal since birth was to target incumbents in the global shave market, which is forecasted to reach $22.5 billion by 2030.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Yay, no errors, warnings, or alerts! --></p>
<p>A year after the FTC blocked <a href="https://www.harrys.com/en/us">Harry’s</a> from getting acquired by Edgewell Personal Care, the direct-to-consumer razor startup raised $155 million in Series E financing to give it a $1.7 billion valuation. Now, months later, Harry’s filed paperwork indicating that it has raised another nine-figure cash tranche.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1556308/000155630822000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml">SEC filings</a> show that Harry’s has raised $139.9 million in a new financing event. The same filing listed the co-founders alongside Zola’s co-founder Shan-Lyn Ma, Addition Capital founder Lee Fixel, Campbell Soup Co. CEO Mark Clouse, politician Helena Foulkes, Zoom chief diversity officer Damien Hooper-Campbell, as well as Harry’s chief financial officer Jeff Lipkin and chief counsel Jack Sarno.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256504" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Harry’s, through a spokesperson, said, “we are not commenting at this moment.”</p>
<p>The new funding gives the company just over $791 million in total known funding since the company was founded in 2013, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/harrys">according to Crunchbase data.</a></p>
<h2>From acquisition target to brand incubator</h2>
<p>Harry’s has been quite active over the past year. It recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/13/harrys-acquisition-d2c-deodorant-lume/">acquired</a> Lumē, <a href="https://lumedeodorant.com/">a direct-to-consumer brand</a> created to help control all-over body odor, in an undisclosed deal. Early in 2021, it launched its Headquarters hair care line. In a previous interview with TechCrunch, Tehmina Haider, Harry’s chief growth officer, spoke to the company’s focus on acquiring businesses with “demonstrated product fit and consumer love.”</p>
<p>“The idea about M&amp;A for Harry’s is we want to be a multi-category CPG company and build a family of CPG brands,” she said. “We want to create more and better things for consumers, and we are looking for brands aligned with that mission, are positioned in a way we can be helpful and are brands serving unmet needs.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Whether or not this is a plan to help it eventually enter the public markets is unclear, but it does help that the late-stage DTC company has some precedent to look to.</p>
<p>Casper, which recently left the public markets after its rocky debut, taught investors and the public about the limits of DTC companies, while <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/warby-parker-makes-it-clear-that-direct-listings-are-unicorn-friendly/">Warby Parker’s direct listing gave the same cohort some hope. </a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/caspers-return-to-private-life-isnt-a-canary-for-dtc-companies-going-public/">As our own Alex Wilhelm puts it</a>, DTC companies that want to go public either need to “grow quickly enough that losses feel secondary, leading to share-price appreciation and the ability to self-fund growth as needed” or find a way to trim losses if growth slows. In other words, it may not appear as SaaS growth, but it could appear as value growth.</p>
<p>Regardless of if it goes down the public market path or not, Harry’s goal since birth was to target incumbents in the global shave market, which is forecasted to reach <a href="https://www.psmarketresearch.com/market-analysis/razor-market">$22.5 billion by 2030.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/harrys-files-paperwork-for-fresh-139-9m-financing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256504</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: After clinching $12.3B valuation, Brex hires Meta exec as chief product officer</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/daily-crunch-after-clinching-12-3b-valuation-brex-hires-meta-exec-as-chief-product-officer/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/daily-crunch-after-clinching-12-3b-valuation-brex-hires-meta-exec-as-chief-product-officer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fertilis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justworks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PST, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em><br />
<!-- Yay, no errors, warnings, or alerts! --></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for January 11, 2022! Today we have new venture funds, spyware news, Brex raising (again), and more. We’re back to 100% of last year’s startup and technology news pace, so we do hope you are rested up. It’s going to be a hectic, busy year. – <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-admin/twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2><strong>The TechCrunch Top 3</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/poland-nso-pegasus-election/">Cybersecurity matters to democracy</a>: Spyware built by the infamous NSO Group was “used to spy on three critics of the Polish government,” according to Citizen Lab, TechCrunch reports. The result of the allegations is that there are now questions regarding Poland’s 2019 parliamentary elections. This is not the last time we’ll see this sort of story around the world.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/turos-s-1-filing-shows-that-unicorns-can-slingshot-out-of-the-pandemic/">Turo’s business roars back in 2021</a>: Car-rental unicorn Turo has filed to go public, so TechCrunch dug into the numbers. The gist is that after a pretty flat 2020, Turo’s business posted strong growth and improved revenue quality during the first three quarters of 2021. We should get more updated numbers in time. (For you IPO fans out there, recall that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/20/justworks-files-to-take-its-smb-focused-hr-themed-saas-business-public/">HR software firm Justworks will debut later this week</a>.)</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/brex-confirms-12-3b-valuation-hires-meta-exec-to-serve-as-its-chief-product-officer/">Brex confirms $300M raise</a>: The race to control the corporate spend market was a key theme last year, and 2022 is starting on a similar note, with well-known market competitor Brex confirming that it raised nine figures in a Series D-2 round that values the former startup at $12.3 billion. We expect Ramp, Brex’s rival, to announce more capital by the time you read this brief, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/ramp-raises-300m-at-a-3-9b-valuation-makes-its-first-acquisition/">given how last year went</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Startups/VC</strong></h2>
<p>Kicking off our startup coverage today, a few notes before we get into the individual bulletins. First, the SPAC boom has left the public market littered with formerly private companies that combined with blank-check entities and then lost half their value. SPACs failed to get enough private companies public last year to cut the number of unicorns, and the lackluster post-combination results <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/the-spac-boom-was-a-failure-yeah/">add up to a general failure</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256445" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>And Kleiner Perkins has joined a16z and Norwerst in announcing more than 10 figures worth of new capital. The venture capital firm, now in its 50th year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/kleiner-perkins-starts-off-50th-year-with-1-8b-in-two-new-funds/">just closed $1.8 billion across two funds</a>. Founders, that sound you just heard was the starting gun.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/locket-an-app-for-sharing-photos-to-friends-homescreens-hits-the-top-of-the-app-store/">Locket shoots to the top of app stores</a>: Today Sarah Perez added me on a new social service, leading to us trading selfies and dog pics back and forth. The app? Locket, which is tearing up the mobile application charts. Read on for what it does and why it’s popular.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/orbit-fabs-on-orbit-fuel-shuttle-will-top-up-astroscales-servicing-satellites/">In-orbit refueling</a>: This story is the coolest. Darrell Etherington, our in-house space expert, writes that “Orbit Fab has teamed with Astroscale to provide on-orbit refueling services to the latter company’s geostationary servicing spacecraft.” This is a solution to a problem that most folks don’t think about. But if we want low-flying satellites to stay, well, afloat, they will at times need more fuel. And it looks like the tech to do so is getting close to maturity.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/back-market-reaches-5-7b-valuation-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/">Back Market puts more points on the board for France</a>: French startups had a pretty good 2021, and Back Market is helping the country’s upstart tech scene start this year on solid footing. The company “operates a marketplace of refurbished electronics devices” and just closed a $510 million Series E that values it at $5.7 billion. Last year it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/back-market-raises-another-335-million-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/">raised $335 million</a>, for reference.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/fertilis-ivf-cell-culture-funding/">IVF tech is hot</a>: If you haven’t had a chance to visit the shores of infertility, you might not be aware of just how complicated the in-vitro fertilization (IVF) process is. It’s complex. The good news for would-be parents is that startups like Fertilis, an Australian company, are raising capital to make the ordeal a bit more likely to result in a live birth.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/novo-the-smb-neobank-nabs-90m-at-a-700m-valuation/">Novo proves that there is still capital in the market for neobanks</a>: Sure, Chime has yet to go public, much to our chagrin, but a lack of exits in the neobanking space is not slowing investors down. Novo, a neobank aimed at SMBs, just closed $90 million at a $700 million valuation.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/fast-charge-ev-battery-maker-storedot-pulls-in-80m-led-led-by-vietnams-vinfast/">StoreDot raises capital for super-fast battery charging</a>: EVs are great, but they are still a bit slow to recharge. While gas-powered cars are not great for the air we breathe, they are incredibly good at onboarding fuel. StoreDot is busy closing a round that could be worth up to $80 million for like, <em>very</em> fast battery topping-up.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/gostudent-raises-340m-series-d-funding-round-as-it-pushes-into-international-markets/">Online tutoring is big business (outside of China)</a>: Sure, the Chinese government <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/as-china-shakes-up-regulations-tech-companies-suffer/">drop-kicked its domestic edtech market</a>, but that doesn’t mean that tutoring is kaput as a business type around the world. Evidence of that? GoStudent just closed a $340 million Series D less than a year after it closed a $244 million Series C.</li>
</ul>
<p>We’re low on time, but there was so much more: This <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-admin/ises-6-2m-pre-series-a/">African e-commerce company</a> just closed a Series A, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/mostly-ai-raises-25-million-to-further-commercialize-synthetic-data-in-europe-and-the-u-s/">Mostly AI landed $25 million</a>, and Qonto – also in the business banking space like Novo! – <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/business-banking-startup-qonto-raises-552-million-at-5-billion-valuation/">raised more than half a billion</a>. It’s <em>busy</em> out there.</p>
<p>And just to squeeze in one more thing, <a href="https://twitter.com/ron_miller">Ron Miller</a> has a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tupu-io-wants-to-help-women-thrive-in-tech-jobs-through-mentorship/">great story up on a group that is helping women in tech thrive through mentorship</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2255889" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255889" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255889" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg" alt="Exclamation mark ,3D render against an orange background." width="1024" height="619" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=768,464 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=680,411 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255889" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=ShadowPix" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ShadowPix <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Startups grow fast, and when you’re building one, it can be easy to lose track of what’s working — and what’s not.</p>
<p>One way to track how well your business is doing is to look at the big-picture numbers, but Karen Peacock, CEO of Intercom, has a warning: Averages can be dangerously misleading.</p>
<p>“If Jeff Bezos walks into a bar with 100 people, suddenly, on average, the net worth of each individual in that bar is over a billion dollars. Is that useful? Would that lead you to take the right actions? No — averages hide true insights.”</p>
<p>Peacock explains how founders can assess where their business’ strengths lie and where they need to work harder, including how to gauge revenue health and use customer segmentation to find “leaks in the bucket.”</p>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZpSeR1VcW7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/dont-trust-averages-how-to-assess-and-strengthen-the-health-of-your-business/">Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/dont-trust-averages-how-to-assess-and-strengthen-the-health-of-your-business/embed/#?secret=ZpSeR1VcW7" data-secret="ZpSeR1VcW7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2><strong>Big Tech Inc.</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/apple-to-allow-third-party-app-payment-options-in-south-korea/">Apple to allow third-party payment options in South Korea</a>: A change in the wind? Perhaps. News that Apple will change its in-app payment rules in South Korea – it didn’t have a choice – could lead other countries to similar rulings. For Apple, focused on preserving a large slice of the iOS economy for itself, it’s bad news.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/edps-decision-european-parliament-covid-19-test-website/">The EU sanctions itself over privacy errors</a>: Here’s a fun one – insert the Spider-Man pointing at Spider-Man meme – the “European Union’s chief data protection supervisor has sanctioned the European Parliament for a series of breaches of the bloc’s data protection rules,” <a href="https://twitter.com/riptari">Natasha Lomas</a> writes. At least they are consistent!</li>
<li>And finally today, the Indian government will <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/vodafone-idea-india-government/">now own just under 36% of Vodafone Idea</a>, “to save the third-largest telecom operator in the country from collapsing.” Wild!</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>TechCrunch Experts</strong></h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend software consultants who have expertise in UI/UX, website development, mobile development and more! If you’re a software consultant, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/daily-crunch-after-clinching-12-3b-valuation-brex-hires-meta-exec-as-chief-product-officer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256445</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s what happened when Mercedes-AMG got its hands on the all-electric EQS</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/first-drive-2022-mercedes-amg-eqs-and-2022-mercedes-amg-sl/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/first-drive-2022-mercedes-amg-eqs-and-2022-mercedes-amg-sl/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roberto Baldwin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auto tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automaker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes EQS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes-AMG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First, there was the dense fog. Then there was the snow. But inclement weather couldn&#8217;t put a damper on the AMG iterations of Mercedes&#8217; flagship EV or its latest generation SL. Performance, luxury, comfort, and technology all hit the mark even when the AMG team gets their hands on the Mercedes EQS and the latest [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">First, there was the dense fog. Then there was the snow. But inclement weather couldn&#8217;t put a damper on the AMG iterations of Mercedes&#8217; flagship EV or its latest generation SL.</p>
<p>Performance, luxury, comfort, and technology all hit the mark even when the AMG team gets their hands on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/all-the-tech-crammed-into-the-2022-mercedes-benz-eqs/">Mercedes EQS</a> and the latest SL Roadster.</p>
<p>At its core, the 2022 Mercedes AMG SL Roadster still has a glimmer of the soul that enveloped the original 300 SL Roadster introduced in the late 1950s. Where that vehicle was the top-down transportation of choice of Hollywood&#8217;s golden era elite, it&#8217;s easy to imagine Clooney, Mirren, and Run the Jewel&#8217;s Killer Mike rolling into an event behind the wheel of this newest convertible.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256366" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2256467" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256467" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256467 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg" alt="The new Mercedes-AMG SL Roadster" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_027.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256467" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG SL 63 4Matic+ <strong>Image credit</strong>: Mercedes-Benz</p></div></p>
<p>And while the Bondish AMG SL Roadster has roots in last century, the AMG EQS is Ironman. It&#8217;s all about all today&#8217;s tech being used to accomplish a goal &#8212; while like the Roadster &#8212; doing so in style.</p>
<p>Both the AMG SL Roadster and AMG EQS are new vehicles and while they share much of the same technology at their core, there is a stark difference.</p>
<p>The menacing roar of the SL is replaced in the EQS by a composed set of sounds. The EQS has instant EV torque, the SL&#8217;s impressive displacement and turbos are no match for the EVs launch potential.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Mercedes will build handcrafted engines for its AMG lineup until the bitter end. There is no handcrafted electric motor in the AMG EQS. The signature of a technician will not show up on a battery pack. Meanwhile, the amount of filth spewed into the air by the EQS is merely a fraction of what the V8 roadster will put into our atmosphere over its lifetime.</p>
<h2>2022 Mercedes AMG EQS</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2256468" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256468" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256468 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg" alt="The new Mercedes-AMG EQS" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_046.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256468" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG EQS 53 4MATIC+ at a charging station. <strong>Image credit</strong>: Mercedes</p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s a concern with a vehicle that&#8217;s built to be luxury-first that it could be slightly ruined by receiving the performance treatment. If a sedan&#8217;s main purpose is to pamper the driver and passengers, stiffening up the ride and remapping the accelerator so that every little tap results in a neck snap, it&#8217;s really no longer accomplishing its goal.</p>
<p>EQS fans that also want to go faster, relax. That hasn&#8217;t happened here. The AMG EQS — the first electric AMG to land in the United States — deftly combines what&#8217;s great about the electric luxury sedan with some tuning by the AMG team.</p>
<p>With a power increase of up to 751 horsepower and 752-pound feet of torque (a jump of ​​133 horsepower and 69-pound feet of torque over the EQS580), the luxury electric sedan feels decidedly quicker than its non-AMG counterpart. An internal being slammed into your spine 3.4 seconds from zero to 60 quicker.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not just the two electric motors that got an upgrade. Tweaks to the cooling system, wiring, and battery management system of the 107.8-kWh capacity pack on the AMG variant also allow the vehicle in Sport and Sport Plus mode to stay at peak performance longer. During my drive from Palm Springs to Los Angeles, I never felt a loss of power after multiple acceleration tests.</p>
<p>That increase also comes with new acceleration-coupled sounds in the vehicle called the AMG sound experience. I&#8217;m a fan of these EV noises. While artificial, they do recreate the audible experience of sudden bursts of speed.</p>
<p>The power increase is accompanied by AMG ride control air suspension with active dampeners. Throw in the 4Matic+ all-wheel-drive system and rear-wheel steering of up to nine degrees and attacking hairpin turns at speed a controlled and impressive experience considering the size and heft of the vehicle. There is some body roll, but it&#8217;s far less than what I&#8217;ve experienced on the regular EQS.</p>
<p>In addition to all those performance hardware and software tweaks and the new Sport Plus, there&#8217;s another new mode that luck would have it, I was able to test. As we climbed higher into the mountains during the drive, and the road transformed from black to gray, to snow-covered white, I was able to use that AMG Slippery mode. Which worked wonderfully in the ice and snow and any loss of traction was short-lived and more likely the result of the AMG EQS rolling on Michelin Pilot Sport EV summer tires.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256472" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256472" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256472 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg" alt="Mercedes AMG EQS electric vehicle" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-13.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256472" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG EQS encounters snowy roads. <strong>Image credit</strong>: Roberto Baldwin</p></div></p>
<p>When choosing the wheels for this drive program Mercedes was clearly expecting dry roads and if not sunny weather, at least dry weather. Mother Nature had other plans. With winter or even all-season rubber, the AMG EQS would have made even those nervous about driving on frozen water more at ease.</p>
<p>Inside, other than a few AMG flourishes here and there, it&#8217;s the same EQS with the latest MBUX infotainment system and its enormous 56-inch Hyperscreen that includes a 12.3 instrument cluster, 17.7 -inch touchscreen display, and 12.3-inch passenger display. All standard in the AMG trim level. The display also includes the Zero Layer interface, which presents a map with widgets of features that appear as needed.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256474" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256474" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256474 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg" alt="The new Mercedes-AMG " width="2000" height="1039" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=300,156 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=768,399 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=680,353 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=1536,798 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0730_041.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256474" class="wp-caption-text">Interior of Mercedes-AMG EQS 53 4MATIC+ shows the expansive infotainment system. Image credit: Mercedes</p></div></p>
<p>The crown jewel of MBUX — the voice assistant — continues to evolve. &#8220;Hey Mercedes&#8221; along with the Zero Layer interface are essentially the standard by what other automakers should strive to accomplish in the vehicle. A robust voice-powered navigation feature coupled with a more focused screen.</p>
<p>On more than a few occasions, I realized that instead of looking for a feature, I&#8217;d ask the vehicle to do what I wanted. Other items, like media controls that in previous generation Mercedes required multiple taps to skip to the next song, were presented readily in the Zero Layer interface hovering over the navigation.</p>
<p>Like with the SL Roadster, the combination of voice assistant and Zero Layer make for an improved infotainment experience although, I&#8217;m still puzzled why Mercedes made the screen so wide it&#8217;s actually blocked by the steering wheel. Sure they moved all the widgets over, but it&#8217;s still an odd decision beyond the ability to say, &#8220;hey, look how big we made that display.&#8221;</p>
<h2>2022 Mercedes AMG SL</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2256478" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256478" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256478 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg" alt="Mercedes AMG EQS electric vehicle" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256478" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG SL on a foggy section of the test drive.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Roberto Baldwin</p></div></p>
<p>While the balance of luxury versus performance errs on the side of speed and handling thanks to up to 577 horsepower and 590 pound-feet of torque on the AMG SL 63 variant, even at slow speeds (thanks to the previously mentions fog), the AMG SL delivers a rich top-down experience.</p>
<p>Mercedes will sell two versions of the vehicle, the AMG SL 55 Roadster with 469 horsepower and 516 pound-feet of torque and the more powerful 63 variant mentioned above. Both are outfitted with the automaker&#8217;s all-wheel-drive 4Matic+ system powered by handcrafted 4.0-liter V8 Biturbo engines.</p>
<p>The result of all that displacement coupled with turbos is impressive and well-mannered power that reacts instantly either from a standstill or while passing slower vehicles. The AMG SL 63 might be the more powerful vehicle, but the AMG SL 55 is likely the better call since there are very few instances where all that extra horsepower and torque are even usable.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256479" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256479" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256479 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg" alt="Mercedes AMG SL" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0108_EQS_SL-5.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256479" class="wp-caption-text">Interior shot of Mercedes-AMG SL<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Roberto Baldwin</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s also the least powerful SL Roadster you&#8217;ll be able to buy of this generation. Mercedes has no plans to release a non-performance version of the roadster. Instead, as with all other Mercedes, it&#8217;s decided to make sure that this vehicle, when not blasting through canyons, is as smooth and luxurious as any other Mercedes. During my tests, I can say that they&#8217;re about 85% there.</p>
<p>On everyday suburban and urban roads, the AMG SL Roadster offers up a nearly glassy ride, but its performance underpinnings are a gentle reminder that this is not an S-Class. You&#8217;re going to feel some of the bumps, holes and ruts in the road. The bright side to that is impressive handling that even on rain-slicked roads, kept the wheels firmly planted to the asphalt with just the slightest bit of oversteer that only appeared when you really pushed the vehicle. Steering is tight and responsive without feeling twitchy and the inclusion of the rear-wheel steering creates the impression of a smaller vehicle both on backroads and while tooling around town.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256477" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256477" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2256477 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg" alt="Mercedes-AMG SL 63 4Matic+ touchscreen" width="2000" height="1333" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/21C0727_0050.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2256477" class="wp-caption-text">Mercedes-AMG SL 63 4Matic+ 11.9-inch touchscreen display can be tilted back and forth. <strong>Image credit</strong>: Mercedes</p></div></p>
<p>Inside, Mercedes has also outfitted the SL with the latest version of its MBUX infotainment system complete with the Zero Layer option. As an extra bonus, because of potential sun glare, the 11.9-inch touchscreen display can be tilted back and forth from 12 to 32 degrees. The reflections of the sun are also why the 12.3-inch instrument cluster has an integrated visor. Sadly neither was needed during my overcast and foggy drive.</p>
<p>With the SL Roadster, Mercedes has built a proper convertible sports car that&#8217;s filled with its latest technology. Neither sides of the vehicle, performance, and tech, contradict the other. It&#8217;s a symbiotic relationship. Essentially, it&#8217;s the James Bond of cars. A nod to the past with a wild side that&#8217;s already ready with the latest gizmo to complete the mission while dressed in a tuxedo.</p>
<p>After driving the AMG EQS and SL vehicles back to back over two days, it&#8217;s interesting to see the beginning of the transition of AMG vehicles. The performance arm of Mercedes, like the automaker itself, is poised to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/mercedes-benz-to-build-eight-battery-factories-in-push-to-become-electric-only-automaker-by-2030/">go fully electric by 2030</a>.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s most striking is thinking about the future, I&#8217;ve driven the first generation SL 300 Roadster. At the time of its launch, it was like something from outer space. At some point in the near future, the automaker might introduce another AMG SL and if Mercedes continues to refine its EV technologies at the pace it&#8217;s doing so right now, it&#8217;ll likely be just as groundbreaking and electric.</p>
<p>Also, it&#8217;ll have no problem driving in snow even with the top down.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/first-drive-2022-mercedes-amg-eqs-and-2022-mercedes-amg-sl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256366</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doordash co-founder and CEO joins Meta&#8217;s board of directors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/doordash-co-founder-and-ceo-joins-metas-board-of-directors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/doordash-co-founder-and-ceo-joins-metas-board-of-directors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Doordash co-founder and CEO Tony Xu has joined Meta&#8217;s board of directors, the Facebook parent company announced on Tuesday. Xu has served as CEO of Doordash since 2013 and was appointed the company&#8217;s board chair in November 2020. Meta says Xu&#8217;s appointment is effective immediately. Xu&#8217;s appointment brings the total number of people on Meta&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Doordash co-founder and CEO Tony Xu has joined Meta&#8217;s board of directors, the Facebook parent company <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2022/01/tony-xu-joins-meta-board-of-directors/">announced</a> on Tuesday. Xu has served as CEO of Doordash since 2013 and was appointed the company&#8217;s board chair in November 2020. Meta says Xu&#8217;s appointment is effective immediately. Xu&#8217;s appointment brings the total number of people on Meta&#8217;s board of directors to 10.</p>
<p>“Millions of local merchants use Meta’s tools to grow and run their businesses every month. I look forward to working with the board as the company enters the next stage of its journey,” said Xu in a press release about the announcement.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s annoucement comes as Meta has been heavily focused on commerce over the past few years, as the company has introduced numerous shopping features across its apps, which includes Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp. The company has been focused on implementing shopping and ecommerce features directly within its services to prevent users from leaving its apps.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256461" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In a statement, Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg outlined that Xu has experience in solving complex challenges in commerce and that the company will leverage Xu&#8217;s expertise as it creates the Metaverse. Commerce will play a major role in the metaverse, which indicates that Xu will likely advise the board on such matters.</p>
<p>“Tony has built a great service for millions of people to get food and more from hundreds of thousands of restaurants and small businesses,&#8221; Zuckerberg said in the statement. &#8220;I’ve always thought it’s important to have great tech leaders on our board, and Tony has direct experience both running a tech company and solving complex challenges in commerce. I look forward to learning from his perspective as we build towards the metaverse.”</p>
<p>Meta&#8217;s board of directors includes Zuckerberg; Peggy Alford, the executive vice president of global sales at PayPal; Marc Andreessen, the co-founder of Andreessen Horowitz; Drew Houston, the co-founder and CEO of Dropbox; Nancy Killefer, a retired senior partner at McKinsey &amp; Company; Robert Kimmitt, Meta’s lead independent director and senior international counsel at WilmerHale LLP; Sheryl K. Sandberg, the chief operating officer of Meta; Peter Thiel, managing partner at Founders Fund and Tracey T. Travis, the executive vice president and CFO of The Estée Lauder Companies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/doordash-co-founder-and-ceo-joins-metas-board-of-directors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256461</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: Cell-cultured meat, alternative financing, avoiding tech debt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/techcrunch-roundup-cell-cultured-meat-alternative-financing-avoiding-tech-debt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/techcrunch-roundup-cell-cultured-meat-alternative-financing-avoiding-tech-debt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 20:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultured meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You don't need to be a scientist to understand the impacts of factory farming: if you've driven past the cattle feedlot in Coalinga, CA, the smell travels for miles.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You don&#8217;t need to be a scientist to understand the impacts of factory farming: if you&#8217;ve been near a North Carolina hog waste lagoon or driven past the enormous cattle feedlot in Coalinga, CA, the smell travels for miles.</p>
<p>In exchange for affordability and convenience, consumers, regulators and meat producers have learned to live with the many downsides of raising animals for food at scale: Greenhouse gases, water pollution, unsafe working conditions, and inhumane practices, just for starters.</p>
<p>But a United Nations report estimates that we&#8217;ll need to double global food production by 2050 to meet the needs of 10 billion people.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256297" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Rising demand for meat is driven in part by the rise of a global middle class. It turns out that the people who have the most buying power are also fans of cheeseburgers, and with consumption and population growth steadily increasing, one might even say meat is eating the world.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription</i></p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/is-cell-cultured-meat-ready-for-prime-time/">In a deeply researched report for TechCrunch+</a>, reporter Christine Hall examined the state of the cell-cultured meat industry and identified many of the startups innovating in the sector, along with the challenges they face when it comes to ramping up production and getting regulators and consumers on their side.</p>
<p>“It is still small-scale, and the most important thing we are doing that other companies should do is focus on the design, engineering and full-scale installations of vessels and the supporting systems to make a lot of it,&#8221; said Josh Tetrick, co-founder and CEO of Eat Just, which sells lab-grown chicken meat in Singapore.</p>
<p>Friederike Grosse-Holz, a director at impact investment firm Blue Horizon, said lab-grown meat is “a little like a moonshot,&#8221; but predicts that 11% of the seafood, meat, eggs and dairy consumed globally in 2035 will come from alternative sources.</p>
<p>“We are far from clear in knowing which technology will be the best,” she said. “So it is good there are so many players and a space for them.”</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading,</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YlKiwsOxy4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/is-cell-cultured-meat-ready-for-prime-time/">Is cell-cultured meat ready for prime time?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Is cell-cultured meat ready for prime time?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/is-cell-cultured-meat-ready-for-prime-time/embed/#?secret=YlKiwsOxy4" data-secret="YlKiwsOxy4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Use alternative financing to fuel VC-level growth without diluting ownership</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2255241" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255241" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255241" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1208301328.jpg" alt="One big piggy bank and an empty road sign on coloured background." width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1208301328.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1208301328.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1208301328.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1208301328.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1208301328.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1208301328.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255241" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=twomeows" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twomeows <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Investors are hungry for startups to throw their money at, but VC funding isn’t always the right option at all times or for every startup.</p>
<p>Alternative financing options such as revenue financing or expense financing are often overshadowed by the VC model, but they can be just as, and sometimes more, useful for SaaS startups, writes Miguel Fernandez, CEO and co-founder of Capchase.</p>
<p>In an in-depth post, Fernandez explains alternative financing for startups, and how to tell which option is right for you.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cSxm7MINjw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/use-alternative-financing-to-fuel-vc-level-growth-without-diluting-ownership/">Use alternative financing to fuel VC-level growth without diluting ownership</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Use alternative financing to fuel VC-level growth without diluting ownership&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/use-alternative-financing-to-fuel-vc-level-growth-without-diluting-ownership/embed/#?secret=cSxm7MINjw" data-secret="cSxm7MINjw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Startup accelerators’ definition of ‘value add’ is due for a refresh</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2255376" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255376" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255376" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1313836884.jpg" alt="Plus sign and increasing arrow print screen on wooden cube block on blue background which it mean positive sign such as more benefit thinking and mindset concept. (Plus sign and increasing arrow print screen on wooden cube block on blue background whi" width="1024" height="622" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1313836884.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1313836884.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1313836884.jpg?resize=300,182 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1313836884.jpg?resize=768,467 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1313836884.jpg?resize=680,413 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1313836884.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255376" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Dilok+Klaisataporn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dilok Klaisataporn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>One of the most notable trends in tech that has emerged during the pandemic is the steady commoditization of capital.</p>
<p>As founders find themselves fielding ample investor interest, accelerators are changing how they invest, what they offer to their cohorts, and how they maximize value and attract top talent, reports Natasha Mascarenhas.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“As capital gets further commoditized, early-stage investors are going back to the drawing board to see what is truly — and excuse my language here — a value-add service.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FITiS801lF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/08/startup-accelerators-definition-of-value-add-is-due-for-a-refresh/">Startup accelerators’ definition of &#8216;value add’ is due for a refresh</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startup accelerators’ definition of &#8216;value add’ is due for a refresh&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/08/startup-accelerators-definition-of-value-add-is-due-for-a-refresh/embed/#?secret=FITiS801lF" data-secret="FITiS801lF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2255889" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255889" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255889" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg" alt="Exclamation mark ,3D render against an orange background." width="1024" height="619" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=768,464 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=680,411 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1281030030.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255889" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=ShadowPix" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ShadowPix <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Startups grow fast, and when you’re building one, it can be easy to lose track of what’s working — and what’s not.</p>
<p>One way to track how well your business is doing is to look at the big-picture numbers, but Karen Peacock, CEO of Intercom, has a warning: averages can be dangerously misleading.</p>
<p>“If Jeff Bezos walks into a bar with 100 people, suddenly, on average, the net worth of each individual in that bar is over a billion dollars. Is that useful? Would that lead you to take the right actions? No — averages hide true insights.”</p>
<p>Peacock explains how founders can assess where their business’ strengths lie, and where they need to work harder, including how to gauge revenue health and using customer segmentation to find “leaks in the bucket.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ioMkKKXO00"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/dont-trust-averages-how-to-assess-and-strengthen-the-health-of-your-business/">Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Don’t trust averages: How to assess and strengthen the health of your business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/dont-trust-averages-how-to-assess-and-strengthen-the-health-of-your-business/embed/#?secret=ioMkKKXO00" data-secret="ioMkKKXO00" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Here’s how startups can prevent tech debt from piling up</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2255183" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255183" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255183" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1226629856.jpg" alt="Sink Full of Dirty Dishes" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1226629856.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1226629856.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1226629856.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1226629856.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1226629856.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1226629856.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255183" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Leland+Bobbe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leland Bobbe <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Focusing on going to market, introducing new features and customizing your product to help land a major client are all proven tactics for driving growth.</p>
<p>But companies that go on building sprees without a clear product roadmap in hand usually end up with a ton of technical debt, writes Sowmyanarayan Raghunathan, VP of Engineering at Talentica Software.</p>
<p>To minimize tech debt, Raghunathan posits four rules for engineering teams:</p>
<ul>
<li>Don’t let specific implementations continue for over three months</li>
<li>Do an architecture review of the product every 18-24 months</li>
<li>Upgrade to new open source versions two months after launch</li>
<li>Understand the product and identify NFRs in advance</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LcCcciUJoK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/heres-how-startups-can-prevent-tech-debt-from-piling-up/">Here&#8217;s how startups can prevent tech debt from piling up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here&#8217;s how startups can prevent tech debt from piling up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/heres-how-startups-can-prevent-tech-debt-from-piling-up/embed/#?secret=LcCcciUJoK" data-secret="LcCcciUJoK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>With more data available than ever, are companies making smarter decisions?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2254229" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2254229" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2254229" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg" alt="Illustration showing a team processing data to support a business idea." width="1024" height="781" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg 1826w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg?resize=150,114 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg?resize=300,229 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg?resize=768,585 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg?resize=680,518 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg?resize=1536,1171 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-896466430.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2254229" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> z_wei / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>For many companies, data is their greatest asset and at the same time, their largest problem.</p>
<p>In a follow-up to a 2014 post about the rise of Big Data, enterprise reporter Ron Miller looks back at the intervening seven years and found that infrastructure, technology and data analysis tools “have all improved dramatically, but it’s by no means a problem solved.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WU62WQ5AKe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/with-more-data-available-than-ever-are-companies-making-smarter-decisions/">With more data available than ever, are companies making smarter decisions?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With more data available than ever, are companies making smarter decisions?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/with-more-data-available-than-ever-are-companies-making-smarter-decisions/embed/#?secret=WU62WQ5AKe" data-secret="WU62WQ5AKe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>3 views on CES 2022</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2255935" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2255935" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2255935" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237579661.jpg" alt="An attendee wears a face mask while taking a selfie in front of the Welcome To Fabulous Las Vegas sign on the show floor during the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) on January 6, 2022 in Las Vegas, Nevada. - The CES tech show threw open its doors Wednesday in Las Vegas despite surging Covid-19 cases in the United States, as one of the world's largest trade fairs tried to get back to business. Despite some obvious gaps on the showfloor -- after high-profile companies like Amazon and Google cancelled over climbing virus risk -- crowds of badge-wearing tech entrepreneurs, reporters and aficionados poured through venues. (Photo by Patrick T. FALLON / AFP) (Photo by PATRICK T. FALLON/AFP via Getty Images)" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237579661.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237579661.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237579661.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237579661.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237579661.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/GettyImages-1237579661.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2255935" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;photographer=PATRICK+T.+FALLON" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PATRICK T. FALLON <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>If an event only attracts 25% of its usual crowd, for whom is it essential?</p>
<p>After covering CES 2022 from multiple angles for several years, TechCrunch Transportation Editor Kirsten Korosec, Hardware Editor Brian Heater and reporter Haje Jan Kamps shared their thoughts on how the pandemic has changed the event, and what this means for hardware companies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Kristin Korosec: CES hasn’t lost its automotive luster</li>
<li>Brian Heater: Hardware startups should reconsider their media strategies</li>
<li>Haje Jan Kamps: I missed it sorely this year</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lbA4lI0dqD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/3-views-on-ces-2022/">3 views on CES 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 views on CES 2022&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/3-views-on-ces-2022/embed/#?secret=lbA4lI0dqD" data-secret="lbA4lI0dqD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/techcrunch-roundup-cell-cultured-meat-alternative-financing-avoiding-tech-debt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256297</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tumblr adds a sensitive content toggle on iOS to comply with App Store rules</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tumblr-sensitive-content-toggle-ios-app-store/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tumblr-sensitive-content-toggle-ios-app-store/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 20:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automattic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baby Yoda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search results]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumblr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For weeks, Tumblr hid search results on iOS for a variety of tags to comply with the App Store&#8217;s guidelines. Today, Tumblr is trying to solve the issue by rolling out a sensitive content toggle for its iOS app, which allows users to opt-in to seeing sensitive content. (The toggle opts you out of seeing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For weeks, Tumblr <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/29/tumblr-ios-tags-ban-apple/">hid search results</a> on iOS for a variety of tags to comply with the App Store&#8217;s guidelines. Today, Tumblr is trying to <a href="https://wip.tumblr.com/post/673094877671800832/an-update-on-the-tumblr-ios-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener">solve the issue</a> by rolling out a sensitive content toggle for its iOS app, which allows users to opt-in to seeing sensitive content. (The toggle opts you out of seeing sensitive content by default.)</p>
<p>When you search for a sensitive tag &#8212; think something like &#8220;marijuana&#8221; &#8212; the updated Tumblr iOS app will now hide search results. Instead, a pop-up will appear, prompting you to turn off the sensitive content filter if you want to see the results of your search. If you click &#8220;show me the settings&#8221; to see sensitive content, you&#8217;re redirected to the Tumblr website on your mobile browser, not an in-app menu. Once you change your settings, you have to restart the iOS app for the change to take effect. Finally, you&#8217;ll be able to see search results that include fan art of Baby Yoda hitting a blunt (yes, really).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256217" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256217" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256217" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg?w=680" alt="Tumblr populates a warning message when searching sensitive content on ios" width="680" height="345" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg?resize=300,152 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg?resize=768,390 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg?resize=680,345 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg?resize=1536,780 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TUMBLRsensitivecontent.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256217" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tumblr</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256214" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>According to Tumblr, when the &#8220;Hide Sensitive Content&#8221; toggle is enabled, the app will hide post recommendations that have sensitive tags, blogs with explicit content and searches with sensitive tags. (Explicit content, by Tumblr&#8217;s definition, is not quite as explicit as <a href="https://tumblr.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/231885248-Adult-Content#blog-moderation">adult content,</a> which Tumblr defines as GIFs, images, videos or illustrations depicting sex or genitals. Adult content is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/03/tumblr-no-more-porn/">currently banned</a>. TechCrunch asked for clarity from Tumblr about the distinction between adult and explicit content but has not received a response yet.)</p>
<p>When the new toggle is disabled, users can see sensitive search results that don&#8217;t violate community guidelines or tap through an overlay to access blogs marked explicit &#8212; though the explicit content will still be hidden on iOS. Users with the toggle disabled will also receive recommendations of potentially sensitive content.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, when the toggle is enabled, some seemingly benign tags may still trigger the warning pop-up. For example, we found in testing that the tag &#8220;submission&#8221; is banned unless you opt out of the sensitive content filter, due to the word&#8217;s sexual context. This is an issue because the tag is often used in another, non-sexual way on Tumblr&#8217;s platform &#8212; if you post something to your blog that another user submitted to you, it will automatically be tagged &#8220;submission.&#8221;</p>
<p>In previous years, Tumblr had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/28/tumblr-just-added-a-switch-in-the-ios-settings-that-lets-you-turn-back-on-the-porn/">offered a similar toggle switch</a> that could block the site&#8217;s adult material directly in iOS Settings, unless a user opted into seeing this content. However, that toggle had been focused on banning the pornographic content Tumblr hosted before its decision to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/03/tumblr-no-more-porn/">officially ban all porn from its platform</a> back in 2018.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;These latest updates provide more control to our community on the iOS app to build the experience that fits them best, and to explore the content that they find interesting,&#8221; Tumblr <a href="https://wip.tumblr.com/post/673094877671800832/an-update-on-the-tumblr-ios-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> in a company blog post. &#8220;While the experience for our community is a top priority, we must also comply with Apple’s App Store Guidelines and our own guidelines.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tumblr-sensitive-content-toggle-ios-app-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A startup founder&#8217;s guide to allocating equity grants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/a-startup-founders-guide-to-allocating-equity-grants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/a-startup-founders-guide-to-allocating-equity-grants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 19:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief people officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Future of Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[options]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shareholders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vesting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leaders need to get better at understanding and articulating not just why equity is important but also how it’s determined.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kirsten Prost</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/TerceraCapital">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kirsten-prost-5071a146/">Kirsten Prost</a> is a VP at Tercera and supports the sourcing, execution, and monitoring of investments in third wave services businesses.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In the war for talent, equity compensation has become more important than ever, but it’s not the easiest concept to explain, especially in privately funded companies.</p>
<p>Equity isn’t a new concept. Public and private companies have been using stock options (or RSUs) to recruit, motivate and retain talent for decades. However, equity compensation has grown in importance when it comes to hiring, retaining and aligning incentives across all employees, not just senior executives.</p>
<p>This is happening for a few reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>A global shortage of skilled tech workers:</strong> Candidates with in-demand skills are now getting multiple offers and can practically name their price. That price, more often than not these days, includes some kind of equity component.</li>
<li><strong>Wage inflation:</strong> The labor shortage and market dynamics are causing significant wage inflation. Companies are looking for ways to increase total compensation while reserving cash. Equity is one way to do this.</li>
<li><strong>A growing focus on private valuations:</strong> The number of companies reaching unicorn status is increasing. According to CB Insights, <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research-unicorn-companies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">over 900 companies globally have achieved unicorn status</a>, and 2021 alone minted more than 450 unicorns, up from the previous high-water mark of 111 in 2019.</li>
<li><strong>Transparency around compensation:</strong> Compensation data is accessible. Historically, companies like Glassdoor have provided robust salary data for more mature organizations. Now, companies like AngelList provide both <a href="https://angel.co/salaries/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">salary and equity benchmarking for startups</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Expectations:</strong> More than half (53%) of millennials say <a href="https://content.schwab.com/web/retail/public/about-schwab/schwab_equity_compensation_survey2020_findings.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">equity compensation was the main reason</a> or one of the main reasons they took their job.</li>
</ul>
<p>Leaders need to get better at understanding and articulating not just why equity is important but also how it’s determined. So let’s start at the beginning.</p>
<p>An ownership mentality is good for both business and morale, which is why many founders choose to allocate some level of equity (even a small piece) beyond leadership roles. Leaders may have the vision, but they need a team to execute and concretize their ideas.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Think strategically, think ahead, and communicate — make sure you’re offering the right equity allocation, for the right strategic reasons, and to achieve the right goals.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>Designing your equity program</h2>
<p>Once you’ve decided stock options are going to be a component of <a href="https://tercera.io/resources/total-rewards-for-the-remote-workforce/">your total rewards package</a>, it’s time to define your philosophy and design your equity program.</p>
<h3>Sizing the equity pool</h3>
<p>First, you’ll need to determine the size of your employee option pool. You will want to formulate your thoughts prior to discussions with investors, who may require the creation of a larger option pool than is necessary if your proposed pool is disconnected from your hiring plan.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/a-startup-founders-guide-to-allocating-equity-grants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256170</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back Market reaches $5.7B valuation for its refurbished device marketplace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/back-market-reaches-5-7b-valuation-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/back-market-reaches-5-7b-valuation-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 19:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Back Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refurbished]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sprints Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Back Market has raised another mega round of funding. In May, the company raised a $335 million Series D round. Today, the company is announcing a $510 million Series E round, which values the company at $5.7 billion. If you’re not familiar with Back Market, the company operates a marketplace of refurbished electronics [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.backmarket.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Back Market</a> has raised another mega round of funding. In May, the company raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/back-market-raises-another-335-million-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/">$335 million Series D round</a>. Today, the company is announcing a $510 million Series E round, which values the company at $5.7 billion.</p>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Back Market, the company operates a marketplace of refurbished electronics devices — mostly smartphones. In other words, if you think smartphones are expensive, you can get a phone that is still in good condition without paying full price.</p>
<p>There are many reasons consumers might buy a phone on Back Market instead of buying a new phone from a carrier or smartphone manufacturer. In addition to saving money, many customers think new phones only feature incremental updates compared to previous generation models.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256352" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Many customers also want to avoid generating additional waste and choose a used device for that reason. Many old smartphones simply end up in a drawer after all. A new battery and sometimes a new display might be enough to turn an old device into an attractive refurbished phone.</p>
<p>Back Market doesn’t refurbish devices directly. Instead, third-party companies act as the sourcing partners for Back Market. By listing their inventory on Back Market’s marketplace, they can find customers more easily.</p>
<p>On the other end of the transaction, customers buy devices through Back Market, as there’s a 30-day money-back guarantee. Overall, 6 million customers have purchased a device on Back Market.</p>
<p>Sprints Capital is leading today’s funding round, with existing investors also participating, such as Eurazeo, Aglaé Ventures, General Atlantic and Generation Investment Management. The French tech ecosystem has been on a roll as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/05/payroll-startup-payfit-is-frances-latest-unicorn-as-it-raises-289-million/">PayFit</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/business-banking-startup-qonto-raises-552-million-at-5-billion-valuation/">Qonto</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/09/ankorstore-reaches-2-billion-valuation-two-years-after-launching-its-wholesale-marketplace/">Ankorstore</a> also announced that they had raised hundreds of millions of euros each over the last few days.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Our goal is to make refurbished electronics the first choice for tech purchases. We expect to see a similar development in the electronics market as we have witnessed in the pre-owned car market in America, where consumer confidence in buying second-hand vehicles has resulted in sales that have increased twofold compared to new car sales,” co-founder and CEO Thibaud Hug de Larauze said in a statement. “The support and confidence of these funds, together with our growing customer base, marks an important step in Back Market’s journey, and more importantly, for the circular economy as a whole.”</p>
<p>One metric that is particularly important for Back Market is the average failure rate. Right now, the company estimates that it has a failure rate of about 4%, which means that one in every 25 phones doesn’t work as expected in one way or another. That’s why customer service is key when it comes to customer satisfaction. The company also estimates that new devices have a 3% failure rate.</p>
<p>The startup expects to double in size with a specific focus on the U.S. market — it currently has 650 employees. Back Market operates in 16 countries, including many European markets, the U.S. and Japan.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/back-market-reaches-5-7b-valuation-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tupu.io wants to help women thrive in tech jobs through mentorship</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tupu-io-wants-to-help-women-thrive-in-tech-jobs-through-mentorship/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tupu-io-wants-to-help-women-thrive-in-tech-jobs-through-mentorship/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 18:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mentoring programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mentorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monica Sarbu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tupu.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xato.io]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2255844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Monica Sarbu, co-founder and CEO at Xata.io, has more than 15 years of experience working at tech companies. She never had a mentor to help her navigate her way inside the organizations where she worked, but she saw how some women and other historically underrepresented people struggled to find their way. She began thinking about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Monica Sarbu, co-founder and CEO at <a href="http://Xata.io">Xata.io</a>, has more than 15 years of experience working at tech companies. She never had a mentor to help her navigate her way inside the organizations where she worked, but she saw how some women and other historically underrepresented people struggled to find their way. She began thinking about how she could help more people succeed inside tech companies, and after much thought, she formed a nonprofit mentoring company in 2020 called <a href="http://tupu.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tupu.io</a> as a side project.</p>
<p>She initially considered writing a book, but she concluded that there is really no one-size-fits-all advice and it would need to be tailored to the individual&#8217;s situation. &#8220;I had this idea to build a mentorship program that would give [people] a custom solution designed for their own needs because most of the time, people come to you for mentorship in general when they have a problem,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>She sees these problems usually falling into one of two categories: They either have a specific issue with someone in the company or they feel stuck in their careers and have grown depressed or fallen victim to imposter syndrome. She felt a program like Tupu could help.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2255844" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>According to career site <a href="https://www.zippia.com/software-engineer-jobs/demographics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zippia.com</a>, just 25% of engineering jobs go to women. That means they are on average outnumbered 3:1, and it&#8217;s often worse than that. That can sometimes lead to a hostile work environment, whether that&#8217;s intentional or not.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have so many things that we can do to advise technical content companies to be better and create a more healthy environment because, in the end, this is what kind of makes you feel like you don&#8217;t want to be part of a tech company anymore. It&#8217;s the culture of the company,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Throughout her career, she has spoken at conferences, first primarily focused on women, and then later more general events, trying to articulate what it was like to be a woman inside an organization with mostly men. Through her speaking engagements, she was able to raise awareness and even empathy even among the mostly male audiences.</p>
<p>&#8220;I began the talk by asking them to try to put [themselves] in the shoes of a woman for a second [inside a tech company dominated by men] and then I tried to build a picture around this about what it feels like,&#8221; Sarbu told me.</p>
<p>She received a lot of positive feedback from men who hadn&#8217;t understood what it&#8217;s like to be one of a few women on technical teams. At that point, she wanted to do something more, and<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> the idea for Tupu began to form in her head.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hQjWZbvRGW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/12/all-raise-taps-stitch-fixs-katrina-lake-and-others-to-mentor-female-founders/">All Raise taps Stitch Fix&#8217;s Katrina Lake and others to mentor female founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All Raise taps Stitch Fix&#8217;s Katrina Lake and others to mentor female founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/12/all-raise-taps-stitch-fixs-katrina-lake-and-others-to-mentor-female-founders/embed/#?secret=hQjWZbvRGW" data-secret="hQjWZbvRGW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>She said that most programs like this charge by the mentee, and this usually limits the number of people who could be involved to the most promising employees, who in her experience have the least need. Her idea was to do this for free, putting in her own money initially while asking for donations from companies to help support the program and match more mentors with folks who need them.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our model going forward is to go to tech companies of all sizes and help them with supporting diversity in their organization by offering mentorship to their employees,&#8221; she said. &#8220;The companies are not forced to choose the most &#8216;promising&#8217; employees to sign up for a mentorship program (as is happening at the moment) and they are able to encourage everyone to sign up for Tupu.io, whether mentees and mentors.&#8221;</p>
<p>The program currently has 57 mentees for 128 mentors. The mentors are men and women who have experience working in tech companies. She said that the platform has been able to attract these users to this point with little or no publicity or advertising.</p>
<p>Sarbu, whose day job is running Xata.io, a startup building a serverless database for the Jamstack environment, wants to make the site self-sufficient through donations from participating companies while making the process of signing up and matching mentors with mentees more automated. The company is working on a more automated version of the site and expects it to be ready soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/tupu-io-wants-to-help-women-thrive-in-tech-jobs-through-mentorship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2255844</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Locket, an app for sharing photos to friends&#8217; homescreens, hits the top of the App Store</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/locket-an-app-for-sharing-photos-to-friends-homescreens-hits-the-top-of-the-app-store/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/locket-an-app-for-sharing-photos-to-friends-homescreens-hits-the-top-of-the-app-store/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[locket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[widgets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new social app, Locket, popped to the top of the App Store charts in recent days thanks to its clever premise to put live photos from friends in a widget on your iOS homescreen. In other words, it turns Apple&#8217;s widget system &#8212; typically used to showcase information like news, weather, inspirational quotes or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new social app, <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1600525061" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Locket</a>, popped to the top of the App Store charts in recent days thanks to its clever premise to put live photos from friends in a widget on your iOS homescreen. In other words, it turns Apple&#8217;s widget system &#8212; typically used to showcase information like news, weather, inspirational quotes or photos from your own iPhone&#8217;s gallery &#8212; into a private social networking platform.</p>
<p>The idea for the app was dreamed up by Matt Moss, a former Apple Worldwide Developer Conference student scholarship winner and recent UC Santa Barbara grad, who had been building a user research and testing platform called <a href="https://www.usehawkeye.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hawkeye Labs</a>.</p>
<p>Locket, he admits, was originally a personal side project &#8212; not his main focus.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256184" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;I built it as a present for my girlfriend for her birthday last summer,&#8221; Moss explains. &#8220;She was going back to school in the fall, so we were about to start a long-distance relationship,&#8221; he says. &#8220;The process of getting a little photo from her on my homescreen&#8230;seemed really appealing. Just a nice way to stay in touch.&#8221;</p>
<p>The developer build the app over a week or two and ended up using it with his girlfriend fairly extensively over the past six months, sending each other an average of five photos per day. As Locket also stores the photos sent and received in its history section, the app became a fun way to look back on their photos, as well.</p>
<p>Soon, the couple&#8217;s friends started taking notice and asked if they could use it with their own significant others, family or friends. So Moss decided to make Locket publicly available to users on the App Store.</p>
<p>The app launched on New Year&#8217;s Day, and has now seen more than 2 million users sign up as of this morning. On Sunday, Lokcet became the No. 1 app overall on the U.S. App Store, per <a href="https://apptopia.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apptopia&#8217;s</a> app store data, and had become the No. 1 Social Networking app the day prior. Apptopia reports only seeing around 1 million global installs so far, with about 31% from the U.S. &#8212; but its data is only through yesterday.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Moss credits Locket&#8217;s rapid adoption to going viral on TikTok, where he published videos to <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@locketcamera" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an accompanying company account</a> for Locket where he could show off the app in action. His video received some 100,000 views over just a couple of days. Other TikTok users then began making their own content featuring the app and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7047999931373652783" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the custom sound used</a> on the original Locket video.</p>
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" style="max-width: 605px; min-width: 325px;" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@locketcamera/video/7047999951283997998" data-video-id="7047999951283997998">
<section><a title="@locketcamera" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@locketcamera" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@locketcamera</a> Link in bio <a title="locket" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/locket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#locket</a> <a title="widget" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/widget" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#widget</a> <a title="2021" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#2021</a> <a title="2022" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#2022</a> <a title="♬ original sound - Locket" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7047999931373652783" target="_blank" rel="noopener">♬ original sound &#8211; Locket</a></section>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"></script></p>
<p>This helped blow up the app even more among TikTok&#8217;s young user base. In fact, one video made by a TikTok user in the U.K. topped 5 million views in a single day, Moss noted.</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s common for app developers to leverage TikTok to drive installs at the time of launch, Moss denies that any sort of paid influencer marketing took place here, nor did he run paid advertisements on TikTok or elsewhere, he says.</p>
<p>Today, Locket remains in the No. 1 position on the iPhone&#8217;s Top Free Apps chart as a result of its TikTok exposure &#8212; and because its early adopters invited their friends to download the app and check it out, driving further installs.</p>
<p>To get started using the app, download Locket from the App Store and sign up by verifying your phone number.</p>
<p>Locket then requests access to your iPhone&#8217;s Contacts and Camera in order to function. Ideally, Locket would allow users to bypass full address book access to instead allow users to invite friends through standalone invitations, as that would be a more privacy-focused approach. Moss tells us he&#8217;s considering changing this aspect of the app&#8217;s behavior, which is meant to make the app easier to use. However, he says Locket doesn&#8217;t store your contact info nor send its invites automatically using its own phone number &#8212; it just pops up the iMessage window so you can customize the text sent to your friends.</p>
<p>However, if you choose to decline Apple&#8217;s pop-up, which requests permission to pull in your Contacts, you aren&#8217;t able to use the app at all, we found.</p>
<p>After inviting and adding friends to join you on Locket, you&#8217;ll then add the app&#8217;s widget to your iOS home screen. The widget will showcase your friends&#8217; photos as they add images throughout the day. You can also launch the app at any time to add photos of your own to be sent to your friends&#8217; widgets.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2256290" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2256290" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2256290" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="347" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg 1972w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg?resize=150,77 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg?resize=300,153 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg?resize=768,392 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg?resize=680,347 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg?resize=1536,784 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Screen-Shot-2022-01-11-at-12.37.47-PM.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2256290" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Locket</p></div></p>
<p>There isn&#8217;t much more to the app than that, really. There are no fancy camera filters or effects, nor can you upload images from your Camera Roll. The experience is designed to be a way to share photos in real time with a small group of up to five friends or loved ones.</p>
<p>Locket&#8217;s quick shot to the top of the App Store has Moss now thinking of his next steps. He plans to later introduce a subscription model and support for additional widgets and, at some point, an Android version. As to whether or not he&#8217;ll take on outside investment, however, remains to be seen.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re definitely thinking about stuff,&#8221; he says. &#8220;We&#8217;ll see.&#8221;</p>
<p>But the creator believes there&#8217;s potential in Locket beyond its current photo widget experience &#8212; perhaps even growing out a set of features inside the app as users share more photos over time.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think there is something pretty meaningful to be built in the close friends and family space,&#8221; Moss says. &#8220;I do think people &#8212; especially younger people &#8212; are a little bit more tired of apps that are kind of very ad-centric and very metric-centric.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;You end up with these huge social circles on the app &#8212; where you have 1,000 friends on Instagram, or you have to send Snapchats back and forth with your 100 closest friends &#8212; which actually takes a lot of effort at the end of the day,&#8221; he continues. &#8220;So the idea of making something that&#8217;s more geared towards those five closest people, or those 10 closest people, and then providing a way to make your phone feel more personal and geared towards people instead of these apps &#8212; I think there&#8217;s a real appetite for that,&#8221; Moss adds.</p>
<p>Locket isn&#8217;t the first to offer a collaborative photo widget experience. Another app called <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/magnets-shared-widgets/id1520682943?ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Magnets</a>, launched in 2020, <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/10/07/magnets-app-lets-you-create-collaborative-photo-widgets-with-your-friends-on-ios-14/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had a similar idea</a> but also supported sending short text messages to friends through its widget. Other apps competing in this space include Ekko, Widgetgram, Lettie, Tile Widget, Fave and others. However, none have yet to achieve any sort of critical mass.</p>
<p>Locket is currently <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1600525061">a free download on iOS</a> but has only achieved a 3.4-star rating, as some users didn&#8217;t seem to understand how to make the widget work, or were struggling with the onboarding process. The latter seemed to largely occur during the height of its viral surge when the app <a href="https://twitter.com/thefuturematt/status/1478527894087344128">was experiencing some issues,</a> but we&#8217;ve since tested Locket and found the problems to be resolved.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/locket-an-app-for-sharing-photos-to-friends-homescreens-hits-the-top-of-the-app-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256184</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twig takes $35M to turn stuff you own into a way to pay</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/twig-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/twig-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B Corp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circular economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fasanara Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gucci]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hermès]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lvmh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256099</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twig, a London-based fintech targeting Gen Z and younger millennial consumers with an e-money account that gives them instant cash-outs on fashion and electronics they want to sell, has closed a $35 million Series A round of funding. The investment is led by U.K.-based fintech specialist, Fasanara Capital, with additional backing from a number of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://twigcard.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twig</a>, a London-based fintech targeting Gen Z and younger millennial consumers with an e-money account that gives them instant cash-outs on fashion and electronics they want to sell, has closed a $35 million Series A round of funding.</p>
<p>The investment is led by U.K.-based fintech specialist, Fasanara Capital, with additional backing from a number of undisclosed strategic investors which Twig says include current and former executives from LVMH, Valentino and Goldman Sachs, among others.</p>
<p>The startup was only founded in mid 2020 &#8212; launching its service in the U.K. last July &#8212; but it touts rapid domestic growth (100,000+ monthly downloads of its apps; reaching sixth position in the iOS App Store&#8217;s top finance apps); and is already gearing up for international expansion.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256099" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The Series A is pegged for launching in the U.S. (slated for Q1 this year) and the EU (Q2; where it&#8217;s eyeing Italy, France and Germany for starters), as well as expanding the product&#8217;s capabilities and feature-set with a focus on the buzz around web3 and digital collectables.</p>
<p>For now, Twig accounts are only available in the U.K. Founder and CEO Geri Cupi tells TechCrunch it has around 250,000 users at this stage.</p>
<p>He adds that the typical user is a 22-year-old, recently graduated professional female &#8212; perhaps with a bunch of stuff in her wardrobe that she&#8217;s outgrown and would be happy to resell.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WLOOMW2XJa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/vinted-raises-303m-for-its-2nd-hand-clothes-marketplace-used-by-45m-and-now-valued-at-4-5b/">Vinted raises $303M for its 2nd-hand clothes marketplace, used by 45M and now valued at $4.5B</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Vinted raises $303M for its 2nd-hand clothes marketplace, used by 45M and now valued at $4.5B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/vinted-raises-303m-for-its-2nd-hand-clothes-marketplace-used-by-45m-and-now-valued-at-4-5b/embed/#?secret=WLOOMW2XJa" data-secret="WLOOMW2XJa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Growth via user referrals looks likely to have helped fuel its early rise, given Twig charges users a £1 transfer fee for users to send money to a third-party account but there&#8217;s no fee if you transfer from one Twig account to another.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also worth noting that despite having a marketing slogan which paints itself as &#8220;your bank of things&#8221;, Twig is not actually a bank; rather a Twig account is an &#8220;e-money account&#8221; &#8212; so there are key regulatory differences (such as Twig accounts not being covered by the U.K.&#8217;s deposit guarantee scheme).</p>
<p>Not being a full fat bank means the startup can scale faster into new markets, with lighter regulatory requirements on the service than if it needed to obtain a banking licence. For now it&#8217;s not in a hurry to turn into an actual bank, per Cupi.</p>
<p>In earlier decades, long before the internet- and open banking-fuelled fintech boom, legacy banks would pitch to get a new crop of school leavers signed up by offering freebies &#8212; like bags, stationery, music or other offers. Now fintech startups compete to offer the most appealing feature mix to net a target youth demographic.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s fair to say that getting money into accounts remains a key aim.</p>
<p>That said, Twig is applying for <a href="https://bcorporation.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">B Corp certification</a> which emphasizes social purpose and environmental performance, as well as transparency and accountability &#8212; Cupi says it&#8217;s in the final stage of the application; it has pending status currently and he anticipates getting full status in Q1 &#8212; while its PR pushes claims of sustainability and circularity, given that it&#8217;s plugging users into selling (rather than binning) their branded goods.</p>
<p>Its website also talks up its use of carbon offsetting and other initiatives to shrink environmental impact.</p>
<p>Thing is, in order for humanity to avert climate catastrophe, major reductions in global CO2 emissions are required &#8212; so, essentially, less consumption overall. Which does call into question the credibility of claims of &#8220;sustainability&#8221; being made to stretch around a concept of resale that risks fuelling increased consumption via instant valuations and cash outs, as Twig offers.</p>
<p>Selling a currently owned thing to free up cash might encourage the consumer to splash out and buy more new things than they otherwise would if they had held onto the original item for longer. Or, to put it another way, circularity needs to work hand in hand with longevity if it&#8217;s to shrink consumption and actually reduce CO2 emissions. And it&#8217;s not clear that reducing friction involved in reselling will lead to consumers buying less overall. On the contrary; it may do the opposite.</p>
<p>So that&#8217;s one potential wrinkle in Twig&#8217;s sustainability pitch.</p>
<p>However when we put this conundrum to Cupi he neatly irons it out &#8212; deploying a (somewhat circular) argument which states that Twig&#8217;s goal of increasing &#8220;liquidity&#8221; of secondhand things can work for sustainability and support reduced consumption by making more secondhand stuff available to buy &#8212; thereby reducing demand for new stuff to be made as more items (re)circulate through this (more vibrant) secondary economy.</p>
<p>&#8220;Essentially our core business is we enable consumers to get paid for their old items and in the process we give a new life to their items &#8212; and this increases supply in the secondary market at least,&#8221; he says. &#8220;The demand in the secondary market has been growing and growing. The reason we can afford just to be on the supply side of the market is there is such a bigger need for extra supply right now in the market. And when consumers get hat extra cash it doesn&#8217;t mean they&#8217;re going to use it to buy more things.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is from what we&#8217;ve seen from our users. Typically from the funds that are being transferred to Twig we see that roughly 42% of them get used for new experiences &#8212; that might be travelling, it might be&#8230; experience-led &#8212; so it doesn&#8217;t mean that if you increase liquidity you necessarily increase consumerization of things that have a negative impact on the environment. And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been seeing so far.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cupi condenses Twig&#8217;s business to a very simple pitch: &#8220;We tokenize assets.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The way Twig works is you can upload &#8212; let&#8217;s say a Gucci Marmont handbag &#8212; on the platform. And what Twig does is it tokenizes that asset and offers you a price for it,&#8221; he explains.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our goal is to make this available externally as well. In that scenario blockchain becomes useful&#8230; We want to increase the liquidity of this asset and make it very easy for consumers to trade the physical goods for virtual goods and use the virtual goods to buy physical goods or experiences.</p>
<p>&#8220;So we just want to make it much easier for them to trade, essentially.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cupi has a background in blockchain and the circular economy &#8212; which has included, back in 2018, <a href="https://medium.com/@socialdnateam/levis-albania-completes-the-acquisition-of-social-dna-ltd-53b76c6e3abd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">selling a denim upcycling business to Levi&#8217;s Albania</a>.</p>
<p>Physical items that resell well include fashion from brands like Nike, Gucci, Chanel, Hermes and other luxury makers, according to a Twig <a href="https://s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/twig.publications/twig-white-paper.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">white paper</a> &#8212; which talks about &#8220;redefining the future of ownership&#8221; and &#8220;empowering Gen Z to live a circular lifestyle&#8221;.</p>
<p>Apple electronics also hold their value well on the secondhand market, per Cupi &#8212; who notes that after Twig added electronics to the secondhand items it&#8217;ll buy, expanding out from buying fashion cast offs, its demographic shifted from over 90% female to around 70:30 female to male.</p>
<p>Twig takes care of the resale of pre-owned items for its users &#8212; providing them with an instant valuation and (potentially) instant cash to spend on whatever they like if it&#8217;s happy to buy the stuff they&#8217;re selling. (It has a pretty specific list of what it will and won&#8217;t buy.)</p>
<p>Shipping the goods to Twig is free for the user &#8212; so by using its service they essentially skip the hassle and risk associated with manually selling their stuff on a second hand marketplace like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/vinted-raises-303m-for-its-2nd-hand-clothes-marketplace-used-by-45m-and-now-valued-at-4-5b/">Vinted</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/06/depop-a-social-app-targeting-millennial-and-gen-z-shoppers-bags-62m-passes-13m-users/">Depop</a>. (Albeit, they may get less than if they sold the items themselves.)</p>
<p>If an item fails a quality check once it arrives at Twig&#8217;s warehouse the user is charged a fee to return it to them (and presumably any instant payment they got for it is also reversed). While if Twig ends up being unable to sell an item it says it donates the goods to charity rather than binning them to avoid sending stuff to landfill because that&#8217;s bad for the environment.</p>
<p>Cupi says it&#8217;s in a growth-focused phase at present so is not seeking to make chunky margin on resales.</p>
<p>The value it&#8217;ll offer for an item varies, depending on various dynamic factors &#8212; its white paper notes that it uses a &#8220;market-based pricing algorithm&#8221; to analyze more than 100 million products on the secondary market to provide &#8220;representative resale values for brands, item categories and market segments&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4iHQtnM1TU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/etsy-asks-how-do-you-do-fellow-kids-with-1-6b-depop-purchase/">Etsy asks, &#8216;How do you do, fellow kids?&#8217; with $1.6B Depop purchase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Etsy asks, &#8216;How do you do, fellow kids?&#8217; with $1.6B Depop purchase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/etsy-asks-how-do-you-do-fellow-kids-with-1-6b-depop-purchase/embed/#?secret=4iHQtnM1TU" data-secret="4iHQtnM1TU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Core to its premise is that factoring in resale value changes the concept of total cost of ownership for the consumer &#8212; which may have the power to shift buying patterns (it could, for example, encourage consumers to opt for high-end fashion to get value longevity over environmentally ruinous and low resale value fast fashion, say).</p>
<p>Combining bank-like functionality &#8212; Twig accounts come with a Twig Visa debit card and include capabilities like the ability to make domestic and international money transfers &#8212; with a baked-in secondhand goods resale service is a pitch tailor-made for the target Gen Z and younger millennial demographic which has shown a keen and growing interest in both the thrift and sustainability of secondhand marketplaces.</p>
<p>Twig&#8217;s target demographic also explains its marketing being heavy on talk of environmental friendliness via circularity. (&#8220;Twig makes it easier and empowers you to adopt a more sustainable lifestyle,&#8221; is one claim on its retro-graphic-heavy website.)</p>
<p>Gen Z especially has been dubbed the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/10/the-environment-is-gen-zs-no-1-concern-but-beware-of-greenwashing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sustainability generation</a> &#8212; with these young consumers prioritizing &#8220;usage of goods over ownership&#8221;, as Twig&#8217;s white paper puts it.</p>
<p>So reimagining the function of a bank as an arbiter and exchange of resale value &#8212; enabling consumers to turn all sorts of stuff into, essentially, quasi-currency to pay for other things they want to have or do (a sort of high tech reinvention of barter if you like) &#8212; rather than as a literal store of financial value starts to look pretty interesting.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s another sustainability wrinkle to tackle, though &#8212; given how thoroughly blockchain is baked into what Twig&#8217;s doing.</p>
<p>While its tech has been built on blockchain from the start you&#8217;d be hard pressed to notice from the user-facing descriptions on its website. But its plan for the Series A risks throwing its Gen Z-friendly eco-sounding marketing right out of whack &#8212; as its PR seeks to tap into the raging web3 hype, with the launch of what it describes as &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">a first-of-its-kind Web 3.0 green payment infrastructure&#8221;. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">This forthcoming functionality will enable users to &#8220;tokenize&#8221; real-world assets and &#8220;make them tradeable in seconds&#8221;, its release goes on, adding that: </span>&#8220;<span class="il">Twig</span> will enable digital and physical items to be monetized and traded in new ways. Such an approach will allow users to trade-in goods at the checkout page and buy crypto currencies as well as NFTs by trading-in their clothes or electronics.&#8221;</p>
<p>Quite how encouraging the trading of crypto and NFTs can be spun as &#8220;green&#8221; is an interesting question to ponder.</p>
<p>After all the energy costs of crypto can look like an extinction level event, in and of themselves.</p>
<p>For example, a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56012952" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study last year</a> by Cambridge University suggested that just one cryptocurrency &#8212; Bitcoin &#8212; consumed more energy annually than the entire country of Argentina.</p>
<p>Another piece of research,<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/mar/10/bitcoin-rise-could-leave-carbon-footprint-size-london" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> from March last year</a>, suggested Bitcoin consumed as much energy as Norway &#8212; with predictions that its carbon footprint would soon be akin to the emissions generated by the entire metropolitan area of London.</p>
<p>In short, the infamous inefficiency of blockchain-based cryptocurrencies &#8212; certainly those that require proof of work to validate transactions &#8212; looks anything but sustainable.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s even more wasteful energy usage being attached to blockchains too: aka the rise of NFTs (non-fungible tokens) which involve &#8212; and further encourage &#8212; the use of energy-intensive transactions by layering the trading of digital collectables atop blockchains.</p>
<p>The current hype around NFTs (as fashion/status symbols) combined with the retail trading of these digital assets &#8212; and the suggestion that hyper quick money can be made by burning energy to shift collectable pixels &#8212; pours yet more fuel on this energy bonfire.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Last year an analysis by a digital artist suggested</a> that an average NFT could have a carbon footprint equivalent to a month&#8217;s worth of electricity usage for a person living in the EU. So, again, it&#8217;s hard to conceive of a way to spin features that encourage users to get busy tokenizing and trading their stuff &#8212; and/or digital collectables &#8212; as, in any shape or form, &#8220;green&#8221;.</p>
<p>Once again, Cupi is not phased by this counter argument, though.</p>
<p>Firstly he says that the blockchain infrastructure Twig has been built on is more energy efficient than some other blockchains.</p>
<p>&#8220;Blockchain itself is not bad for the environment as a technology &#8212; there&#8217;s different applications of it,&#8221; he argues. &#8220;In our case the blockchain that we built on top of &#8212; it&#8217;s Hyperledger Sawtooth &#8212; the energy usage is very, very small compared to the other solutions out there.</p>
<p>&#8220;So we try to minimize the usage of energy intensive solutions.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also specifies that Twig is calculating its internal energy usage to try to quantify its environmental impact and &#8212; at a minimum &#8212; it&#8217;s doing carbon offsetting to counteract this.</p>
<p>He says it is also supporting projects that are seeking to sequester/remove CO2 from the atmosphere.</p>
<p>Although how viable/credible the specific projects are is a whole other matter.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L47tizUtvY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/back-market-raises-another-335-million-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/">Back Market raises $335M for its refurbished device marketplace, now valued at $3.2B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Back Market raises $335M for its refurbished device marketplace, now valued at $3.2B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/17/back-market-raises-another-335-million-for-its-refurbished-device-marketplace/embed/#?secret=L47tizUtvY" data-secret="L47tizUtvY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While Twig may be seeking to minimize/offset its own energy usage/carbon footprint, the bigger potential environmental impact is likely to be from secondary (for want of a better word) usage &#8212; aka, any consumption, energy use and CO2 emissions that Twig&#8217;s users and suppliers generate as a result of what its platform enables them to do.</p>
<p>Calculating those linked but indirect impacts &#8212; sometimes called &#8220;Scope 3&#8221; emissions, in sustainability reporting terms &#8212; is much harder than doing an internal audit of a business&#8217; direct energy usage. Yet Scope 3 emissions also tend to comprise the biggest chunk of an organization&#8217;s carbon footprint. So you can&#8217;t just wish all those connected transactions, emissions and effects away.</p>
<p>Twig is clearly trying to tackle some of this &#8212; by doing carbon offsetting to cover the shipping of goods, for example. And its ambition to gain B Corp status looks laudable.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s a lot harder to predict what sort of energy costs its platform may ultimately end up generating &#8212; based on the consumer demands and trends it might feed and/or drain.</p>
<p>By encouraging users to buy crypto and get into trading NFTs it&#8217;s clear there will be associated energy costs. And there is a risk that such intensive energy costs could end up erasing potential environmental gains (if Twig is able to turn increased liquidity of secondhand goods into a net reduction in manufacturing of new items via reduced demand from consumers to buy new).</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s also possible that such a radical reimagining of what can be used to make a payment &#8212; all sorts of items/things/stuff; in theory a consumer may not need to ever spend actual money in a world of tokenized value &#8212; could lead to substantial shifts in consumption that can actually move the needle on circularity. And move our societies away from the vicious circle of throwaway consumption that&#8217;s characterized so many decades of capitalism.</p>
<p>Put another way, if the things we have can be relied upon to more predictably sustain their value for resale &#8212; thanks to the help of blockchain-based tokenization (which can support authentication to combat fakes) and more stable valuations (based on knowing the full ownership history via a distributed ledger infrastructure) &#8212; consumers may be nudged to take better care of the stuff they have in order to preserve its longevity for better resale, meaning the world&#8217;s industries won&#8217;t need to make half so many things in the first place &#8212; lifting crippling systemic pressure on planetary resources.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s certainly a thought.</p>
<p>De-emphasizing money by making it much easier to make payments by exchanging all sorts of things might be exactly the kicker we need to rework how we think about value, ownership and wealth. And, indeed, planetary resources.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s Cupi again: &#8220;Instead of using your own cash to buy NFTs you can use things that you have at home and don&#8217;t use anymore &#8212; for instance you might have an old iPhone that you don&#8217;t use anymore and you can trade that for an NFT or you can trade that for some cryptocurrency or you can use that to buy an experience &#8212; you can use that to buy a trip to New York or you can use that to pay for your next vocational course&#8230; So the whole purpose of Twig is to increase liquidity in the market and &#8212; essentially &#8212; to make it very easy for people to use assets that they don&#8217;t use anymore and give them a second life.</p>
<p>&#8220;That way our ethos is you can both do good to your wallet and to the Earth.&#8221;</p>
<p>The vision for Twig is therefore to turn itself into a payments platform &#8212; but one that translates physical goods into payments on behalf of its users/customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;At the moment Twig is just a B2C platform &#8212; but it&#8217;s going to become a B2B2C platform. So it will be connected as a payment gateway of different providers,&#8221; he says, noting that it has inked agreements with &#8220;a couple of big merchants&#8221; to be plugged into its infrastructure (he&#8217;s not disclosing which retailers as yet).</p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re trying to do &#8212; essentially &#8212; is to reinvent the definition of wealth,&#8221; Cupi adds, discussing how he sees the notion of money evolving. &#8220;So if everything that you own can be treated as money your perception of wealth also changes.</p>
<p>&#8220;The old definition of wealth is the value of your largest asset &#8212; the value of your house, the value of your car&#8230; But you don&#8217;t see as part of your wealth &#8212; typically &#8212; the value of your wardrobe, for instance. This is what we&#8217;re trying to change. And in that way if everything has instant liquidity you can treat your things as cash. It doesn&#8217;t make a difference whether it&#8217;s cash &#8212; or a Gucci Marmont handbag. If you want to buy something in pounds it&#8217;s then the same.&#8221;</p>
<p>So if Twig gets its way the future of payments might get a whole lot more visual and physical &#8212; maybe you&#8217;ll be buying a secondhand iPhone by dragging and dropping an NFT you minted into the ecommerce payment window.</p>
<p>Or posting off a pair of limited edition Nikes to score that sweet Spring city break you&#8217;ve been looking forward to.</p>
<p>Or, er, buying a chunk of prime real estate with some prize pieces of diamond-encrusted jewellery&#8230;</p>
<p>While younger consumers may already be comfortable with a world of fairly commoditized value tradable stuff, what about older consumers? Does Cupi reckon Boomers or Gen X can be convinced to start making payments by parting with things they&#8217;ve ploughed their cash into?</p>
<p>Are first edition signed books and prize vinyl pressings going to end up folded into the future payment mix?</p>
<p>&#8220;To be honest I don&#8217;t know the answer to that,&#8221; he says. &#8220;At the moment we&#8217;re seeing our product, Gen Z reacts very well to it. And also young millennials &#8212; so twentysomethings&#8230; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; and in the U.K. It might be a different picture once we go to other markets as well.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ymibsEeYUM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/vestiaire-collective-raises-216-million-for-its-second-hand-fashion-platform/">Vestiaire Collective raises $216 million for its second-hand fashion platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Vestiaire Collective raises $216 million for its second-hand fashion platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/vestiaire-collective-raises-216-million-for-its-second-hand-fashion-platform/embed/#?secret=ymibsEeYUM" data-secret="ymibsEeYUM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yBXXDMP1Dy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/swappie-bags-40-6m-to-sell-more-secondhand-iphones-across-europe/">Swappie bags $40.6M to sell more secondhand iPhones across Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Swappie bags $40.6M to sell more secondhand iPhones across Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/16/swappie-bags-40-6m-to-sell-more-secondhand-iphones-across-europe/embed/#?secret=yBXXDMP1Dy" data-secret="yBXXDMP1Dy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/twig-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256099</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s Chang&#8217;e-5 probe finds on-site evidence of water on the Moon&#8217;s surface</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/chinas-change-5-probe-finds-on-site-evidence-of-water-on-the-moons-surface/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/chinas-change-5-probe-finds-on-site-evidence-of-water-on-the-moons-surface/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256302</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China’s Chang’e-5 lunar lander has found water on the surface of the Moon, marking the first-ever time scientists have found on-site evidence of the substance on Earth’s satellite.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Igor Bonifacic</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Igor Bonifacic is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/the-entry-level-2022-polestar-2-will-have-an-epa-estimated-range-of-270-miles/">The entry-level 2022 Polestar 2 will have an EPA-estimated range of 270 miles</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/six-more-women-sue-tesla-over-workplace-sexual-harassment/">Six more women sue Tesla over workplace sexual harassment</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">China’s <a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-change-5-lunar-mission-234824988.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1"><ins>Chang’e-5</ins></a> lunar lander has found water on the surface of the Moon, marking the first-ever time scientists have found on-site evidence of the substance on Earth’s satellite. In a study published in <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.abl9174" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><em><ins>Science Advances</ins></em></a>, Chinese researchers claim the lander detected signs of water molecules or hydroxyl, a close chemical cousin of H2O. Chang’e-5 used a spectrometer to analyze the composition of regolith in close proximity to its landing site. It found that most of the soil had a water concentration of less than 120 parts per million, making the surface of Luna much drier than that of the Earth.</p>
<figure><img src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2022-01%2F1c80cfb0-7304-11ec-bffd-e6c9de19ef1b&amp;thumbnail=675%2C&amp;client=49kdj93ncb8s938hkdo&amp;signature=4d90ca4aad46ff73ddd3a039cbe85a9650e4e3df" alt="Chang'e-5" data-uuid="81c80422-4669-36c3-a385-ee517201907d" /><figcaption></figcaption><div class="photo-credit">Honglei Lin et al.</div>
</figure>
<p>Chinese scientists believe most of the molecules came to the Moon through a process called solar wind implantation. Charged particles from the sun drove hydrogen atoms to the lunar surface where they later bonded with oxygen to form water and hydroxyl. The study builds on findings NASA <a href="https://www.engadget.com/nasa-moon-sunlight-water-sofia-artemis-162600047.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1"><ins>published in 2018</ins></a> when it found evidence of water on the sunlit surfaces of the Moon using an airborne infrared telescope. For decades, scientists had believed the Moon was completely dry due to its almost nonexistent atmosphere. With no atmosphere, the thought was there was nothing there to protect water molecules from the sun’s harsh radiation.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/china-finds-on-site-evidence-water-moon-174108765.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256302" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/chinas-change-5-probe-finds-on-site-evidence-of-water-on-the-moons-surface/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256302</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Second Amazon warehouse union vote planned for next month via mail-in ballot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/second-amazon-warehouse-union-vote-planned-for-next-month-via-mail-in-ballot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/second-amazon-warehouse-union-vote-planned-for-next-month-via-mail-in-ballot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vote]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The National Labor Relations Board today issued an announcement detailing plans for a second vote among Amazon’s Bessemer, Alabama warehouse employees. The planned follow-up would be conducted via USPS mail-in ballots, which will be mailed out February 4 and counted March 28. Late last year, the director of the NLRB’s 10th region announced that a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The National Labor Relations Board today issued an announcement detailing plans for a second vote among Amazon’s Bessemer, Alabama warehouse employees. The planned follow-up would be conducted via USPS mail-in ballots, which will be mailed out February 4 and counted March 28.</p>
<p>Late last year, the director of the NLRB’s 10th region <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/29/labor-board-authorizes-new-amazon-union-vote/">announced</a> that a second vote would occur, following Amazon’s lopsided victory against unionization. In a notice published by the NLRB, the organization notes:</p>
<blockquote><p>The election that commenced on February 8, 2021, was set aside because the National Labor Relations Board found the Employer interfered with the employees’ exercise of a free and reasoned choice by creating the appearance of irregularity in the election procedure by causing a mailbox to be installed outside the Employer’s main entrance and by improperly polling employees’ support during mandatory meetings. Therefore, a new election will be held in accordance with the terms of this Notice of Second Election. All eligible voters should understand the National Labor Relations Act, as amended, gives them the right to cast their ballots as they see fit and protects them in the exercise of this right, free from interference by any of the parties.</p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256294" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The ruling on a second vote followed complaints from the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union that Amazon had violated the vote by installing an on-site mailbox and “vote no” signage around the site. The company has long insisted that the failure to unionize reflects the will of its fulfillment center workers.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for the company told TechCrunch at the time, “Our employees have always had the choice of whether or not to join a union, and they overwhelmingly chose not to join the RWDSU earlier this year. It’s disappointing that the NLRB has now decided that those votes shouldn’t count.”</p>
<p>Questions around in-person voting were raised by the RWDSU during the initial vote, due to both pandemic concerns and potential voter coercion. The new vote will be conducted via secret ballot.</p>
<p>The RWDSU offered TechCrunch the following statement in the wake of this morning&#8217;s news,</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">Amazon’s misconduct during the first union election so tainted the outcome that the NLRB overturned the results and directed a second election for workers in Bessemer, Alabama. We are deeply concerned that the decision fails to adequately prevent Amazon from continuing its objectionable behavior in a new election. We proposed to the NLRB a number of remedies that could have made the process fairer to workers, which were not taken up in the Notice of Election issued today. Workers&#8217; voices can and must be heard fairly, unencumbered by Amazon’s limitless power to control what must be a fair and free election, and we will continue to hold them accountable for their actions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">Amazon responded to the news, as well, telling TechCrunch, “Our employees have always had the choice of whether or not to join a union, and they overwhelmingly chose not to join the RWDSU last year. We look forward to our team in BHM1 having their voices heard again.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/second-amazon-warehouse-union-vote-planned-for-next-month-via-mail-in-ballot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256294</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IBM looks to sustainability with acquisition of emissions data company Envizi</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/ibm-looks-to-sustainability-with-acquisition-of-emissions-data-company-envizi/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/ibm-looks-to-sustainability-with-acquisition-of-emissions-data-company-envizi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[envizi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[IBM announced this morning that it has acquired Australian startup Envizi to add to its package of ESG (environmental, social and governance) offerings to help measure environmental impact up and down the supply chain. The companies did not share the terms of the acquisition, but with Envizi Big Blue gets a platform for measuring, managing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://ibm.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IBM</a> announced this morning that it has acquired Australian startup <a href="http://envizi.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Envizi</a> to add to its package of ESG (environmental, social and governance) offerings to help measure environmental impact up and down the supply chain.</p>
<p>The companies did not share the terms of the acquisition, but with Envizi Big Blue gets a platform for measuring, managing and optimizing a customer&#8217;s environmental sustainability efforts. In other words, it&#8217;s taking a data-centric approach to the problem just as it did when it was<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/09/10/ibm-watson-health-unit-begins-to-take-shape/"> building Watson Health in 2016</a>, a division that it is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/07/ibm-reportedly-shopping-watson-health-just-as-healthcare-gets-hot/">reportedly trying to sell</a> at the moment.</p>
<p>Kareem Yusuf, general manager for IBM AI Applications, said that companies need data to drive insights, and that&#8217;s what his company is getting with Envizi.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256229" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Envizi&#8217;s software provides companies with a single source of truth for analyzing and understanding emissions data across the full landscape of their business operations and dramatically accelerates IBM&#8217;s growing arsenal of AI technologies for helping businesses create more sustainable operations and supply chains,&#8221; Yusuf said in a statement.</p>
<p>Envizi CEO and co-founder David Solsky sees this as a way to scale the company by taking advantage of IBM&#8217;s global presence, a typical argument for a company being swallowed up by a much larger one. &#8220;Today doesn’t mark the end of an era, nor the beginning of a new one. Rather, it is a transition to a structure that is going to allow us to scale at an unprecedented rate and globally help our clients accelerate progress toward their sustainability commitments,&#8221; Solsky wrote <a href="https://envizi.com/blog/envizi_acquisition_ibm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in a company blog post</a> announcing the deal.</p>
<p>IBM sees Envizi as AI-driven software to add to its existing package of products that includes the IBM Environmental Intelligence Suite, IBM Maximo asset management solutions and IBM Sterling supply chain solutions. The latter uses the IBM blockchain for sourcing and traceability along the supply chain, which could improve safety or traceability.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5IZISO1sg9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/24/walmart-is-betting-on-the-blockchain-to-improve-food-safety/">Walmart is betting on the blockchain to improve food safety</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Walmart is betting on the blockchain to improve food safety&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/24/walmart-is-betting-on-the-blockchain-to-improve-food-safety/embed/#?secret=5IZISO1sg9" data-secret="5IZISO1sg9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that even as the company continues to pursue AI-fueled solutions, this time it did not attach the name Watson to its ESG efforts, as it did with the healthcare initiative six years ago. Perhaps IBM has decided <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/16/technology/what-happened-ibm-watson.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Watson brand</a> has lost some of its shine over the years and has moved on from attaching the name to every AI-driven solution in the company.</p>
<p>The company notes that it is using these same software tools in-house to help drive its own sustainability efforts as it works to reach<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/salesforce-reaches-net-zero-energy-usage-announces-updates-to-sustainability-cloud/"> net-zero</a> greenhouse gas emissions by 2030.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/ibm-looks-to-sustainability-with-acquisition-of-emissions-data-company-envizi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roku adds a new &#8216;Live TV Zone&#8217; to its homescreen</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/roku-adds-a-new-live-tv-zone-to-its-homescreen/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/roku-adds-a-new-live-tv-zone-to-its-homescreen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Radio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pay tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pluto tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xumo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roku is furthering its investment in its Live TV platform with today&#8217;s introduction of a new &#8220;Live TV Zone&#8221; that will roll out to the main, left-side navigation on Roku devices. The addition is designed to promote and highlight Roku&#8217;s livestreaming options, which include its rapidly growing live TV channel guide, now offering free access [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Roku is furthering its investment in its Live TV platform with today&#8217;s introduction of a new &#8220;Live TV Zone&#8221; that will roll out to the main, left-side navigation on Roku devices. The addition is designed to promote and highlight Roku&#8217;s livestreaming options, which include its rapidly growing live TV channel guide, now offering free access to <a href="https://www.roku.com/blog/the-roku-channel-15-new-live-linear-channels" target="_blank" rel="noopener">over 200 live channels</a> featuring news, weather, kids&#8217; content, sports, movies, tv shows, Spanish-language programming and more.</p>
<p>The company first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/02/the-roku-channel-expands-to-include-over-100-live-channels-adds-a-live-tv-guide/">launched</a> its live TV channel guide in 2020 as part of its broader free streaming hub, The Roku Channel, where Roku owners can also stream ad-supported TV shows and movies. At the time, the guide had provided access to over 100 channels from a branded, purple tile that appeared within The Roku Channel. When launched, users could browse through 12 hours of programming information. The experience, which is similar to how pay-TV viewers can browse what&#8217;s now airing in their own provider&#8217;s guide, helps to make the transition to Roku easier for cord-cutters who are used to turning on their TV and accessing live content. However, it also serves as a way to stream shows, movies, news and more without a paid streaming subscription &#8212; an option that may appeal to those looking to save money through cord-cutting.</p>
<p>With the live TV service, Roku positioned itself as more of a direct challenger to other free streamers, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/22/viacom-buys-the-free-video-streaming-service-pluto-tv-for-340-million/">ViacomCBS-owned</a> Pluto TV and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/02/25/comcast-to-buy-xumo-for-ad-supported-streaming-service-and-technology.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Comcast&#8217;s</a> XUMO. The former, which <a href="https://deadline.com/2021/08/pluto-tv-reaches-1-billion-annual-revenue-milestone-streaming-advertising-1234809600/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reached $1 billion</a> in annual revenue last year &#8212; about a year ahead of schedule &#8212; is an indication of the sizable revenue available in this market. Plus, the rollout of livestreaming has enabled media software maker Plex to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plex-raises-50m-growth-round-to-fuel-ad-supported-streaming-expansions/">grow its business</a> and further fund its mission of becoming a one-stop shop for consumers&#8217; media needs.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256152" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Roku, meanwhile, generates the majority of its revenue through its platform, not device sales. In other words, largely through advertising inserted inside its free content and content distribution. That&#8217;s also the part of the business that&#8217;s currently growing.</p>
<p>In the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/03/roku-q3-2021-earnings.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most recent quarter</a>, Roku&#8217;s platform revenue was up 82% year-over-year, to $582.5 million, while player revenue dropped by 26%, to $97.4 million. Streaming hours in the quarter were also up 21%, to 18 billion, with active accounts (56.4 million) streaming 3.5 hours per day.</p>
<p>The company noted, too, that its <a href="https://roku-blog.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Report_FINAL_Sept-2021.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://roku-blog.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roku-Streaming-Report_FINAL_Sept-2021.pdf&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1641995612603000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3o9LFkPkTVPm-3lWob2KaK">recent streaming survey</a> found that 61% of users without traditional pay TV still watch live news at least multiple times a week. So this update will play into that demand by making live news easier to access.</p>
<p>To get to the new Live TV Zone, you can either scroll down on the left-hand navigation to the &#8220;Live TV&#8221; option or do a search for &#8220;Live TV Zone&#8221; from the device. The feature is rolling out starting today.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/roku-adds-a-new-live-tv-zone-to-its-homescreen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256152</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Magna acquires tech, hires engineers of autonomous vehicle startup Optimus Ride</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/magna-acquires-autonomous-vehicle-startup-optimus-ride/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/magna-acquires-autonomous-vehicle-startup-optimus-ride/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 16:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magna Electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[optimus ride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Magna has acquired the technology, IP and assets of Optimus Ride, a startup based in Boston that was trying to commercialize electric autonomous shuttles. As part of the deal announced Tuesday, Magna has hired more than 120 employees of Optimus Ride. The financial terms of the agreement were not disclosed, Optimus Ride CEO Sean Harrington [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Magna has acquired the technology, IP and assets of Optimus Ride, a startup based in Boston that was trying to commercialize electric autonomous shuttles. As part of the deal <a href="https://www.magna.com/company/newsroom/releases/release/2022/01/11/news-release---magna-adds-more-than-120-engineers-strengthens-adas-capabilities" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced Tuesday</a>, Magna has hired more than 120 employees of Optimus Ride. The financial terms of the agreement were not disclosed,</p>
<p>Optimus Ride CEO Sean Harrington will not make the jump over to Magna and the AV startup will cease its operations.</p>
<p>Magna aims to leverage the tech and expertise from Optimus Ride to beef up its efforts in advanced driver assistance systems — technology that is in high demand. Magna has been keen to build out its ADAS offerings; last year the company tried to acquire Swedish automotive tech company Veoneer, but was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/qualcomm-acquires-veoneer-for-4-5-billion-canceling-its-agreement-with-magna/">nudged out by Qualcomm</a>. Veoneer&#8217;s Arriver tech &#8212; an advanced driver assistance system stack that includes sensors and software &#8212; was sold to Qualcomm, while the Swedish company&#8217;s other Tier 1 supplier businesses were retained by investment group SSW Partners.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256216" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;Growing our engineering bench strength in sensing hardware and software helps accelerate our path forward in a rapidly growing ADAS market,&#8221; John O&#8217;Hara, president of Magna Electronics, said in a statement.</p>
<p>The former Optimus Ride engineers will remain in Boston. Magna will use this new team to establish a Boston-based engineering center, which in turn could help the company attract more software and robotics talent.</p>
<p>&#8220;As advancements in autonomy continue, we saw an opportunity to bring in additional expertise to support current programs as well as future customer needs. We are happy to welcome the Optimus Ride employees to the Magna family,&#8221; O&#8217;Hara added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/magna-acquires-autonomous-vehicle-startup-optimus-ride/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256216</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orbit Fab&#8217;s on-orbit fuel shuttle will top up Astroscale&#8217;s servicing satellites</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/orbit-fabs-on-orbit-fuel-shuttle-will-top-up-astroscales-servicing-satellites/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/orbit-fabs-on-orbit-fuel-shuttle-will-top-up-astroscales-servicing-satellites/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 16:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astroscale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orbit Fab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satellites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a new partnership that should break new ground for sustainable orbital operations, &#8220;gas stations in space&#8221; startup Orbit Fab has teamed with Astroscale to provide on-orbit refueling services to the latter company&#8217;s LEXI (life extension in-orbit) geostationary servicing spacecraft. Both Astroscale and Orbit Fab&#8217;s core offerings are designed to provided ways for satellites to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a new partnership that should break new ground for sustainable orbital operations, &#8220;gas stations in space&#8221; startup Orbit Fab has teamed with Astroscale to provide on-orbit refueling services to the latter company&#8217;s LEXI (life extension in-orbit) geostationary servicing spacecraft.</p>
<p>Both Astroscale and Orbit Fab&#8217;s core offerings are designed to provided ways for satellites to extend their useful life. Orbit Fab has designed technology that aims to make it easy for satellites to get fueled up while in space, with a custom interface that makes it possible for other spacecraft to latch on and transfer fuel easily while on orbit. Astroscale is using its LEXI satellite to mission extension provide to existing spacecraft located in geostationary orbit (GEO), by attaching to them and correcting their course, or relocating them to a new target inclination.</p>
<p>Astroscale is touting LEXI as &#8220;the first satellite designed to be refueled,&#8221; which makes it a perfect target customer for Orbit Fab&#8217;s refueling interface (the Rapidly Attachable Fluid Transfer Interface or RAFTI for short) and roving orbital tanker. If all goes to plan, the first Astroscale LEXI will be active in space by 2026, and Orbit Fab is contracted to provide the LEXI fleet with up to 1,000 kg of Xenon propellant for top ups.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256227" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Orbit Fab says it plans to have &#8220;dozens&#8221; of fuel tankers and shuttles in space over the next five to 10 years, with spacecraft placed strategically in low Earth orbit (LEO), GEO and also in cislunar space, which should become a more active destination as NASA ramps its Artemis program. The first Orbit Fab fueling spacecraft should be in LEO by 2023 if all goes to plan.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/orbit-fabs-on-orbit-fuel-shuttle-will-top-up-astroscales-servicing-satellites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256227</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Healthcare tech platform Doctolib acquires encryption startup Tanker</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/healthcare-tech-platform-doctolib-acquires-encryption-startup-tanker/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/healthcare-tech-platform-doctolib-acquires-encryption-startup-tanker/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 16:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doctolib]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tanker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2256195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Doctolib is expected to close the acquisition of Tanker today (based on regulatory filings). Doctolib is a French unicorn that develops a software-as-a-service product to help doctors and medical workers with admin tasks. In particular, Doctolib acts as a booking platform that connects doctors with patients; 300,000 health professionals pay for the service [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.doctolib.fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Doctolib</a> is expected to close the acquisition of <a href="https://tanker.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tanker</a> today (based on regulatory filings). Doctolib is a French unicorn that develops a software-as-a-service product to help doctors and medical workers with admin tasks. In particular, Doctolib acts as a booking platform that connects doctors with patients; 300,000 health professionals pay for the service and 60 million people have used it in Europe.</p>
<p>Tanker helps healthcare tech companies secure user data. The startup has developed a protocol as well as client-side development kits that can be integrated in a web app, a mobile app or a desktop app.</p>
<p>After you add Tanker to your product, messages and files that are shared between patients and health professionals are end-to-end encrypted. Tanker and its customers can’t decrypt files or messages as it doesn’t have access to the private encryption key. In other words, if you’re not the sender nor the recipient, you can’t decrypt the data.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2256195" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>With a focus on the healthcare industry, Tanker lists Doctolib, healthcare insurance startup <a href="https://alan.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alan</a> and telehealth startup <a href="https://www.qare.fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Qare</a> as its customers on <a href="https://tanker.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the company’s website</a>. In June 2020, Doctolib announced that it added end-to-end encryption thanks to a <a href="https://info.doctolib.fr/blog/doctolib-adopte-le-chiffrement-de-bout-en-bout-nouvelle-etape-dans-la-securisation-des-donnees-de-sante/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">partnership with Tanker</a>.</p>
<p>A source sent me a regulatory filing from January 3, 2022 with details on the transaction between Doctolib and Tanker. A previous regulatory filing from December 22, 2021 also mentions the acquisition. You can view both of these documents on <a href="https://www.pappers.fr/entreprise/doctolib-794598813" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pappers</a>.</p>
<p>“Doctolib plans to acquire the shares of the company named Tanker,” a lawyer writes in a letter. “This transaction would be conducted based on the terms of the agreement protocol signed on December 9th, 2021, which involves transferring 100% of the shares of the capital of the company Tanker for the benefit of Doctolib.”</p>
<p>The most recent filing mentions January 11, 2022 as the closing date for the transaction, which is today. Another source told me that the acquisition was currently happening. We have reached out to Doctolib, but received a &#8220;no comment&#8221; on the matter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Based on the legal documents, Doctolib is acquiring Tanker in a cash and stock transaction, which would value Tanker at $28 million to $34 million (€25 million to €30 million).</p>
<h2>The valuation enigma</h2>
<p>Yesterday, I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/doctolib-is-now-used-by-300000-doctors-and-medical-workers/">wrote</a> about Doctolib’s press conference on its most recent metrics and upcoming product releases. Interestingly, Doctolib co-founder and CEO Stanislas Niox-Chateau said they “have stopped communicating on funding rounds for the past several years. Every quarter, every year, investors invest once again or invest for the first time based on our long-term project.”</p>
<p>Back in 2019, the company said that it had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/19/doctolib-is-now-a-unicorn-with-new-170-million-round/">reached</a> a valuation of $1.13 billion (€1 billion). That’s the last time Doctolib talked about funding rounds.</p>
<p>But that’s not the most recent funding round. For instance, as Charlie Perreau <a href="https://twitter.com/CharliePERREAU/status/1480602092796526596" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spotted</a>, General Atlantic invested $69 million (€61 million) in the company back in February 2020.</p>
<p>As for the company’s valuation, based on Tanker’s acquisition, each Doctolib share is worth €170.91. There are currently around 18 million Doctolib shares, which means that Doctolib could be valued at roughly €3 billion ($3.4 billion).</p>
<p>That valuation seems low given Doctolib&#8217;s customer base (300,000) and Doctolib&#8217;s starting price (€129 per month). Maybe Doctolib&#8217;s shares were a bit undervalued as a nice gesture for Tanker investors. Maybe Doctolib hasn&#8217;t raised in a while and is about to raise at a higher valuation. It remains an enigma for now.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0QSYXhJJgw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/doctolib-is-now-used-by-300000-doctors-and-medical-workers/">Doctolib is now used by 300,000 doctors and medical workers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Doctolib is now used by 300,000 doctors and medical workers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/10/doctolib-is-now-used-by-300000-doctors-and-medical-workers/embed/#?secret=0QSYXhJJgw" data-secret="0QSYXhJJgw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/11/healthcare-tech-platform-doctolib-acquires-encryption-startup-tanker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2256195</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
