<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:40:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Atlys raises $4.25M to make visa applications faster and easier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/atlys-raises-4-25m-to-make-visa-applications-faster-and-easier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/atlys-raises-4-25m-to-make-visa-applications-faster-and-easier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlys]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[International travel is slowly opening up again, but that also means business and leisure travelers alike will once again have to think about visa restrictions as they take to the air. Nobody has ever enjoyed the process of applying for a visa, but Atlys promises to take the hassle out of the process. The company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">International travel is slowly opening up again, but that also means business and leisure travelers alike will once again have to think about visa restrictions as they take to the air. Nobody has ever enjoyed the process of applying for a visa, but <a href="https://www.atlys.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlys</a> promises to take the hassle out of the process. The company today announced that it has raised a $4.25 million seed funding round led by Andreessen Horowitz. Pinterest co-founders Ben Silbermann and Evan Sharp also participated in this round, together with The Chainsmokers’ Mantis VC (yes, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Io0fBr1XBUA">those Chainsmokers</a>), Long Journey Ventures, South Park Commons Fund and Ari Emmanuel’s Endeavor.</p>
<p>Atlys argues that it can take travelers up to 13 hours to work through the visa process for various countries &#8212; and that&#8217;s without trying to figure out the ever-changing COVID testing and vaccination requirements. While most business travelers work with agencies that speed up this process by quite a bit, especially for repeat applications, Atlys promises to bring the process down to five minutes.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225848" style="width: 210px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225848" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-medium wp-image-2225848" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?w=200" alt="Mohak Nahta, Founder of Atlys" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg 3268w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=768,1151 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=454,680 454w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=1025,1536 1025w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=1367,2048 1367w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Mohak-Nahta_Atlys_-Headshot-1.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2225848" class="wp-caption-text">Atlys founder Mohak Nahta. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Atlys</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225750" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Using the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/atlys-simplify-travel/id1514036839" target="_blank" rel="noopener">company&#8217;s iPhone app</a>, travelers answer a few questions about their travels (where you are, where you are going, why you are traveling, etc.) and scan their documents. There are some smart integrations here, too, with the ability to take passport photos and then pick them up at Walgreens (or get delivery) or to ask your manager for a letter of employment signed through DocuSign.</p>
<p>Pricing depends on where you are and where you are going, but it tops out at about $50.</p>
<p>The company was founded by Mohak Nahta, who came to the U.S. as an immigrant himself. &#8220;I am thrilled to have such an incredible group of investors supporting <span class="il">Atlys</span> and our mission,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It is with their invaluable experience and guidance that will propel us further in our quest to simplify travel and create a seamless process for all.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company plans to use the new funding to build out its team and expand its coverage across more country pairs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;One of the things we look for in founders is &#8216;founder-product fit&#8217;, meaning does the founder have a unique insight into the market or problem they are trying to solve? As an immigrant myself, I immediately appreciated how deeply and personally Mohak also understood the cumbersome visa process, and how he was leveraging his insights to build Atlys,&#8221; said Sriram Krishnan, general partner at Andreessen Horowitz. &#8220;The magic of Atlys lies in its ability to connect many disparate systems behind the scenes, while offering a simple, streamlined end-customer experience.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u7LPtGjiOMQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MEi3P6xCyy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/the-chainsmokers-just-closed-their-debut-venture-fund-mantis-with-35-million/">The Chainsmokers just closed their debut venture fund, Mantis, with $35 million</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Chainsmokers just closed their debut venture fund, Mantis, with $35 million&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/the-chainsmokers-just-closed-their-debut-venture-fund-mantis-with-35-million/embed/#?secret=MEi3P6xCyy" data-secret="MEi3P6xCyy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/atlys-raises-4-25m-to-make-visa-applications-faster-and-easier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225750</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook changes its corporate branding to Meta</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frances Haugen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard blumenthal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, it&#8217;s official. After 17 years of being called Facebook, the social networking parent company behind Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Oculus has a new name. Facebook&#8217;s corporate entity is now Meta. Facebook creator Mark Zuckerberg announced the change at the company&#8217;s AR/VR-focused Connect event, sharing that the new title captured more of the company&#8217;s core [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Well, it&#8217;s official. After 17 years of being called Facebook, the social networking parent company behind Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and Oculus has a new name.</p>
<p>Facebook&#8217;s corporate entity is now Meta.</p>
<p>Facebook creator Mark Zuckerberg announced the change at the company&#8217;s AR/VR-focused Connect event, sharing that the new title captured more of the company&#8217;s core ambition: to build the metaverse.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225747" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;To reflect who we are and what we hope to build, I am proud to announce that starting today, our company is now Meta. Our mission remains the same &#8212; it&#8217;s still about bringing people together. Our apps and our brands &#8212; they&#8217;re not changing either,&#8221; Zuckerberg said. &#8220;From now on, we&#8217;re going to be metaverse-first, not Facebook-first.&#8221;</p>
<p>The name change comes at a&#8230; convenient time for Facebook, which has seen a sustained backlash to its brand, particularly in recent weeks after a former employee leaked a trove of documents to the media and government bodies, detailing the missteps Facebook has made over the years in building out its platform responsibly. Facebook had been laying the groundwork for this change for months, seemingly in an effort to move its core branding further from the relentless negative headlines surrounding its most popular product which has been a lightning rod for angst among consumers.</p>
<p>In July, CEO Mark Zuckerberg announced in a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview">Verge</a> profile that Facebook was betting it all on the metaverse. It was a surprise announcement for the trillion-dollar company, mainly because while Facebook has spent plenty of money and effort on virtual reality hardware, it&#8217;s social VR products have largely been short-lived failures and it had said barely anything about its beta Horizons social platform since announcing it more than a year-and-a-half earlier.</p>
<p>In August, Facebook organized an unusually large press push around a VR app designed to let people take meetings in VR. Zuckerberg hit the morning shows and dedicated a surprising amount of effort towards showcasing the small VR app.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In September, in a blog post called &#8220;Building the Metaverse Responsibly&#8221; Facebook announced a $50 million fund dedicated towards investment in research &#8220;to ensure these products are developed responsibly.&#8221; This month, Facebook announced a smaller $10 million creator fund for developers on its nascent Horizon Worlds platform and they also detailed that they planned to hire a whopping 10,000 employees in the EU specifically to build out their metaverse platform.</p>
<p>Last week, a story in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse">The Verge</a> floated that Facebook was mulling a name change to their corporate entity.</p>
<p>Ultimately, distancing the company&#8217;s core business from a product associated with the most problems is an unsurprising move for them, but changing its name to Meta will require Facebook to align it&#8217;s core brand with a product that could be years from relevancy and could encounter many failures on the way to potential mainstream success. Facebook still has 2.5 billion users while their metaverse products likely have a few thousand users at most currently.</p>
<p>A major name change from one of tech’s biggest companies isn’t without precedent. In 2015, Google rolled out a new corporate structure of its own, creating a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/02/google-becomes-alphabet/">parent company known as Alphabet</a>. Google remains a subsidiary of Alphabet, but colloquially most people still call anything having to do with the company or its subsidiaries ‘Google,’ for better or worse. After almost two decades of building its brand and growing its products to almost three billion monthly users, Facebook can probably expect the same treatment.</p>
<p>While Google wasn’t trying to put distance between itself and its own name, Facebook has very different reasons for a rebrand. The company’s business continues to soar, but its brand has taken a beating in recent years, from Russian election disinformation in 2016, to major privacy lapses like the Cambridge Analytica scandal and now the flurry of ongoing revelations from Frances Haugen, a former member of Facebook’s civic integrity team turned Facebook whistleblower.</p>
<p>Facebook is also arguably under more regulatory scrutiny at the moment than any other company in the tech industry. In Congress, where lawmakers seldom agree on anything, Republicans and Democrats have united in their shared distaste for the company’s unfettered growth, cutthroat business tactics and concerns over Instagram’s detrimental effects on teen mental health.</p>
<p>During a Senate hearing last week with TikTok, Snap and YouTube, each social media company scrambled to explicitly contrast their own business practices with Facebook. YouTube posited that it didn’t “prioritize profits over safety.” Snap pointed to its own focus on ephemeral conversations, while TikTok argued that it thinks carefully about the wellbeing of teen users. But the efforts by Facebook’s peers appeared to be in vain.</p>
<p>“Being different from Facebook is not a defense,” Senator Richard Blumenthal said. “That bar is in the gutter.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225747</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tenways CGO 600 is a very serviceable, urban, belt-drive e-bike, great for commutes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/the-tenways-cgo-600-is-a-very-serviceable-urban-belt-drive-e-bike-great-for-commutes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/the-tenways-cgo-600-is-a-very-serviceable-urban-belt-drive-e-bike-great-for-commutes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bicycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric bicycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tenways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tenways is an e-bike maker which has launched its first model, the CGO 600, on Indiegogo. Priced at around $1,400 this is a relatively affordable e-bike in the scheme of things, and has plenty of features to satisfy even the most discerning of customers. Now before we get into it, it behooves me to say [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://tenways.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tenways</a> is an e-bike maker which has launched its first model, the CGO 600, on Indiegogo. Priced at around $1,400 this is a relatively affordable e-bike in the scheme of things, and has plenty of features to satisfy even the most discerning of customers.</p>
<p>Now before we get into it, it behooves me to say that there is always an inherent risk when buying into new products promoted on crowdfunding platforms like Indiegogo, <a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/tenways-ebike-the-best-urban-ride-ever#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">where the CGO 600 is listed</a>.</p>
<p>However, the good news is that Tenways is adamant that its bikes are already rolling off production, and this, evidently, appears to be the case. Certainly, the review model I was sent attested to this claim, as it came with all the full and final hardware listed on the site. Furthermore, Tenways is an established company that uses Indiegogo in a marketing manner, largely to advertise its bike, rather than raise money to develop and build it.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225896" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2225913" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="678" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg 1807w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg?resize=768,508 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg?resize=680,450 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg?resize=1536,1017 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tenways1.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>So, is this urban electric bicycle worth your consideration? The short answer is yes.</p>
<p>Here’s the longer answer:</p>
<p>First of all, we are talking about an e-bike optimized for the urban environment.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It certainly looks like it’s built for the city. The electric motor and battery are more discreet than in other e-bikes, giving it that cool, messenger-bike styling. The carbon belt-drive system means it is quieter and more maintenance-free, as these do not need oiling or adjusting. Similarly, the hydraulic disc brake system is not going to require much maintenance.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2225912" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222287.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="390" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222287.jpg 590w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222287.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222287.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222287.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" /></p>
<p>The bike rides well, and at only 33 lb (15 kg), it is easy to pick up to carry up or downstairs. As there is no throttle, the pedal assist is activated by a torque sensor which works well.</p>
<p>The 250W motor is enough to give you that extra boost as you ride up a hill or on the flat, but you also have three power levels to pick from.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2225911" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222286.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="390" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222286.jpg 590w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222286.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222286.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222286.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" /></p>
<p>With its relatively small 252 Wh battery, Tenways claims the bike has a range of 80 miles (130 km) per charge in “ideal conditions” which is probably optimistic. But then who rides 130 km on a commute? After all, this is really what this bike is designed for. Removing the battery for charging is not easy, so it will be simpler to charge the bike in situ.</p>
<p>Tenways has been shipping from September, and who wouldn’t want a good-looking e-bike with these features, be they an ‘urban’ hipster or an average commuter.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2225910" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222292.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="390" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222292.jpg 590w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222292.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222292.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222292.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" /></p>
<p>Here are the Tenways CGO 600 tech specs, according to the company:</p>
<p><strong>Rider height</strong>: 2 sizes cover 165 cm ~200 cm<br />
<strong>Weight</strong>: 15 kg<br />
<strong>Battery range</strong>: 70km~130km<br />
<strong>Charging time</strong>: 100% fully charge 2.5 hours<br />
<strong>Top speed</strong>: 25 km/h<br />
<strong>Warranty</strong>: 2 years<br />
<strong>Control mode</strong>: integrated smart LCD controller or smartphone app<br />
<strong><br />
Bike</strong>:<br />
<strong>Frame</strong>: astronautic aluminum alloy 6061<br />
<strong>Fork</strong>: astronautic aluminum alloy 6061<br />
<strong>Belt</strong>: Gates carbon belt &#8211; offering a 30.000 km lifetime<br />
<strong>Brakes</strong>: Hydraulic<br />
<strong>Tires</strong>: 35 mm Tenways-custom tires, puncture-resistant tires<br />
<strong><br />
Electrics</strong>:<br />
<strong>Motor</strong>: Custom-designed 40 Nm / 250 W rear hub motor<br />
<strong>Connectivity</strong>: Bluetooth<br />
<strong>Battery</strong>: 7Ah, 252 WH<br />
<strong>Charger</strong>: Custom-designed 36V / 3A charger<br />
<strong>Mobile app</strong>: iOS and Android<br />
<strong>Digital controller</strong>: integrated on handlebar, 3 level pedal-assistance, password security power<br />
<strong>Price</strong>: From $1799 on IndieGoGo</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2225909" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222290.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="390" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222290.jpg 590w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222290.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222290.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Tenways-C-GO-600-Electric-Bike-Price-UK-IndieGogo-Campaign-Buy-Price-Release-Get-Now-3222290.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/the-tenways-cgo-600-is-a-very-serviceable-urban-belt-drive-e-bike-great-for-commutes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225896</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zuckerberg on the Quest 2 as a fitness device &#8212; &#8216;It&#8217;s kind of like a Peloton&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/zuckerberg-on-the-quest-2-as-a-fitness-device-its-kind-of-like-a-peloton/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/zuckerberg-on-the-quest-2-as-a-fitness-device-its-kind-of-like-a-peloton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Headset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peloton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook wants the Quest 2 be known as more than a game console for your face. At the company&#8217;s Facebook Connect developer conference, CEO Mark Zuckerberg highlighted the company&#8217;s efforts to make the Quest a fitness platform for third-party apps like Supernatural and FitXR. He compared it directly to the Peloton as a connected fitness [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook wants the Quest 2 be known as more than a game console for your face.</p>
<p>At the company&#8217;s Facebook Connect developer conference, CEO Mark Zuckerberg highlighted the company&#8217;s efforts to make the Quest a fitness platform for third-party apps like Supernatural and FitXR. He compared it directly to the Peloton as a connected fitness device.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of you are already using Quest to stay fit, it lets you work out in some completely new ways,&#8221; Zuckerberg said in the keynote. &#8220;It&#8217;s kind of like a Peloton, but instead of your bike you just have your VR headset and with it, you can do anything from boxing lessons to sword-fighting to even dancing.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225886" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company is leaning further into this classification with its hardware detailing that next year they will release an &#8220;Active Pack&#8221; that allows users to customize their Quest 2 headset to make it better featured for working out. The pack will add grips to the controllers and a facial pad that addresses the issue of sweaty headsets.</p>
<p>In recent years, the company began pushing fitness harder in-headset, showcasing a product called Oculus Move which measures activity and calorie-burning tracking into the Quest 2.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/zuckerberg-on-the-quest-2-as-a-fitness-device-its-kind-of-like-a-peloton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225886</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cover, a modular home builder that&#8217;s modeled in ways after Tesla, has raised a $60 million Series B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/cover-a-modular-home-builder-thats-modeled-in-ways-after-tesla-has-raised-a-60-million-series-b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/cover-a-modular-home-builder-thats-modeled-in-ways-after-tesla-has-raised-a-60-million-series-b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fifty years]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gigafund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modular homes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naval ravikant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valor equity partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225744</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are lot of startups now working on modular home design. Among the most interesting is Cover, a seven-year-old, L.A.-based company that says it manufactures fully complete wall, floor, and roof panels in its factory, then transports them on a standard truck and assembles them on site &#8212; without a crane. The materials it is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are lot of startups now working on modular home design. Among the most interesting is <a href="https://buildcover.com/">Cover</a>, a seven-year-old, L.A.-based company that says it manufactures fully complete wall, floor, and roof panels in its factory, then transports them on a standard truck and assembles them on site &#8212; without a crane.</p>
<p>The materials it is using are lightweight steel for the building frame and aluminum for the ceilings. The panels are made of a rubber composite because, as founder and CEO Alexis Xavier Rivas explains, &#8220;drywall is not designed for manufacturing or transport &#8212; it&#8217;s too brittle.&#8221;</p>
<p>Clearly, a lot of thought has been invested in how these buildings are designed. For example, the company installs all plumbing and electrical wiring in the ceiling, so that if an owner wants to run a new wire or pipe, she or he need only pop off the ceiling to do it.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225744" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It sounds strange, but it&#8217;s a lot less strange than sawing a series of holes in a wall, then patching them up and repainting them to achieve the same end. (It also requires less help from the kind of craftspeople like plumbers and electricians that is in short supply right now.)</p>
<p>Others of the materials used include real wood and wood composites for the floors and exterior, and solid surface countertops and bathroom floors that are nonporous, meaning they&#8217;re more hygienic as these things go, which matters increasingly to homeowners as the world emerges from a pandemic.</p>
<p>How the materials come together is naturally even more crucial, given that with Cover, much of the focus &#8212; and the promise &#8212; is on both quick assembly and customization.</p>
<p>According to Rivas, the process works as follows: a customer works with the company to create a design. Right now, that design is limited to single-story units that are 1,200-square-feet or smaller but which take into account factors such as where windows should be placed to minimize energy waste. (Rivas also notes here that the glass, made by Cover, is LEED-certified, and that its homes are airtight, vastly improving their energy efficiency.)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Cover then takes the agreed-upon design, at a price that&#8217;s established up front and includes permitting fees, city fees, foundation fees and the home itself &#8212; think $200,000 for 400-square foot studio; $250,000 for a one-bedroom, 600-square-foot unit; and up to $500,000 for a three-bedroom, 1,200-foot dwelling &#8212; and it gets to work engineering the pieces.</p>
<p>Somewhat amazingly, it says that after the foundation is complete, it can have the building built and installed within 30 days, down from the 120-window that it used to promise customers previously.</p>
<p>It also offers a 100% money-back guarantee if it can&#8217;t obtain the <a href="https://www.hcd.ca.gov/building-standards/manufactured-modular-factory-built/factory-built-housing.shtml">necessary permits</a>, along with a lifetime structural warranty and a one-year warranty for everything else.</p>
<p>These buildings are &#8220;not going to rot,&#8221; says Rivas. &#8220;They aren&#8217;t going to be eaten by termites.&#8221; If a customer needs new air filters, on the other hand, &#8220;we&#8217;ll change them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rivas, who grew up in Toronto, studied architecture in college and bounced briefly around a number of architectural firms before founding Cover, takes pride in being able to attract engineers from SpaceX and Tesla to the mission and at various points during a conversation earlier this week, likened Cover&#8217;s processes to that of the automaker.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s seemingly not the only one who sees similarities.The company is today announcing that it has raised $60 million in Series B funding led by Gigafund, an investment firm that was founded by two former Founders Fund investors who have bet heavily on SpaceX.</p>
<p>Joining the round are Valor Equity Partners and Founders Fund &#8212; both of which are also early investors in SpaceX and Tesla &#8212; and a whole bunch of other notable backers, including General Catalyst, Lennar, Fifty Years, AngelList cofounder Naval Ravikant, Lowercase Capital founder Chris Sacca, Marathon Asset Management CEO Bruce Richards, and Dropbox cofounder Arash Ferdowsi, among others.</p>
<p>Certainly, there&#8217;s no dearth of demand for what Cover is building, given the national housing &#8212; and construction &#8212; shortage. In fact, asked about Cover&#8217;s sales team, Rivas says that there is so much inbound interest that just &#8220;one third of one person&#8217;s time is in sales&#8221; right now.</p>
<p>As for what people are ordering, Rivas says that most of the company&#8217;s customers have bought dwellings to accommodate either family moving in (an aging parent, a kid coming back from college); to create a home office apart from their house; or to establish a way to drum up rental income.</p>
<p>Still, beyond the roughly 20 backyard homes it has already built, the company &#8212; which has now raised $75 million altogether &#8212; very much intends to begin building bigger, multilevel homes, as well as multifamily units.</p>
<p>It mostly boils down to using more panels, Rivas says, which the company will be able to produce from the 100,000-square-foot factory into which it&#8217;s moving from the 25,000-square-foot warehouse it operates currently. (That&#8217;s where some of that $60 million is headed.)</p>
<p>Indeed, he says, if all goes as planned, sometime soon, even existing customers will be able to easily enlarge the homes they&#8217;ve already bought using the Cover app. It&#8217;ll be a snap, by his telling.</p>
<p>&#8220;You&#8217;ll go on the app, you&#8217;ll click on room to which you want to add, then schedule it, pay online, and get your renovation done in two to three days.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the kind of curtain raiser for which Elon Musk is known. Now to see if Cover can pull it off.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/cover-a-modular-home-builder-thats-modeled-in-ways-after-tesla-has-raised-a-60-million-series-b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225744</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter launches Spaces Recording feature to testers on iOS, global launch to follow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/twitter-launches-spaces-recording-feature-to-testers-on-ios-global-launch-to-follow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/twitter-launches-spaces-recording-feature-to-testers-on-ios-global-launch-to-follow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter announced last month it would soon introduce an option that allows hosts to record their live audio sessions in Twitter Spaces to make them available for replay. While the company at the time said the feature would launch in a &#8220;few months,&#8221; it&#8217;s not surprising that, given Twitter&#8217;s accelerated pace of development, the company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/23/twitter-accelerates-again-with-bitcoin-tips-nfts-recorded-spaces-creator-fund-and-more/">announced</a> last month it would soon introduce an option that allows hosts to record their live audio sessions in Twitter Spaces to make them available for replay. While the company at the time said the feature would launch in a &#8220;few months,&#8221; it&#8217;s not surprising that, given Twitter&#8217;s accelerated pace of development, the company is rolling out its first iteration of the feature starting today.</p>
<p>Initially, the Spaces Recording option will be will made available to a limited number of Twitter Spaces hosts on iOS and all listeners on iOS and Android worldwide. Twitter says the first users to receive access will be those who were in the original Spaces Beta. It will then roll out the feature to the rest of the Twitter audience in a few more weeks, the company says.</p>
<p>To use the feature, Spaces host will create their live audio room by giving their Space a title and selecting up to three tags to describe what the room&#8217;s about, as usual. Then can then toggle on the new setting, &#8220;Record Space,&#8221; before tapping on the &#8220;Start a Space&#8221; button to begin their live audio session.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225636" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>If in a Twitter Space that&#8217;s being recorded, participants will see a &#8220;Rec&#8221; button with a red dot next to it at the top of the Space as an indication that the recording is underway.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225666" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225666" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2225666" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pasted-image-0.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225666" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>When the host is ready to end the Space, they&#8217;ll tap on the &#8220;End&#8221; button at the top-right as they would otherwise, and will then be presented with a pop-up box that asks them to confirm they want to end both the Space and stop the recording.</p>
<p>Once wrapped, the recording of the Space can be shared across Twitter&#8217;s platform, allowing listeners to play it back at any time or re-share it themselves. Twitter does not yet have an audio export option available, we&#8217;re told. Instead, users would have to <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterMedia/status/1405262233299345413">request a download of their data</a> to access the recordings directly.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Live audio grew in popularity as the Covid-19 pandemic surged, as it gave something for locked-down users to do while stuck at home. But the appeal has <a href="https://variety.com/vip/clubhouse-has-cooled-off-in-the-u-s-heres-why-it-shouldnt-panic-1235050042/">somewhat</a> dwindled as Covid restrictions lifted and people began to venture back out. Popular live audio app Clubhouse, for example, saw app <a href="https://www.digitalmusicnews.com/2021/06/22/clubhouse-app-over/">installs decline</a> earlier this year, but <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/clubhouse-downloads-pace-jump-179-230212153.html">jump again</a> with an Android release. However, the app also faced lagging engagement in some emerging markets, <a href="https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/has-clubhouse-plateaued-before-it-hit-the-peak-11631816511362.html">like India</a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22696403/clubhouse-creators-first-sponsorship-program">struggled</a> with its creator program.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225668" style="width: 683px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225668" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2225668" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?w=673" alt="" width="673" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg 1372w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=148,150 148w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=297,300 297w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=768,776 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=673,680 673w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-28-at-9.48.10-AM.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 673px) 100vw, 673px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225668" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Recently, Clubhouse <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/clubhouse-adds-clips-replays-for-asynchronous-listening-better-search-and-spatial-audio-for-android/">expanded</a> its feature set to offer options that would allow for asynchronous listening, including support for clips, replays, and audio exports &#8212; tools that are pushing the app closer to being a podcast creation platform, rather than just a live audio network. (It&#8217;s actually a wonder Apple hasn&#8217;t snatched it up to become an in-house rival to Spotify&#8217;s Anchor.)</p>
<p>Other Twitter Spaces&#8217; competitors, including <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/1322627964798415/?helpref=related">Facebook&#8217;s Live Audio Rooms</a> and newer startups like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/mark-cuban-backed-live-entertainment-app-fireside-launches-to-creators/">Fireside</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/callin-david-sacks-social-podcasting-app-launches-and-announces-a-12m-series-a-round/">Callin</a>, also support audio recordings.</p>
<p>With so much of the live audio landscape now embracing recordings, Twitter had to catch up.</p>
<p>The release follows shortly after a few other updates to Twitter Spaces, including <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1453449025877942288">yesterday&#8217;s launch</a> of a Spaces test that brings the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/twitter-redesigns-its-mobile-app-to-make-spaces-the-center-tab/">dedicated Spaces Tab</a> to Android users and <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1447639305397194755">an update bringing easier DM invites</a>. Twitter will also now <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1453446589817704451">feature popular Spaces</a> in the Explore / Trending tab on iOS to increase their visibility.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/twitter-launches-spaces-recording-feature-to-testers-on-ios-global-launch-to-follow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VSC wants to craft the stories of startups, then invest in them too</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/vsc-startup-fund-climate/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/vsc-startup-fund-climate/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Firm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vsc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VSC Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[VSC, a public relations firm that has helped the likes of startups such as ClearCo, Poshmark and Tile craft their stories, has raised millions to invest in the companies they work with. While its bigger fund is estimated to close at $20 million, VSC confirmed that it has raised a $7 million tranche for climate [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://vsc.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VSC</a>, a public relations firm that has helped the likes of startups such as ClearCo, Poshmark and Tile craft their stories, has raised millions to invest in the companies they work with. While <a href="http://edgar.secdatabase.com/2767/186454721000002/filing-main.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its bigger fund is estimated to close at $20 million</a>, VSC confirmed that it has raised a $7 million tranche for climate tech startups to start.</p>
<p>VSC Ventures will back early-stage companies with checks between $250,000 to $500,000, and also provide media relations and multimedia content development as a service. The venture arm will be run by VSC CEO Vijay Chattha and General Partner Jay Kapoor, who was recently hired by VSC off of his six-years investing experience.</p>
<p>For VSC, which has helped more than 500 venture-backed startups through 50 exits, 20 unicorns and four IPOs, the argument for its venture arm is that cutting through the noise can help folks get coveted cap table spots.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225856" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>VSC Ventures’ debut focus, climate, is related to its competitive advantage of knowing a thing or two about telling stories.<a href="https://vsc.co/climb" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Climb</a>, also announced today, is VSC’s practice dedicated to building awareness and action around sustainability-focused startups. The duo thinks that, as every major VC fund begins to invest in the thorny and complicated world of climate, startups will need help explaining why their solutions make sense.</p>
<p>“It&#8217;s not just about hyping up on Twitter &#8212; that is something everybody can do,&#8221; Kapoor said. “It&#8217;s about actually having experience working with the founders to help them with their messaging, to help them with their positioning, and actually have done that consistently over time. Maybe some platform services have a person here and there that can help companies, but that isn’t their core competency and it’s not what they&#8217;re designed for.”</p>
<p>The investors’ own personal track records don&#8217;t hurt either. Before the fund, both Chattha and Kapoor made a slew of climate-focused investments on their own, including Revel, Modumate, Zume, Poshmark, Molekule and Rocean. The firm will eventually back startups in future of work and wellness, as well.</p>
<p>As every venture firm appears to be going the full-stack approach, offering a suite of services beyond simply capital, VSC’s move feels warranted. These days, founders want valuable services from their investors, such as hiring help, or simply, hype. Those within the media have found themselves in a fortuitous, and potentially lucrative spot, as the storytelling skill set skyrockets in demand from aspiring entrepreneurs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For example, Harry Stebbings, the well-known podcaster behind “20 minute VC,” recently raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/harry-stebbings-turns-up-the-volume-on-20vc-with-new-140m-fund/">$140 million for his venture capital fund</a> launched off of his show’s success. Morning Brew CEO Austin Rief <a href="https://angel.co/austin-riefs-rolling-fund/syndicate?utm_campaign=syndicate_direct_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has a fund</a> of his own. It’s happening in reverse too. Andreessen Horowitz, a more traditional fund, has put significant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/andreessen-horowitz-goes-into-publishing-with-future/">investment into Future</a>, a media property in which it will publish stories about topics related to areas in which the firm invests.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IEMZDHV4fd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/the-only-take-about-the-future-of-media-is-that-media-is-the-future/">The only take about the future of media is that media is the future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The only take about the future of media is that media is the future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/the-only-take-about-the-future-of-media-is-that-media-is-the-future/embed/#?secret=IEMZDHV4fd" data-secret="IEMZDHV4fd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Despite the blending of media and VC, few public relations firms have raised a fund, it appears.</p>
<p>“Many firms have experimented with equity for services since the late 1990s but abandon it quickly when the startup markets slow down,” Chattha said. “We are using LP capital to back companies and therefore are committed to this approach.”</p>
<p>Fear of a bubble burst aside, another reason that PR firms may not have gone into the investment game is the sheer complexity of managing clients and portfolio companies at the same time. Will there be a tension between VSC clients and VSC portfolio companies that are competing for the same partners’ time?</p>
<p>“We get asked this a lot,” Chattha said. “While the climate tech practice comes with money, in general, a lot of our companies are beyond where we can invest in them.” Since the majority of VSC’s current clients are Series B and beyond, the new fund will only be able to put money into a fraction of clients &#8212; which helps the investors draw a line on who they will and won’t back. This could change if VSC continues to raise more funds in the future.</p>
<p>Public relations firms also sometimes work as crisis communications, helping startups better message their mistakes to investors, employees, customers and, of course, the press. One could argue that founders may feel less incentivized to be vulnerable with a PR firm about struggles if they are also their investors, the same people they are incentivized to impress.</p>
<p>“Because we&#8217;re not the lead investor, we don&#8217;t ever put that kind of peer pressure on them,” Chattha said. “We have enough skin in the game to be honest and vulnerable with them, but not so much that we&#8217;re going to guide them into the wrong for their business.”</p>
<p>The venture arm, still in its early days, wants to be clear that it’s prepared for the startup boom to quiet down &#8212; whenever that happens.</p>
<p>“We’re in an up and to the right era, but it won’t be like this forever,” Chattha said. “Every vertical has its own ups and downs&#8230; and by not being the biggest check in or the lead check in, you know, we take that pressure off.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/vsc-startup-fund-climate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225856</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas is in development for Oculus Quest 2</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/gta-san-andreas-oculus-quest-2-facebook/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/gta-san-andreas-oculus-quest-2-facebook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Display technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Las Vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During its big VR and AR-focused event Thursday, Facebook founder and CEO Mark Zuckerberg announced a major new title headed to its VR platform that should turn a few heads. Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas is on the way to the Oculus Quest 2. San Andreas is Rockstar&#8217;s well-loved 2004 entry into the hit GTA [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">During its big VR and AR-focused event Thursday, Facebook founder and CEO Mark Zuckerberg announced a major new title headed to its VR platform that should turn a few heads.</p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas is on the way to the Oculus Quest 2. San Andreas is Rockstar&#8217;s well-loved 2004 entry into the hit GTA franchise, which invites players to wreak havoc in an urban open world fashioned after cities like Los Angeles and Las Vegas.</p>
<p>&#8220;This new version of what I think is one of the greatest games ever made will offer players an entirely new way to experience this iconic world in virtual reality,&#8221; Zuckerberg said.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225878" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Bringing such an iconic game into the fold is certainly one way to lure more users into the company&#8217;s emerging virtual world — one that even folks squeamish about Facebook&#8217;s VR account login requirements might find enticing.</p>
<p>While Zuckerberg didn&#8217;t offer many details about what to expect or when, Facebook has apparently been working on bringing the GTA classic to its VR headset for years.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sXINaZtNXc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/">Slack is coming to the Oculus Quest</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Slack is coming to the Oculus Quest&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/embed/#?secret=sXINaZtNXc" data-secret="sXINaZtNXc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/gta-san-andreas-oculus-quest-2-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225878</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook teases Polar, a mobile app for creating AR filters</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-teases-polar-a-mobile-app-for-creating-ar-filters/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-teases-polar-a-mobile-app-for-creating-ar-filters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At Facebook&#8217;s AR/VR-focused event Connect, the company announced a new app focused on bringing more creators into the world of building for augmented reality. The upcoming iOS app, called Polar, allows users to build their own AR filters for Facebook and Instagram powered by the Spark AR platform. Users will be able to easily create [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At Facebook&#8217;s AR/VR-focused event Connect, the company announced a new app focused on bringing more creators into the world of building for augmented reality.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2225862 alignright" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fb_connect_Polar_Long_version.mp4.00_00_12_35.Still010.png" alt="" width="214" height="465" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fb_connect_Polar_Long_version.mp4.00_00_12_35.Still010.png 374w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fb_connect_Polar_Long_version.mp4.00_00_12_35.Still010.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fb_connect_Polar_Long_version.mp4.00_00_12_35.Still010.png?resize=138,300 138w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fb_connect_Polar_Long_version.mp4.00_00_12_35.Still010.png?resize=313,680 313w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Fb_connect_Polar_Long_version.mp4.00_00_12_35.Still010.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 214px) 100vw, 214px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The upcoming iOS app, called Polar, allows users to build their own AR filters for Facebook and Instagram powered by the Spark AR platform. Users will be able to easily create these filters in a visual way using templates &#8212; a much lighter technical lift than existing frameworks.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225834" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As Instagram has pushed video harder through its Reels platform, the uptake for AR filters has gotten more sustained among users, providing an opportunity for Facebook to push them on creators.</p>
<p>The app seems to be pretty early in production, Facebook says it will be going into closed beta later this year as they handpick certain creators to onboard. Eventually, the company will be rolling this out widely as a free app that helps anyone create their own AR filters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-teases-polar-a-mobile-app-for-creating-ar-filters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225834</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Lawler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buy now pay later]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A year ago, the biggest players in the BNPL space were companies founded solely to offer consumers the ability to pay in installments at the point of sale. But the landscape looks very different now.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Buy now, pay later is here to stay.</p>
<p>A year ago, the biggest players in the space were companies founded solely to offer consumers the ability to pay in installments at the point of sale. Sweden’s Klarna, Australia’s Afterpay and U.S.-based Affirm were the top names associated with BNPL.</p>
<p>But the landscape looks very different now that more companies recognize the opportunity and fight for a piece of the pie. PayPal last month spent $2.7 billion for Japan’s Paidy in an effort <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/paypal-acquires-japans-paidy-for-2-7b-to-crack-the-buy-now-pay-later-market-in-asia/">to crack the market in Asia</a>. In early August, Square announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/">plans to acquire Afterpay</a> in a $29 billion deal. Even <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/what-impact-will-apples-buy-now-pay-later-push-have-on-startups/">Apple is said to be getting into the BNPL game</a>.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s BNPL space is seeing a slow emergence of a symbiotic relationship between traditional financial institutions, payments upstarts and leading companies. As credit card and payments firms eye BNPL as a new growth opportunity, incumbents like Klarna and Affirm are seeking ways to make their installment loans available to more consumers.</p>
<h2>The bigwigs enter the fray</h2>
<p>Now that consumers are growing comfortable with BNPL services, the big credit card providers are taking steps to ensure they aren&#8217;t left behind. Visa said on Wednesday that a &#8220;growing list&#8221; of issuers, acquirers and fintechs are using its technology to offer BNPL options to their customers.</p>
<p>In a statement, Mary Kay Bowman, Visa’s SVP and global head of payment and platform products, said the company has been &#8220;enthusiastically embracing BNPL&#8221; for years &#8220;because it expands choice and convenience for buyers and sellers alike.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;If shoppers prefer a BNPL fintech solution, we are here and enabling it,&#8221; she said. &#8220;If they want an option from their banks, we’re helping offer those too.&#8221; Interestingly, Visa said today it has inked a &#8220;global brand deal&#8221; with BNPL giant Klarna to accelerate its expansion and scale in several markets.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook Messenger audio calls are coming to Oculus Quest</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-messenger-audio-calls-are-coming-to-oculus-quest/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-messenger-audio-calls-are-coming-to-oculus-quest/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook is keen to improve the process of joining VR experiences in its Quest headset with friends. Today at the company&#8217;s Connect conference, they announced that Quest users will be able to make and take audio calls via Messenger. The functionality will be available later this year, the company says. The Quest has generally struggled [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook is keen to improve the process of joining VR experiences in its Quest headset with friends. Today at the company&#8217;s Connect conference, they announced that Quest users will be able to make and take audio calls via Messenger. The functionality will be available later this year, the company says.</p>
<p>The Quest has generally struggled with its social interfaces over the years, a surprising shortcoming for a device made by a social networking company. Its new mandate last year for users to sign into the platform with their Facebook IDs created some PR issues for the company but has enabled them eliminate some redundancies in their social workflows.</p>
<p>Users will be able to make calls, send messages or request users join their &#8220;party&#8221; directly from the native Messenger integration inside the Quest.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225721" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Earlier this year, Facebook announced support for Messenger chat inside the Oculus ecosystem, but audio calls will likely help users organize VR meetups more efficiently and help them stay away from typing in VR which is still a pretty rough experience.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iaU5qwK5aN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/facebook-messenger-lands-on-oculus-quest/">Facebook Messenger lands on Oculus Quest</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook Messenger lands on Oculus Quest&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/facebook-messenger-lands-on-oculus-quest/embed/#?secret=iaU5qwK5aN" data-secret="iaU5qwK5aN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-messenger-audio-calls-are-coming-to-oculus-quest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225721</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Slack is coming to the Oculus Quest</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Display technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus Rift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web browser]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Soon you&#8217;ll be able to read incessant Slack messages without ever having to take your VR headset off. At Facebook&#8217;s Connect conference, the company showcased a new framework for bringing 2D apps into the Oculus Store so that users will have to duck out of VR less to check notifications on their phone. While a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Soon you&#8217;ll be able to read incessant Slack messages without ever having to take your VR headset off.</p>
<p>At Facebook&#8217;s Connect conference, the company showcased a new framework for bringing 2D apps into the Oculus Store so that users will have to duck out of VR less to check notifications on their phone. While a number of Facebook apps are available today, the company also shared that Slack will soon be coming to the Oculus store.</p>
<p>The Quest has previously had very light support for 2D experiences, with most confined to the Oculus web browser. Facebook also previously rolled out native support for Messenger on the Oculus Quest 2 and announced today that they&#8217;ll bringing support for audio calls to the platform.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225821" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In August, Facebook showed off its Horizon Workrooms meeting simulator which integrated with Zoom and promised to bring users a more productive VR experience. The lack of app-support was a major roadblock on the way to this goal.</p>
<p>Typing in VR isn&#8217;t exactly a solved problem, so it&#8217;s likely that this will be an experience most suited for users that have paired their keyboard to the headset or are more comfortable just checking up on notifications rather than firing off a ton of lengthy messages.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2t1fKdp59e"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-opens-oculus-store-to-2d-progressive-web-apps/">Facebook opens Oculus Store to 2D progressive web apps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook opens Oculus Store to 2D progressive web apps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-opens-oculus-store-to-2d-progressive-web-apps/embed/#?secret=2t1fKdp59e" data-secret="2t1fKdp59e" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225821</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook opens Oculus Store to 2D progressive web apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-opens-oculus-store-to-2d-progressive-web-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-opens-oculus-store-to-2d-progressive-web-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 17:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Display technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus Quest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartsheet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearable devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web app]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook wants to make its Quest 2 headset a productivity device for a new generation of remote workers, but in order to pull that off, it needs apps. Today, Facebook announced that they&#8217;re bringing 2D apps into the Oculus Store for the first time. The new apps which are based on the Progressive Web App [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook wants to make its Quest 2 headset a productivity device for a new generation of remote workers, but in order to pull that off, it needs apps.</p>
<p>Today, Facebook announced that they&#8217;re bringing 2D apps into the Oculus Store for the first time. The new apps which are based on the Progressive Web App (PWA) industry standard will allow users to check apps that they would have previously needed to take off their headset and see on their phone.</p>
<p>A handful of 2D apps are available in the Oculus Store as of today, including Facebook, Instagram, Smartsheet and Spike. Other apps on the way include Dropbox, Monday.com, MURAL, My5 (UK), Pluto TV and Slack, the company says.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225814" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qsqnzE8iXo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/">Slack is coming to the Oculus Quest</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Slack is coming to the Oculus Quest&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/slack-is-coming-to-the-oculus-quest/embed/#?secret=qsqnzE8iXo" data-secret="qsqnzE8iXo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While the Oculus Store has seen native VR support from a handful of app-makers, maintaining a dedicated virtual reality app is complicated on multiple fronts and has led to apps from companies like Netflix and Hulu seeing very rare updates. Relying on PWAs will make the developer lift significantly lighter and will hopefully lead to broader adoption than Oculus has generally seen from app-makers.</p>
<p>The inclusion of 2D apps is part of a broader effort to bring the Quest into the workplace. In August, the company announced an app called Horizon Workrooms which allowed workers to bring their desktop into VR and communicated in a shared social VR space.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Cwxv9nqe3V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/facebook-finally-made-a-good-virtual-reality-app/">Facebook finally made a good virtual reality app</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook finally made a good virtual reality app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/facebook-finally-made-a-good-virtual-reality-app/embed/#?secret=Cwxv9nqe3V" data-secret="Cwxv9nqe3V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-opens-oculus-store-to-2d-progressive-web-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225814</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Didi expands, inDriver monetizes to rival Uber, Bolt in Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/didi-expands-indriver-monetizes-to-rival-uber-bolt-in-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/didi-expands-indriver-monetizes-to-rival-uber-bolt-in-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 16:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The on-demand transport space in Africa has evolved since San Francisco-based ride-hailing firm Uber first set up operations in South Africa in 2013, setting the stage for its foray across the continent while radically transforming the entire taxi industry. Almost a decade later, Africa’s taxi industry is now dominated by tens of local and international [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The on-demand transport space in Africa has evolved since San Francisco-based ride-hailing firm </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/18/uber-tests-shared-rides-in-africa-as-uberpool-stays-shut-in-us-canada/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Uber</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> first set up operations in South Africa in 2013, setting the stage for its foray across the continent while radically transforming the entire taxi industry.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Almost a decade later, Africa’s taxi industry is now dominated by tens of local and international tech-led ride-on-demand platforms, with the latest additions being global giants Didi Chuxing from China and Russia’s inDriver.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking to edge out its competitors, Chinese behemoth Didi is currently expanding across the continent, stepping up competition for market leaders Uber and Estonia-based Bolt. Evidence shows it is preparing to enter Nigeria, having begun operations in South Africa in March and Egypt just last month when the company </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">posted a job opening for a driver center manager in Lagos – the same role it first advertised for when entering South Africa and Egypt.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225714" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A key indicator of the company’s imminent expansion into Nigeria was hidden within the lines of the driver center manager&#8217;s responsibilities – &#8220;to collaborate with operations and Didi&#8217;s team to support the successful launch.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Didi did not respond to multiple TechCrunch requests for comment about its expansion plans in Africa.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225766" style="width: 357px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225766" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2225766" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?w=347" alt="Didi" width="347" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg 1170w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?resize=76,150 76w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?resize=153,300 153w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?resize=768,1507 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?resize=347,680 347w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?resize=783,1536 783w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?resize=1044,2048 1044w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/E520036E-6E8E-4A20-A012-70076D6191AA.jpeg?resize=25,50 25w" sizes="(max-width: 347px) 100vw, 347px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225766" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot of Didi’s app in Nigeria</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Didi is one of the biggest ride-hailing services in the world. However, unlike global competitors Uber and Bolt, which years ago saw Africa as a key market in their quest for global dominance, the Chinese firm held off the continent until now.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2012, Didi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/how-do-ride-hailing-giants-didi-uber-compare-2021-06-30/#:~:text=%2D%20Didi%20has%2015%20million%20annual,twelve%20months%20ended%20March%2C%202021.&amp;text=%2D%20Uber%20in%20February%202020%20said,some%205%20million%20drivers%20worldwide.&amp;text=%2D%20Didi%20was%20loss%2Dmaking%20from,the%20first%20quarter%20this%20year.">has around 600 million users</a> across 17 countries in Africa, Asia, Latin America and Russia. The company also has over 15 million annual active drivers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to launching other mobility platforms, Didi now owns minority stakes in other global platforms &#8212; the United States&#8217; Lyft and Uber, Indonesia&#8217;s Grab, Egypt&#8217;s Careem and India&#8217;s Ola. It also fully acquired Brazil&#8217;s 99.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Didi starts its incursion into Africa, Russia’s inDriver is firming up its presence across the same markets, where it recently started taking commissions from drivers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike other taxi-hailing apps that have a unilateral billing structure, inDriver allows riders to negotiate trip charges with drivers, making it popular among taxi users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taxi drivers in Kenya’s capital Nairobi using inDriver, which rolled out its services in Africa in 2018, have over the last few days received notifications from the company confirming the introduction of a 9.52% commission for every trip made. The commission is lower than Didi’s 13%, although both are much lower than Uber’s 25% and Bolt’s 20%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">InDriver inferred that it was introducing the charges due to the increased demand of the service, but it was keen to keep the commission lower than those of its competitors. The app was launched about three years ago across multiple markets in Africa including South Africa, Nigeria, Tanzania, Morocco and Botswana with the promise of a commission-free first year. The company is just now introducing commissions in some of these markets, although the deductions are already in effect in Nigeria and South Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a notification sent to drivers in Kenya, inDriver said that it “became a noticeable event in the passenger rides market in Nairobi. Many people use it daily and their number is increasing. This extensive work requires significant costs. To cover these costs, we introduce payments for each order in the amount of 9.52%. To keep inDriver still profitable for both passengers and drivers, the amount of payments is lower than in other services, where payments can range from 15% to 30% of each order.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new update comes as the company plans to grow in different markets, having already diversified into the courier business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company launched its delivery business in April last year, at the height of the pandemic, to tap the demand for parcel delivery services. Courier services enlisted on the app include auto, foot and moto, and are available in over 16 countries. The company is now introducing freight services in different markets around the world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2013 by</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/arsentomsky/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Arsen Tomsky</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, inDriver is currently available in 34 countries and recently crossed the 100-million download mark. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As it joins Didi to step up competition in Africa, market pioneers Uber and Bolt are expanding their service range in cities across the continent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently, Uber is rolling out Pool Chance, a feature that lets riders headed in the same direction share the cost of the journey, in Kenya, with plans to offer the low-cost service in Ghana and Nigeria. The company says that the rollout of budget services is part of its plan to attract price-sensitive users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Across the continent, Uber has over the last few months expanded into new regions and introduced new products as part of its strategy to retain existing customers and attract new ones amid growing competition.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier this month, the firm entered two additional cities in Nigeria &#8212; Ibadan and Port Harcourt &#8212; bringing into the regions a service that is already available in three other cities. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225736" style="width: 210px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225736" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-medium wp-image-2225736" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?w=200" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Frans-Hiemstra..jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225736" class="wp-caption-text">Frans Hiemstra, general manager for Uber Sub-Saharan Africa</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In South Africa, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Uber is now available in 40 cities, serving 80% of the urban population, with</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> premium services Uber Comfort, UberX and UberBlack and budget service UberGo. It recently expanded into 21 new cities and added a feature last August that allows the booking of trips a month in advance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to continue investments into African cities through collaborations with national and local authorities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We know that we face significant competition across local transportation modes in Africa. These are vibrant and competitive with many viable alternatives, including ridesharing, personal cars and public transportation—which consumers can and do choose between,” Frans Hiemstra, the general manager for Uber Sub-Saharan Africa, told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We believe competition makes us better, which improves the service for our riders and earners alike,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Uber is still king in terms of combined market share in Africa; it claims to have about 150,000 drivers in its eight markets across the continent, while Bolt comes in second.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bolt has been aggressively</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bolt-to-expand-ev-option-in-south-africa/?tpcc=tcplustwitter"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">expanding its services in Africa</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The firm is planning to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">roll out electric taxi options in South Africa four months after introducing e-bike food delivery services in Johannesburg and Cape Town.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Bolt also launched its food delivery service in Nigeria last month.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like Uber, Bolt sees myriad opportunities in the continent.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We see that there is room for several players across the continent. The infrastructure and experience we have built up with our ride-hailing business give us a good platform to expand and diversify our services,” said Bolt’s regional director for Africa and Middle East, Paddy Partridge.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For new players like Didi, it will be an entry to a market that dealt with drivers and partners demanding better working terms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Nigeria and Kenya, both Uber and Bolt faced a series of protests earlier this year as their drivers expressed displeasure with the ride-hailing companies&#8217; decision to increase their commissions, despite burdening users with price surges. However, no notable changes have been made from either of the two companies in line with the demands of drivers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Didi’s operations elsewhere have not been without drama. Before it went public on the NYSE this year – nine years after operating as a privately held startup and raising $25 billion from investors – the Alibaba, SoftBank and Apple-backed company faced scrutiny from the Chinese government and regulators. It was accused of employing anti-competitive practices and pricing and misusing users&#8217; personal information.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Didi&#8217;s fallout with China is just one of the many struggles it dealt with this year. Trying to compensate for the troubles at home, the firm looked to enter the U.K. market, but the move was met with concerns from the British Parliament that China could harvest data from Brits using Didi&#8217;s service. However, it seems its entry into African markets has been smooth &#8212; and could explain why it wants to keep its operations quiet: to avoid scrutiny.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/didi-expands-indriver-monetizes-to-rival-uber-bolt-in-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225714</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tim Berners-Lee’s startup Inrupt in talks to raise over $30 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tim-berners-lee-startup-inrupt-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tim-berners-lee-startup-inrupt-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 16:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inrupt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim-berners lee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tim Berners-Lee created the standards for the world wide web three decades ago, setting the pathway for countless of companies to flourish at unimaginable scale. His new venture, called Inrupt, wants to fix some of the mess many of those companies have made &#8212; and it&#8217;s in the market to raise money. Inrupt is in talks [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tim Berners-Lee created the standards for the world wide web three decades ago, setting the pathway for countless of companies to flourish at unimaginable scale. His new venture, called Inrupt, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/08/tim-berners-lees-startup-inrupt-releases-solid-privacy-platform-for-enterprises/">wants to fix some of the mess</a> many of those companies have made &#8212; and it&#8217;s in the market to raise money.</p>
<p><a href="https://inrupt.com">Inrupt</a> is in talks with a handful of investors to raise between $30 million to $50 million at a pre-money valuation of $140 million, according to two people familiar with the matter and an investor pitch deck obtained by me. The round &#8212; Series A &#8212; hasn&#8217;t closed, so the terms may change, the people said, requesting anonymity as the matter is private.</p>
<p>An Inrupt spokesperson declined to comment.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225709" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The startup, which counts Akamai Technologies and Glasswing Ventures among its investors, says it is attempting to “reshape the internet” by building a platform that gives users control of their data. Inrupt has built a platform where users can store their personal data in something called a POD (Personal Online Datastores). Its customers include governments and enterprises.</p>
<p>&#8220;Governments and enterprises want to help manage their users&#8217; data, but unfortunately, they do not have a platform to do so. Corporations want access to that consumer data without necessarily storing it, but again, there is no global open protocol for them to do so,&#8221; the investor deck reads.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are now creating a new platform and infrastructure that gives the global population control over their data, governments the ability to put data programs in place to securely store that data and enterprises the ease of use to access that data without fear of insecurity or abuse,&#8221; the pitch reads, pointing to the startup&#8217;s product called Solid.</p>
<p>Inrupt believes, it said in the investor pitch, that its addressable market is the “entire data market,&#8221; as it attempts emulate the core infrastructure companies such as Visa for credit card processing and Verisign, which commercialized the DNS standard.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup has signed contracts with governments of Sweden, Argentina, and Basque. These partnerships have not been previously reported. It generated $225,000 in revenue last year, and $200,000 in revenue last month, according to the investor pitch.</p>
<p>&#8220;Inrupt&#8217;s management team and Board of Directors are committed to a governance system that ensures that the company operates with utmost integrity, transparency and with the highest ethical and privacy standards,&#8221; the investor pitch reads.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/tim-berners-lee-startup-inrupt-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225709</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NerdWallet&#8217;s IPO proves you can write your way to a unicorn valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/nerdwallets-ipo-proves-you-can-write-your-way-to-a-unicorn-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/nerdwallets-ipo-proves-you-can-write-your-way-to-a-unicorn-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 16:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nerdwallet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rent the Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We can put a value on NerdWallet's business of as much as $1.25 billion. That must be more than $1 per word that NerdWallet has published, implying a pretty good return on scribbling.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you make some software and sell it online, you can make lots of money. Thanks to low-cost distribution, it&#8217;s possible to write one bit of code and sell it many times, generating fat margins in the process. Throw in a larger industry trend toward recurring pricing as opposed to single-shot sales, and you have the foundation for rich software company valuations in hand.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Writing was supposed to be the same, but it mostly didn&#8217;t work out. The internet allows you to write once and distribute those words to anyone at incredibly low costs, but the economics wound up being pretty tough. The real way to make money writing online, it turned out, was to treat words as code to a degree and release them under a subscription aegis, allowing media companies to look quite a lot more like modern software companies than we expected in the earlier days of the internet.</p>
<p>The New York Times &#8212; 68% subscription revenues <a href="https://nytco-assets.nytimes.com/2021/08/Press-Release-6.27.2021-PM-7Xc0A2HHkQj.pdf">in Q2 2021</a> &#8212; is a good example of how this can work. TechCrunch+ is another example of the model, though we&#8217;re about a zillion times smaller.</p>
<p>The model of writing and distributing it for <em>free</em> online was predicated on advertising rates translating from older businesses like television and print to the web. They mostly didn&#8217;t, even if certain publication niches can command reasonable ad rates at the moment.</p>
<p>Then there&#8217;s NerdWallet, a business that has proven that you can not only make a lot of money with writing on the internet while not charging for it, but also that if you manage the feat, you can generate huge amounts of value at the same time. We love a counterexample here at TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s IPO <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001625278/000162828021020521/nerdwallets-1a2.htm">dropped pricing details this week</a>, giving us a window into its expected public-market valuation, and the good news for fans of making words appear for others to consume is that NerdWallet is set to command a unicorn price when it does begin to trade.</p>
<p>Who would have thought!</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s NerdWallet worth?</h2>
<p>Naturally, what NerdWallet does is different from pure journalism. But the firm does make noise &#8212; as we noted in both <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/nerdwallets-ipo-filing-reveals-high-margin-content-business-accelerating-marketing-spend/">an earlier piece on the company</a> and on a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/nerdwallet-gen-z-and-the-value-of-the-written-word/?tpcc=tcplustwitter">writing-focused episode of Equity</a> &#8212; about its writing team being editorially independent.</p>
<p>In theory, then, the company&#8217;s writing teams are working for the reader and not for the near-term goals of the company&#8217;s revenue and marketing functions.</p>
<p>NerdWallet even noted in its IPO filing that it will avoid sugar-high, near-term revenue hits to preserve long-term credibility, i.e., it doesn&#8217;t intend to take extra checks from folks to recommend lesser products. NerdWallet&#8217;s business model is built around trust &#8212; that it will recommend the best products regardless of how much they pay in commission for sending users their direction.</p>
<p>As something of a personal finance Wirecutter, trust and the work the company does to preserve it are key foundations of NerdWallet&#8217;s relationship with end users.</p>
<p>Back to valuations: When we consider that NerdWallet expects to sell stock in its IPO at $17 to $19 per share, against a non-diluted share count of 64,747,341, or 65,834,841 inclusive of shares reserved for its underwriting banks, we can put a value on its business of as much as $1.25 billion. That must be more than $1 per word that NerdWallet has published, implying a pretty good return on scribbling.</p>
<p>My favorite group of IPO heads, Renaissance Capital, <a href="https://www.renaissancecapital.com/IPO-Center/News/87760/Personal-finance-platform-NerdWallet-sets-terms-for-$131-million-IPO">peg the company&#8217;s fully diluted valuation</a> at the midpoint of its IPO price range as $1.3 billion. At $19 per share, that figure rises to $1.37 billion. Again, not bad for a company predicated on being able to extract dollars from words.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/nerdwallets-ipo-proves-you-can-write-your-way-to-a-unicorn-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225672</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anomalo launches with $33M Series A to automatically find issues in data sets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/anomalo-launches-with-33m-series-a-to-find-issues-in-data-sets-automatically/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/anomalo-launches-with-33m-series-a-to-find-issues-in-data-sets-automatically/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data integrity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As companies gather ever-growing sets of data, finding issues with that data that could impact the viability of a machine learning model becomes increasingly important. Anomalo is putting machine learning to work to help solve the data viability issue automatically. Today the company announced a $33 million Series A investment led by Norwest Venture Partners [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As companies gather ever-growing sets of data, finding issues with that data that could impact the viability of a machine learning model becomes increasingly important. <a href="http://anomalo.com">Anomalo</a> is putting machine learning to work to help solve the data viability issue automatically.</p>
<p>Today the company announced a $33 million Series A investment led by Norwest Venture Partners with participation from Two Sigma Ventures, Foundation Capital, First Round Capital and Village Global.</p>
<p>The company was founded by two Instacart veterans who worked at solving similar problems at their previous company. Elliot Shmukler, co-founder and CEO at Anomalo, said that if you&#8217;re counting on data to run your business, any issues in that data can be problematic for the organization.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225719" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;What Anomalo does is it connects to these enterprise data warehouses like Snowflake, where they&#8217;re stockpiling all of this data that companies collect, and it monitors all those data sets for unusual issues and unwelcome changes in that data, which can cause lots of issues if you&#8217;re actually trying to rely on that data to run your business,&#8221; Shmukler explained.</p>
<p>It sounds simple enough, but what Anomalo is doing behind the scenes is connecting to these data warehouses and training a machine learning model on what is normal for this particular set of data and reporting when it finds issues. Shmukler says that this approach is in contrast to other solutions, which force data teams to explicitly define what good data looks like, a method he says becomes increasingly unmanageable as the number and size of the data sets grow.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you look at other solutions &#8230; they require folks on the data team to go in and essentially define the expectations for them, to say, this is what good data looks like, [and] that&#8217;s a tremendous amount of work. As your data changes and you launch new products and new geographies, you have to keep updating those definitions,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>It was a problem the founders saw when they were on the data team at Instacart, where they had to constantly update these definitions. When they launched Anomolo, one of their goals was to automate that process for data teams so they didn&#8217;t have to deal with that manual work.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t an easy problem to solve. The two founders &#8212; Shmukler and CTO Jeremy Stanley &#8212; left Instacart in 2018 to launch the company and it took a couple of years to get that machine learning model to work the way they wanted it to, without too many false positives or requiring too much history as a basis for learning.</p>
<p>While the founders didn&#8217;t want to reveal the exact number of current employees, the plan is to hire another 40 or 50 in the next year. Shmukler says that when he and Stanley decided to start a company, they set core values that included diversity.</p>
<p>&#8220;We actually wrote down a set of values for the organization to abide by, and one of them was being diverse. That was something very important to us at Instacart and something that we just wanted to continue working on [at this company]. And so we&#8217;re very mindful of making sure that when we&#8217;re recruiting for a role that we bring in a diverse set of candidates for that role &#8230; and the good news is that it&#8217;s working, at least today, where 25% of our engineering team are women, which is probably unusual for an early-stage company. And we hope to keep that going and continue to improve that,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>While the company is formally launching today, it has paying customers and reports that it has at least $1 million in revenue already. It charges by the data set it&#8217;s monitoring rather than by the user or data coming through its pipeline. Customers out of the gate include BuzzFeed, Discover Financial Services and Substack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/anomalo-launches-with-33m-series-a-to-find-issues-in-data-sets-automatically/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225719</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fundamentally altering antitrust laws will harm US startups and slow the economy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/fundamentally-altering-antitrust-laws-will-harm-us-startups-and-slow-the-economy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/fundamentally-altering-antitrust-laws-will-harm-us-startups-and-slow-the-economy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 15:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The very recipe that created America’s economic success is being threatened by antitrust proposals in Congress that will make creating a new business less attractive.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Linda Moore</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/lindamooredc">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Linda Moore is the president and CEO of <a href="http://www.technet.org/">TechNet</a>, a bipartisan policy and political network.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/03/04/computer-science-is-the-key-to-americas-skills-crisis/">Computer science is the key to America&#8217;s skills crisis</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/21/the-new-technology-policy-battlegrounds/">The New Technology Policy Battlegrounds Are Getting Closer To Home</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Bobby Franklin</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/nvca">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Bobby Franklin is the president and CEO of the <a href="https://nvca.org/">National Venture Capital Association</a>. 
	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/5-policies-washington-should-enact-to-end-the-climate-crisis-and-joblessness/">5 policies Washington should enact to end the climate crisis and joblessness</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/taking-stock-of-the-vc-industrys-progress-on-diversity-equity-and-inclusion/">Taking stock of the VC industry&#8217;s progress on diversity, equity and inclusion</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Neil Bradley</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/neilbradleydc">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Neil Bradley is the executive vice president, chief policy officer and head of strategic advocacy for the <a href="https://www.uschamber.com/">U.S. Chamber of Commerce</a>, the world’s largest business organization representing companies of all sizes across every sector of the economy.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The United States is the land of opportunity, where anyone with an idea can bring it to market. This philosophy has fueled America’s growth and prosperity and made the U.S. the global leader of innovation.</p>
<p>However, the very recipe that created America’s economic success is being threatened by proposals in Congress that will make creating a new business less attractive. Proposed changes to the existing framework of merger and acquisition law would handcuff successful businesses in every industry, have a chilling effect on investment in the next great American idea and close the door on the greatest engine of job creation our country has seen.</p>
<p>The startup ecosystem is unique. At the beginning, young businesses use capital from friends, family or even outside investors to help them get started. Not all are successful, and that’s OK. Those that do succeed graduate to other levels of financing, including angel or venture capital.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225250" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>While some companies will eventually grow big enough to become public through the IPO process, most don’t. The regulatory impediments have made this more difficult, and, as a result, there is less than <a href="https://www.sec.gov/spotlight/investor-advisory-committee-2012/jeffrey-solomon-presentation.pdf">half the number</a> of public companies than a generation ago. That’s why most entrepreneurs seek and <a href="https://www.svb.com/globalassets/library/uploadedfiles/content/trends_and_insights/reports/startup_outlook_report/suo_global_report_2020-final.pdf">welcome being acquired</a>.</p>
<p>Acquisition is an attractive and common exit opportunity that contributes to the health of our economy. Last year, 886 venture-backed companies <a href="https://nvca.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/NVCA-2021-Yearbook.pdf">were acquired</a>, while just 103 went public.</p>
<p>Acquisitions allow venture capital partners to make new investments in the next generation of entrepreneurs. This continued investment is a key driver of economic growth and has helped startups create jobs more than <a href="https://morningconsult.com/opinions/new-wave-innovation-job-creation/">five times faster</a> than more established companies. In fact, startups are responsible for almost all of the <a href="https://www.kauffman.org/entrepreneurship/reports/firm-formation-and-growth-series/the-importance-of-startups-in-job-creation-and-job-destruction/">net new jobs</a> created in the U.S. over the past 45 years. Nonetheless, international competition for capital is the fiercest it has ever been.</p>
<p>By fundamentally altering antitrust laws, Congress will punish American businesses by taking away incentives for entrepreneurs and investors. Congress would make it less attractive to start a new business or invest in any new company.</p>
<p>Those great ideas and investment dollars, along with the jobs they create, will go elsewhere, including to our foreign competitors, where the proposed antitrust laws will not apply. With the U.S. share of global venture capital investment <a href="https://nvca.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NVCA-2021-Yearbook.pdf">falling</a> more than 30 percentage points in the past 15 years, enacting these policies will only exacerbate the problem and push investment outside the United States.</p>
<p>It will also have devastating effects and unintended consequences on U.S. competitiveness and national security while benefiting countries looking to undermine American influence and values. A dozen former top U.S. national security officials made this very point in <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21062393-national-security-letter-on-antitrust?responsive=1&amp;title=1">a letter to Congress</a> urging lawmakers to more closely examine the global impact of antitrust legislation.</p>
<p>Instead of harmful legislation that will stifle economic growth and benefit our competitors, Congress should provide robust resources to government agencies to challenge any merger or acquisition that is likely to lessen competition and harm consumers. We must improve our current system not tear it down.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Over the past 20 years, the government has challenged <a href="https://www.uschamber.com/sites/default/files/calera_u.s._chamber_analysis_-_mergers_-_final.pdf">approximately 780 mergers</a>, with the merging parties winning in court only 11 times. With a success rate of 98.5%, government agencies have the ability to protect competition. But, some in Congress want to dramatically overhaul the system and shift the burden, making companies “guilty until proven innocent.” This approach is antithetical to current bipartisan antitrust policy.</p>
<p>A strong startup economy is key to America’s future, especially in communities outside of traditional hubs where entrepreneurism is currently <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/571681753c44d835a440c8b5/t/60819983b7f8be1a2a99972d/1619106194054/The+State+of+the+Startup+Ecosystem.pdf">thriving</a>.</p>
<p>But young companies need the right tools to succeed. Without attractive investment opportunities, jobs will be lost or go overseas. By making it harder for companies to be acquired, our economy will be weakened and our foreign adversaries strengthened amid an increasingly competitive race for leadership in the next generation of global brands.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/fundamentally-altering-antitrust-laws-will-harm-us-startups-and-slow-the-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Climate accounting platform Persefoni raises $101M Series B led by Prelude and TPG</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/climate-accounting-platform-persefoni-raises-101m-series-b-led-by-prelude-and-tpg/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/climate-accounting-platform-persefoni-raises-101m-series-b-led-by-prelude-and-tpg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alumni Ventures Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon offset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kentaro Kawamori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Persefoni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prelude ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[series B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uipath]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s nothing like an increasing level of regulations to create spaces for new startups to appear, especially in SaaS. Asset managers, banks, and other financial institutions need to calculate their financed CO2 emissions footprint in a manner that is auditable and compliant with both the Greenhouse Gas Protocol and the Partnership for Carbon Accounting Financials [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There’s nothing like an increasing level of regulations to create spaces for new startups to appear, especially in SaaS. Asset managers, banks, and other financial institutions need to calculate their financed CO2 emissions footprint in a manner that is auditable and compliant with both the Greenhouse Gas Protocol and the Partnership for Carbon Accounting Financials (PCAF) methodologies. Thus, we’ve seen the rise of the likes of like Plan A, South Pole, and Watershed. And of course, Salesforce’s sustainability cloud is a huge player.</p>
<p><a href="https://persefoni.com/">Persefoni</a>, a Climate Management &amp; Accounting Platform (CMAP) for enterprises and financial institutions, is the latest to benefit from this rising tide, with the news today that it has raised $101 million in its Series B financing round. Persefoni&#8217;s pitch is that it is an “ERP for Carbon Data&#8221; which replaces the traditional manual and consulting-based approach, and avoids proprietary approaches which could create problems when it comes to auditing.</p>
<p>Leading the round were Prelude Ventures and TPG Rise Climate. Also participating for the first time are Clearvision Ventures, Parkway Ventures, Bain &amp; Co., EDF (Électricité de France), Sumitomo Mitsui Banking Corporation (SMBC), The Ferrante Group, Alumni Ventures Group, and New Valley Ventures. Existing investors including NGP Energy Technology Partners, Sallyport Investments, and strategic angels also returned to participate. Persefoni is claiming this to be the largest round for a SaaS ClimateTech company, although TechCrunch could not confirm that at publication. Certainly, it’s significant. The Series B investment brings Persefoni&#8217;s total capital raised to $114.2 million.<br />
 <br />
Persefoni helps asset managers, banks, and other financial institutions calculate their financed emissions footprint in the compliance methods mentioned above. It now claims to have four of the 10 largest global Private Equity firms and four of the world’s 20 largest banks using it, along with several global insurance companies and pensions/endowments. It also works with corporates across manufacturing, agriculture, energy, apparel, retail, software, and business services.<br />
 <br />
Kentaro Kawamori, CEO &amp; Co-Founder of Persefoni said: “Carbon and climate disclosures will be the biggest compliance market since the advent of Sarbanes Oxley and GDPR, but with even greater complexity. The market is rife with data and software solutions that create new proprietary methodologies every day, and our customers are beyond tired of that approach. We work daily with the world’s pre-eminent industry standards setters and regulators to enable transparency and trust at the highest levels.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224861" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Persefoni has recently struck strategic corporate partnerships with Bain &amp; Co. , EDF (EURONEXT: EDF), and SMBC (TYO: 8316), expanded into the Japanese market and released a free tier of its base carbon accounting platform for SMBs. It also launched a Temperature Scoring Model to enable users to instantly create 1.5C or 2C implied temperature rise models for their organizations.</p>
<p>Speaking to me over a call Kawamori said: “We cracked the code on taking the best from the financial ledger technology, where the accounting process is completely automated, so we don&#8217;t do any services. We’ve got a pretty significant channel strategy mirroring very similar to what you might have seen from UiPath in the early days where the primary route to market was through, big four and significant consulting partners.”</p>
<p>He added that while Persefoni partners with the Patch offsetting platform, it doesn’t take a revenue stream from that, since to recommend offsetting platforms would be a conflict of interest.</p>
<p>He said: &#8220;We partnered with Patch and we’re doing that in a completely commission-free, pass-through way, because we actually think it&#8217;s a massive conflict to be doing both the accounting and selling people offsets for profit, which is what some of our competitors do. We think that&#8217;s terrible, doesn&#8217;t scale and doesn&#8217;t pass audit at scale.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/climate-accounting-platform-persefoni-raises-101m-series-b-led-by-prelude-and-tpg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224861</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-driving startup Aurora taps Pixar veterans to make a more realistic virtual world for testing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/self-driving-startup-aurora-taps-pixar-veterans-to-make-a-more-realistic-virtual-world-for-testing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/self-driving-startup-aurora-taps-pixar-veterans-to-make-a-more-realistic-virtual-world-for-testing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 15:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pixar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aurora, the autonomous vehicle startup scheduled to make its debut on Nasdaq next week, is turning to a team of Pixar veterans to help make the computer simulation tool used to test and train its self-driving system more like the real world. The three-person computer graphic imagery startup Colrspace, which has been operating in stealth, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Aurora, the autonomous vehicle startup scheduled to make its debut on Nasdaq next week, is turning to a team of Pixar veterans to help make the computer simulation tool used to test and train its self-driving system more like the real world.</p>
<p>The three-person computer graphic imagery startup <a href="http://colrspace.com/">Colrspace</a>, which has been operating in stealth, is joining Aurora&#8217;s perception team. Aurora will also own Colrspace&#8217;s IP, specifically technology that combines CGI and machine learning. The trio, which includes <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-fu-11966982/">Michael Fu</a>, Allen Hemberger and Alex Harvill, has developed a technique that can reconstruct 3D objects and materials from a photo or image. Essentially, it makes the simulation more &#8220;realistic,&#8221; which Aurora and other autonomous vehicle developers contend helps make testing more effective. (Below is a sample of Colrspace&#8217;s work; TechCrunch turned the mp4 into a gif)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225803" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CS_swatchtest_720p.2021-10-28-10_56_55.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225803" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2225803 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/CS_swatchtest_720p.2021-10-28-10_56_55.gif" alt="Auroa acquires Colrspace Pixar veterans" width="640" height="360" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2225803" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Aurora</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225543" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Fu, Hemberger and Harvill will join Aurora&#8217;s perception team, which already includes people from 7D, a simulation startup founded by former Pixar software engineer Magnus Wrenninge. TechCrunch learned in 2019 that it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/23/fresh-off-a-530m-round-aurora-acquires-lidar-startup-blackmore/">had acquired 7D</a>.</p>
<p>While Aurora and competitors like Argo AI, Cruise and Waymo regularly conduct real-world tests on closed courses and public roads, computer simulations are seen as an essential tool to test, train and validate their autonomous vehicle technology. Simulation can be used to help the self-driving system test various scenarios or play back what happened in the real world. The end game is to train and evaluate the software stack so it&#8217;s safe in the real world.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not uncommon for the biggest AV companies to run through thousands, even millions, of simulations daily. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Aurora, for instance, estimates its simulator is the equivalent of running more than 50,000 trucks driving continuously.</span> Aurora&#8217;s computer simulator, called the Virtual Testing Suite, runs through a diverse range of driving conditions as well as common and unusual (edge case) scenarios to catch errors early and before it is deployed in vehicles operating on public roads. Data captured while driving on public roads is also fed back into the simulator.</p>
<p>This year, Aurora has put more effort and resources to scale up its simulation program. Aurora said this month that it expects to have driven the equivalent of over 9 billion simulated miles by the end of the year, with 6 billion of these miles clocked so far in 2021.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/self-driving-startup-aurora-taps-pixar-veterans-to-make-a-more-realistic-virtual-world-for-testing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225543</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
