<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 15:38:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>How VCs are adapting to meet an increasingly global startup market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/how-vcs-are-adapting-to-meet-an-increasingly-global-startup-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/how-vcs-are-adapting-to-meet-an-increasingly-global-startup-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 17:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter for your weekend enjoyment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s inspired by the </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><em>daily TechCrunch+ column</em></a><em> where it gets its name. </em><em>Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up </em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><em>here</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p>Good morning my dear friends, I trust you are well. It’s the weekend! Here’s hoping you are going to consume more sugar in the next few days than your doctor would approve of. After all, we all die in the end. And on that encouraging note, let’s get to work!</p>
<p>TechCrunch’s recurring coverage of venture capital trends has taken on an increasingly global tilt as the startup market has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/global-startups-raise-158b-in-q3-an-all-time-record/">expanded to fill every geography</a>. Hence our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/investors-say-indian-startup-funding-could-get-even-hotter-after-record-q3/">ramping coverage of India’s startup scene</a>, not to mention our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/african-startups-join-global-funding-boom-as-fintech-shines/">increasing focus on the startups coming out of the African continent</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226507" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>With so many startups raising so very much money, it can be hard to keep it all straight. But we’re not the only organization with its eyes on upstart technology companies busy adapting to the new global startup reality. Venture capitalists are as well.</p>
<p>We’ve seen VCs shake up their operations to better suit a flat world for technology innovation in recent years. Larger funds with more partners to spread focus, for example, or the creation of country- or region-specific funds.</p>
<p>White Star is one such firm with an increasingly broad focus. The venture group recently closed its third fund, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/fund/white-star-capital-raised-white-star-capital-fund-iii--d8476841">a $360 million vehicle</a>, and TechCrunch caught up with founder <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericmartineaufortin/">Eric Martineau-Fortin</a> a few days back. But instead of chatting about valuations, or sectors, we mostly talked about geographies.</p>
<p>Martineau-Fortin lives in Guernsey, a small island that sits roughly between France and the United Kingdom. Residing between two major landmasses is fitting for the investor, as his firm’s first fund focused on the United States and Europe, roughly splitting investments between the two.</p>
<p>White Star’s second fund expanded its geographical purview to include a modest Asia focus as well. The group’s third fund will split roughly 40/40/20 between America, Europe and Asia, Martineau-Fortin said.</p>
<p>Notably, the group doesn’t actively pursue the Indian market. Which stood out, given how much capital is flowing into the country, but White Star keeps its focus more on the South Korean and Japanese markets, so it can invest in Asia more broadly while not putting India atop its list.</p>
<p>I riffed with Martineau-Fortin about other markets. He had rather positive things to say about Brazil’s startup scene — not a huge surprise with Nubank’s IPO in the offing — and Mexico. More simply, the Latin American venture capital market is respected even by investors that don’t have a focus there.</p>
<p>The world’s venture market remains uneven, despite some flattening. The United States saw $72.3 billion in total VC activity in Q3 2021, <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/research/report/venture-trends-q3-2021/">per CB Insights data</a>. Asia as a whole saw $50.2 billion. Europe managed $24.2 billion, and Latin America just $5.3 billion. That means that there’s likely arbitrage out there for the investor willing to add new time zones to their mix.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, White Star could split its investment focus into thirds among the U.S., Europe and Asia. I wonder if that will become a normal split in time. After all, the internet is everywhere at once — sans North Korea, China and a few other markets — so why not put capital into companies, well, everywhere?</p>
<h2>The future of consumer investing</h2>
<p>Taking a hard right turn this morning, let’s talk about consumer investing in the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>I promise I am going somewhere with this!</p>
<p>The Exchange caught up with <a href="https://freetrade.io/">Freetrade</a> this week, auspicious timing as our call came in the wake of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/robinhoods-nasty-quarter-shows-the-ups-downs-of-trading-incomes/">Robinhood’s poor earnings report</a>. As a reminder, Robinhood shares fell after the company announced a sharp sequential-quarterly revenue decline, falling active users and slim figures on total funded accounts.</p>
<p>The short answer to what happened from Q2 2021 to Q3 2021 at Robinhood is that crypto trading fell off a cliff on its platform, leading to a lackluster revenue result. The company’s Q4 is forecasted to be even smaller than its Q3. Not good!</p>
<p>I expected the Robinhood results to prove indicative of what Freetrade was seeing amongst its own user base. But, per the <a href="https://twitter.com/doddsie">company’s CEO Adam Dodds</a>, nothing of the sort. Indeed, the company recently announced that it has reached one million users, but more importantly that it has secured 110,000 new <em>funded</em> accounts thus far in October. That’s a <em>huge</em> portion of the company’s aggregate user base in a single month!</p>
<p>That hardly bearish fact in hand, Dodds doesn&#8217;t see Freetrade’s core market of the U.K. as nearly tapped out, and the company has expansion plans involving Canada, Australia and more coming in the next few months. Along with, yes, crypto trading.</p>
<p>The other difference of note between Robinhood and Freetrade, apart from their presently disparate user growth figures, is that the latter company doesn’t engage in payment for order flow. Instead, Dodds explained, the company makes money from subscriptions, a small slice of FX transactions and interest on held user cash.</p>
<p>The subscription element is key to the company’s long-term value, I reckon. Why? Because recurring software revenues are investor catnip, and Dodds said that something akin to a quarter of folks opt to pony up for the paid version of its service.</p>
<p>If that ratio holds up — or merely experiences modest declines — Freetrade could build a huge software business. Given just how much more penetration the startup anticipates in its home market, let alone foreign shores, there’s money to be made. More when Freetrade raises again.</p>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/alex">— Alex</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/how-vcs-are-adapting-to-meet-an-increasingly-global-startup-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226507</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Internet shutdowns are a political weapon. It&#8217;s time to disarm.</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/internet-shutdowns-are-a-political-weapon-its-time-to-disarm/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/internet-shutdowns-are-a-political-weapon-its-time-to-disarm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 16:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom of speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jigsaw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Myanmar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Global Affairs Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tunisia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scott Carpenter Contributor Share on Twitter Scott Carpenter is Jigsaw’s Director of Policy and International Engagement. Prior to Google, Carpenter served as the Keston Family Fellow at the Washington Institute for Near East Policy and as the U.S. Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Democracy and Human Rights. Authoritarian governments from twenty-one [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Scott Carpenter</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/JSCarpenter11">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Scott Carpenter is Jigsaw’s Director of Policy and International Engagement. Prior to Google, Carpenter served as the Keston Family Fellow at the Washington Institute for Near East Policy and as the U.S. Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Democracy and Human Rights.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Authoritarian governments from twenty-one countries have deliberately shut down internet service at least fifty times this year, and the problem is only bound to get worse. As regimes such as Venezuela face elections and Cuba experience protests, they’re finding it easier to contain dissent by curtailing digital freedoms – and are becoming increasingly brazen in doing so.</p>
<p>Shutting down the internet can be as easy as flipping a switch. Hosni Mubarak’s Egypt took this approach in 2011, and ten years later, Myanmar’s daily shutdowns lasted <i>months</i> – depriving hundreds of thousands of people of the means to communicate and shrinking the country’s GDP by an estimated 2.5 percent. Just this week in Sudan, citizens are experiencing disruptions to internet access in the midst of an ongoing military coup.</p>
<p>Most governments are more nuanced, however.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226666" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2226330 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?w=300" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>The Iranian government was among the first to block websites, as it did in 2009 during the Green Movement. Others, like Tunisia, blocked only certain websites amidst protests demanding greater accountability this year. Increasingly, governments use their control over internet service providers to ‘throttle’, or slow down, particular domains to an unusable speed. Russia, for instance, recently throttled Twitter for refusing to remove “objectionable” content about opposition figure Alexei Navalny.</p>
<p>Governments provide myriad reasons for restricting internet access. Officials often cite national security or a fear of violence during public demonstrations. But as people live more of their lives online, governments’ ability to restrict internet access represents a grave threat to safety, freedom and well-being.</p>
<p>After all, the internet’s growth as a global, borderless network of networks has been a boon to human freedom, providing new ways to discover information and new channels to organize. But growing opposition to a truly global open internet from a surprising number of governments risks a mounting erosion of freedoms as more aspects of our lives shift online.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The problem of deliberate shutdowns has escalated – and UN Special Rapporteur Clement Voule recently<a href="https://undocs.org/A/HRC/47/24/Add.2"> warned</a> that shutdowns are getting worse and more widespread. Internet shutdowns are increasingly being used as the primary tool for governments to silence dissent and control their populations without attracting the ire of the international community.</p>
<p>Internet shutdowns affect people far beyond restricting communication: they immobilize economies by halting commerce and trade, keep people from attending school, and endanger lives. But as covert blocking techniques like throttling have become commonplace, detection of shutdowns has become more difficult. The increasing complexity of the internet makes it difficult to determine what is happening when a government limits its citizens’ access, though. And it’s impossible to condemn what you can’t see.</p>
<p>Documenting even partial internet shutdowns is a critical first step to addressing this issue globally. No government should be able to shut down the internet without the international community knowing about it. That’s why Jigsaw is working with leading researchers at Access Now, Censored Planet, Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), and others to make information available, build understanding, and mitigate the impact of shutdowns.</p>
<p>A number of resources can reduce the impact of internet shutdowns. Mesh networks, virtual private networks (VPNs), and shared proxy servers can provide the means to help people connect to the open web during shutdowns. Implementing internet-wide standards can make domain-level throttling more difficult.</p>
<p>But technology is only one part of the solution. Preventing future shutdowns requires political action: raising the cost of such action in the eyes of the international community.</p>
<p>Grassroots efforts to highlight internet shutdowns such as the #KeepItOn movement, a coalition of more than 240 organizations from 105 countries, provides a range of advocacy, technical support, and legal interventions to prevent future shutdowns.</p>
<p>Democratic governments, too, should unite in action.</p>
<p>As the world&#8217;s most technologically advanced democracies formalize their multilateral coordination on technology issues in groupings like the T-12 or the Quad, they should prioritize internet shutdowns as a key pillar of their agenda. Through the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, the United States and other like-minded states could build on the work of the Online Freedom Coalition, a grouping of thirty-five democracies committed to online freedom, to enhance funding efforts to understand the technical aspects of the threat and develop technical and policy responses. They could ensure concerted condemnation accompanies future shutdowns and articulate ‘red lines’ to trigger sanctions on countries violating their commitments under international human rights law.</p>
<p>Despite the challenges, it is up to democracies to take up the rallying cry for a free and open internet. Only then might the promise of a universally accessible internet be fulfilled.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-footer.jpg" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/internet-shutdowns-are-a-political-weapon-its-time-to-disarm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226666</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neurodiversity in technology: Are businesses missing out on key talent?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/neurodiversity-in-technology-are-businesses-missing-out-on-key-talent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/neurodiversity-in-technology-are-businesses-missing-out-on-key-talent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 14:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neurodiversity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Neurodiversity presents a huge opportunity for leaders to bring in unique talent with different skill sets to drive progress in the tech industry. 
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Tracie Gildea</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/gildeatracie">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracie-gildea-7023084/">Tracie Gildea</a> is chief marketing officer of STANLEY Security and is a vocal advocate for diversity and inclusion in the workplace.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">My son was diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder in the first grade. As a mother, it took an ecosystem of support from schools, counselors and family members to ensure that we understood his needs and provided support for his learning and personal development.</p>
<p>Through our own journey, I’ve seen firsthand the challenges that people with neurological variations like autism face on a daily basis, but perhaps one of the biggest hurdles is overcoming society’s underestimation of this incredibly gifted population.</p>
<p>In my experience, people with neurodiversity are consistently underestimated for their knowledge and skills — but if my son is any indication of the value they can bring to the tech industry, then business leaders are missing out until they prioritize cognitive diversity.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225053" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>Why is neurodiversity important in the technology industry?</h2>
<p>One of the key factors in making each of us different is our neurological makeup. This difference can result in people interpreting, understanding and reacting differently in certain situations within personal and working life. And it often creates different skills and talents within people, such as heightened levels of analytical and creative processing.</p>
<p>The technology industry spans various roles and functions, from data scientists to developers, analysts and many more – not to mention the jobs that have yet to be created as we approach the Fifth Industrial Revolution and our world undergoes a significant digital transformation.</p>
<p>As an industry, we need to work harder to educate how talent can be leveraged in different ways to fulfill these roles, because employees are often a company’s greatest asset.</p>
<p>Throughout history, we’ve relied on our ability as a society to think differently in order to survive and thrive. With differences in thinking, neurodiverse people can bring alternative perspectives that may not have been explored before. It’s critical that businesses continue to prioritize cognitive diversity in their workforce, as every individual brings unique knowledge, experiences, and skills to the table and can help drive progress in technological innovation.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>How can the tech sector recognize and recruit neurodiverse talent?</h2>
<p>One of the first barriers to entry for someone who is neurodiverse is the interview process. Traditional interviews take into consideration things like body language and awareness of social cues that can put a neurodiverse person at a disadvantage.</p>
<p>Neurodiversity might affect the way that someone communicates; for example, the inability to read non-verbal social cues, resulting in limited eye contact and limited language softening. This behavior could lead to the removal of neurodiverse people from candidacy based on “cultural fit.&#8221; In reality, this is a much larger miscommunication that’s likely to screen out neurodiverse talent from positions in which they could excel.</p>
<p>Chemistry and character-based stages of the hiring process tend to take place first, before digging into the more technical elements of a role, where neurodiverse people can display their advanced skills. This leads us to ask: Are businesses doing enough to support diversity, equity and inclusion if they aren’t giving equal opportunity to neurodiverse people?</p>
<p>One way businesses can address this challenge is by partnering with community organizations to gain expert guidance, education, and best practices around talent acquisition and talent nurturing.</p>
<p>For example, across Stanley Black &amp; Decker, we’re collaborating with the National Organization on Disability and Autism Speaks to establish a hiring program that helps us recruit and retain talent of all abilities. As a leading global company, we have a responsibility to ensure our future is developed for everyone, by everyone, and that means taking steps to ensure our workforce is diverse and inclusive of people of all abilities, including neurodiverse people.</p>
<p>By taking steps to understand how we can all implement inclusive hiring practices, the tech industry can greatly benefit from a talent pool that might have otherwise been untapped. This could provide at least part of the solution to the technology talent shortage that continues to impact the industry.</p>
<p>Job mobility and career advancement within the neurodiverse community can also be explored and developed to ensure that career advancement is not limited to lower-skilled positions.</p>
<p>We must keep in mind the limitations on soft skills and associated characteristics stereotypically looked for in management and leadership roles, such as self-awareness and interpersonal communication.</p>
<p>When you look at case studies of neurodiverse teams, there is a distinct uplift in productivity, particularly in analytical roles. As such, I’d encourage leaders to identify opportunities for all talent to excel in their areas of expertise.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3lhmCUluv6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/addressing-the-cybersecurity-skills-gap-through-neurodiversity/">Addressing the cybersecurity skills gap through neurodiversity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Addressing the cybersecurity skills gap through neurodiversity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/addressing-the-cybersecurity-skills-gap-through-neurodiversity/embed/#?secret=3lhmCUluv6" data-secret="3lhmCUluv6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Can the tech sector help optimize the future of the workplace for neurodiverse people?</h2>
<p>During the past 18 months, we have seen a dramatic shift in requirements from leadership. Employees have more autonomy than ever before, and the same goes for people who are neurodiverse.</p>
<p>They now have the ability to request workplace accommodations that might not have been considered “essential” in the past — for example, more flexible working arrangements or the availability of choices to support alternative requirements to thrive in their working day. This could include variety in their immediate work environment and spaces for limited social interaction, noise or distraction, as well as the availability of headphones to limit auditory overstimulation.</p>
<p>Not only that, but the virtual world in which we’re living presents an added opportunity for people who are neurodiverse because it requires fewer of the typical in-person social skills that were previously expected within the workplace. This means that now more than ever, there are many flexible processes and policies that organizations can put in place to meet employees where they are.</p>
<p>A great way to provide additional support to employees is by encouraging engagement in employee resource groups (ERGs). In 2018, I co-founded our Abilities Network, a global ERG committed to supporting employees with disabilities, employee family caregivers of those with disabilities and the greater global community. It provides them with an engaging environment where they can pursue advancement, bring their full selves to work and thrive.</p>
<p>It was my personal experience that inspired me to establish this ecosystem of support &#8212; I knew how essential it was in helping our family advocate for our son. I did this through charity partnerships such as Autism Speaks. First initiated in 2018, we wanted to provide guidance for our workforce and leverage the National Organization on Disabilities to enhance our education and progress in this area.</p>
<p>By developing these communities, we can open conversations around neurodiversity and create more inclusive environments in which all employees have the tools, resources and support they need to succeed.</p>
<p>This also allows us to support employees as the business adapts. For example, during the pandemic, we saw a large increase in employees suffering from anxiety. Therefore, the Abilities Network partnered with Understanding Anxiety to offer support and tools to employees who need it.</p>
<p>It’s important that we bring best practices in inclusivity to all elements of the business, from hiring to marketing and everything in between.</p>
<p>From a marketing perspective, this means creating, for example, accessible website experiences across a company’s digital platforms to ensure people of all abilities are able to access and experience the company’s information. We’ve been successful in deploying numerous digital experiences with “accessibility by design” through the support of the Abilities Network ERG.</p>
<p>By tracking the progress of the employee experience through employment statistics and employee objectives in a Disability Employment Tracker, we have seen a 54% increase in talent sourcing and a 20% increase in “people, policies and practices” leading to an overall cultural accessibility increase of 105%.</p>
<p>My son has been a tremendous help throughout this process, acting as a sounding board to help me drive toward a more inclusive future, and I’m forever grateful for his partnership. He has been the inspiration behind my passion to ensure inclusivity remains at the heart of everything that I do.</p>
<h2>Neurodiversity presents business opportunities</h2>
<p>Technology changes the world and shapes the future of all industries. As leaders in this space, we have a responsibility to ensure that this future is inclusive and representative of all of us. We must ensure diversity, equity and inclusion initiatives aid not only new talent, but the neurodiverse people already within the talent pool.</p>
<p>My son, now 19 years old, is studying biotechnology and molecular bioscience at a technology university. When he was first diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder, we were met with low expectations for his personal and professional development — a collective underestimation of the value his unique skills could bring to the table.</p>
<p>This has driven my passion and efforts to ensure that we at Stanley Black &amp; Decker — and other companies — provide inclusive opportunities for all people.</p>
<p>Neurodiversity presents a huge opening for leaders to bring in unique talent with different skill sets to ultimately drive progress in the tech industry and beyond. And unless we’re tapping into this pool of talent, companies are missing out.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="36aopBoGdB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/neurodiversity-and-the-software-design-dilemma/">Neurodiversity and the software design dilemma</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Neurodiversity and the software design dilemma&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/neurodiversity-and-the-software-design-dilemma/embed/#?secret=36aopBoGdB" data-secret="36aopBoGdB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/30/neurodiversity-in-technology-are-businesses-missing-out-on-key-talent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225053</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A new venture studio, SuperLayer, aims to become a preeminent Web3 launch pad</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/a-new-venture-studio-superlayer-aims-to-become-a-preeminent-web3-launching-pad/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/a-new-venture-studio-superlayer-aims-to-become-a-preeminent-web3-launching-pad/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 04:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forté]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kabam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Chou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rally]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s a new venture studio in the world that looks rather different from earlier venture studios from a structural standpoint. Unlike renowned outfits like Atomic or Science or Expa that create companies that then sell equity to VCs who expect that equity to rise in value, this new studio, SuperLayer, plans to spin up consumer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There’s a new venture studio in the world that looks rather different from earlier venture studios from a structural standpoint. Unlike renowned outfits like Atomic or Science or Expa that create companies that then sell equity to VCs who expect that equity to rise in value, this new studio, <a href="https://www.superlayer.io/">SuperLayer</a>, plans to spin up consumer projects then instead of sell equity to VCs, it will invite the communities that use these products to invest in them by acquiring tokens, which can then be bought or sold or used to participate in other projects.</p>
<p>Indeed, in the case of SuperLayer, the tokens might all look a bit different, but they will all be tied to a blockchain network called Rally that SuperLayer’s founders created earlier and want to help popularize by creating more interesting apps atop it.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s part of what early crypto adherents have labeled Web3 and describe as the<a href="https://future.a16z.com/why-web3-matters/"> internet owned by the builders and users and orchestrated with tokens</a>. It&#8217;s also a world that many venture firms continue to approach warily. But they may well miss the boat as more outfits like SuperLayer begin to emerge, many of them created by battle-tested founders.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226680" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In the case of Superlayer, that founder is Kevin Chou, who sold his gaming company, Kabam, for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/28/gaming-company-kabams-roller-coaster-ride-to-a-700-million-exit/">$800 million</a> back in 2018 and almost immediately jumped headlong into the world of blockchain technologies, which he believes can unlock new economic opportunities, including for gamers and or creators.</p>
<p>In fact, before spinning up SuperLayer, Chou cofounded the blockchain gaming startup called <a href="https://www.forte.io/">Forte</a>; he is also the cofounder of <a href="https://rally.io/">Rally</a>, a launchpad for creators to build and distribute their own digital currencies that are essentially white-labeled versions of the RLY coin, as it&#8217;s called.</p>
<p>Chou has had the support along the way of investors like Coinbase Ventures and Andreessen Horowitz, and they&#8217;ve already seen meaningful upside. Those RLY coins, worth five cents when all 15 billion of them were minted, are now trading on Coinbase and several other exchanges for roughly $.052. Investors and team members reportedly control more than three-quarters of that supply right now &#8212; so they have to hold them or tank their price &#8212; but the idea is for the community to own 70% once all are distributed over time.</p>
<p>If all goes as planned, it could make a lot of wealthy people wealthier, and enrich many less-wealthy token holders, too. Consider: just about 7% of the coins are in circulation, giving the currency a market cap of $800 million. But if all 15 billion coins were released at today’s price, the coins’ fully diluted market cap would be $7.9 billion.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The efforts of Chou and company to decentralize its social token infrastructure is interesting on its own. Still, the real story here may be the opportunities and challenges that an organization like SuperLayer is beginning to pose to venture firms because of its relative complexity compared with traditional equity investments.</p>
<p>It’s largely why  Sequoia Capital announced earlier this week that it is becoming a registered investment advisor. As Roelof Botha, the head of Sequoia’s U.S. operations, <a href="https://medium.com/sequoia-capital/the-sequoia-fund-patient-capital-for-building-enduring-companies-9ed7bcd6c7da">wrote Tuesday</a> on Medium, becoming an RIA expands the firm’s flexibility in a number of ways; it also enables Sequoia to further increase its investments in emerging assets classes, such as cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>Chou doesn&#8217;t necessarily think Sequoia is restructuring itself because of its growing interest in crypto deals. But he does think more firms will need to follow suit if they want to capitalize on endeavors like his own.</p>
<p>“In a world where there are these new types of technology platforms that are being created that are powered by these tokens with a very different business model and very different technology architecture,&#8221; smart firms recognize that &#8220;We have to do that,&#8221; says Chou.</p>
<p>By &#8220;that,&#8221; he means, evolve. One of the biggest challenges of traditional funds, notes Chou, is that once an investment becomes liquid, a firm’s obligation to its own investors is to either give them the cash from that “exit,” of distribute their shares in the entity, at which point, their investors can decide if they want to hold them or sell them.</p>
<p>But in the world of crypto, the idea is often to use the tokens from one project and to use them to participate in the growth of another project. It can mean buying and selling and being both an active &#8212; and sometimes very patient &#8212; participant. And it&#8217;s work that comparatively few venture firms right now fully understand, Chou suggests.</p>
<p>They may come to regret it, as Chou says that crypto founders are running out of patience with traditional VCs &#8212; and just as more blockchains and their applications are beginning to reach mainstream adoption. While a few years ago, entrepreneurs didn’t mind having to hold investors&#8217; hands, he says, “More and more in 2021, a founder of a cryptocurrency that’s getting some traction and is trying to raise money is not going to go to the traditional Sand Hill Road firm.”</p>
<p>It’s not worth the time and effort, says Chou. Many have strict limitations around tokens, and most still need a whole lot of hand-holding. He knows, having lived it. “We’ve had to spend a lot of time with finance [teams] that [have] never done a crypto investment. We&#8217;ve had to do investment committee meetings, CFO meetings, lawyer meetings &#8212; just to give them delivery of their tokens. Then [you have] to help them set up their security and operations around how does the general partnership hold the tokens and how does it disperse the tokens to their LPs&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p>The process, he says, was &#8220;really painful.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/a-new-venture-studio-superlayer-aims-to-become-a-preeminent-web3-launching-pad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226680</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 signs that a startup&#8217;s &#8216;impact&#8217; is just a marketing ploy for investors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/3-signs-that-a-startups-impact-is-just-a-marketing-ploy-for-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/3-signs-that-a-startups-impact-is-just-a-marketing-ploy-for-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 23:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative fuels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biofuels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[impact investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2224864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For some founders, tying themselves to impact is a way to play into trends and get noticed by investors, but there's a fine line between impact and pushing a narrative for marketing purposes.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jonathan Greechan</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jonnystartup">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jonathan Greechan is CEO and co-founder of the world's largest pre-seed accelerator, <a href="https://fi.co/">Founder Institute</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/do-you-fit-the-mold-for-the-next-generation-of-values-driven-vcs/">Do you fit the mold for the next generation of values-driven VCs?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/14/3-best-practices-that-will-maximize-the-value-of-your-online-events/">These best practices maximize the value of your online events</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, a report from the EU showed that <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_21_269">42%</a> of companies exaggerate their level of sustainability. This &#8220;greenwashing&#8221; is now so prevalent that one organization has <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/19/greenwashing-needs-to-be-abolished-says-climate-entrepreneur.html">launched a platform</a> to calculate businesses&#8217; true environmental impact and avoid misleading marketing.</p>
<p>Today’s global impact investment market is valued at <a href="https://thegiin.org/impact-investing/need-to-know/">$715 billion</a> and growing. But as VCs, angels and celebrities rush to put their dollars in businesses that do good, they&#8217;re not doing sufficient due diligence.</p>
<p>For some founders, tying themselves to impact is a way to play into trends and get noticed by investors. It&#8217;s why some people identify themselves as an &#8220;impactpreneur.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2224864" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>There&#8217;s a fine line between impact and pushing a narrative for marketing purposes, and misjudging a startup&#8217;s genuineness can cost investors money as well as their reputation. During my time working with thousands of startups, I’ve picked up on these three signs that a startup is using impact to gain traction on the public stage &#8212; not make real change.</p>
<h2>They aren&#8217;t recording and tracking impact metrics</h2>
<p>If a company isn&#8217;t measuring the impact they claim to focus on, that&#8217;s a red flag. Startups that are really striving for impact will have a clear definition of what their goals are, how they&#8217;re getting there and what metrics are monitored along the way.</p>
<p>At Founder Institute, we have defined several “<a href="https://fi.co/insight/impact-kpi-assessing-startup-esg-progress">impact KPIs</a>” that help startups track their incremental impact steps.</p>
<p>For example, a women-led accelerator program that hopes to increase the number of successful female founders could have metrics around the number of female attendees per month and year, the number of attendees that launch a business and how much funding those businesses received. No impact is created overnight, but by breaking the journey into granular chunks, businesses demonstrate that they&#8217;re committed to building and refining their path to impact.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Tracking metrics also forces companies to be fully accountable for the impact they advertise. The companies that publish their metrics even when they aren&#8217;t positive tend to conduct deep dives into what went wrong and put in place plans to remedy the situation.</p>
<p>A great example is Duke Energy, which shared a <a href="https://sustainabilityreport.duke-energy.com/">report</a> acknowledging that it fell short on team diversity goals last year. To<a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/duke-energy-appoints-chief-diversity-190500722.html"> improve the metrics</a>, the company hired a new chief diversity and inclusion officer and committed $4 million to advocate for equality in the communities it serves.</p>
<p>We investors also have to ensure that metrics are present throughout a company &#8212; that startups practice what they preach. If a business has stated that it wants to improve access to education for more people, the founder should be able to provide metrics around in-house training programs, course offerings, development plans and promotions.</p>
<p>If they don&#8217;t have this information, that could be a sign that the company&#8217;s impact only targets lateral goals and isn&#8217;t built into internal operations.</p>
<h2>The CMO is responsible for the impact strategy</h2>
<p>Impact should ultimately fall on the shoulders of the CEO. It may sound obvious, but if the chief marketing officer is the go-to person for conversations and reporting about impact, that&#8217;s a problem.</p>
<p>When impact exists solely in the marketing realm, it can be easy for people to have accidental or convenient impact &#8212; where they retrospectively look at data and celebrate successes that weren&#8217;t the direct result of an impact strategy. For example: A startup claims that it reduced its carbon footprint by 10% in 2020, when really the drop was due to operations being shut down during the pandemic.</p>
<p>Likewise, if a startup&#8217;s impact objectives seem too good to be true, they usually are. Marketing departments go big when they want to make a splash (see: Theranos), but with impact, companies need to be acting at the ground level before they shoot for the moon.</p>
<p>Take ExxonMobil, which advertised its experimental algae biofuels as a means to reduce transport emissions. Consumers were <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/exxon-sees-green-gold-in-algae-based-fuels-skeptics-see-greenwashing-11633258802">quick to point out</a> that the company had made no pledge to net zero carbon emissions before shooting for &#8220;sexier&#8221; impact alternatives.</p>
<h2>They&#8217;re about projections, not progress</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s natural that when founders are fundraising, they emphasize their most disruptive edge. That they can end poverty, close inequality gaps or reduce the effects of climate change. These promises can raise investor eyebrows, but they have to be rooted in the <em>how</em>.</p>
<p>Every investor knows the feeling of glossing over the financial projections in a startup pitch deck. It&#8217;s not so much the figures that matter, but the process behind them. It&#8217;s exactly the same with impact.</p>
<p>If a startup&#8217;s whole identity is the future numbers of their impact goals, investors should be wary. The methodology is far more telling than the statistics.</p>
<p>For example, GSK has announced ambitious plans to be net zero carbon by 2030, but its breakdown of <a href="https://www.gsk.com/en-gb/responsibility/environment/carbon/">key activities</a> like switching to renewable electricity, electric cars and green chemistry is what confirms that the company is actually moving toward that impact. If the company doesn&#8217;t reach total net zero status, the intent is still clearly there, and progress will be made &#8212; but perhaps at a slower pace.</p>
<p>If Theranos has taught us anything, it&#8217;s that companies are wise to the allure of impact when raising funds. For investors, being able to distinguish real impact from marketing ploys not only protects them, it helps their capital go to places that can really make a difference.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/3-signs-that-a-startups-impact-is-just-a-marketing-ploy-for-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: BNPL competition heats up, Bowery Farming TC-1, Silicon Valley dreams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/techcrunch-roundup-bnpl-competition-heats-up-bowery-farming-tc-1-silicon-valley-dreams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/techcrunch-roundup-bnpl-competition-heats-up-bowery-farming-tc-1-silicon-valley-dreams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 23:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[allbirds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bowery Farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colorado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[denver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rent the Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweetgreen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is Southeast Asia about to hit an inflection point for tech startups? Four hundred million people in the region already use the internet, but by year&#8217;s end, one estimate suggests that 80% of the population over the age of 15 in Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam will be digital consumers. &#8220;As per [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Is Southeast Asia about to hit an inflection point for tech startups?</p>
<p>Four hundred million people in the region already use the internet, but by year&#8217;s end, one estimate suggests that 80% of the population over the age of 15 in Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam will be digital consumers.</p>
<p>&#8220;As per Jungle Ventures’ calculations, the total value of the region’s digital companies is around $340 billion today and is estimated to grow to $1 trillion by 2025,&#8221;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/"> says founding partner Amit Anand</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226606" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription.</i></p>
<hr />
<p>E-commerce, fintechs and the rapid digitization of the region&#8217;s SME workforce are a few of the factors reshaping the landscape for Southeast Asia&#8217;s startups, but supply chain technology is also a major opportunity, Anand says.</p>
<p>&#8220;With new deals and intentions to list in the U.S. being announced more frequently, the region shows no sign of slowing down and the birth of many more unicorns is on the horizon.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading TechCrunch+ this week!</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NMCeyofd6r"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/">Predicting the next wave of Southeast Asia tech giants</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Predicting the next wave of Southeast Asia tech giants&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/embed/#?secret=NMCeyofd6r" data-secret="NMCeyofd6r" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The Bowery Farming TC-1</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2224807" style="width: 3010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224807" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224807 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg" alt="" width="3000" height="2000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/NSussman_Techcrunch_BoweryFarming-FINAL_full-L.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224807" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nigel Sussman</p></div></p>
<p>Just over a tenth of Americans have jobs in food and agriculture, so it’s easy to see why many of us lack a keen awareness about what we’re eating or where it comes from.</p>
<p>Our food supply isn’t as secure or predictable as we assumed: Climate change, safety recalls, the COVID-19 pandemic and even immigration policies can directly impact what’s available at the store.</p>
<p>The technological leaps that made it possible to feed (most of) the world will not see us through the next century unless we change course.</p>
<p>Plant-based protein has gotten a lot of press, but vertical farming that leans on hardware and robotics has reached scale, reports Brian Heater, TechCrunch hardware editor.</p>
<p>In a four-part series, he explores the origins and operations of Bowery Farming, a profitable startup that has raised almost $500 million since 2015 to create new tech and facilities that raise leafy greens sold in nearly 900 markets.</p>
<p>Part 1: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-origin/">Bowery Farming is forcing us all to look up at the future of vertical agriculture</a></p>
<p>Part 2: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-produce/">Hacking lettuce for taste and profit</a></p>
<p>Part 3: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-technology/">Can LEDs ultimately replace the sun?</a></p>
<p>Part 4: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1-competition/">The voracious fight for your salad bowl</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2kvvLfbxOV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1/">The Bowery Farming TC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Bowery Farming TC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/bowery-tc1/embed/#?secret=2kvvLfbxOV" data-secret="2kvvLfbxOV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Since Big Tech came to Denver, investors can’t buy enough local startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996010" style="width: 2890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996010" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1996010 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg" alt="" width="2880" height="2160" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2880px) 100vw, 2880px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996010" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Denver, Colorado is nicknamed the Mile High City, but enthusiastic investors don&#8217;t seem to mind the thin air.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Per a recent CB Insights report, Denver-based startups raised around $2.7 billion in all of 2020,&#8221; report Anna Heim and Alex Wilhelm in today&#8217;s edition of The Exchange.</p>
<p>&#8220;The same dataset says that startups in the city have raised $3.1 billion through Q3 of 2021 — more capital in less time.&#8221;</p>
<p>Colorado&#8217;s central location and quality of life have made Denver and nearby Boulder attractive hubs for Big Tech firms. Now that remote work has become the norm, remote investment in the area has dialed up as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;Denver was ready for the Zoom boom, and is reaping the — venture capital — rewards.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OrVNDbNb0o"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/since-big-tech-came-to-denver-investors-cant-buy-enough-local-startups/">Since Big Tech came to Denver, investors can’t buy enough local startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Since Big Tech came to Denver, investors can’t buy enough local startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/since-big-tech-came-to-denver-investors-cant-buy-enough-local-startups/embed/#?secret=OrVNDbNb0o" data-secret="OrVNDbNb0o" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1925371" style="width: 2113px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1925371" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1925371 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg" alt="direct listing slice cake" width="2103" height="1426" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg 2103w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg?resize=768,521 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg?resize=680,461 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg?resize=1536,1042 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg?resize=2048,1389 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/GettyImages-134574965.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2103px) 100vw, 2103px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1925371" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Photo_Concepts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Photo Concepts <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Giving consumers the convenience of deferring payment for a product is not a new idea, but now that upstarts like Klarna, Afterpay and Affirm have taken the concept to the next level, legacy credit card companies and payment firms are taking notice.</p>
<p>Mary Ann Azevedo and Ryan Lawler have identified a &#8220;slow emergence&#8221; in the BNPL space &#8220;of a symbiotic relationship between traditional financial institutions, payments upstarts and leading companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Visa announced this week that many companies are using its technology to power point-of-sale BNPL solutions; last month, its rival rolled out Mastercard Installments, its bespoke offering.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s not really a surprise that these credit card companies are stepping it up when it comes to BNPL,&#8221; reported Ryan and Mary Ann. &#8220;If anything, it’s a wonder that it took them this long.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HO81XorDVA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/">Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Credit card and payments companies compete for a slice of the growing BNPL market&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/everyone-loves-bnpl/embed/#?secret=HO81XorDVA" data-secret="HO81XorDVA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Dear Sophie: Any advice for living my dreams in Silicon Valley?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2099516" style="width: 3210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2099516" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2099516 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg" alt="lone figure at entrance to maze hedge that has an American flag at the center" width="3200" height="1800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dear-sophie-immigration-maze-3.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3200px) 100vw, 3200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2099516" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Dear Sophie,</strong></p>
<p><strong>After trying to find an H-1B job to immigrate to the United States for several years, I took a senior software engineer position with a company in Canada. </strong></p>
<p><strong>My dream is to immigrate to Silicon Valley to start my own venture. Any advice?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Eager Entrepreneur</strong></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AX1kQkeboB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/dear-sophie-any-advice-for-living-my-dreams-in-silicon-valley/">Dear Sophie: Any advice for living my dreams in Silicon Valley?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Dear Sophie: Any advice for living my dreams in Silicon Valley?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/dear-sophie-any-advice-for-living-my-dreams-in-silicon-valley/embed/#?secret=AX1kQkeboB" data-secret="AX1kQkeboB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Heavily VC-backed salad chain Sweetgreen heads toward public markets</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1747015" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1747015" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1747015 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-873326822.jpg" alt="Inside A Sweetgreen Inc. Restaurant As Chain Expands" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-873326822.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-873326822.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-873326822.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-873326822.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-873326822.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/GettyImages-873326822.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1747015" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adam Glanzman/Bloomberg / Getty Images / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>At a previous job, I worked near a Sweetgreen location, stopping in once each week to pick up our startup&#8217;s lunch order.</p>
<p>The salads were delicious, but the prices definitely made me appreciate our free lunch policy. While reading Alex Wilhelm&#8217;s review of Sweetgreen&#8217;s S-1, I recalled something else: whenever I visited, I was usually the only customer waiting for a pickup.</p>
<p>Heavily reliant on digital orders and office workers, Sweetgreen &#8220;is rather unprofitable and doesn’t appear to be on the cusp of a rapid march toward profitability,&#8221; writes Alex.</p>
<p>At the same time, &#8220;the company’s overall business plan appears sound on paper.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AFAjJDW5bi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/heavily-vc-backed-salad-chain-sweetgreen-heads-toward-public-markets/">Heavily VC-backed salad chain Sweetgreen heads toward public markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Heavily VC-backed salad chain Sweetgreen heads toward public markets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/heavily-vc-backed-salad-chain-sweetgreen-heads-toward-public-markets/embed/#?secret=AFAjJDW5bi" data-secret="AFAjJDW5bi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How to root out shadow IT and maximize SaaS investments</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2224601" style="width: 1410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224601" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224601 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-637552576.jpg" alt="Cartoon Style Eye Peeping through Yellow Color on Paper Texture" width="1400" height="933" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-637552576.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-637552576.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-637552576.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-637552576.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-637552576.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-637552576.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224601" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=MirageC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MirageC <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>In a modern, mostly remote workplace, unapproved SaaS applications used by individual employees may lead to duplicate subscriptions, wasted IT spend and greater risk of a data breach.</p>
<p>How do you chase away the shadows? Just shine a light on your SaaS portfolio, according to CEO and co-founder of Zylo, Eric Christopher.</p>
<p>&#8220;Once IT has a line of sight into all applications in use and how they are used, they are positioned to optimize investments,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Implementing self-service SaaS at your organization is easier than you may think.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b70HV7GMbI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/how-to-root-out-shadow-it-and-maximize-saas-investments/">How to root out shadow IT and maximize SaaS investments</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to root out shadow IT and maximize SaaS investments&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/how-to-root-out-shadow-it-and-maximize-saas-investments/embed/#?secret=b70HV7GMbI" data-secret="b70HV7GMbI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Robinhood’s nasty quarter shows the ups, downs of trading incomes</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 2890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1996007 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="2880" height="2160" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2880px) 100vw, 2880px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Any stock that trades on the prospect of a company&#8217;s growth rather than its current business value is treading on thin ice.</p>
<p>So when trading platform Robinhood reported worse-than-expected Q3 revenue and profit, and predicted Q4 revenue also below analysts&#8217; expectations, the market responded.</p>
<p>In an in-depth examination of the company&#8217;s Q3 results, Alex Wilhelm found that Robinhood&#8217;s user base, crypto trading revenues and revenue per user all fell, which led to its profitability &#8220;taking a beating.&#8221;</p>
<p>If competitor Coinbase &#8220;has seen even a fraction of the downturn that Robinhood has experienced in terms of crypto transaction incomes, it could have a tough quarter,&#8221; he says.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="twagNqhgE5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/robinhoods-nasty-quarter-shows-the-ups-downs-of-trading-incomes/">Robinhood&#8217;s nasty quarter shows the ups, downs of trading incomes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Robinhood&#8217;s nasty quarter shows the ups, downs of trading incomes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/robinhoods-nasty-quarter-shows-the-ups-downs-of-trading-incomes/embed/#?secret=twagNqhgE5" data-secret="twagNqhgE5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How 2 companies leveraged organic and inorganic growth</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2224893" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2224893" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2224893 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1263055085-e1635343603112.jpg" alt="a small green plant grows inside a metal gear" width="1024" height="632" /><p id="caption-attachment-2224893" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Ivan+Bajic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ivan Bajic <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Taking a thoughtful, balanced approach to combining organic growth with the booster shot of a merger or acquisition can unlock sustainable growth, writes Progress Partners&#8217; senior managing director, Chris Legg.</p>
<p>He highlights two examples of successful M&amp;A strategies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Outside Inc.&#8217;s aggressive vertical acquisition spree to expand its offerings while entering completely new markets.</li>
<li>Trusted Media Brands&#8217; deal with Jukin Media to diversify its content and increase its advertising base.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E4rlBC0S16"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/how-2-companies-leveraged-organic-and-inorganic-growth/">How 2 companies leveraged organic and inorganic growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How 2 companies leveraged organic and inorganic growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/how-2-companies-leveraged-organic-and-inorganic-growth/embed/#?secret=E4rlBC0S16" data-secret="E4rlBC0S16" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Crafting a pitch deck that can’t be ignored</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2225292" style="width: 1410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225292" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2225292 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1273444988.jpg" alt="a wooden model's figure is pulling a drape off of a five-pointed star" width="1400" height="1094" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1273444988.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1273444988.jpg?resize=150,117 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1273444988.jpg?resize=300,234 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1273444988.jpg?resize=768,600 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1273444988.jpg?resize=680,531 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1273444988.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225292" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Boris+SV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Boris SV <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>To find out what a pitch deck needs to stand out, Managing Editor Danny Crichton hosted a panel at TechCrunch Disrupt featuring Mar Hershenson, the founding MD of Pear VC; Mercedes Bent, a partner at Lightspeed, and Saba Karim, who heads the global startup pipeline at TechStars.</p>
<p>Their chat contains valuable insights into how pitches have evolved over the past year, the VCs&#8217; thought process when reading decks and what founders should focus on if they don&#8217;t want to be ignored.</p>
<p>&#8220;The decks are getting better and better in terms of design,&#8221; said Bent. &#8220;I think more and more people have realized that the visual representation of your deck is just as important as the material and the content that’s in there.</p>
<p>Originality definitely helps an entrepreneur break apart from the crowd, said Karim.</p>
<blockquote><p>The best pitch deck that I got in a different format would be from a company that recently got into TechStars — it was actually a podcast version of their pitch deck that had my face on it. I went into Apple Podcasts and it said, “Hey, Saba, here’s my pitch.” That was amazing! But the second or third time that happens, it might not be as impressive because I’ve seen it before.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XwGCxsk7VJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/crafting-a-pitch-deck-that-cant-be-ignored/">Crafting a pitch deck that can’t be ignored</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Crafting a pitch deck that can’t be ignored&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/crafting-a-pitch-deck-that-cant-be-ignored/embed/#?secret=XwGCxsk7VJ" data-secret="XwGCxsk7VJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Allbirds flotation should help the market sort the value of tech-enabled IPOs</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996011" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996011" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996011" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-GRY2.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996011" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve always had an interest in the origin of words: We use &#8220;bellwether&#8221; as a term to describe trendsetters, but it originally referred to a sheep with a bell tied around its neck, which encouraged the rest of the flock to follow.</p>
<p>Similarly, IPO filings offer a glimpse into a company&#8217;s inner workings, but they can also offer insight into prevailing market trends.</p>
<p>Tech-enabled footwear maker Allbirds&#8217; IPO filing serves both purposes quite well, reports Alex Wilhelm: The company expects to debut between $12-$14 per share, which would value it about $2 billion at the upper end of the range — not far from where Rent the Runway debuted at in its IPO this week.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lh3fdCJupr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/allbirds-flotation-should-help-the-market-sort-the-value-of-tech-enabled-ipos/">Allbirds flotation should help the market sort the value of tech-enabled IPOs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Allbirds flotation should help the market sort the value of tech-enabled IPOs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/allbirds-flotation-should-help-the-market-sort-the-value-of-tech-enabled-ipos/embed/#?secret=lh3fdCJupr" data-secret="lh3fdCJupr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/techcrunch-roundup-bnpl-competition-heats-up-bowery-farming-tc-1-silicon-valley-dreams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226606</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Jio and Google set November 4 rollout for India&#8217;s $87 JioPhone Next</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/2226522/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/2226522/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 22:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for October 29, 2021. If you feel a little snowed-under after all the news from the week, we understand. This week saw Facebook change its name, new hardware from Google and Samsung, Apple laptops reviews, Sequoia revamping its entire structure, Big Tech earnings, issues at Ro, and eighty-eleven startup funding rounds and product launches.</p>
<p>But we made it through, so let’s go back over today’s biggest news and then get right into this weekend! —<a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226522" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/cloud-infrastructure-market-hits-180b-run-rate-in-q3-as-even-chip-shortages-cant-slow-it-down/"><strong>Public cloud revenues reach $45B:</strong></a><strong> </strong>In the third quarter, the value of public cloud revenues from Google, Microsoft and Amazon hit $45 billion, a figure good for a $180 billion run rate. That figure underscores how far the cloud has come in recent years and represents spend from a host of companies big and small, tech and otherwise. TechCrunch dug into what impact the chip shortage is, and isn’t, having on growth amongst the public cloud lords, in case you were curious about that particular dynamic.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/mastodon-issues-30-day-ultimatum-to-trumps-social-network-over-misuse-of-its-code/"><strong>Trump’s social network already in trouble:</strong></a> Sure, it was mocked when it was announced. And, yes, pranksters got busy in a hurry. But the biggest threat to former U.S. President Trump’s Truth Social product is an open source project that you’ve not heard from in some time, namely Mastodon. Per TechCrunch, the social project “alleges that Truth Social is passing open source software off as its own and has given them 30 days to fix this.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/since-big-tech-came-to-denver-investors-cant-buy-enough-local-startups/"><strong>The American heartland is startup-central:</strong></a> After our look into the larger Midwest startup market in the United States, TechCrunch took the time today to parse results from the city of Denver. Along with regional siblings, startups in the Mile High City are raising huge amounts of capital. But what we learned is that Denver’s startup boom came after a long period of investments in its local technology scene from the industry’s biggest players.</li>
<li>And, for something lighter, <strong>Google’s partnership with Jio to create and sell a budget smartphone in India</strong> is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/google-and-jios-smartphone-with-custom-android-os-for-india-launches-november-4-for-87/">bearing hardware fruit</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/kurly-the-korean-online-grocery-startup-says-it-plans-ipo-in-june-at-estimated-5-9b-valuation/"><strong>Kurly targets $5.9B IPO:</strong></a> Grocery delivery comes in a few forms. There’s the “instant” players, the two-hour delivery crew and then what Kurly is up to in Korea, namely delivering foodstuffs the next day. The slower model hasn’t harmed the unicorn, which intends to list next year at a valuation that could reach nearly six billion dollars.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/will-smith-kevin-durant-and-sean-diddy-combs-invest-in-electric-boat-startup-arc/"><strong>Celebrities back electric boat venture:</strong></a> A bit like how venture capitalists will keep backing email startups in hopes of eventually solving their personal communications crisis, a number of celebrities are backing Arc, which makes a very snazzy, if expensive electric boat. With a price tag around $300,000, it’s not a surprise that well-known celebrities-cum-investors Will Smith, Kevin Durant and Diddy are backing the company given that its product is inside their price range. You and I will have to get by with a Matchbox version.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/patreon-confirms-its-exploring-crypto-as-a-way-for-creators-to-make-money/"><strong>Patreon wants to say yes to crypto:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Creator payments and content platform Patreon may get in on the crypto boom. TechCrunch repots that the company is looking into how crypto might intersect with its creator-heavy user base.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/social-chat-launches-with-6m-to-bring-brands-closer-to-their-customers/"><strong>Social Chat bets consumers want higher-touch digital shopping experiences:</strong></a> Personally one of the best things about online shopping is not having to talk to other humans. However, many consumers disagree, Social Chat appears to be arguing. The company just raised $6 million to help make online shopping more like buying stuff IRL.</li>
<li>And in case you want to know which three funding rounds <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">the Equity crew</a> thought were the hottest of the week, well, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/the-new-alchemy-is-turning-gold-to-crypto/">we have your back</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Predicting the next wave of Southeast Asia tech giants</h2>
<p>Is Southeast Asia about to hit an inflection point for tech startups?</p>
<p>Four hundred million people in the region already use the internet, but by year&#8217;s end, one estimate suggests that 80% of the population over the age of 15 in Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam will be digital consumers.</p>
<p>&#8220;As per Jungle Ventures’ calculations, the total value of the region’s digital companies is around $340 billion today and is estimated to grow to $1 trillion by 2025,&#8221; says founding partner Amit Anand.</p>
<p>E-commerce, fintechs and the rapid digitization of the region&#8217;s SME workforce are a few of the factors reshaping the landscape for Southeast Asia&#8217;s startups, but supply chain technology is also a major opportunity, Anand says.</p>
<p>&#8220;With new deals and intentions to list in the U.S. being announced more frequently, the region shows no sign of slowing down and the birth of many more unicorns is on the horizon.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lXjm05VNiJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/">Predicting the next wave of Southeast Asia tech giants</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Predicting the next wave of Southeast Asia tech giants&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/predicting-the-next-wave-of-southeast-asia-tech-giants/embed/#?secret=lXjm05VNiJ" data-secret="lXjm05VNiJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/twitter-now-lets-all-ios-users-super-follow-select-creators/"><strong>If you are on iOS, you now have access to Super Follows:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Twitter’s product barrage has generated hits (Spaces) and flops (Fleets). But Twitter is forging ahead with more product work on its Super Follow product, regardless of early momentum or a lack thereof. Now all iOS users – globally! – can pay to “Super” follow creators.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/bosch-boosts-investment-semiconductor-chip-capacity/"><strong>German company to invest more in chip production:</strong></a> In the future, chip independence will replace food independence in terms of national security precedence. And Germany might sit pretty when it does, as domestic concern Robert Bosch GmbH is dropping nearly a half-billion into boosting chip output. More of this, please.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>If you have a software consultant that you think other startup founders should know about, fill out the survey <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com">here</a>.</p>
<p>Read one of the testimonials we’ve received below!</p>
<p><strong>Consultant: </strong><a href="https://729solutions.com/">729 Solutions</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommended by: </strong>Stuart Harris, <a href="https://www.altafoodcraft.com/">AltaFoodcraft</a></p>
<p><strong>Testimonial: </strong>“They excel at defining the problem, mapping out a strategy, setting expectations and managing the project to completion. They allowed us to complete and launch new products on time and within budget. Having a reliable partner that can uphold their piece of the project is critical to successful execution.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/2226522/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226522</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 ways to humanize support automation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/3-ways-to-humanize-support-automation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/3-ways-to-humanize-support-automation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 22:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Your bot is an extension of your company and is likely to be the first interaction a customer will have on your website or app. Use this opportunity to showcase the qualities your customers want.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">David Karandish</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/dkarandish">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidkarandish">David Karandish</a> is founder and CEO of <a href="https://capacity.com/">Capacity</a>, an enterprise artificial intelligence SaaS company headquartered in St. Louis, MO.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The global help desk automation industry is expected to grow to <a href="https://www.marketresearchfuture.com/reports/helpdesk-automation-market-4709">$11 billion by 2023</a> as support automation empowers companies to serve their customers more effectively. By automating repetitive tasks and FAQs, companies give employees more time to spend on more human tasks that involve building relationships and generating revenue.</p>
<p>Customers are also increasingly valuing self-service options. Chatbots allow customers to quickly address concerns at any time of the day without needing to pick up the phone. However, adding a human touch to that process will always be helpful.</p>
<p>Consider these three ways to humanize your support automation.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Your chatbot will feel more human if its responses are thoughtful rather than robotic.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<h2>Give your bot a name and personality in line with your brand</h2>
<p>Your bot is an extension of your company and is likely to be the first interaction a customer will have on your website or app. Use this opportunity to showcase the qualities your customers want to encounter. Design the chatbot to introduce itself with a memorable name that fits into your brand. Consider the voice your company uses across channels and incorporate the tone into your chatbot’s scripting. Feel free to include jokes or emojis — but only if they are consistent with the voice of your brand.</p>
<p>Your chatbot will feel more human if its responses are thoughtful rather than robotic. An AI-powered chatbot can ask more open-ended questions, which frees the user from the restraints of a few generic options. Your bot should use the customer’s name in conversation and explain if it’s searching for an answer or needs additional details to make the conversation feel more natural. Creating that comfortable dialogue will humanize your chatbot and separate it from the crowd.</p>
<p>Your bot’s personality should include the ability to react to written expressions of emotion. It should ask clarifying questions and confirm the details of a customer’s problem or question. Such guided conversations help a customer feel heard and understood. A natural-sounding diction and a personality that matches your brand will keep customers and potential customers from closing the tab.</p>
<h2>Connect to a knowledgeable human for help</h2>
<p>For a chatbot to be effective, it&#8217;s important that it asks follow-up questions and respond in thoughtful ways, but it should also be able to escalate a problem to a human expert. A chatbot that’s a dead end is not a true solution. When a customer thinks you’ve replaced traditional, human customer service with an inadequate substitute, they’ll feel undervalued.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/3-ways-to-humanize-support-automation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meta (Facebook) is buying Within, creators of the &#8216;Supernatural&#8217; VR fitness app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/meta-facebook-is-buying-within-creators-of-the-supernatural-vr-fitness-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/meta-facebook-is-buying-within-creators-of-the-supernatural-vr-fitness-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 20:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oculus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Within]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A day after Facebook’s rebranding as Meta (and simultaneous and unceremonious dropping of the Oculus brand), the company announced that it is acquiring Within. The Los Angeles firm is the developer of Supernatural, a Beat Saber-style workout app, Supernatural has been one of the real success stories in virtual reality fitness, with movement-based high-impact cardio [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A day after Facebook’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-changes-its-corporate-branding-to-meta/">rebranding as Meta</a> (and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/28/facebook-errr-meta-unceremoniously-kills-off-oculus-brand/">simultaneous and unceremonious dropping</a> of the Oculus brand), the company announced that it is acquiring Within. The Los Angeles firm is the developer of Supernatural, a Beat Saber-style workout app, Supernatural has been one of the real success stories in virtual reality fitness, with movement-based high-impact cardio exercises.</p>
<p>It’s a sensible acquisition as the company looks to broaden its VR and other ambitions into a kind of metaverse. Supernatural was also, no doubt, a particularly hot commodity over the past year and a half as more people have looked at home solutions amid widespread gym closures and other workout constraints.</p>
<p>“We are excited because our partnership with Meta means we will have more resources to expand and bring you even more music, more creative ways to workout, more features and more social experiences for VR. And of course, we will still be launching new workouts every single day,” Within CEO Chris Milk and Head of Fitness Leanne Pedante wrote in a <a href="https://cdn.getsupernatural.com/images/Leanne_Letter_v7_Mobile.png">blog</a> post.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226577" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company adds that its existing staff of coaches, choreographers and managers will remain on board after the acquisition. Supernatural will operate as part of Meta’s Reality Labs division.</p>
<p>“Together we will also explore ways we can enhance future hardware to support VR fitness apps, encouraging other developers to bring new fitness experiences to VR,” Meta’s VP of Play Jason Rubin wrote in a separate <a href="https://www.oculus.com/blog/within-to-join-meta/">post</a>. “We believe fitness will be a massive success in VR where multiple third party fitness apps can succeed.</p>
<p>Founded in 2015, Within has raised in excess of $50 million, including, <a href="https://variety.com/2017/digital/news/chris-milk-within-40-million-series-b-1202507040/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most recently a $40 million Series B</a> back in 2017. That round was led by Temasek and Emerson Collective. Other investors include Andreessen Horowitz, 21st Century Fox, Raine Ventures, WPP and Macro Ventures.</p>
<p>Financial details of the acquisition have not been disclosed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/meta-facebook-is-buying-within-creators-of-the-supernatural-vr-fitness-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226577</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick observations on Udemy’s unicorn edtech IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/quick-observations-on-udemys-unicorn-edtech-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/quick-observations-on-udemys-unicorn-edtech-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 20:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pluralsight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[udemy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Udemy IPO might seem like good news. After all, the company sold more than $420 million worth of its stock while going public at a price that surpassed its final private-market price. And yet.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Edtech unicorn Udemy <a href="https://investors.udemy.com/news-releases/news-release-details/udemy-announces-pricing-initial-public-offering">priced its IPO</a> at $29 per share, the upper end of its IPO range. Using a simple share count, the company was worth around $4 billion at its IPO price and a few hundred million more if a full -diluted share count is employed in our valuation calculations.</p>
<p>For edtech, the Udemy IPO might seem like good news. After all, the company sold more than $420 million worth of its stock while going public at a price that surpassed its final private-market price. And yet.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Ultimately, a disappointing debut is never a perfect indicator of a company’s long-term success.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In trading today, shares of Udemy declined $1.80 per share as of the time of writing, just over 6%. As far as IPO results go, that’s not the sort of opening day CEOs dream of.</p>
<p>Investors, either.</p>
<p>After tracking the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/udemy-files-to-go-public-on-back-of-growing-b2b-incomes/">company’s financial evolution</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/udemy-targets-valuation-of-4b-in-major-edtech-ipo/">its pricing in some detail</a>, this afternoon we wanted to offer a few observations regarding the final accounting of the Udemy IPO as it has been written thus far.</p>
<h2>Shifting to business sales isn’t a panacea</h2>
<p>Inclusive of its trading declines, <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/update-2-online-learning-firm-udemy-valued-at-2437-bln-in-tepid-market-debut/ar-AAQ6ufo">Reuters pegs</a> the Udemy&#8217;s value at $3.7 billion. Recall that based on its own estimates, Udemy had revenues between $125.7 million and $130.9 million in the third quarter. That figure puts Udemy on a run rate of $523.6 million. Or, in multiples terms, Udemy is worth 7x its present revenues.</p>
<p>For software companies that sell to other businesses, that’s far lower than we’d usually see. The company’s somewhat flat revenues in 2021 compared to 2020 are likely to blame for why that number is so low compared to SaaS norms. But muted growth expectations for coming years are also a factor — and edtech in a post-pandemic context, at least from an investor mindset perspective, may be at play.</p>
<p>So, sure, it’s good that Udemy is shifting to selling to stickier, and likely more lucrative corporations, but until that proves to unlock net revenue growth, the company’s valuation appears ready to hold fast in second gear.</p>
<h2>Private-market edtech valuations may have plateaued</h2>
<p><a href="http://crunchbase.com">Crunchbase</a> pegs the final Udemy private-market price at $3.25 billion. <a href="http://pitchbook.com">PitchBook</a> has it down to $3.3 billion. Regardless, the company did manage to surpass its final private price. But only by so much.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/quick-observations-on-udemys-unicorn-edtech-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226518</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon reveals 20% stake in Rivian ahead of EV maker&#8217;s IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/amazon-reveals-20-stake-in-rivian-ahead-of-ev-makers-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/amazon-reveals-20-stake-in-rivian-ahead-of-ev-makers-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 20:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon disclosed Friday that it owns a 20% stake in Rivian, the electric automaker that filed for an IPO earlier this month. As of September 30, the e-commerce giant held equity investments, including preferred stock of Rivian that represented about 20% ownership interest, according to the filing. That holding had a &#8220;carrying value&#8221; of $3.8 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon disclosed Friday that it owns a 20% stake in Rivian, the electric automaker that filed for an IPO earlier this month.</p>
<p>As of September 30, the e-commerce giant held equity investments, including preferred stock of Rivian that represented about 20% ownership interest, according to the filing. That holding had a &#8220;carrying value&#8221; of $3.8 billion, up from $2.7 billion as of December 31, 2020.</p>
<p>The disclosure, which popped up in a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/0001018724/000101872421000028/amzn-20210930.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">regulatory filing</a>, provides fresh insight into how closely Rivian&#8217;s future is tied to Amazon. Amazon has invested $1.345 billion into Rivian, according to the EV maker&#8217;s initial public offering. Amazon also recently purchased $490 million worth of convertible notes in Rivian that will convert to Class A shares after the IPO, pursuant to certain pricing provisions.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226557" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Amazon is not only an investor in Rivian; it&#8217;s also a customer. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In September 2019, Rivian entered into an agreement with Amazon to produce 100,000 electric delivery vans. Rivian disclosed earlier this month that it e</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">xpects to deliver at least 10 vehicles in the month of December 2021. All of the vans (that would be the remaining 99,990) will be delivered by 2025.</span></p>
<p>When Rivian&#8217;s initial public offering filing first dropped it was clear that Amazon was a big part of Rivian&#8217;s universe. For instance, there are 81 mentions of Amazon in the Rivian S-1 filing, a high number due to Amazon&#8217;s dual status as investor and customer.</p>
<p>At the time, it seemed that Amazon owned at least 5% of Rivian, though that final number was not yet available. The disclosure from Amazon shows that its stake is far larger.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/7-takeaways-from-rivians-ipo-filing/">TechCrunch has noted before</a>, the company&#8217;s strong connection to Amazon is both a boon and a risk. Per Rivian&#8217;s S-1&#8217;s risk-factor section:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>We expect that a significant portion of our initial revenue will be from one customer that is an affiliate of one of our principal stockholders. If we are unable to maintain this relationship, or if this customer purchases significantly fewer vehicles than we currently anticipate or none at all, our business, prospects, financial condition, results of operations and cash flows could be materially and adversely affected.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/amazon-reveals-20-stake-in-rivian-ahead-of-ev-makers-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226557</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Balancing risk: Modern architecture&#8217;s role in the BNPL playbook</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/balancing-risk-modern-architectures-role-in-the-bnpl-playbook/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/balancing-risk-modern-architectures-role-in-the-bnpl-playbook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 20:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buy now pay later]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumer Financial Protection Bureau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marqeta]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226020</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buy now, pay later (BNPL) is an old form of payment that is new again in a big way. And that could mean trouble for BNPL fintechs that are just getting to know the world of lending.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Matt Bivons</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mattbivons">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Matt Bivons is CEO and co-founder of <a href="https://canopyservicing.com/">Canopy Servicing</a>, an API-first platform for personalized and transparent lending. He previously served as VP and GM at GreenSky, and head of growth at Earnest and VaycayHero.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Buy now, pay later (BNPL) is an old form of payment that is new again in a big way. And that could mean trouble for BNPL fintechs that are just getting to know the world of lending and the pitfalls associated with traditional banking infrastructure.</p>
<p>Recent data from FIS — one of several payment processors — pegs BNPL at <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/21/how-buy-now-pay-later-became-a-100-billion-industry.html">a $100 billion industry</a>, or 2.1% of global e-commerce transactions. Marqeta, another processor, says BNPL transactions on its platform have increased 350% this year.</p>
<p>The success of the BNPL format has been attributed to the lift it provides to merchants at checkout and the convenience it offers consumers seeking to avoid interest payments and debit card fees. Last year, <a href="https://dfpi.ca.gov/2021/10/07/dfpi-report-shows-changes-in-consumer-lending-decrease-in-pace-program/">at least 91% of consumer loans</a> in California were BNPL.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			For BNPL providers, switching to modern architecture for loan management and servicing can minimize third-party merchant risk.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>According to Klarna, one of the largest BNPL providers, the average order value at checkout increases by <a href="https://www.klarna.com/us/blog/why-use-buy-now-pay-later-klarna/">as much as 45%</a> when shoppers are given the opportunity to pay for their purchases in four interest-free payments. BNPL is so convenient, compared to old-fashioned installment loans, that consumer advocates worry it encourages people to take on more debt than they can manage.</p>
<p>If that happens, the BNPL providers could get hurt badly during an economic downturn. <a href="https://www.paymentsdive.com/news/the-convenience-of-buy-now-pay-later-creates-risks-fitch/604437/">In a report published</a> in the summer, Fitch Ratings, one of the Big Three U.S. credit rating agencies, described the performance of BNPL debt as “opaque.” The report cited a survey in which nearly one in three respondents (31%) had either been late with a BNPL payment or incurred a late fee.</p>
<p>But the other side of BNPL is not just consumer credit risk, which BNPL providers say they can manage with non-traditional, data-driven underwriting. BNPL providers also face a double whammy of risk on the merchant side.</p>
<p>Three-sided loans, in which a lender relies on a merchant to act as a reseller, became a focus of regulatory scrutiny with the passage of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act in 2010.</p>
<p>Dodd-Frank did many things. Among the most influential provisions was the creation of a <a href="https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/documents/102012_cfpb_unfair-deceptive-abusive-acts-practices-udaaps_procedures.pdf">Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</a> endowed with the authority to act against any provider of consumer financial products or services who engage in “any unfair, deceptive, or abusive acts or practices in connection with any transaction with a consumer for a consumer financial product or service, or the offering of a consumer financial product or service.”</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/balancing-risk-modern-architectures-role-in-the-bnpl-playbook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226020</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flox, an app to help friend groups meet each other, is wooing college students in NYC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/flox-an-app-to-help-friend-groups-meet-each-other-is-wooing-college-students-in-nyc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/flox-an-app-to-help-friend-groups-meet-each-other-is-wooing-college-students-in-nyc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 19:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banana capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bbg ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bumble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columbia University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hinge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whitney Wolfe Herd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s nothing like the growing pains of new adulthood, but for college-aged Gen Zers who have spent these formative years in lockdown, it can be even more difficult to form meaningful friendships. While attending Columbia University remotely during the pandemic, first-generation college student Jamie Lee realized how this isolation was affecting her peers, especially those [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There&#8217;s nothing like the growing pains of new adulthood, but for college-aged Gen Zers who have spent these formative years in lockdown, it can be even more difficult to form meaningful friendships. While attending Columbia University remotely during the pandemic, first-generation college student Jamie Lee realized how this isolation was affecting her peers, especially those who would travel to school for their sophomore or junior years without having met any classmates in person yet.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Since I had first downloaded Instagram in middle school, I&#8217;ve always just been presenting myself online as an individual, but I felt like I was having a lot of anxiety about not presenting myself authentically online,&#8221; Lee told TechCrunch. &#8220;I wanted to lean into that idea of, okay, how can we find a way to connect people authentically? And I thought the best way to do that would be with our friends, who we&#8217;re most authentic around.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p>In summer 2020, Lee launched a no-code beta test for <a href="https://www.downtoflox.com/">Flox</a>, an idea for an app that would help people meet. It&#8217;s like Tinder, Hinge or Bumble, where you create a profile and match with others, only you&#8217;re signing up as a group and connecting with other groups of friends.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225684" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;People gave me feedback that it was the most fun they&#8217;d had online in forever, so that was my turning point where I was like, this could be something super serious, and I knew that it was now or never,&#8221; Lee said.</p>
<p>So, she dropped out of Columbia with just a year left of school to charge full-speed ahead on the app.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226503" style="width: 322px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226503" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2226503" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png?w=312" alt="Screenshot of Flox app" width="312" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png 818w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png?resize=138,300 138w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png?resize=768,1671 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png?resize=312,680 312w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png?resize=706,1536 706w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-7.09.31-PM.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 312px) 100vw, 312px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2226503" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Flox</p></div></p>
<p>In February 2021, Lee and two full-time engineers &#8212; the extent of her team &#8212; conducted an alpha test with around 250 users, which then developed into a private beta test exclusively in New York City for undergrads and recent graduates. By now, their waitlist has over 20,000 users, but Lee says in the next month or so, Flox will begin opening up to college-aged New Yorkers on the waitlist before expanding to other cities later on. Plus, Flox just closed a $1.2 million funding round led by Honeycomb Asset Management, with BBG Ventures and Banana Capital participating.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not gonna lie, raising my first round was incredibly difficult. I&#8217;m Puerto Rican and Chinese, I was 21 at the time, I never had any background in this, and I had just like, dropped out of Columbia,&#8221; Lee said. &#8220;Going into these conversations, I think people definitely had opinions formed about me before the conversation began. I was told in a pitch meeting to be more like Zuck.&#8221;</p>
<p>As a founder developing a platform for people in her own age group, Lee is smart about how she markets the app &#8212; she wants to make it feel authentic. So, she&#8217;s met her audience where they are on TikTok, posting promotional videos about the app that have gone viral, garnering about 1.8 million views over three posts.</p>
<p>&#8220;You can&#8217;t even go to the bathroom alone,&#8221; Lee says in <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jamietylerlee/video/6902236596750404870?is_copy_url=1&amp;is_from_webapp=v1">one TikTok</a>. &#8220;So why are you on these dating apps alone?&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@jamietylerlee/video/6905238996863962374" data-video-id="6905238996863962374" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;" >
<section> <a target="_blank" title="@jamietylerlee" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jamietylerlee">@jamietylerlee</a> </p>
<p>WELCOME TO FLOX. Waitlist early access in bio<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f9ca.png" alt="🧊" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a title="StartUp" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/StartUp">#startup</a> <a title="entrepreneur" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/entrepreneur">#entrepreneur</a> <a title="app" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/app">#app</a> <a title="friends" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/friends">#friends</a> <a title="dating" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/dating">#dating</a> <a title="fyp" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp">#fyp</a> <a title="selfimprovement" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/selfimprovement">#selfimprovement</a> <a title="watchmegrow" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/watchmegrow">#watchmegrow</a> <a title="tech" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/tech">#tech</a> <a title="foryou" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/foryou">#foryou</a></p>
<p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - Jamie Lee" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6905238964849265413">♬ original sound &#8211; Jamie Lee</a> </section>
</blockquote>
<p> <script async src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"></script></div>
<p>Flox isn&#8217;t the first app to try group-based social networking &#8212; Tinder had this idea with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/27/oops-tinders-new-friend-finding-feature-tinder-social-is-outing-which-of-your-friends-use-the-app/">Tinder Social</a>, a feature that let you join groups with your friends and match with other groups. But the feature was <a href="https://www.help.tinder.com/hc/en-us/articles/115005734383-Tinder-Social-#:~:text=Tinder%20Social%20was%20discontinued%20in,for%20our%20community%20of%20members.">discontinued</a> a little over a year after a rocky launch in 2016, when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/04/27/oops-tinders-new-friend-finding-feature-tinder-social-is-outing-which-of-your-friends-use-the-app/">accidentally</a> revealed who in your contacts had a Tinder profile. Lee said that she thinks Tinder Social didn&#8217;t work because Tinder had already branded itself as a dating (or hookup) app &#8212; and since you only had one profile, you&#8217;d be showing the same version of yourself to potential friends and potential dates.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want to move away from the focus on the individual, because I think that points to dating,&#8221; Lee said. &#8220;We want to really lean into the group identity, so you might see a flock called &#8216;apartment 11,&#8217; and then you would see who makes up the group, rather than, here are these individuals who form the group. It&#8217;s reversing what&#8217;s emphasized.&#8221; While the focus is on meeting new people, Lee hopes that friends who make a Flox group (a Flock) together will be brought closer too.</p>
<p>Even though Bumble started as a dating app too, it also now has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/18/bumble-now-lets-you-filter-potential-matches-on-bumble-date-bizz-and-bff/">modes</a> for making friends and finding business partners. Lee cites Bumble BFF as an inspiration for Flox, but she said that when she used the app, it seemed like most people said they were looking for roommates, rather than looking to make new friends.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226504" style="width: 323px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226504" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2226504 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png?w=313" alt="Flox app screenshot" width="313" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png 812w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png?resize=138,300 138w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png?resize=768,1667 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png?resize=313,680 313w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png?resize=708,1536 708w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-21-at-9.29.13-AM-1.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 313px) 100vw, 313px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2226504" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: Flox</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Gen Z is the most lonely, anxious, depressed generation, and there&#8217;s so many people who need friends,&#8221; said Lee. &#8220;But there&#8217;s a social stigma that [using one-on-one friendship apps] carries with it. Unfortunately, oftentimes, when you&#8217;re looking for friends one-on-one, what that implies to the other person, or to anyone who might know that you&#8217;re on Bumble BFF, is that you don&#8217;t have any friends, and that doesn&#8217;t really put you in a desirable position. So our goal with Flox is also to make it way more comfortable, safe and fun, removing that social stigma behind friend finding.&#8221;</p>
<p>The app hinges on Lee&#8217;s hypothesis that people are most comfortable meeting new people when their existing friends have their back. But the group dynamic adds a built-in layer of safety. Even though Flox isn&#8217;t a dating app, Lee knows that some people are going to use it for that purpose &#8212; but meeting new people in groups can help mitigate the risks inherent in meeting strangers one-on-one.</p>
<p>&#8220;I had a really bad experience on a dating app when I was in the city a couple of years ago, and I remember reporting the incident, and nothing was followed up on, and I just didn&#8217;t feel protected on that platform,&#8221; Lee said. &#8220;One of the first conversations I had with users last year was people said, &#8216;I&#8217;m not comfortable meeting up with other people on dating apps, because I feel unsafe one-on-one.&#8217; So we really want to give people this more comfortable, safe environment to meet people.&#8221;</p>
<p>With Flox&#8217;s recent seed round, Lee hopes to continue building out the app and letting more and more users in &#8212; but she wants to take it slow to make sure that the experience remains positive and authentic for existing users.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/flox-an-app-to-help-friend-groups-meet-each-other-is-wooing-college-students-in-nyc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225684</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When should your B2C startup enter a new market?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/when-should-your-b2c-startup-enter-a-new-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/when-should-your-b2c-startup-enter-a-new-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 18:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international expansion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The toughest questions most entrepreneurs face will involve international expansion. Whether to, when to, where to and how to expand all involve a wealth of complex considerations.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jim Mann</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/thrasio">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jim Mann is director of acquisitions at <a href="https://www.thrasio.com/">Thrasio</a>, a consumer goods company reimagining omnichannel commerce and consumer products.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The toughest questions most entrepreneurs face will involve international expansion. Whether to, when to, where to and how to expand all involve a wealth of complex considerations. The stakes are high: Success could mean the creation of a global multimillion-dollar business, whereas failure can often be fatal to a startup&#8217;s long-term viability.</p>
<p>Luckily, international expansion doesn’t have to be a blind gamble. With the right research and strategy combined with knowledge of the most common pitfalls, founders can mitigate a lot of risk and give their startup the best chance to succeed.</p>
<p>Naturally, many of the factors that we need to explore vary considerably between tech verticals. For ease, we will concentrate on midsized startups that sell directly to consumers. However, don’t be disheartened if you operate a B2B startup, as the approach I will outline may broadly apply to your business, too.</p>
<h2>Go big by staying home</h2>
<p>A mistake we often encounter is that businesses see expansion as a goal in itself rather than a move necessary to fulfill a clearly defined commercial strategy. There can be a tendency to rush the process without doing all the objective reflection needed. It’s important to ask yourself, with the risk involved, if international expansion is the only way to realize your dreams for your business. If so, are you really ready?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			It may be that through luck or ingenuity, your business has thrived in your home country with minimal marketing spend, but there is absolutely no guarantee this will happen abroad.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>In relation to being &#8220;ready,&#8221; the most successful consumer businesses use their home market to refine their product offering, build their team and infrastructure, and critically, learn to adapt their business per shifting consumer expectations and demand. It is generally much cheaper to gain experience and make your mistakes at home rather than abroad. If, after mulling these questions over, you’re ready to roll, great! Where should you go?</p>
<h2>Start with the simple questions</h2>
<p>There is absolutely no substitute for research, and you can never do enough. You&#8217;ll first need to gather data points from your existing customer base. In an ideal world, a percentage of sales would already come from international clients, and this information may, on the face of it, point to potential demand in a particular region.</p>
<p>However, this is by no means definitive. Sales may be concentrated in a particular country simply because of the language your website is in or, if you&#8217;re selling via a third-party platform, due to where that customer base is. Pay attention to the customer journey and how interest has fluctuated over time. Flat demand or outlying surges could indicate a ceiling in that market or an extraneous factor that has skewed the data.</p>
<p>The next step is to shortlist locations. Countries with a similar time zone, commercial culture, language, and legal and regulatory framework should be at the top of the list.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/when-should-your-b2c-startup-enter-a-new-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225692</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla&#8217;s deal with Hertz opens a new frontier for the EV maker</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/teslas-deal-with-hertz-opens-a-new-frontier-for-the-ev-maker/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/teslas-deal-with-hertz-opens-a-new-frontier-for-the-ev-maker/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 18:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hertz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rental cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Auto rental giant Hertz gave its strongest signal to the markets that it had resurrected from bankruptcy with this week&#8217;s news that it would purchase 100,000 Tesla vehicles for a reported $4.2 billion. Hertz made headlines again two days later, when it said that Uber committed to renting up to half of that order for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Auto rental giant Hertz gave its strongest signal to the markets that it had resurrected from bankruptcy with this week&#8217;s news that it would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/25/tesla-hertz-shares-rise-electric-vehicle-order/">purchase 100,000 Tesla vehicles</a> for a reported $4.2 billion. Hertz made headlines again two days later, when it said that Uber <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/uber-will-rent-up-to-50000-tesla-evs-to-drivers/">committed to renting up to half of that order</a> for its drivers.</p>
<p>But the biggest winner in the deal may end up being Tesla &#8212; which can leverage its first-to-rental market advantage and inventory constraints facing other automakers to potentially capture a growing pool of EV-curious drivers.</p>
<p>The first thing that jumps out is the scale of the deal &#8212; until now unheard of for EVs, Ivan Drury, an auto industry analyst with Edmunds.com, explained. “[Rental car companies] are not buying a lot EVs,” he said. “We’re not talking about bulk order traditional fleet sales.” (Hertz, Enterprise Holdings and Avis Budget Group declined to disclose what portion of their fleets are electric.)</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226426" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“For Hertz to go forward and buy 100,000 [Teslas], but on top of that, 50,000 are reserved for Uber drivers &#8212; that throws in a completely different dynamic from what we&#8217;ve ever seen from the rental agencies,” he added.</p>
<p>The sale &#8212; which was apparently for sticker price, <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1452794619410927625" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CEO Elon Musk confirmed</a> &#8212; is also a clear indicator that Tesla is prepared to fulfill a major order of Model 3s by the end of next year. Traditional automakers, meanwhile, may be hung up on a backlog of EV reservations for new customers, Michelle Krebs, an analyst at Cox Automotive, said. “Automakers have been focusing on retail sales to consumers, not selling to rental car fleets during the pandemic and subsequent chip and vehicle inventory shortage,” she said.</p>
<h2>&#8220;Try before you buy&#8221; at scale</h2>
<p>The upside isn’t just monetary. According to <a href="https://www.enterpriseholdings.com/en/press-archive/2015/06/survey-finds-91-percent-of-millennials-believe-car-ownership-is-important.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2015 survey</a> from Enterprise Holdings, the parent company of Enterprise Rent-A-Car, National Car Rental and Alamo Rent A Car, around 62% of respondents said a positive rental experience with a specific model made them consider purchasing one themselves.</p>
<p>EVs have been unable to benefit from this potential consumer interest in the traditional rental car market. Until this point, startups have largely been filling in the gap for those looking to rent an EV for their getaway. Nextmove and Future.rent in Germany specialize in EV-only rentals, while here in the U.S. peer-to-peer car rental marketplace Turo offers a mix of electric and internal combustion engine models.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The demand is there, at least according to peer-to-peer rental marketplace Turo. The number of Teslas listed for rent on Turo has exploded over the past five years, the company said. In 2014, there were 67 Teslas listed on Turo’s marketplace; so far in 2021, that number has jumped to 21,599. For EVs overall, for the same time period, the number increased from 196 to 26,956.</p>
<p>Many people who list cars on Turo report that their Teslas are being rented not necessarily for trips, but for longer test drives. “For a lot of people, the hour that you have sitting in a Tesla [for a test drive] isn&#8217;t enough,” a Turo spokesperson said. “Some potential buyers have range anxiety and want to try a Tesla out for long-distance trips. A lot of our hosts are telling us that guests have been trying Teslas on Turo because in a way you can really call it your own for an extended period of time.”</p>
<p>The market for Tesla rentals at Hertz will not just be traveling Tesla owners, but also consumers who have wanted to test drive a Tesla and possibly “EV curious” consumers, Krebs said.</p>
<p>“It is a great marketing situation for Tesla, which doesn’t buy advertising,” she added. “Instead, Hertz is doing the advertising using 7-time Super Bowl Champion Tom Brady &#8212; and Tesla rides the coattails.” Of course, while Tesla does not use traditional advertising to sell its vehicles, it&#8217;s worth noting that Musk has 54 million followers on Twitter and has shown his is adept at keeping his (and his company’s name) in the press.</p>
<p>Drury also noted that automakers often aim to use rental car agencies as marketing arms to push their most-loaded vehicles. “So for Tesla, this becomes a test drive center.”</p>
<h2>The risk of anti-rental bias</h2>
<p>Of course, there’s no free lunch. The main risk to Tesla, Drury said, is if the Model 3 falls prey to the perception that rental vehicles, and possibly vehicles used for Uber rides, have less value than non-rental cars. “Is the rental stigma going to stick to them? Or this [deal] is going to shed that off?”</p>
<p>Hertz has said that it will offer a “premium and differentiated rental experience” for the Tesla EVs, and that rental prices will be comparable to Hertz’ existing luxury segment, which suggests that the company could maintain its premium associations. Teslas booked through Uber will not be limited to Uber Black, its premium service; they will also be available to those booking through UberX.</p>
<p>There could also eventually be a risk to Tesla in the secondhand market, should the volume of Teslas in rental fleets increase. According to a 2017 <a href="https://static.ed.edmunds-media.com/unversioned/img/car-news/data-center/2017/edmunds-2017-used-vehicle-market-report.pdf">report from Edmunds</a>, used cars that came from rental fleets sold for 9% less in the secondhand market compared to those that did not. This matters for Tesla because these 100,000 Model 3s sold to Hertz will eventually end up in auction (or at Carvana, through a new deal with Hertz), and the automaker could risk saturating the used car market and devaluing their brand, or that specific model. This single order will likely not be enough units to make that happen, but it nevertheless introduces a new dynamic between the Tesla Model 3 and the used car market that wasn&#8217;t there prior.</p>
<p>Regardless of how popular perception pans out, we’re likely to see similar deals for fleet-level orders for more EVs in the future, especially as major automakers ramp up production volumes in non-sedan segments, like trucks and SUVs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/teslas-deal-with-hertz-opens-a-new-frontier-for-the-ev-maker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226426</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Luma raises $4.3M to make 3D models as easy as waving a phone around</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/luma-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/luma-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 18:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matrix Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When online shopping, you&#8217;ve probably come across photos that spin around so you can see a product from all angles. This is typically done by taking a number of photos of a product from all angles, and then playing them like an animation. Luma &#8212; founded by engineers who left Apple&#8217;s AR and computer vision [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When online shopping, you&#8217;ve probably come across photos that spin around so you can see a product from all angles. This is typically done by taking a number of photos of a product from all angles, and then playing them like an animation. <a href="https://lumalabs.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Luma</a> &#8212; founded by engineers who left Apple&#8217;s AR and computer vision group &#8212; wants to shake all of that up. The company has developed a new neural rendering technology that makes it possible to take a small number of photos to generate, shade and render a photo-realistic 3D model of a product. The hope is to drastically speed up the capture of product photography for high-end e-commerce applications, but also to improve the user experience of looking at products from every angle. Best of all, because the captured image is a real 3D interpretation of the scene, it can be rendered from any angle, but also in 3D with two viewports, from slightly different angles. In other words: you can see a 3D image of the product you&#8217;re considering in a VR headset.</p>
<p>For any of us who&#8217;ve been following this space for a while, we&#8217;ve seen for a long time startups trying to do 3D representations using consumer-grade cameras and rudimentary photogrammetry. Spoiler alert: It has never looked particularly great &#8212; but with new technologies come new opportunities, and that&#8217;s where Luma comes in.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225332" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225332" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2225332" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/ferrari.gif" alt="" width="300" height="165" /><p id="caption-attachment-2225332" class="wp-caption-text">A demo of Luma&#8217;s technology working on a real-life example. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Luma</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225314" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;What is different now and why we are doing this now is because of the rise of these ideas of neural rendering. What used to happen and what people are doing with photogrammetry is that you take some images, and then you run some long processing on it, you get point clouds and then you try to reconstruct 3D out of it. You end up with a mesh &#8212; but to get a good-quality 3D image, you need to be able to construct high-quality meshes from noisy, real-world data. Even today, that problem remains a fundamentally unsolved problem,&#8221; Luma AI&#8217;s founder Amit Jain explains, making the point that &#8220;inverse rendering,&#8221; as it known in the industry. The company decided to approach the issue from another angle.</p>
<p>&#8220;We decided to assume that we can&#8217;t get an accurate mesh from a point cloud, and instead are taking a different approach. If you have perfect data about the shape of an object &#8212; i.e. if you have the rendering equation &#8212; you can do Physics Based Rendering (PBR). But the issue is that because we are starting from photographs, we don&#8217;t have enough data to do that type of rendering. So we came up with a new way of doing things. We would take 30 photos of a car, then show 20 of them to the neural network,&#8221; explains Jain. The final 10 photos are used as a &#8220;checksum&#8221; &#8212; or the answer to the equation. If the neural network is able to use the 20 original images to predict what the last 10 images would have looked like, the algorithm has created a pretty good 3D representation of the item you are trying to capture.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s all very geeky photography stuff, but it has some pretty profound real-world applications. If the company gets it way, the way you browse physical goods in e-commerce stores will never be the same. In addition to spinning on its axis, product photos can include zooms and virtual movement from all angles, including angles that weren&#8217;t photographed.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2225819" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2225819" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2225819" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?resize=150,127 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?resize=300,254 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?resize=768,650 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?resize=680,576 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?resize=1536,1301 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?resize=2048,1734 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/luma-reconstruction.png?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2225819" class="wp-caption-text">The top two images are photographs, which formed the basis of the Luma-rendered 3D model below. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Luma</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Everyone want to show their products in 3D, but the problem is that you need to involve 3D artists to come in and make adjustments to scanned objects. That increases the cost a lot,&#8221; says Jain, who argues that this means that 3D renders will only be available to high-end, premium products. Luma&#8217;s tech promises to change that, reducing the cost of capture and display of 3D assets to tens of dollars per product, rather than hundreds or thousands of dollars per 3D representation.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2226383" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226383" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2226383" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg 5533w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Founders-Luma.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226383" class="wp-caption-text">Luma&#8217;s co-founders, Amit Jain (CEO) and Alberto Taiuti (CTO). <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Luma</p></div></p>
<p>The company is planning to build a YouTube-like embeddable player for its products, to make it easy for retailers to embed the three-dimensional images in product pages.</p>
<p>Matrix Partners, South Park Commons, Amplify Partners, RFC’s Andreas Klinger, Context Ventures, as well as a gaggle of angel investors believe in the vision, and backed the company to the tune of $4.3 million. Matrix Partners led the round.</p>
<p>“Everyone who doesn’t live under a rock knows the next great computing paradigm will be underpinned by 3D,” said Antonio Rodriguez, general partner at Matrix, “but few people outside of Luma understand that labor-intensive and bespoke ways of populating the coming 3D environments will not scale. It needs to be as easy to get my stuff into 3D as it is to take a picture and hit send!”</p>
<p>The company shared a video with us to show us what its tech can do:</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rZKnz8J5It4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/luma-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225314</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MIT&#8217;s CSAIL self-driving water taxis launched in the Amsterdam canals</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/mit-csail/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/mit-csail/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT CSAIL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Granted, there aren&#8217;t many cities where self-driving water taxis are a viable option, but Amsterdam may just be one of those places. This week, scientists from MIT’s Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL) and the Senseable City Laboratory launched the first self-navigating, fully autonomous robot boats. They call &#8217;em Roboats (geddit?), and they made [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Granted, there aren&#8217;t many cities where self-driving water taxis are a viable option, but Amsterdam may just be one of those places. This week, scientists from MIT’s Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (<a href="https://www.csail.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSAIL</a>) and the <a href="https://senseable.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Senseable City Laboratory</a> launched the first self-navigating, fully autonomous robot boats. They call &#8217;em Roboats (<em>geddit?</em>), and they made their maiden voyages in the canals today.</p>
<p>The boats are big enough to carry five people. The team suggests they can also be used to collect waste, deliver goods and do other boaty things that people do with boats. The straight-out-of-Blade Runner vessels are battery-powered and can charge wirelessly when they&#8217;re at the dock. The team claims there&#8217;s enough juice on board for 10 hours of operation.</p>
<p>To autonomously determine a free path and avoid crashing into objects, Roboat uses lidar and a number of cameras to enable a 360-degree view. Navigation is done much like you would in a car &#8212; using GPS to figure out a safe route from where it is to where it&#8217;s going.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226399" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2226416" style="width: 3850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2226416" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2226416 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg" alt="" width="3840" height="1634" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg?resize=150,64 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg?resize=300,128 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg?resize=768,327 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg?resize=680,289 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg?resize=1536,654 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg?resize=2048,871 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Roboat10©MIT_AMS-Institute.jpg?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3840px) 100vw, 3840px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2226416" class="wp-caption-text">Roboat is now merrily floating about in the canals of Amsterdam. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Roboat</p></div></p>
<p>“We now have higher precision and robustness in the perception, navigation and control systems, including new functions, such as close proximity approach mode for latching capabilities, and improved dynamic positioning, so the boat can navigate real-world waters,” says MIT professor and CSAIL Director Daniela Rus. “Roboat’s control system is adaptive to the number of people in the boat.”</p>
<p>One clever aspect of the Roboat is that the boat is built on an universal platform &#8212; a hull that can be used for multiple purposes, along with its batteries and propulsion systems. The top deck can be switched out, making it possible to deploy it in different ways, for different use cases.</p>
<p>&#8220;As Roboat can perform its tasks 24/7, and without a skipper on board, it adds great value for a city. However, for safety reasons it is questionable if reaching Level A autonomy is desirable,&#8221; says Fábio Duarte, a lead scientist on the project. &#8220;An onshore operator will monitor Roboat remotely from a control center. One operator can monitor over 50 Roboat units, ensuring smooth operations.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You can see the technology in action on <a href="https://roboat.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Roboat.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/mit-csail/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Smith, Kevin Durant and Sean &#8216;Diddy&#8217; Combs invest in electric boat startup Arc</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/will-smith-kevin-durant-and-sean-diddy-combs-invest-in-electric-boat-startup-arc/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/will-smith-kevin-durant-and-sean-diddy-combs-invest-in-electric-boat-startup-arc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Sacca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric boats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Durant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lowercarbon Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Smith]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arc, a startup that launched 10 months ago with ambitions to electrify everything on the water, starting with a limited-edition $300,000 boat, has captured the attention and capital of some of the entertainment industry&#8217;s biggest stars. The startup, which closed a seed round in February led by VC firm Andreessen Horowitz, has brought on several [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Arc, a startup that launched 10 months ago with ambitions to electrify everything on the water, starting with a limited-edition $300,000 boat, has captured the attention and capital of some of the entertainment industry&#8217;s biggest stars. The startup, which closed a seed round in February led by VC firm Andreessen Horowitz, has brought on <a href="https://arcboats.com/blog/expanding-the-crew/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">several new investors</a>, including funds from Will Smith&#8217;s Dreamers VC, Kevin Durant and Rich Kleiman&#8217;s Thirty Five Ventures and Sean &#8220;Diddy&#8221; Combs&#8217; Combs Enterprises.</p>
<p>The new investment, which co-founder and CEO Mitch Lee describes as a strategic round, pushes Arc&#8217;s total funding past $7 million. Chris Sacca&#8217;s Lowercarbon Capital and Ramtin Nami&#8217;s Abstract Ventures invested in Arc&#8217;s seed round.</p>
<p>&#8220;All of these people, in addition to just being world class at what they do, have a ton of experience building brands and marketing products, and generally cultivating a community,&#8221; Lee told TechCrunch in a recent interview.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226382" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>In short, Combs, Durant and Smith have a sphere of influence that taps into the market that Arc is hoping to reach. The upper luxury segment, in which that first $300,000 boat sits, is not Arc&#8217;s end game, Lee explained.</p>
<p>Lee and former SpaceX engineer Ryan Cook co-founded Arc with a plan to develop and sell electric watercraft at various price points and use cases. The company of more than 10 people — many with long stints at SpaceX — started with the hull, Lee explained.</p>
<p>Even though electric boats are quieter, quicker, more reliable and less expensive to maintain, they have not scaled because of three challenges, Lee said. Historically, there hasn&#8217;t been a supply chain for batteries needed for boats, the right high-voltage electrical systems and a hull designed to accommodate the weight and volume needed for large battery packs, according to Lee.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we approached this we said, we are going to start with a purpose-built hull and purpose-built battery packs that are laid out in a way that makes sense if you were to just start from scratch,&#8221; Lee said, noting that the engineering talent from SpaceX has been key to developing the hull and high-voltage electrical system needed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company now has a working alpha prototype called the Arc One, a 24-foot aluminum boat that produces 475 horsepower and can run between 3 to 5 hours on a single charge. Arc will produce fewer than 25 Arc One boats.</p>
<p>The Arc One is not aesthetically finished, according to Lee, who noted the attention has been on designing the hull, electrical system and battery packs. But the boat does work; the team recently took it waterskiing. Serial production of the Arc One is expected to begin next month, with the first deliveries to customers occurring early next year.</p>
<p>Arc&#8217;s plan is to use the funds from investors to scale its production and develop boats than can be price competitive with gas-powered ones — a strategy employed by Tesla.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are not planning to make very many of these, but it sets the tone for what an electric boat can be in this market and it creates a new anchor for us — pun intended,&#8221; Lee said. From there, Arc hopes to introduce and start selling a new boat by the end of 2022 that will be directly targeted at consumers in the mass watersports market. While Arc hasn&#8217;t set pricing for its next boat, it would need to be around $150,000 to $200,000 to compete with its gas-powered brethren.</p>
<p>The timing of that next boat will depend on the timing and amount of additional capital Arc ends up raising, Lee shared. For now, the company hopes its first boat will charge up demand for its future electric products.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/will-smith-kevin-durant-and-sean-diddy-combs-invest-in-electric-boat-startup-arc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226382</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mastodon issues 30-day ultimatum to Trump&#8217;s social network over misuse of its code</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/mastodon-issues-30-day-ultimatum-to-trumps-social-network-over-misuse-of-its-code/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/mastodon-issues-30-day-ultimatum-to-trumps-social-network-over-misuse-of-its-code/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastodon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Former President Trump&#8217;s new social network might be in hot water before it even launches. Mastodon, a free social media framework, alleges that Truth Social is passing open source software off as its own, and has given them 30 days to fix this. If it doesn&#8217;t fix things by the end of next month, things [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Former President Trump&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/trump-launches-his-own-social-media-platform-truth-social/">new social network</a> might be in hot water before it even launches. Mastodon, a free social media framework, alleges that Truth Social is passing open source software off as its own, and has <a href="https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2021/10/trumps-new-social-media-platform-found-using-mastodon-code/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">given them 30 days to fix this</a>. If it doesn&#8217;t fix things by the end of next month, things could get messy.</p>
<p>In a post to the Mastodon blog, founder and CEO Eugen Rochko explained that the problem is not simply that Truth Social uses Mastodon, but that it does so while claiming ownership over the site&#8217;s code. People inspecting the code of the pre-launch site last week found it was very clearly using Mastodon&#8217;s code without acknowledgment.</p>
<p>&#8220;The terms of service included a worrying passage, claiming that the site is proprietary property and all source code and software are owned or controlled by them or licensed to them,&#8221; he wrote. &#8220;Mastodon is free software published under the AGPLv3 license, which requires any over-the-network service using it to make its source code and any modifications to it publicly accessible.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226415" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>No mention of Mastodon was made by Truth, although it&#8217;s plain that the company&#8217;s code is being used.</p>
<p>This sort of license is common in open source software, which is provided free of charge even in many cases to large corporations, which are free to use and modify it — as long as they do so publicly and make their work part of the overall development of the tool. This has produced a rich environment of collaboration between people volunteering their time and companies whose engineers are essentially being paid to contribute.</p>
<p>But such licenses are frequently not respected. Often it&#8217;s by companies large enough to think they can get away with it, or simply don&#8217;t understand what&#8217;s required of them, even if it may only be a use acknowledgement or a GitHub page documenting how they changed the code. The consequences of violations are not at all clear and depend on many factors. For instance, if a company were to use the open source software under a free license in order to avoid paying for an available paid license, a lawsuit might be filed seeking monetary damages for lost income. Or a suit could purely be motivated by a desire to keep the code open, such as <a href="https://sfconservancy.org/copyleft-compliance/vizio.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this recent case against Vizio</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RH7XEVya4v"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/trump-launches-his-own-social-media-platform-truth-social/">Trump to launch his own social media platform, calling it TRUTH Social</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Trump to launch his own social media platform, calling it TRUTH Social&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/trump-launches-his-own-social-media-platform-truth-social/embed/#?secret=RH7XEVya4v" data-secret="RH7XEVya4v" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The sheer number of license violations out there means many will slip through the cracks, but the Trump social network&#8217;s highly public flouting of the license probably won&#8217;t. Rochko&#8217;s post says that if Truth Social doesn&#8217;t comply by acknowledging and posting the Mastodon-sourced code for review, their license to said code will be revoked on November 26 (30 days after a letter explaining all this was sent to Truth Social&#8217;s chief legal officer).</p>
<p>This is the very remedy which <a href="https://sfconservancy.org/blog/2021/oct/21/trump-group-agplv3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Software Freedom Conservancy predicted</a> would come into play last week, since as they point out, &#8220;That&#8217;s how AGPLv3&#8217;s cure provision works — no exceptions — even if you&#8217;re a real estate mogul, reality television star, or even a former POTUS.&#8221; This &#8220;cure&#8221; only awaited notification by the copyright holder (i.e. Mastodon) assuming no other agreement was reached.</p>
<p>&#8220;Someone using the code without a license would be infringing on our copyright,&#8221; Rochko told TechCrunch in an email. &#8220;The avenues for fighting copyright infringement would be open to us then.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rochko admits that they&#8217;re not pleased that the Trump faction is using their software, but that they all were prepared for that when they got into this business, and that their only real objection is that it&#8217;s not being used according to the rules:</p>
<blockquote><p>As far as personal feelings are concerned, of course we would prefer if people so antithetical to our values did not use and benefit from our labour, but the reality of working on free software is that you give up the possibility of choosing who can and cannot use it from the get-go, so in a practical sense the only issue we can take with something like Truth Social is if they don’t even comply with the free software license we release our work under.</p></blockquote>
<p>Mastodon was deliberately designed so that instances of it are essentially completely independent, and the company can&#8217;t reach out and shut one down. Ironically, it&#8217;s the exact sort of social media tool Trump&#8217;s allies have been crying out for while complaining about the centralized authority of Twitter and Facebook; Mastodon has been available for years, yet in adopting it Trump&#8217;s company has done so in the most dubious possible way and put the whole operation at risk.</p>
<p>If Truth Social backpedals on its claims to have created the social network itself — and not simply set up a branded instance of Mastodon, which anyone can do in an afternoon — it will be safe but may lose a bit of luster. If it doesn&#8217;t, then it&#8217;s a textbook case and a lawsuit may force the company to build its own code base after all, which they may find is harder than expected.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/mastodon-issues-30-day-ultimatum-to-trumps-social-network-over-misuse-of-its-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226415</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Facebook&#8217;s angry emoji should interest the US SEC</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/why-facebooks-angry-emoji-should-interest-the-us-sec/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/why-facebooks-angry-emoji-should-interest-the-us-sec/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cambridge Analytica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frances Haugen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lina Khan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2226192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission must thoroughly investigate Facebook and enforce our laws. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Lisa Gilbert</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/lisa_pubcitizen">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Lisa Gilbert is the vice president of <a href="https://www.citizen.org/">Public Citizen</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Facebook may have a new name, but a rebrand won’t erase the multiple recent disclosures illustrating how destructive the company is for society — and how harmful it is for its own investors.</p>
<p>The revelations from Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen were shocking but not surprising. According to Haugen, who worked for the tech giant on election security matters before leaving and turning over a large cache of documents to the press, lawmakers and regulators, Facebook consistently knew that its algorithms were harming society and the vulnerable, with reprehensible actions like <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/10/frances-haugen-takes-on-facebook-the-making-of-a-modern-us-hero">pushing so-called “thin-spiration”</a> to teenage girls, which can increase the likelihood of anorexia.</p>
<p>A recent analysis of internal Facebook documents showed that Facebook engineers treated emoji reactions — including the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/10/26/facebook-angry-emoji-algorithm/">“angry” emoji</a> — as five times more valuable than “likes,” favoring controversial posts to keep users engaged &#8212; and profits flowing.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2226192" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This isn’t just a story of a company acting against the public interest and harming its own consumers; it is also a story about one acting against its investors. According to Haugen, the company misled its shareholders about <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/05/facebook-whistleblower-accuses-firm-of-serially-misleading-over-safety">basic business facts</a>, from how it addresses safety to the size of its user base.</p>
<p>By serially failing to tell investors this kind of critical information, Facebook may have violated our securities laws and regulations. And Haugen has filed <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-misinformation-public-60-minutes-2021-10-03/">at least eight complaints</a> with the Securities and Exchange Commission alleging that Facebook has broken the law for withholding material information related to the company’s internal research.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/10/22/facebook-new-whistleblower-complaint/">second unnamed whistleblower</a> provided an affidavit to the SEC alleging that Facebook prioritizes growth and profits over hate speech and misinformation.</p>
<p>As notable as whistleblower allegations are, it is surprising that the role the SEC could play in regulating and containing Facebook hasn’t received top billing. While Facebook is a tech company, it is first and foremost a publicly traded company, and therefore subject to SEC regulations and oversight.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It was the Obama-era SEC that originally <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/facebook-stock-approved-for-listing-on-the-nasdaq/">approved</a> Facebook’s 2012 initial public offering although the process included a <a href="https://www.herrick.com/publications/sec-challenges-dual-class-structures/">strange special class of shares</a> that continued to give Mark Zuckerberg total effective control over the company even after it became public. Additionally, it was the Trump-era SEC that <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2019-140">settled</a> with Facebook over its failure to properly disclose to investors that it knew the scandalous data company Cambridge Analytica had accessed and misused the Facebook data of approximately 30 million Americans.</p>
<p>Asking the SEC to take a closer look at Facebook, a company that has settled with the commission within the last two and a half years over securities law violations, should be ordinary, reasonable and what we expect of our securities regulator.</p>
<p>Americans are lucky that the Biden administration has placed strong regulators in charge of the SEC and Federal Trade Commission by appointing Gary Gensler and Lina Khan their respective chairs. But just as Facebook and the other Big Tech behemoths have come to touch all aspects of our economy, politics and everyday life, the task of properly regulating and containing these firms is larger than any one or two agencies.</p>
<p>What we need to truly tackle the questions and threats posed by large tech firms is a whole-of-government approach. The Biden administration has made <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/09/executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">a good first step</a> with its Council on Competition, but this must represent the first cut rather than a final product. It also means refusing to give large tech firms access to new markets to dominate, from fintech to currency to special government contracts, understanding that these companies would almost certainly use these opportunities to grow even more powerful at the expense of smaller firms and consumers.</p>
<p>We also need the engagement of Congress on these critical questions. On the same day that Haugen was testifying before a Senate subcommittee, the House Financial Services Committee held a hearing on SEC oversight. Despite several days of coverage of Haugen’s incendiary claims, the hearing went for hours without a single comment or question about the SEC’s role in holding <span style="font-size: 1rem;"><span style="letter-spacing: -.1pt;">Facebook </span>accountable to its investors.</span></p>
<p>The failure of this key oversight opportunity represents a lack of imagination and coordination. To truly address the dangers of Big Tech, we need every member to be thinking about remedies for dealing with these gigantic companies, including pushing the Biden administration to do more.</p>
<p>Haugen is not the first whistleblower to emerge from Facebook, nor will she be the last. The time has passed for the U.S. federal government to meekly watch as Big Tech employees, shareholders, contractors and even the founders lay out the dangers these companies pose to Americans.</p>
<p>As the companies grow in size, power and danger, now is the time for the Biden administration to act boldly, aggressively and cohesively, beginning with the SEC taking up the cause and thoroughly investigating Facebook and fully enforcing our laws.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/why-facebooks-angry-emoji-should-interest-the-us-sec/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2226192</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
