<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 23:02:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>GoTo Global drives European expansion with acquisition of German e-moped sharing company emmy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/goto-global-drives-european-expansion-with-acquisition-of-german-e-moped-sharing-company-emmy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/goto-global-drives-european-expansion-with-acquisition-of-german-e-moped-sharing-company-emmy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 22:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emmy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoTo Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wunder Mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israeli shared multimodal mobility operator GoTo Global Mobility has acquired German shared electric scooter company emmy. The strategic deal will help GoTo Global, which offers customers access to shared cars, vans, mopeds, scooters and bikes, reach its goal of expanding to every major European city by 2025. GoTo Global would not share the financial terms [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Israeli shared multimodal mobility operator GoTo Global Mobility has acquired German shared electric scooter company emmy. The strategic deal will help GoTo Global, which offers customers access to shared cars, vans, mopeds, scooters and bikes, reach its goal of expanding to every major European city by 2025. GoTo Global would not share the financial terms of the deal.</p>
<p>Acquiring emmy, which has a fleet of over 3,000 shared electric step-through scooters (not kick scooters) across Berlin, Hamburg and Munich, gives GoTo a direct path to the German market. The company&#8217;s current footprint includes Spain, Malta and Israel.</p>
<p>&#8220;In Germany for us is a huge opportunity because emmy is a great company with five years under its belt, but they have only mopeds, and you cannot create user loyalty without creating mobility confidence, and this is what we try to do,&#8221; said Gil Laser, CEO of GoTo Global. &#8220;We try to give you with our app the same feeling that you have a solution to move, anytime, anywhere. We can take [emmy&#8217;s] user base of more than 300,000 people, and using GoTo technology, convert this company from a mono-vertical to a multimodal, and immediately start to offer them cars and other micromobility options, short trips and long trips.&#8221;</p>
<p>As part of the acquisition, GoTo also takes on emmy&#8217;s debts. In April, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/wunder-mobilitys-new-lending-business-helps-micromobility-startups-finance-fleets/">shared mobility software company Wunder Mobility launched a lending service</a> and announced plans to help emmy finance 1,500 retrofitted Yadea scooters, which will now be GoTo&#8217;s responsibility to pay back. Laser said GoTo intends to maintain the relationship with Wunder in the future.</p>
<p>Emmy users won&#8217;t immediately notice a difference in branding until next year, when GoTo intends to fully integrate the service under its own brand umbrella and connect users to other forms of mobility. Laser said GoTo will bring other forms of mobility, like cars and e-bikes, to Germany starting Q1 of next year. The company also recently raised rounds totaling $22.5 million and is currently raising more to help it expand into Italy, Netherlands and Portugal in the next year, according to Laser.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our goal is to be the Netflix of mobility,&#8221; Laser told TechCrunch. &#8220;In the end users will pay us X amount of dollars and you get free rides on whichever vehicle you want.&#8221;</p>
<p>Until such a point, the company has to establish a presence and brand loyalty. Laser says multimodality that includes car rentals is the company&#8217;s secret sauce for success, part of a strategy that has led GoTo to be profitable and cashflow positive in its most mature market of Israel. The company hopes the strategy will also translate to an annual revenue that exceeds $116 million by the end of 2023.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s a balancing act between the cost of user acquisition and how much money you can generate from a user, says Laser. Shared micromobility companies have a low cost of acquisition because they just put their assets all over the streets, people see them, download the app and then they&#8217;re a customer. The problem is that the revenue per each user (RPU) is usually low, in large part because there&#8217;s no difference in service between companies, and therefore no loyalty, according to Laser.</p>
<p>Car rental companies have a different problem. They have a higher RPU because you can charge $20 to $30 per ride, but the marketing costs to acquire a user is really high.</p>
<p>&#8220;How we solve this problem is the multimodality philosophy,&#8221; said Laser. &#8220;We convert the user to use more and more services. Like you came to the supermarket to buy veggies but then you also end up buying meat and milk.&#8221;</p>
<p>One way the company does this is through a variety of promotion-type schemes. For example, Laser says GoTo charges €3 for the first 15 minutes of any ride on any vehicle. If a new user comes on to book a ride on a scooter and adds €3 to their wallet, they might automatically see €9 in the wallet that can be used toward the purchase of a car ride. This alerts the user to other use cases and, hopefully, creates brand loyalty in a way that&#8217;s cheaper than spending hundreds of millions of dollars on advertising with Google and Facebook, says Laser.</p>
<p>The result so far has been 90% of B2C revenue comes from return users, and 41% of all customers are multimodal users. Part of this might also be due to the fact that GoTo also charges a membership, which can range from around $2 to $7, to use its service.</p>
<p>In order to achieve healthy unit economics, the company also combines owning and leasing assets.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the end our product is more efficient,&#8221; said Laser. &#8220;By not owning the assets, we enjoy the arbitrage from taking a car or moped and renting it for two years and renting it back to our users for two minutes, and by doing that we can gain a lot of profit.&#8221;</p>
<p>GoTo has MoUs with Renault, Toyota, Nio and Segway. It currently leases its cars and mopeds and owns its own smaller micromobility vehicles, but hopes to lease those, too, in the future. However, one of the main problems micromobility operators have faced has been the way shared assets depreciate very quickly, so it&#8217;s hard to imagine a scooter manufacturer wanting to own the asset and not generate rental revenue from it.</p>
<p>One way to make that scheme work would be to have really high utilization rates, which requires different types of demand that peaks at different hours. Aside from its main customer base of commuters, GoTo is actively targeting business customers through three different models. The first and second is to get companies to offer employees benefits in the form of either subscriptions or mobility wallets. The third is for companies to reserve dedicated fleets for their employees, usually between specific work hours like from 8am to 6pm. After 6pm, the fleets would go back to being available for communities, says Laser. Business customers currently make up 13% of GoTo&#8217;s revenue, but the goal is to boost that up to 50% by 2025.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We are today on course to register 100% year on year growth in 2021 and we know that GoTo’s multimodal mobility experience means we can hit right at the heart of the urban mobility problem,&#8221; said Laser. &#8220;Today we assume to be at least 30-36 months ahead of other platforms and offerings in the market.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/goto-global-drives-european-expansion-with-acquisition-of-german-e-moped-sharing-company-emmy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212861</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Sora selected as Super Smash Bros. Ultimate&#8217;s final DLC character</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/daily-crunch-71/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/daily-crunch-71/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 22:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for October 5, 2021. We warned you that a bunch of tech startups were going to go public in Q4. That’s coming true. But we also have video game news, crypto news and all sorts of goodies below. Let’s do it! – <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/telegram-says-it-added-70m-users-while-facebook-and-whatsapp-were-down/"><strong>Facebook down, Telegram up:</strong></a><strong> </strong>During Facebook’s pretty embarrassing outage yesterday, rival messaging service Telegram said that it picked up some 70 million new users. Recall that <em>all</em> Facebook services were down, which meant that WhatsApp also went kaput for a while there. In other Facebook news, a whistleblower from the company’s former employee ranks <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/">testified today in front of the U.S. Senate</a>.</li>
<li><strong>IPO SZN: </strong>Get your boots on, everyone, we have some S-1 exploring to do. Yes, today TechCrunch dug <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/udemy-files-to-go-public-on-back-of-growing-b2b-incomes/">into IPO filings from Udemy</a></strong> (an edtech unicorn) <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/what-rent-the-runways-ipo-filing-says-about-the-business-of-loaner-garments/">and Rent the Runway</a></strong> (a DTC fashion rental unicorn). Udemy should help set the tone for edtech debuts ahead of Byju’s own, while Rent the Runway will represent the direct-to-consumer market to a lesser degree.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/sora-is-the-final-super-smash-bros-ultimate-fighter/"><strong>The final fighter in Super Smash Bros. Ultimate is:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Sora? Apparently? If you haven’t played the Kingdom Hearts franchise this will mean nothing to you. But according to TechCrunch analytics this was one hell of a big deal. So, here you go, by popular demand!</li>
</ul>
<p><em>And from the TechCrunch Experts crew, “</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/who-are-the-best-software-development-consultants-for-startups/"><em>we’re looking to profile great software development shops that work with startups</em></a><em>.” So if that is you, hit the link!</em></p>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Kicking off our startup coverage today, two accelerator classes for your perusal. TechCrunch wrote up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/here-are-the-23-companies-pitching-at-alchemist-accelerators-demo-day-xxviii-today/">the 23 companies that are part of the latest Alchemist batch</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/meet-the-12-companies-launching-out-of-the-entrepreneurs-roundtable-accelerator/">the 14 companies that are launching from the Entrepreneurs Roundtable group</a>. We love an accelerator class here at the blog, mostly because they often provide an interesting perspective on where founders are finding company-worthy problems to solve.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/the-uae-aims-to-launch-a-probe-to-the-asteroid-belt-between-mars-and-jupiter-in-2028/"><strong>Launch outdated forms of government into space:</strong></a><strong> </strong>That’s my takeaway from news that the United Arab Emirates (UAE) wants to launch a probe to the asteroid belt. I am in favor of any and all space launches, except perhaps those from countries with official religions and, well, monarchs.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/appsmith-raises-8m-to-take-on-the-internal-corporate-app-market-with-open-source-code/"><strong>Appsmith raises $8M for its OSS-focused internal app service:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The market for building software that helps companies create internal apps is big &#8212; and competitive. And a newer player made waves this morning by announcing that it has raised fresh capital for its open source approach. Appsmith has yet to commercialize its project, but with fresh funds and notable pickup from the open source community, it’s a company to watch.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/podcastle-raises-7m-for-its-all-in-one-platform-for-podcast-production-and-publishing/">Podcastle raises $7M for all-in podcast service:</a> </strong>While it is very easy to create a <em>bad</em> podcast, it’s actually rather complicated and difficult to create a <em>good</em> podcast. Happily for all the folks out there who have yet to kick off their own episodic audiocast, Podcastle just raised lots of new capital for its all-in-one (“recording, production and publishing,” per TechCrunch) podcasting service. So, now you have no excuse to have poor audio and lackluster editing.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/contrary-capitals-20m-fund-ii-is-all-about-community-first-investments/"><strong>Contrary Capital raises $20M for second fund:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Our own Natasha Mascarenhas wrote about a new venture capital fund today, the second from Contrary Capital. She writes that founder Eric Tarczynski “noticed there was an absence of venture capital firms focused on entrepreneurs within universities.” So, Tarczynski went fishing in that particular pond. It must have gone pretty well, as Contrary is now back with a second installment of LP cash to invest.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/duality-nabs-30m-for-its-privacy-focused-data-collaboration-tools-built-using-homomorphic-encryption/">Duality raises $30M to help companies share data securely:</a> </strong>Cybersecurity isn’t just a big deal these days because VCs are investing in the space. It’s a big deal because the digital world is still full of holes, and attack vectors are more myriad than stars in the sky. Duality — the startup, <strong><a href="https://youtu.be/UjUIKd-qQRM?t=42">not the excellent song</a></strong> — wants to use homomorphic encryption to build tools that “make it easier for companies to share data and collaborate with each other without compromising sensitive information,” we reported.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Finding product-market fit, from the earliest stages through growth</h2>
<p>There&#8217;s no magic moment when a startup reaches product-market fit: no flashing lights, no siren, no balloons falling from the ceiling.</p>
<p>&#8220;Especially for first-time founders, assessing product-market fit at a stage where it’s mostly anticipation can be as much art as science,&#8221; writes News Editor Darrell Etherington, who interviewed three VCs about the topic for TechCrunch Disrupt:</p>
<ul>
<li>Heather Hartnett, Human Ventures</li>
<li>David Thacker, Greylock</li>
<li>Victoria Treyger, Felicis</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CSN8LFaSvm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/finding-product-market-fit-from-the-earliest-stages-through-growth/">Finding product-market fit, from the earliest stages through growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Finding product-market fit, from the earliest stages through growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/finding-product-market-fit-from-the-earliest-stages-through-growth/embed/#?secret=CSN8LFaSvm" data-secret="CSN8LFaSvm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/co-streaming-rolls-out-to-all-creators-on-facebook-gaming/"><strong>Facebook rolls out co-streaming to all creators:</strong></a><strong> </strong>While Facebook is largely in the news for, ahem, other reasons, the company is still building stuff. Including getting the groundwork in place to allow more streamers to cast in pairs.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/review-the-surface-pro-8-with-windows-11-is-fast-and-fresh/"><strong>TechCrunch likes the new Surface hardware:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Story time! Back during my first stint at TechCrunch, I flew to Redmond to get an early look at some Surface hardware. I brought along a TechCrunch camera to snap some pics. And, in my infinite genius, took a million photos <em>of which I swear only two or three were not entirely blurry</em>. I nearly blacked out from panic when I got home and found out. The good news today is that my colleague Matthew Burns can actually take pictures. The better news is that he took many pictures of the new Surface Pro 8. And best news of all? He liked it, so there’s new competition out there for your computing needs.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/apple-launches-new-coding-guide-for-elementary-school-students/"><strong>Apple wants to teach kids to code:</strong></a><strong> </strong>1-800-kode-for-kids is what I would have titled this piece. Aisha Malik has actually good sense, so she went with something a bit more sober. Regardless, Apple’s “Everyone Can Code Early Learners” program means that even tots can get a jump on learning how to forget where they put semicolons.</li>
<li><em>In other news, please welcome Aisha to the TechCrunch crew by <a href="https://twitter.com/AiishaMalik1">following her on Twitter</a>!</em></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/robinhood-finally-brings-on-demand-phone-support-to-all-of-its-users/"><strong>And, to close us out, Robinhood has finally launched 24/7 phone support:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Which is big news for the stocks-and-crypto trading company that captured the attention of both retail traders and regulators during its short, high-flying life.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Introducing TechCrunch Experts: Software Consulting</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2212893" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212893" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2212893" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2212893" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch Experts is expanding to another vertical! Just like with growth marketing, many startups are outsourcing their software development. You can read more about those reasons <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/who-are-the-best-software-development-consultants-for-startups/?">here</a>. We want to know which software consultants you’ve worked with for anything from UI/UX to cloud architecture. Let us know <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl?typeform-source=techcrunch.com">here</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pMQmQWOKLd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/who-are-the-best-software-development-consultants-for-startups/">Who are the best software development consultants for startups?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Who are the best software development consultants for startups?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/who-are-the-best-software-development-consultants-for-startups/embed/#?secret=pMQmQWOKLd" data-secret="pMQmQWOKLd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>To start off our editorial coverage for this new topic, Miranda Halpern interviewed Joshua Davidson from Chop Dawg:<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/app-agency-chop-dawg-on-helping-startups-build-for-the-long-term/"> “App agency Chop Dawg on helping startups build for the long term.”</a></p>
<p>As we expand into software consulting (and eventually other service verticals for startups), we&#8217;ll keep profiling growth marketers via the existing survey, which you can <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/oYNNmGpd">fill out here.</a></p>
<p>As always, as the recommendations come in, we’ll share them publicly so that startups can find the right expert for what they need.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8nIhVAgiAQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/app-agency-chop-dawg-on-helping-startups-build-for-the-long-term/">App agency Chop Dawg on helping startups build for the long term</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;App agency Chop Dawg on helping startups build for the long term&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/app-agency-chop-dawg-on-helping-startups-build-for-the-long-term/embed/#?secret=8nIhVAgiAQ" data-secret="8nIhVAgiAQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/daily-crunch-71/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212882</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Technical interview platform Byteboard spins out of Google&#8217;s Area 120, takes on new funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/technical-interview-platform-byteboard-spins-out-of-googles-area-120-takes-on-new-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/technical-interview-platform-byteboard-spins-out-of-googles-area-120-takes-on-new-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 21:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Byteboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome os]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowboy ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoodRx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Byteboard, a service designed to replace the pre-onsite technical interview part of a company&#8217;s hiring process with a web-based alternative, will be spinning out of Google, TechCrunch learned and Google confirmed. The product was originally incubated as part of the company&#8217;s internal R&#38;D lab known as Area 120, where it&#8217;s been led by CEO Sargun [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://byteboard.dev/">Byteboard</a>, a service designed to replace the pre-onsite technical interview part of a company&#8217;s hiring process with a web-based alternative, will be spinning out of Google, TechCrunch learned and Google confirmed. The product was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/17/googles-area-120-launches-byteboard-to-improve-technical-interviews/">originally incubated</a> as part of the company&#8217;s internal R&amp;D lab known as Area 120, where it&#8217;s been led by CEO Sargun Kaur. With this move, Byteboard will be the first Area 120 project to exit Google and become its own standalone company. But Google notes this will be an exception, not the rule.</p>
<p>Google told us that the spinout will have no impact on any existing Area 120 teams or the group&#8217;s future strategy. Instead, its R&amp;D division will continue to focus on funding projects that are most likely to advance Google&#8217;s own opportunities, the company said.</p>
<p>In addition to the spinout, Byteboard has taken on new investment from Cowboy Ventures and others, in the $10 million-$15 million range. But we understand this is not a &#8220;buyout,&#8221; as Google will retain equity in the new company, which will continue to be led by co-founders Kaur and Nikke Hardson-Hurley.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re thrilled to see the strides Byteboard has made over the past three years incubating within Google’s Area 120,&#8221; a Google spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Byteboard’s solution is equipping high-growth businesses with the tools they need to assess and hire top technical talent, with greater efficiency and fairness. We look forward to continuing our work with Sargun, Nikke, and the rest of the Byteboard team,&#8221; they said.</p>
<p>Launched in 2019, Byteboard&#8217;s idea was to create a tool that would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/17/googles-area-120-launches-byteboard-to-improve-technical-interviews/">make the technical interview experience</a> less tedious and more effective. The team noted at the time that the current process for interviewing software engineers didn&#8217;t really work for measuring how well someone would do in a day-to-day engineering job. Instead, interviews often benefitted those who had the time and resources to prepare, as they would test more for memorization rather than the practical application of people&#8217;s skills.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1856555" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1856555" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1856555" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?w=680" alt="byteboard interview technical spec exercise" width="680" height="381" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png 5116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?resize=1536,860 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?resize=2048,1146 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/byteboard_interview_technical_spec_exercise.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1856555" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Byteboard</p></div></p>
<p>Byteboard flips this around by presenting job candidates with a real-world coding environment where they can select from supported languages like Java, Python, Ruby, C++, C#, JavaScript (node.js), Go, and PHP.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The web-based interview is conducted in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript while the mobile interview is offering in Swift (iOS) and Kotlin (Android), and the <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">data engineering interview is offered in Python and Java.</span></p>
<p>Its end-to-end service includes the interview platform, a bank of calibrated questions across 20+ essential software engineering skills, and an assessment after the fact. A group of experienced engineers review and rate the interviews. And this evaluation is handled anonymously, with the aim of taking the bias out of the process.</p>
<p>The business took off following its 2019 debut. After a brief slump during the early days of Covid lockdowns, Byteboard picked up again in Q3 2020 as companies returned to hiring. According to <a href="https://byteboard.dev/case-studies">Byteboard&#8217;s website</a>, those using its service have included Lyft, Hulu, Figma, Imperfect Foods, PlayVS, Betterment, Robinhood, GoodRx, ETHOS, Ezoic, and Glowforge.</p>
<p>In addition to the benefits of running the interview process through the web, instead of in-person (another concern in the Covid era), the quality of the data and assessment, and the less stressful environment for the candidates, Byteboard could also save companies money as they would no longer have to pay engineers to staff the interviews and measure the results.</p>
<p>However, the potential for Byteboard may have been limited as a Google-owned product.</p>
<p>Because engineers are a part of the human evaluation process with Byteboard, that would have made Google a part of the hiring group for other companies &#8212; including, in some cases, companies it directly competed with. That obviously raises ethical issues, as companies generally wouldn&#8217;t let competitors involve themselves in their hiring process. This is largely why Byteboard is moving forward as its own business, instead of a Google-owned project.</p>
<p>Of the half-dozen total team members at Byteboard, a few are joining the standalone company and a couple are choosing to stay at Google where they&#8217;ll move on to new projects, a source close to the matter told TechCrunch. Google didn&#8217;t confirm the details of this aspect of the deal, but noted Byteboard will continue to expand on its core product and operational focus, with more to share over the next few months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/technical-interview-platform-byteboard-spins-out-of-googles-area-120-takes-on-new-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212649</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Improving startup results through female leadership</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/improving-startup-results-through-female-leadership/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/improving-startup-results-through-female-leadership/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 21:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity and inclusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you hiring and organizing to access the widest range of ideas and perspectives?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Leah Edwards</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/greenleah">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Leah Edwards is a passionate fan and connector in technology and impact, a lecturer at UC Berkeley and Stanford and a partner at <a href="https://www.pegasustechventures.com/">Pegasus Tech Ventures</a>, a Silicon Valley-based VC firm.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">During my career — spanning entrepreneurship, academia, arts management and venture capital — I’ve learned the importance of female leadership in contributing to successful outcomes.</p>
<p>Diverse perspectives, including those of female leaders, improve problem-solving and decision-making. I believe that novel perspectives generate “additive” moments: instances when one member of a team makes another member’s idea even better. Teams made up of like-minded people from similar backgrounds are limited in their breadth of perspectives, and, as a result, they limit the potential of their companies.</p>
<p>So, the question is this: Are you hiring and organizing to access the widest range of ideas and perspectives?</p>
<p>As a partner at <a href="https://www.pegasustechventures.com/">Pegasus Tech Ventures</a>, I’m aware that the VC industry boasts about finding teams with outlying and industry-changing ideas. However, the truth is that the industry has a low percentage of female leaders compared to other industries.</p>
<p>Not only are there few female partners in VC funds, we are also not doing enough to support female founders. Startups received an unprecedented amount of financial investment during the pandemic, yet female founders lost ground.</p>
<p>Research has proven repeatedly that diversity is good for business. Public companies with at least one female board member typically outperform companies with only male members. Diverse teams have also been found to produce the most creative ideas.</p>
<p>A key tenant of the Design Thinking and Lean Startup methods — which have served entrepreneurial ecosystems well — is to lead with action. Let’s take specific actions that will result in more female leadership in the startup world.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here’s what I’m doing; I hope it will inspire you to take actions of your own.</p>
<h2>Hiring to improve results</h2>
<p>I believe that startups (and venture capital firms) need to change their hiring practices to diversify their teams. While it is easier to rely on the founders’ existing networks to recruit, it’s worth the effort to expand your outreach.</p>
<p>One technique I’ve used is to partner with top-tier universities around the world that have made the commitment to recruit diverse student bodies. This helps me tap into a bigger pool of diverse talent, including female leaders. These new recruits have a wider range of backgrounds and life experiences, so they bring novel perspectives to the table.</p>
<p>It’s also helpful for startup leaders to host open office hours during which potential applicants can ask questions about the company’s culture, open positions and how to apply for them. Personally, I’ve been successful in attracting a more diverse pool of applicants when I made it a comfortable and welcoming process. Make sure that applicants understand your company’s objectives and your belief that diverse perspectives contribute directly to the creativity and productivity of your teams.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a great case study: Orchestras discovered that they naturally achieved more gender diversity when they auditioned new members with review panels who did not know the names of the candidates and could not see them. By focusing only on what matters — their musical talent — they were able to overcome unconscious biases.</p>
<p>How can we do that in startups? Some companies hide the names of candidates while resumes are reviewed, and some give tests or other assignments where candidates’ aptitudes for specific types of work can be evaluated, independent of their gender or background.</p>
<h2>Investing in diversity</h2>
<p>On the VC investment side, the parallel to hiring is selecting what type of leadership teams you want to invest in. By seeking out entrepreneurial teams with female managers and employees, you are likely to find more creative, more resilient startups.</p>
<p>It’s better to challenge and improve products during the development process, not after they launch. A diverse team gives you a better opportunity to see your target market accurately and understand the customer’s perspective. As an investor, you’ll get exactly what every investor wants by supporting more diverse teams: more financial reward for a given level of risk.</p>
<p>A healthy, diverse team will challenge old ideas and generate a wider variety of novel solutions. If you are investing in consumer-facing companies, you can’t afford to exclude women from leadership roles. Since women control the majority of spending decisions and an increasing amount of wealth, you’ll be improving your chances of success by investing in teams that include female decision-makers.</p>
<p>We should also look in the mirror. These principles would benefit the operations of venture capital firms, not just our portfolio companies. Staffing your VC firm with diverse talent helps broaden your perspective on where the next big idea may come from. By diversifying investment teams, we will counter unconscious bias and recognize great ideas no matter where they come from.</p>
<p>At Pegasus Tech Ventures, we strive to hire diverse employees. About 40% of decision-makers at Pegasus are women.</p>
<p>I don’t believe we should promote more female participation in startups and venture capital just because it is fair. Smart startup founders and investors should pursue their enlightened self-interest: Recruit and invest in female employees and leaders to improve your results.</p>
<p>By doing so, you’ll be establishing and supporting startups that are set up for long-term success. Better ideas, more innovation, higher revenue and long-term profitability will be your reward.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/improving-startup-results-through-female-leadership/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212843</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Masterworks raises $110M to sell fractional shares of physical art &#8212; not NFTs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/masterworks-raises-110m-to-push-fractional-shares-of-physical-art-not-nfts-into-investor-portfolios/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/masterworks-raises-110m-to-push-fractional-shares-of-physical-art-not-nfts-into-investor-portfolios/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 21:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Left Lane Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Masterworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valuation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As investors look to diversify their holding amid exceptionally top-heavy traditional asset markets, more tech-enabled platforms are popping up to make the case for their alternative investment platform of choice. Masterworks, a startup that sells fractionalized shares of paintings and other works by famous artists, has achieved a unicorn valuation as it looks to corner [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As investors look to diversify their holding amid exceptionally top-heavy traditional asset markets, more tech-enabled platforms are popping up to make the case for their alternative investment platform of choice. Masterworks, a startup that sells fractionalized shares of paintings and other works by famous artists, has achieved a unicorn valuation as it looks to corner the market on bringing fine art exposure into people&#8217;s portfolios.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.masterworks.io/">Masterworks</a> announced today that they&#8217;ve raised $110 million in Series A funding at a valuation north of $1 billion. The round was led by NYC-based venture fund Left Lane Capital, with participation from Galaxy Interactive and Tru Arrow Partners, among others.</p>
<p>Alternative assets have become big business in the past couple years as public markets have grown frothier and investors look to chase bigger returns in less traditional markets. The alternative asset class is a diverse one, and among markets for mint condition N64 cartridges, Pokémon Cards, Air Jordans and NFTs, fine art occupies a more traditional segment of the class and one with more predictable upside and downside.</p>
<p>&#8220;Art as an asset class is not a GameStop or an NFT, at the end of the day the returns are fairly predictable,&#8221; CEO Scott Lynn tells TechCrunch. &#8220;Investing in one of these paintings, you&#8217;re never going to earn 10 times your money, but you&#8217;re also probably never going to lose 90% of your money.&#8221;</p>
<p>As such, Masterworks isn&#8217;t a platform backing up-and-coming painters, they&#8217;re wholly investing in artists that have a proven market around the value of their work, Lynn says. &#8220;We really believe that the only investable segment of the art market are paintings [worth] a million dollars or more, generally speaking, and when I say investable, I mean something that produces predictable returns,&#8221; he tells us.</p>
<p>Masterworks buys and stores a number of paintings by famed contemporary artists like Andy Warhol, Keith Haring, Jean-Michel Basquiat and Yayoi Kusama, selling shares in qualified public offerings that are registered with the SEC, allowing investors to trade those shares on its secondary market once an offering closes. Shareholders get paid out when Masterworks eventually sells a painting. The startup makes money by selling those paintings at a profit, earning 20% of the profit each time a painting sells alongside a 1.5% per year management fee on each piece of artwork.</p>
<p>The startup is still chasing after investors with a fair amount of capital to invest, with Lynn noting that their average investor puts more than $5,000 into each painting they back, investing around $30,000 over their lifetime.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/masterworks-raises-110m-to-push-fractional-shares-of-physical-art-not-nfts-into-investor-portfolios/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212684</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: Palihapitiya on SPACs, inside Rivian&#8217;s IPO, BaaS pros talk shop</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/techcrunch-roundup-palihapitiya-on-spacs-inside-rivians-ipo-baas-pros-talk-shop/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/techcrunch-roundup-palihapitiya-on-spacs-inside-rivians-ipo-baas-pros-talk-shop/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 21:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chamath Palihapitiya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gene berdichevsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hana Mohan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harlem Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[informatica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reid Hoffman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPACs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have worked in startups for more than half of my life, and for most of that time, I was the only Black person in the room. As a result, the lack of representation in tech isn’t abstract to me. Besides my experience, I read and talk about diversity in tech every day, so when [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">I have worked in startups for more than half of my life, and for most of that time, I was the only Black person in the room. As a result, the lack of representation in tech isn’t abstract to me.</p>
<p>Besides my experience, I read and talk about diversity in tech every day, so when I was offered a chance to speak to three founders from underrepresented groups at TechCrunch Disrupt, I was eager for the opportunity.</p>
<p>I was joined by Hana Mohan, a transgender woman who is the CEO and co-founder of MagicBell; Leslie Feinzaig, a Latina entrepreneur who started the Female Founders Alliance; and Stephen Bailey, a Black man who is the founder and CEO of ExecOnline, an online leadership development platform.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription.</i></p>
<hr />
<p>Every entrepreneur swims against a current, but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/3-founders-share-strategies-for-navigating-bias-and-building-confidence/">these founders face challenges that their white, male counterparts do not</a>.</p>
<p>Each of them has cracked the code that grants access to capital and influential social networks, but I also wanted to learn about how they approached leadership and management, hear some of their strategies for building confidence and find out whether generic best practices for startup success applied to their lived experiences.</p>
<p>Thanks again to the panelists who joined me. We went slightly over our allotted time, but it was a candid discussion that uncovered some unique perspectives. I picked out some of the highlights for the recap, but there’s a video that captures the entire chat.</p>
<p>Have a great week, and thanks for reading TechCrunch+!</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="YCiQE7o7BI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/3-founders-share-strategies-for-navigating-bias-and-building-confidence/">3 founders share strategies for navigating bias and building confidence</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 founders share strategies for navigating bias and building confidence&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/3-founders-share-strategies-for-navigating-bias-and-building-confidence/embed/#?secret=YCiQE7o7BI" data-secret="YCiQE7o7BI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Where and when to spend your recently raised dollars</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2168991" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2168991" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2168991" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="651" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg 2172w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg?resize=768,488 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg?resize=680,432 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg?resize=1536,976 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg?resize=2048,1301 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1284113915.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2168991" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>PM Images / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Startups have lots of options when it comes to fundraising, with “ample capital, a focus on distributed investing [and] more first-check investors than ever before,” Natasha Mascarenhas writes.</p>
<p>At TechCrunch Disrupt, Harlem Capital’s Henri Pierre-Jacques and BBG Ventures’ Nisha Dua explained how founders should allocate recently raised dollars in today’s environment.</p>
<p>“It’s easier to raise and harder to spend these days, because there’s such a high demand for talent,” Dua said. “The answer for where to spend is going to be different for every company across many different industries.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rW8lcGZXyQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/where-and-when-to-spend-your-recently-raised-dollars/">Where and when to spend your recently raised dollars</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where and when to spend your recently raised dollars&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/where-and-when-to-spend-your-recently-raised-dollars/embed/#?secret=rW8lcGZXyQ" data-secret="rW8lcGZXyQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Battery chemistry company Sila’s founder Gene Berdichevsky on the science of scaling up</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2210210" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2210210" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2210210" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/gene.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2210210" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin</p></div></p>
<p>As part of an ongoing series of interviews with founders of transportation companies, Rebecca Bellan spoke to Sila Nano founder Gene Berdichevsky about his company’s efforts to build and scale the next generation of EV batteries.</p>
<p>“We want to be a world leader and do for the energy storage industry what Intel did for the personal computing industry,” he said.</p>
<p>“Intel didn’t make every single chip or the motherboards or the PCs. They made the most important components whose performance drove the adoption of the devices people actually wanted, and the better the microprocessor got, the better computers got, the more people used them and the more the world changed.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sdva3h13D1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/battery-chemistry-company-silas-founder-gene-berdichevsky-on-the-science-of-scaling-up/">Battery chemistry company Sila&#8217;s founder Gene Berdichevsky on the science of scaling up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Battery chemistry company Sila&#8217;s founder Gene Berdichevsky on the science of scaling up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/battery-chemistry-company-silas-founder-gene-berdichevsky-on-the-science-of-scaling-up/embed/#?secret=sdva3h13D1" data-secret="sdva3h13D1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What you should know about working with corporate venture investment committees</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2210659" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2210659" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2210659" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1195020064.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2210659" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=syolacan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">syolacan <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Most founders are exclusively focused on getting a check from a private VC firm, but in the first half of this year, corporate venture capital funding totaled $79 billion across 2,099 deals globally.</p>
<p>In a guest post for TechCrunch+, WIND Ventures’ Brian Walsh explains key differences between CVC and VC and shares his basic best practices for getting a “yes” out of a corporate investment committee.</p>
<p>It’s a different environment, but there are “great opportunities with this growing investor set,” he writes.</p>
<p>“By understanding the roles, processes and how to help get their deal through a CVC IC, all parties stand to benefit.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gu4lbDkh5B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/what-you-should-know-about-working-with-corporate-venture-investment-committees/">What you should know about working with corporate venture investment committees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What you should know about working with corporate venture investment committees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/what-you-should-know-about-working-with-corporate-venture-investment-committees/embed/#?secret=gu4lbDkh5B" data-secret="gu4lbDkh5B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Evil Geniuses CEO on the path toward esports ubiquity</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2207317" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2207317" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2207317" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1162013884.jpg" alt="Call of Duty World League Championship 2019" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1162013884.jpg 1392w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1162013884.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1162013884.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1162013884.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1162013884.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1162013884.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2207317" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> John McCoy / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The esports league Evil Geniuses (EG) was founded in 1999, but at TechCrunch Disrupt, CEO Nicole LaPointe Jameson told Lucas Matney that the industry is still in its infancy.</p>
<p>“Today, it’s a bit of a dance to bridge the understanding for some of the older generations that have negative perceptions of what gaming is, which often aren’t factually correct,” she said.</p>
<p>“I am a complete optimist around the younger generations — I don’t believe esports will be perceived as a niche sport for younger audiences.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="URdf83kMUd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/evil-geniuses-ceo-on-the-path-toward-esports-ubiquity/">Evil Geniuses CEO on the path toward esports ubiquity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Evil Geniuses CEO on the path toward esports ubiquity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/evil-geniuses-ceo-on-the-path-toward-esports-ubiquity/embed/#?secret=URdf83kMUd" data-secret="URdf83kMUd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Investors share how infrastructure as code is taking over DevOps</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2212084" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212084" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2212084" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-95469621.jpg" alt="Data center equipment: server racks and jumbles of ethernet cables" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-95469621.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-95469621.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-95469621.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-95469621.jpg?resize=768,511 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-95469621.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-95469621.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212084" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Erik+Isakson" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Erik Isakson <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>“Infrastructure as code (IaC) has been gaining wider adoption among DevOps teams in recent years, but the complexities of data center configuration and management continue to create problems — and opportunities,” Karan Bhasin writes.</p>
<p>He surveyed top investors in IaC startups to find out more:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sheila Gulati, managing director, Tola Capital</li>
<li>S. Somasegar, managing director, Madrona Venture Group</li>
<li>Aaron Jacobson, partner, New Enterprise Associates</li>
<li>Sri Pangulur, partner, Tribe Capital</li>
<li>Teddie Wardi, managing director, Insight Partners</li>
<li>Tim Tully, partner, Menlo Ventures</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LtMydKGmd3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/investors-share-how-infrastructure-as-code-is-taking-over-devops/">Investors share how infrastructure as code is taking over DevOps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors share how infrastructure as code is taking over DevOps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/investors-share-how-infrastructure-as-code-is-taking-over-devops/embed/#?secret=LtMydKGmd3" data-secret="LtMydKGmd3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Informatica’s IPO will test public markets’ appetite for slower-growing tech offerings</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2209873" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2209873" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2209873" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg" alt="A close-up on a data set of random binary numbers" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg 2309w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-805184148.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2209873" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> matejmo / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Six years after a PE firm took it private, Informatica filed to go public last week at a valuation reportedly as high as $10 billion.</p>
<p>“A number that big demands exploration,” declared Alex Wilhelm, who pored over the S-1 with great interest yesterday afternoon.</p>
<p>“If investors can get to a point where they consider that the company’s subscription revenues are set for long-term growth, a 7x multiple doesn’t seem too wild,” he writes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mZFFDX2221"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/informaticas-ipo-will-test-public-markets-appetite-for-slower-growing-tech-offerings/">Informatica&#8217;s IPO will test public markets&#8217; appetite for slower-growing tech offerings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Informatica&#8217;s IPO will test public markets&#8217; appetite for slower-growing tech offerings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/informaticas-ipo-will-test-public-markets-appetite-for-slower-growing-tech-offerings/embed/#?secret=mZFFDX2221" data-secret="mZFFDX2221" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Index, Sequoia and Canvas investors weigh in on how to raise your first dollars</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2211486" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211486" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2211486" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-168277426.jpg" alt="a paper boat with a dollar bill for a sail" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-168277426.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-168277426.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-168277426.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-168277426.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-168277426.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-168277426.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2211486" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=RapidEye" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RapidEye <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>“Founders seeking to raise their first round of capital may feel overwhelmed by the prospect,” Mary Ann Azevedo writes. “There is definitely plenty of capital out there, but there are also a lot of startups clamoring for it.”</p>
<p>At TechCrunch Disrupt, three investors unpacked this dilemma, sharing insider tips that will help entrepreneurs clarify their thinking, forge closer partnerships with investors and reset their expectations.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nina Achadijan, partner, Index Ventures</li>
<li>Rebecca Lynn, co-founder and general partner, Canvas Ventures</li>
<li>Luciana Lixandru, partner, Sequoia Capital</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OryETcNNNK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/index-sequoia-and-canvas-investors-weigh-in-on-how-to-raise-your-first-dollars/">Index, Sequoia and Canvas investors weigh in on how to raise your first dollars</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Index, Sequoia and Canvas investors weigh in on how to raise your first dollars&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/index-sequoia-and-canvas-investors-weigh-in-on-how-to-raise-your-first-dollars/embed/#?secret=OryETcNNNK" data-secret="OryETcNNNK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>As Apple messes with attribution, what does growth marketing look like in 2021?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2211848" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211848" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2211848" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235391605.jpg" alt="Apple logo is seen displayed on a phone screen in this illustration photo taken in Krakow, Poland on September 21, 2021. (Photo Illustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images)" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235391605.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235391605.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235391605.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235391605.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235391605.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235391605.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2211848" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;photographer=NurPhoto" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NurPhoto <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Apple rolled out app tracking transparency in April, giving users the ability to stop their phones from sharing data about their behavior.</p>
<p>More recently, changes in iOS 15 permitted consumers to opt into mail privacy protection and exert additional control over app permissions.</p>
<p>This is all great news for privacy-minded consumers, but for startups that live and die by their ability to measure growth and engagement, there’s confusion and uncertainty.</p>
<p>To learn more about how growth marketers are recalibrating data collection, Managing Editor Danny Crichton interviewed three experts at TechCrunch Disrupt:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jenifer Ho, VP marketing, Elation Health</li>
<li>Shoji Ueki, head of marketing and analytics, Point</li>
<li>Nik Sharma, owner, Sharma Brands</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o3Faa9HTCD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/as-apple-messes-with-attribution-what-does-growth-marketing-look-like-in-2021/">As Apple messes with attribution, what does growth marketing look like in 2021?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As Apple messes with attribution, what does growth marketing look like in 2021?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/as-apple-messes-with-attribution-what-does-growth-marketing-look-like-in-2021/embed/#?secret=o3Faa9HTCD" data-secret="o3Faa9HTCD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why and when startups should look to diverse sources of capital</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2211499" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211499" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2211499" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-86284305.jpg" alt="Man using metal detector at beach" width="1024" height="672" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-86284305.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-86284305.jpg?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-86284305.jpg?resize=300,197 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-86284305.jpg?resize=768,504 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-86284305.jpg?resize=680,446 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-86284305.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2211499" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Hill+Street+Studios" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hill Street Studios <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Is chasing venture capital the right choice for your startup, or are you doing it because it’s what’s expected?</p>
<p>“Venture capital is a popular source of capital for early-stage startups, but it’s definitely not the only one,” Mary Ann Azevedo writes. “Debt is an increasingly popular alternative, as is non-dilutive, revenue-based financing.”</p>
<p>She spoke with three experts at TechCrunch Disrupt to discuss the various ways companies can raise capital and which might be the best avenue for startups:</p>
<ul>
<li>Arun Mathew, partner, Accel</li>
<li>Michele Romanow, co-founder and president, Clearco</li>
<li>Harry Hurst, co-founder and co-CEO, Pipe</li>
</ul>
<p>“We’re very bullish about some of the categories that haven’t traditionally got as much funding,” said Romanow. “We just think that you should think about what you’re spending the money for, and maybe use cheaper capital for those repeatable expenses.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QRGxZSpdx4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/03/why-and-when-startups-should-look-to-diverse-sources-of-capital/">Why and when startups should look to diverse sources of capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why and when startups should look to diverse sources of capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/03/why-and-when-startups-should-look-to-diverse-sources-of-capital/embed/#?secret=QRGxZSpdx4" data-secret="QRGxZSpdx4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Chamath Palihapitiya speaks to SPAC concerns, from fees to disclosures to quality</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1716764" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1716764" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1716764" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="809" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg 3881w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg?resize=150,119 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg?resize=300,237 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg?resize=768,607 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg?resize=680,537 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg?resize=1536,1213 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg?resize=2048,1618 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/GettyImages-615650710.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1716764" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Michael Kovac / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Investor Chamath Palihapitiya has formed at least 10 special purpose acquisition companies so far: The New Yorker dubbed him the “Pied Piper of SPACs,” while Bloomberg crowned him “King of SPACs.”</p>
<p>Connie Loizos spoke to him at TechCrunch Disrupt about some of the downsides of SPAC financing that have given concern to many, such as corporate disclosures. “I think the big concern with SPACs is there’s a lot of pixie dust,” she said.</p>
<p>Palihapitiya’s response:</p>
<p>If you look at social media, there was Facebook, and then there [were] a bunch of other crappy social networks that went out of business. I think SPAC sponsorship will look the same way. I think there will be a handful of groups that prove consistently through their actions that they are doing a great job for investors, for disclosure, for regulators [and] for these companies…</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TGhBisqk5k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/chamath-palihapitiya-speaks-to-spac-concerns-from-fees-to-disclosures-to-quality/">Chamath Palihapitiya speaks to SPAC concerns, from fees to disclosures to quality</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chamath Palihapitiya speaks to SPAC concerns, from fees to disclosures to quality&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/chamath-palihapitiya-speaks-to-spac-concerns-from-fees-to-disclosures-to-quality/embed/#?secret=TGhBisqk5k" data-secret="TGhBisqk5k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>7 takeaways from Rivian’s IPO filing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2211586" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211586" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2211586" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg" alt="Rivian R1T electric trucks IPO" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/IMG_2396.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2211586" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kirsten Korosec</p></div></p>
<p>Transportation Editor Kirsten Korosec and Alex Wilhelm reviewed the IPO for electric vehicle company Rivian and shared seven takeaways.</p>
<p>Building an EV company is costly; so far the company has raised nearly $11 billion and employs around 8,000 people. And it’s just getting started.</p>
<p>Kirsten and Alex reviewed Rivian’s operating results going back to 2019 and found much to discuss — everything except revenue, that is.</p>
<p>It doesn’t exist because Rivian has essentially zero historical revenues to report; that of course makes sense because Rivian is just starting to deliver the first R1T trucks (revenue yay!) to customers. You can spy a dribble of income in the interest section, but that’s effectively it; Rivian has only made money thus far from simply having lots of cash, some of which generated a paltry return.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TrIHGLp0K2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/7-takeaways-from-rivians-ipo-filing/">7 takeaways from Rivian’s IPO filing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;7 takeaways from Rivian’s IPO filing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/7-takeaways-from-rivians-ipo-filing/embed/#?secret=TrIHGLp0K2" data-secret="TrIHGLp0K2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The first win: Getting early customers to take a chance with you</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2211388" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211388" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2211388" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1218827148.jpg" alt="Man walks towards a big number one symbol that lights up. He is surrounded by darkness, but walks on a path of sunshine reaching first place. Note: Digitally generated image." width="1024" height="551" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1218827148.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1218827148.jpg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1218827148.jpg?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1218827148.jpg?resize=768,414 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1218827148.jpg?resize=680,366 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1218827148.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2211388" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=mikkelwilliam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mikkelwilliam <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>There’s a reason why business owners frame the first dollar they earn: It recognizes their own effort, but it also pays tribute to the customer who decided to give them a chance.</p>
<p>“You may be looking ahead to raising some funds and trying to juggle the administrative aspects of running a business, but before all that, the purpose of your company is to sell your solution and generate revenue,” writes Ron Miller.</p>
<p>“But to do that requires customers, so how do you get someone to take a chance with you?”</p>
<p>To answer that question, he interviewed three industry veterans at TechCrunch Disrupt:</p>
<ul>
<li>Kate Taylor, head of customer experience, Notion</li>
<li>Pablo Viguera, co-CEO and co-founder, Belvo</li>
<li>Vineet Jain, CEO and co-founder, Egnyte</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qpu0bjBO6F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/the-first-win-getting-early-customers-to-take-a-chance-with-you/">The first win: Getting early customers to take a chance with you</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The first win: Getting early customers to take a chance with you&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/the-first-win-getting-early-customers-to-take-a-chance-with-you/embed/#?secret=qpu0bjBO6F" data-secret="qpu0bjBO6F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Reid Hoffman on the evolution of ‘blitzscaling’ amid the pandemic</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2199683" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199683" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2199683" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg" alt="Reid Hoffman" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg 2863w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-838037008.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199683" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kelly Sullivan/Getty Images for LinkedIn</p></div></p>
<p>Like many buzzwords in tech circles, “blitzscaling” has taken on a life of its own since it was coined by Greylock partner and LinkedIn co-founder Reid Hoffman.</p>
<p>“Blitzscaling itself isn’t the goal,” he clarified during TechCrunch Disrupt.</p>
<p>“Blitzscaling is being inefficient; it’s spending capital inefficiently and hiring inefficiently; it’s being uncertain about your business model; and those are not good things.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KRJQHvoDsZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/reid-hoffman-on-the-evolution-of-blitzscaling-amid-the-pandemic/">Reid Hoffman on the evolution of ‘blitzscaling’ amid the pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reid Hoffman on the evolution of ‘blitzscaling’ amid the pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/reid-hoffman-on-the-evolution-of-blitzscaling-amid-the-pandemic/embed/#?secret=KRJQHvoDsZ" data-secret="KRJQHvoDsZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>​​What a community means in the modern world of startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2211490" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2211490" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2211490" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1246919607.jpg" alt="Many different colored rubber ducks sit in wooden pigeon hole compartments. Concept image regarding different ethnicity/gender people living together in harmony together in the same social environment, getting along together, living side by side." width="1024" height="721" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1246919607.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1246919607.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1246919607.jpg?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1246919607.jpg?resize=768,541 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1246919607.jpg?resize=680,479 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1246919607.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2211490" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=enviromantic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">enviromantic <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>When I worked as a community manager, it quickly became apparent that each company I worked at had different ideas about what “community” meant.</p>
<p>Is it a function of customer service? Marketing? Should product teams work to promote it? What’s the best way to measure it?</p>
<p>“What, precisely, do we mean when we use the word ‘community’ in the world of startups?” Brian Heater asked the members of his TechCrunch Disrupt panel:</p>
<ul>
<li>Alex Angel, chief community officer, Commsor</li>
<li>Lolita Taub, corporate Development VP at Catalyte, co-founder and general partner, The Community Fund</li>
<li>Katelin Holloway, 776 founding partner</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iuotF3o0o1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/02/what-a-community-means-in-the-modern-world-of-startups/">What a community means in the modern world of startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What a community means in the modern world of startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/02/what-a-community-means-in-the-modern-world-of-startups/embed/#?secret=iuotF3o0o1" data-secret="iuotF3o0o1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Who needs a BaaS partner, anyway?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2210735" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2210735" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2210735" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1250588887.jpg" alt="Young woman hanging from large green currency symbol balloons against white background" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1250588887.jpg 1300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1250588887.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1250588887.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1250588887.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1250588887.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1250588887.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2210735" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Klaus+Vedfelt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Klaus Vedfelt <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Banking-as-a-service (BaaS) startups tap into banking infrastructure, which makes it easier for developers to create tools that facilitate payments and transfers. As Ryan Lawler noted recently, it’s never been easier to offer your own credit card.</p>
<p>To get a better understanding of the problem BaaS providers are trying to solve, Ryan spoke with several founders in this space, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unit CEO Itai Damti</li>
<li>Bond CEO Roy Ng</li>
<li>Synctera CEO Peter Hazlehurst</li>
</ul>
<p>“Unless you’re super deep in financial services already, the time and effort required to figure it out yourself is not worth it and you will never get a great deal,” Hazlehurst said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TKeb1H53Ch"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/who-needs-a-baas-partner-anyway/">Who needs a BaaS partner, anyway?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Who needs a BaaS partner, anyway?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/who-needs-a-baas-partner-anyway/embed/#?secret=TKeb1H53Ch" data-secret="TKeb1H53Ch" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/techcrunch-roundup-palihapitiya-on-spacs-inside-rivians-ipo-baas-pros-talk-shop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212810</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Distraction-free reading service Scroll is shutting down and becoming a feature of Twitter Blue</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-is-shutting-down-and-becoming-a-feature-of-twitter-blue/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-is-shutting-down-and-becoming-a-feature-of-twitter-blue/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 20:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter blue]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Distraction-free reading service Scroll will shut down in approximately 30 days and become a feature of Twitter Blue, Twitter confirmed in an email to TechCrunch. Twitter acquired Scroll in May and had said it planned to offer Scroll as a premium feature on its platform. Once Scroll shuts down as an independent service, it will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Distraction-free </span>reading service Scroll will shut down in approximately 30 days and become a feature of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/twitter-launches-its-premium-subscription-twitter-blue-initially-in-canada-and-australia/">Twitter Blue</a>, Twitter confirmed in an email to TechCrunch. Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/twitter-acquires-distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-to-beef-up-its-subscription-product/?guccounter=1">acquired Scroll in May</a> and had said it planned to offer Scroll as a premium feature on its platform. Once Scroll shuts down as an independent service, it will become &#8220;Ad-Free Articles&#8221; as part of Twitter Blue.</p>
<p>“Subscribe to Twitter Blue when available to continue to read fast-loading, ad-free articles, while supporting journalism on your favorite sites,” an email sent to current Scroll subscribers states.</p>
<p>Currently, Scroll offers paid subscribers ad-free browsing on numerous websites, including USA Today, Buzzfeed News, The Atlantic, The Verge and more for $5 a month. Using Scroll is similar to using a reader view, as ads, trackers and other website junk is stripped so readers can focus on the content. Part of the monthly subscription goes toward funding the content that subscribers read.</p>
<p>Once the two companies announced the acquisition, Scroll stopped accepting new subscribers and moved to private beta, as the team worked to integrate it into Twitter. As for current subscribers, it’s unknown when the service will be available on Twitter Blue and whether there will be a direct transition. The two companies are promising to provide more information in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Twitter previously noted that when subscribers use Scroll through Twitter, a portion of their subscription revenue will go to support the publishers and the writers creating the content. The social media giant had stated that premium subscribers would be able to use Scroll to easily read articles from news outlets and from Twitter’s own newsletters product, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">Revue</a>, another recent acquisition that’s already been integrated into Twitter.</p>
<p>It’s worth noting that Twitter Blue is currently only <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/twitter-launches-its-premium-subscription-twitter-blue-initially-in-canada-and-australia/">available in Canada and Australia</a>. The subscription gives Twitter users access to premium features, including tools to organize bookmarks and an “Undo Tweet” feature, which seems to be the closest thing Twitter will offer in relation to the long-requested “edit” button. Twitter Blue also comes with a reader mode feature, which Twitter previously noted isn’t related to its plans for Scroll. Although some may have expected something else for the feature, reader mode is more of an alternative to third-party apps like Thread Reader, as opposed to a more robust offering like Scroll.</p>
<p>In Canada and Australia, a Twitter Blue subscription currently costs $3.49 CAD or $4.49 AUD, respectively. It’s unknown if the price for Twitter Blue will increase with this upcoming integration.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/distraction-free-reading-service-scroll-is-shutting-down-and-becoming-a-feature-of-twitter-blue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212899</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen testifies before the Senate</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 20:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frances Haugen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news feed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidential election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Section 230]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the wall street journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yelp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After revealing her identity on Sunday night, Frances Haugen &#8212; the whistleblower who leaked controversial Facebook documents to The Wall Street Journal &#8212; testified before the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on Tuesday. Haugen&#8217;s testimony came after a hearing last week, when Facebook global head of Safety Antigone Davis was questioned about the company&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After revealing her identity on Sunday night, Frances Haugen &#8212; the whistleblower who leaked <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/seeking-to-respin-instagrams-toxicity-for-teens-facebook-publishes-annotated-slide-decks/">controversial</a> Facebook documents to The <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-instagram-is-toxic-for-teen-girls-company-documents-show-11631620739?mod=article_inline">Wall Street Journal</a> &#8212; testified before the Senate <a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</a> on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Haugen&#8217;s testimony came after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/">a hearing last week</a>, when Facebook global head of Safety Antigone Davis was questioned about the company&#8217;s negative impact on children and teens. Davis stuck to Facebook&#8217;s script, frustrating senators as she failed to answer questions directly. But Haugen, a former project manager on civic misinformation at Facebook, was predictably more forthcoming with information.</p>
<p>Haugen is an algorithm specialist, having served as a project manager at companies like Google, Pinterest and Yelp. While she was at Facebook, she addressed issues related to democracy, misinformation and counter-espionage.</p>
<p>&#8220;Having worked on four different types of social networks, I understand how complex and nuanced these problems are,&#8221; Haugen said in her opening statement. &#8220;However, the choices being made inside Facebook are disastrous &#8212; for our children, for our public safety, for our privacy and for our democracy &#8212; and that is why we must demand Facebook make changes.&#8221;</p>
<h2>The algorithm</h2>
<p>Throughout the hearing, Haugen made clear that she thinks that Facebook&#8217;s current algorithm, which rewards posts that generate meaningful social interactions (MSIs), is dangerous. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/11/facebook-time-well-spent/">Rolled out</a> in 2018, this news feed algorithm prioritizes interactions (such as comments and likes) from the people who Facebook thinks you&#8217;re closest to, like friends and family.</p>
<p>But as <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-algorithm-change-zuckerberg-11631654215">the documents leaked</a> by Haugen show, data scientists raised concerns that this system yielded &#8220;unhealthy side effects on important slices of public content, such as politics and news.&#8221;</p>
<p>Facebook also uses engagement-based ranking, in which an AI displays the content that it thinks will be most interesting to individual users. This means content that elicits stronger reactions from users will be prioritized, boosting misinformation, toxicity and violent content. Haugen said she thinks that chronological ranking would help mitigate these negative impacts.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve spent most of my career working on systems like engagement-based ranking. When I come to you and say these things, I&#8217;m basically damning 10 years of my own work,&#8221; Haugen said in the hearing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212778" style="width: 1986px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212778" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2212778 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg" alt="Committee Senators listen as former Facebook employee and whistleblower Frances Haugen (C) testifies before a Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation hearing on Capitol Hill, October 5, 2021, in Washington, DC." width="1976" height="1317" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg 1976w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/GettyImages-1235711855.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1976px) 100vw, 1976px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212778" class="wp-caption-text">Committee Senators listen as former Facebook employee and whistleblower Frances Haugen (center) testifies before a Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation hearing on Capitol Hill, October 5, 2021, in Washington, DC. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> DREW ANGERER/POOL/AFP via Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>As Haugen told &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=idalYO_c_ec">60 Minutes</a>&#8221; on Sunday night, she was part of a civic integrity committee that Facebook dissolved after the 2020 election. Facebook implemented safeguards to reduce misinformation ahead of the 2020 U.S. presidential election. After the election, it turned off those safeguards. But after the attacks on the U.S. Capitol on January 6, Facebook switched them back on again.</p>
<p>&#8220;Facebook changed those safety defaults in the run up to the election because they knew they were dangerous. Because they wanted that growth back after the election, they returned to their original defaults,&#8221; Haugen said. &#8220;I think that&#8217;s deeply problematic.&#8221;</p>
<p>Haugen said that Facebook is emphasizing a false choice &#8212; that they can either use their volatile algorithms and continue their rapid growth, or they can prioritize user safety and decline. But she thinks that adopting more safety measures, like oversight from academics, researchers and government agencies, could actually help Facebook&#8217;s bottom line.</p>
<p>&#8220;The thing I&#8217;m asking for is a move [away] from short-term-ism, which is what Facebook is run under today. It&#8217;s being led by metrics and not people,&#8221; Haugen said. &#8220;With appropriate oversight and some of these constraints, it&#8217;s possible that Facebook could actually be a much more profitable company five or 10 years down the road, because it wasn&#8217;t as toxic, and not as many people quit it.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Establishing government oversight</h2>
<p>When asked as a &#8220;thought experiment&#8221; what she would do if she were in CEO Mark Zuckerberg&#8217;s shoes, Haugen said she would establish policies about sharing information with oversight bodies including Congress; she would work with academics to make sure they have the information they need to conduct research about the platform; and that she would immediately implement the &#8220;soft interventions&#8221; that were identified to protect the integrity of the 2020 election. She suggested requiring users to click on a link before they share it, since other <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/24/twitter-read-before-retweet/">companies like Twitter</a> have found these interventions to reduce misinformation.</p>
<p>Haugen also added that she thinks Facebook as it&#8217;s currently structured can&#8217;t prevent the spread of vaccine misinformation, since the company is overly reliant on AI systems that Facebook itself says will likely never catch more than 10% to 20% of content.</p>
<p>Later on, Haugen told the committee that she &#8220;strongly encourages&#8221; reforming Section 230, a part of the United States Communications Decency Act that absolves social media platforms from being held liable for what their users post. Haugen thinks Section 230 should exempt decisions about algorithms, making it possible for companies to face legal consequences if their algorithms are found to cause harm.</p>
<p>&#8220;User-generated content is something companies have less control over. But they have 100% control over their algorithms,&#8221; Haugen said. &#8220;Facebook should not get a free pass on choices it makes to prioritize growth, virality and reactiveness over public safety.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sen. John Hickenlooper (D-CO) asked how Facebook&#8217;s bottom line would be impacted if the algorithm promoted safety. Haugen said that it would have an impact, because when users see more engaging content (even if it&#8217;s more enraging than engaging), they spend more time on the platform, yielding more ad dollars for Facebook. But she thinks the platform would still be profitable if it followed the steps she outlined for improving user safety.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0kuMZAFMFC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/">Facebook grilled in Senate hearing over teen mental health</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook grilled in Senate hearing over teen mental health&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/embed/#?secret=0kuMZAFMFC" data-secret="0kuMZAFMFC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>International security</h2>
<p>As <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-drug-cartels-human-traffickers-response-is-weak-documents-11631812953?mod=article_inline">reported</a> in one of The Wall Street Journal&#8217;s Facebook Files stories, Facebook employees flagged instances of the platform being used for violent crime overseas, but the company&#8217;s response was inadequate, according to the documents Haugen leaked.</p>
<p>Employees raised concerns, for example, about armed groups in Ethiopia using the platform to coordinate violent attacks against ethnic minorities. Since Facebook&#8217;s moderation practices are so dependent on artificial intelligence, that means that its AI needs to be able to function in every language and dialect that its <a href="https://investor.fb.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2021/Facebook-Reports-Second-Quarter-2021-Results/default.aspx">2.9 billion monthly active users</a> speak. According to the WSJ, Facebook&#8217;s AI systems don&#8217;t cover the majority of the languages spoken on the site. Haugen said that though only 9% of Facebook users speak English, 87% of the platform&#8217;s misinformation spending is devoted to English speakers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It seems that Facebook invests more in users who make the most money, even though the danger may not be evenly distributed based on profitability,&#8221; Haugen said. She added that she thinks Facebook&#8217;s consistent understaffing of the counter-espionage, information operations and counterterrorism teams is a national security threat, which she&#8217;s communicating with other parts of Congress about.</p>
<h2>The future of Facebook</h2>
<p>The members of the Senate committee indicated that they&#8217;re motivated to take action against Facebook, which is also in the midst of an antitrust lawsuit.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m actually against the breaking up of Facebook,&#8221; Haugen said. &#8220;If you split Facebook and Instagram apart, it&#8217;s likely that most advertising dollars will go to Instagram, and Facebook will continue to be this &#8216;Frankenstein&#8217; that is endangering lives around the world, only now there won&#8217;t be money to fund it.&#8221;</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">Read more on TechCrunch</h4>
		
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-whatsapp-instagram-return/">Facebook, WhatsApp and Instagram are slowly returning. Why did they disappear to begin with?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/zuckerberg-is-turning-trillion-dollar-facebook-into-a-metaverse-company-he-tells-investors/">Zuckerberg is turning trillion-dollar Facebook into a ‘metaverse’ company, he tells investors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/facebook-is-shook-asks-for-removal-of-ftc-chair-khan-from-antitrust-cases-against-it/">Facebook is shook, asks for removal of FTC Chair Khan from antitrust cases against it</a></li>
</ul>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>But critics argue that yesterday&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">six-hour Facebook outage</a> &#8212; unrelated to today&#8217;s hearing &#8212; showed the downside of one company having so much control, especially when platforms like WhatsApp are so integral to communication abroad.</p>
<p>In the meantime, lawmakers are drawing up legislation to promote safety on social media platforms for minors. Last week, Sen. Ed Markey (D-MA) announced that he would <a href="https://www.markey.senate.gov/news/press-releases/senators-markey-and-blumenthal-rep-castor-reintroduce-legislation-to-protect-children-and-teens-from-online-manipulation-and-harm">reintroduce</a> legislation with Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) called the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/3411/text">KIDS (Kids Internet Design and Safety) Act</a>, which seeks to create new protections for online users under 16. Today, Sen. John Thune (R-SD) brought up a bipartisan bill he introduced with three other committee members in 2019 called the <a href="https://www.thune.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/2019/11/thune-colleagues-introduce-bipartisan-bill-to-increase-internet-platform-transparency-and-provide-consumers-with-greater-control-over-digital-content">Filter Bubble Transparency Act</a>. This legislation would increase transparency by giving users the option to view content that&#8217;s not curated by a secret algorithm.</p>
<p>Sen. Blumenthal even suggested that Haugen come back for another hearing about her concerns that Facebook is a threat to national security. Though Facebook higher-ups <a href="https://twitter.com/andymstone/status/1445403468945055755">spoke against</a> Haugen during the hearing, policymakers seemed moved by her testimony.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0kuMZAFMFC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/">Facebook grilled in Senate hearing over teen mental health</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook grilled in Senate hearing over teen mental health&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/facebook-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-teen-mental-health/embed/#?secret=0kuMZAFMFC" data-secret="0kuMZAFMFC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-testifies-before-the-senate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding product-market fit, from the earliest stages through growth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/finding-product-market-fit-from-the-earliest-stages-through-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/finding-product-market-fit-from-the-earliest-stages-through-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 19:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heather Hartnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product market fit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three VCs shared their perspectives on what makes for good product-market fit, how to spot it and how to use it to your best advantage for both your business' growth and for raising capital.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At this year&#8217;s TechCrunch Disrupt, we assembled an all-star panel of venture capitalists working across the entire range of startup growth and got their insights on assessing product-market fit — a perennial and evergreen challenge for entrepreneurs at all levels of experience.</p>
<p>Human Ventures&#8217; Heather Hartnett, Greylock&#8217;s David Thacker, and Felicis&#8217; Victoria Treyger all shared their perspectives on what makes for good product-market fit, how to spot it and how to use it to your best advantage for both your business&#8217; growth and for raising capital.</p>
<h2>What to look for before there are even any metrics</h2>
<p>Product-market fit gets easier to assess the further along in the company development process you are; it&#8217;s a lot simpler to figure out if what you&#8217;re offering is what your users want once you actually have users. But what about before that?</p>
<p>Especially for first-time founders, assessing product-market fit at a stage where it&#8217;s mostly anticipation can be as much art as science, but our panelists provided some advice about how to set yourself up for success.</p>
<p>Hartnett:</p>
<blockquote><p>Our view of product-market fit is at the earliest, earliest stages, really at that point, you&#8217;re looking for metrics that are not even there yet, right? You&#8217;re looking for the earliest indicators that customers even want what your messaging and value prop is, and then you have a strong hypothesis about what that value is, and you have a strong hypothesis about how you can grow that value over time. And then it&#8217;s just a lot of experiments to figure out if you can even see some of those early indicators. You know, my father used to say, &#8220;You don&#8217;t have to tell a thirsty man that he needs water.&#8221; So we always just think about &#8220;What is that thing that you&#8217;re not trying to double sell?&#8221; But it&#8217;s the single sell that people really do want.</p></blockquote>
<p>Thacker added that while it may seem counterintuitive, it actually behooves entrepreneurs to raise as much money as possible on a concept in order to have the right resources from which to find and maximize product-market fit.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/finding-product-market-fit-from-the-earliest-stages-through-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211161</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This new platform is teaching emerging fund managers how to survive and thrive</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/this-new-platform-is-teaching-emerging-fund-managers-how-to-survive-and-thrive/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/this-new-platform-is-teaching-emerging-fund-managers-how-to-survive-and-thrive/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 19:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emerging manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fund management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lo toney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oper8r]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plexo capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More people have begun turning to venture investing as a full-time pursuit, only to discover that it&#8217;s not as easy as it looks. That realization explains the rise of Oper8r, a for-profit, venture-backed accelerator that launched last year as a kind of Y Combinator for emerging fund managers. It explains the broad appeal of AngelList, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">More people have begun turning to venture investing as a full-time pursuit, only to discover that it&#8217;s not as easy as it looks. That realization explains the rise of Oper8r, a for-profit, venture-backed accelerator that launched last year as a kind of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/29/y-combinator-for-emerging-fund-managers-oper8r/">Y Combinator for emerging fund managers</a>. It explains the broad appeal of AngelList, which handles a lot of the hassle of fund administration in exchange for a fee.</p>
<p>Now, <a href="https://plexocap.com/">Plexo Capital</a>, which is both a venture firm and an outfit that backs other venture funds, is taking the wraps off its own program to help educate investors on the many facets involved in everything from forming a fund, to raising capital, to properly managing those assets.</p>
<p>Called, <a href="https://gpx.plexocap.com/">GPx</a>, the program features an impressive number of free, educational modules that have been recorded by a long list of esteemed VCs and limited partners, including Charles Hudson of Precursor Ventures, Michael Seibel of Y Combinator and Beezer Clarkson of Sapphire Ventures. But the program is also organized around cohorts into which a select number of emerging fund managers is invited to work more closely with course instructors, service providers (like law firms) and subject matter experts.</p>
<p>Notably, GPx is a not-for-profit program but rather sponsored entirely by Alphabet (which is Plexo Capital&#8217;s anchor investor), City National Bank, Practical VC, and the global law firm Gunderson Dettmer. The presumed benefit to Plexo Capital is that it gives the firm better insight into managers it might want to fund, but to learn more, we caught up quickly yesterday with firm founder Lo Toney. Our chat has been edited lightly for length.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What&#8217;s the overarching objective here?</strong></p>
<p>LT: I would say our objective is to really add as much value as we can as an LP. When I started Plexo Capital, coming out GV [where Toney was an investor previously], I realized there were so many resources that we had there. I didn&#8217;t have to think about a lot of the back office because there were finance and legal and operations teams to handle all the things related to reporting and putting together docs for deals. Also, Alphabet is the sole LP of GV, so there wasn&#8217;t a need to fundraise. When I went out to start Plexo Capital, [it was eye-opening].</p>
<p><strong>What is the advantage to you in putting together this platform? Do you get a stake in the managers accepted into the cohort?</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>There are a couple of advantages that we take very seriously. Number one, we like to be aware of what&#8217;s happening in the market and this is a way to get another touch point with GPs to understand globally what their thoughts are about putting together a fund, and what&#8217;s the profile of folks [and] what types of opportunities are they targeting.</p>
<p>This is also a really good way for us to give back. For too long, the information required to make that transition from being a great investor to hanging one&#8217;s own shingle and becoming a great fund manager has been a little hidden. I was fortunate to have people like Georganne Perkins [a longtime former director of private equity at the Stanford Management Company] to really help me understand all of these nuances. But there is so much that&#8217;s not known. People really don&#8217;t know what they what they don&#8217;t know. There is no kind of comprehensive &#8220;VC Fund Management for Dummies&#8221; book.</p>
<p><strong>Are you an investor in these funds? Is that part of the deal?</strong></p>
<p>We have in some cases committed to some [of the funds] and in other cases, we have not. But there&#8217;s no cost, there&#8217;s nothing that we do to have any preferred economics.</p>
<p>The goal is to be able to create a community amongst the [cohort] to be able to kind of go through the modules on the website &#8212; the video content &#8212; at their own pace. Then with the cohort, we bring those folks in to go deeper on select topics like, for example, portfolio construction, or how to identify a family office, or how to put together a go-to-market strategy.  We also provide access to some of our professionals on the Plexo Capital team. Vishal [Tripathi], who&#8217;s our portfolio manager, works with the GPs on a one-on-one basis on portfolio construction. We have Kuji [Chahal] who runs investor relations for Plexo Capital, and he sits down with each GP and he helps put together a bespoke list of prospective LPs, then helps the GPs with the right approach to access those LPs.</p>
<p><strong>Do these have to be people working on their debut funds? Presumably there are a lot of people who are launching second funds who could also use some help.</strong></p>
<p>We just completed our first cohort where we had about 13 GPs from about 10 firms, and they are, for the most part, [working] on Fund One. We&#8217;d like to isolate this to folks who are emerging managers looking to do their first fund or fund two &#8212; that&#8217;s where our sweet spot is.</p>
<p>But whether it&#8217;s someone&#8217;s first fund or fifth fund, anyone that wants access to the open source content can go in and register for it. This is a journey. This isn&#8217;t a static process. I&#8217;m still learning myself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/this-new-platform-is-teaching-emerging-fund-managers-how-to-survive-and-thrive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212773</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Firefox Focus gets new logo, shortcuts, dark theme and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/firefox-focus-gets-new-logo-shortcuts-dark-theme-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/firefox-focus-gets-new-logo-shortcuts-dark-theme-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 19:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox focus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private browsing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mozilla has updated its privacy-centric mobile browser Firefox Focus with a new look, shortcuts and more privacy controls. Firefox Focus first launched in 2016 and basically offers private browsing mode by default. The browser now has new colors, a new logo and a dark theme. Mozilla also added a new shortcut feature to allow users [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mozilla has <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/news-from-firefox-focus-and-firefox-on-mobile/">updated its privacy-centric mobile</a> browser Firefox Focus with a new look, shortcuts and more privacy controls. Firefox Focus first <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/17/mozilla-launches-firefox-focus-a-private-web-browser-for-iphone/">launched in 2016</a> and basically offers private browsing mode by default. The browser now has new colors, a new logo and a dark theme. Mozilla also added a new shortcut feature to allow users to get to sites they frequently visit faster.</p>
<p>The latest update also brings a new shield icon that lets you quickly turn individual trackers on and off directly from the icon. Mozilla also added a new global counter that shows users all the trackers blocked for them. The company notes that this latest refresh aims to allow users to quickly complete searches without distractions or fears of being tracked.</p>
<p>As part of Cybersecurity Awareness Month, Mozilla is also adding new features on Firefox for Android. Users who create an account for any app can now also create and add a new password that can be saved directly in the browser to be used on both mobile and desktop.</p>
<p>Additionally, users can now autofill their password on their phone and use any password they’ve saved in the browser to log into any online account. Users who have a Firefox account will be able to sync all of their passwords across desktop and mobile devices. Mozilla now also lets users unlock accounts using their faces or fingerprints.</p>
<p>Mozilla also announced that Firefox will be available in the Windows store later this year after, as Microsoft has loosened restrictions that had banned third-party browsers from the store.</p>
<p>“We welcome the news that their store is now more open to companies and applications, including independent browsers like Firefox. We believe that a healthier internet is one where people have an opportunity to choose from a diverse range of browsers and browser engines,” the company said in <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/mozilla/news/news-from-firefox-focus-and-firefox-on-mobile/">a statement.</a></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/firefox-focus-gets-new-logo-shortcuts-dark-theme-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212845</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Telegram says it added 70M users during day of Facebook and WhatsApp outage</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/telegram-says-it-added-70m-users-while-facebook-and-whatsapp-were-down/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/telegram-says-it-added-70m-users-while-facebook-and-whatsapp-were-down/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 18:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s hours-long outage on Monday may have hurt the company, its founder, shareholders and many businesses that rely on the social juggernaut&#8217;s services. But for its instant messaging rivals, it was a very good day. Telegram founder and chief executive Pavel Durov said on Tuesday that his instant messaging app added a staggering 70 million [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/facebook-messenger-instagram-whatsapp-are-all-down/">hours-long outage on Monday</a> may have hurt the company, its founder, shareholders and many businesses that rely on the social juggernaut&#8217;s services. But for its instant messaging rivals, it was a very good day.</p>
<p>Telegram founder and chief executive Pavel Durov said on Tuesday that his instant messaging app added a staggering 70 million users yesterday in what he described as a &#8220;record increase in user registration and activity&#8221; for the service.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am proud of how our team handled the unprecedented growth because Telegram continued to work flawlessly for the vast majority of our users,&#8221; <a href="https://t.me/durov/170">wrote</a> Durov on his Telegram channel. But the day wasn&#8217;t so flawless.</p>
<p>&#8220;That said, some users in the Americas may have experienced slower speed than usual as millions of users from these continents rushed to sign up for Telegram at the same time,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Telegram, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/telegram-tops-1-billion-downloads/">recently topped 1 billion downloads</a>, had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/telegram-to-launch-an-ad-platform-as-it-approaches-500-million-users/">500 million monthly active users</a> as of early this year.</p>
<p>Signal, which competes with both Telegram and WhatsApp, also added new users. It said yesterday in a tweet that &#8220;millions of new users&#8221; had joined the app.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t the first time Telegram and Signal have gained at the expense of their chief rival. The two added millions of users earlier this year as well when WhatsApp was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/whatsapp-is-doing-fine-despite-months-long-backlash-over-policy-update/">struggling to explain</a> exactly what its new privacy policy entailed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The smallest of events helped trigger the largest of outcomes,” said Brian Acton, the executive chairman of Signal&#8217;s holding company, of WhatsApp&#8217;s debacle earlier this year, in an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/signal-brian-acton-talks-about-exploding-growth-monetization-and-whatsapp-data-sharing-outrage/">interview with TechCrunch</a>.</p>
<p><em>The headline was updated for clarity.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/telegram-says-it-added-70m-users-while-facebook-and-whatsapp-were-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212788</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple launches new coding guide for elementary school students</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/apple-launches-new-coding-guide-for-elementary-school-students/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/apple-launches-new-coding-guide-for-elementary-school-students/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 18:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Everyone Can Code]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple is rolling out several new resources for elementary school students, including a new &#8220;Everyone Can Code Early Learners&#8221; activity guide. The new guide extends Apple&#8217;s curriculum resources from kindergarten to college. This latest rollout is part of the tech giant’s Everyone Can Code initiative, which aims to help educators and families introduce coding to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple is rolling out <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-unveils-resources-for-elementary-school-coding-and-inclusive-app-design/">several new resources</a> for elementary school students, including a new &#8220;Everyone Can Code Early Learners&#8221; activity guide. The new guide extends Apple&#8217;s curriculum resources from kindergarten to college. This latest rollout is part of the tech giant’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/20/apple-expands-and-updates-its-everyone-can-code-program/">Everyone Can Code</a> initiative, which aims to help educators and families introduce coding to students early on.</p>
<p>“Coding and app design are essential literacies — these skills help students think critically and creatively, regardless of whether they go on to be app developers,” said Susan Prescott, Apple’s vice president of education and enterprise marketing, in a statement. “Apple now offers coding resources for learners from kindergarten to college and challenges them to design amazing apps that are inclusive and accessible to users.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Everyone Can Code Early Learners guide will allow students in kindergarten through third grade to build a foundation in core coding concepts through several subjects including music, art, science and physical education. For instance, Apple notes that students will learn about coding commands through dance moves. Another exercise will ask students to discuss calming techniques to allow for social-emotional learning.</p>
<p>Apple is also encouraging educators to try its new one-hour inclusive &#8220;App Design&#8221; activity session. The new lesson aims to help teachers guide their students to remember the importance of inclusion and accessibility when it comes to designing apps. The session essentially helps students think critically about how to build apps. The lesson will help students identify problems they’re passionate about and then plan solutions.</p>
<p>Apple is also adding support for a survey tool called &#8220;exit tickets&#8221; within its Schoolwork app. The tech giant notes that exit tickets are a way for educators to check in with students during or after class through questions aimed at gauging reactions and engagement. Teachers now also have the ability to create Schoolwork accounts for students more easily.</p>
<p>The Everyone Can Code Early Learners guide is available within the Swift Playgrounds app. The guide is launching in English, Dutch, French, German, Italian, Norwegian, Spanish and Swedish, with support for more languages to come. Apple has been expanding its Everyone Can Code program over the years and making it available for more ages. In 2019, Apple launched a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/20/apple-expands-and-updates-its-everyone-can-code-program/"> program called Everyone Can Code Puzzles</a>, which aims to help students experiment with concepts. Last year, the tech giant<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/09/apple-expands-its-free-coding-courses-and-materials-for-educators/"> launched Everyone Can Code Adventures,</a> a new program with more advanced activities.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/apple-launches-new-coding-guide-for-elementary-school-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212728</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The UAE aims to launch a probe to the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter in 2028</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/the-uae-aims-to-launch-a-probe-to-the-asteroid-belt-between-mars-and-jupiter-in-2028/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/the-uae-aims-to-launch-a-probe-to-the-asteroid-belt-between-mars-and-jupiter-in-2028/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UAE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UAE Space Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united arab emirates]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United Arab Emirates (UAE) Space Agency will be sending a probe to the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, with the aim of ultimately landing on an asteroid in the early 2030s, in a mission that will surely be a major boost for the country’s private sector space companies. The mission will launch in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The United Arab Emirates (UAE) Space Agency will be sending a probe to the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, with the aim of ultimately landing on an asteroid in the early 2030s, in a mission that will surely be a major boost for the country’s private sector space companies.</p>
<p>The mission will launch in 2028. From there the spacecraft will have a long and winding journey: It will travel 3.6 billion kilometers over five years, boomeranging around both Venus and Earth to build enough velocity to eventually arrive at the asteroid belt beyond Mars in 2030. The UAE aims to land the spacecraft on an asteroid in 2033 &#8212; an ambitious target for a country that only founded its space agency in 2014.</p>
<p>If successful, the UAE Space Agency would join a very small group &#8212; including NASA, the European Space Agency and Japan’s space agency JAXA &#8212; in landing a vehicle on a planetoid. The exact scientific goals of the mission will be announced next year, but any data the spacecraft collects could help deepen our understanding of the origins of the universe. That’s because asteroids are thought by some scientists to be celestial leftovers from when the solar system was formed.</p>
<p>This is the latest, and most ambitious, effort from the UAE, which has been aiming to boost its domestic space sector. Crucially, the UAE will give priority access to contracts and procurement to Emirari companies, which stand to benefit from the project.</p>
<p>Last year, the country launched the Emirates Mars Mission Hope probe, which went into orbit around Mars in February of this year. That probe will spend one Martian year (687 days) orbiting the red planet and collecting data about its atmosphere.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kXf02oYy2y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/uae-successfully-launches-mars-probe-aboard-japanese-h-iia-rocket/">UAE successfully launches Mars probe aboard Japanese H-IIA rocket</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UAE successfully launches Mars probe aboard Japanese H-IIA rocket&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/uae-successfully-launches-mars-probe-aboard-japanese-h-iia-rocket/embed/#?secret=kXf02oYy2y" data-secret="kXf02oYy2y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The UAE will also be sending a 22-pound lunar rover, dubbed Rashid, to the moon in 2022. That payload, which also includes tech from three private Canadian companies, will be delivered aboard Japanese space startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/japanese-space-company-ispace-aims-to-send-landers-to-the-moon/">ispace’s Hakuto-R lander</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sarah Al Amiri, chair of the UAE Space Agency, said this newest mission will be “in the order of five times more complex” than the mission to Mars. Among the new challenges will be “spacecraft design and engineering, interplanetary navigation and complex systems integration,” as well as higher performance requirements from the spacecraft’s communications, power and propulsion systems, the UAE said in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/the-uae-aims-to-launch-a-probe-to-the-asteroid-belt-between-mars-and-jupiter-in-2028/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212736</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>App agency Chop Dawg on helping startups build for the long term</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/app-agency-chop-dawg-on-helping-startups-build-for-the-long-term/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/app-agency-chop-dawg-on-helping-startups-build-for-the-long-term/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Software Consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile App Development Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2208580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chop Dawg describes itself as an app development agency, but these days that can mean helping startups build and scale software over many years. Founded in 2009 by Joshua Davidson when he was 16 years old, the Philadelphia-based company has worked on the launch of over 350 digital products to date. Clients range from big [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2212793" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212793" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg" alt="Joshua Davidson of Chop Dawg" width="1024" height="684" class="size-full wp-image-2212793" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/joshua-davidson-chop-dawg-full.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212793" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adobe Creative Jam | Philadelphia</p></div><br />
Chop Dawg describes itself as an app development agency, but these days that can mean helping startups build and scale software over many years. Founded in 2009 by Joshua Davidson when he was 16 years old, the Philadelphia-based company has worked on the launch of over 350 digital products to date. Clients range from big companies like Six Flags Great Adventure, to startups like SLAY, a fitness app by Mari Llewellyn, and nonprofits like Village Pledge, which is working to eliminate student-loan debt.</p>
<p>We sat down with Joshua to learn more about the company, why it does more than just software consulting, and how startups can best work with it, as part of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/who-are-the-best-software-development-consultants-for-startups/">our new series profiling great startup software consultants</a>. The answers aren&#8217;t as straightforward as you might think they would be, but Joshua walked us through a few different scenarios where it would make sense to reach out to them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best software consultants for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>What is <a href="https://chopdawg.com/">Chop Dawg</a> and how did you get started?</strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve been around since August of 2009. So, in dog years we&#8217;re pretty old. On paper, we are an app development agency, but we actually consider ourselves to be a technology-based company because we&#8217;ve really transcended beyond just traditional mobile apps and web apps. We call ourselves a technology company because we like to look at it, we are very agnostic anywhere that software could be, we try to build and cater for; which is really exciting and fun for us. In our case, we deal with really two types of audiences. So a huge segment of who we work with for are early-stage brand new startups and companies, and we help them bring their ideas to life and we do that all under one roof, but then we also work with existing companies that are typically not on a technical nature or missing a piece that requires a technical branch. In essence what we try to do is be like a Swiss Army knife so everything from, if you need everything from us we have that capability to if you just need us for design or if you just need us for programming.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Chop Dawg does more than just building programming — you do marketing and fundraising, you&#8217;ll help with and attract media attention. What led you to be more than just programming? </strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s almost like a civic duty. I think that&#8217;s the only way I can articulate it. For every technical entrepreneur trying to build a tech product in this day and age, there are 10 non-technical individuals trying to do the same thing. Except for lack of technical insight, there&#8217;s usually folks who are seasoned entrepreneurs or know what technology can do and how it can solve for your industry. Their expertise is missing. For example, right now we are working with a music producer who&#8217;s trying to solve a huge problem in his industry. He produces for some of the biggest artists on the planet. He can&#8217;t build an app, but he knows exactly what type of technology to use and how it could [be used] to disrupt an industry. So it was more than realizing, oh my goodness, there&#8217;s this huge segment that&#8217;s just not getting help. And if you put yourself in their shoes, well they&#8217;re going to reach out to the app agencies. Most organizations are focusing on expertise and knowledge, or just, &#8220;OK here&#8217;s a bill for what you want to do,&#8221; and we wanted to make sure when we started a company like this is our craft. We want to build things that are going to be successful for the long haul. If we can help you with every aspect of this, we&#8217;re going to increase your probability of success, and if we can make you more knowledgeable, we can increase your probability for success, and if we can act more as kind of like your outsourced CTO and technical team, we can take away an area that&#8217;s already a conceived liability for you.</p>
<p>For us it was like, this makes more sense of this approach. You know I&#8217;m not naive. We aren&#8217;t cheap because of the service we provide, we pay real people&#8217;s salaries, we have everything under one roof, but our job is to produce ROI. Make an asset that we scale for the long term and do it where someone is going to invest money, time and resources into it. You&#8217;re going to have the highest probability of success. It just came down to that kind of context. So I like to look at it like it just feels like our ethical or fiducial obligation. In the industry, there&#8217;s so much saturation, there&#8217;s so much competitiveness, and being around as long as we have, we have seen so many companies come and go. I think the reason we&#8217;ve had that longevity is just because we&#8217;ve always come in with a partnership first approach — but to be frank, we do that even when it&#8217;s not startups and early-stage companies, I just think there&#8217;s a huge knowledge gap and we have a lot of things we&#8217;ve learned — what to do, what not to do, and we can use that as an area of expertise to help folks we work with.</p>
<p><strong>What makes Chop Dawg unique?</strong></p>
<p>I think the biggest thing at this point is our track record itself. We&#8217;ve been around since the early days, and we have maintained relevancy. If you asked one of our partners, that’s what we call our clients, I think what they&#8217;re going to tell you is that longevity allows us to tell people not just what to do, but that we know why to do it that way, and how to be more pragmatic — save time, save energy, but also know what not to do. From being around so long, we&#8217;ve probably made every mistake you can possibly think of. Which is an advantage. Once you know that lesson, we can also help folks avoid that mistake. I think the third piece and this is more my personal bias that says this, more than anything, but I genuinely do believe it. We are industry agnostic, we&#8217;ve worked in almost every industry you can literally think of. I mean professional cuddling is really in our portfolio at this point. We&#8217;ve done it all. What&#8217;s cool is you start learning that there are trends and playbooks that work in different industries that can be brought to an industry not done before. It&#8217;s such a saturated market a lot of folks really are focusing on, and I just don&#8217;t think they focus with the right intention. For us, like I think most people on our team if they could work for free to do it for free would, but you know, the reality of living in a capitalist society. We come in with that, have a background like this is the craft level we do and we get to build things we&#8217;re proud of and work with people we really love working with.</p>
<p><strong>What trends are you seeing right now in the industry?</strong></p>
<p>I think the first thing is using AI. I think, as a user, we expect our products to just do things intuitively for us more than ever before. Social is in almost everything at this point. It&#8217;s crazy to think that we&#8217;re building social base functionality in even internal apps for organizations. There is not a single app I can think of that we&#8217;re building right now that doesn&#8217;t have some form of social element involved, which makes perfect sense to me as being social beings, making technology being an extension of ourselves and just more industry niche-based products at this point. One more trend of notice is that there&#8217;s a cliche in business called &#8220;riches in the niches,&#8221; but I think you&#8217;re really starting to see this now in the app world, where instead of one app eats the entire world, so to speak, there&#8217;s a lot more companies that are focusing on just owning a niche and being absolutely best at it and then having minimal competition — no competitors, things like that.</p>
<p><strong>Has the pandemic affected the trends that you&#8217;re seeing?</strong></p>
<p>The thing it has impacted is a lot of folks, who I feel like probably would have been a little bit more hesitant to go build apps and software, are now going in. I think it&#8217;s just jump=started the industry, like &#8220;Oh snap, we might never have a full office again,” our customer base or user base is less probable to come out, or they have a different type of learned behavior now because of a year living through Zoom and not leaving your home. So there is no direct trend as far as like, here&#8217;s these type of apps and software coming. I think the trend is more you&#8217;re seeing organizations and companies and ideas come out that maybe would have taken a couple more years to make that jump. While I can’t share who they are because of an NDA, I talked to a nonprofit yesterday, who, if it wasn&#8217;t for the pandemic, they would have never been entertaining, &#8220;we need to build an app that does X, Y and Z.” It’s a nonprofit. For them to talk about an app and saying we&#8217;re gonna invest 1,000s of dollars is pretty staggering. But I think that&#8217;s the pandemic, in a nutshell. Where it’s forcing folks to have a whole new playbook or approach that didn&#8217;t exist before.</p>
<p><strong>Have you seen a lot more companies, outsourcing their tech and getting more comfortable working with you since remote work has increased?</strong></p>
<p>There&#8217;s been a plethora of Fortune 500 companies who reached out to us. I&#8217;ve noticed some are companies who I think cut back at costs or were like, we&#8217;re gonna let go of our development department for this segment, let&#8217;s say it was React Native, but we still have React Native needs so we&#8217;ll begin offshoring it, or outsourcing it or finding a team for hire for a specific engagement. I think that&#8217;s definitely become a big thing.</p>
<p>Then I think what you&#8217;re seeing too is a lot of folks are realizing what a benefit agencies are. You know, there&#8217;s one thing I talk to partners all the time about and it’s there is merit to when you want to hire internally and grow a team in-house, but there are also times where having an agency — having a partner like that makes perfect sense too. For a lot of our partners, where it makes sense is that it&#8217;s pay as you go. If you don&#8217;t need us for a year, you&#8217;re not on the hook for multiple developer salaries, a project manager salary, a UI, UX designer salary, a QA salary. You can control your coffin. The liability is more on our shoulders at this point than it is on them; there&#8217;s always risk in business, to build a successful business, but if you made the wrong hires and you&#8217;re building a new company, or running a company — that is completely on you versus you hire an agency that falters, they&#8217;re legally liable to provide what is contracted and we&#8217;ve been obligated to do it right. So there&#8217;s also that perspective.</p>
<p>I think the third thing is you&#8217;re also seeing, more than ever, folks trying to get things done as quickly as possible. Where a benefit comes into more established agencies is when you have a methodology they&#8217;ll actually be quicker to move because you can jive and you have the resources, you have the process nailed down, you know what you&#8217;re doing versus when you&#8217;re building a team, rebuilding a team doing it internally, you still have to figure these things out too and figure out how to work well together. But again, there&#8217;s no such thing as absolutes. No way. When we talk to people, it comes down to what aligns with your business goals, objectives and, you know, like, I feel like agencies short term can be more expensive but long term saves you so much more money, and that comes from our position but, it comes down to what they&#8217;re trying to do and trying to accomplish.</p>
<div style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" data-tf-widget="MXehi2kl"></div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p>
<p><strong>At what point do you think is the best time for a startup to come and work with an agency?</strong></p>
<p>There&#8217;s different dynamics for it to make sense. I&#8217;ll give you a couple different examples because I don&#8217;t know if there is just one smoking gun to work with agencies.</p>
<p>There would be a situation like, I have very limited funds, funds to the point where I can&#8217;t go and even build a team internally or hire a major agency to build my own product, and I&#8217;m trying to get enough of proof of concept because I want to possibly fundraise with it, or I possibly want to go in front of potential users and get preorders or get interest, or I want to hedge my risk before I even build it. Well then maybe doing a non-functioning prototype where you design the app with an agency, start to finish. We don&#8217;t touch a line of code, we use a tool like Figma to create the illusion of a working app that can make a lot of sense because one, let&#8217;s say, God forbid you find out people are not interested or you can&#8217;t raise money off of it. It&#8217;s significantly better to find that out, spending the least amount of money than it is to go all in and go do something.</p>
<p>Then we also get folks all the time who will reach out to us and they&#8217;ll say, I&#8217;m interested in doing an MVP, minimum viable product, and working with an agency can actually make a lot of sense in that regard if that&#8217;s the context they have.</p>
<p>But I will say, I’ve turned down quite a few folks who reach out to us, even if they have the financials. One of the reasons is folks who might have the money, but you can clearly tell they haven&#8217;t put any effort into market research, understanding ideas and maturing the vision. The first thing I like to tell folks is you need to know that you are committing yourself to this thing; you&#8217;re building a business. This isn&#8217;t a hobby that you&#8217;re willing to make just the next five years of your life.</p>
<p>Then there are folks that reach out to you or they have an idea, but you can tell the idea is still not fully fleshed out. It&#8217;s almost like they came up with a key feature, but they haven&#8217;t fully well rounded it yet. So one of the things I encourage like, do you understand your market? Do you understand your competitors? Do you understand the logistics of running an app? Because even when you&#8217;re done with the agency [it] doesn&#8217;t mean your app cost is gone. There are servers, there are APIs, there&#8217;s a third party you may have to pay for marketing, customer support, legal insurance, like just all the logistics. Have you put proper follow through to understand it?</p>
<p>There are different contexts when people reach out to figure out what&#8217;s a good fit and it&#8217;s going to be, yes, you&#8217;re ready to make this investment versus again, I look at like like a fiduciary duty like, I get to do that; you might have the money but you&#8217;re gonna end up with an expensive toy.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not like &#8220;Field of Dreams,&#8221; &#8216;if you build it they will come,'&#8221; that&#8217;s not how it works. I think if you&#8217;re looking at the sign to work with agencies you have, I don&#8217;t want to say a business plan because frankly I never had a business plan, but you understand the industry you&#8217;re getting in, you understand a clear vision of what you&#8217;re doing, you understand the pragmatic approach of how you&#8217;re going to roll it out. You know who your customer base is going to be, how you&#8217;re going to get to them. You have an idea of what your cost is going to be to operate it, and you have an idea of projections on what it&#8217;s going to take to break even, become profitable, to scale for the big picture. And if not that, at least have an idea enough like, I want to go to fundraise, or I want to get preorders so I can fund it, like a strategy or even a non-functioning prototype can make sense to hedge your risk.</p>
<p>So it&#8217;s a mixture of those things and this, if in a given day I talked to five, six companies that reach out to us. I&#8217;d say three to four fall in the bucket of that they need to go back to the drawing board and really take more time and careful consideration. It kind of comes into going back to a question you asked earlier like &#8220;what makes us different?&#8221; I think because we&#8217;ve done this for so long, I learned a lesson early in my career. What happened when you try to fit a square peg in a round hole, like how disastrous that is even if everyone has the right intention. So it&#8217;s like finding the right fit. And to be frank, there&#8217;s even another question that comes out of this and what is the right agency partner for people too.</p>
<p>One thing I tell folks all the time is that we&#8217;re a remarkably collaborative company … our partners are meeting with us every single week. We are having Slack or real-time conversations during the week. They&#8217;re going to be putting in several hours a week to work with us, on top of what we&#8217;re doing, and they have to be ready for that and to be involved and be able to pay attention and be able to context switch. There&#8217;s a lot of things that happen, we even do orientation week before we start our project where we literally spend a week before the project begins training the partner on how to be the best partner possible, how to pay attention to understand everything. That&#8217;s definitely a big component in that regard. Companies reach out to us, or individuals, like I just need someone for the next three months to build this and come back and say, &#8220;Here you go.&#8221; That just doesn&#8217;t fit in our DNA. It&#8217;s not how we&#8217;re going to be successful. Or the approach we take from design and development QA might not align with the type of approach that they&#8217;re looking for. So, it doesn&#8217;t even mean these people are bad or it doesn&#8217;t mean they don&#8217;t have great ideas but this is part of even finding a good cultural fit from like a methodology perspective. Us as an organization, we&#8217;re a salary-based agency, so we don&#8217;t bill by our week or month, we really take the time to figure out in advance what we are doing. I&#8217;m a big believer in you should know exactly what it&#8217;s going to cost and take in time, and what&#8217;s needed for expectations setting to get that goal. I just think it&#8217;s a really big thing, ethically for us to do the right way. But again, these are all pieces, there&#8217;s not one solution out there that fits for everyone.</p>
<p><strong>What else should we know about Chop Dawg?</strong></p>
<p>I think the set rate is a big thing for our partners, just because everyone&#8217;s been in a situation, doesn&#8217;t matter if you&#8217;re in this business or not, where you&#8217;re halfway through your budget and you find out you&#8217;re not even a third of the way through the project. It&#8217;s kind of one of the worst things in the world. I personally never liked the weekly or monthly billing model because I feel like it incentivizes the service provider to take as long as possible, versus everyone having the same incentives; the same goal. Accountability was always a big thing to me as we created a culture and the DNA as an organization; everyone should be in the same alignment with the same goals, and then have the same transparency and goals and alignment within that.</p>
<p>As a company, we purposely are constantly just trying to be better and better at what we do. Even today, with my CEO hat on, I’m constantly like, &#8220;How can our process improve? What new technologies can we adapt? What do new design trends, technology trends can we be leveraging?&#8221; I think that&#8217;s probably one of the things I&#8217;m most proud of. The fact that we just have an amazing team that I know is like genuinely bought into helping people and it&#8217;s cool to see where once upon a time we started just need like, 50 plus people and you see them, build a career here, have families, have kids, buy a home, like have the company create something bigger than itself. I think the third thing is this constant quest. We always feel like although we&#8217;re great at what we do, there&#8217;s so much room for improvement. And how do you have that lens to constantly just reevaluate nonstop, how to be better, because I feel like that&#8217;s our, again, our fiduciary and ethical duty for who we work with and who we work for, to constantly push the envelope to just improve.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/app-agency-chop-dawg-on-helping-startups-build-for-the-long-term/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2208580</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Udemy files to go public on back of growing B2B incomes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/udemy-files-to-go-public-on-back-of-growing-b2b-incomes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/udemy-files-to-go-public-on-back-of-growing-b2b-incomes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rent the Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[udemy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If we only valued Udemy on its business revenues, at its final private-market valuation, it would be worth 4.5x its Q2 2021 ARR. That's incredibly cheap.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After digging into the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/what-rent-the-runways-ipo-filing-says-about-the-business-of-loaner-garments/">Rent the Runway IPO filing</a> this morning, we&#8217;re turning to Udemy.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001607939/000119312521291460/d163445ds1.htm">Udemy offering</a> comes in the wake of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/duolingo-boosts-ipo-price-target-in-boon-to-edtech-startups/">successful Duolingo IPO earlier this year</a>. And the company&#8217;s debut may prove to be the final major edtech IPO <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/04/indian-edtech-giant-byjus-valued-at-18-billion-in-new-funding/">ahead of Byju&#8217;s eventual debut</a> &#8212; how well Udemy performs in its public offering could impact others in its market, including some incredibly wealthy education technology players.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </strong></em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</strong></em></p>
<hr />
<p>So, how does the company&#8217;s growth profile appear after the pandemic-powered wave of demand for edtech has passed?</p>
<p>In the case of Udemy, we&#8217;re looking at an online learning service that raised north of $300 million while private. A $50 million Series F raised in late 2020 valued the company at a touch over $3.2 billion, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/udemy-series-f--dafd7d75">per Crunchbase data</a>.</p>
<p>For Lightbank, Insight Partners, Norwest Venture Partners, Mindrock Capital and Tencent, the company&#8217;s IPO is a material liquidity event; there&#8217;s lots of capital riding on its success.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995213 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>The edtech company is an interesting two-part business, with one piece of its operations aimed at consumers and the second at businesses. To understand how healthy Udemy is, we&#8217;ll have to dig into each half of its business model &#8212; we&#8217;ll also want to know what&#8217;s happening to the company&#8217;s aggregate revenue mix and which direction it&#8217;s leaning in recent quarters.</p>
<p>Sound like fun? I&#8217;m super stoked to get into this one. So, let&#8217;s.</p>
<h2>Udemy&#8217;s business through the pandemic</h2>
<p>From 2019 to 2020, Udemy grew from $276.3 million in revenue to $429.9 million, or 55.6%. That&#8217;s quite a lot for a company that has already reached material scale, or revenues of $100 million and above. More recently, in the first half of 2021, Udemy posted $250.6 million in total revenues, up 24.5% compared to H1 2020.</p>
<p>But we expected Udemy to grow more slowly after its pandemic bump, frankly, so to see the company&#8217;s revenue growth decline into 2021 is not a huge shock. How investors value a slower-growing &#8212; but larger and more profitable &#8212; edtech company will be interesting to watch.</p>
<p>Not that Udemy actually makes money. It does not. But it is losing less money over time:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212565" style="width: 923px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212565" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2212565 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-05-at-9.46.42-AM.png" alt="" width="913" height="394" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-05-at-9.46.42-AM.png 913w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-05-at-9.46.42-AM.png?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-05-at-9.46.42-AM.png?resize=300,129 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-05-at-9.46.42-AM.png?resize=768,331 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-05-at-9.46.42-AM.png?resize=680,293 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-05-at-9.46.42-AM.png?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 913px) 100vw, 913px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212565" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Udemy S-1</p></div></p>
<p>If you want to get a net income number excluding the cost of share-based compensation, you can deduct $20.6 million from its H1 2020 number and $16.5 million from its H1 2021 figure. The latter calculation will get you down to less than $13 million in losses during the first half of 2021 at Udemy. That&#8217;s far closer to profitability than the company has managed in prior periods, indicating that Udemy enjoyed some operating leverage during the pandemic, cutting losses while its revenues expanded.</p>
<h2>Revenue mix</h2>
<p>We&#8217;re going to break our general rule of not including marketing-friendly charts in our S-1 teardowns for the following exception:</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/udemy-files-to-go-public-on-back-of-growing-b2b-incomes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212548</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 founders share strategies for navigating bias and building confidence</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/3-founders-share-strategies-for-navigating-bias-and-building-confidence/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/3-founders-share-strategies-for-navigating-bias-and-building-confidence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity and inclusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 Impact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transgender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2211878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Entrepreneurs from underrepresented groups are more likely to face an uphill climb than their white, male counterparts, but their challenges stretch beyond systemic bias and lack of access to capital.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Entrepreneurs from underrepresented groups are more likely to face an uphill climb than their white, male counterparts, but their challenges stretch well beyond systemic bias and a general lack of access to capital.</p>
<p>Women, transgender and Black startup founders must navigate myriad issues for which there is no playbook: People of color may question how much of their authentic selves they can bring to the workplace, CEO moms are more likely to shoulder the majority of their family’s childcare responsibilities, and many workers have never been led by someone who’s gone through gender transitioning.</p>
<p>In a TechCrunch Disrupt Extra Crunch Stage panel titled &#8220;The Path for Underrepresented Founders,&#8221; I spoke with Hana Mohan, a transgender woman who is the CEO and co-founder of MagicBell, a notification platform for product teams; Leslie Feinzaig, a Latina entrepreneur who started the Female Founders Alliance; and Stephen Bailey, a Black man who is the founder and CEO of Exec Online, an online leadership development platform.</p>
<p>We went slightly over our allotted time; the conversation was a blend of frank talk about their lived experiences and practical discussion about some of the strategies that help them keep moving forward.</p>
<p>Despite their varied backgrounds, each panelist agreed that it’s important for founders who aren’t from privilege or wealth to understand and accept that systemic bias is real. And because Silicon Valley touts itself as a meritocracy, the gap between expectation and reality can create cognitive dissonance.</p>
<p>When Feinzaig was fundraising in 2017, &#8220;I expected that it would be hard. But I also expected that it would be fair,&#8221; she said. &#8220;And in reality, it was just kind of a gaslit experience. I felt like I was in this really dark room. And nobody would tell me how to turn on the lights.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mohan, whose company graduated Y Combinator’s Winter 2021 cohort, said pattern-recognition bias doesn’t just influence who investors decide to work with; it also informs how founders present themselves and their companies.</p>
<p>&#8220;White cis men, they tend to have a bravado about how they talk, this kind of exuberant, &#8216;we are going to crush the competition,'&#8221; she said. &#8220;I definitely felt that when I would sprinkle my pitch with some of those words, it definitely resonated more, like you have to communicate that excitement is naturally amply balanced.&#8221;<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/3-founders-share-strategies-for-navigating-bias-and-building-confidence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2211878</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Co-streaming rolls out to all creators on Facebook Gaming</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/co-streaming-rolls-out-to-all-creators-on-facebook-gaming/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/co-streaming-rolls-out-to-all-creators-on-facebook-gaming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Co-streaming is rolling out to all users on Facebook&#8217;s game-streaming platform Facebook Gaming. The feature will allow users to team up and stream with one another, while enabling viewers to navigate between co-streams and choose which perspective they&#8217;d like to see the action from. The feature had previously only been available to streamers in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Co-streaming is rolling out to all users on Facebook&#8217;s game-streaming platform Facebook Gaming. The feature will allow users to team up and stream with one another, while enabling viewers to navigate between co-streams and choose which perspective they&#8217;d like to see the action from.</p>
<p>The feature had previously only been available to streamers in the service&#8217;s partner program but is now seeing a wider release. The feature is currently limited to four co-streamers at one time.</p>
<p>&#8220;With co-streaming, we aim to increase discoverability for creators, encourage collaboration between creators and elevate the overall viewing experience for everyone,&#8221; a company blog post reads.</p>
<p>Facebook Gaming has been slowly bulking up its capabilities as it aims to grab a bigger slice of the game-streaming duopoly currently dominated by Alphabet&#8217;s YouTube Gaming and Amazon&#8217;s Twitch. It&#8217;s been doing a pretty solid job eating away at YouTube Gaming&#8217;s growth but Twitch still looms large in both hours streamed and hours watched. A big part of Facebook Gaming&#8217;s strategy for chipping away at that lead has been building out a substantial partner program of streamers with a close relationship to the company that are there to test and give feedback on new programs like co-streaming.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/co-streaming-rolls-out-to-all-creators-on-facebook-gaming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212276</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon is reportedly working on a smart fridge that tracks what&#8217;s inside</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/amazon-is-reportedly-working-on-a-smart-fridge-that-tracks-whats-inside/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/amazon-is-reportedly-working-on-a-smart-fridge-that-tracks-whats-inside/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 16:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212724</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon is reportedly aiming to bring some of the tech it uses at cashierless Amazon Go stores to a smart fridge that can monitor items and help order replacements if you're running low on something.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/imdbs-free-tv-service-arrives-in-the-uk/">IMDb&#8217;s free TV service arrives in the UK</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/27/beyond-meats-plant-based-chicken-tenders-are-coming-to-grocery-stores/">Beyond Meat&#8217;s plant-based &#8216;chicken&#8217; tenders are coming to grocery stores</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Amazon is reportedly aiming to bring some of the tech it uses at cashierless <a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/amazon%20go" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">Amazon Go</a> stores to your kitchen. According to <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-is-building-smart-fridge-that-monitors-your-buying-patterns-2021-10" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1"><em>Insider</em></a>, the company has been working on a smart fridge that can monitor items and help you order replacements if you&#8217;re running low on something.</p>
<p>The team behind the Amazon Go systems is said to be heading the charge on the project, which has been in the works for at least two years. The <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazons-just-walk-out-tech-comes-to-two-whole-foods-stores-101036042.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">Just Walk Out tech</a> used at Go stores tracks what shoppers put in their carts and automatically charges them when they leave. Members of the Amazon Fresh and Lab126 hardware teams are reportedly involved with the fridge project too.</p>
<div id="max-player-injector" class="vmmi-si" data-maxi="0">
<div class="vdb_player">
<div><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The fridge would monitor the items inside and keep tabs on your purchasing habits, according to the report. If you run low on something you buy frequently, the fridge would notify you and make it easier to order more from Whole Foods or Amazon Fresh, which could give the company&#8217;s grocery division a boost. The fridge could offer recipe suggestions too, which may prove useful if you forget about an item that&#8217;s about to expire.</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Amazon wouldn&#8217;t make the fridges itself, <em>Insider</em>&#8216;s sources said. It&#8217;s looking to team up with an appliance manufacturer. There&#8217;s a possibility that Alexa voice control could be included. That&#8217;s said to not be a major concern, but given Amazon&#8217;s propensity for stuffing Alexa into nearly every other type of product, including <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-astro-robot-165934602.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">home robots</a> and <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-fire-tv-2021-update-omni-fire-tv-4-series-130041393.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">its own TVs</a>, it wouldn&#8217;t be a surprise if the fridge has voice assistant support.</p>
<p>The company has reportedly spent upwards of $50 million per year on the project so far. Even so, there&#8217;s no guarantee that the fridge will come to market as it&#8217;s possible Amazon will shelve the plans. If the fridge does come to market, it likely won&#8217;t come cheap. An Amazon spokesperson told Engadget the company doesn&#8217;t comment “on rumors or speculation.”</p>
<p>The concept isn&#8217;t entirely new. In 2016, Samsung <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-01-04-samsung-family-hub-smart-fridge.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">revealed a fridge</a> that can help you keep track of what&#8217;s inside without having to open the door. You can even <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2016-01-08-samsung-family-hub-smart-fridge-hands-on.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">order groceries</a> using <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-01-07-samsung-updates-family-hub-smart-fridge-new-ui.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="26" data-v9y="1">the built-in touchscreen</a>. Amazon&#8217;s fridge would take the idea a little further, though, since it would flag items that you&#8217;re about to run out of and help you order more through the company&#8217;s own grocery ecosystem.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/amazon-smart-fridge-report-162623916.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/amazon-is-reportedly-working-on-a-smart-fridge-that-tracks-whats-inside/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212724</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here are the 23 companies pitching at Alchemist Accelerator&#8217;s Demo Day XXVIII today</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/here-are-the-23-companies-pitching-at-alchemist-accelerators-demo-day-xxviii-today/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/here-are-the-23-companies-pitching-at-alchemist-accelerators-demo-day-xxviii-today/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 16:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alchemist accelerator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2212668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s that time again! Today is the 28th Demo Day for Alchemist, an accelerator that primarily focuses on enterprise companies — or those that sell to other companies, primarily, rather than directly to consumers. This latest cohort comes in at 23 companies. Like the last few Alchemist batches, this one was entirely virtual — a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s that time again! Today is the 28th Demo Day for <a href="https://www.alchemistaccelerator.com/">Alchemist</a>, an accelerator that primarily focuses on enterprise companies — or those that sell to other companies, primarily, rather than directly to consumers.</p>
<p>This latest cohort comes in at 23 companies. Like the last few Alchemist batches, this one was entirely virtual — a move that Alchemist director Ravi Belani tells me has proven to work well, noting that attendance of their virtual demo day is &#8220;up 100%&#8221; over its in-person equivalent.</p>
<p>I hopped on a call with Belani, who gave me a rundown of what each company is working on and shared some updates on the accelerator itself. <strong>Some of those updates:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Alchemist has raised another $4 million in funds to invest, backed by NEC, Johnson Controls and Nornickel.</li>
<li>The accelerator (via its AlchemistX arm) is starting to build out regional programs, working with government organizations to help them figure out how to nurture local startups. The first programs will be launched in Canada, Japan and Korea. In Canada, for example, it&#8217;s working with Innovate Edmonton on an accelerator program <a href="https://innovateedmonton.com/community-safety-and-wellness-accelerator/">focused on community safety</a>.</li>
<li>Alchemist companies have now raised more than $1.7 billion in funding, collectively.</li>
</ul>
<p>Alchemist&#8217;s Demo Day <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TZoYHPX1qCs">will be streamed live later today</a> beginning at 10:30 AM Pacific.</p>
<p><strong>Meanwhile, here are the 23 companies in the order they&#8217;re expected to present:</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.codelock.it/">Codelock</a></strong>: An automated system that aims to prevent any unauthorized changes to your company&#8217;s application by signing and monitoring &#8220;every line of code&#8221;.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.creatify.art/">Creatify</a></strong>: A simplified platform for buying and selling NFTs, allowing creators to quickly put together a white-labeled NFT marketplace that plays friendly with multiple blockchains.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.engflow.com/">EngFlow</a></strong>: A system meant to help developers compile their code faster (5-10x faster, in their cited examples) by distributing the build process across multiple machines.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://speechki.io/">Speechki</a></strong>: A text-to-speech tool for creating audiobooks from synthetic voices. Allows publishers to choose from one of over 200 voices, and tweak the results (pacing, pauses, etc.) to their liking.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://mymoodbit.com/">Moodbit</a></strong>: An AI-powered system that aims to detect when employees are losing interest or becoming burned out, automatically suggesting &#8220;science-based nudges&#8221; to help.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.knowron.com/">Knowron</a></strong>: A virtual assistant built just for industrial service workers, allowing them to say something like &#8220;Why is this machine heating up?&#8221; and have it blast through said machine&#8217;s service manuals and offer up insights on what might be wrong. Also helps to flag things like which machines cause the most issues or slowdowns.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://11sight.com/">11Sight</a></strong>: Browser-based video/audio call widget that can be placed on your website to quickly connect potential customers with your sales team, then track leads and integrate that data into your CRM accordingly.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getbright.app/">The Bright App</a></strong>: An all in one platform for virtual personal trainers (weightlifting, yoga, dance, etc.), helping them to handle things like booking and payments. The company says they&#8217;ve already got more than 2,000 trainers onboarded.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://copyrightdelta.com/">Copyright Delta</a></strong>: A blockchain-based platform for verifying and managing who owns the rights to a piece of media.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.gaudium.ai/">Gaudium.AI</a></strong>: Generative AI for helping your social media team come up with new posts, generating unique copy within your specifications.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.arcturus.io/">Arcturus</a></strong>: A &#8220;climate data analytics&#8221; tool meant to help companies identify shortcomings in their sustainability plans, or help asset managers determine how climate change and new regulation will impact their portfolio.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.altcomm.co/">AltComm</a></strong>: An in-office tool meant to help patients with communication barriers more easily and accurately communicate with their doctors.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.ontrack-rehab.com/">OnTrack Rehab</a></strong>: An in-home training program meant to help seniors improve their balance and reduce falls. Evaluates their progress through 15-minute exercises four times a week.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.sensoryrobotics.com/">Sensory Robotics</a></strong>: A computer vision-based safety system for factories; using redundant 3D cameras, it watches for things like a robotic arm that&#8217;s about to collide with a human and adjusts its behavior (slowing, stopping or changing the path of the machine) accordingly.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://direktiv.io/#overview">Direktiv</a></strong>: It&#8217;s honestly a bit over my head, but Direktiv pitches itself as a platform-agnostic &#8220;event-driven serverless orchestration engine&#8221; in the cloud.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.embermed.com/"><strong>EMBER Medical</strong></a>: A telemedicine and doctor-visit booking platform built for the Middle East/North Africa. The company says it currently has over 900 doctors on the platform.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.simularge.com">Simularge</a></strong>: Creates a &#8220;digital twin&#8221; of a manufacturing line to help find inefficiencies and potential cost-reductions.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.fixtender.com/">Fixtender</a></strong>: A platform for those handling/overseeing bids on large construction projects, aiming to move the process out of e-mails/spreadsheets and into something much more contained and easily perusable.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2212694" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2212694" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2212694" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tensorfield.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="508" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tensorfield.jpg 990w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tensorfield.jpg?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tensorfield.jpg?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tensorfield.jpg?resize=768,573 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tensorfield.jpg?resize=680,508 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/tensorfield.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2212694" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tensorfield</p></div></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://tensorfield.ag/">Tensorfield Agriculture</a></strong>: Autonomous weed-killer robots for agriculture, using computer vision to identify weeds in crops and precisely spray them with heated vegetable oil to kill them.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://exovibe.com/">ExoVibe</a></strong>: a &#8220;digital ergonomics&#8221; platform that uses motion capture data to identify ergonomic risks in the workplace and, hopefully, prevent injury.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.freightify.com/">Freightify</a></strong>: Pitching itself as &#8220;Shopify for maritime freight&#8221;, Freightify gives freight forwarders an online store and the tools to handle it. We <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/freightify-lands-2-5m-to-make-rate-management-easier-for-freight-forwarders/">wrote about Freightify here.</a></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://esperbionics.com/">Esper Bionics</a></strong>: Building a prosthetic hand that they say &#8220;improves and gains abilities over time&#8221;, with machine learning-powered signal detection that helps it grow more accurate as the user wears it.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://qvalon.com/">QVALON</a></strong>: A cloud-based platform for retail store management, giving retail teams a place to communicate, track tasks, report issues and keep an eye on performance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/here-are-the-23-companies-pitching-at-alchemist-accelerators-demo-day-xxviii-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212668</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
