<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:53:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Self-driving truck startup Kodiak partnering with SK Group to expand into Asia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/self-driving-truck-startup-kodiak-partnering-with-sk-group-to-expand-into-asia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/self-driving-truck-startup-kodiak-partnering-with-sk-group-to-expand-into-asia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kodiak Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TuSimple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kodiak Robotics, the U.S.-based self-driving truck startup, is partnering with South Korean conglomerate SK to explore the possibility of deploying its autonomous vehicle technology in Asia. The ultimate aim of the partnership is to sell and distribute Kodiak&#8217;s self-driving technology in the region. Kodiak will examine how it can use SK&#8217;s products, components and technology [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Kodiak Robotics, the U.S.-based self-driving truck startup, is partnering with South Korean conglomerate SK to explore the possibility of deploying its autonomous vehicle technology in Asia.</p>
<p>The ultimate aim of the partnership is to sell and distribute Kodiak&#8217;s self-driving technology in the region. Kodiak will examine how it can use SK&#8217;s products, components and technology for its autonomous system, including artificial intelligence microprocessors and advanced emergency braking systems. Both companies have also agreed to work together to provide fleet management services for customers in Asia.</p>
<p>Kodiak co-founder and CEO Don Burnette couched the initial agreement as a first step towards a commercial enterprise in Asia.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;This is really just the first handful of steps to explore the possibility,&#8221; Burnette said. &#8220;What would it would look like to bring Kodiak&#8217;s AV technologies to Asian markets? What would be required? Who would be the partners? What are the regulatory forces that we have to contend with?&#8221;</p>
<p>Kodiak, which is based in Mountain View, Calif. and has operations in Texas, would be squaring off against at least two other self-driving companies — Plus and TuSimple — that already have a presence in the region. Both Plus and TuSimple announced mergers in the past six months with special purpose acquisition companies, an increasingly popular path for startup to go public.</p>
<p>While the partnership is at its earliest stage, it does connect Kodiak with a company that has a vast reach in South Korea as well as other countries in the region. The partnership is with SK Inc., a holding company of SK Group that has more than 120 operating companies, including ones connected to the logistics industry.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our partnership with Kodiak will help accelerate the commercialization of self-driving trucks in Asia,&#8221; said Jungho Shin, executive vice president of SK Inc. &#8220;Kodiak&#8217;s industry-leading technology and SK&#8217;s unrivaled reach in Korea and across Asia make this a natural partnership. We look forward to working with Kodiak to make autonomous trucking a reality around the globe.&#8221;</p>
<p>Burnette told TechCrunch the partnership agreement was reached after SK conducted an extensive technical review.</p>
<p>&#8220;They recognize the importance of AV technology broadly, they recognize the safety benefits, the economic benefits, and they want to play a role,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>This is Kodiak&#8217;s first international expansion. But it might not be the last. Burnette said the company has been interested in certain international markets since it launched in 2018.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve had conversations about the Australian market,&#8221; Burnette noted. &#8220;I think Australia is another great market with future potential for this AV technology, particularly the long-haul highway, out-in-the-middle-of-nowhere kind of driving. There&#8217;s South American markets. Brazil is a big one that&#8217;s interesting to us, and, of course, Europe.</p>
<p>This partnership with SK Inc. follows an announcement with the U.S. Air Force for a contract to bring autonomous transportation to the U.S. Department of Defense&#8217;s Dover Air Force base in Delaware.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/self-driving-truck-startup-kodiak-partnering-with-sk-group-to-expand-into-asia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157491</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram launches a new section for shopping product drops</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/instagram-launches-a-new-section-for-shopping-product-drops/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/instagram-launches-a-new-section-for-shopping-product-drops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flash sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram today announced it&#8217;s adding a new feature to help connect online shoppers to product drops through its app. Drops, which are a newer e-commerce trend, help sellers create buzz for forthcoming products in the days and weeks leading up to their availability. The products themselves are often only available in limited supplies or for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram today announced it&#8217;s adding a new feature to help connect online shoppers to product drops through its app. Drops, which are a newer e-commerce trend, help sellers create buzz for forthcoming products in the days and weeks leading up to their availability. The products themselves are often only available in limited supplies or for a short period of time, increasing demand.</p>
<p>On Instagram, drops will now have their <a href="https://www.instagram.com/_n/shopping_home?destination=drops">own destination</a> inside the app at the top of the Shop tab, where consumers can discover, browse and shop all the latest product launches as well as view upcoming launches. Shoppers can also sign up to receive reminders about products they&#8217;re interested in from here, and look through products and collections from other drops that recently took place on Instagram.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157687" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157687" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2157687" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9477.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157687" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> screenshot of Drops on Instagram</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Like other online shopping offered through Instagram, consumers can make their <a href="https://www.instagram.com/_n/shopping_home?destination=drops">Drops</a> purchases directly in the Instagram app itself via Checkout on Instagram, not by visiting third-party websites. This model will eventually allow Instagram to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/help/223030991929920?id=533228987210412">collect fees</a> on purchases &#8212; something that&#8217;s become a more important part of Facebook and Instagram&#8217;s overall business model in the wake of Apple&#8217;s privacy crackdown on iOS apps that <a href="https://www.adexchanger.com/mobile/facebook-could-take-a-multibillion-revenue-hit-from-apples-idfa-changes/">impacts</a> Facebook&#8217;s ad revenues.</p>
<p>However, Instagram has temporarily waived its selling fees to both help businesses who are recovering from the last year of Covid. The move will also help it to gain ground in online shopping against new competitors, including TikTok.</p>
<p>Brands on Instagram had already been running drops before today, following Instagram&#8217;s release of a product reminders feature <a href="https://business.instagram.com/blog/new-testing-product-launches-for-instagram-shopping">back in 2019</a> that allowed consumers to get notified when an item they were interested in became available for purchase. To date, brands across fashion, beauty, streetwear and others have leveraged the feature, the company says, including <a href="https://www.instagram.com/hillhouse">Hill House Home</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/dragunbeauty">Dragun Beauty</a>, adidas, and others.</p>
<p>The new Drops location simply organizes the product launches in one place to make it easier to browse and shop. Instagram tells us it&#8217;s curating the featured drops in this section. To be considered, brands need to use the product launch feature which is available to businesses on Checkout with Instagram.</p>
<p>At launch, some of the drops available include today&#8217;s <a href="https://www.instagram.com/officialnocta/">Drake x NOCTA ‘Cardinal Stock’ collection</a> and upcoming drops like <a href="https://www.instagram.com/wrenandglory">Wren + Glory</a> hand-painted summer collection and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/ctilburymakeup">Charlotte Tilbury</a> Exclusive Pillow Talk Lips &amp; Dreams Lashes Kit. This week, there are five total drops available. This number will vary from week to week as Instagram continues to test the new feature, the company tells us.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157689" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157689" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2157689" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IMG_9478.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157689" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> screenshot of Drops on Instagram</p></div></p>
<p>On an individual brand&#8217;s page inside Drops, consumers can view info like when the product became available, pricing, and other item details. They can also bookmark the item to add it to a wishlist or share the drop with a friend through Instagram&#8217;s direct messaging feature. From the top of the Drops page, users can return to their Cart or Wishlist at any time to complete the checkout &#8212; assuming they aren&#8217;t too late, of course.</p>
<p>In addition, the brand&#8217;s Live shopping can be scheduled to align with their product drop. When the brand goes live for a drop, there&#8217;s an on-screen countdown and confetti animation when the product becomes available.</p>
<p>The new feature is currently only available in the Instagram app in the U.S., and only on mobile devices (iOS and Android), not the web.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/instagram-launches-a-new-section-for-shopping-product-drops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157670</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flywire&#8217;s flotation suggests the IPO slowdown is behind us</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/flywires-flotation-suggests-the-ipo-slowdown-is-behind-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/flywires-flotation-suggests-the-ipo-slowdown-is-behind-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FlyWire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157616</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Flywire IPO is neat from a financial perspective and notable in that it's a Boston exit as opposed to yet another New York or San Francisco-based flotation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Boston-based payment processor Flywire <a href="https://ir.flywire.com/news-releases/news-release-details/flywire-announces-pricing-initial-public-offering">announced</a> its IPO pricing last night. The company sold 10.44 million shares at $24 per share, the upper limit of its $22 to $24 per share price range. At that share count and price, Flywire&#8217;s gross IPO proceeds stood at $250.6 million.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.renaissancecapital.com/IPO-Center/News/82076/Payment-processor-Flywire-prices-IPO-at-$24-the-high-end-of-the-range">Renaissance Capital pegs</a> the company&#8217;s fully diluted valuation at $2.8 billion. Using a simple share count, the company is worth $2.40 billion at its IPO price.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money.  </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>The Flywire IPO is neat from a financial perspective and notable in that it&#8217;s a Boston exit as opposed to yet another New York or San Francisco-based flotation. It&#8217;s nice to see some other cities put points on the board.</p>
<p>But more than that, this IPO is a useful measuring stick for keeping tabs on the IPO market as a whole. This year and the last are shaping up to be key exit periods for startups and unicorns of all shapes and sizes; many a venture capital fund return rests on these public debuts.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/flywires-flotation-suggests-the-ipo-slowdown-is-behind-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157616</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cataclysms are a growth industry</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/cataclysms-are-a-growth-industry/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/cataclysms-are-a-growth-industry/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[911]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cornea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disaster tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gridware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perimeter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. For this week’s deep dive, Alex and Natasha dug into Danny&#8217;s latest mega-project: A long, fascinating, and deeply-reported series into the world of disaster tech. It&#8217;s all about the market, startups, and their backers, so it was perfect fare for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/512d3529-18ef-4d2b-8b75-044d5b018779?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>For this week’s deep dive, <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> dug into <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny&#8217;s</a> latest mega-project: A long, fascinating, and deeply-reported series into the world of disaster tech. It&#8217;s all about the market, startups, and their backers, so it was perfect fare for our Wednesday episode, in which we dive deep into a single topic.</p>
<p><strong>Part 1: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/01/the-most-disastrous-sales-cycle-in-the-world/">The most disastrous sales cycle in the world</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Part 2: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/data-was-the-new-oil-until-the-oil-caught-fire/">Data was the new oil, until the oil caught fire</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Part 3<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/08/when-the-earth-is-gone-at-least-the-internet-will-still-be-working/">: When the Earth is gone, at least the internet will still be working</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Part 4: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/the-human-focused-startups-of-the-hellfire/">The human-focused startups of the hellfire</a></strong></p>
<p>We were super curious why Danny had picked disaster tech to niche into, as we hadn&#8217;t heard that much about it, frankly. But past the fact that it&#8217;s a world where <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/01/the-most-disastrous-sales-cycle-in-the-world/">sales cycles can last as long as House Congressional tenures</a>, there was quite a lot to get into:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Consumer: </strong>Dorothy wants to to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/dorothy-is-a-startup-that-offers-faster-cash-post-disaster/">provide bridge loans to folks who get rekt by a hurricane</a>. As government, and insurance money can take ages to arrive, the startup could be onto something. and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/when-wildfires-rage-close-perimeter-wants-to-tell-you-where-to-go/">Perimeter wants</a> to take data, and help folks actually know where to go when there is am emergency.</li>
<li><strong>Data:</strong> Danny&#8217;s deep dive into the world of data in the disaster space <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/data-was-the-new-oil-until-the-oil-caught-fire/">came with a provocative headline</a>, but the market backs him up. In this space we took a look at Cornea, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/cornea-eyes-in-on-fighting-wildfires-using-better-data/">just raised $15 million to help firefighters better understand conflagrations</a>, and Gridware <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/gridware-is-building-early-detection-sensors-for-power-grid-failures-and-wildfires/">raised $5.3 million to install boxes on power lines</a>. Very smart boxes, we should add.</li>
<li><strong>Mental health: </strong>We end with a riff on how companies are preparing humans to better handle disaster before and after it strikes. <a href="https://www.altoneuroscience.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alto Neuroscience</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is a stealthy startup founded by</span><a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/amit-etkin"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Amit Etkin</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, is looking to solve PTSD with brain-wave data, while </span><a href="https://www.neuroflow.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NeuroFlow</span></a> uses polling, and savvy collabs with practitioners to monitor emerging symptoms. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Psychedelic therapeutics also might have some opportunity to shine thanks to </span><a href="https://osmind.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Osmind.</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p>The series was fun to mine through, and expect Danny&#8217;s byline to be all over the topic in the coming weeks. Talk soon, unless &#8211; actually especially, if &#8211; all of hell breaks loose!</p>
<p><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/cataclysms-are-a-growth-industry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Treet, with $2.8 million in seed funding, gets brands involved in the resale market</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/treet-with-2-8-million-in-seed-funding-gets-brands-involved-in-the-resale-market/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/treet-with-2-8-million-in-seed-funding-gets-brands-involved-in-the-resale-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[treet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Treet, a company rethinking the resale retail market, announced the close of a $2.8 million seed round today. The financing comes from Bling Capital, Matchstick Ventures, Techstars, BABM Ventures, BBG Ventures, Green Meadow, Interlace Ventures, V1.VC, and Alante Capital. Despite the fact that selling old clothes is the most sustainable, and most financially beneficial way [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.treet.co/">Treet</a>, a company rethinking the resale retail market, announced the close of a $2.8 million seed round today. The financing comes from Bling Capital, Matchstick Ventures, Techstars, BABM Ventures, BBG Ventures, Green Meadow, Interlace Ventures, V1.VC, and Alante Capital.</p>
<p>Despite the fact that selling old clothes is the most sustainable, and most financially beneficial way to dispose of them, the process can be super tedious for both sellers and buyers.</p>
<p>Treet&#8217;s approach to simplifying its market and lowering consumer friction is to go through brands. Essentially, Treet helps brands set up their own resale sites where buyers and sellers can list and find items. Because Treet is tied in with the brand itself, sellers can easily list their items based on SKU and buyers can trust that the items they&#8217;re browsing are the real deal.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For brands, they get the chance to own their secondhand market and potentially gain new customers. The company says that 30 percent of buyers on Treet haven&#8217;t purchased directly from the brand before.</p>
<p>Involving brands benefits Treet in a big way, too. Brands are best positioned to know who has their items, and can send emails and messaging encouraging resale through Treet. They also have the distribution to put potential customers on to the resale site.</p>
<p>Treet gives sellers two options to redeem their funds. If they choose cash, a ten percent cut goes to the brand and a ten percent cut goes to Treet. If they choose to redeem via brand credit, only Treet takes 10 percent.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s customer list currently includes Boyish, Coclico, Altar, and époque évolution, with Goodfair and Birdy Grey launching soon.</p>
<p>&#8220;The greatest challenge is brands being hesitant about getting into resale,&#8221; said cofounder and CEO Jake Disraeli. &#8220;For a brand, promoting a used item with lesser margins is kind of a scary thought. We&#8217;re starting to prove out that they can expand their potential customer base and give brands the chance to participate alongside their customers who are reselling items on third-party platforms anyway.&#8221;</p>
<p>The clothing and fashion startup market has been active in recent quarters. The Real Real <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/23/luxury-consignment-e-tailer-the-realreal-to-enter-the-unicorn-club-with-new-funding/">went public back in 2019</a>, Poshmark <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/18/unpacking-poshmarks-ipo-filing/">went public last year</a>, while fellow resale company ThreadUp <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/unraveling-thredups-ipo-filing-slow-growth-but-a-shifting-business-model/">held an IPO this year</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-fashion-portal-lyst-raises-85m-in-a-pre-ipo-round-reportedly-at-a-500m-valuation/">UK-based Lyst raised $85 million the other week</a>. Treet&#8217;s funding fits neatly into the theme.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/treet-with-2-8-million-in-seed-funding-gets-brands-involved-in-the-resale-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157620</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Parametrix Insurance raises $17.5 million to offer cloud downtime insurance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/parametrix-insurance-raises-17-5-million-to-offer-cloud-downtime-insurance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/parametrix-insurance-raises-17-5-million-to-offer-cloud-downtime-insurance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FirstMark Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Insurtech is picking up steam in a big way, but startup Parametrix thinks there is still plenty of room left to innovate. The company, which today announced the close of a $17.5 million funding round, offers insurance policies for companies who rely on third-party cloud providers, ecommerce services, payment gateways and CRM systems. In essence, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Insurtech is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/as-next-insurance-makes-its-first-acquisition-insurtech-looks-energetic/">picking up steam in a big way</a>, but startup <a href="https://parametrixinsurance.com/">Parametrix</a> thinks there is still plenty of room left to innovate. The company, which today announced the close of a $17.5 million funding round, offers insurance policies for companies who rely on third-party cloud providers, ecommerce services, payment gateways and CRM systems.</p>
<p>In essence, downtime from one of these services can cost a company millions in revenue, but it&#8217;s completely out of their control. A fact of life, one might say, until Parametrix.</p>
<p>Parametrix approaches this problem in two key ways.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The first is that the company has developed a system that continuously monitors third-party IT services all over the world, giving the startup a direct view into service interruptions down to the millisecond. This system is also aware of the interdependent nature of many of these services and incorporates that into the precision monitoring.</p>
<p>The second differentiator is its pricing model, which uses millions of data points to help customers estimate the financial risk involved with downtime and lets them customize the payout per hour of downtime. The model spits out a premium based on that payout rate.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve all felt the pain of downtime,&#8221; said co-founder and CTO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/netarozy?originalSubdomain=il">Neta Rozy</a>. &#8220;When any part of the infrastructure goes down, the companies go down as well. Normally, when you have a pain caused by technology, you try to fix it with technology. Downtime is inevitable. It doesn&#8217;t matter how great your infrastructure is or how redundant your platform is and there are almost always direct financial losses.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jyFlKkxtyr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/insurtech-startups-are-leveraging-rapid-growth-to-raise-big-money/">Insurtech startups are leveraging rapid growth to raise big money</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurtech startups are leveraging rapid growth to raise big money&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/insurtech-startups-are-leveraging-rapid-growth-to-raise-big-money/embed/#?secret=jyFlKkxtyr" data-secret="jyFlKkxtyr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The combination of the pricing model and monitoring system means that this product that looks very different from the insurance policies we&#8217;re used to in another key way. Parametrix is named for the parametric model it uses. Essentially, if the insurer event happens, the customer gets compensation immediately, with no claim process and no proof of loss.</p>
<p>Parametrix is not a carrier itself, but rather partners with incumbent insurance carriers to payout customers. As you can imagine, when it rains it pours for something like downtime insurance, where infrastructure downtime could affect many policy holders at once.</p>
<p>The Parametrix team is 30 people, and gender diversity is split down the middle across the entire team, including upper management and the founding team.</p>
<p>FirstMark Capital and F2 Venture Capital led this new $17.5 million funding round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/parametrix-insurance-raises-17-5-million-to-offer-cloud-downtime-insurance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157590</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zoom fatigue no more: Rewatch raises $20M to index, transcribe and store enterprise video content</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/zoom-fatigue-no-more-rewatch-raises-20m-to-index-transcribe-and-store-enterprise-video-content/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/zoom-fatigue-no-more-rewatch-raises-20m-to-index-transcribe-and-store-enterprise-video-content/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rewatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video calls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video conferencing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We don&#8217;t hear as much these days about &#8220;Zoom fatigue&#8221; as we did in the first months after the Covid-19 pandemic kicked off last year, but what&#8217;s less clear is whether people became more tolerant to the medium, or if they&#8217;d found ways of coping with it better, or if they were hopeful that tools [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We don&#8217;t hear as much these days about &#8220;Zoom fatigue&#8221; as we did in the first months after the Covid-19 pandemic kicked off last year, but what&#8217;s less clear is whether people became more tolerant to the medium, or if they&#8217;d found ways of coping with it better, or if they were hopeful that tools for coping would soon be around the corner.</p>
<p>Today, a startup that has come up with a solution to handling all that video is announcing some funding to grow, on the understanding that whatever people are doing with video today, there will be a lot more video to handle in the future, and they will need more than just a good internet connection, microphone and video camera to deal with it.</p>
<p><a href="https://rewatch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rewatch</a>, which has built a set of tools for organizations to create a &#8220;system of record&#8221; for their internal video archives &#8212; not just a place to &#8220;rewatch&#8221; all of their older live video calls, but to search and organise information arising from those calls &#8212; has closed a $20 million round of funding.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Along with this, Rewatch from today is opening up its platform from invite-only to general availability.</p>
<p>This latest round is a Series A and is being led by Andreessen Horowitz, with Semil Shah at Haystack and Kent Goldman at Upside Partners, as well as a number of individuals, also participating.</p>
<p>It comes on the heels of Rewatch announcing a $2 million seed round only in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/rewatch-seed/">January of this year</a>. But it&#8217;s had some buzz in the intervening months: customers that have started using Rewatch include GitHub (where co-founders Connor Sears and Scott Goldman previously worked together), Brex, Envoy, and The Athletic.</p>
<p>The issue that Rewatch is tackling is the fact that a lot more of our work communications are happening over video. But while video calling has been hailed as a great boost to productivity &#8212; you can work wherever you are now, as long as you have a video connection &#8212; in fact, it&#8217;s not.</p>
<p>Yes, we are talking to each other a lot, but we are also losing information from those calls because they&#8217;re not being tracked as well as they could be. And, by spending all of our time talking, many of us are working on other things less, or are confined into more rigid times when we can.</p>
<p>Rewatch has built a system that plugs into Zoom and Google Meet, two of the most-used video tools in the workplace, and automatically imports all of your office&#8217;s or team&#8217;s video chats into a system. This lets you browse libraries of video-based conversations or meetings to watch them on-demand, on your time. It also provides transcripts and search tools for finding information in those calls.</p>
<p>You can turn off the automatic imports, or further customize how meetings are filed or accessibility. Sears said that Rewatch can be used for any video created on any platform, for now those require manually importing the videos into the Rewatch system.</p>
<p>Sears also said that over time it will also be adding in ways to automatically turn items from meetings into, say, work tickets to follow them up.</p>
<p>While there are a number of transcription services available on tap these days, as well as any number of cloud-based storage providers where you can keep video archives, what is notable about Rewatch&#8217;s is that it&#8217;s identified the pain point of managing and indexing those archives and keeping them in a single place for many to use.</p>
<p>In this way, Rewatch is highlighting and addressing what I think of as the crux of the productivity paradox.</p>
<p>Essentially, it is this: the tech industry has given us a lot of tools to help us work better, but actually, the work required to use those tools can outweigh the utility of the tools themselves.</p>
<p>(And I have to admit, this is one of the reasons why I&#8217;ve grown to dislike Slack. Yes, we all get to communicate on it, and it&#8217;s great to have something to connect all of us, but it just takes up so much damn time to read through everything and figure out what&#8217;s useful and what is just watercooler chat.)</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;We go to where companies already are, and we automate, pull in video so that you don’t have to think about it,&#8221; Sears said. &#8220;The effort around a lot of this takes a lot of diligence to make sure people are recording and transcribing and distributing and removing. We are making this seamless and effortless.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">It sometimes feels like we are on the cusp, technologically, of leaning on tools by way of AI and other innovations that might finally cross that chasm and give us <em>actual</em> productivity out of our productivity apps.</p>
<p class="p1">In another example of how this is playing out, Dooly, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/dooly-raises-80m-more-for-its-ai-tools-to-help-salespeople-manage-their-busywork/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised funding last week</a>, is looking to do the same in the world of sales software (automatically populating various sales software with data from your phone, video and text chats, and other sources).</p>
<p>Similarly, we&#8217;re starting to see an interesting wave of companies emerge that are looking for better ways to manage and tap into all that video content that we now have swimming around us.</p>
<p>AnyClip, which announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/anyclip-snaps-up-47m-for-its-video-search-and-analytics-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">funding yesterday</a>, is also applying better analytics and search to internal company video libraries, but also has its sights on a wider opportunity: organizing any video trove. That points, too, to the bigger opportunity for Rewatch.</p>
<p>For now, though, enterprises and businesses are an opportunity enough.</p>
<p>&#8220;As investors we get excited about founders first and foremost, and Connor and Scott immediately impressed us with their experience, clear articulation of the problem, and their vision for how Rewatch could be the end-all solution for video and knowledge management in an organization,&#8221; noted <a href="https://a16z.com/2021/05/26/investing-in-rewatch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">David Ulevitch</a>, a general partner at Andreessen Horowitz, in a blog post. &#8220;They both worked at GitHub in senior roles from the early days, as a Senior Director of Product Design and a Principal Engineer, respectively, and have first-hand experience scaling a product. Since founding Rewatch in early 2020, they have very quickly built a great product, sold it to large-scale customers, and hired top-tier talent, demonstrating rapid founder and company velocity that is key to building an enduring company.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/zoom-fatigue-no-more-rewatch-raises-20m-to-index-transcribe-and-store-enterprise-video-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157611</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon is buying MGM Studios for $8.45B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/amazon-is-buying-mgm-studios-for-8-45b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/amazon-is-buying-mgm-studios-for-8-45b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MGM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The big media consolidation continues &#8212; day after rumors swirled around Amazon’s acquisition of MGM, the online massive retailer confirmed today that it will be acquiring the nearly 100-year-old studio for a cool $8.45 billion. The deal is another big step toward bolster Amazon’s fight in the streaming wars, with some 4,000 films. The list [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The big media consolidation continues &#8212; day after rumors swirled around Amazon’s acquisition of MGM, <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210526005648/en/Amazon-and-MGM-have-signed-an-agreement-for-Amazon-to-acquire-MGM/?feedref=JjAwJuNHiystnCoBq_hl-SixzGpg-aPrNklZ4nvkcE4TY94BwQxjampCy0ugQmZbnkvYMqDDYxFrLs-oQ2BHQ0lNV9vE3ogUB8lg9me5DJ5HOIe_ZSOSL3m4JhK3aYyB9HNxCGXiDSWsXl5s-JshAwUr0fO6FA4Gx3o4ssEAaW4=">the online massive retailer confirmed today</a> that it will be acquiring the nearly 100-year-old studio for a cool $8.45 billion.</p>
<p>The deal is another big step toward bolster Amazon’s fight in the streaming wars, with some 4,000 films. The list includes the James Bond and Rocky series and classics ranging from Fargo to Robocop to Silence of the Lambs. Also included are more than 17,000 TV shows. Once the deal closes, the short term impact will be unfettered access for Amazon&#8217;s Prime Video platform, giving the service a leg up against rivals like Netflix, Hulu and HBO Max.</p>
<p>As we&#8217;ve seen with the launch of studio streaming platforms like Disney+, the deal will also likely result in that content being pulled from competing services, once existing contracts end. “The real financial value behind this deal is the treasure trove of IP in the deep catalog that we plan to reimagine and develop together with MGM’s talented team,” Amazon Studios/Prime Video SVP Mike Hopkins said in a release. “It’s very exciting and provides so many opportunities for high-quality storytelling.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Amazon also says it will be making efforts to preserve older films. The press material includes all of the standard language you would expect about marrying the old with the new. Here&#8217;s MGM Board Chairman, Kevin Ulrich, “I am very proud that MGM’s Lion, which has long evoked the Golden Age of Hollywood, will continue its storied history, and the idea born from the creation of United Artists lives on in a way the founders originally intended, driven by the talent and their vision. The opportunity to align MGM’s storied history with Amazon is an inspiring combination.”</p>
<p>Amazon has, of course, already been making an aggressive push into original content through its own production studio and distribution. On the film side, it has produced notable titles like Manchester By the Sea, which nabbed a screenwriting Oscar and its list of shows includes Transparent. The company is also embarking on a massive (and massively expensive) series based on Lord of Rings.</p>
<p>While Amazon has thrived with massive coffers, MGM&#8217;s had a more difficult 21st century. In 2010, the studio filed for a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748703506904575592200573445526">prepackaged Chapter 11 bankruptcy </a>after switching hands several times. The studio was reorganized and its creditors took control.</p>
<p>The deal is just the latest in a flurry of media consolidation, including Disney/Fox, Viacom/CBS and AT&amp;T/Time Warner. As <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ever with these massive deals, the acquisition is pending all sorts of regulator scrutiny.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/amazon-is-buying-mgm-studios-for-8-45b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157630</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook and Instagram will now allow users to hide &#8216;Like&#8217; counts on posts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/facebook-and-instagram-will-now-allow-users-to-hide-like-counts-on-posts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/facebook-and-instagram-will-now-allow-users-to-hide-like-counts-on-posts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital wellbeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[likes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[well being]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2156794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook this week will begin to publicly roll out the option to hide Likes on posts across both Facebook and Instagram, following earlier tests beginning in 2019. The project, which puts the decision about Likes in the hands of the company&#8217;s global user base, had been in development for years, but was deprioritized due to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook this week <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/05/giving-people-more-control/">will begin to</a> publicly roll out the option to hide Likes on posts across both Facebook and Instagram, following <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/instagram-private-like-counts/">earlier tests</a> beginning in 2019. The project, which puts the decision about Likes in the hands of the company&#8217;s global user base, had been in development for years, but was deprioritized due to the COVID-19 pandemic and the response work required on Facebook&#8217;s part, the company says.</p>
<p>Originally, the idea to hide Like counts on Facebook&#8217;s social networks was focused on depressurizing the experience for users. Often, users faced anxiety and embarrassment around their posts if they didn&#8217;t receive enough Likes to be considered &#8220;popular.&#8221; This problem was particularly difficult for younger users who highly value what peers think of them &#8212; so much so that they <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/teens-curate-their-instagram-accounts-2016-5">would take down posts</a> that didn&#8217;t receive enough Likes.</p>
<p>Like-chasing on Instagram, especially, also helped create an environment where people posted to gain clout and notoriety, which can be a less authentic experience. On Facebook, gaining Likes or other forms of engagement could also be associated with posting polarizing content that required a reaction.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As a result of this pressure to perform, some users grew hungry for a &#8220;Like-free&#8221; safer space, where they could engage with friends or the wider public without trying to earn these popularity points. That, in turn, gave rise to a new crop of social networking and photo-sharing apps such as <a href="https://www.minutiae-app.org/">Minutiae</a>, <a href="https://vero.co/">Vero</a>, <a href="https://www.dayflashapp.com/">Dayflash</a>, <a href="http://hipstamatic.com/oggl/">Oggl</a> and, now, newcomers like<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/spark-capital-decides-to-sever-all-ties-with-david-dobriks-dispo-app-weeks-after-leading-investment/"> Dispo</a> and newly viral <a href="https://www.protocol.com/bulletins/what-is-poparazzi-app">Poparazzi</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HEbakj9mzL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/spark-capital-decides-to-sever-all-ties-with-david-dobriks-dispo-app-weeks-after-leading-investment/">Spark Capital decides to &#8216;sever all ties&#8217; with David Dobrik’s Dispo app weeks after leading deal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spark Capital decides to &#8216;sever all ties&#8217; with David Dobrik’s Dispo app weeks after leading deal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/spark-capital-decides-to-sever-all-ties-with-david-dobriks-dispo-app-weeks-after-leading-investment/embed/#?secret=HEbakj9mzL" data-secret="HEbakj9mzL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Though Facebook and Instagram could have chosen to remove Likes entirely and take its social networks in a new direction, the company soon found that the metric was too deeply integrated into the product experience to be fully removed. One key issue was how the influencer community today trades on Likes as a form of currency that allows them to exchange their online popularity for brand deals and job opportunities. Removing Likes, then, is not necessarily an option for these users.</p>
<p>Instagram realized that if it made a decision for its users, it would anger one side or the other &#8212; even if the move in either direction didn&#8217;t really impact other core metrics, like app usage.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157105" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157105" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2157105" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="432" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png 1700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png?resize=768,488 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png?resize=680,432 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png?resize=1536,976 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Consumer-View.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157105" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;How many likes [users] got, or other people got &#8212; it turned out that it didn&#8217;t actually change nearly as much about the experience, in terms of how people felt or how much they use experience, as we thought it would. But it did end up being pretty polarizing,&#8221; admitted Instagram head, Adam Mosseri. &#8220;Some people really liked it and some people really didn&#8217;t.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;For those who liked it, it was mostly what we had hoped &#8212; which is that it depressurized the experience. And, for those who didn&#8217;t, they used Likes to get a sense for what was trending or was relevant on Instagram and on Facebook. And they were just super annoyed that we took it away,&#8221; he added. This latter group sometimes included smaller creators still working on establishing a presence across social media, though larger influencers were sometimes in favor of Like removals. (Mosseri name-checked Katy Perry as being pro Like removals, in fact.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bquMKEu59m"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/hype-machine-sinan-aral/">MIT professor wants to overhaul &#8216;The Hype Machine&#8217; that powers social media</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MIT professor wants to overhaul &#8216;The Hype Machine&#8217; that powers social media&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/hype-machine-sinan-aral/embed/#?secret=bquMKEu59m" data-secret="bquMKEu59m" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Ultimately, the company decided to split the difference. Instead of making a hard choice about the future of its online communities, it&#8217;s rolling out the &#8220;no Likes&#8221; option as a user-controlled setting on both platforms.</p>
<p>On Instagram, both content consumers and content producers can turn on or off Like and View counts on posts &#8212; which means you can choose to not see these metrics when scrolling your own Feed and you can choose whether to allow Likes to be viewed by others when you&#8217;re posting. These are configured as two different settings, which provides for more flexibility and control.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157104" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157104" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2157104" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="432" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png 1700w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png?resize=768,488 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png?resize=680,432 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png?resize=1536,976 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/IG-Hiding-Likes-Producer-View.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157104" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<p>On Facebook, meanwhile, users access the new setting from the &#8220;Settings &amp; Privacy&#8221; area under News Feed Settings (or News Feed Preferences on desktop). From here, you&#8217;ll find an option to &#8220;Hide number of reactions&#8221; to turn this setting off for both your own posts and for posts from others in News Feed, groups and Pages.</p>
<p>The feature will be made available to both public and private profiles, Facebook tells us, and will include posts you&#8217;ve published previously.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157366" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157366" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2157366" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_ReactionPreferences.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_ReactionPreferences.jpg 375w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_ReactionPreferences.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_ReactionPreferences.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_ReactionPreferences.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_ReactionPreferences.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157366" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>Instagram<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/"> last month restarted its tests on this feature</a> in order to work out any final bugs before making the new settings live for global users, and said a Facebook test would come soon. But it&#8217;s now forging ahead with making the feature available publicly. When asked why such a short test, Instagram told TechCrunch it had been testing various iterations on this experience since 2019, so it felt it had enough data to proceed with a global launch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QrYAIWPmxI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/">Instagram&#8217;s new test lets you choose if you want to hide &#8216;Likes,&#8217; Facebook test to follow</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram&#8217;s new test lets you choose if you want to hide &#8216;Likes,&#8217; Facebook test to follow&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/embed/#?secret=QrYAIWPmxI" data-secret="QrYAIWPmxI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Mosseri also pushed back at the idea that a decision on Likes would have majorly impacted the network. While removal of Likes on Instagram had some impact on user behavior, he said, it was not enough to be concerning. In some groups, users posted more &#8212; signaling that they felt less pressure to perform, perhaps. But others engaged less, Mosseri said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157367" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157367" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2157367" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_Reactions_News-Feed.jpg?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_Reactions_News-Feed.jpg 375w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_Reactions_News-Feed.jpg?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_Reactions_News-Feed.jpg?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_Reactions_News-Feed.jpg?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/FacebookApp_Reactions_News-Feed.jpg?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157367" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Often people say, &#8216;oh, this has a bunch of Likes. I&#8217;m gonna go check it out,&#8217; &#8221; the exec explained. &#8220;Then they read the comments, or go deeper, or swipe to the carousel. There&#8217;s been some small effects &#8212; some positive, some negative &#8212; but they&#8217;ve all been small,&#8221; he noted. Instagram also believes users may toggle on and off the feature at various times, based on how they&#8217;re feeling.</p>
<p>In addition, Mosseri pointed out, &#8220;there&#8217;s no rigorous research that suggests Likes are bad for people&#8217;s well-being&#8221; &#8212; a statement that pushes back over the growing concerns that a gamified social media space is bad for users&#8217; mental health. Instead, he argued that Instagram is still a small part of people&#8217;s day, so how Likes function doesn&#8217;t affect people&#8217;s overall well-being.</p>
<p>&#8220;As big as we are, we have to be careful not to overestimate our influence,&#8221; Mosseri said.</p>
<p>He also dismissed some of the current research pointing to negative impacts of social media use as being overly reliant on methodologies that ask users to self-report their use, rather than measure it directly.</p>
<p>In other words, this is not a company that feels motivated to remove Likes entirely due to the negative mental health outcomes attributed to its popularity metrics.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth mentioning that another factor that could have come into play here is Instagram&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/facebook-instagram-for-kids-state-attorneys-general-letter/">plan to make a version of its app available to children under the age of 13,</a> as competitor TikTok did <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/27/musical-ly-tiktok-fined-5-7m-by-ftc-for-violating-childrens-privacy-laws-will-update-app-with-age-gate/">following its FTC settlement</a>. In that case, hiding Likes by default &#8212; or perhaps adding a parental control option &#8212; would necessitate such a setting. Instagram tells TechCrunch that, while it&#8217;s too soon to know what it would do with a kids app, it will &#8220;definitely explore&#8221; a no Likes by default option.</p>
<p>Facebook and Instagram both told TechCrunch the feature will roll out starting on Wednesday but will reach global users over time. On Instagram, that may take a matter of days.</p>
<p>Facebook, meanwhile, says a small percentage of users will have the feature Wednesday &#8212; notified through an alert on News Feed &#8212; but it will reach Facebook&#8217;s global audience &#8220;over the next few weeks.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="66skDvIuCj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/facebook-instagram-for-kids-state-attorneys-general-letter/">State AGs tell Facebook to scrap Instagram for kids plans</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;State AGs tell Facebook to scrap Instagram for kids plans&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/facebook-instagram-for-kids-state-attorneys-general-letter/embed/#?secret=66skDvIuCj" data-secret="66skDvIuCj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/facebook-and-instagram-will-now-allow-users-to-hide-like-counts-on-posts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2156794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lightrun raises $23M for its debugging and observability platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/lightrun-raises-23m-for-its-debugging-and-observability-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/lightrun-raises-23m-for-its-debugging-and-observability-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDEs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightrun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lightrun, a startup that helps developers debug their live production code, today announced that it has raised a $23 million Series A round led by Insight Partners. Glilot Capital Partners, which led the company&#8217;s $4 million seed round, also participated in this round. What makes Lightrun stand out in a sea of monitoring startups is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://lightrun.com/">Lightrun</a>, a startup that helps developers debug their live production code, today announced that it has raised a $23 million Series A round led by <a href="https://www.insightpartners.com/">Insight Partners</a>. <a href="https://glilotcapital.com/">Glilot Capital Partners</a>, which led the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/lightrun-raises-4m-for-its-continuous-debugging-and-observability-platform/">$4 million seed round</a>, also participated in this round.</p>
<p>What makes Lightrun stand out in a sea of monitoring startups is its focus on developers (more so than IT teams) and its ability to help developers debug their production code right from their IDEs. With a few keystrokes, they can also instrument the code for monitoring, but the key here is that Lightrun offers what the company calls an &#8220;ops-free&#8221; process that puts the developers in control. This &#8220;shift-left&#8221; approach moves the application monitoring process away from ops-centric tools like Splunk and New Relic and instead puts them right into the workspaces with which developers are already familiar.</p>
<p>&#8220;The observability market has been very oriented towards IT operators. When an IT operator gets that dreaded page that a service is down, they see health metrics on running instances on servers and have a variety of failover methods and ways to restore service health,&#8221; Lightrun co-founder and CEO Ilan Peleg explained. &#8220;And they do this all natively on the same interfaces that they use every day for systems management. But when a developer gets that dreaded notification that there is a bug, it’s like the early stages of a crime scene investigation that has no suspects and usually only minor clues.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/yLL1A4Q-Hn0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Currently, the service only supports Java and the IntelliJ development environment, but the team plans to expand its language and platform coverage by adding support for Python and Node.js, as well as additional IDEs.</p>
<p>“We’ve seen a number of observability solutions joining the market, but found Lightrun’s shift-left approach to be truly unique,” said Teddie Wardi, managing director, Insight Partners, who led the round and will join the board of directors. “The main point of shifting observability to the left in the software development lifecycle is incorporating observability into the day-to-day developer workflow. Lightrun makes observability more ops-free, real-time and ergonomic to the development process than any other platform, and we believe they are in a position to capture a large international market of development teams at enterprises that prioritize rapid feature development and frequent shipping.”</p>
<p>The company recently launched a free community edition of its service and introduced a set of new integrations with services like Datadog, IntelliJ IDEA, Logz.io, Prometheus, Slack and StatsD. Some of Lightrun&#8217;s current customers include Taboola, Sisense and Tufin.</p>
<p>The company doubled its employee count over the course of the last year. It will continue to use the new funding to expand its developer community and hire across functions. The company also plans to expand its U.S. presence.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PEKIZWm4M6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/lightrun-raises-4m-for-its-continuous-debugging-and-observability-platform/">Lightrun raises $4M for its continuous debugging and observability platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lightrun raises $4M for its continuous debugging and observability platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/lightrun-raises-4m-for-its-continuous-debugging-and-observability-platform/embed/#?secret=PEKIZWm4M6" data-secret="PEKIZWm4M6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eoPgBySg9n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/5-machine-learning-essentials-non-technical-leaders-need-to-understand/">5 machine learning essentials nontechnical leaders need to understand</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 machine learning essentials nontechnical leaders need to understand&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/5-machine-learning-essentials-non-technical-leaders-need-to-understand/embed/#?secret=eoPgBySg9n" data-secret="eoPgBySg9n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/lightrun-raises-23m-for-its-debugging-and-observability-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157374</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tractive raises $35M as it expands GPS pet tracking to the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/tractive-raises-35m-as-it-expands-gps-pet-tracking-to-the-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/tractive-raises-35m-as-it-expands-gps-pet-tracking-to-the-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guidepost Growth Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[location tracker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tractive]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another sizable raise for a pet (cats and dogs) tracking company this morning. Austria-based Tractive has announced a $35 million Series A, led by Guidepost Growth Equity. The round is the company’s first since 2013, when its GPS-based tracker first hit the market. Along with the funding round, the company is also announcing its official [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Another sizable raise for a pet (cats and dogs) tracking company this morning. Austria-based Tractive has announced a $35 million Series A, led by Guidepost Growth Equity. The round is the company’s first since 2013, when its GPS-based tracker first hit the market.</p>
<p>Along with the funding round, the company is also announcing its official push into the U.S. market &#8212; though Tractive has had some presence here through a “soft launch” of an LTE tracker over the summer. That product apparently made the States its fastest growing market, in spite of a lack of official presence.</p>
<p>The funding will go toward its expansion into the U.S./North American market, along with additional scaling and headcount. For the latter, the company is already naming a new EVP of North America and a VP of marketing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Tractive is like a seatbelt for your dog or cat. It provides coverage when and where they need it,” said co-founder and CEO Michael Hurnaus in a release. “We designed Tractive to deliver the best possible experience, with up-to-the-second information, so that all pet parents can care for their dogs and cats the way they want and deserve &#8212; whether that means monitoring activity levels to reduce the risk of obesity or tracking a dog or cat that slipped out of the yard.”</p>
<p>Also new is the arrival of an upgraded tracker from the company, primarily focused on improved battery life. The big change is the use of Wi-Fi to reduce battery strain when a pet is in the home. The company says it&#8217;s able to bump up battery life up to 5x. The tracker is available for $50 in the U.S., plus a monthly subscription fee.</p>
<p>In February, smart pet collar maker Fi announced a $30 million Series B.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tWGVgb0ona"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/connected-pet-collar-company-fi-raises-a-30m-series-b/">Connected pet collar company Fi raises a $30M Series B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Connected pet collar company Fi raises a $30M Series B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/connected-pet-collar-company-fi-raises-a-30m-series-b/embed/#?secret=tWGVgb0ona" data-secret="tWGVgb0ona" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jd6R5jCH5M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/from-surviving-to-thriving-as-a-hardware-startup/">From surviving to thriving as a hardware startup</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From surviving to thriving as a hardware startup&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/from-surviving-to-thriving-as-a-hardware-startup/embed/#?secret=jd6R5jCH5M" data-secret="jd6R5jCH5M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/tractive-raises-35m-as-it-expands-gps-pet-tracking-to-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skiff, an end-to-end encrypted alternative to Google Docs, raises $3.7M seed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/skiff-encrypted-collaboration-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/skiff-encrypted-collaboration-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[end-to-end encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eventbrite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Allo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Yang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Hennessy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Hartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signal foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Imagine if Google Docs was end-to-end encrypted so that not even Google could access your documents. That&#8217;s Skiff, in a nutshell. Skiff is a document editor with a similar look and feel to Google Docs, allowing you to write, edit and collaborate in real-time with colleagues with privacy baked in. Because the document editor is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Imagine if Google Docs was end-to-end encrypted so that not even Google could access your documents. That&#8217;s <a href="https://skiff.org/">Skiff</a>, in a nutshell.</p>
<p>Skiff is a document editor with a similar look and feel to Google Docs, allowing you to write, edit and collaborate in real-time with colleagues with privacy baked in. Because the document editor is built on a foundation of end-to-end encryption, Skiff doesn&#8217;t have access to anyone&#8217;s documents — only users, and those who are invited to collaborate, do.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an idea that has already attracted the attention of investors. Skiff&#8217;s co-founders Andrew Milich (CEO) and Jason Ginsberg (CTO) announced today that the startup has raised $3.7 million in seed funding from venture firm Sequoia Capital, just over a year since Skiff was founded in March 2020. Alphabet chairman John Hennessy, former Yahoo chief executive Jerry Yang, and Eventbrite co-founders Julia and Kevin Hartz also participated in the round.</p>
<p>Milich and Ginsberg told TechCrunch that the company will use the seed funding to grow the team and build out the platform.</p>
<p>Skiff isn&#8217;t that much different from WhatsApp or Signal, which are also end-to-end encrypted, underneath its document editor. &#8220;Instead of using it to send messages to a bunch of people, we&#8217;re using it to send little pieces of documents and then piecing those together into a collaborative workspace,&#8221; said Milich.</p>
<p>But the co-founders acknowledged that putting your sensitive documents in the cloud requires users to put a lot of trust into the startup, particularly one that hasn&#8217;t been around for long. That&#8217;s why Skiff <a href="https://www.skiff.org/security">published a whitepaper</a> with technical details of how its technology works, and has <a href="https://www.skiff.org/updates/skiff-is-open-sourcing">begun to open source</a> parts of its code, allowing anyone to see how the platform works. Milich said Skiff has also gone through at least one comprehensive security audit, and the company counts advisors from the Signal Foundation to Trail of Bits.</p>
<p>It seems to be working. In the months since Skiff soft-launched through an invite-only program, thousands of users — including journalists, research scientists and human rights lawyers — use Skiff every day, with another 8,000 users on a waitlist.</p>
<p>&#8220;The group of users that we&#8217;re most excited about are just regular people that care about privacy,&#8221; said Ginsberg. &#8220;There are just so many privacy communities and people that are advocates for these types of products that really care about how they&#8217;re built and have sort of lost trust in big companies.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;re using us because they&#8217;re really excited about the vision and the future of end-to-end encryption,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/skiff-encrypted-collaboration-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157350</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Insurtech startup Obie raises $10.7M Series A led by Battery Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/insurtech-startup-obie-raises-10-7m-series-a-led-by-battery-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/insurtech-startup-obie-raises-10-7m-series-a-led-by-battery-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casualty insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landlord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Brown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thomvest Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Obie, which has developed an insurtech platform for landlords, has raised $10.7 million in a Series A funding round led by Battery Ventures. Thomvest Ventures, Funders Club, MetaProp and Second Century Ventures also participated in the financing. If this sounds like a niche offering, that’s because it is. Obie’s software specifically targets small-to-medium size apartment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.obierisk.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Obie</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which has developed an insurtech platform for landlords, has raised $10.7 million in a Series A funding round led by Battery Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thomvest Ventures, Funders Club, MetaProp and Second Century Ventures also participated in the financing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If this sounds like a niche offering, that’s because it is. Obie’s software specifically targets small-to-medium size apartment landlords who own single-family rentals and/or larger apartment buildings.  </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chicago-based Obie &#8212; which also went through the Y Combinator program &#8212; says its platform stands out because it offers instant quotes (by instant, they mean in about three to five minutes). The company also claims to save policyholders up to 25-30% compared to other insurance premiums. Over the past year, Obie has secured insurance for over $3 billion worth of property.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Obie co-founders (and brothers) Aaron and Ryan Letzeiser have taken their respective backgrounds in insurance and real estate private equity to build out the Obie platform. They are operating under the premise that despite being the largest class of real estate investors in the U.S, this group of landlords “is significantly underserved.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Generally SMB landlords have been ignored in the market, and there&#8217;s 11 million of them,” Aaron said. “And we beat target premiums, on average, by 31.7%.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The demand appears to be there. According to the pair, Obie saw its premiums climb to about $1 million in its first 12 months of being in business. Over the last 12 months, that number has climbed to about $10 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conjunction with its funding announcement, Obie also announced today the extension of its property and casualty insurance to all 50 states.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2157275" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2157275" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2157275 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/yc1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2157275" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Obie</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, how does it work? Landlords and investors answer a series of questions on Obie’s site. The platform extracts a few data points from client responses, which its technology then combines with public and private data points such as the proximity of the landlord to the property. (This can be an indicator of how quickly a landlord can conduct proactive and preventative maintenance and general attentiveness to tenant issues.) </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once Obie runs its analysis, the platform uses a “proprietary” algorithm to match an application to carriers based on what they describe as “risk-appetite” profiles. For example, some carriers don’t want to cover properties built before a certain year. The platform then provides the landlords and property owners with a quote. If they’re OK with the quote, landlords can be “immediately underwritten,” according to the company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At its core, said Ryan, the brothers want to make Obie “the easiest way for landlords to get the insurance that they need.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use its new capital to expand upon its product and “really try to own the entire vertical.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Historically, we&#8217;ve been an agency-based business but we are in the process of putting together our own product that is slated to roll out right at the end of the second quarter,” said Aaron. “Very similar to Lemonade and Hippo, and we’re doing it with a large insurer that’s backing us.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In other words, Obie believes it has validated its brokerage model in the market and is now planning to use the data it’s been able to gather to become its own carrier. The company expects the rollout to take time, so until it gets approval in all 50 states, it will partner with other carriers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our goal at the end of the day is to go from agency to eventually carrier,” said Ryan. “This is a tried and true path. Next has done it. Hippo has done it. Lemonade has done it.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The brothers believe their backgrounds allow them “to speak the same language” to their clients. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We have lived the pain points of our clients so we can understand how the price of the premium of coverage experience plays into the overall business strategy,” Aaron said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Battery Ventures’ Michael Brown, who has taken a seat on Obie’s board, agrees the embedded nature of the startup’s offering gives them a competitive advantage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Allowing their end customers to buy professional liability or general liability or commercial auto right from the vertical software that is servicing their business is really interesting and a great distribution channel for Obie,” Brown told TechCrunch. “Landlords can go direct or through their channel partners.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brown says Battery &#8212; as long-term investors in the insurance sector &#8212; was also attracted to the fact that Obie is focused on commercial lines rather than personal because the firm believes “they are larger markets, less competitive and can probably drive higher value just given the overall size of the premiums involved.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0qlEmsx8Gx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/insurtech-startups-are-leveraging-rapid-growth-to-raise-big-money/">Insurtech startups are leveraging rapid growth to raise big money</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insurtech startups are leveraging rapid growth to raise big money&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/insurtech-startups-are-leveraging-rapid-growth-to-raise-big-money/embed/#?secret=0qlEmsx8Gx" data-secret="0qlEmsx8Gx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/insurtech-startup-obie-raises-10-7m-series-a-led-by-battery-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157271</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uptycs secures $50M Series C as security platform continues to expand</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/uptycs-secures-50m-series-c-as-security-platform-continues-to-expand/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/uptycs-secures-50m-series-c-as-security-platform-continues-to-expand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boston startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uptycs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Uptycs, a Boston-area startup that uses data to help understand and prevent security attacks, announced a $50 million Series C today, 11 months after announcing a $30 million Series B. Norwest Venture Partners led the round with participation from Sapphire Ventures and ServiceNow Ventures. Company co-founder and CEO Ganesh Pai says that he was still [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.uptycs.com/">Uptycs</a>, a Boston-area startup that uses data to help understand and prevent security attacks, announced a $50 million Series C today, 11 months after announcing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/uptycs-lands-30m-series-b-to-keep-building-security-analytics-platform/">a $30 million Series B</a>. Norwest Venture Partners led the round with participation from Sapphire Ventures and ServiceNow Ventures.</p>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Ganesh Pai says that he was still well capitalized from last year&#8217;s investment, and wasn&#8217;t actually looking to raise funds, but the investors came looking for him and he saw a way to speed up some aspects of the company&#8217;s roadmap.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was one of those things where the round came in primarily as a function of execution and success to date, and we decided to capitalize on that because we know the partners and raised the capital so that we could use it meaningfully for a couple of different things, primarily sales and marketing acceleration,&#8221; Pai said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He said that part of the reason for the company&#8217;s success over the last year was that the pandemic generated more customer interest as people moved to work from home, the SolarWinds hack happened and companies were moving to the cloud faster. &#8220;We provided a solution which was telemetric powered and very insightful when it came to solving their security problems and that&#8217;s what led to triple digit growth over the last year,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xjgDPnj5j2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/2020-was-a-disaster-but-the-pandemic-put-security-in-the-spotlight/">2020 was a disaster, but the pandemic put security in the spotlight</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;2020 was a disaster, but the pandemic put security in the spotlight&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/2020-was-a-disaster-but-the-pandemic-put-security-in-the-spotlight/embed/#?secret=xjgDPnj5j2" data-secret="xjgDPnj5j2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But Pai says that the company has not been sitting still in terms of the platform. While last year, he described it primarily as a forensic security data solution, helping customers figure out what happened after a security issue has happened, he says that the company has begun expanding on that vision to include all four main areas of security including being proactive, reactive, predictive and protective.</p>
<p>The company started primarily in being reactive by figuring what happened in the past, but has begun to expand into these other areas over the last year, and the plan is to continue to build out that functionality.</p>
<p>&#8220;In <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">the context of SolarWinds</a>, what everyone is trying to figure out is how soon into the supply chain can you figure out what could be potentially wrong by looking at indications of behavior or indications of compromise, and our ability to ingest telemetry from a diverse set of sources, not as a bolt on solution, but something which is built from the ground up, resonated really well,&#8221; Pai explained.</p>
<p>The company had 65 employees when we spoke last year for the Series B. Today, Pai says that number is approaching 140 and he is adding new people every week with a goal to get to around 200 people by the end of the year. He says as the company grows, he keeps diversity top of mind.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we grow and as we raise capital diversity has been something which has been a high priority and very critical for us,&#8221; he said. In fact, he reports that more than 50% of his employees come from under-represented groups whether it&#8217;s Latinx, Black or Asian heritage.</p>
<p>Pai says that one of the reasons he has been able to build a diverse workforce is his commitment to a remote workplace, which means he can hire from anywhere, something he will continue to do even after the pandemic ends.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xQK1dbxTEy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/uptycs-lands-30m-series-b-to-keep-building-security-analytics-platform/">Uptycs lands $30M Series B to keep building security analytics platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uptycs lands $30M Series B to keep building security analytics platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/uptycs-lands-30m-series-b-to-keep-building-security-analytics-platform/embed/#?secret=xQK1dbxTEy" data-secret="xQK1dbxTEy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/uptycs-secures-50m-series-c-as-security-platform-continues-to-expand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157259</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India says WhatsApp&#8217;s lawsuit over new regulations a clear act of defiance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/india-says-whatsapps-lawsuit-over-new-regulations-a-clear-act-of-defiance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/india-says-whatsapps-lawsuit-over-new-regulations-a-clear-act-of-defiance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India said on Wednesday that WhatsApp’s lawsuit challenging the new local IT rules is an “unfortunate last moment” attempt to prevent new regulations from going into effect in &#8220;a clear act of defiance,&#8221; and said the Facebook-owned service didn’t raise any specific objection about the traceability requirement in writing after October 2018. Ravi Shankar Prasad, India’s Electronics [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India said on Wednesday that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/whatsapp-sues-india-government/">WhatsApp’s lawsuit challenging the new local IT rules</a> is an “unfortunate last moment” attempt to prevent new regulations from going into effect in &#8220;a clear act of defiance,&#8221; and said the Facebook-owned service didn’t raise any specific objection about the traceability requirement in writing after October 2018.</p>
<p>Ravi Shankar Prasad, India’s Electronics and IT Minister, said WhatsApp’s refusal to comply with the guidelines, the deadline of which expires Wednesday, is a “clear act of defiance of a measure whose intent can certainly not be doubted.”</p>
<p>WhatsApp sued the Indian government earlier on Wednesday in a Delhi court, saying the world&#8217;s second largest internet market&#8217;s new IT rules could allow authorities to make people’s private messages “traceable,” and conduct mass surveillance.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Ministry of Electronics and IT said the government needs to trace the first originator of a message for the &#8220;purposes of prevention, investigation, punishment etc. of inter alia an offence relating to sovereignty, integrity and security of India, public order incitement to an offence relating to rape, sexually explicit material or child sexual abuse material punishable with imprisonment for not less than five years.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It is in public interest that who started the mischief leading to such crime must be detected and punished. We cannot deny as to how in cases of mob lynching and riots etc. repeated WhatsApp messages are circulated and recirculated whose content are already in public domain. Hence the role of who originated is very important.&#8221;</p>
<p>India first proposed WhatsApp to deploy software changes to make the originator of a message traceable in 2018. The suggestion came at a time when WhatsApp was grappling with containing spread of false information in India, where circulation of such hoaxes resulted in multiple real-life casualties. The suggestion became a part of the new rules in February this year.</p>
<p>WhatsApp has argued that the end-to-end encryption it offers to users &#8212; a move that security and policy experts have long praised &#8212; makes it impossible for the firm, used by over 2 billion users worldwide, to find identifying information about a user.</p>
<p>India is the largest market by users for the Facebook-owned popular instant messaging service. According to a government estimate, WhatsApp has amassed over 530 million users in India.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Electronics and IT said any company&#8217;s operations in India is &#8220;subject to the law of the land,&#8221; and argued that similar or tougher regulations have been enforced or proposed in other markets.</p>
<p>&#8220;What India is asking for is significantly much less than what some of the other countries have demanded,&#8221; it said, adding that it would be &#8220;foolhardy&#8221; to doubt the objective of the new rules.</p>
<p>One one hand, &#8220;WhatsApp seeks to mandate a privacy policy wherein it will share the data of all its user with its parent company, Facebook, for marketing and advertising purposes,&#8221; the ministry added. &#8220;On the other hand, WhatsApp makes every effort to refuse the enactment of the Intermediary Guidelines which are necessary to uphold law and order and curb the menace of fake news.&#8221;</p>
<p>The ministry wrote to social media firms earlier on Wednesday to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/india-asks-social-media-firms-if-they-have-complied-with-the-new-regulations/">ask for an update on whether they had complied with the new rules</a>, TechCrunch first reported. In the letter, the ministry sought information (name and contact address) of officials who the firms had appointed as part of the compliance to the new rules that require officers to be available on the ground to address local concerns.</p>
<p>&#8220;WhatsApp’s attempt to portray the Intermediary Guidelines of India as contrary to the right to privacy is misguided. [&#8230;] The Government of India recognises that ‘Right to Privacy’ is a Fundamental right and is committed to ensure the same to its citizens,&#8221; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/india-says-whatsapps-lawsuit-over-new-regulations-a-clear-act-of-defiance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157621</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Axle raises $10m Series A to advance its freight financing services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/axle-raises-10m-series-a-to-advance-its-freight-financing-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/axle-raises-10m-series-a-to-advance-its-freight-financing-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[axle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[axle payments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Axle recently announced it raised $10m in Series A financing after a stellar year of growth. The round was led by Crosslink Capital with participation from FJ Labs, Flexport, Tribeca Early Stage Partners, and others including existing investors Anthemis Group, Techstars, and Plug and Play Ventures. In a press release, the company points to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.axlepayments.com">Axle</a> recently announced it raised $10m in Series A financing after a stellar year of growth. The round was led by Crosslink Capital with participation from FJ Labs, Flexport, Tribeca Early Stage Partners, and others including existing investors Anthemis Group, Techstars, and Plug and Play Ventures.</p>
<p>In a press release, the company points to the past 12 months of operations where it saw volume grow 850% on its payments and financing platform designed specifically for freight brokers and carriers. The company’s services allows incumbent operators to quickly modernize and compete against new startups. Axle says its solutions also automates carrier payments, involving, and collections, which allows operators to connect all aspects of their fright operations.</p>
<p>Axle anticipates using the new capital to expand operations, develop new services, and strength the company’s payment and financing platform.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Co-founders Bharath Krishnamoorthy and Shawn Vo founded the company in 2019. The company raised a $1.4 million pre-seed round from Trucks VC in 2020, followed by a $2.7m seed round from Techstars and Anthemis Group and a $27.7 million debt and equity round later that year.</p>
<p>CEO and co-founder, Bharath Krishnamoorthy, says in a released statement “Axle’s proprietary technology levels the playing field, so our customers can compete in a highly competitive market. With our financial platform, we’re empowering freight intermediaries to rapidly grow and differentiate their businesses in a cutthroat industry. We’re excited to partner with Crosslink to transform the freight and logistics industry.”</p>
<p>Crosslink Capital partner David Silverman says Krishnamoorthy and Vo established themselves as an industry leader in freight factoring and payment processing, and points to the company’s previous 12 month as being impressive. “We look forward to helping them scale operations,” he says.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/axle-raises-10m-series-a-to-advance-its-freight-financing-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157604</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Salt Security lands $70M for tech to protect APIs from malicious abuse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/salt-security-lands-70m-for-tech-to-protect-apis-from-malicious-abuse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/salt-security-lands-70m-for-tech-to-protect-apis-from-malicious-abuse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[API security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[APIs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salt security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[APIs make the world go round in tech, but that also makes them a very key target for bad actors: as doorways into huge data troves and services, malicious hackers spent a lot of time looking for ways to pick their locks or just force them open when they&#8217;re closed, in order to access that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">APIs make the world go round in tech, but that also makes them a very key target for bad actors: as doorways into huge data troves and services, malicious hackers spent a lot of time looking for ways to pick their locks or just force them open when they&#8217;re closed, in order to access that information. And a lot of recent security breaches stemming from API vulnerabilities (see <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/peloton-bug-account-data-leak/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>, <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/hackers-use-google-analytics-to-steal-credit-cards-bypass-csp/?mid=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/geico-driver-license-numbers-scraped/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a> for just a few) show just how real and current the problem is.</p>
<p>Today, a company that&#8217;s building a network of services to help those using and producing APIs to identify and eradicate those risks is announcing a round of funding to meet a growing demand for its services. <a href="https://salt.security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Salt Security</a>, which provides AI-based technology to identify issues and stop attacks across the whole of your API library, has closed $70 million in funding, money that it will be using both to meet current demand but also continue building out its technology for a wider set of services and use cases for API management.</p>
<p>The funding is being led by Advent International, by way of Advent Tech, with Alkeon Capital, DFJ Growth and previous backers Sequoia Capital, Tenaya Capital, S Capital VC, and Y Combinator all also participating.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Salt, founded in Israel and now active globally, is not disclosing valuation but I understand from a reliable source it that it is in the region of $600-700 million.</p>
<p>As with many of the funding rounds that seem to be getting announced these days, this one is coming on the heels of both another recent round, as well as strong growth. Salt has raised $131 million since 2016, but nearly all of that &#8212; $120 million, to be exact &#8212; has been raised in the last year.</p>
<p>Part of the reason for that is Salt&#8217;s performance: in the last 12 months, it&#8217;s seen revenue grow 400% &#8212; with customers including a range of Fortune 500 and other large businesses in the financial services, retail and SaaS sectors like Equinix, Finastra, TripActions, Armis, and DeinDeal; headcount grow 160%; and, perhaps most importantly, API traffic on its network grow 380%.</p>
<p>That growth in API traffic underscores the issue that Salt is tackling. Companies these days use a variety of APIs &#8212; some private, some public &#8212; in their tech stack as a way to interface with other businesses and run their services. APIs are a huge part of how the Internet and digital services operate, with Akamai estimating that as much as 83% of all IP traffic is API traffic.</p>
<p>The problem, Roey Eliyahu, CEO and co-founder of Salt Security told me, is that this usage has outpaced how well many manage those APIs.</p>
<p>&#8220;How APIs have evolved is very different to how developers used APIs years ago,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Before, there were very few, and you could say they were more manageable, and they contained less sensitive data, and there were very few changes and updates made to them,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Today with the pace of development, not only are they always getting updated, but you have thousands of them now touching crown jewels of the company.&#8221;</p>
<p>This has made them a prime target for malicious hackers. Eliyahu notes Gartner stats that predict that by 2022, APIs will make up the largest attack vector in cybercrime.</p>
<p>Salt&#8217;s approach starts with taking stock of a whole network and doing a kind of spring clean to find all the APIs that might be used or abused.</p>
<p>&#8220;Companies don&#8217;t know how many APIs they even have,&#8221; Eliyahu said, noting that there some 40%-80% of the APIs in existence for a typical company&#8217;s data are not even in active operation, lying there as &#8220;shadow APIs&#8221; for someone to pick up and misuse.</p>
<p>It then looks at what vulnerabilities might inadvertently be contained in this mix and makes suggestions for how to alter them to fix that. After this, it also monitors how they are used in order to stop attacks as they happen. The third of these also involves remediation &#8220;insights&#8221;, but carrying out the remediation is done by third parties at the moment, Eliyahu said. All of this is done through Salt&#8217;s automated, AI-based, flagship Salt Security API Protection Platform.</p>
<p>There are a number of competitors in the same space as Salt, including Ping, and newer players like Imvision and 42Crunch (which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/api-security-startup-42crunch-raises-17m-series-a-led-by-energy-impact-partners/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised funding</a> earlier this month), and the list is likely to grow as not just other API management companies get deeper into this huge space, but cyber security companies do, too.</p>
<p>“The rapid proliferation of APIs has dramatically altered the attack surface of applications, creating a major challenge for large enterprises since existing security mechanisms cannot protect against this new threat,” said Bryan Taylor, managing partner and head of Advent’s technology team, in a statement. “We continue to see API security incidents make the news headlines and cause significant reputational risk for companies. As we investigated the API security market, Salt stood out for its multi-year technical lead, significant customer traction and references, and talented team. We look forward to drawing on our deep experience in this sector to partner with Salt in this exciting new chapter.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/salt-security-lands-70m-for-tech-to-protect-apis-from-malicious-abuse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157582</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LatAm-focused corporate spend startup Clara raises $30M months after its last round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/latam-focused-corporate-spend-startup-clara-raises-30m-months-after-its-last-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/latam-focused-corporate-spend-startup-clara-raises-30m-months-after-its-last-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DST Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monashees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ramp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157335</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning Clara announced that it closed a new, $30 million funding round and secured a $50 million revolving debt facility. The startup, which provides corporate cards to Mexican companies, raised funds earlier this year when it was busy launching its product. Since then, growth has proven rapid for the Mexico City-based company. TechCrunch learned [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This morning <a href="https://www.clara.cc/">Clara</a> announced that it closed a new, $30 million funding round and secured a $50 million revolving debt facility.</p>
<p>The startup, which provides corporate cards to Mexican companies, raised funds <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/10/latam-corporate-spend-management-startup-clara-raises-3-5m-comes-out-of-stealth/">earlier this year</a> when it was busy launching its product. Since then, growth has proven rapid for the Mexico City-based company.</p>
<p>TechCrunch learned that the company is valued around $130 million after this latest investment, according to sources familiar with its latest fundraising. The round added DST and monashees to Clara&#8217;s cap table; prior investor General Catalyst also contributed funds to the deal.</p>
<p>We spoke with <a href="https://twitter.com/ggiaco?lang=en">Gerry Giacomán Colyer</a>, a co-founder at the startup and its CEO, about why Clara raised more capital so quickly after it last closed a financing round. The short gist is that the company&#8217;s growth, and market, allowed it to raise easily. And that the startup has pretty big plans, so having more capital with which to hire is welcome.</p>
<p>Per Giacomán Colyer, since he last spoke to this publication the transaction volume (GTV) that Clara supports has grown by 100x. His company is managing 2x week-over-week growth at times, which is super rapid. That&#8217;s precisely the sort of usage growth that venture capitalists covet; and as Clara makes revenue from interchange fees that stem from transaction volume, the startup is likely seeing its revenue advance at roughly the same rate as its GTV.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WQdDokGuWD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/how-brex-more-than-doubled-its-valuation-in-a-year/">How Brex more than doubled its valuation in a year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Brex more than doubled its valuation in a year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/how-brex-more-than-doubled-its-valuation-in-a-year/embed/#?secret=WQdDokGuWD" data-secret="WQdDokGuWD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That Clara was able to raise more capital is unsurprising. Not only is it growing quickly in its home market with designs on Brazil in the future, a U.S.-based player in the same space recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/">sold for north of $2 billion</a>. Divvy&#8217;s sale was likely a shot in the arm for not only Clara, but also Brex and Ramp, two other well-known players in the larger corporate spend world.</p>
<p>Clara&#8217;s success in Mexico makes it likely that related startups also targeting markets that lack a modern corporate spend solution will see strong venture capital interest; I would not be surprised if we heard from a number of other companies attacking geographies with favorable interchange economics with a similar model, as it has proven to be so lucrative.</p>
<p>TechCrunch asked Giacomán Colyer about who his company is targeting in terms of customers; Brex famously got its start working with high-growth startups before moving to work with a broader array of companies. Clara is working with startups in the Mexican market, the company said, but also with larger firms as well. Its CEO said that its underwriting model is set up to support more traditional cash-flow modeling.</p>
<p>So far Clara has largely attracted customers via word-of-mouth, and is working to bolster its referral system. But now that it has lots more capital, it will be interesting to see if the startup builds out a more aggressive go-to-market motion.</p>
<p>And more than just equity capital, the debt that Clara also secured as part of its recent funding round will help it underwrite customers without having to work off of its own balance sheet. Giacomán Colyer said that even after the capital costs associated with the facility, Clara&#8217;s economics are still good. Interchange is a flexible beast, it seems.</p>
<p>To that end, TechCrunch asked Giacomán Colyer if his company intends to charge for software in time, or merely eat off of interchange. In the United States, Brex is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/how-brex-more-than-doubled-its-valuation-in-a-year/">now in camp one</a>, along <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/05/spend-control-focused-airbase-adds-23-5m-to-its-series-a-as-it-posts-quick-growth/">with Airbase</a>, while Ramp is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/spend-management-startup-ramp-confirms-115m-raise-1-6b-valuation/">sticking to camp two</a>. Divvy proved that you can get to nine-figures in top line without charging for software, though having some ARR in the mix along with interchange incomes could provide a margin-boost to interchange top line. Regardless, Clara appears happy to keep to interchange for the time being.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see how quickly Clara can keep scaling. We&#8217;ll check back with the company in a few months.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fEzlSyEVGY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/">Why did Bill.com pay $2.5B for Divvy?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why did Bill.com pay $2.5B for Divvy?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/why-did-bill-com-pay-2-5b-for-divvy/embed/#?secret=fEzlSyEVGY" data-secret="fEzlSyEVGY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/latam-focused-corporate-spend-startup-clara-raises-30m-months-after-its-last-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157335</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Collab Capital closes $50 million debut fund to back Black founders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/collab-capital-closes-50-million-debut-fund-for-black-founders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/collab-capital-closes-50-million-debut-fund-for-black-founders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Collab Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jewel burks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A decade before investing outside of San Francisco and New York became trendy, entrepreneurs Jewel Burks, Justin Dawkins and Barry Givens were betting on Atlanta. Each experienced first-hand the biases that disproportionately hurts Black founders &#8211; while also being living proof of the wave of Black innovation and opportunity in their city. Last year, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A decade before investing outside of San Francisco and New York became trendy, entrepreneurs <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jewelburks">Jewel Burks</a>,<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/justindawkins/"> Justin Dawkins </a>and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/barrygivens/">Barry Givens</a> were betting on Atlanta. Each experienced first-hand the biases that disproportionately hurts Black founders &#8211; while also being living proof of the wave of Black innovation and opportunity in their city.</p>
<p>Last year, the trio saw opportunity in that disconnect and launched <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/collab-capital-launches-with-a-50-million-target-and-a-mission-to-help-black-entrepreneurs/">Collab Capital</a>, a firm designed to invest explicitly in Black founders. It debuted with $2 million in capital and a massive end target: $50 million. Today, the firm announced that it has met that goal, with backers such as Apple, Goldman Sachs, Google, The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, Mailchimp, and PayPal, making it one of the largest funds closed from an entirely Black-led firm solely committed to Black founders.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wEi24X2W07"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/collab-capital-launches-with-a-50-million-target-and-a-mission-to-help-black-entrepreneurs/">Collab Capital launches with a $50 million target and a mission to help Black entrepreneurs</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Collab Capital launches with a $50 million target and a mission to help Black entrepreneurs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/collab-capital-launches-with-a-50-million-target-and-a-mission-to-help-black-entrepreneurs/embed/#?secret=wEi24X2W07" data-secret="wEi24X2W07" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We really wanted to build a fund that was appropriate for the opportunity that we see [in Black founders],” Burks said. “And honestly I would say, it’s a small fund out there relative to the number of Black-led companies out there that are looking and seeking funding.”</p>
<p>With the new fund, Collab Capital plans to invest in 50 companies over a three-to-five-year period with check sizes between $500,000 and $750,000. The firm has also reserved up to $2 million per investment for follow-on bets. It is targeting ownership between 10% to 15% in each deal. To date, Collab Capital has backed six companies in the healthcare, edtech, and future of work spaces, including Music Tech Works and Hairbrella.</p>
<p>Internally, the team plans to stay based in Atlanta. Burks, who founded Atlanta-based PartPic, a TC Battlefield company that sold to Amazon, said that reinvesting in the community has always been a part of Collab Capital’s intention. Case in point? The firm’s first three deals were in Atlanta. As Zoom investing became more popular in the wake of the coronavirus, the team invested in startups from Kansas City, Washington, D.C., and Miami, as well.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2jwNdwx5Z9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/how-did-atlanta-become-a-top-breeding-ground-for-billion-dollar-startups-in-the-southeast/">How did Atlanta become a top breeding ground for billion-dollar startups in the Southeast?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How did Atlanta become a top breeding ground for billion-dollar startups in the Southeast?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/how-did-atlanta-become-a-top-breeding-ground-for-billion-dollar-startups-in-the-southeast/embed/#?secret=2jwNdwx5Z9" data-secret="2jwNdwx5Z9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We’re excited to be able to support founders anywhere in the United States, but we’re really focused on cities that have a high concentration of Black innovators and a lower concentration of capital,” she said.</p>
<h2><strong>The world before June</strong></h2>
<p>While part of Collab’s focus is avoiding coastal cities, network matters. The firm’s ability to secure heavyweight investors such as Apple and PayPal gives it a key signal that validates its bet on Black founders.</p>
<p>Burks thinks part of the reason that investors might be more intentional about backing firms such as hers is the result of the racial injustice that was highlighted in the wake of the murder of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and countless other Black people at the hands of police.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ix7vU7SFB1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/02/diverse-startups-and-investors-matter/">Venture firms rush to find ways to support Black founders and investors</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture firms rush to find ways to support Black founders and investors&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/02/diverse-startups-and-investors-matter/embed/#?secret=ix7vU7SFB1" data-secret="ix7vU7SFB1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>After Floyd and Taylor were murdered, there was a global movement spearheaded by Black Lives Matter in response to police brutality and racism in the United States. Burks says that Collab Capital had only raised a few million at that time, but then witnessed “a shift in the hearts and minds of capital allocators.”</p>
<p>Burks noted that when Collab Capital was first raising its fund, potential investors told them to have a “wider perspective” on what kinds of entrepreneurs to back. Some thought they should create a fund around underrepresented founders or multicultural founders. With general VC volatility in the early months of the pandemic, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/09/collab-capital-launches-with-a-50-million-target-and-a-mission-to-help-black-entrepreneurs/">Collab Capital saw some of its LPs pull back</a> or delay commitments.</p>
<p>“We were very adamant that the most important thing we wanted to solve was the funding gap for Black founders, so we were not willing to broaden the spectrum there because we saw that there were so many firms out there for diverse founders, and even in some of those, Black founders were still marginalized.”</p>
<p>While the majority of venture dollars are still managed by white men, Black-led venture capital firms are having quite the year. Collab Capital’s news is preceded by Harlem Capital, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/harlem-capital-fund-ii/">closed a $134 million seed fund </a>earlier this year, Cleo Capital, which set a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/cleo-capital-is-targeting-20-million-for-fund-ii/'"> $20 million target for Fund II</a>, and MaC VC <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/closing-on-103-million-mac-venture-capital-is-changing-the-face-of-venture-capital/">landing $103 million for its inaugural fund. </a></p>
<p>Beyond a broader understanding of the importance of diversity in tech, Burks pointed to Zoom as a value unlock.</p>
<p>“If you&#8217;d asked me a year ago [if] I think we&#8217;d be successful in raising $50 million over Zoom meetings, I would have said absolutely not,” she said. “But you can build meaningful relationships with people and not even have to be in person. That’s a big surprise &#8212; and, oh, the realization that you don’t have to travel so much.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/collab-capital-closes-50-million-debut-fund-for-black-founders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157279</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Glovo splurges $208M on three Delivery Hero brands in the Balkans</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/glovo-delivery-hero-brands-consolidation-chicken/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/glovo-delivery-hero-brands-consolidation-chicken/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balkans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barcelona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bulgaria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[central europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[croatia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delivery Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eastern europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foodpanda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[just eat takeaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Just-Eat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Montenegro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niklas ostberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oscar Pierre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[take out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Takeaway.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The high stakes game of chess (or, well, consolidation chicken) that is on-demand food delivery rolls on today with a little more territorial swapping in Europe: Barcelona-based Glovo has agreed to buy three of Berlin-based Delivery Hero&#8217;s food delivery brands in Central and Eastern Europe &#8212; with deals that it said are worth a total [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The high stakes game of chess (or, well, consolidation chicken) that is on-demand food delivery rolls on today with a little more territorial swapping in Europe: Barcelona-based Glovo has agreed to buy three of Berlin-based Delivery Hero&#8217;s food delivery brands in Central and Eastern Europe &#8212; with deals that it said are worth a total value of €170 million (~$208M).</p>
<p>Specifically, it&#8217;s picking up Delivery Hero&#8217;s foodpanda brand in Romania and Bulgaria; the Donesi brand in Serbia, Montenegro, Bosnia and Herzegovina; and Pauza in Croatia.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s some notable symmetry here: Last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/delivery-hero-picks-up-glovos-latam-ops-for-272m-in-latest-food-delivery-consolidation/">Delivery Hero shelled out $272M for a bunch of Glovo&#8217;s LatAm brands</a>, as the latter gave up on a region it had already <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/21/glovo-exits-the-middle-east-and-drops-two-latam-markets-in-latest-food-delivery-crunch/">started withdrawing from</a> in its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/19/spains-glovo-grabs-166m-series-e-for-its-deliver-anything-app/">quest for profitability</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Glovo said then that it would be focusing on &#8220;key markets where we can build a long-term sustainable business and continue to provide our unique multi-category offering to our customers&#8221;.</p>
<p>Earlier this month the Barcelona-based &#8216;deliver anything&#8217; app also announced it was picking up Ehrana, a local delivery company in Slovenia. So it&#8217;s been on quite the (local) shopping spree of late.</p>
<p>Its existing operational footprint covers markets in South West Europe, Eastern Europe and Sub-Saharan Africa. So its attention here, on the Balkans, suggests it sees a chance to eke out profitable potential in more of Central Europe too.</p>
<p>Glovo said the transactions in Bosnia Herzegovina, Bulgaria, Croatia, Montenegro and Serbia are expected to close &#8220;within the next few weeks&#8221;, subject to fulfilment of closing conditions and relevant regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>While it said Romania will be completed following approval from the competition authority &#8212; but gave no timeline for that.</p>
<p>Its splurge on Central and Eastern European rival food delivery brands follows a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/spains-glovo-picks-up-528m-as-the-food-deliver-market-continues-to-heat-up/">$528M Series F funding round in April</a> &#8212; so it&#8217;s evidently not short of VC cash to <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">burn</span> spend.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Oscar Pierre, CEO and co-founder, said: “It’s always been central to our long-term strategy to focus on markets where we see clear opportunities to lead and where we can build a sustainable business. Central and Eastern Europe is a very important part of that plan. The region has really embraced on-demand delivery platforms and we’re very excited to be strengthening our presence and increasing our footprint in countries that continue to show enormous potential for growth.” <b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr">In another supporting statement Delivery Hero made it clear it has bigger fish to fry (than can be served up to hungry customers in the Balkans) right now.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Delivery Hero has built a clear leading business in the Balkan region in the last couple of years. However, with a lot of operational priorities on our plate, we believe <span class="il">Glovo</span> would be better positioned to continue building an amazing experience for our customers in this region,&#8221; said Niklas Östberg, its CEO and co-founder.</p>
<p dir="ltr">A relevant, recent development for <a href="https://www.deliveryhero.com/newsroom/delivery-hero-to-launch-operations-in-berlin/">Delivery Hero</a>&#8216;s business is the decision to re-enter its home market of Germany &#8212; Europe&#8217;s biggest economy &#8212; under its foodpanda brand, starting in its home city of Berlin this summer (but with a national expansion planned to follow).</p>
<p dir="ltr">This is notable because back in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/21/takeaway-delivery-hero-gobble-gobble/">2018</a> it sold its German operations to another on-demand food delivery rival, the Dutch giant Takeaway.com &#8212; in a $1.1BN deal which included the Lieferheld, Pizza.de and foodora brands <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8212; temporarily stepping out of the competitive fray.</span> (<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Meanwhile Takeaway.com has since merged with the UK&#8217;s Just Eat to become&#8230; </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/23/justeat-takeaway-7-6b-merger-approved-pair-pick-up-756m-in-new-funding/">Just Eat Takeaway</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> so, uh, keep up.)</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">Delivery Hero is returning to Germany now because it can, and because the market is huge. A two-year non-compete clause between it and Just Eat Takeaway recently expired &#8212; allowing for reheating (rehashing?) of the competitive food delivery mix in German cities.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Speaking to the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6b52561c-63a9-4393-928b-c05a03ae6404">FT</a> back in May about this market return, Östberg suggested Delivery Hero has girded itself (and its investors) for a long fight.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;We don’t see necessarily that we are going to go in and win the market in the next year or so. This is a 10-year game,&#8221; he said. “Of course we will definitely make sure we put in enough money to be the clear number two, the clear challenger [to Just Eat Takeaway.com].”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Winning at food delivery is certainly a(n expensive) marathon, not a sprint.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There are also of course multiple races being run in markets around the world, depending on local conditions and competitive mix &#8212; with the chance that the winner of the biggest and most lucrative races will reach such a position of VC-sponsored glory that it can buy up the top competitors from the smaller races and consolidate everything &#8212; maximizing economies of scale and gaining the ability to squeeze out fresh competition to grab a juicy profit for themselves.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Or, well, that&#8217;s the theory. Competition regulators are likely to take increasing interest in this space, for one thing. Rising awareness of gig economy workers rights is also putting pressure on the model.</p>
<p>For now, the thin-margin food delivery business needs the right base conditions to survive. The model only functions in cities and ideally in highly dense urban environments. Most of the players in this space also do not employ the armies of riders that are needed to make deliveries &#8212; because doing so would make the model far more costly. And in Europe political attention on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/europe-kicks-off-bid-to-find-a-route-to-better-gig-work/">gig economy workers rights </a>could force reforms that raise regional operational costs, putting further pressure on margins.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/spain-agrees-on-labor-reform-that-will-recognize-delivery-platform-riders-as-employees/">Spain has its own labor reforms in train</a> that will affect Glovo in its home market, for example.</p>
<p>Achieving sustainability (i.e. profitability without the need for ongoing VC funding injections) remains a huge hurdle for delivery apps. It will likely require massive market consolidation and/or convincing users to switch from making the occasional order of a hot meal on a weekend to relying on app-based delivery for far more of their local shopping needs &#8212; not just lunch/dinner but groceries and toiletries, and other fast moving consumers goods and household items.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s notable that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/spains-glovo-inks-real-estate-tie-up-to-add-more-dark-stores-for-speedy-urban-delivery/">super fast grocery delivery is a major focus for Glovo</a>, for example &#8212; which has recently been building out networks of inner city dark stores to service in-app convenience store shopping.</p>
<p>Lots of other on-demand app players are also ramping up on that front. Including Delivery Hero &#8212; which has been paying more attention to groceries (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/on-demand-grocery-startup-instashop-acquired-by-delivery-hero-for-360m/">picking up InstaShop last year</a> in a deal worth $360M).</p>
<p>Glovo building out in Central Europe while exiting markets further afield suggests it believes it can use a concentrated market footprint to drive operational efficiencies and strong order margins through a tightly integrated meal delivery and dark store play.</p>
<p>If it can do that &#8212; and offer at least the whiff of profitability &#8212; it could make its business an attractive future acquisition target for a larger global giant that&#8217;s looking to up the &#8216;consolidation chicken&#8217; stakes by bolting on new regions.</p>
<p>A larger player like Delivery Hero may even be a potential future suitor &#8212; having shown it&#8217;s happy to return to markets it left earlier. After all, it surely knows Glovo&#8217;s business pretty well since they&#8217;ve done a number of market swaps. But, for now, that&#8217;s pure speculation.</p>
<p>Zooming out, what the on-demand model of app-based urban convenience means for the future of urban environments is a whole other question &#8212; and one which both competition and urban regulators will need to ponder very carefully.</p>
<p>If the rush to scale delivery platforms drives unstoppable consolidation that sees smaller players gobbled up by a few global giants &#8212; that can then use their size and scale to outcompete local shops &#8212; it may spell even more dark times for the traditional High Street and its family-run bodegas.</p>
<p>Local retail in many places has already been hammered by Internet giants like Amazon. Delivery apps are another high tech threat to bricks-and-mortar shopping. Touch of a button convenience does carry wider costs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VtP6DwwT8G"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/21/glovo-exits-the-middle-east-and-drops-two-latam-markets-in-latest-food-delivery-crunch/">Glovo exits the Middle East and drops two LatAm markets in latest food delivery crunch</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Glovo exits the Middle East and drops two LatAm markets in latest food delivery crunch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/21/glovo-exits-the-middle-east-and-drops-two-latam-markets-in-latest-food-delivery-crunch/embed/#?secret=VtP6DwwT8G" data-secret="VtP6DwwT8G" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H3fLAm8Mb9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/spains-glovo-picks-up-528m-as-the-food-deliver-market-continues-to-heat-up/">Spain&#8217;s Glovo picks up $528M as Europe&#8217;s food delivery market continues to heat up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spain&#8217;s Glovo picks up $528M as Europe&#8217;s food delivery market continues to heat up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/spains-glovo-picks-up-528m-as-the-food-deliver-market-continues-to-heat-up/embed/#?secret=H3fLAm8Mb9" data-secret="H3fLAm8Mb9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qmiIUVjBIf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/delivery-hero-ceo-shares-what-hes-learned-about-managing-logistics-during-a-pandemic/">Delivery Hero CEO shares what he&#8217;s learned about managing logistics during a pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delivery Hero CEO shares what he&#8217;s learned about managing logistics during a pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/delivery-hero-ceo-shares-what-hes-learned-about-managing-logistics-during-a-pandemic/embed/#?secret=qmiIUVjBIf" data-secret="qmiIUVjBIf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/glovo-delivery-hero-brands-consolidation-chicken/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157555</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
