<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 22:55:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Teaching robots to socialize</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/teaching-robots-to-socialize/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/teaching-robots-to-socialize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 22:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSAIL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Politeness doesn’t really amount to much when you’re programmed to get from point A to point B. But if robots are going to play an increased role in human society, questions arise around how precisely they’ll get along with the rest of us. “Robots will live in our world soon enough and they really need [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Politeness doesn’t really amount to much when you’re programmed to get from point A to point B. But if robots are going to play an increased role in human society, questions arise around how precisely they’ll get along with the rest of us.</p>
<p>“Robots will live in our world soon enough and they really need to learn how to communicate with us on human terms,” MIT CSAIL research scientist Boris Katz said in a statement tied to <a href="https://openreview.net/pdf?id=3HZLte8gMYS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a new research paper.</a> “They need to understand when it is time for them to help and when it is time for them to see what they can do to prevent something from happening.”</p>
<p>The team calls the paper, “the first very serious attempt for understanding what it means for humans and machines to interact socially.” The validity of such a claim may be up for dispute; the problem it’s attempting to solve in a very early stage is no doubt one roboticists will increasingly consider as robots begin to play an outsized role in our lives.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230189" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Researchers conducted tests in a simulated environment, to develop what they deemed “realistic and predictable” interactions between robots. In the simulation, one robot watches another perform a task, attempts to determine the goal and then either attempts to help or hamper it in that task.</p>
<p>“We have opened a new mathematical framework for how you model social interaction between two agents,” fellow project lead Ravi Tejwani said in a statement. “If you are a robot, and you want to go to location X, and I am another robot and I see that you are trying to go to location X, I can cooperate by helping you get to location X faster. That might mean moving X closer to you, finding another better X, or taking whatever action you had to take at X. Our formulation allows the plan to discover the ‘how’; we specify the ‘what’ in terms of what social interactions mean mathematically.”</p>
<p>The model is currently a relatively simple 2D simulation. The team is working to move toward a 3D version, while adding a neural network-based robot planner to increase the speed with which the robots learn from these actions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/teaching-robots-to-socialize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230189</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I learned building a fact-checking startup</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/what-i-learned-building-a-fact-checking-startup/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/what-i-learned-building-a-fact-checking-startup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 22:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fact checking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factmata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fake news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Global Affairs Project]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our thesis was clear: If technology could drive people to seek truth, facts, statistics and data to make their decisions, we could build an online discourse of reason and rationality.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Dhruv Ghulati</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Dhruv Ghulati founded one of the first global startups tackling online misinformation and is one of the first machine learning scientists to research automated fact-checking. He holds degrees in economics and computer science from the London School of Economics and University College London.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In the aftermath of the 2016 U.S. election, I set out to build a product that could tackle the scourge of fake news online. My initial hypothesis was simple: build a semi-automated fact-checking algorithm that could automatically highlight any false or dubious claim and suggest the best-quality contextual facts for it. Our thesis was clear, if perhaps utopian: If technology could drive people to seek truth, facts, statistics and data to make their decisions, we could build an online discourse of reason and rationality instead of hyperbole.</p>
<p>After five years of <a href="https://medium.com/factmata/3-stage-plan-e2f9f06bdd62">hard work</a>, Factmata has had some successes. But for this space to truly thrive, there are a great deal of barriers, from economic to technological, that still must be overcome.</p>
<h2>Key challenges</h2>
<p>We quickly realized that automated fact-checking represents an extremely hard research problem. The first challenge was defining just what facts we were checking. Next, it was thinking about how we could build and maintain up-to-date databases of facts that would allow us to assess the accuracy of given claims. For example, the commonly-used <a href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Wikidata:Main_Page">Wikidata</a> knowledge base was an obvious option, but it updates too slowly to check claims about rapidly changing events.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2226330 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?w=300" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-sq.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2228948" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>We also discovered that being a for-profit fact-checking company was an obstacle. Most journalism and fact-checking networks are nonprofit, and social media platforms prefer working with nonprofits in order to avoid accusations of bias.</p>
<p>Beyond these factors, building a business that can rate what is &#8220;good&#8221; is inherently complex and nuanced. Definitions are endlessly debatable. For example, what people called &#8220;fake news&#8221; often turned out to be extreme hyperpartisanship, and what people proclaimed &#8220;misinformation&#8221; were really contrarian opinions.</p>
<p>Thus, we concluded that detecting what was &#8220;bad&#8221; (toxic, obscene, threatening or hateful) was a much easier route from a business standpoint. Specifically, we decided to detect &#8220;gray area&#8221; harmful text — content that a platform is not sure should be removed but needs additional context. To achieve this, we built an API that scores the harmfulness of comments, posts and news articles for their level of hyperpartisanship, controversiality, objectivity, hatefulness and 15 other signals.</p>
<p>We realized that there was value in tracking all the claims evolving online about relevant corporate issues. Thus, beyond our API we built a SaaS platform that tracks rumors and &#8220;narratives&#8221; evolving in any topic, whether it is about a brand’s products, a government policy or COVID-19 vaccines.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>If this sounds complicated, that’s because it is. One of the biggest lessons we learned was just how little $1 million in seed funding goes in this space. Training data around validated hate speech and false claims is no ordinary labeling task — it requires subject-matter expertise and precise deliberations, neither of which comes cheaply.</p>
<p>In fact, building the tools we needed — including multiple browser extensions, website demos, a data labeling platform, a social news commenting platform and live real-time dashboards of our AI’s output — was akin to building several new startups all at the same time.</p>
<p>Complicating things further, finding product-market fit was a very hard journey. After many years of building, Factmata has shifted to brand safety and brand reputation. We sell our technology to online advertising platforms looking to clean up their ad inventory, brands looking for reputation management and optimization, and smaller scale platforms looking for content moderation. It took us a long time to reach this business model, but in the last year we have finally seen multiple customers sign up for trials and contracts every month, and we are on target for $1 million in recurring revenues by mid-2022.</p>
<h2>What needs to be done</h2>
<p>Our journey demonstrates the high number of barriers to building a socially impactful business in the media space. As long as virality and drawing eyeballs are the metrics for the online advertising, search engines and newsfeeds, change will be hard. And small firms can’t do it on their own; they will need both regulatory and financial support.</p>
<p>Regulators need to step up and start enacting strong laws. Facebook and Twitter have taken massive strides, but the online advertising systems are far behind and emerging platforms have no incentive to evolve differently. Right now, there is no incentive for companies to moderate their platforms of any speech that isn’t illegal — reputational damage or fear of user churn are not enough. Even the most ardent supporters of free speech, as I am, recognize the need to create financial incentives and bans so that platforms really take action and start spending money to reduce harmful content and promote ecosystem health.</p>
<p>What would an alternative look like? Bad content will always exist, but we can create a system that promotes better content.</p>
<p>As flawed as they may be, algorithms have a big role to play; they have the potential to automatically assess online content for its &#8220;goodness,&#8221; or quality. These &#8220;quality scores&#8221; could be the basis to create new social media platforms that aren’t ad based at all but used to promote (and pay for) content that is beneficial to society.</p>
<p>Given the scope of the problem, it will take immense resources to build these new scoring algorithms — even the most innovative startups will struggle without tens, if not hundreds, of millions of dollars in funding. It will require multiple companies and nonprofits, all providing different versions that can embed in people’s newsfeeds.</p>
<p>Government can help in several ways. First, it should define the rules around &#8220;quality&#8221;; firms trying to solve this problem shouldn’t be expected to make up their own policies.</p>
<p>Government should also provide funding. Government funding would allow these companies to avoid watering down their goals. It would also encourage firms to make their technologies open to public scrutiny and create transparency around flaws and biases. The technologies could even be encouraged to be released to the public for free and available use, and ultimately provided for public benefit.</p>
<p>Finally, we need to embrace emerging technologies. There have been positive strides by the platforms to invest seriously in the deep technology required to do content moderation effectively and sustainably. The ad industry, four years on, has also made progress adopting new brand safety algorithms such as Factmata’s, that of the Global Disinformation Index and Newsguard.</p>
<p>Although initially a skeptic, I am also optimistic about the potential of cryptocurrency and token economics to present a new way of funding and encouraging good quality, fact-checked media to prevail and distribute at scale. For example, &#8220;experts&#8221; in tokenized systems can be encouraged to fact-check claims and efficiently scale data labeling for AI content moderation systems without firms needing large upfront investments to pay for labeling.</p>
<p>I don’t know if the original vision I set out for Factmata, as the technological component of a fact-based world, will ever be realized. But I am proud that we gave it a shot and am hopeful that our experiences can help others chart a healthier direction in the ongoing battle against misinformation and disinformation.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-global-affairs-project/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/global-affairs-project-footer.jpg" alt="Read more from the TechCrunch Global Affairs Project" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/what-i-learned-building-a-fact-checking-startup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228948</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helion Energy will use $500M Series E to power up its fusion energy efforts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-energy-will-use-500m-series-e-to-power-up-its-fusion-energy-efforts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-energy-will-use-500m-series-e-to-power-up-its-fusion-energy-efforts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 22:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for November 5, 2021! We made it, everyone, happy Friday. Don’t forget to take off in the direction of our upcoming Space event before we reach exit velocity and leave you behind! And have a relaxed weekend. We’re all a little tired. — Alex All systems go: Buy your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for November 5, 2021! We made it, everyone, happy Friday. Don’t forget to take off in the direction of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/">our upcoming Space event</a> before we reach exit velocity and leave you behind! And have a relaxed weekend. We’re all a little tired. — <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TUQkIlmsNC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/">All systems go: Buy your pass to TC Sessions: Space 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;All systems go: Buy your pass to TC Sessions: Space 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/embed/#?secret=TUQkIlmsNC" data-secret="TUQkIlmsNC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/"><strong>How Cruise intends to make robotaxis a commercial reality:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Curious why we are not yet zipping around in computer-driven cars, putting the days of wondering if right turns on a red light are allowed? Me too. The answer is that to get to that point is much more work than folks may have thought. Cruise is turning to simulators and custom silicon for its own efforts. Let’s hope they have cracked it. I hate driving.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/hashicorps-ipo-filing-reveals-a-growing-business-but-at-a-slower-pace/"><strong>HashiCorp’s IPO details an open source powerhouse:</strong></a> It’s always good fun to chat with companies building open source code. Once an oddity, many startups today are working on and with code that is open for all. HashiCorp has ridden the trend all the way to an IPO filing, which we were more than excited to read.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-series-e/"><strong>$500M+ for commercial fusion:</strong></a><strong> </strong>While we are on the subject of tricky tech challenges like self-driving cars, let’s talk about fusion for a minute. Helion Energy just raised $500 million for its efforts to pull energy from fusion reactions, with another $1.7 billion in the offing if it can hit certain milestones. The question, TechCrunch notes, is whether the company can yank more power from its fusion tech than it takes to operate. Let’s see.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we get into specific news items, if it feels like today’s venture capitalists are putting more capital to work, more quickly, while getting smaller ownership stakes in global startups, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/vcs-are-racing-to-pay-more-to-get-smaller-pieces-of-less-profitable-companies/">you are right!</a> The question is if they are growing more quickly.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230146" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/lime-raises-523-million-as-it-prepares-to-go-public/"><strong>Lime raises pre-IPO round:</strong></a> Now that Bird is a public company, it only seems fitting that its former archrival Lime is also prepping its own public offering. The green-branded scooter and e-bike company just locked in $523 million in new funding, including $418 million of convertible debt. Let’s see if Lime can <em>scoot</em> its way to an IPO in short order.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/momenta-500-million/"><strong>More money for self-driving tech:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Speaking of nine-figure rounds for things that move, Momenta has just added $500 million to its own coffers. The autonomous driving tech company from China had previously raised $300 million in a round that it just extended. That’s a lot of duckets. At this point I am curious if we’ve seen north of $100 billion invested privately to tackle this particular technology challenge.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/dji-mavic-3-best-drone-price-msrp-2199/"><strong>New DJI drone is good, expensive:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Drone tech has taken leaps and bounds in recent years, improving across nearly all strata that we care about. Our own Matt Burns confirms as much in his review of the new DJI Mavic 3. Sadly it costs north of $2,000, so will fly far from the hands of most consumers.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/"><strong>Thirteen Lune raises $3M, partners with major American retailer:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The beauty market is big business, and Thirteen Lune is taking its direct-to-consumer beauty platform to the masses with a partnership with Target. That deal made TechCrunch sit up and take note of the company’s funding and progress.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/milkrun-lands-new-capital-to-deliver-farm-fresh-groceries/"><strong>Today in good startup names, we present MilkRun:</strong></a> Regardless of if you buy milk by the gallon, or the <a href="https://www.chron.com/news/local/article/CNN-segment-Twitter-losing-it-Texas-milk-16592454.php">dozens of gallons</a>, we all eat and drink each day. MilkRun wants to feed you with its “subscription service delivering weekly grocery staples sourced from small, local farms,” TechCrunch reports. Now flush with a $6 million Series A, the startup is hoping to extend its growth that saw it bolster revenues by 15x in 2020.</li>
<li>And if you want the TechCrunch take on recent venture capital data regarding female founders, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/three-quarters-of-record-breaking-funding-for-female-founders-is-a-win/">we have just the podcast for you</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</h2>
<p>With only three weeks left to the start of the holiday shopping season, Miranda Halpern checked in with several growth marketers to find out how they&#8217;re advising their clients to prepare for supply chain disruptions.</p>
<p>Cargo ships are stacked up outside ports, and empty shipping containers are in short supply, as are the truck drivers who would take them to market. This is not the time for doing business as usual.</p>
<p>To gather advice and insights, she interviewed:</p>
<ul>
<li>Julio Lopez, director of client strategy, retail practice lead, Movable Ink</li>
<li>Chris Toy, CEO and co-founder, Marketer Hire</li>
<li>Kristin Dick, head of operations and growth marketer, Tuff</li>
<li>Dipti Parmar, founder, Dipti Parmar Consulting</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HSQWy16n9i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/embed/#?secret=HSQWy16n9i" data-secret="HSQWy16n9i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(TechCrunch+ is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/tencent-chips-semiconductor/"><strong>Don’t be surprised that Tencent is making its own chips:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Thus argues our own Rita Liao, who does a killer job on the China beat. The Chinese tech giant got a stock market boost this week when it showed off new chips under its own imprint. With news from Cruise and Tencent this week on the silicon front, perhaps we should expect every company over a certain market cap to have its own chips coming in the future.</li>
<li>“A flagship framework used by Google and scores of other advertisers for gathering claimed consent from web users for creepy ad targeting looks set to be found in breach of Europe’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR),” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/"><strong>writes our own Natasha Lomas</strong></a>, our reporter on the EU privacy beat. It turns out that a method of collecting consent to comply with GDPR isn’t, well, in compliance.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2217068" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2217068" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2217068" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg" alt="dc experts" width="1024" height="628" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg 7956w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=300,184 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=768,471 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=680,417 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=1536,941 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=2048,1255 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/TCexperts_softwareconsulting-1.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2217068" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SEAN GLADWELL / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how these surveys are shaping our coverage, check out this article on TechCrunch+ from Miranda Halpern, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">“The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?”</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-energy-will-use-500m-series-e-to-power-up-its-fusion-energy-efforts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230146</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New antitrust suit from Phhhoto alleges Facebook copied and killed the competition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/phhhoto-sues-meta-facebook-antitrust/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/phhhoto-sues-meta-facebook-antitrust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 21:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boomerang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gary reback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gif]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Systrom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Menlo Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phhhoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK parliament]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A former upstart Instagram rival is suing Meta, formerly known as Facebook, over allegations that the company violated antitrust laws by cloning a competing product and ultimately killing its business. The app, Phhhoto, launched in 2014, inviting users to create and share short GIF-like videos. If that sounds familiar, that&#8217;s because the same functionality was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A former upstart Instagram rival is suing Meta, formerly known as Facebook, over allegations that the company violated antitrust laws by cloning a competing product and ultimately killing its business.</p>
<p>The app, Phhhoto, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/15/phhhoto-is-an-addictive-albeit-poorly-named-gif-style-photo-app/">launched in 2014,</a> inviting users to create and share short GIF-like videos. If that sounds familiar, that&#8217;s because the same functionality was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/22/instagram-boomerang/">popularized in Boomerang</a>, an app made by Instagram. That feature is now integrated into Instagram&#8217;s core app experience.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rEQfK0Z2y5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/15/phhhoto-is-an-addictive-albeit-poorly-named-gif-style-photo-app/">Phhhoto Is An Addictive, Albeit Poorly Named, Gif-Style Photo App</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230141" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Phhhoto Is An Addictive, Albeit Poorly Named, Gif-Style Photo App&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/09/15/phhhoto-is-an-addictive-albeit-poorly-named-gif-style-photo-app/embed/#?secret=rEQfK0Z2y5" data-secret="rEQfK0Z2y5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The newly filed lawsuit, embedded below, alleges that Facebook&#8217;s behavior violated antitrust laws by cutting off the app&#8217;s access to its social graph, slow-walking a proposed relationship and then eventually releasing its own copy of Phhhoto&#8217;s core feature: the seconds-long looping video.</p>
<p>Menlo Park-based lawyer Gary Reback will represent Phhhoto in the suit. Reback is best known for his involvement in setting the stage for the federal government&#8217;s successful antitrust case against Microsoft, which ultimately didn&#8217;t split up the tech giant but did force the company to open up some aspects of its computing business — consequences that continue to reverberate in the tech industry today.</p>
<p>Reback argues that Phhhoto&#8217;s experience underlines why it&#8217;s detrimental to the market when a massive tech company buys out its competition and starts running those businesses.</p>
<p>&#8220;The record here demonstrates that Facebook would have partnered with Phhhoto and launched to prominence this great new social network that would have competed with Instagram,&#8221; Reback said. He highlighted the unusually hands-on approach that Facebook&#8217;s top leadership took with the nascent competitor.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Phhhoto climbed the iOS app charts after its launch, eventually boasting 3.7 monthly active users at its peak popularity. As the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/03/30/phhhoto-tops-1-million-users/">hot new social app attracted attention</a>, Facebook executives took interest — including Mark Zuckerberg.</p>
<p>&#8220;On or about August 8, 2014, Zuckerberg downloaded and installed the app onto his phone, entered the phone number of his device into the Phhhoto app, created a personal account, and posted a profile picture of himself (reproduced below) to his new Phhhoto account,&#8221; the suit reads.</p>
<p>The suit includes receipts — namely, Zuckerberg&#8217;s own selfie, taken as he was testing the app.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2230181" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2230181" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2230181" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?w=650" alt="Zuckerberg Phhhoto selfie" width="650" height="672" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png 650w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=145,150 145w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=290,300 290w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-05-at-12.08.02-PM.png?resize=48,50 48w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2230181" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Phhhoto</p></div></p>
<p>Instagram co-founder Kevin Systrom, who led Instagram at the time, also downloaded the app and explored its features. According to the lawsuit, Facebook began courting Phhhoto, offering partnership opportunities that it later reneged on:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;&#8230; Hurren, then Facebook’s Strategic Partnerships Manager, reached out to<br />
Phhhoto, asserting that Phhhoto was &#8216;really awesome.&#8217; Hurren first offered to incorporate<br />
Phhhoto’s technology into the Facebook Messenger service. When Phhhoto declined, Hurren offered to incorporate Phhhoto’s content into Facebook’s users’ Newsfeeds. Phhhoto invested heavily in this project, but ultimately Hurren did not move forward, citing internal “legal conversations” that “hung” the project up.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>After the relationship failed to materialize, the suit alleges that Facebook took a number of actions meant to drive it out of business, including removing pre-populated Instagram hashtags that indicate where content on the app originated. Instagram also cut Phhhoto off from its social graph, blocking the perceived competitor&#8217;s users from connecting with their Instagram friends in the app.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zJGwjksstx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/24/nochill/">Instagram Cuts Off Hot GIF App Phhhoto From Its Social Graph</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram Cuts Off Hot GIF App Phhhoto From Its Social Graph&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/24/nochill/embed/#?secret=zJGwjksstx" data-secret="zJGwjksstx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Phhhoto&#8217;s demise had some dramatic moments: On October 22, 2015, the same day the company was set to launch an Android version of its app, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/10/22/instagram-boomerang/">Instagram launched Boomerang</a>. The suit identifies Boomerang product manager John Barnett as an &#8220;active Phhhoto user.&#8221; At the time of launch, TechCrunch noted that Boomerang appeared &#8220;suspiciously similar&#8221; to Phhhoto.</p>
<p>The suit alleges that Boomerang was the culmination of Facebook&#8217;s anticompetitive effort, effectively killing the smaller company with a copycat app that reproduced Phhhoto&#8217;s innovations &#8220;feature-by-feature.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to the suit, Phhhoto wasn&#8217;t even aware of the extent of Facebook&#8217;s aggressive behavior against other competitors at the time, learning more after the UK Parliament released a<a href="https://www.parliament.uk/globalassets/documents/commons-committees/culture-media-and-sport/Note-by-Chair-and-selected-documents-ordered-from-Six4Three.pdf"> trove of the company&#8217;s internal documents in late 2018</a>.</p>
<p>Phhhoto wasn&#8217;t afraid to speak out about Facebook&#8217;s moves as this all went down. &#8220;We watched Systrom and his product team quietly using Phhhoto almost a year before Boomerang was released,&#8221; Phhhoto co-founder Champ Bennett <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/phhhoto-shuts-down/">told TechCrunch in 2017</a>.</p>
<p>After the app shut down, Bennett said that it &#8220;wasn’t a surprise at all&#8221; to see Instagram launch its own clone.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/537444585/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-sYNyLLMrS7fNrk06UG1w"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_537444585" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/537444585" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A1LjuGjTAB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/24/nochill/">Instagram Cuts Off Hot GIF App Phhhoto From Its Social Graph</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram Cuts Off Hot GIF App Phhhoto From Its Social Graph&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/04/24/nochill/embed/#?secret=A1LjuGjTAB" data-secret="A1LjuGjTAB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wcu6Vtiiih"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/phhhoto-shuts-down/">Phhhoto shutters app and pivots to photobooths, blaming Instagram</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Phhhoto shutters app and pivots to photobooths, blaming Instagram&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/06/20/phhhoto-shuts-down/embed/#?secret=wcu6Vtiiih" data-secret="wcu6Vtiiih" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/phhhoto-sues-meta-facebook-antitrust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230141</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter is rolling out a feature to make it easier to search a user&#8217;s tweets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/twitter-is-rolling-out-a-feature-to-make-it-easier-to-search-a-users-tweets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/twitter-is-rolling-out-a-feature-to-make-it-easier-to-search-a-users-tweets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 21:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real time Web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some Twitter users on iOS are starting to get access to a feature that makes it easy to search an individual user&#8217;s tweets. For those with access, when you navigate to a user&#8217;s profile, you&#8217;ll see a search icon in the top right corner of the screen on the user&#8217;s profile banner, next to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Some Twitter users on iOS are starting to get access to a feature that makes it easy to search an individual user&#8217;s tweets. For those with access, when you navigate to a user&#8217;s profile, you&#8217;ll see a search icon in the top right corner of the screen on the user&#8217;s profile banner, next to the three-dot menu. Then, you can type in keywords to search the user&#8217;s tweets. Twitter told TechCrunch that this feature is available to all global users on iOS and will continue to slowly roll out on web and Android.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Twitter <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f50d.png" alt="🔍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> search user’s tweets button on profiles is now available (for some users)</p>
<p>h/t <a href="https://twitter.com/RefaelCohe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RefaelCohe</a> <a href="https://t.co/K8QSUZ0iHr">pic.twitter.com/K8QSUZ0iHr</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229941" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&mdash; Matt Navarra (@MattNavarra) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1447556138145394692?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It was already possible to perform searches like this on Twitter &#8212; you just needed to know how to format an <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/twitter-advanced-search">advanced search</a>. So, if you search &#8220;from:@TechCrunch Twitter,&#8221; for example, you&#8217;ll be able to see all TechCrunch tweets containing the word &#8220;Twitter,&#8221; regardless of whether you have access to the new search feature. Twitter&#8217;s longstanding <a href="https://twitter.com/search-advanced">advanced search</a> feature can be accessed by searching for something, then clicking the three-dot menu next to the search bar on the web. You can filter searches by date, by the amount of engagement and more.</p>
<p>Still, this easily accessible search button makes it easier to find tweets from a specific user &#8212; so, using the same example, if you didn&#8217;t know how to perform an advanced search, it would be much easier to use the search button to look for &#8220;Twitter&#8221; on TechCrunch&#8217;s account, rather than scrolling through dozens of daily tweets to find what you&#8217;re looking for.</p>
<p>Of course, it&#8217;s possible that this feature could make it easier for people to dig up others&#8217; old, troublesome tweets. But, as always, it&#8217;s a great social media strategy to just not tweet potentially harmful content in the first place (also, delete old tweets).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/twitter-is-rolling-out-a-feature-to-make-it-easier-to-search-a-users-tweets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With a Section 1045 rollover, founders can salvage QSBS before 5 years</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/with-a-section-1045-rollover-founders-can-salvage-qsbs-before-5-years/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/with-a-section-1045-rollover-founders-can-salvage-qsbs-before-5-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 20:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capital gains tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[countries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228020</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Section 1045 allows a founder or stockholder whose company has been sold before the five-year holding period to defer the capital gain by rolling the sale proceeds into a replacement QSBS.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Peyton Carr</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/jpeytoncarr">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Peyton Carr is a financial adviser to founders, entrepreneurs and their families, helping them with planning and investing. He is a managing director of <a href="https://keystonegp.com/">Keystone Global Partners</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/advanced-tax-strategies-for-startup-founders/">Advanced tax strategies for startup founders</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/22/what-you-need-to-know-before-selling-your-companys-stock/">What you need to know before selling your company&#8217;s stock</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Calvin Lo</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/calvinlo">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://keystonegp.com/team-members/calvin-lo-cfa-cfpr">Calvin Lo</a>, CFA, CFP, is a managing director at Keystone Global Partners LLC.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The tax code contains provisions that encourage investments in the technology startup ecosystem and small businesses by rewarding founders, VCs and investors for taking high levels of risk in founding or investing in a startup. One of these provisions is the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/04/how-to-build-or-invest-in-a-startup-without-paying-capital-gains-tax/">Qualified Small Business Stock (QSBS) or Section 1202 stock</a>, which offers the opportunity to eliminate capital gains tax entirely if specific requirements are met.</p>
<p>It is important to note that this 100% capital gains exclusion, made permanent by the Obama administration, has been included in the draft legislation by the House Ways and Means Committee, and includes a proposed cut from 100% exclusion to a 50% exclusion for gains recognized on the sale of QSBS. For the purpose of this article, I’ll speak specifically to the 100% exclusion.</p>
<p>You can learn more about the QSBS rules and requirements <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/04/how-to-build-or-invest-in-a-startup-without-paying-capital-gains-tax/">here</a>. One rule we discuss today is that stockholders must meet a five-year holding period to qualify. However, not everyone can time when to sell their company. The fact that many acquisitions happen before five years leaves some founders and investors short of qualifying for these powerful tax savings.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Stockholders can multiply — or “stack” — the benefit of a 1045 rollover by spreading the QSBS exclusion to more than one new investment.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Section 1045 can salvage the opportunity in some cases.</p>
<h2>What is Section 1045?</h2>
<p>Section 1045 allows a founder or stockholder whose company has been sold before the five-year holding period to defer the capital gains by rolling the sale proceeds into a replacement QSBS.</p>
<h3>Benefits and opportunities</h3>
<p>A 1045 rollover enables founders and investors to take advantage of multiple tax benefits and opportunities they would otherwise miss.</p>
<h3>Extended tax deferral</h3>
<p>With a 1045 rollover, the stockholder can defer taxes on the sale of the original QSBS by investing in a replacement QSBS. Under the right circumstances, tax can be deferred until the replacement QSBS is sold.</p>
<p>If the combined holding period is five years and other requirements (discussed below) are met, no federal capital gains taxes are due. But if the requirements are not met, then taxes will be due upon the sale of the replacement QSBS.</p>
<h3>Shortened holding period</h3>
<p>Typically, the holding period for all taxable exchanges will begin the day after the exchange. However, the holding period for the replacement QSBS includes the holding period of the original QSBS, avoiding a reset of the five-year requirement. This means a 1045 rollover shortens the next QSBS holding period requirement and allows the clock to continue ticking.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2228078" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228078" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2228078" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg" alt="1045 Rollover" width="1024" height="569" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg 1429w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=768,427 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=680,378 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/image1-2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228078" class="wp-caption-text">1045 Rollover.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Keystone Global Partners</p></div></p>
<h3>QSBS exclusion stacking<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/with-a-section-1045-rollover-founders-can-salvage-qsbs-before-5-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228020</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why we rebuilt our equity plan for flexibility (and how you can, too)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/why-we-rebuilt-our-equity-plan-for-flexibility-and-how-you-can-too/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/why-we-rebuilt-our-equity-plan-for-flexibility-and-how-you-can-too/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postscript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[talent acquisition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[talent retention]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The most competitive startups will not only give staff the shares that they deserve but will also do so in a way that’s tax-advantaged, de-risked and highly customizable.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Colin Turner</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/cdturns">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Colin Turner is co-founder and COO of <a href="https://www.postscript.io/">Postscript</a>, an SMS marketing platform leveraged by thousands of Shopify businesses.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Mailchimp made <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/intuits-12b-mailchimp-acquisition-is-about-expanding-its-small-business-focus/">headlines last month</a> when it sold to Intuit for $12 billion, but many of the stories surrounding the news were far from glowing. Its 1,200 employees didn’t get any equity in the company and missed out on the life-changing financial upside that would typically come from a deal of this magnitude.</p>
<p>We know this isn’t the norm. Most startups follow a standard playbook for issuing employee equity, but it’s a system riddled with complications. The industry has even coined terms like &#8220;golden handcuffs&#8221; to describe one of the all too common scenarios where employees have millions in stock options but can’t afford the taxes they’d owe to leave their current company before a liquidity event like an IPO or acquisition.</p>
<p>The employee equity status quo isn’t going to work for much longer. As talent wars rage on, companies are getting more competitive on base salary, bonuses, benefits and workplace flexibility. Equity is bound to be the next to change in the battle for talent.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2228255" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The most competitive startups will not only give staff the shares that they deserve but will also do so in a way that’s tax-advantaged, de-risked and highly customizable. Early on in the journey to build my startup Postscript with my co-founders Adam Turner and Alex Beller, we decided an equity plan that puts employees first was going to be a top priority. We hadn’t done this before, and we weren’t following the standard playbook, so it took time, research and creativity.</p>
<h2>Flexibility and choice are paramount in employee equity</h2>
<p>Our first initiative focused on providing employees with an extended exercise window. If someone has been at the company for two years and quits, they don’t need to buy shares right away. In fact, they have up to five years to make that decision. This is a great option for employees that want to &#8220;wait and see,&#8221; and de-risks their equity.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Within the next few years, I predict that we’re going to see a shift in how employers approach equity as a benefit and that flexibility will become the norm, rather than the exception.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The next component of our program was in response to demand from employees confident in our long-term prospects. We crafted a plan that allows employees to exercise their stock early — at any time, in fact. This is a great option for employees that believe strongly in our success and want to reap the tax advantages of buying their shares early on.</p>
<p>With these two programs, we’re not assuming anything about each employee&#8217;s personal situation or forcing our beliefs on anyone. We’re also careful to not make promises about the future that would influence decisions, as we saw happen with Mailchimp. We don’t believe in declarative statements like &#8220;we’ll never go public&#8221; or &#8220;we’ll never be acquired,&#8221; even if well intentioned. No executive can fully predict the future with absolute certainty.</p>
<p>For businesses that are ready to revamp their employee equity plan, here are a few key lessons we figured out along the way:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h3>Get buy-in from your board of directors</h3>
<p>The first step should be a discussion with your board, likely during the next board meeting. This group of individuals usually hold significant equity in the business, so they may be just as invested in the decision as the founders. If you lead with the business benefits that the changes could have on recruiting, culture and morale, the opportunity for pushback will be limited.</p>
<h3>Get outside support from legal experts</h3>
<p>After the key stakeholders are aligned, loop in the experts. Unless they’re already on the team, find a law firm or legal consultant that knows employee equity inside out. They’ll need to consider every possibility and develop new documentation and contracts that might not already exist. Our legal partner played a huge role in making sure that our plan was initiated without a hitch.</p>
<h3>Double down on employee and candidate education</h3>
<p>Finally, the people and recruiting teams should be educated well on the program. It’s their responsibility to ensure that employees and prospects understand how the program works, as well as the implications of the decisions they make. Equity is complex and can be difficult to understand, so this undertaking shouldn’t be approached lightly and should be ongoing.</p>
<p>Within the next few years, I predict that we’re going to see a shift in how employers approach equity as a benefit and that flexibility will become the norm, rather than the exception. At the end of the day, this is good news for employees and employers alike.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/why-we-rebuilt-our-equity-plan-for-flexibility-and-how-you-can-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228255</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ roundup: Holiday marketing tips, low-cost NFTs, SaaS sprawl study</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/techcrunch-roundup-holiday-marketing-tips-low-cost-nfts-saas-sprawl-study/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/techcrunch-roundup-holiday-marketing-tips-low-cost-nfts-saas-sprawl-study/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[battery ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer acquisition cost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiffany Chu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zillow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cargo ships are stacked up outside ports, and empty shipping containers are in short supply, as are the truck drivers who would take them to market. This is not the time for doing business as usual.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Boston-based VC firm OpenView interviewed nearly 600 SaaS companies for its annual pricing survey and the results are in: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/">Automation is taking usage-based pricing (USP) mainstream</a>.</p>
<p>Last year, 34% of survey respondents said they were using a flexible pricing model. This year, that figure rose to 45%.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription.</i></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230067" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<hr />
<p>“Seats are just an outdated way of charging and don’t allow a company to communicate value or invest in features that would add more value,&#8221; said OpenView operating partner Kyle Poyar.</p>
<p>“In fact,” he said, “it might even be negatively correlated: When AI can automate tasks, the more successful the solution is, the fewer people need to be logging in.&#8221;</p>
<p>The report had many interesting findings, but here&#8217;s the one that left the biggest impression on me: Startups that adopt USP and product-led growth strategies pay back customer acquisition costs faster <strong>and</strong> have higher net-dollar retention.</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading TechCrunch+ — I hope you have a relaxing weekend.</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch+<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jj4OcmWj56"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/">Why more SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based pricing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why more SaaS companies are shifting to usage-based pricing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/more-saas-companies-are-shifting-to-usage-based-pricing/embed/#?secret=jj4OcmWj56" data-secret="jj4OcmWj56" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2229582" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229582" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2229582" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg" alt="Directly Above Shot Of Open Cardboard Box Over White Background" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-1290504387.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229582" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=paolomartinezphotography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">paolomartinezphotography <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>With only three weeks left to the start of the holiday shopping season, Miranda Halpern checked in with several growth marketers to find out how they&#8217;re advising their clients to prepare for supply chain disruptions.</p>
<p>Cargo ships are stacked up outside ports, and empty shipping containers are in short supply, as are the truck drivers who would take them to market. This is not the time for doing business as usual.</p>
<p>To gather advice and insights, she interviewed:</p>
<ul>
<li>Julio Lopez, director of client strategy, retail practice lead, Movable Ink</li>
<li>Chris Toy, CEO and co-founder, Marketer Hire</li>
<li>Kristin Dick, head of operations and growth marketer, Tuff</li>
<li>Dipti Parmar, founder, Dipti Parmar Consulting</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KyAP1HElcL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/">The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The holiday shopping season is coming: How are growth marketers preparing?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/the-holiday-shopping-season-is-coming-how-are-growth-marketers-preparing/embed/#?secret=KyAP1HElcL" data-secret="KyAP1HElcL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Bring on the low-cost NFTs</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The NFT marketplace is still a bit of a head-scratcher for those of us without loads of expendable income, but new data from DappRadar provides some insight into what the masses value.</p>
<p>As Alex Wilhelm reports, a lot of  activity is focused on games like Axie Infinity, where players can collect and do battle with Pokémon-esque NFTs priced at around $250.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That gives us a look into the nascent non-fungible token ecosystem and what people want to buy and trade: more affordable, value-generating NFTs that &#8220;unlock an activity that are not artificially supply constrained.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SE3o4rzgcc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/bring-on-the-low-cost-nfts/">Bring on the low-cost NFTs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bring on the low-cost NFTs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/bring-on-the-low-cost-nfts/embed/#?secret=SE3o4rzgcc" data-secret="SE3o4rzgcc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The consequences of SaaS sprawl: A real-world study</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228116" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228116" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228116" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg" alt="Spaghetti and sauce spilled on kitchen floor" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-522063342.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228116" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Lew+Robertson" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lew Robertson <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no way to avoid SaaS sprawl: When employees can independently select software that meets their personal needs, every organization must dodge this pothole.</p>
<p>In a detailed breakdown of a recent research study, returning contributors Tomer Y. Avni and Mark Settle explore the myriad impacts of running a business partially on shadow IT.</p>
<p>Besides numerous administrative problems, SaaS sprawl can create fundamental security risks, especially for companies where many employees can access IP and personally identifiable information.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vdR8Hgne9t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/the-consequences-of-saas-sprawl-a-real-world-study/">The consequences of SaaS sprawl: A real-world study</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The consequences of SaaS sprawl: A real-world study&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/the-consequences-of-saas-sprawl-a-real-world-study/embed/#?secret=vdR8Hgne9t" data-secret="vdR8Hgne9t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>We’re still just scratching the surface of the cloud’s potential</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228389" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228389" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228389" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg" alt="The state of the public cloud in 2021 looks pretty good" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-465993754.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228389" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.in/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=your_photo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">your_photo <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The cloud storage and services market is nowhere near maturity, according to Battery Ventures&#8217; 2021 State of the OpenCloud report.</p>
<p>According to the firm&#8217;s estimate, the market could eventually be worth as much as $1 trillion.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you consider that the vast majority of work, development and computing will be done in the cloud at some point, the investment group’s round-number projection may prove modest,&#8221; write Ron Miller and Alex Wilhelm, who broke down the report and spoke to Battery General Partner Dharmesh Thakker.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uZc5o9PXkw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/were-still-just-scratching-the-surface-of-the-clouds-potential/">We&#8217;re still just scratching the surface of the cloud&#8217;s potential</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;We&#8217;re still just scratching the surface of the cloud&#8217;s potential&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/were-still-just-scratching-the-surface-of-the-clouds-potential/embed/#?secret=uZc5o9PXkw" data-secret="uZc5o9PXkw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What does Zillow’s exit tell us about the health of the iBuying market?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2229680" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229680" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2229680" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg" alt="For Sale sign board in front of a model home" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg 2121w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-82959960.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229680" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Glow+Images" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Glow Images <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>I always learn something while editing stories written by TechCrunch reporters: Because Ryan Lawler covers proptech for us, I asked him to explain the significance of Zillow&#8217;s decision to depart the iBuying business.</p>
<p>This story has been very well covered, but I haven&#8217;t seen anyone else put it this succinctly:</p>
<blockquote><p>Selling an asset at a loss is a bad idea in most areas of business, but it is a particularly bad idea in a market where sales cycles are slow, unpredictable and largely out of your control.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pymoK1Plro"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/zillow-ibuying-exit-opendoor-offerpad/">What does Zillow’s exit tell us about the health of the iBuying market?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What does Zillow’s exit tell us about the health of the iBuying market?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/zillow-ibuying-exit-opendoor-offerpad/embed/#?secret=pymoK1Plro" data-secret="pymoK1Plro" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Via’s Tiffany Chu on the importance of govtech for planning mobility ecosystems</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228055" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228055" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228055" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg" alt="Illustration of Tiffany Chu, SVP and co-founder of Remix by Via" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Tiffany-chu.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228055" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin</p></div></p>
<p>Robots that can make salads and cheeseburgers are fascinating, which means they&#8217;re more likely to hog the headlines than companies making technology that optimizes governmental operations.</p>
<p>But govtech and civic tech has a greater social impact than burger-flipping robots. Startups that bridge the public and private sectors can build sustainable businesses with strong returns, says Tiffany Chu, SVP of mobility firm Via and former CEO of Remix.</p>
<p>&#8220;What’s special about this space is that it’s the intersection of a customer base that will always be around,&#8221; Chu says.</p>
<p>&#8220;Governments rarely go out of business, so there’s a very direct, targeted customer base that makes it clear who your product needs to serve.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9Nfx9I1jZu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/vias-tiffany-chu-on-the-importance-of-govtech-for-planning-mobility-ecosystems/">Via&#8217;s Tiffany Chu on the importance of govtech for planning mobility ecosystems</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Via&#8217;s Tiffany Chu on the importance of govtech for planning mobility ecosystems&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/vias-tiffany-chu-on-the-importance-of-govtech-for-planning-mobility-ecosystems/embed/#?secret=9Nfx9I1jZu" data-secret="9Nfx9I1jZu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Female founders are making a buzzing, venture-backed comeback</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2228491" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228491" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2228491" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg" alt="Woman wearing floppy hat driving car with a giant piggy bank on top" width="1024" height="685" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=768,514 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=680,455 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/GettyImages-464675083.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2228491" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Colin+Anderson+Productions+pty+ltd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Colin Anderson Productions pty ltd <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We are nowhere near achieving parity or representation when it comes to startup funding, but the gender gap is narrowing, according to PitchBook data.</p>
<p>Funding for U.S.-based, female-founded startups nearly doubled in the last year: So far in 2021, women-led companies have closed 2,661 deals worth $40.4 billion.</p>
<p>“Thus far in 2021, the backsliding has more than stopped,” report Natasha Mascarenhas and Alex Wilhelm. “Indeed, it has shot the other direction.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3bkLeFB8Ky"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/female-founders-are-making-a-buzzing-venture-backed-comeback/">Female founders are making a buzzing, venture-backed comeback</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Female founders are making a buzzing, venture-backed comeback&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/female-founders-are-making-a-buzzing-venture-backed-comeback/embed/#?secret=3bkLeFB8Ky" data-secret="3bkLeFB8Ky" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Why LatAm’s fintech boom is more than hype and superlative venture investment</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Venture capital is flowing around the world in unprecedented volumes, but it&#8217;s not hyperbole to say that Latin America&#8217;s fintech startups are having their best year ever.</p>
<p>Unprecedented tailwinds, a wealth of opportunities and strong competition are together driving fintechs in the region to innovate faster than ever, report Anna Heim and Alex Wilhelm. And despite intense competition, VCs are jumping in feet first, looking for more opportunities.</p>
<p>&#8220;Nubank is setting the bar of how big can a business get on an IPO and will make VCs think more thoroughly about how big can a business get if everything [goes] right,&#8221; said one investor.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A69BQG5PDv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/why-latams-fintech-boom-is-more-than-hype-and-superlative-venture-investment/">Why LatAm&#8217;s fintech boom is more than hype and superlative venture investment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why LatAm&#8217;s fintech boom is more than hype and superlative venture investment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/why-latams-fintech-boom-is-more-than-hype-and-superlative-venture-investment/embed/#?secret=A69BQG5PDv" data-secret="A69BQG5PDv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/techcrunch-roundup-holiday-marketing-tips-low-cost-nfts-saas-sprawl-study/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230067</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All systems go: Buy your pass to TC Sessions: Space 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marquise Foster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 18:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2225694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Space Race 2.0 is heating up fast, and whether your role lies in the private or public sector, TC Sessions: Space 2021 focuses on the emerging trends, essential data science and creative collaborations required to build a sustainable space economy. Yesterday, we announced a portion of the fully virtual event&#8217;s agenda. Take a look.  We [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Space Race 2.0 is heating up fast, and whether your role lies in the private or public sector, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> focuses on the emerging trends, essential data science and creative collaborations required to build a sustainable space economy. Yesterday, we announced a portion of the fully virtual event&#8217;s agenda. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/04/announcing-the-agenda-for-techcrunch-sessions-space-2021/">Take a look. </a></p>
<p>We can’t divulge the full agenda quite yet, but TC Sessions events always deliver the foremost leaders from across the tech and investing spectrum. Space 2021 will be no exception.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=TRUE">If you buy your pass today</a>, you save $100 with the general admission price and will join the global, early-stage space startup community for two full days on December 14-15. Want to bring your space crew? Take advantage of group discounts when you buy four or more passes. We also offer discounts on student tickets.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2225694" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Given the astronomical cost of virtually anything related to space, we’ll have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/find-out-what-it-takes-to-make-smart-early-bets-in-the-space-industry-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">plenty of investors in the house</a>, including Chad Anderson (Space Capital), Tess Hatch (Bessemer Venture Partners) and Jessica Robinson (Assembly Ventures), to name a few.</p>
<p>Panel discussions, interviews and breakout session will cover a range of topics, like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/learn-why-in-space-propulsion-systems-are-essential-for-a-sustainable-space-economy-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">in-space propulsion systems are essential</a> for a sustainable space economy</li>
<li>What <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/learn-how-studying-lunar-samples-may-help-sustain-human-life-beyond-our-planet-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">studying lunar samples</a> can teach us about sustaining human life beyond Earth</li>
<li>How <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/learn-about-the-benefits-of-on-orbit-operations-and-servicing-at-tc-sessions-space-2021/">on-orbit operations and servicing technologies</a> extend the life of space craft, reduce space junk and save money (lots of money)</li>
</ul>
<p>You might go faster alone, but you go farther together. That’s a round-about way of saying take advantage of this prime networking opportunity. Whether you’re looking for funding, a potential space unicorn or to hire a brilliant mind, this is a solid way to build meaningful relationships.</p>
<p>Early-stage space founders &#8212; buy a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=TRUE">Space Startup Exhibitor Package</a> and demo your game-changing tech to this very targeted community. We’re talking top investors, aerospace primes and government entities &#8212; the folks who can make big things happen, like cutting through government red tape.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> takes place on December 14-15. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=space2021&amp;utm_content=generaladmission&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=110521post&amp;display=TRUE">Buy your pass</a> and stay ahead of the orbital curve.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Space 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			width="100%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-c594f6a45f3ff3eabbf91af2a7d9403e'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/all-systems-go-buy-your-pass-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2225694</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An inclusive new DTC beauty platform secures $3 million in funding &#8212; and a supercharged offline strategy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 18:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brick-and-mortar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fearless fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inclusivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jcpenney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nyakio Grieco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sephora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thirteen Lune]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2230031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this week, Thirteen Lune, a direct-to-consumer beauty platform that was launched last year in LA, announced $3 million in seed funding. We might not normally pause on this kind of development, especially in a market where dozens of startups are announcing funding every day, but this deal stood out for a few reasons. First, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this week, <a href="https://thirteenlune.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thirteen Lune</a>, a direct-to-consumer beauty platform that was launched last year in LA, announced $3 million in seed funding. We might not normally pause on this kind of development, especially in a market where dozens of startups are announcing funding every day, but this deal stood out for a few reasons.</p>
<p>First, its co-founder is Nyakio Grieco, a veteran of the cosmetics industry who earlier launched a skin-care brand that she sold to Sundial Brands, which is now part of Unilever. Her new e-commerce platform sells products from 100 different brands, 90% of which were founded by Black, Indigenous, and people of color. And the outfit leading the financing is <a href="https://www.fearless.fund/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fearless Fund</a>, a venture firm that was founded by women of color and is making its mark by focusing exclusively on backing women of color.</p>
<p>Also very interesting: a tie-up with JCPenney that immediately gives Thirteen Lune the kind of reach that most nascent startups can only dream about. JCPenney long partnered with Sephora, but Sephora&#8217;s contract with JCPenney is expiring in 2023, and it chose not to renew, leaving the retailer &#8212; which last year <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-07/jcpenney-survives-going-bankrupt-now-comes-the-hard-part?sref=gni836kR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survived going bankrupt</a> &#8212; with space to fill. Going into those spots right now are in-store &#8220;JCPenney Beauty&#8221; shops, and Thirteen Lune is a featured part of that offering, with 10 locations already up and running and plans for 600 more locations by the end of 2023.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2230031" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Put together, the pieces add up to what Thirteen Lune is characterizing, persuasively, as among one of the first truly inclusive beauty platforms. Grieco told us a bit more this week, though she declined to answer questions about the financial mechanics of the JCPenney deal, citing a confidentiality agreement with the outfit.</p>
<p>Excerpts from this conversation have been edited for length.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How did you get started in the beauty business?</strong></p>
<p>NG: I&#8217;m a first-generation American of Kenyan descent, and almost 20 years ago, I left my job working in Hollywood to create a beauty brand based on my Kenyan family beauty secrets. My grandmother was a Kenyan coffee farmer, and my grandfather was a medicine man, and I felt that the continent of Africa at the time was very underrepresented in premium beauty. So I left my job to start making my grandmother&#8217;s coffee scrub and to learn to create products based in sustainable oils, the kind that my grandfather had the ability to go out in nature and extract to treat the skin.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>I started as a very independent brand out of my apartment in my 20s and served every role: founder, shipping and receiving, customer service, accounting. I learned very quickly as a young Black woman and first-time entrepreneur how difficult it was to raise money, but I was able to get a little bit of friends-and-family capital together to take the products to market.</p>
<p><strong>You initially launched at Fred Segal; your skin creams were later carried in Ulta and are now <a href="https://www.target.com/s?searchTerm=nyakio" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available</a> at Target. Why dive back into a new brand last year?</strong></p>
<p>While we were dealing with the global pandemic, as well as the most heightened moment of the Black Lives Matter movement of our lifetime, I found myself showing up on all of the lists of, you know, top Black-owned, Black-founded brands to shop and to follow. And while we saw a significant increase in sales at Target, it was really built on the precipice of such a heartbreaking time. And I just thought to myself, how strange is it that this moment is making people pay attention to my brand? I was in deep gratitude, but they were asking me questions like, &#8216;Can I use your products on my skin because I don&#8217;t look like you?&#8217; [At the same time], I was seeing amazing initiatives like the <a href="https://15percentpledge.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">15% Pledge</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/pullupforchange/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pull Up for Change</a> come about, and in my head, when I was shopping those lists, I thought to myself, &#8216;I could fill a whole store with these incredible beautiful brands, many of which had such little distribution and visibility and most of which were direct to consumer . . . So my co-founder and I built Thirteen Lune based on a 90/10 rule, which is that 90% of all the products that we carry are created by BIPOC founders who create products for people of all colors &#8212; we are Black and brown for all. And then 10% of our brands are dedicated to fostering allyship, because it&#8217;s not our fight to fight alone. We have to join together. We&#8217;ve lived too many years in divisive times.</p>
<p><strong>You are dealing with a lot of products that a third-party logistics provider sends out to customers because you want to own that experience. How do you vet what you&#8217;re selling?</strong></p>
<p>A product has to have a strong founder story, because people buy into people before they buy into product. We also have what we call our beauty vanguard, which is influencers, makeup artists, celebrities and friends who help us, because we have such an enormous amount of products coming our way. And we have certain standards, including that we want all products to be clean, nontoxic, with good-for-you ingredients. [And we want them] to really serve a need, focusing on our melanin-rich, textured-hair customer first &#8212; those who have been the most underserved &#8212; but also to really represent the globe.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of the products that are geared more toward people with melanin-rich skin? Also, as a Greek-American with fair skin, what are some of the products that I perhaps haven&#8217;t been exposed to but might turn to Thirteen Lune to order?</strong></p>
<p>Melanin rich [could apply] all the way from somebody who&#8217;s just slightly darker than maybe you all the way to a tone much darker than myself, and we often have a sensitivity to certain acids and chemical exfoliators and things like that will burn our skin or just color our skin. We&#8217;re more prone to hyperpigmentation. We&#8217;re more prone to eczema and rosacea and those types of skin conditions. So the products that we bring to shelf are things like a chemical peel that&#8217;s made with maybe azelaic acid and not maybe other acids that would be too harsh for our skin.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the same with textured hair. Shampoo is shampoo and conditioner is conditioner, but at the end of the day, especially as we are moving to a place where we are living with such multiracial and generational qualities and properties to our hair and our hair texture, [brands are on the rise like] <a href="https://bombacurls.com/">Bomba Curls</a>, which was created by an Afro-Latina founder named Lulu Cordero. She grew up with Dominican culture and back in those days, it was about having the straight &#8212; they call it &#8220;pelo malo&#8221; &#8212; hair to look more like white women from the Western world. And it caused a lot of damage to her, so much so that she suffered hair loss going into her college years.</p>
<p>She also happens to be brilliant and she was a chemistry major and she started playing with ingredients while she was in her college chemistry lab that would help to stimulate her hair growth; she started researching things that come from the earth and her culture like coffee and castor oil, and she developed her own hair oil [that was later lab-certified as counter safe]. That doesn&#8217;t mean that my friends that are blond-haired and blue-eyed can&#8217;t use Bomba Curls. The difference is that [the product] was created by a Black woman who understands our hair texture and understands the damage that we have done to our hair for so long, and she&#8217;s able to deliver on her promise [to repair that damage].</p>
<p><strong>You are also planning to roll out a private label brand. Why?</strong></p>
<p>When we look at Thirteen Lune and the data that we&#8217;re getting and will have access to [regarding] what this customer still needs and how we can better serve he, she, them, they through the lens of inclusivity, I&#8217;m excited about being able to create again. I love being a beauty retailer, but I&#8217;m a beauty founder first. That&#8217;s my passion, and I&#8217;ve missed being in a lab and being able to create. It&#8217;s literally my happy place.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/an-inclusive-new-d2c-beauty-platform-secures-3-million-in-funding-and-a-supercharged-offline-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2230031</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Appetiser&#8217;s co-founders discuss building client relationships and getting to MVP</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/appetisers-co-founders-discuss-building-client-relationships-and-getting-to-mvp/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/appetisers-co-founders-discuss-building-client-relationships-and-getting-to-mvp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 17:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agile software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[australian startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Software Consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outsourcing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prototyping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We interviewed Jamie Shostak and Michael MacRae, co-founders of Australian agency Appetiser, which focuses on designing, building and growing mobile and web apps.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://appetiser.com.au/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Appetiser</a>&#8216;s site lists three factors for app success: Technology, marketing and design. And while the Australian agency was recommended to TechCrunch via our <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl">our survey to identify software development partners for startups</a>, it could just have well have come through our survey to recommend growth marketers, which you can answer <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">here</a>.</p>
<p>With a focus on designing, building and growing mobile and web apps, Appetiser&#8217;s co-founders Jamie Shostak and Michael MacRae were endorsed by several clients who worked with them from the earliest days of their projects. &#8220;Every startup has to start with an idea. And some of the best startups can come from people who experience the problem firsthand, even if they are not the most technical,&#8221; Shostak noted.</p>
<p>TradeNow, an Australian pay-later financing option for trade businesses and their customers, is one such customer. “The Appetiser team has developed great leading applications and also believed in the vision of TradeNow from the very start,&#8221; its founder Matt Brennan wrote. &#8220;We were able to develop a great working relationship early on and continue this along the journey.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229520" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Fellow entrepreneur Andre Eikmeier praised the flexibility of Appetiser&#8217;s model. &#8220;We were able to use our CTO to lead a team of six devs from the Appetiser team, with occasional UX/UI, product management and project management as needed. It was properly collaborative, not a blackbox agency arrangement. So we were able to build capability in-house at the same time, rather than dependency.&#8221;</p>
<p>To find out more, we interviewed both Shostak and MacRae, in a discussion that went from prototyping to growth, and from MVP to design excellence.</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s note: This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</em></p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s Appetiser&#8217;s origin story?</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Jamie Shostak: </strong>Back in 2017, I ran into a tall German guy at the coffee machine of a co-working space in Melbourne: Michael. He had apps with millions of users, and I was running a growth marketing agency. After getting to know each other, we discovered a mutual passion for building and growing tech products. We had some healthy debates and identified how we could help others with their own product’s success: Speed to market, data-driven insights, top-level quality and strong teams. And that’s how Appetiser was born.</p>
<p><strong>What size is your team now, and how is it structured?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael MacRae: </strong>We have a team of 150 in Asia and 30 people in Australia. Our teams are built around efficiency: Small, client-embedded production squads comprising iOS, Android and back-end developers, as well as UX designers, product managers and QA/PM specialists. These squads work together in an agile environment and scale up or down based on the needs of the project. Appetiser itself is relatively flat, with a huge focus on data-driven decision-making via iterative testing.</p>
<p><strong>One of your clients told TechCrunch that Appetiser is &#8220;the opposite of a blackbox.&#8221; What does that mean?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>The “Telephone Game” is a popular children&#8217;s game to teach us the consequences of messages traveling from person to person. Sadly, agencies love “shielding” their team of developers, testers and designers from clients by introducing layers. Simply put, we do the opposite. When we build your team at Appetiser, it will be your team! Join standups, ideate with your team, discuss challenges or even have one-on-ones. We replicated the structure of successful startups with in-house teams, and then we rebuilt it in an agency form.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best software consultants for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/MXehi2kl">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Your site mentions that beyond designing and building apps, you are your clients’ &#8220;growth machine.&#8221; Can you explain?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>The vision for Appetiser was never to be an app development company. Instead, we think of ourselves as a product success agency. Simply put, we try to maximize the chances of a product becoming a success story. We measure how many of our apps become successful, how many users they’ve got, how much revenue they generate and how much money they raise.</p>
<p>Our entire team is held accountable to these success metrics, which means we do whatever it takes to help our clients get there. This may include design, development and growth, but often it’s also strategy, help with fundraising and more.</p>
<p><strong>Why does your strategy require defining a minimum viable product (MVP)?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Shostak: </strong>We’ve spent years refining internal IP based on data to rapidly deliver reliable, high-quality products. We use this to help entrepreneurs get to market fast with an MVP.</p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>Defining that MVP comes down to creating real-world value but also emotionally detaching ourselves from nice-to-haves. They can always be added later! As a result, we reduce the amount of time and iteration cycles to find product-market fit. Our clients save time and money, which will be invested into growing their products. Our client <a href="https://movewithus.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Move With Us</a> used this approach to cut development timelines in half, resulting in them gaining huge traction in both Australia and the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>But before that, you do prototyping. Why?<br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong>Shostak: </strong>Whether you’re someone with an idea or a big business, we always start with a standalone design stage and interactive prototype. It allows us to visually scope out the project whilst building an industry leading front-end experience. In Steve Jobs’ words, we like to start with the user experience and [work backward to the technology].</p>
<p>This also acts as a great starting point to raise capital, get stakeholder buy-in or validate their idea before taking steps into full development. We’re extremely proud of clients like <a href="https://goodempire.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Good Empire</a> and <a href="https://vello.vip/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vello</a> that have been able to raise [funding] even before development.</p>
<p><strong>Why do you value design quality?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>On the App Store, you’ve got seconds to convince a user to download your app. On the web, if you don&#8217;t convert a visitor within seconds, they’re gone forever. So at first, design excellence is a matter of understanding what users desire. This accelerates user acquisition. And once you’ve signed up your user, a strong user experience retains them.</p>
<p>We also believe that product design is not just a creative field; it’s a matter of performance: One design will always outperform the other. We try to centralize the learnings from all of our projects to design based on proven tactics to minimize risky assumptions.</p>
<p><strong>How do you share knowledge internally?<br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong>MacRae: </strong>Appetiser has created more internal IP than a majority of agencies. This includes our baseplate; our gold standards to unify the team based on best practices, which a large portion of our team ongoingly investigates, tests and iterates upon; and our educational materials and courses.</p>
<p>For the latter, we established the Appetiser University. It has a growing curriculum of production-relevant topics such as standards, best practices and guidelines, and also covers topics like economics, CRO and data analysis. Appetiser employees even have weekly exams that ask them to apply their learnings.</p>
<p><strong>What are some of your plans for the next year?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Shostak: </strong>With a remote-first culture, our plan was always to hire the best talent in the world. This started with a focus first on Asia Pacific. So far we’re in Davao, Cebu, Manilla, Melbourne and Sydney. In 2022, we are looking to expand this across a few more continents [ … ] and you can expect to see us in the U.S. within the next 12 months.</p>
<p>In addition, starting in 2022 and beyond, we want to build our own startup community and platform, and expand that globally. From partnering with investors, crowdfunding platforms, lawyers and accountants to creating our own educational content. We want to enable startups to conquer international markets. And we’re also currently building an incubator called Appetiser Ventures, where we will help accelerate clients&#8217; startups further and even potentially build some internally.</p>
<div style="width: 100%; height: 400px;" data-tf-widget="MXehi2kl"></div>
<p><script src="//embed.typeform.com/next/embed.js"></script></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/appetisers-co-founders-discuss-building-client-relationships-and-getting-to-mvp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229520</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cruise lays out its plan for &#8216;how&#8217; it will make robotaxis a reality</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ridehail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The string of engineers who spoke Thursday night during a deep dive into Cruise&#8217;s autonomous vehicle technology never mentioned Tesla&#8217;s name. They didn&#8217;t have to, although the message was clear enough. GM&#8217;s self-driving subsidiary Cruise presented a technical and deployment roadmap — at a granular level — that aimed to show how it has built [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The string of engineers who spoke Thursday night during a deep dive into Cruise&#8217;s autonomous vehicle technology never mentioned Tesla&#8217;s name. They didn&#8217;t have to, although the message was clear enough.</p>
<p>GM&#8217;s self-driving subsidiary Cruise presented a technical and deployment roadmap — at a granular level — that aimed to show how it has built autonomous vehicles that are safer and more scalable than any human-driven vehicle, including those equipped with advanced driver assistance systems.</p>
<p>While Cruise was clearly making a case for its own technology (not to mention trying to recruit fresh talent), the event was also an argument for autonomous vehicles in general. Each engineer or product lead who spoke Thursday presented various components, from how it uses simulations and the development of its own chips and other hardware to the design of its app and the vehicle itself.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229818" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The branded &#8220;Under the Hood&#8221; event built off of comments CEO Dan Ammann made last month during GM&#8217;s investor day, in which he laid out the company&#8217;s plan to launch a commercial robotaxi and delivery service <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/self-driving-company-cruise-on-track-for-early-commercial-operations-in-2022/">starting with retrofitted Chevy Bolts</a> and eventually scaling to an army of tens of thousands of purpose-built Origin AVs on the road over the next few years.</p>
<p>Cruise <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/cruise-waymo-get-ok-to-launch-robotaxi-service-in-san-francisco/">just gained approval in California</a> to perform commercial delivery services, and is still one permit away from being able to charge for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/cruise-launches-driverless-robotaxi-service-for-employees-in-san-francisco/">driverless ride-hailing</a>. Still, Cruise thinks it&#8217;ll be able to drive down costs enough to scale up and out quickly.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s how.</p>
<h2>Using simulations to scale, not just verify the system</h2>
<p>Cruise is relying on simulations not only to prove out its safety case, but also to scale to new cities without having to perform millions of miles of tests in them first.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company will still have to map the cities it enters. But it won&#8217;t have to remap cities to track changes to the environment that inevitably happen, like lane changes or street closures. When Cruise goes to new cities, it starts with a technology it calls WorldGen, which it says does accurate, large-scale generation of entire cities, &#8220;from their quirky layouts to the smallest details,&#8221; which allows engineers to test out new operational design domains, according to Sid Gandhi, technical strategy lead of simulation at Cruise. In other words, WorldGen becomes the stage where the future simulations are set.</p>
<p>To ensure optimal world creation, Cruise takes into account things like lighting at 24 different unique times of day and weather conditions, even going as far as to systematically measure light from a range of street lamps in San Francisco.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we combine a high-fidelity environment with a procedurally generated city, that&#8217;s when we unlock the capability to efficiently scale our business to new cities,&#8221; said Gandhi.</p>
<p>He then laid out the technology for the &#8220;Road to Sim,&#8221; which transforms into editable simulation scenarios real events that have been collected by AVs on the road. This ensures that the AV doesn&#8217;t regress by testing against scenarios it has already seen.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Road to Sim combines information from perception with heuristics learned from our millions of real-world miles to recreate a full simulation environment from road data,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;Once we have the simulation, we can actually create permutations of the event and change attributes like vehicle and pedestrian types. It&#8217;s a super easy and extremely powerful way to build test suites that accelerate AV development.&#8221;</p>
<p>For specific scenarios that Cruise hasn&#8217;t been able to collect in real-world road conditions, there&#8217;s Morpheus. Morpheus is a system that can generate simulations based on specific locations on the map. It uses machine learning to automatically enter as many parameters as it wants to generate thousands of interesting and rare scenarios against which it tests the AV.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we work on solving the longtail, we&#8217;ll rely less and less on real-world testing because when you have an event that happens rarely, it takes thousands of road miles to test it properly, and it&#8217;s just not scalable,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;So we&#8217;re developing technology to scalably explore large-scale parameter spaces to generate test scenarios.&#8221;</p>
<p>Test scenarios also include simulating the way other road users react to the AV. Cruise&#8217;s system for this is called non-player character (NPC) AI, which is usually a video game term, but in this context, refers to all of the cars and pedestrians in a scene that represent complex multi-agent behaviors.</p>
<p>&#8220;So Morpheus, Road to Sim and NPC AI work together in this really thoughtful way to let us perform more robust testing around rare and difficult events,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;And it really gives us the confidence that we can solve rare issues now and in future similar issues, as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Generating synthetic data helps the Cruise AV target specific use cases, said Gandhi, pointing specifically to identifying and interacting with emergency vehicles, presumably for no other reason than to take a dig at Tesla, whose Autopilot ADAS system has come under federal scrutiny for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/u-s-safety-regulator-opens-investigation-into-tesla-autopilot-following-crashes-with-parked-emergency-vehicles/">repeated crashes into emergency vehicles</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Emergency vehicles are rare compared to other types of vehicles, but we need to detect them with extremely high accuracy, so we use our data generation pipeline to create millions of simulation images of ambulances, fire trucks and police cars,&#8221; said Gandhi. &#8220;In our experience targeted synthetic data is about 180 times faster than collecting road data, and millions of dollars cheaper. And with the right mix of synthetic and real data, we can increase relevant data in our data sets by an order of magnitude or more.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Two custom silicon chips developed in-house</h2>
<p>During GM&#8217;s investor day in October, Cruise CEO Dan Ammann outlined the company&#8217;s plan to invest heavily into the compute power of the Origin in order to decrease costs by 90% over the next four generations so it can scale profitably. At the time, Ammann mentioned Cruise&#8217;s intention to manufacture custom silicon in-house to cut costs, but didn&#8217;t admit outright using that silicon to build a chip &#8212; but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/cruise-plans-to-have-tens-of-thousands-of-origin-avs-on-roads-in-coming-years/">TechCrunch had its theories</a>. On Thursday, Rajat Basu, chief engineer for the Origin program, validated those theories.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our fourth-generation compute platform will be based on our in-house custom silicon development,&#8221; said Basu. &#8220;This is purpose-built for our application. It enables focus and improves processing capability, while significantly reducing piece costs and power consumption. Compute is a critical system from a safety perspective, and has redundancy built into it. Add to that an AV system that is processing up to 10 gigabits of data every second, we end up consuming a fair amount of power. Our MLH chip allows us to run our complex machine learning pipelines in a much more focused manner, which in turn helps us to be more energy efficient without compromising on performance.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cruise&#8217;s AI team developed two chips: The sensor processing chip will handle edge processing for the range of sensors like cameras, radar and acoustics. The second chip, which is designed to be a dedicated neural network processor, supports and accelerates machine learning applications like those large, multitask models developed by the AI team. Basu says the machine learning accelerator (MLA) chip is just the right size to solve exactly a certain class of neural net and ML applications, and nothing more.</p>
<p>&#8220;This keeps the performance at an extremely high level, and it ensures that we are not wasting energy on doing anything that is not value added for us,&#8221; said Basu. &#8220;It can be paired with multiple external hosts or operate standalone. It supports single Ethernet networks up to 25G with a total bandwidth of 400G. The MLA chip we&#8217;re putting into volume production is just the start. Over time we will continue to make this even higher-performing while reducing power consumption.&#8221;</p>
<h2>The Cruise ecosystem</h2>
<p>One thing Cruise made clear during its event is that it hasn&#8217;t just thought of the AV tech needed to scale up successfully, but also the entire ecosystem, which includes things like remote assistance operators to validate the AV&#8217;s decision when it comes across unknown scenarios, customer service, a vehicle that people actually want to ride around in and an app that can efficiently and easily handle things like customer support and incidence response.</p>
<p>&#8220;To truly cross the chasm from research and development to a beloved product requires more than just artificial intelligence and robotics,&#8221; said Oliver Cameron, Cruise&#8217;s VP of product, at the event. &#8220;A safe self-driving vehicle alone is insufficient and simply the first step on a long, long journey. To truly build and scale a competitive product that is adopted by millions into their daily lives, you need to build a host of differentiated features and tools atop a safe self-driving foundation. How these features need to be implemented is non-obvious, especially if your company&#8217;s still heads-down solving safety issues.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/cruise-lays-out-its-plan-for-how-it-will-make-robotaxis-a-reality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IAB Europe says it&#8217;s expecting to be found in breach of GDPR</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behavioral advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belgium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data controller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Data Protection Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european parliament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iab europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johnny Ryan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is this the beginning of the end for the hated tracking cookie consent pop-up? A flagship framework used by Google and scores of other advertisers for gathering claimed consent from web users for creepy ad targeting looks set to be found in breach of Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). A year ago the IAB [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Is this the beginning of the end for the hated tracking cookie consent pop-up? A flagship framework used by Google and scores of other advertisers for gathering claimed consent from web users for creepy ad targeting looks set to be found in breach of Europe&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/">A year ago</a> the IAB Europe&#8217;s self-styled Transparency and Consent Framework (TCF) was found to fail to comply with GDPR principles of transparency, fairness and accountability, and the lawfulness of processing in a preliminary report by the investigatory division of the Belgian data protection authority.</p>
<p>The complaint then moved to the litigation chamber of the DPA &#8212; and a whole year passed without a decision being issued, in keeping with the glacial pace of privacy enforcement against adtech in the region.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229932" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But the authority is now in the process of finalizing a draft ruling, according to a <a href="https://iabeurope.eu/all-news/update-on-the-belgian-data-protection-authoritys-investigation-of-iab-europe/">press statement</a> put out by the IAB Europe today. And the verdict it&#8217;s expecting is that the TCF breaches the GDPR.</p>
<p>It will also find that the IAB Europe is itself in breach. Oopsy.</p>
<p>The online advertising industry body looks to be seeking to get ahead of a nuclear finding of non-compliance, writing that the DPA &#8220;will apparently identify infringements of the GDPR by IAB Europe,&#8221; and trying to further spin the finding as &#8220;fixable&#8221; within six months (it doesn&#8217;t say how, however) &#8212; while simultaneously implying the breach finding may not itself be fixed because other EU DPAs still need to weigh in on the decision as part of the GDPR&#8217;s standard cooperation procedure (which applies to cross-border complaints).</p>
<p>The preemptive statement (and its Friday afternoon timing) looks very much like the IAB Europe trying to both fuzz and bury bad news and thereby calm the nerves of the tracking industry ahead of looming headlines that a flagship tool is unlawful &#8212; something EU privacy campaigners have of course been saying for literally years.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In terms of timing, a final verdict on the investigation is still likely months off &#8212; and may not emerge &#8217;til deep into 2022. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Appeals are also almost inevitable. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But the tracking industry&#8217;s problems are starting to look, well, appropriately sticky. </span></p>
<p>In the short term, the IAB says it expects a draft ruling to be shared by Belgium with other EU DPAs in the next two to three weeks &#8212; at which point they get 30 days to review it and potentially file objections.</p>
<p>If DPAs don&#8217;t agree with the lead authority&#8217;s finding and can&#8217;t agree among themselves, the European Data Protection Board may need to step in and take a binding decision &#8212; such as happened in another cross-border case against WhatsApp (which led to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/whatsapp-faces-267m-fine-for-breaching-europes-gdpr/">a $267 million fine</a>, a larger penalty that the lead DPA in that case had originally proposed).</p>
<p>So this GDPR cooperation mechanism can spin procedures out for many more months yet.</p>
<p>Complainants against the IAB Europe and its TCF, meanwhile, told us they have not seen nor been given details of the draft ruling by the DPA.</p>
<p>So it looks pretty whiffy that the ad industry body has had sight of an incoming decision ahead of the other parties to the complaint.</p>
<p>But one of complainants, the Irish Council for Civil Liberties&#8217; Johnny Ryan, quickly posted a <a href="https://www.iccl.ie/news/online-consent-pop-ups-used-by-google-and-other-tech-firms-declared-illegal/">press statement</a> of his own, in which he writes: &#8220;We have won. The online advertising industry and its trade body, &#8216;IAB Europe&#8217;, have been found to have deprived hundreds of millions of Europeans of their fundamental rights.</p>
<p>&#8220;IAB Europe designed the misleading &#8216;consent&#8217; pop-ups that feature on almost all (80%+) European websites and apps. That system is known as IAB Europe’s &#8216;Transparency &amp; Consent Framework&#8217; (TCF). These popups purport to give people control over how their data are used by the online advertising industry. But in fact, it does not matter what people click.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Big news. <br />Google and the entire tracking industry relies on IAB Europe’s consent system, which will now be found to be illegal. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TCF?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TCF</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDPR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDPR</a><a href="https://twitter.com/ICCLtweet?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ICCLtweet</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/panoptykon?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@panoptykon</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/bitsoffreedom?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@bitsoffreedom</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Jausl00s?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Jausl00s</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/PiDewitte?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PiDewitte</a> <a href="https://t.co/yDWptBhI6V">https://t.co/yDWptBhI6V</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Johnny Ryan (@johnnyryan) <a href="https://twitter.com/johnnyryan/status/1456630527721680902?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The looming finding of unlawfulness comes at an interesting time for the tracking ads industry with moves afoot in the European Parliament to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/inside-a-european-push-to-outlaw-creepy-ads/">push for an outright ban on behavioral advertising</a> to be incorporated into incoming pan-EU regulations for digital services &#8212; in favor of privacy-safe alternatives like contextual advertising.</p>
<p>A finding that the flagship tool used by the tracking industry to claim &#8220;consent&#8221; to behavioral ads isn&#8217;t actually operating lawfully under EU law will surely amplify calls to clean house by outlawing the practice entirely.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hXIZ0cxz0Q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/inside-a-european-push-to-outlaw-creepy-ads/">Inside a European push to outlaw creepy ads</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Inside a European push to outlaw creepy ads&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/inside-a-european-push-to-outlaw-creepy-ads/embed/#?secret=hXIZ0cxz0Q" data-secret="hXIZ0cxz0Q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to the IAB Europe, the draft ruling by the Belgian DPA will find that it is a data controller for TCF “TC Strings,” aka &#8220;the digital signals created on websites to capture data subjects’ choices about the processing of their personal data for digital advertising, content and measurement,&#8221; as it puts it.</p>
<p>(Or &#8212; in Ryan&#8217;s words &#8212; &#8220;the identification code created about a person, based on which apps they use and which websites they visit, and what they click in consent popups.&#8221;)</p>
<p>It will also find the IAB Europe is a &#8220;joint controller&#8221; for TC Strings that are used in OpenRTB (Real-Time Bidding) &#8212; meaning the industry body will have a string of risky new responsibilities attached to the data processing around programatic behavioral advertising (with legal liability aplenty and the risk of big fines if they fail to live up to requirements in the GDPR such as privacy by design and default; consent that&#8217;s specific, informed and freely given; and appropriate security wrapping people&#8217;s data).</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s Ryan again, laying out the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/gdpr-adtech-complaints-keep-stacking-up-in-europe/">parallel case against RTB</a> in brief:</p>
<blockquote><p>For almost four years, websites and apps have plagued Europeans with this &#8220;consent&#8221; spam. But our evidence reveals that IAB Europe knew that conventional tracking-based advertising was “incompatible with consent under GDPR” before it launched the consent system.</p>
<p>This is because the primary tracking-based ad system, called &#8220;Real-Time Bidding&#8221; (RTB), broadcasts internet users’ behaviour and real-world locations to thousands of companies, billions of times a day. RTB is the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/21/irelands-data-watchdog-slammed-for-letting-adtech-carry-on-biggest-breach-of-all-time/">biggest data breach ever recorded</a>. There is no way to protect data in this free-for-all. (We are <a href="https://www.iccl.ie/rtb-june-2021/">litigating</a> against RTB in Hamburg, too.)</p>
<p>In proceedings initiated by a group of complainants coordinated by the Irish Council for Civil Liberties, the Belgian Data Protection Authority is close to adopting a draft decision that will find IAB Europe’s its &#8220;consent&#8221; pop-up system infringes the GDPR, vindicating our arguments over several years.</p></blockquote>
<p>The IAB Europe&#8217;s spin for trying to eschew responsibility for protecting people&#8217;s data is to try to spread blame elsewhere &#8212; claiming it has not considered itself a data controller &#8220;based on guidance from other DPAs up to now,&#8221; among other excuses.</p>
<p>&#8220;Therefore, it has naturally not fulfilled certain obligations that accrue to data controllers under the Regulation,&#8221; the IAB Europe goes on in studiously avoiding making any kind of apology.</p>
<p>(Here&#8217;s Ryan&#8217;s take again: &#8220;IAB Europe is jointly responsible and liable with thousands of online advertising firms when personal data are broadcast in to the RTB data free-for-all. IAB Europe had tried to deny this.&#8221;)</p>
<p>Instead of apologizing, the IAB Europe directs its energy toward suggesting there will be an easy way to fix the tracking industry&#8217;s lawfulness problem, writing: &#8220;The draft ruling will require IAB Europe to work with the APD to ensure that these obligations are met going forward.&#8221;</p>
<p>Making more market calming noises, it also describes itself as &#8220;optimistic&#8221; that the TCF can be fixed.</p>
<p>But, well, it would say that wouldn&#8217;t it?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IsJ9zIfe2p"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/behavioural-advertising-is-out-of-control-warns-uk-watchdog/">Behavioural advertising is out of control, warns UK watchdog</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Behavioural advertising is out of control, warns UK watchdog&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/20/behavioural-advertising-is-out-of-control-warns-uk-watchdog/embed/#?secret=IsJ9zIfe2p" data-secret="IsJ9zIfe2p" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The online ad industry body has previously denied there was any case to bring against the TCF or RTB&#8217;s use of people&#8217;s data.</p>
<p>So, well, its record here shouldn&#8217;t inspire confidence.</p>
<p>“Google and the entire tracking industry relies on IAB Europe’s consent system, which will now be found to be illegal,” added Ryan in a statement. “IAB Europe created a fake consent system that spammed everyone, every day, and served no purpose other than to give a thin legal cover to the massive data breach in at the heart of online advertising. We hope the decision of the Belgian Data Protection Authority will finally force the online advertising industry to reform.”</p>
<p>Another complainant in the case, Jef Ausloos, a postdoc researcher in data privacy at the University of Amsterdam, suggests the IAB Europe&#8217;s statement is an attempt to sow doubt among other EU DPAs &#8212; and called its claim that identification codes used for targeted advertising aren&#8217;t personal data &#8220;preposterous.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also described the Belgian finding as &#8220;only the very start of the process as I see it,&#8221; adding: &#8220;We&#8217;ve come a long way already but, regardless, this will still take a while.&#8221;</p>
<p>At the time of writing the Belgian DPA had not responded to our request for confirmation of an impending draft ruling.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the IAB Europe claimed it has &#8220;only been informed about the headline findings of the draft ruling.&#8221; She did not specify how it had obtained the information ahead of the complainants. (<strong>Update:</strong> We asked if the information came from the Belgian DPA and she said &#8220;yes, that&#8217;s correct.&#8221;)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zhd15gr6wG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/">IAB Europe&#8217;s ad tracking consent framework found to fail GDPR standard</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;IAB Europe&#8217;s ad tracking consent framework found to fail GDPR standard&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/16/iab-europes-ad-tracking-consent-framework-found-to-fail-gdpr-standard/embed/#?secret=zhd15gr6wG" data-secret="zhd15gr6wG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/iab-europe-tcf-gdpr-breach-belgium/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229932</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US government offers $10M bounty for DarkSide ransomware hackers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CISA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colonial pipeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[east coast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Bureau of Investigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of State is upping the ante in its fight against ransomware by offering a reward of up to $10 million for information that helps identify or track down leaders of the notorious DarkSide ransomware group. The State Department said it’s also offering as much as $5 million for information that leads to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. Department of State is upping the ante in its fight against <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ransomware/">ransomware</a> by offering a reward of up to $10 million for information that helps identify or track down leaders of the notorious DarkSide ransomware group.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.state.gov/reward-offers-for-information-to-bring-darkside-ransomware-variant-co-conspirators-to-justice/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">State Department said</a> it’s also offering as much as $5 million for information that leads to the arrest or conviction of anyone ”conspiring to participate in or attempting to participate in a DarkSide variant ransomware incident.” This is likely a nod to the group’s affiliate program, in which members receive a custom variant of the DarkSide ransomware and receive a chunk of any ransom payment profits.</p>
<p>“In offering this reward, the United States demonstrates its commitment to protecting ransomware victims around the world from exploitation by cybercriminals,” the State Department said. “The United States looks to nations who harbor ransomware criminals that are willing to bring justice for those victim businesses and organizations affected by ransomware.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229968" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2229993" style="width: 706px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229993" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2229993 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg" alt="" width="696" height="900" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg 696w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=526,680 526w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/fbi-darkside-wanted-poster.jpg?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229993" class="wp-caption-text">The FBI&#8217;s wanted poster for the DarkSide ransomware group. (<strong>Image Credits:</strong> FBI)</p></div></p>
<p>The State Department says it launched the bounty in the wake of DarkSide’s attack on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/colonial-pipeline/">Colonial Pipeline</a> earlier this year, which led to the shutdown of a 5,500-mile pipeline that carries 45% of the fuel used on the U.S. east coast.</p>
<p>The group went dark shortly after its servers were hacked, and later rebranded as BlackMatter, which went on to attack <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/12/technology-giant-olympus-hit-by-blackmatter-ransomware/">Japanese technology giant Olympus</a> in September and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/cisa-nsa-blackmatter-food-industry/">“multiple” organizations deemed critical infrastructure</a>, including two companies in the U.S. food and agriculture sector. BlackMatter said this week that it was also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/blackmatter-ransomware-shut-down/">ceasing operations</a> due to pressure from law enforcement agencies.</p>
<p>The $10 million reward is being offered under the Department of State’s Transnational Organized Crime Rewards Program (TOCRP), which it manages with federal law enforcement partners as part of the government’s effort to disrupt and dismantle international crime syndicates. The State Department noted that it had paid $135 million in rewards since it was created in 1986.</p>
<p>Jake Williams, CTO at BreachQuest, told TechCrunch that the State Department’s bumper reward will cause ripples far beyond DarkSide: “With rewards this large, there’s a substantial incentive for these criminals to turn on one another. Perhaps more importantly than the specific impacts to DarkSide, this action undermines trust across the ransomware as a service affiliate model.</p>
<p>“This is especially good timing since it capitalizes on the recent REvil infiltration by law enforcement. The law enforcement action against REvil in July already caused significant trust issues among operators. This drives that wedge deeper and will extend far beyond DarkSide.”</p>
<p>This is the latest in a long line of efforts by the Biden administration to crack down on the growing ransomware threat. Most recently, the Treasury took steps to crack down on virtual currency exchanges <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/23/us-treasury-sanctions-suex-ransomware/">by sanctioning Suex for its role in facilitating ransomware payments</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HinRtcvjfX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/blackmatter-ransomware-shut-down/">BlackMatter ransomware gang says it&#8217;s shutting down over law enforcement pressure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BlackMatter ransomware gang says it&#8217;s shutting down over law enforcement pressure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/03/blackmatter-ransomware-shut-down/embed/#?secret=HinRtcvjfX" data-secret="HinRtcvjfX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/state-department-darkside-bounty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229968</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rent the Runway co-founder Jenny Fleiss and Volition Capital&#8217;s Larry Cheng talk early-stage fundraising on TechCrunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/rent-the-runway-co-founder-jenny-fleiss-and-volition-capitals-larry-cheng-talk-early-stage-fundraising-on-techcrunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/rent-the-runway-co-founder-jenny-fleiss-and-volition-capitals-larry-cheng-talk-early-stage-fundraising-on-techcrunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jenny fleiss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Larry Cheng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rent the Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volition capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rent the Runway is more than 10 years old now and has raised upwards of $500 million, recently filing to IPO at a valuation north of $1 billion. Jenny Fleiss is a co-founder at Rent the Runway and sits on the board of several notable companies, including Shutterfly, Party City and, of course, Rent the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rent the Runway is more than 10 years old now and has raised upwards of $500 million, recently filing to IPO at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/working-to-understand-rent-the-runways-ipo-valuation/">a valuation north of $1 billion</a>.</p>
<p>Jenny Fleiss is a co-founder at Rent the Runway and sits on the board of several notable companies, including Shutterfly, Party City and, of course, Rent the Runway. She&#8217;s also a partner at Volition Capital alongside Larry Cheng.</p>
<p>On an upcoming episode of TechCrunch Live, Fleiss and Cheng will sit down to discuss their fundraising philosophy and for Fleiss, how her experience at building a unicorn influences investments in early stage startups now. They will also talk through the current early-stage fundraising landscape, which is nearly unrecognizable from the environment Fleiss fundraised in a decade ago.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2228419" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>This episode takes place Wednesday, November 10, at 12 p.m. PT / 3 p.m. ET. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-volition-capital?ref=14cba39fb3ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Register for free here!</a></p>
<p>TechCrunch Live is all about helping founders build better venture-backed businesses. We do this by sitting down with founders and the investors who finance them to hear how they chose one another, how they tackled challenges and how successful founders quickly grow their businesses.</p>
<p>The weekly event series also features the TechCrunch Live pitch-off, which invites founders in the audience to join our virtual stage and pitch their products to the audience and our expert speakers, who give live feedback on the pitches.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Live is 100% free to attend, but access to the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/techcrunch-live/">massive library of on-demand TCL content</a> is reserved exclusively for TechCrunch+ members.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The show goes down every <a href="https://hopin.com/events/techcrunch-live-with-volition-capital?ref=14cba39fb3ca" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wednesday at 3 p.m. ET/noon PT</a>. See you there!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/rent-the-runway-co-founder-jenny-fleiss-and-volition-capitals-larry-cheng-talk-early-stage-fundraising-on-techcrunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228419</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VCs are racing to pay more to get smaller pieces of less profitable companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/vcs-are-racing-to-pay-more-to-get-smaller-pieces-of-less-profitable-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/vcs-are-racing-to-pay-more-to-get-smaller-pieces-of-less-profitable-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cb insights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchBase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitchbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silicon valley bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229012</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While perusing SVB's State of the Market" report, we found an interesting pattern: Venture capital investors are racing to pay more to buy smaller pieces of startups that are less profitable than before.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s data season, with groups like Silicon Valley Bank (SVB), CB Insights, PitchBook and Crunchbase News putting out data sets that we&#8217;re having fun exploring. This morning, we&#8217;re adding one more to our arsenal.</p>
<p>The Exchange spent some time this week diving into the SVB &#8220;<a href="https://www.svb.com/trends-insights/reports/state-of-the-markets-2021-q4-report">State of the Market</a>&#8221; report for the fourth quarter. As is common from the bank&#8217;s publications, it&#8217;s a dense riff of charts and notes, ranging from economic data and trade figures to venture capital statistics.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>While perusing the collected information, we found an interesting pattern: Venture capital investors are racing to pay more to buy smaller pieces of startups that are less profitable than before.</p>
<p>While that may sound somewhat rude, it isn&#8217;t. Instead, the capital crush that we&#8217;ve seen overtake startups around the world, the round preemption that has become common, the rising valuation marks that have become the entry price to hot startups&#8217; cap tables and investments into growth have all come together to create a venture capital market unlike any that I can recall.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2229732 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/exchange-banner-sq-yllw-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />SVB gave The Exchange permission to share a few charts, so what follows is a graphical dig into the data, proving that I am not a brat for claiming that venture investors are getting a rawer deal than usual but merely sharing what the data indicates.</p>
<h2>Less for more</h2>
<p>First, let&#8217;s examine how the time between funding rounds has fallen. SVB data shows a useful 2020 versus 2021 differential, with an aggregate chart tracking the same data over a longer time period on the right:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2229017" style="width: 850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229017" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2229017 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-04-at-8.36.17-AM.png" alt="" width="840" height="287" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-04-at-8.36.17-AM.png 840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-04-at-8.36.17-AM.png?resize=150,51 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-04-at-8.36.17-AM.png?resize=300,103 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-04-at-8.36.17-AM.png?resize=768,262 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-04-at-8.36.17-AM.png?resize=680,232 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Screen-Shot-2021-11-04-at-8.36.17-AM.png?resize=50,17 50w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229017" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SVB</p></div></p>
<p>As you can see in both charts, venture capitalists are accelerating the pace at which they make successive investments into startups. This is what we meant by <em>faster</em>.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/vcs-are-racing-to-pay-more-to-get-smaller-pieces-of-less-profitable-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229012</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple and Amazon ML/AI leads to speak on accessibility at Sight Tech Global 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/apple-and-amazon-ml-ai-leads-to-speak-on-accessibility-at-sight-tech-global-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/apple-and-amazon-ml-ai-leads-to-speak-on-accessibility-at-sight-tech-global-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sight Tech Global 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sensors and data are proliferating. Whether it’s from a phone, a car or smart home devices, astonishing amounts of data fuel the work of researchers and product developers conceiving new products and experiences. Among those who stand to benefit, even more than they already do, are people who are blind or visually disabled. That’s why [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Sensors and data are proliferating. Whether it’s from a phone, a car or smart home devices, astonishing amounts of data fuel the work of researchers and product developers conceiving new products and experiences. Among those who stand to benefit, even more than they already do, are people who are blind or visually disabled.</p>
<p dir="ltr">That’s why <a href="https://sighttechglobal.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://sighttechglobal.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1636129618893000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFOD7es_l2oa88nfsdxUDWT340Nsg">Sight Tech Global </a>is delighted to announce two sessions, one with Apple and a separate one with Amazon, focused on how those two tech leaders in machine learning and artificial intelligence see the future unfolding, especially around new experiences that will help people with vision loss. Sight Tech Global is a free, global and virtual event to be held on December 1 &amp; 2. <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfberR7NW3F74cBNleiOVauGQ8wrSV0FcZqf1HH5X60mUrS6Q/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfberR7NW3F74cBNleiOVauGQ8wrSV0FcZqf1HH5X60mUrS6Q/viewform&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1636129618893000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFzTlVmzHy8lYIJGM6JyLuA6l1B8g">Register today</a>.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Designing for everyone: Accessibility and machine learning at Apple</h2>
<p dir="ltr">For the Apple session, TechCrunch editor-in-chief Matthew Panzarino will speak with Jeff Bigham and Sarah Herrlinger.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229733" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p dir="ltr">Bigham is the research lead for AI/ML accessibility at Apple, as well as an associate professor of computer science at Carnegie-Mellon. He leads a team of researchers and engineers focused on advancing accessibility through artificial intelligence and machine learning.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Herrlinger is Apple’s senior director of Global Accessibility Policy &amp; Initiatives. She leads accessibility programs for Apple — including support for disability communities worldwide, the accessibility technologies built into all Apple hardware, software and services, as well as other initiatives that promote Apple’s culture of inclusion.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Apple’s iPhone and VoiceOver are among the most treasured tools available to blind people because they provide so many services, from navigation to reading email out loud. With the addition of lidar and computer-vision capabilities, among others, the phone in combination with cloud compute has become even more capable as a source of data about the world and a means to interpret that information in meaningful ways. Herrlinger and Bigham will provide an overview of Apple’s approach to accessible design, advances of the past year, inclusivity in machine learning research and latest approaches and future features.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Why Amazon’s vision includes talking less to Alexa</h2>
<p dir="ltr">For the Amazon session, Be My Eyes’ vice president Will Butler will speak with Prem Natarajan, vice president of Alexa AI and Beatrice Geoffrin, director of Alexa Trust.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">Geoffrin is a director of Product Management on the Alexa team at Amazon. She leads the Alexa Trust organization that is focused on earning and maintaining the trust customers have in Alexa and making Alexa accessible, overseeing the Alexa for Everyone team.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Natarajan leads a multidisciplinary science, engineering and product organization which improves customer experience through advances in dialog modeling, natural language understanding, entity linking and resolution, and related machine learning technologies.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Amazon’s Alexa is already a standard feature in most homes, and it’s another great addition to a blind person’s technology tool set. As homes become increasingly more technology-driven, inputs from multiple sources — teachable AI, multimodal understanding, sensors, computer vision and more — will create a truly ambient, surround experience. Already, 1 in every 5 Alexa smart home interactions is initiated by Alexa without any spoken command. As Alexa develops an understanding of us and our home well enough to predict our needs and act on our behalf in meaningful ways, what are the implications for accessibility?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Don’t forget to <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfberR7NW3F74cBNleiOVauGQ8wrSV0FcZqf1HH5X60mUrS6Q/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfberR7NW3F74cBNleiOVauGQ8wrSV0FcZqf1HH5X60mUrS6Q/viewform&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1636129618893000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFzTlVmzHy8lYIJGM6JyLuA6l1B8g">register now</a>. Sight Tech Global is free, virtual and global.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Sight Tech Global is a production of the Vista Center for the Blind and Visually Impaired. We’re grateful to current sponsors Ford, Google, Humanware, Microsoft, Mojo Vision, Facebook, Fable, APH and Vispero. If you would like to sponsor the event, <a href="https://sighttechglobal.com/sponsorship-opportunities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://sighttechglobal.com/sponsorship-opportunities/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1636129618893000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGEnnuHXJy2-Wo3ZWMLsYPSwuaMOg">please contact us</a>. All sponsorship revenues go to the nonprofit <a href="https://www.vistacenter.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.vistacenter.org/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1636129618893000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGLAfVMWJk2xzCozLJnKso80mkjhw">Vista Center for the Blind and Visually Impaired</a>, which has been serving the Silicon Valley area for 75 years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/apple-and-amazon-ml-ai-leads-to-speak-on-accessibility-at-sight-tech-global-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229733</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guardians Collective wants to make parenting easier, or at least less alone</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/guardians-collective-wants-to-make-parenting-easier-or-at-least-less-alone/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/guardians-collective-wants-to-make-parenting-easier-or-at-least-less-alone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early childhood education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guardian's Collective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reach Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While few would argue over the need for a tech-enabled solution to make parenting easier, the demand is more obvious than the execution. Parenting is hard and requires support for a whole range of moments, from when your kid accidentally eats a button to early signs of depression during the remote school day. The diversity [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Output copied to clipboard! --></p>
<p>While few would argue over the need for a tech-enabled solution to make parenting easier, the demand is more obvious than the execution. Parenting is hard and requires support for a whole range of moments, from when your kid accidentally eats a button to early signs of depression during the remote school day. The diversity of issues that parents face could thus be a customer service nightmare, but it&#8217;s exactly the reason that founder Saurabh Kamalapurkar feels strongly about building Guardians Collective.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.aboutgc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Guardians Collective</a> brings together small groups of families and pairs them with an early childhood educator, a broad term that can describe a professional who has experience working in early learning and development programs or is licensed in a state to run a day care. The mission, and broader goal of the company, is to make early childhood educators more accessible to families, who once had to lean on formal day cares as the only way to get support. Instead, it’s offering a more savvy, supported way to scale peer-to-peer learning — early mornings and late nights included.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2229618" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Today, the startup announced a $3.5 million seed investment round led by Reach Capital with participation from Impact America Fund and Gary Philanthropies.</p>
<p>In my view, Guardians Collective is bringing a fresh take on a controversial trend from the early innings of COVID-19: learning pods. The term, somewhat synonymous with microschools, pandemic pods and small-group learning, describes small clusters of children within the same age range who are paired with a private instructor with the goal of replacing, or supplementing, school learning. Critics saw the growing trend as a threat to low-income students who would consequently face an even larger gap in access to learning material.</p>
<p>Chian Gong, who led the investment for Reach Capital, thinks Guardians Collective is much more than a learning pod, or even a WhatsApp group with other parents.</p>
<p>“WhatsApp connects you to people you already know … whereas Guardians Collective brings you together with 3-5 other families and an early childhood educator in a safe space to ask the questions you can&#8217;t ask anywhere else,” she said. “You get the wisdom, insights and empathy of an educator who has worked with thousands of young kids and who is guiding dialogue among four other families with children at the same age [and] stage.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2229632" style="width: 445px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2229632" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2229632" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png" alt="" width="435" height="774" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png 1242w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png?resize=768,1365 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png?resize=383,680 383w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png?resize=864,1536 864w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png?resize=1152,2048 1152w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PS3-1.png?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 435px) 100vw, 435px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2229632" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Guardians Collective</p></div></p>
<p>She added that she thinks the magic of the platform is its combination of expertise, content and community. Winnie, another venture-backed startup in the early childhood space, is a marketplace for childcare that parents can use to find physical day care and preschools near them. And recently, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/kaipod-learning-thinks-learning-pods-are-here-to-stay/">KaiPod Learning raised millions</a> to give homeschooled children exposure to local, supplemental and socially focused learning hubs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>All the startups differ in execution and product strategy, but seemingly fit within the same vision of bringing more connection and access to resources to empower children at scale.</p>
<p>Part of Guardians Collective’s strategy includes convincing more early childhood educators to get on its platform. It’s a political issue, considering that most states require people to get licensed to run day care centers — and prices plus bias can increase who can actually go through that process. The startup is figuring out how to balance quality assurance with people who aren’t licensed but have been supporting children for generations.</p>
<p>“A lot of systems won’t even call these people educators,” Kamalapurkar said. “But they’re not just diaper changers — they’re teachers.” Teacher organizations are biting at the idea of joining a more asynchronous workforce: Guardians Collective did a callout to recruit 40 educators and got 470 applications within days.</p>
<p>So far, Guardians Collective has families using its app in Detroit, New Orleans, Alaska, Navajo Nation, Oklahoma and California’s Central Valley. Over half of the customers are classified as low income, the founder said. The startup uses a subscription model, with a sliding scale, to make sure it can offer an affordable price point to any family that wants to use it.</p>
<p>With venture money in the tank, Guardians Collective will need to balance user retention with new expectations on growth. The company has over 700 families using its platform in the Bay Area but sports a nationwide growth rate of 16x since the beginning of 2020. It also claims that retention is 94%, and 94% of users use the app daily on weekdays.</p>
<p>The big metric that Kamalapurkar is focused on is an elusive one, looking at what families are talking about, where the conversations are occurring and what percentage of messages get answered in a useful way.</p>
<p>“Scale is not only a function of the number of customers we reach, but in what we mean to them,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/guardians-collective-wants-to-make-parenting-easier-or-at-least-less-alone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HashiCorp&#8217;s IPO filing reveals a growing business, but at a slower pace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/hashicorps-ipo-filing-reveals-a-growing-business-but-at-a-slower-pace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/hashicorps-ipo-filing-reveals-a-growing-business-but-at-a-slower-pace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 15:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HashiCorp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terraform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn IPO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2229900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To understand HashiCorp's performance, we'll need to spend a minute talking about how it approaches the market. If you are a fan of open source software (OSS), it should be an interesting read.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">HashiCorp <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001720671/000119312521319849/d205906ds1.htm">filed go public this week</a>, becoming the latest addition to our growing roster of expected fourth-quarter IPOs.</p>
<p>The cloud infrastructure unicorn presents an interesting mix of open source and proprietary code, with recurring revenues and a nascent hosted product.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>To understand HashiCorp&#8217;s performance, we&#8217;ll need to spend a minute talking about how it approaches the market. If you are a fan of open source software (OSS) or curious how companies with a core of open code make money, it should be an interesting read.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220369 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>In very broad terms, HashiCorp grew about 50% in its most recent quarter from a year earlier, but with narrower losses. The company has reached nine-figure revenue scale, meaning that the unicorn <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/funding_round/hashicorp-series-e--515a0e65">worth some $5 billion or so</a> back in 2020 is going to make a splash when it lists.</p>
<p>No more throat clearing, let&#8217;s talk OSS, how it shakes out into a business model and how strong HashiCorp&#8217;s historical results appear through this July.</p>
<h2>HashiCorp&#8217;s open source approach</h2>
<p>When we wrote above that HashiCorp is a cloud infrastructure company, we meant it. It has built a suite of tools that help other companies manage cloud applications (Terraform), keep them and their data secure (Boundary, Vault), handle networking on a granular level (Consul) and deal with orchestration and cross-platform deployment (Nomad, Waypoint).</p>
<p>That&#8217;s an incredibly brief overview, but it should give you an idea of the breadth of the software that HashiCorp has built over the course of its life. We expected a good amount of code, frankly; this is a company going public after all, not some middling Series C startup with hopes of one day growing into a unicorn price.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s where things get fun. Per the company&#8217;s S-1 filing, it has &#8220;deliberately built [its] products using an open-core software development model.&#8221; In practical terms, that means that all HashiCorp software products are &#8220;developed as open source projects, with large communities of users, contributors, and partners collaborating on their development.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Exchange has written some about how OSS has evolved from exoticism to in-market advantage <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/26/2170552/">in recent months</a>. For investors just now picking up on the monetization possibilities that open source software can unlock in-market, HashiCorp&#8217;s IPO should be a klaxon that they are behind.</p>
<p>Regardless, how <em>does</em> HashiCorp make money from open source software? The company has built proprietary code atop its open source products that it sells, while also offering support and a hosted version of its products.</p>
<p>The company generates revenue in several buckets. The first and biggest bucket is subscription revenues. The second is professional services — this is generally understood, so we&#8217;ll leave it alone.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/hashicorps-ipo-filing-reveals-a-growing-business-but-at-a-slower-pace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2229900</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Helion secures $2.2B to commercialize fusion energy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-series-e/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-series-e/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 14:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helion Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam altman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2228508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Helion Energy, a clean energy company committed to creating a new era of plentiful, zero-carbon electricity from fusion, today announced the close of its $0.5 billion Series E, with an additional $1.7 billion of commitments tied to specific milestones. The round was led by Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI and former president of Y Combinator. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.helionenergy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Helion Energy</a>, a clean energy company committed to creating a new era of plentiful, zero-carbon electricity from fusion, today announced the close of its $0.5 billion Series E, with an additional $1.7 billion of commitments tied to specific milestones.</p>
<p>The round was led by Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI and former president of Y Combinator. Existing investors, including co-founder of Facebook Dustin Moskovitz, Peter Thiel&#8217;s <a href="https://www.mithril.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mithril Capital</a> and notable sustainable tech investor <a href="https://capricornllc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Capricorn Investment Group</a> also participated in the round. The funding includes commitments of an additional $1.7 billion dollars tied to Helion reaching key performance milestones. Round-leader Altman has been involved in the company as an investor and chairman since 2015.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fusion_power" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fusion energy</a> has been a fiery dream for lovers of clean energy since the first controlled thermonuclear fusion reaction was accomplished some 60 years ago. The technology promises all the benefits of current-generation <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuclear_fission" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nuclear fission</a> generators, at a fraction of the risk, with far less radioactivity when running, and with very little radioactive waste. There&#8217;s been one catch: So far, it has been hard to get the fusion process to generate more energy than it has been consuming to keep the reaction under control.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2228508" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Helion, as a company, has been focusing less on fusion as a science experiment and more on a more important question: Can their technology generate electricity at a commercial and industrial scale?</p>
<p>&#8220;Some projects in the fusion space talk about heat, or energy, or other things. Helion is focused on electricity generation. Can we get it out fast, at a low cost? Can we get it to industrial-scale power?&#8221; asks David Kirtley, Helion&#8217;s co-founder and CEO. &#8220;We are building systems that are about the size of a shipping container and that can deliver industrial-scale power &#8212; say on the order of 50 megawatts of electricity.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2228760" style="width: 394px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Helion-technology-pulse.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228760" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2228760" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Helion-technology-pulse.gif?w=384" alt="" width="384" height="216" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2228760" class="wp-caption-text">Deuterium and Helium-3 are heated, then accelerated through magnets, compressed and captured as inductive current. Animation courtesy of Helion Energy.</p></div></p>
<p>In June of this year, Helion<a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210622005366/en/Helion-Energy-Achieves-100-Million-Degrees-Celsius-Fusion-Fuel-Temperature-and-Confirms-16-Month-Continuous-Operation-of-Its-Fusion-Generator-Prototype" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210622005366/en/Helion-Energy-Achieves-100-Million-Degrees-Celsius-Fusion-Fuel-Temperature-and-Confirms-16-Month-Continuous-Operation-of-Its-Fusion-Generator-Prototype&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1636070604211000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHpiyZtJtoGXpUg4x0r2PrDyjwWVg"> published results</a> confirming it had become the first private fusion company to heat a fusion plasma to 100 million degrees Celsius, an important milestone on the path to commercial electricity from fusion. Soon after, the company announced it had broken ground on building its factory to start the process of preparing for manufacturing of its seventh-generation fusion generator, which the company calls &#8220;Polaris.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TechCrunch was surprised to learn of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/08/14/y-combinator-and-mithril-invest-in-helion-a-nuclear-fusion-startup/">the company&#8217;s $1.5 million round back in 2014</a>, when the company said it would be able to get net power generation of fusion up and running within three years. Here we are seven years later, and it appears that Helion hit a couple of wobbles &#8212; but the company also found a focus along the way.</p>
<p>&#8220;We ended up pivoting a little bit in direction, to focus less on scientific milestones of energy and focus more specifically on electricity. We had to prove some of the technologies on the electricity, and electricity extraction side of things. We also needed some funding things that had to happen to get us all the way to those technical milestones,&#8221; Kirtley reflects. &#8220;Unfortunately, that took a little bit longer than we had hoped.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2228774" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2228774" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2228774" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg 2464w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?resize=300,177 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?resize=768,453 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?resize=680,401 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?resize=1536,906 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?resize=2048,1209 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/0-1.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2228774" class="wp-caption-text">The Helion team standing by to energize you. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Helion Energy</p></div></p>
<p>As part of the investment round, Sam Altman steps up from being the chairman of the board, to Helion&#8217;s executive chairman, with a higher degree of activity, including input into the commercial direction of the company.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our first funding round was led by Mithril Capital, and Y Combinator was part of it. That&#8217;s where we got introduced to Sam. He has been involved in our fundraising ever since. He is an ambassador that actually understands physics; it&#8217;s pretty amazing. We were really pleased that he was interested in leading the investment, rather than us having to bring in external investors that might have been differently aligned and have a less deep understanding of the technology,&#8221; Kirtley explains. &#8220;He&#8217;s seen the successes, and he has seen what they mean. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re excited not only to have him as an investor but have him more actively involved. It means we can accelerate the timelines. The funding is part of it, and the technology is another part of it. Ultimately, we need to get it out there in the world, and that&#8217;s something Sam can help us do.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I’m delighted to be investing more in Helion, which is by far the most promising approach to fusion I’ve ever seen,&#8221; said Altman. &#8220;With a tiny fraction of the money spent on other fusion efforts, and the culture of a startup, this team has a clear path to net electricity. If Helion is successful, we can avert climate disaster and provide a much better quality of life for people.&#8221;</p>
<p>Helion&#8217;s CEO speculates that its first customers may turn out to be data centers, which have a couple of advantages over other potential customers. Data centers are power-hungry, and often already have power infrastructure in place in order to be able to accept backup generators. In addition, they tend to be a little away from population centers.</p>
<p>&#8220;They have a backup power of diesel generators, giving them a few megawatts that keep the data centers running just long enough to sustain any power grid issues,&#8221; Kirtley says, but suggests that the company is more ambitious than just replacing backup diesel generators. The low cost and high power availability mean that the company could start powering whole data centers as the default power source: &#8220;We are excited about being at the 50-megawatt scale, and being able to get electricity costs down to a cent per kilowatt-hour. You can completely change how data centers work, and you can really start answering climate change. Our focus is making low-cost and carbon-free electricity.&#8221;</p>
<p>Due to physical limitations with the way the power is generated, the current generation of the company&#8217;s tech wouldn&#8217;t be able to replace your Tesla Powerwall and solar panels &#8212; the size of a generator is roughly the size of a shipping container. But at 50 megawatts, the generators could power around 40,000 homes, and with that amount of power, the technology could open some really interesting opportunities for distributed power grids.</p>
<p>One interesting innovation in Helion&#8217;s power generation solution is that it doesn&#8217;t use water and steam as intermediary steps in the power generation.</p>
<p>&#8220;At the beginning of my career, I kept looking at the way we were doing fusion and said hey, you have this beautiful energy that is all electric, including the plasma. And then what do you do? You boil water, you use an old, low-efficiency, capital-intensive process,&#8221; explains Kirtley. Instead of going via water, the company decided to skip a step and use inductive energy instead. &#8220;Can you bypass that whole era? Could we do the equivalent of bypassing the gasoline engine and go right to electric cars right from the beginning? And so that&#8217;s been what we&#8217;ve been focusing on.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company is aiming to be able to generate more electricity than what it takes to run the fusion reactor by 2024, and the CEO points out that the goal at this point is to generate electricity at a commercial scale.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our 2024 date is not a key demonstration of the science at this point. The goal is to go after commercially installed power generation. There&#8217;s a huge market, and we want to be able to get this out in the world as soon as possible,&#8221; concludes Kirtley.</p>
<p>&#8220;By focusing on getting to electricity as soon as possible, we should be able to count on fusion as part of the natural conversation we&#8217;re having about climate change and about carbon free electricity generation. We&#8217;re really excited we&#8217;ve secured this funding, and the amount we raised should be able to get us all the way there.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/05/helion-series-e/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2228508</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
