<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 17:24:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Triller owner gets a new CEO with acquisition of Amplify.AI; also acquires live streaming service FITE TV</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/triller-owner-gets-a-new-ceo-with-acquisition-of-amplify-ai-also-acquires-live-streaming-service-fite-tv/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/triller-owner-gets-a-new-ceo-with-acquisition-of-amplify-ai-also-acquires-live-streaming-service-fite-tv/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 17:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amplify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Lu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opera mediaworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opera software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snoop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ssl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Triller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verisign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Would be TikTok competitor Triller, operated by parent company TrillerNet, is gaining a new CEO, the company announced today. The short-form video app said it&#8217;s acquiring an A.I.-based customer engagement platform, Amplify.AI, whose co-founder Mahi de Silva will now become TrillerNet&#8217;s CEO. Existing CEO Mike Lu will transition to President of TrillerNet and will focus [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Would be TikTok competitor Triller, operated by parent company TrillerNet, is gaining a new CEO, the company announced today. The short-form video app said it&#8217;s <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/trillernet-acquires-leading-ai-powered-customer-engagement-platform-amplifyai-for-completion-of-trillers-launch-of-internet-3-0-301269016.html">acquiring</a> an A.I.-based customer engagement platform, Amplify.AI, whose co-founder Mahi de Silva will now become TrillerNet&#8217;s CEO. Existing CEO Mike Lu will transition to President of TrillerNet and will focus on investor relations. The company separately announced the <a href="https://www.thewrap.com/triller-parent-company-buys-combat-sports-streaming-service-fite-tv/">acquisition</a> of FITE TV, a live event and pay-per-view combat sports streaming platform.</p>
<p>New CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mdesilva/">Mahi de Silva</a> had been closely involved with Triller before today. The company&#8217;s press release today says he&#8217;s been serving as non-executive chairman since 2016, but his LinkedIn notes the year was 2019 (which would be following Triller&#8217;s 2019 <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/triller-announces-record-breaking-growth-new-funding-by-proxima-media-and-acquisition-of-ai-music-platform-300944115.html">funding</a> by Proxima Media, when the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/triller-announces-record-breaking-growth-new-funding-by-proxima-media-and-acquisition-of-ai-music-platform-300944115.html">press release at the time</a> noted he was assuming the role of &#8220;chairman.&#8221;)  These are both wrong, the company discovered when we reached out for clarity. The correct year is 2018.</p>
<p>Ahead of the acquisition, de Silva had been serving as CEO and co-founder to Amplify.AI since 2017, and before that was CEO of Opera Mediaworks, the marketing and advertising arm of Opera Software, and co-founder and CEO of Botworx.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Amplify.AI, which works with brands in CPG, financial services, automotive, telecom, <a href="https://www.businessinsider.in/business/startups/news/amplify-ai-the-conversational-ai-startup-founded-by-two-south-asians-has-scored-big-with-brands-and-governments/articleshow/80443958.cms">politics</a>, and digital media, among others, will continue to operate as a subsidiary of TrillerNet following the deal. Other team members include former RSA and Verisign executive Ram Moskowitz who helped design and develop the digital certificates for SSL and code signing; and Amplify.ai co-founder and CTO Manoj Malhotra, a pioneer in B2C SMS messaging, the company notes.</p>
<p>TrillerNet also today announced it&#8217;s acquiring another strategic property to help shift its business further into the direction of live events: FITE TV. This deal gives Triller more of a foothold in the live events and pay-per-view streaming market, it says. As a result, FITE, which touts 10 million users, will become the exclusive digital distributor of all Triller Fight Club boxing events going forward.</p>
<p>&#8220;Acquiring FITE is part of the larger Triller strategy to bring together content, creators and commerce for the first time and the only place where they truly interact,&#8221; said Triller&#8217;s Ryan Kavanaugh, the former head of movie studio Relativity Media (<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/triller-wants-to-be-the-next-tiktok-its-backers-want-a-second-act-11602255601">and controversial figure</a>) whose Proxima Media <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/04/triller-tiktok/">became</a> Triller&#8217;s majority investor in <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/triller-announces-record-breaking-growth-new-funding-by-proxima-media-and-acquisition-of-ai-music-platform-300944115.html">2019.</a> &#8220;We have invested hundreds of millions of dollars and believe we have created a better more efficient e-commerce content platform,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The acquisition follows several others TrillerNet has made to expand into live events, now that becoming a TikTok replacement in the U.S. is no longer a viable option, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/tiktoks-forced-sale-to-oracle-is-put-on-hold/">the Trump ban was put on hold</a> by the Biden administration. Triller also in March acquired live music streaming platform Verzuz, founded by Swizz Beats and Timbaland. And it operates Triller Flight Club in partnership with Snoop Dogg, as well as a streaming platform Triller TV.</p>
<p>While specific deal terms were not revealed, Triller told TechCrunch it&#8217;s spent $250 million in the aggregate on its acquisitions, including Halogen, Mashtraxx, Verzuz, FITE and Amplify today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/triller-owner-gets-a-new-ceo-with-acquisition-of-amplify-ai-also-acquires-live-streaming-service-fite-tv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138444</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blue Origin launches and lands New Shepard rocket in key prep flight for human passengers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/blue-origin-launches-and-lands-new-shepard-rocket-in-key-prep-flight-for-human-passengers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/blue-origin-launches-and-lands-new-shepard-rocket-in-key-prep-flight-for-human-passengers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 17:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronaut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blue moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new shepard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Origin has launched its New Shepard rocket for the second time this year, and the 15th time overall. The mission profile saw the reusable spacecraft fly to suborbital space, and then return for a parachute-assisted landing at Blue Origin&#8217;s launch facility in West Texas. This flight was a little different than its usual missions, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Origin has launched its New Shepard rocket for the second time this year, and the 15th time overall. The mission profile saw the reusable spacecraft fly to suborbital space, and then return for a parachute-assisted landing at Blue Origin&#8217;s launch facility in West Texas.</p>
<p>This flight was a little different than its usual missions, because it included a rehearsal component with people standing in for what will eventually be Blue Origin&#8217;s paying private astronaut customers. What that means is that they actually went through the process of flight preparations, including transporting to the pad, and even climbing in to the New Shepard vehicle and getting seated as if they were going along for the ride.</p>
<p>The crucial difference between this and an actual passenger flight is that Blue Origin then paused the countdown, and the mock crew disembarked, before the countdown was resumed and the flight proceeded as planned — without any passengers, save for Mannequin Skywalker, the Blue Origin test dummy who flies on these preparation missions to take crucial readings during the launch and return.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>New Shepard returned and touched down without any issue, and in fact showed off one of its smoothest landings yet. This was the second launch and landing for this particular booster stage. The capsule also touched down as planned, with a soft landing facilitated by the spacecraft&#8217;s parachute descent system.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138511" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ns-15-landing-blue-origin.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138511" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2138511 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ns-15-landing-blue-origin.gif" alt="" width="1000" height="552" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138511" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Blue Origin</p></div></p>
<p>Next up, Blue Origin is going to do a dry run of what would be the ending stage of the mission for an actual human crew, by bringing out those rehearsal astronauts and putting them back into the capsule, then rehearsing in full the astronaut recovery and departure process that would occur during a live tourist flight.</p>
<p>All of today&#8217;s activities showed off what Blue Origin hopes to accomplish sometime this year with people on board. It&#8217;s yet another way paying private astronauts can get to space, in a growing roster of options that now includes SpaceX Dragon flights, and hopefully soon, Virgin Galactic launches.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4fxwVlF15q"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/">As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/embed/#?secret=4fxwVlF15q" data-secret="4fxwVlF15q" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/blue-origin-launches-and-lands-new-shepard-rocket-in-key-prep-flight-for-human-passengers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138485</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uber hit with default &#8216;robo-firing&#8217; ruling after another EU labor rights GDPR challenge</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/uber-hit-with-default-robo-firing-ruling-after-another-eu-labor-rights-gdpr-challenge/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/uber-hit-with-default-robo-firing-ruling-after-another-eu-labor-rights-gdpr-challenge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App Drivers & Couriers Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automated decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig. worker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Farrar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport for london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Labor activists challenging Uber over what they allege are &#8216;robo-firings&#8217; of drivers in Europe have trumpeted winning a default judgement in the Netherlands &#8212; where the Court of Amsterdam ordered the ride-hailing giant to reinstate six drivers who the litigants claim were unfairly terminated &#8220;by algorithmic means.&#8221; The court also ordered Uber to pay the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Labor activists challenging Uber over what they allege are &#8216;robo-firings&#8217; of drivers in Europe have trumpeted winning a default judgement in the Netherlands &#8212; where the Court of Amsterdam <a href="https://uitspraken.rechtspraak.nl/inziendocument?id=ECLI:NL:RBAMS:2021:1415&amp;showbutton=true&amp;keyword=ECLI%3aNL%3aRBAMS%3a2021%3a1415">ordered</a> the ride-hailing giant to reinstate six drivers who the litigants claim were unfairly terminated &#8220;by algorithmic means.&#8221;</p>
<p>The court also ordered Uber to pay the fired drivers compensation.</p>
<p>The challenge references Article 22 of the European Union&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) &#8212; which provides protection for individuals against purely automated decisions with a legal or significant impact.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The activists say this is the first time a court has ordered the overturning of an automated decision to dismiss workers from employment.</p>
<p>However the judgement, which was issued on February 24, was issued by default &#8212; and Uber says it was not aware of the case until last week, claiming that was why it did not contest it (nor, indeed, comply with the order).</p>
<p>It had until March 29 to do so, per the litigants, who are being supported by the App Drivers &amp; Couriers Union (ADCU) and Worker Info Exchange (WIE).</p>
<p>Uber argues the default judgement was not correctly served and says it is now making an application to set the default ruling aside and have its case heard &#8220;on the basis that the correct procedure was not followed.&#8221;</p>
<p>It envisages the hearing taking place within four weeks of its Dutch entity, Uber BV, being made aware of the judgement &#8212; which it says occurred on April 8.</p>
<p>“Uber only became aware of this default judgement last week, due to representatives for the ADCU not following proper legal procedure,&#8221; an Uber spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for WIE denied that correct procedure was not followed but welcomed the opportunity for Uber to respond to questions over how its driver ID systems operate in court, adding: &#8220;They [Uber] are out of time. But we&#8217;d be happy to see them in court. They will need to show meaningful human intervention <em>and</em> provide transparency.&#8221;</p>
<p>Uber pointed to a separate judgement by the Amsterdam Court <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/12/dutch-court-rejects-uber-drivers-robo-firing-charge-but-tells-ola-to-explain-algo-deductions/">last month</a> &#8212; which rejected another ADCU- and WIE-backed challenge to Uber&#8217;s anti-fraud systems, with the court accepting its explanation that algorithmic tools are mere aids to human &#8220;anti-fraud&#8221; teams who it said take all decisions on terminations.</p>
<p>&#8220;With no knowledge of the case, the Court handed down a default judgement in our absence, which was automatic and not considered. Only weeks later, the very same Court found comprehensively in Uber’s favour on similar issues in a separate case. We will now contest this judgement,&#8221; Uber&#8217;s spokesperson added.</p>
<p>However WIE said this default judgement &#8220;robo-firing&#8221; challenge specifically targets Uber&#8217;s Hybrid Real-Time ID System &#8212; a system that incorporates facial recognition checks and which labor activists recently found <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/uber-under-pressure-over-facial-recognition-checks-for-drivers/">misidentifying drivers in a number of instances</a>.</p>
<p>It also pointed to a separate development this week in the U.K. where it said the City of London Magistrates Court ordered the city&#8217;s transport regulator, TfL, to reinstate the licence of one of the drivers revoked after Uber routinely notified it of a dismissal (also triggered by Uber&#8217;s real time ID system, per WIE).</p>
<p>Reached for comment on that, a TfL spokesperson said: “The safety of the travelling public is our top priority and where we are notified of cases of driver identity fraud, we take immediate licensing action so that passenger safety is not compromised. We always require the evidence behind an operator’s decision to dismiss a driver and review it along with any other relevant information as part of any decision to revoke a licence. All drivers have the right to appeal a decision to remove a licence through the Magistrates’ Court.”</p>
<p>The regulator has been applying pressure to Uber since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/22/uber-loses-its-license-to-operate-in-london/">2017</a> when it took the (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/23/uber-only-has-itself-to-blame-for-london-license-loss/">shocking to Uber</a>) decision to revoke the company&#8217;s licence to operate &#8212; citing safety and corporate governance concerns.</p>
<p>Since then Uber has been able to continue to operate in the U.K. capital but the company remains under pressure to comply with a laundry list of requirements set by TfL as it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/uber-wins-latest-london-licence-appeal/">tries to regain a full operator licence</a>.</p>
<p>Commenting on the default Dutch judgement on the Uber driver terminations in a statement, James Farrar, director of WIE, accused gig platforms of &#8220;hiding management control in algorithms.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;For the Uber drivers robbed of their jobs and livelihoods this has been a dystopian nightmare come true,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They were publicly accused of ‘fraudulent activity’ on the back of poorly governed use of bad technology. This case is a wake-up call for lawmakers about the abuse of surveillance technology now proliferating in the gig economy. In the aftermath of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/uber-loses-gig-workers-rights-challenge-in-uk-supreme-court/">recent U.K. Supreme Court ruling</a> on worker rights gig economy platforms are hiding management control in algorithms. This is misclassification 2.0.&#8221;</p>
<p>In another supporting statement, Yaseen Aslam, president of the ADCU, added: &#8220;I am deeply concerned about the complicit role Transport for London has played in this catastrophe. They have encouraged Uber to introduce surveillance technology as a price for keeping their operator’s license and the result has been devastating for a TfL licensed workforce that is 94% BAME. The Mayor of London must step in and guarantee the rights and freedoms of Uber drivers licensed under his administration<em>.&#8221;  </em></p>
<p>When pressed on the driver termination challenge being specifically targeted at its Hybrid Real-Time ID system, Uber declined to comment in greater detail &#8212; claiming the case is &#8220;now a live court case again&#8221;.</p>
<p>But its spokesman suggested it will seek to apply the same defence against the earlier &#8220;robo-firing&#8221; charge &#8212; when it argued its anti-fraud systems do not equate to automated decision making under EU law because &#8220;meaningful human involvement [is] involved in decisions of this nature&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bQm2N8eM6N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/uber-under-pressure-over-facial-recognition-checks-for-drivers/">Uber under pressure over facial recognition checks for drivers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber under pressure over facial recognition checks for drivers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/19/uber-under-pressure-over-facial-recognition-checks-for-drivers/embed/#?secret=bQm2N8eM6N" data-secret="bQm2N8eM6N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BOyqiSMAfo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/uber-loses-gig-workers-rights-challenge-in-uk-supreme-court/">Uber loses gig workers rights challenge in UK Supreme Court</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber loses gig workers rights challenge in UK Supreme Court&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/uber-loses-gig-workers-rights-challenge-in-uk-supreme-court/embed/#?secret=BOyqiSMAfo" data-secret="BOyqiSMAfo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="orr6yiqWNK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/uber-wins-latest-london-licence-appeal/">Uber wins latest London licence appeal &#8212; but renewal is only for 18 months</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Uber wins latest London licence appeal &#8212; but renewal is only for 18 months&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/28/uber-wins-latest-london-licence-appeal/embed/#?secret=orr6yiqWNK" data-secret="orr6yiqWNK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/uber-hit-with-default-robo-firing-ruling-after-another-eu-labor-rights-gdpr-challenge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138379</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Pilot charted a course of not raising too much money</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/how-pilot-charted-a-course-of-not-raising-too-much-money/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/how-pilot-charted-a-course-of-not-raising-too-much-money/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bezos Expeditions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bookkeeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waseem Daher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whale Rock Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago, we wrote about fintech Pilot raising a $100 million Series C that doubled the company’s valuation to $1.2 billion. Bezos Expeditions — Amazon founder Jeff Bezos’ personal investment fund — and Whale Rock Capital joined the round, adding $40 million to a $60 million raise led by Sequoia about one month [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few weeks ago, we wrote about fintech Pilot raising </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/jeff-bezos-investment-fund-is-backing-a-startup-hoping-to-be-the-aws-for-smb-accounting/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $100 million Series C</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that doubled the company’s valuation to $1.2 billion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bezos Expeditions — Amazon founder Jeff Bezos’ personal investment fund — and Whale Rock Capital joined the round, adding $40 million to a $60 million raise led by Sequoia about one month prior.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That raise came after </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/18/index-ventures-stripe-back-bookkeeping-service-pilot-with-40m/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $40 million Series B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in April 2019 co-led by Stripe and Index Ventures that valued the company at $355 million.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both raises were notable and warranted coverage. But sometimes it’s fun to take a peek at the stories behind the raises and dig deeper into the numbers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So here we go.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uLylNiO7FV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/jeff-bezos-investment-fund-is-backing-a-startup-hoping-to-be-the-aws-for-smb-accounting/">Jeff Bezos&#8217; investment fund is backing a startup hoping to be the AWS for SMB accounting</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jeff Bezos&#8217; investment fund is backing a startup hoping to be the AWS for SMB accounting&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/jeff-bezos-investment-fund-is-backing-a-startup-hoping-to-be-the-aws-for-smb-accounting/embed/#?secret=uLylNiO7FV" data-secret="uLylNiO7FV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First off, San Francisco-based Pilot &#8212; which has a mission of affordably providing back-office services such as bookkeeping to startups and SMBs &#8212; apparently had term sheets that offered “2x the $40M” raised in its Series B. But it chose not to raise so much capital. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I also heard that the same investor that ended up leading a now defunct competitor&#8217;s $60 million raise first asked to invest $60 million in Pilot as a follow-on to that Series B prior to making the other investment. While I don’t know for sure, I can only presume that what is being referred to is ScaleFactor’s</span><a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/scalefactor-raises-third-round-60m-in-13-months-after-700-arr-growth-in-2018/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $60 million Series C raise</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in August 2019 that was led by Coatue Management. (ScaleFactor </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidjeans/2020/07/20/scalefactor-raised-100-million-in-a-year-then-blamed-covid-19-for-its-demise-employees-say-it-had-much-bigger-problems/?sh=5fdc8e1f2928"><span style="font-weight: 400;">crashed and burned</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last year.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to CFO Paul Jun: “There were many periods when Pilot turned away new customers and growth capital instead of absolutely maximizing short-term growth&#8230;Pilot prioritized building the foundational investments needed for scalability, reliability and high velocity. When it was presented with the opportunity for additional funding towards further growth in 2019, it declined to do so.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Co-founder and CEO Waseem Daher elaborates, pointing out that the first company that Pilot&#8217;s founding team ran, Ksplice, was bootstrapped before getting acquired by Oracle in 2011. (It&#8217;s also worth noting that the founding team are all MIT computer scientists.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Ultimately, the reason to raise money is you believe that you can deploy the capital, to grow the company or to basically cause the company to grow at the rate you&#8217;d like to grow. And it doesn&#8217;t make sense to raise money if you don&#8217;t need it, or don&#8217;t have a good plan for what to do with it,” Daher told TechCrunch. “Too much capital can be bad because it sort of leads you to bad habits&#8230;When you have the money, you spend the money.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So despite what he describes as “a great deal of institutional interest” in 2019, Pilot opted to raise just $40 million, instead of $80 million to $100 million, because it was the amount of capital the company had confidence that it could deploy successfully.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gzkBc7Tmlv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/pilot-ceo-waseem-daher-tears-down-his-companys-60m-series-c-pitch-deck/">Pilot CEO Waseem Daher tears down his company&#8217;s $60M Series C pitch deck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pilot CEO Waseem Daher tears down his company&#8217;s $60M Series C pitch deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/pilot-ceo-waseem-daher-tears-down-his-companys-60m-series-c-pitch-deck/embed/#?secret=gzkBc7Tmlv" data-secret="gzkBc7Tmlv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, Jun shared some numbers beyond the recent raise amount and valuation.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has tripled revenue every year since inception, except for 2020 when it doubled revenue.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pilot claims to have had a cash burn of $800,000 per month in 2020 against a starting balance of $40 million.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup touts a 60% GAAP gross margin. Daher notes: </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We feel really good about having long-term unit economics that will work for this business without resorting to offshoring or outsourcing in a way that could compromise quality and compromise relationships.”</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Bottom line is companies don&#8217;t have to accept all the capital that&#8217;s offered to them. And maybe in some cases, they shouldn&#8217;t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/how-pilot-charted-a-course-of-not-raising-too-much-money/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138317</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amira Learning raises $11M to put its AI-powered literacy tutor in post-COVID classrooms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amira-learning-raises-11m-to-put-its-ai-powered-literacy-tutor-in-post-covid-classrooms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amira-learning-raises-11m-to-put-its-ai-powered-literacy-tutor-in-post-covid-classrooms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renaissance learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[School closures due to the pandemic have interrupted the learning processes of millions of kids, and without individual attention from teachers, reading skills in particular are taking a hit. Amira Learning aims to address this with an app that reads along with students, intelligently correcting errors in real time. Promising pilots and research mean the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">School closures due to the pandemic have interrupted the learning processes of millions of kids, and without individual attention from teachers, reading skills in particular are taking a hit. <a href="https://www.amiralearning.com/">Amira Learning</a> aims to address this with an app that reads along with students, intelligently correcting errors in real time. Promising pilots and research mean the company is poised to go big as education changes, and it has raised $11 million to scale up with a new app and growing customer base.</p>
<p>In classrooms, a common exercise is to have students read aloud from a storybook or worksheet. The teacher listens carefully, stopping and correcting students on difficult words. This &#8220;guided reading&#8221; process is fundamental for both instruction and assessment: It not only helps the kids learn, but the teacher can break the class up into groups with similar reading levels so she can offer tailored lessons.</p>
<p>&#8220;Guided reading is needs-based, differentiated instruction and in COVID we couldn&#8217;t do it,&#8221; said <span style="color: #000000;">Andrea Burkiett, director of Elementary Curriculum and Instruction at the Savannah-Chatham County Public School System. Breakout sessions are technically possible, &#8220;but when you&#8217;re talking about a kindergarten student who doesn&#8217;t even know how to use a mouse or touchpad, COVID basically made small groups nonexistent.&#8221;</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Amira replicates the guided reading process by analyzing the child&#8217;s speech as they read through a story and identifying things like mispronunciations, skipped words and other common stumbles. It&#8217;s based on research going back 20 years that has tested whether learners using such an automated system actually see any gains (and they did, though generally in a lab setting).</p>
<p>In fact I was speaking to Burkiett out of skepticism — &#8220;AI&#8221; products are thick on the ground and while it does little harm if one recommends you a recipe you don&#8217;t like, it&#8217;s a serious matter if a kid&#8217;s education is impacted. I wanted to be sure this wasn&#8217;t a random app hawking old research to lend itself credibility, and after talking with Burkiett and CEO Mark Angel I feel it&#8217;s quite the opposite and could actually be a valuable tool for educators. But it needed to convince educators first.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jbcU74AaY1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/">Outschool is the newest edtech unicorn</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Outschool is the newest edtech unicorn&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/embed/#?secret=jbcU74AaY1" data-secret="jbcU74AaY1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Not a replacement but a force multiplier</h2>
<p>&#8220;You have to start by truly identifying the reason for wanting to employ a tech tool,&#8221; said Burkiett. &#8220;There are a lot of tech tools out there that are exciting, fun for kids, etc., but we could use all of them and not impact growth or learning at all because we didn&#8217;t stop and say, this tool helps me with this need.&#8221;</p>
<p>Amira was decided on as one that addresses the particular need in the K-5 range of steadily improving reading level through constant practice and feedback.</p>
<p>&#8220;When COVID hit, every tech tool came out of the woodwork and was made free and available,&#8221; Burkiett recalled. &#8220;With Amira you&#8217;re looking at a 1:1 tutor at their specific level. She&#8217;s not a replacement for a teacher — though it has been that way in COVID — but beyond COVID she could become a force multiplier,&#8221; said Burkiett.</p>
<p>You can see the old version of Amira in action below, though it&#8217;s been updated since:</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/KRto8CIxb7Q?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Testing Amira with her own district&#8217;s students, Burkiett replicated the results that have been obtained in more controlled settings: As much as twice or three times as much progress in reading level based on standard assessment tools, some of which are built into the teacher-side Amira app.</p>
<p>Naturally it isn&#8217;t possible to simply attribute all this improvement to Amira — there are other variables in play. But it appears to help and doesn&#8217;t hinder, and the effect correlates with frequency of use. The exact mechanism isn&#8217;t as important as the fact that kids learn faster when they use the app versus when they don&#8217;t, and furthermore this allows teachers to better allocate resources and time. A kid who can&#8217;t use it as often because their family shares a single computer is at a disadvantage that has nothing to do with their aptitude — but this problem can be detected and accounted for by the teacher, unlike a simple &#8220;read at home&#8221; assignment.</p>
<p>&#8220;Outside COVID we would always have students struggling with reading, and we would have parents with the money and knowledge to support their student,&#8221; Burkiett explained. &#8220;But now we can take this tool and offer it to students regardless of mom and dad&#8217;s time, mom and dad&#8217;s ability to pay. We can now give that tutor session to every single student.&#8221;</p>
<h2>&#8220;Radically suboptimal conditions&#8221;</h2>
<p>This is familiar territory for CEO Mark Angel, though the AI aspect, he admits, is new.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of the Amira team came from Renaissance Learning. bringing fairly conventional edtech software into elementary school classrooms at scale. The actual tech we used was very simple compared to Amira — the big challenge was trying to figure out how to make applications work with the teacher workflow, or make them friendly and resilient when 6-year-olds are your users,&#8221; he told me.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u5eDL08RkX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/03/13/private-equity-firm-hellman-friedman-acquires-learning-analytics-company-renaissance-learning-for-1-1b-in-cash/">Private Equity Firm Hellman &amp; Friedman Acquires Learning Analytics Company Renaissance Learning For $1.1B In Cash</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Private Equity Firm Hellman &amp; Friedman Acquires Learning Analytics Company Renaissance Learning For $1.1B In Cash&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/03/13/private-equity-firm-hellman-friedman-acquires-learning-analytics-company-renaissance-learning-for-1-1b-in-cash/embed/#?secret=u5eDL08RkX" data-secret="u5eDL08RkX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Not to make it trite, but what we&#8217;ve learned is really just listen to teachers — they&#8217;re the superusers,&#8221; Angel continued. &#8220;And to design for radically suboptimal conditions, like background noise, kids playing with the microphone, the myriad things that happen in real-life circumstances.&#8221;</p>
<p>Once they were confident in the ability of the app to reliably decode words, the system was given three fundamental tasks that fall under the broader umbrella of machine learning.</p>
<p>The first is telling the difference between a sentence being read correctly and incorrectly. This can be difficult due to the many normal differences between speakers. Singling out errors that matter, versus simply deviation from an imaginary norm (in speech recognition that is often American English as spoken by white people) lets readers go at their own pace and in their own voice, with only actual issues like saying a silent k noted by the app.</p>
<p>(On that note, considering the prevalence of English language learners with accents, I asked about the company&#8217;s performance and approach there. Angel said they and their research partners went to great lengths to make sure they had a representative dataset, and that the model only flags pronunciations that indicate a word was not read or understood correctly.)</p>
<p>The second is knowing what action to take to correct an error. In the case of a silent k, it matters whether this is a first grader who is still learning spelling or a fourth grader who is proficient. And is this the first time they&#8217;ve made that mistake, or the tenth? Do they need an explanation of why the word is this way, or several examples of similar words? &#8220;It&#8217;s about helping a student at a moment in time,&#8221; Angel said, both in the moment of reading that word, and in the context of their current state as a learner.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138059" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138059" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2138059 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png" alt="Screenshot of a reading assessment in the app Amira." width="1024" height="667" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png 1182w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png?resize=300,195 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png?resize=768,500 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png?resize=680,443 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/amira-assessment.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138059" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amira Learning</p></div></p>
<p>Third is a data-based triage system that warns students and parents if a kid may potentially have a language learning disorder like dyslexia. The patterns are there in how they read — and while a system like Amira can&#8217;t actually diagnose, it can flag kids who may be high risk to receive a more thorough screening. (A note on privacy: Angel assured me that all information is totally private and by default is considered to belong to the district. &#8220;You&#8217;d have to be insane to take advantage of it. We&#8217;d be out of business in a nanosecond.&#8221;)</p>
<p>The $11 million in funding comes at what could be a hockey-stick moment for Amira&#8217;s adoption. (The round was led by <span id="m_-6083167058463108285gmail-docs-internal-guid-347fe175-7fff-45d4-1b28-f8097a400b8b">Authentic Ventures II, LP, with participation from Vertical Ventures, Owl Ventures and Rethink Education.</span>)</p>
<p>&#8220;COVID was a gigantic spotlight on the problem that Amira was created to solve,&#8221; Angel said. &#8220;We&#8217;ve always struggled in this country to help our children become fluent readers. The data is quite scary — more than two-thirds of our fourth graders aren&#8217;t proficient readers, and those two-thirds aren&#8217;t equally distributed by income or race. It&#8217;s a decades-long struggle.&#8221;</p>
<p>Having basically given the product away for a year, the company is now looking at how to convert those users into customers. It seems like, just like the rest of society, &#8220;going back to normal&#8221; doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean going back to 2019 entirely. The lessons of the pandemic era are sticking.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Sjd3yXvbtI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/y-combinator-widens-its-bet-in-edtech-in-latest-batch/">Y Combinator widens its bet in edtech in latest batch</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Y Combinator widens its bet in edtech in latest batch&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/y-combinator-widens-its-bet-in-edtech-in-latest-batch/embed/#?secret=Sjd3yXvbtI" data-secret="Sjd3yXvbtI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;They don&#8217;t have the intention to just go back to the old ways,&#8221; Angel explained. &#8220;They&#8217;re searching for a new synthesis — how to incorporate tech, but do it in a classroom with kids elbow to elbow and interacting with teachers. So we&#8217;re focused on making Amira the norm in a post-COVID classroom.&#8221;</p>
<p>Part of that is making sure the app works with language learners at more levels and grades, so the team is working to expand its capabilities upward to include middle-school students as well as elementary. Another is building out the management side so that success at the classroom and district levels can be more easily understood.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138069" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138069" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2138069 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg" alt="Cartoon illustration of an adventurous looking woman in front of a jungle and zeppelin." width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Amira_Onboarding.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138069" class="wp-caption-text">Amira&#8217;s appearance got an update in the new app as well. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amira Learning</p></div></p>
<p>The company is also launching a new app aimed at parents rather than teachers. &#8220;A year ago 100% of our usage was in the classroom, then three weeks later 100% of our usage was at home. We had to learn a lot about how to adapt. Out of that learning we&#8217;re shipping Amira and the Story Craft that helps parents work with their children.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hundreds of districts are on board provisionally, but decisions are still being kicked down the road as they deal with outbreaks, frustrated parents and every other chaotic aspect of getting back to &#8220;normal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Perhaps a bit of celebrity juice may help tip the balance in their favor. A new partnership with Houston Texans linebacker Brennan Scarlett has the NFL player advising the board and covering the cost of 100 students at a Portland, OR school through his education charity, the Big Yard Foundation — and more to come. It may be a drop in the bucket in the scheme of things, with a year of schooling disrupted, but teachers know that every drop counts.<span id="m_-6083167058463108285gmail-docs-internal-guid-347fe175-7fff-45d4-1b28-f8097a400b8b"></span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="X915dbP16O"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/">How is edtech spending its extra capital?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How is edtech spending its extra capital?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/how-is-edtech-spending-its-extra-capital/embed/#?secret=X915dbP16O" data-secret="X915dbP16O" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tH7JhdHrqc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;13 investors say lifelong learning is taking edtech mainstream&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/embed/#?secret=tH7JhdHrqc" data-secret="tH7JhdHrqc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amira-learning-raises-11m-to-put-its-ai-powered-literacy-tutor-in-post-covid-classrooms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137876</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bird, Lime and VeoRide selected for NYC e-scooter pilot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric scooters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veoride]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2133136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lime, Bird and VeoRide have scored coveted permits to New York City&#8217;s first e-scooter pilot. The New York City Department of Transportation, which originally released a request for proposals in October for the pilot that was meant to start in early March, made its selections public Wednesday. The three companies are expected to begin operations in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lime, Bird and VeoRide have scored coveted permits to New York City&#8217;s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">first e-scooter pilot. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The New York City Department of Transportation, which originally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/the-scooter-battle-for-new-york-city-is-on/">released a request for proposals in October</a> for the pilot that was meant to start in early March, made its selections public Wednesday. The three companies are expected to begin operations in the Bronx by early summer with 1,000 electric scooters each.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“After a competitive selection process, Bird, Lime and Veo unveil e-scooter models and pricing plans that will allow most rides for under $5,” said NYC DOT in a statement.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “New bicycle lanes planned for pilot zone over the next two years will also enhance e-scooter mobility and safety.” </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Micromobility operators have been competing fiercely to win a dwindling number of city concessions. If you can make it in New York, you can make it anywhere, says Frank Sinatra, and winning the Big Apple plays a massive role in determining which operators will survive as the rideshare industry consolidates under a few powerful players. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bird is already in over 100 cities around the United States, Europe and the Middle East, while Lime is ubiquitous, with around 130 cities in the U.S., Europe, the Middle East and Australia under its belt. This win calcifies the clout the two already have in the industry. Chicago-based VeoRide is arguably the underdog of the trio, with service in around 20 U.S. cities, so getting the chance to operate in New York could be a game-changer for the </span><a href="https://veo-mobility.medium.com/sorry-boys-the-first-profitable-micromobility-company-was-veo-not-lime-97b6b279243f"><span style="font-weight: 400;">already profitable</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> company. This is especially true in a city where people are simultaneously still wary of coronavirus and eager to get out and catch up with friends and family this summer. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Or4DoJ542K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/the-scooter-battle-for-new-york-city-is-on/">The scooter battle for New York City is on</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The scooter battle for New York City is on&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/the-scooter-battle-for-new-york-city-is-on/embed/#?secret=Or4DoJ542K" data-secret="Or4DoJ542K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This e-scooter pilot program couldn’t come at a better time, as New York focuses on providing low-cost transportation options that allow residents to travel socially-distanced in the open air,” Lime CEO Wayne Ting said in a statement. “In welcoming a new mode of transportation to its streets, New York demonstrates its dedication to shepherding a sustainable recovery from COVID-19 — one that isn’t hampered by the crippling traffic congestion that depresses growth.”</span></p>
<p>Superpedestrian and Spin are among the companies that weren&#8217;t selected for participation in the program. Superpedestrian CEO Assaf Biderman said in a statement that the company was proud of the proposal it presented. &#8220;We know this is just a beginning, and there are more communities in every corner of the city that are calling out for new, safe and sustainable transportation options&#8211;something we can deliver,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite general fanfare, there may be a limit to how far operations can spread beyond the Bronx in the future. The first phase of the pilot covers neighborhoods in the East Bronx spanning from Eastchester to Van Nest; the second phase extends south to Soundview and east to Edgewater with another 4,000 to 6,000 scooters. The DOT said it chose these geographic boundaries to reach transit deserts that are unserved by existing bike-share programs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That last bit is important to note. Lyft-owned Citi Bike has a monopoly over shared micromobility in NYC, with bike docks all over Manhattan and in parts of Brooklyn, Queens and the South Bronx. While </span><a href="https://legistar.council.nyc.gov/LegislationDetail.aspx?ID=3763648&amp;GUID=05DFE6C0-4E1E-4E49-A95C-BDD1F9C44555&amp;Options=ID%7CText%7C&amp;Search=1266"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2018 legislation that allowed for the introduction of dockless e-scooters in NYC</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> aims to “prioritize” neighborhoods with no access to Citi Bike, the pilot zones were designed specifically to avoid overlap with Bronx neighborhoods targeted by the docked bike share’s expansion plans. </span></p>
<h2>What to expect from the e-scooter pilot in the Bronx</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aside from operating in alignment with NYC’s Vision Zero and equity goals, the DOT chose companies that would play ball with the city’s strong enforcement mechanisms, and that very much includes managing sidewalk clutter with dedicated parking corrals and fleet management software, a DOT spokesperson told TechCrunch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lime intends to combine its corral and lock-to parking strategies for the first time in NYC to ensure its Gen 3 and Gen 4 scooters don’t become a bother to the community. It’ll also rely on its backend fleet management software and a “tidy crew” that will patrol the pilot area to rebalance scooters. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“At high-traffic locations like transit stations, riders must park in physical parking corrals enforced using Lime’s industry-leading geofence technology,” Phil Jones, Lime’s senior government relations director told TechCrunch. Lime uses a combination of onboard and cloud computing to determine the locations of geofences, so it’ll be interesting to see how this tech holds up in such a dense city, where even Google Maps often has trouble placing individuals. “Using our LimeLocks, riders must lock their e-scooters at bike racks or other places where traditional bike parking is permitted.”</span></p>
<p><a href="https://veo-mobility.medium.com/getting-scooters-right-for-new-yorkers-541cad84de3d"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Veo also plans to implement lock-to parking</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to keep scooters from falling over or blocking sidewalks.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pilot will cover an 18-square-mile area that’s home to 570,000 residents, 80% of whom are Black or Latino. The median household income in the Bronx is $40,088, with a poverty rate of 26.2%, according to the </span><a href="https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/bronxcountybronxboroughnewyork"><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. Census Bureau</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, so equity was top of mind for the city when evaluating operators. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bird already has an Access program that offers unlimited rides for $5 a month to low-income residents who are on government assistance, and even allows riders to pay with cash and unlock vehicles via SMS.</span><b> </b><a href="https://www.veoride.com/veo-access/#:~:text=Veo%20Access,state%2C%20or%20federal%20assistance%20program.">Veo has an access program, but the terms are unclear</a><b>. </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lime’s Access Program is similar, in that it offers 50% off rides to those on public assistance, but with NYC the program will see a rebrand as Lime Aid and expand to cover </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">frontline healthcare workers, teachers and people in the performing arts, nonprofit and hospitality sectors — those who have been most affected by the pandemic. Lime also has agreements with employment offices like BronxWorks and the Center for Employment Opportunities to source employees for the pilot locally.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">About 11% of Bronx residents under the age of 65 have a disability, so the DOT also evaluated operators based on accessibility. Victor Calise, commissioner of the mayor’s office for people with disabilities, was one of the people on the grading panel, so Lime made a point of focusing on accessibility for the disabled community. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lime recently launched a program in San Francisco that allows people with disabilities to order an accessible scooter delivered to their house with 24-hours advance notice, and the company intends to try out the same service in New York. In preparation for the Bronx pilot, Lime designed and built seven vehicle types to meet various physical abilities, including a three-wheeled, sit-down vehicle for someone who has challenges balancing; a two-wheeled sit-down for someone who can’t stand for long periods of time; a tandem scooter of sorts so someone who has trouble seeing or is blind can have a partner with full vision with them; and a tricycle with a shopping basket. These vehicles are available on demand and will be delivered directly to users upon request. </span></p>
<p>[gallery ids="2138246,2138250,2138242"]</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We didn’t want to just think what </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">might</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a disabled person want, but to actually go to the New York disabled community and learn from them,” said Jones, noting that Lime worked with New York’s Center for Independence of the Disabled, as well as other advocacy groups, prior to submitting its bid. “There’s a vocal and vibrant community here, and we are not just addressing their concerns around parking on the street, but how they can actually use our devices so we can provide a meaningful service to them.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Veo will offer its stand-up Astro e-scooter and its futuristic-looking Cosmo seated e-scooter because seated rides are more accessible for many, especially those taking longer trips. The company has also stated that it’s committed to ADA compliance and will make available upon request electric-powered attachments that allow private non-motorized wheelchairs to operate as motorized devices.  </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="usUQpkSpI2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/maas-transit-the-business-of-mobility-as-a-service/">MaaS transit: The business of mobility as a service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MaaS transit: The business of mobility as a service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/maas-transit-the-business-of-mobility-as-a-service/embed/#?secret=usUQpkSpI2" data-secret="usUQpkSpI2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In terms of reducing traffic congestion and air pollution, Veo also touts its waterproof, durable, swappable batteries, which don’t require a gas-guzzling van to replace batteries but which can be done via cargo bike or even the Cosmo. Lime also has swappable batteries, but according to a </span><a href="https://www.bird.co/blog/understanding-risks-swappable-e-scooter-batteries/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">November blog post</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Bird has still not implemented this technology in full. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To enhance safety, Bird recently launched Beginner Mode as a new feature built for the Bird Two, alongside autonomous emergency braking and skid detection. This gives new riders a gentle acceleration option so they can gradually work their way up to full speed.  </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2133136</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Check out the tech leaders joining us on Extra Crunch Live in May</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/check-out-the-tech-leaders-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-may/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/check-out-the-tech-leaders-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-may/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live, our weekly event series that connects founders with tech leaders, is really picking up speed. Recently, we had a conversation with Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine and Scale&#8217;s Alexandr Wang about how sometimes, unconventional VC deals are the best deals. We&#8217;ve also taken a walk through early decks from companies like Poshmark, Steady and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a>, our weekly event series that connects founders with tech leaders, is really picking up speed. Recently, we had a conversation with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/scale-ceo-alex-wang-and-accels-dan-levine-explain-why-sometimes-unconventional-vc-deals-are-best/">Accel&#8217;s Dan Levine and Scale&#8217;s Alexandr Wang about how sometimes, unconventional VC deals are the best deals</a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve also taken a walk through early decks from companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/ceo-manish-chandra-and-investor-navin-chaddha-explain-why-poshmarks-series-a-deck-sings/">Poshmark</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/steadys-adam-roseman-and-investor-emmalyn-shaw-outline-what-worked-and-what-was-missing-in-the-series-a-deck/">Steady</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/28/justworks-series-b-pitch-deck-may-be-the-most-wonderfully-simple-deck-ive-ever-seen/">Justworks</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZxhezApyql"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/steadys-adam-roseman-and-investor-emmalyn-shaw-outline-what-worked-and-what-was-missing-in-the-series-a-deck/">Steady&#8217;s Adam Roseman and investor Emmalyn Shaw outline what worked (and what was missing) in the Series A deck</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Steady&#8217;s Adam Roseman and investor Emmalyn Shaw outline what worked (and what was missing) in the Series A deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/steadys-adam-roseman-and-investor-emmalyn-shaw-outline-what-worked-and-what-was-missing-in-the-series-a-deck/embed/#?secret=ZxhezApyql" data-secret="ZxhezApyql" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But we&#8217;re only getting started. We have an amazing lineup of speakers hanging out with us in May.</p>
<p>As a reminder, Extra Crunch Live goes down every Wednesday at 3pm ET/noon PT and is open to anyone who wants to join. We talk to investor/founder duos about how their deals came together, including the challenges, and usually take a look at their original decks. We also look at pitch decks submitted by audience members and our guests give their live feedback. If that sounds like something you&#8217;d be into, <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/Lutrgz8Q">you can submit your deck using this form</a>.</p>
<p>One other note: On-demand access to this content is reserved for Extra Crunch members (who also get unfettered access to loads of premium content like market maps, investor surveys, EC-1s and more). If you&#8217;ve been on the fence about joining Extra Crunch,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> just do it</a>.</p>
<p>So without any further ado, let me tell you a little bit about our May lineup.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Extra Crunch Live: FirstMark Capital and Orchard</h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>May 5 &#8211; 3pm ET/noon PT</strong></em></p>
<p>Court Cunningham launched Orchard (formerly Perch) in 2017 and turned it into one of the brightest stars in the universe of prop tech. The company has raised more than $350 million to rethink the way people buy and sell homes (simultaneously). Rick Heitzmann, managing partner at FirstMark Capital, led the company&#8217;s Series A, adding to a long list of ultimately successful early-stage companies that Heitzman has bet on. Hear this duo talk about the growth of prop tech, how they came together on that Series A deal and what&#8217;s next in the world of startup venture.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-firstmark-capital-and-orchard">Register here.</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2138435 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-05.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Extra Crunch Live: Toyota AI Ventures and May Mobility</h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>May 12 &#8211; 3pm ET/noon PT</strong></em></p>
<p>The mobility industry has evolved rapidly in the last decade. On Extra Crunch Live, we&#8217;re lucky to be joined by Toyota AI Ventures&#8217; Jim Adler and May Mobility&#8217;s Nina Grooms Lee and Edwin Olson. We&#8217;ll talk about how Toyota AI Ventures led May&#8217;s seed round, and how May went on to raise more than $80 million. Adler, Lee and Olson will also give their live feedback on decks submitted by the audience.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-toyota-ai-ventures-and-may-mobility">Register here.</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2138437 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-12.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Extra Crunch Live: Sequoia and Vise</h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>May 19 &#8211; 3pm ET/noon PT</strong></em></p>
<p>Shaun Maguire, partner at Sequoia, has been on both sides of the table, as an entrepreneur and investor. His portfolio includes Stripe, Opendoor, IonQ, SpinLaunch, Lambda School, Dandelion Energy, Clutter and Vise. Samir Vasavada co-founded Vise in 2016 to bring AI to financial advisors and has raised more than $60 million. Hear these two discuss how the fintech landscape is evolving, how to successfully raise funding in fintech and how they overcome challenges together.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-sequoia-and-vise">Register here.</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2138442 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-19.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Extra Crunch Live: Bessemer and Toast</h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>May 26 &#8211; 3pm ET/noon PT</strong></em></p>
<p>Kent Bennett has invested in companies like Blue Apron, Bevi and Toast, among others. It wouldn&#8217;t be an overstatement to say he&#8217;s an expert in retail and hospitality tech. Aman Narang founded Toast in 2011 and the restaurant POS service has raised more than $900 million. Hear these two discuss how they came together for Toast&#8217;s Series B deal and how they work together today.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-bessemer-and-toast">Register here.</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2138443 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ECL-2021-05-26.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/check-out-the-tech-leaders-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-may/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137651</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: How can I get an H-1B without the lottery?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dear-sophie-how-can-i-get-an-h-1b-without-the-lottery/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dear-sophie-how-can-i-get-an-h-1b-without-the-lottery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H-1B visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sophie Alcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For the past few years, our company has put very promising candidates into the annual H-1B lottery. None of them have been selected. Are there any other ways we can obtain H-1Bs for our team members?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/dear-sophie-help-my-h-1b-wasnt-chosen/">Dear Sophie: Help! My H-1B wasn’t chosen!</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/dear-sophie-what-should-i-know-about-prenups-and-getting-a-green-card-through-marriage/">Dear Sophie: What should I know about prenups and getting a green card through marriage?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie: </strong></p>
<p><strong>For the past few years, our company has put very promising candidates into the annual H-1B lottery. None of them have been selected — and none of them meet the requirements for other work visas like an O-1A. </strong></p>
<p><strong>We lost out again in this year’s H-1B lottery. Are there <em>any</em> other ways we can obtain H-1Bs for our team members?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Soldiering On in Sunnyvale</strong></p>
<p>Dear Soldiering:</p>
<p>Thank you for your timely question &#8212; you are not alone! Many employers face the same frustration given that the number of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/episode-09-what-makes-a-strong-h-1b-petition/">H-1B visas</a> the government issues each year is capped at 85,000, while typically more than twice that number are sought by employers annually.</p>
<p>At my Silicon Valley immigration law firm, we’ve been delighted for the opportunity to collaborate with the nonprofit <a href="https://www.openavenuesfoundation.org/">Open Avenues Foundation</a> to support private companies with a Plan B: a cap-exempt, concurrent H-1B for their employees, without needing to go through the H-1B lottery.</p>
<p>It’s a timely, predictable solution that supports teams whether the beneficiary is currently outside <em>or</em> inside the United States.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>I recently <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/066-cap-exempt-h-1bs-with-danielle-goldman/">interviewed</a> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniellesgoldman/">Danielle Goldman</a>, co-founder and executive director of Open Avenues, on my podcast. Through the <a href="https://www.openavenuesfoundation.org/global-talent">Global Talent Fellowship</a> program, the foundation offers a unique solution for employers like you to have a Plan B for H-1Bs: It’s possible to obtain an H-1B visa for an existing or prospective employee without going through the <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/060-h-1b-lottery-planning-part-2/">H-1B lottery</a> process — or the randomness and timing restrictions that come with it. Goldman refers to the program as “innovation within legislation.”</p>
<p>So how does that work? Well, first off, you should know that four categories of employers are exempt from the annual H-1B lottery, meaning they can apply for an H-1B visa at any time of year and their pool of H-1B visas is not capped. The four categories of employers that are eligible for cap-exempt H-1Bs include:<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/dear-sophie-how-can-i-get-an-h-1b-without-the-lottery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toyota taps Apex.AI for its autonomous vehicle operating system</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/toyota-taps-apex-ai-for-its-autonomous-vehicle-operating-system/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/toyota-taps-apex-ai-for-its-autonomous-vehicle-operating-system/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apex.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tier IV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Automakers shifting to all-electric and tech-laden vehicles have discovered that software — and more aptly software that is free of bugs and can be updated wirelessly — has become a consistent speed bump on the road to attracting customers. It is an issue that plagued Volkswagen&#8217;s launch of its all-electric VW ID.3, the 2022 Volvo [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Automakers shifting to all-electric and tech-laden vehicles have discovered that software — and more aptly software that is free of bugs and can be updated wirelessly — has become a consistent speed bump on the road to attracting customers. It is an issue that plagued Volkswagen&#8217;s launch of its all-electric VW ID.3, the 2022 Volvo XC40 Recharge and the Ford Mustang Mach-E. </span></p>
<p>Apex.AI, a startup founded by Bosch veterans and automated systems engineers Jan Becker and Dejan Pangercic, has spent four years rewriting the robot operating system that will give automakers the tools to integrate software within the vehicle and make sure all the applications run reliably. Now, freshly armed with a safety certification that validates its software development kit (SDK) is sophisticated enough to be used in production vehicles, Apex.AI has landed Toyota and Japanese tech startup Tier IV as partners.</p>
<p>Toyota&#8217;s Woven Planet Group is integrating the Apex.OS SDK into its own vehicle development platform, called Arene. The Apex SDK will handle the safety-critical applications and aims to speed up autonomous software development and ultimately bring it to production vehicles. In a separate deal announced Wednesday, <a href="https://tier4.jp/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://tier4.jp/en/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618356688676000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFXt4mZajNIXkusnbI_B5KZFKfzxg">Tier IV,</a> a startup in Japan known as the original creator of open-source software for autonomous driving, called Autoware, said it will use Apex.AI&#8217;s software stack for safety-critical autonomous systems.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;A trend that has become obvious in the past year, is in order to beat Tesla, car companies are aiming for what they call a software-defined vehicle,&#8221; Becker said in a recent interview. Automakers are moving away from distributing 100 electric control units (computers) throughout a vehicle and instead are having just a few high-performance computers with all the functions being implemented by the software, Becker explained.</p>
<p>That shift might mean hundreds or even thousands of software developers might be working on one vehicle. &#8220;And that really only works if they are all using the same interface, and not in silos,&#8221; Becker said. &#8220;And this is exactly what this SDK now enables. So it&#8217;s the first time, with Apex.OS that there&#8217;s this common abstraction layer or SDK, which can address practically all functions in a vehicle.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apex&#8217;s toolkit has attracted the attention of private and strategic investors. In 2018, the company raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/15/apex-ai-raises-15-5-million-for-autonomous-vehicle-software/">Series A round of $15.5 million</a>. Since then, the company has taken <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/05/volvo-invests-in-autonomous-vehicle-operating-system-startup-apex-ai-though-its-vc-arm/">strategic investment</a> from Airbus, JLR&#8217;s InMotion Ventures, Toyota and Volvo Group. Becker wouldn&#8217;t disclose the amounts of those investments, but noted the company is now raising for a Series B.</p>
<p>The roots of Apex.OS are the open-source Robot Operating System known as ROS that is commonly used for R&amp;D projects and the development of autonomous vehicles. Apex&#8217;s aim was to rewrite the code to handle functional safety and real-time processing. The SDK was recently certified by TÜV NORD for functional safety. This means the technology is verified for use in production vehicles.</p>
<p>It was a longstanding belief that open-source code was not certifiable, according to Becker. The company spent a year working on the certification.</p>
<p>&#8220;If a software crash happens on your laptop it&#8217;s inconvenient, but if software crashes in any safety-critical function of a vehicle it can be catastrophic,&#8221; Becker said. &#8220;This is why we set out to write reliable software that protects against system crashes or operation failures. The certification proves we accomplished our goal as our software targets failure rates so low that they cannot be expressed statistically.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MZKpkQkKcF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/as-autonomy-stalls-lidar-companies-learn-to-adapt/">As autonomy stalls, lidar companies learn to adapt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As autonomy stalls, lidar companies learn to adapt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/as-autonomy-stalls-lidar-companies-learn-to-adapt/embed/#?secret=MZKpkQkKcF" data-secret="MZKpkQkKcF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/toyota-taps-apex-ai-for-its-autonomous-vehicle-operating-system/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138319</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gay dating site Manhunt hacked, thousands of accounts stolen</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/gay-dating-site-manhunt-hacked/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/gay-dating-site-manhunt-hacked/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@jack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ashley madison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[securedrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Manhunt, a gay dating app that claims to have 6 million male members, has confirmed it was hit by a data breach in February after a hacker gained access to the company&#8217;s accounts database. In a notice filed with the Washington attorney general&#8217;s office, Manhunt said the hacker &#8220;gained access to a database that stored [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Manhunt, a gay dating app that claims to have 6 million male members, has confirmed it was hit by a data breach in February after a hacker gained access to the company&#8217;s accounts database.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/20615089-mhnextllc2021-04-01">a notice</a> filed with the Washington attorney general&#8217;s office, Manhunt said the hacker &#8220;gained access to a database that stored account credentials for Manhunt users,&#8221; and &#8220;downloaded the usernames, email addresses and passwords for a subset of our users in early February 2021.</p>
<p>The notice did not say how the passwords were scrambled, if at all, to prevent them from being read by humans. Passwords scrambled using weak algorithms can sometimes be decoded into plain text, allowing malicious hackers to break into their accounts.</p>
<p>Following the breach, Manhunt force-reset account passwords began alerting users in mid-March. Manhunt did not say what percentage of its users had their data stolen or how the data breach happened, but said that more than 7,700 Washington state residents were affected.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s attorneys did not reply to an email requesting comment.</p>
<p>But questions remain about how Manhunt handled the breach. In March, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/Manhunt/status/1370012193056493568 ">tweeted</a> that, &#8220;At this time, all Manhunt users are required to update their password to ensure it meets the updated password requirements.&#8221; The tweet did not say that user accounts had been stolen.</p>
<p>Manhunt was launched in 2001 by Online-Buddies Inc., which also offered gay dating app Jack&#8217;d before it <a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/newyork/news/2019/07/10/perry-street-owner-of-scruff-buys-jackd.html">was sold</a> to Perry Street in 2019 for an undisclosed sum. Just months before the sale, Jack&#8217;d had <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2019/02/indecent-disclosure-gay-dating-app-left-private-exposed-to-web/">a security lapse</a> that exposed users&#8217; private photos and location data.</p>
<p>Dating sites store some of the most sensitive information on their users, and are frequently a target of malicious hackers. In 2015, Ashley Madison, a dating site that encouraged users to have an affair, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/03/have-i-been-pwned/">was hacked</a>, exposing names, and postal and email addresses. Several people <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/08/24/ashley-madison-offering-500000-reward-for-info-on-hack-now-linked-to-two-suicides/">died by suicide</a> after the stolen data was posted online. A year later, dating site AdultFriendFinder was hacked, exposing <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/adultfriendfinder-network-hack-exposes-secrets-of-412-million-users/">more than 400 million user accounts</a>.</p>
<p>In 2018, same-sex dating app Grindr <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/azeenghorayshi/grindr-hiv-status-privacy">made headlines</a> for sharing users&#8217; HIV status with data analytics firms.</p>
<p>In other cases, poor security — in some cases none at all — led to data spills involving some of the most sensitive data. In 2019, Rela, a popular dating app for gay and queer women in China, left a server unsecured with no password, allowing anyone to access sensitive data — including sexual orientation and geolocation — on more than 5 million app users. Months later, Jewish dating app JCrush <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/04/jcrush-exposed-data-messages/">exposed</a> around 200,000 user records.</p>
<p><strong>Read more: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/27/rela-data-exposed/">Rela, a Chinese lesbian dating app, exposed 5 million user profiles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/04/jcrush-exposed-data-messages/">Jewish dating app JCrush exposed user data and private messages</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/28/security-flaw-in-grindr-exposed-locations-to-third-party-service/">Security flaw in Grindr exposed locations to third-party service</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/grindr-account-hijack-flaw/">A security flaw in Grindr let anyone easily hijack user accounts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/grindr-on-the-hook-for-e10m-over-gdpr-consent-violations/">Grindr on the hook for €10M over GDPR consent violations</a></li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p><em>Know something, say something. Send tips securely over Signal and WhatsApp to +1 646-755-8849. You can also send files or documents using our SecureDrop. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/techcrunch-launches-securedrop/">Learn more</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/gay-dating-site-manhunt-hacked/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138412</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon&#8217;s latest Echo Buds are a shameless Apple knock-off</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AirPod pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[echo buds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is Amazon&#8217;s latest hardware product: The redesigned Alexa earbuds. TechCrunch covered the announcement here, where the specs and capabilities are listed. I&#8217;m sure they work fine, too, but the case design is a blatant rip-off of Apple&#8217;s AirPod Pros. This is just lazy. Amazon has a long history of selling and promoting lookalikes, copycats, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This is Amazon&#8217;s latest hardware product: The redesigned Alexa earbuds. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-alexa-earbuds-return-with-a-smaller-design-and-wireless-charging/">TechCrunch covered the announcement here</a>, where the specs and capabilities are listed. I&#8217;m sure they work fine, too, but the case design is a blatant rip-off of Apple&#8217;s AirPod Pros.</p>
<p>This is just lazy.</p>
<p>Amazon has a long history of selling and promoting lookalikes, copycats, and clones of other products. Likewise, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/amazon-and-valentino-team-up-in-joint-lawsuit-against-new-york-counterfeiter-over-rockstud-knock-offs/">the retailer sued</a> third-party sellers for doing the same thing. Amazon also has been accused of investing in companies and later producing clones of the products. In 2020 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/29/bezos-cant-guarantee-no-anti-competitive-activity-as-congress-catches-him-flat-footed/">CEO Jeff Bezos testified on this subject</a> in front of a congressional hearing where he couldn&#8217;t guarantee the company would end this process. Often the products Amazon copies come from small startups without the resources to fight a giant like Amazon.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Last month California-based <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HbxWGjQ2szQ">Peak Design took to YouTube to protest Amazon&#8217;s unabashed copy of one of Peak&#8217;s top products</a>. As Peak points out, Amazon&#8217;s take is a cheap knockoff made from lower quality materials and without Peak Design&#8217;s ethical manufacturing. The video quickly went viral, amassing over 4.5 million hits and highlighting Amazon&#8217;s shady practices.</p>
<p>For the latest Echo Buds, Amazon copied a market leader instead of a small startup. To recap, Amazon, a company worth over a trillion dollars, just released a product that looks essentially identical to a top-selling product from Apple, a company worth 2 trillion dollars.</p>
<p>The Echo Buds are much less expensive than Apple&#8217;s $250 AirPod Pros, too. The standard Echo Buds costs $100, and the version with wireless charging runs $120. It&#8217;s important to note the wireless buds themselves do not look like AirPods. Amazon only copied the ubiquitous AirPod Pro case.</p>
<p>The consumer is the loser here. With more resources than many countries, Amazon can produce world-class products, yet it decided to copy a rival&#8217;s market-leading product. In the end, it&#8217;s easier (and cheaper) to follow trends than become a trendsetter.</p>
<hr />
<h2>Peak Design takes on Amazon</h2>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/HbxWGjQ2szQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/amazons-latest-echo-buds-are-a-shameless-apple-knock-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138361</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I can&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s not meat! Mycelium meat replacement company aims for summer launch of first products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acre venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congruent Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecovative Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jerky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michelle obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mycelium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MycoWorks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prelude ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silicon valley bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White House]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meati, a company turning mycelium (the structural fibers of fungi) into healthier meat replacements for consumers, is prepping for a big summer rollout. Co-founder Tyler Huggins expects to have the first samples of its whole-cut steak and chicken products in select restaurants around the country &#8212; along with their first commercial product, a jerky strip. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://meati.com/">Meati</a>, a company turning mycelium (the structural fibers of fungi) into healthier meat replacements for consumers, is prepping for a big summer rollout.</p>
<p>Co-founder Tyler Huggins expects to have the first samples of its whole-cut steak and chicken products in select restaurants around the country &#8212; along with their first commercial product, a jerky strip.</p>
<p>For Huggins, the product launch is another step on a long road toward broad commercial adoption of functional fungi foods as a better-for-you alternative to traditional meats.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Use this as a conversation starter. About 2 ounces of this gives you 50% of your protein; 50% of your fiber; and half of your daily zinc. There really is nothing that can compare to this product in terms of nutritionals,&#8221; Huggins said. </span></p>
<p>And moving from meat to mushrooms is a better option for the planet.</p>
<p>Meati expects to turn on its pilot plant this summer and is joining a movement among mushroom fans that includes milk replacements, from <a href="https://perfectdayfoods.com/">Perfect Day</a>, more meat replacements from <a href="https://www.atlastfood.co/">Atlast</a>, and leather substitutes from <a href="https://ecovativedesign.com/mycoflex">Ecovative</a> and <a href="https://www.mycoworks.com/">MycoWorks</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DfZODAruTl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ecovative-sees-a-fungal-future-for-fashion-food-and-foam-packaging-and-has-a-fresh-60m-to-make-it/">Ecovative sees a fungal future for fashion, food and foam packaging and has a fresh $60M to make it</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ecovative sees a fungal future for fashion, food and foam packaging and has a fresh $60M to make it&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ecovative-sees-a-fungal-future-for-fashion-food-and-foam-packaging-and-has-a-fresh-60m-to-make-it/embed/#?secret=DfZODAruTl" data-secret="DfZODAruTl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re definitely all in this together,&#8221; said Huggins of the other mob of mycelium-based tech companies bringing products to market.</p>
<p>However, not all mycelium is created equally, Huggins said. Meati has what Huggins said was a unique way of growing its funguses (not a real word) that &#8220;keep it in its most happy state.&#8221; That means peak nutritional content and peak growth efficiency, according to the company.</p>
<p>For Huggins, whose parents own a bison ranch and who grew up in cattle country, the goal is not to replace a t-bone or a ribeye, but the cuts of meat and chicken that find their ways into a burrito supreme or other quick serve meat cuts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138406" style="width: 426px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138406" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2138406" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg" alt="" width="416" height="624" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg 3689w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Meati_Summer_2020-43.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 416px) 100vw, 416px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138406" class="wp-caption-text">Rendering of Meati mushroom meats in a Banh Mi. Image Credit: Meati</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Head to head with that kind of cut, we win,&#8221; Huggins said. &#8220;I&#8217;d rather pick a fight there now and buy ourselves some time. I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re going to go super high-end to start.&#8221;</p>
<p>That said, the company&#8217;s cap table of investors already includes some pretty heady culinary company. <a href="http://acre.vc/#company-info-full">Acre Venture Partners</a> (which counts Sam Kass &#8212; President Barack Obama&#8217;s Senior Policy Advisor for Nutrition Policy, Executive Director for First Lady Michelle Obama&#8217;s Let&#8217;s Move! campaign, and an Assistant Chef in the White House &#8212; among its partnership) is an investor. So is Chicago&#8217;s fine dining temple, Alinea.</p>
<p>But Huggins wants Meati to be an everyday type of meat replacement product. &#8220;I want to make sure that people think this is an every day protein,&#8221; Huggins said.</p>
<p>Meati thinks its future meat replacements will be cost competitive with conventional beef and chicken, but to whet consumers&#8217; appetites, the company is starting with jerky.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Meati’s delicious jerky,&#8221; said Huggins. &#8220;It provides this blank canvas. We’ll start with these beef jerky like flavors. But I want to come out of the gate and say that we’re mycelium jerky.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The company currently has 30 people on staff led by Huggins and fo-founder Justin Whiteley. The two men initially started working on Meati as a battery replacement. Based on their research (Huggins with mycelium and Whiteley with advanced batteries) the two men received a grant for a mycelium-based electrode for lithium ion batteries.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were trying to tweak the chemical composition of the mycelium to make a better battery. What we found was that we were making something nutritious and edible,&#8221; said Huggins.</p>
<p>Also&#8230; the battery companies didn&#8217;t want it.</p>
<p>Now, backed by $28 million from Acre, Prelude Ventures, Congruent Ventures and Tao Capital, Meati is ready to go to market. The company also has access to debt capital to build out its vast network of mycelium growing facilities. It&#8217;s just raised a $18 million debt round from Trinity and Silicon Valley Bank.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Two years ago … most companies in this space … there wasn’t this ability to take on debt to put steel in the ground,&#8221; said Huggins. &#8220;It’s an exciting time to be in food tech given that you can raise VC funding and there’s this ready available market for debt financing. You’ll start seeing faster and more rapid development because of it.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138413" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138413" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2138413" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg 5203w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/02-Tyler-Justin-2.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138413" class="wp-caption-text">Meati co-founders Tyler Huggins and Justin Whiteley. Image Credit: Meati</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/i-cant-believe-its-not-meat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138294</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inside the US’ epic first-quarter venture capital results</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitchbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We're diving into the data with help from Sarah Kunst of Cleo Capital, Jenny Lefcourt of Freestyle Capital, Iris Choi of Floodgate and Laela Sturdy of CapitalG.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/is-substack-really-worth-650m/">no surprise</a> that the venture capital market was incredibly active in the United States during the first quarter of 2021, but precisely how strong has only recently become clear. This morning, we’re digging into the data.</p>
<p>According to a<a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/reports/q1-2021-pitchbook-nvca-venture-monitor"> report from PitchBook</a>, venture capitalists unleashed a wave of capital in the first three months of the year. So much, in fact, that funding in the United States nearly doubled compared to the same quarter of 2020.</p>
<p>We’ll dig into specific numbers and trends regarding aggregate venture capital results in a moment, but what stood out the most while digesting the Q1 dataset was how strong VC results appeared across different states; a solo late-stage boom the quarter was not.</p>
<p>Seed deal volume appeared strong and early-stage venture capital activity could reach new highs in 2021, but late-stage venture capital activity in the United States is already setting records in both deal count and invested dollars.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>We&#8217;ll parse the headline numbers and then dive into seed and super late-stage data with the help of Sarah Kunst of Cleo Capital, Jenny Lefcourt of Freestyle Capital, Iris Choi of Floodgate and Laela Sturdy of CapitalG.</p>
<p>With their help, we’ll contextualize the numbers and weave anecdotal observations into what the charts and graphs tell us. Especially in the case of seed data, which is famously laggy, added context is crucial. Let’s go!</p>
<h2>A Q1 overview</h2>
<p>According to PitchBook’s report, some 3,987 venture capital rounds were closed in the United States during Q1 2021. Those deals were worth $69 billion, a figure up nearly 93% from 2020’s first-quarter results.</p>
<p>In broad strokes, the United States had a crushing venture capital start to the new year, pandemic be damned. That is especially true when we consider 2020’s full-year figures. Last year, venture capitalists deployed some $166 billion into U.S.-based startups across 12,546 rounds. In contrast, if the first quarter’s pace was maintained during the rest of 2021, the United States would see around 16,000 rounds worth around $280 billion.</p>
<p>Of course, we cannot see the future, so those projections are merely shared to underscore how active the first quarter proved to be; we’ll have to wait for at least another quarter’s data to confidently predict full-year records for 2021.</p>
<p>Powering the rapid start to the venture capital year was a holistic boom: Seed deal volume is forecasted to have set a multiyear high, perhaps matching the historically strong Q2 2018 period. Early-stage venture capital during Q1 2021 was also robust, with $14.5 billion deployed across 1,170 rounds. Both numbers set a pace for fresh records in 2021.</p>
<p>Then there was late-stage dealmaking, which soared in the first quarter. In 2020, late-stage venture capital deals were worth $111.4 billion raised from 3,504 rounds. In the first quarter of 2021, some $51.9 billion was invested into late-stage startups across 1,291 deals.</p>
<p>Valuations and round sizes continued to rise across the board. If there was a better time to raise a big whack of venture capital as a U.S.-based startup, we cannot recall it. And the data seems to scream that the good times are now as good, or gooder, than ever.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138308</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Astranis raises $250M at a $1.4B valuation for smaller, cheaper geostationary communications satellites</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/astranis-raises-250m-at-a-1-4b-valuation-for-smaller-cheaper-geostationary-communications-satellites/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/astranis-raises-250m-at-a-1-4b-valuation-for-smaller-cheaper-geostationary-communications-satellites/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astranis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite constellation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite constellations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venrock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Space startup Astranis has raised a $250 million Series C round to provide it with a capital injection to help scale manufacturing of its unique MicroGEO satellites — geostationary communications satellites that are much smaller than the typical massive, expensive spacecraft used in that orbital band to provide communications and connectivity to specific points on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Space startup Astranis has raised a $250 million Series C round to provide it with a capital injection to help scale manufacturing of its unique MicroGEO satellites — geostationary communications satellites that are much smaller than the typical massive, expensive spacecraft used in that orbital band to provide communications and connectivity to specific points on Earth.</p>
<p>The Astranis Series C was led by BlackRock-managed funds, and includes participation from a host of new investors including Baillie Gifford, Fidelity, Koch Strategic Platforms and more. Existing investors including Andreessen Horowitz, Venrock, and more also chipped in, with the raise valuing the company at $1.4 billion post-money.</p>
<p>This brings the total funding raised by Astranis to over $350 million, including both equity and debt financing. Astranis got started only in 2016, and was part of the YC Winter 2016 cohort. While a lot of other companies are looking to build satellite constellations in low-Earth orbit to provide low-cost broadband on Earth, Astranis, led by co-founder and CEO John Gedmark, is focused on the GEO band, where the large legacy communications satellites currently operate, orbiting the Earth at a fixed position and providing connectivity to a set area on Earth.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4yz8fFod38"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/astranis-reaches-key-milestone-with-microgeo-communication-satellite-aims-for-service-to-begin-next-summer/">Astranis reaches key milestone with MicroGEO communication satellite, aims for service to begin next summer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Astranis reaches key milestone with MicroGEO communication satellite, aims for service to begin next summer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/astranis-reaches-key-milestone-with-microgeo-communication-satellite-aims-for-service-to-begin-next-summer/embed/#?secret=4yz8fFod38" data-secret="4yz8fFod38" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Gedmark has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/17/astranis-reaches-key-milestone-with-microgeo-communication-satellite-aims-for-service-to-begin-next-summer/">told me previously</a> that the company&#8217;s offering is very different from the LEO constellations being put up and operated by companies including SpaceX, because they&#8217;re essentially a much more targeted, nimble solution that works with existing ground infrastructure. Customers who have a specific regional need for connectivity can get Astranis to put one one up at a greatly reduced cost compared to a traditional GEO communications satellite, and do so to replace or upgrade aging existing satellite network infrastructure, for example.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that BlackRock, which led this round, has also been a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/rocket-startup-astra-is-going-public-vis-spac/">key participant in the PIPE components of high-profile space startup SPACs like launcher company Astra&#8217;s</a>. Not saying that&#8217;s the exit plan this round is setting up, but definitely something to think about.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TDI5qhiQNx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/9-top-space-tech-vcs-on-the-markets-opportunities-and-challenges/">9 top space tech VCs on the market&#8217;s opportunities and challenges</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;9 top space tech VCs on the market&#8217;s opportunities and challenges&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/9-top-space-tech-vcs-on-the-markets-opportunities-and-challenges/embed/#?secret=TDI5qhiQNx" data-secret="TDI5qhiQNx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/astranis-raises-250m-at-a-1-4b-valuation-for-smaller-cheaper-geostationary-communications-satellites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138366</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creatively raises $5M to help creative professionals showcase and find work</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/creatively-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/creatively-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creatively]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Link Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Creatively — a startup that helps designers, photographers, illustrators and other creative professionals showcase their work and find their next job — is announcing that it has raised in $5 million. Founded by Stacey Bendet (founder and CEO of fashion company Alicia + Olivia) and Joe Indriolo (who also serves as Creatively&#8217;s chief product officer), [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://creatively.life">Creatively</a> — a startup that helps designers, photographers, illustrators and other creative professionals showcase their work and find their next job — is announcing that it has raised in $5 million.</p>
<p>Founded by Stacey Bendet (founder and CEO of fashion company Alicia + Olivia) and Joe Indriolo (who also serves as Creatively&#8217;s chief product officer), the startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/creatively-launch/">launched last May</a>.</p>
<p>At the time, CEO Greg Gittrich emphasized the customizability of its creative portfolios, allowing each user to showcase their work in different ways. Potential employers, meanwhile, post creative jobs, and after a job has been completed on the platform, it can become the next piece in the artist&#8217;s portfolio.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup says there are now more than 125,000 creatives on the platform, while 650 companies (including HBO, Tom Ford, SKIMS, Nickelodeon, Ro, CNN and The Gap) have used it to recruit.</p>
<p>Gittrich told me via email that he&#8217;s been surprised by &#8220;the breadth of talent and variety of disciplines&#8221; on the platform, which includes &#8220;photographers like <a href="https://creatively.life/emmanuelsmonsalve" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/emmanuelsmonsalve&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGYdMf7LSQJ-okBznGKixQDUobAsA">Emmanuel Sanchez Monsalve</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/derrickoboateng" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/derrickoboateng&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFjekL87LIpWrsjQd1p6q3o1rAbGA">Derrick Ofosu Boateng</a>, creative directors like <a href="https://creatively.life/Kameron_DePaul" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/Kameron_DePaul&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGKfonp4SevhSUjMfR4-Mauk2BkcA">Kameron Mack</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/ericfranklin" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/ericfranklin&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEm9GMb7Gw9Ww7CpW3G5LlJfriJmg">Eric Alexander Franklin</a>, illustrators and animators like <a href="https://creatively.life/tarajacoby" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/tarajacoby&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGoVg7csd0h8S6VbHyPmrbCNlkp3w">Tara Jacoby</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/mulanfu" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/mulanfu&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE8U01pYXu3dEJnwux3Ru2kA7bkzg">Mulan Fu</a>, visual artists like <a href="https://creatively.life/kingkesia" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/kingkesia&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG2y8DRUaRyN1N5YOOlzeMz9PCdZA">King Kesia</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/bbroadie04" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/bbroadie04&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEj6G0uDJ977R2HUtAXA2N26oW4bQ">Bryane Broadie</a>, and designers like <a href="https://creatively.life/kidsuper" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/kidsuper&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHba200tWE27jRmKj1Yi0axFB4Vow">KidSuper</a> and <a href="https://creatively.life/azizaabdullahnicole" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://creatively.life/azizaabdullahnicole&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1618492164346000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEmrij7kdFHFG5BBqmzyGTKafqxbQ">Aziza-Abdullah Nicole</a>.&#8221; He also pointed to the popularity of the free <a href="https://creatively.life/classes">Creatively Classes</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hxMp9cuwqq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/creatively-launch/">Creatively helps designers and other creative talent showcase their work</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Creatively helps designers and other creative talent showcase their work&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/05/creatively-launch/embed/#?secret=hxMp9cuwqq" data-secret="hxMp9cuwqq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We originally envisioned Classes as a one-time virtual event for October,&#8221; Gittrich said. &#8220;But the number of sign-ups and the engagement for the first slate of instructors was so overwhelming that we made Classes into a monthly series. All the classes are taught by experienced creatives in our community and they’re designed to give our community the skills, mentorship and inspiration they need to succeed.”</p>
<p>The seed round was led by Link Ventures. (Previous investors include Michael Eisner’s Tornante Company and Shari Redstone’s Advancit Capital.) This investment also connects Creatively to the firm&#8217;s incubator Cogo Labs, which will help the startup grow revenue and lower customer acquisition costs.</p>
<p>In a statement, Link Ventures Managing Director Lisa Dolan described Creatively as &#8220;LinkedIn for the creative world.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Today’s job market needs Creatively,&#8221; she continued. &#8220;Businesses are looking to recruit creatives directly, but lack the network and resources to find qualified, diverse talent. Creatively changes that. Their growth in less than a year is very impressive, and we’re excited to be a part of the team.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IvxMHu7kqI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/05/design-may-be-the-next-entrepreneurial-gold-rush/">Design may be the next entrepreneurial gold rush</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Design may be the next entrepreneurial gold rush&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/05/design-may-be-the-next-entrepreneurial-gold-rush/embed/#?secret=IvxMHu7kqI" data-secret="IvxMHu7kqI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/creatively-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138340</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PlexTrac raises $10M Series A round for its collaboration-centric security platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plextrac-raises-10m-series-a-round-for-its-collaboration-centric-security-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plextrac-raises-10m-series-a-round-for-its-collaboration-centric-security-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrona venture group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayo Clinic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noro-Moseley Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qualys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ServiceNow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PlexTrac, a Boise, ID-based security service that aims to provide a unified workflow automation platform for red and blue teams, today announced that it has raised a $10 million Series A funding round led by Noro-Moseley Partners and Madrona Venture Group. StageDot0 ventures also participated in this round, which the company plans to use to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://plextrac.com/">PlexTrac</a>, a Boise, ID-based security service that aims to provide a unified workflow automation platform for red and blue teams, today announced that it has raised a $10 million Series A funding round led by <a href="https://noromoseley.com/">Noro-Moseley Partners</a> and <a href="https://www.madrona.com/">Madrona Venture Group</a>. <a href="https://www.stagedoto.com/">StageDot0</a> ventures also participated in this round, which the company plans to use to build out its team and grow its platform.</p>
<p>With this new round, the company, which was founded in 2018, has now raised a total of $11 million, with StageDot0 leading its 2019 seed round.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138058" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138058" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2138058" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?w=300" alt="PlexTrac CEO and President Dan DeCloss" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg 400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Dan.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138058" class="wp-caption-text">PlexTrac CEO and President Dan DeCloss</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I have been on both sides of the fence, the specialist who comes in and does the assessment, produces that 300-page report and then comes back a year later to find that some of the critical issues had not been addressed at all.  And not because the organization didn’t want to but because it was lost in that report,&#8221; PlexTrac CEO and President Dan DeCloss said. &#8220;These are some of the most critical findings for an entity from a risk perspective. By making it collaborative, both red and blue teams are united on the same goal we all share, to protect the network and assets.&#8221;</p>
<p>With an extensive <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ddecloss/">career</a> in security that included time as a penetration tester for Veracode and the Mayo Clinic, as well as senior information security advisor for Anthem, among other roles, DeCloss has quite a bit of first-hand experience that led him to found PlexTrac. Specifically, he believes that it&#8217;s important to break down the wall between offense-focused red teams and defense-centric blue teams.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138045" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138045" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2138045" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png" alt="" width="1024" height="658" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png 2560w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=768,494 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=680,437 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=1536,988 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=2048,1317 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Analytics.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2138045" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PlexTrac</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;Historically there has been more of the cloak and dagger relationship but those walls are breaking down&#8211; and rightfully so, there isn’t that much of that mentality today&#8211; people recognize they are on the same mission whether they are internal security team or an external team,&#8221; he said. &#8220;With the PlexTrac platform the red and blue teams have a better view into the other teams’ tactics and techniques &#8211; and it makes the whole process into an educational exercise for everyone.&#8221;</p>
<p>At its core, PlexTrac makes it easier for security teams to produce their reports &#8212; and hence free them up to actually focus on &#8216;real&#8217; security work. To do so, the service integrates with most of the popular scanners like Qualys, and Veracode, but also tools like ServiceNow and Jira in order to help teams coordinate their workflows. All the data flows into real-time reports that then help teams monitor their security posture. The service also features a dedicated tool, WriteupsDB, for managing reusable write-ups to help teams deliver consistent reports for a variety of audiences.</p>
<p>&#8220;Current tools for planning, executing, and reporting on security testing workflows are either nonexistent (manual reporting, spreadsheets, documents, etc…) or exist as largely incomplete features of legacy platforms,&#8221; Madrona&#8217;s S. Somasegar and Chris Picardo write in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;The pain point for security teams is real and PlexTrac is able to streamline their workflows, save time, and greatly improve output quality. These teams are on the leading edge of attempting to find and exploit vulnerabilities (red teams) and defend and/or eliminate threats (blue teams).&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/plextrac-raises-10m-series-a-round-for-its-collaboration-centric-security-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138039</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram&#8217;s new test lets you choose if you want to hide &#8216;Likes,&#8217; Facebook test to follow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influencers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[like button]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[likes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram today will begin a new test around hiding Like counts on users&#8217; posts, following its experiments in this area which first began in 2019. This time, however, Instagram is not enabling or disabling the feature for more users. Instead, it will begin to explore a new option where users get to decide what works [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram today will begin a new test around hiding Like counts on users&#8217; posts, following its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/14/instagram-private-like-counts/">experiments</a> in this area which first began in 2019. This time, however, Instagram is not enabling or disabling the feature for more users. Instead, it will begin to explore a new option where users get to decide what works best for them &#8212; either choosing to see the Like counts on others&#8217; posts, or not. Users will also be able to turn off Like counts on their own posts, if they choose. Facebook additionally confirmed it will begin to test a similar experience on its own social network.</p>
<p>Instagram says tests involving Like counts were deprioritized after Covid-19 hit, as the company focused on other efforts needed to support its community. (Except for that <a href="https://www.engadget.com/instagram-likes-hidden-024925910.html">brief period this March</a> where Instagram accidentally hid Likes for more users due to a bug.)</p>
<p>The company says it&#8217;s now revisiting the feedback it collected from users during the tests and found a wide range of opinions. Originally, the idea with hiding Like counts was about reducing the anxiety and embarrassment that surrounds posting content on the social network. That is, people would stress over whether their post would receive enough Likes to be deemed &#8220;popular.&#8221; This problem was particularly difficult for Instagram&#8217;s younger users, who care much more about what their peers think &#8212; so much so that they would <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/teens-curate-their-instagram-accounts-2016-5">take down posts that didn&#8217;t receive &#8220;enough&#8221; Likes</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition, the removal of Likes helped reduce the sort of herd mentality that drives people to like things that are already popular, as opposed to judging the content for themselves.</p>
<p>But during tests, not everyone agreed the removal of Likes was a change for the better. Some people said they still wanted to see Like counts so they could track what was trending and popular. The argument for keeping Likes was more prevalent among the <a href="https://www.refinery29.com/en-gb/2019/05/232006/instagram-hidden-like-count-influencers-creators">influencer community</a>, where creators <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/08/instagram-hide-likes-us/">used the metric</a> in order to communicate their value to partners, like brands and advertisers. Here, lower engagement rates on posts could directly translate to lower earnings for these creators.</p>
<p>Both arguments for and against Likes have merit, which is why Instagram&#8217;s latest test will put the choice back into users&#8217; own hands.</p>
<p>This new test will be enabled for a small percentage of users globally on Instagram, the company says.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been opted in, you&#8217;ll find a new option to hide the Likes from within the app&#8217;s Settings. This will prevent you from seeing Likes on other people&#8217;s posts as you scroll through your Instagram Feed. As a creator, you&#8217;ll be able to hide Likes on a per-post basis via the three-dot &#8220;&#8230;&#8221; menu at the top. Even if Likes are disabled publicly, creators are still able to view Like counts and other engagements through analytics, just as they did before.</p>
<p>The tests on Facebook, which has also been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/02/facebook-hidden-likes/">testing Like count removals</a> for some time, have not yet begun. Facebook tells TechCrunch those will roll out in the weeks ahead.</p>
<p>Making Like counts an choice may initially seem like it could help to address everyone&#8217;s needs. But in reality, if the wider influencer community chooses to continue to use Likes as a currency that translates to popularity and job opportunities, then other users will continue to do the same.</p>
<p>Ultimately, communities themselves have to decide what sort of tone they want to set, preferably from the outset &#8212; before you&#8217;ve attracted millions of users who will be angry when you later try to change course.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a question as to whether social media users are really hungry for an &#8220;Like-free&#8221; safer space. For years we&#8217;ve seen startups focused on building an &#8220;anti-Instagram&#8221; of sorts, where they drop one or more Instagram features, like algorithmic feeds, Likes and other engagement mechanisms, such as <a href="https://www.minutiae-app.org/">Minutiae</a>, <a href="https://vero.co/">Vero</a>, <a href="https://www.dayflashapp.com/">Dayflash</a>, <a href="http://hipstamatic.com/oggl/">Oggl</a>, and now, newcomers like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/spark-capital-decides-to-sever-all-ties-with-david-dobriks-dispo-app-weeks-after-leading-investment/">troubled Dispo</a>, or under-the-radar <a href="https://www.instagram.com/herd.app/?hl=en">Herd</a>. But Instagram has yet to fail because of an anti-Instagram rival. If anything is a threat, it&#8217;s a new type of social network entirely, like TikTok &#8211;where it should be noted getting Likes and engagements is still very important for creator success.</p>
<p>Instagram didn&#8217;t say how long the new tests would last or if and when the features would roll out more broadly.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re testing this on Instagram to start, but we&#8217;re also exploring a similar experience for Facebook. We will learn from this new small test and have more to share soon,&#8221; a Facebook company spokesperson said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/instagrams-new-test-lets-you-choose-if-you-want-to-hide-likes-facebook-test-to-follow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138307</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Large-scale CO2 removal startup Carbo Culture raises $6.2M Seed led by True Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/large-scale-co2-removal-startup-carbo-culture-raises-6-2m-seed-led-by-true-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/large-scale-co2-removal-startup-carbo-culture-raises-6-2m-seed-led-by-true-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carbo Culture — a startup that has scaled an industrial process to create large-scale CO2 removal using woody waste from agriculture and forests — has raised $6.2 million in seed a financing round led by Silicon Valley VC True Ventures. The round was co-led by European early-stage venture firm Cherry Ventures. Swiss climate investor Übermorgen Ventures [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://carboculture.com">Carbo Culture</a> — a startup that has scaled an industrial process to create large-scale CO2 removal using woody waste from agriculture and forests — has raised $6.2 million in seed a financing round led by Silicon Valley VC True Ventures. The round was co-led by European early-stage venture firm Cherry Ventures. Swiss climate investor Übermorgen Ventures also participated. The new funding will be used to grow the team, product development, and build one of Europe&#8217;s largest carbon removal facilities. </p>
<p>Energy from the sun creates photosynthesis in plants and turning CO2 into plant matter that eventually decomposes and re-enters the atmosphere. Carbo Culture mimics this existing process, it just makes it much, much faster.</p>
<p>Carbo Culture describes its process as an “ultra-rapid conversion” where woody residues are turned into functional biocarbons at an extremely high temperature. The process then “locks” the carbon into a sort of charcoal that won’t degrade for 1,000 years.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg" alt="" width="819" height="546" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2138365" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg 819w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carbo-culture2547.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 819px) 100vw, 819px" /></p>
<p>As well as removing CO2 from the wood, the whole process of generating this biocarbon from the wood waste generates renewable heat which can literally be used to heat homes or drive turbines to make electricity. The left-over biocarbon product can be used in biomaterials or environmental engineering, and could replace other polluting materials or be used in gasifiers, reducing greenhouse-gas emissions or perhaps in agriculture to improve soil health.</p>
<p>Thus, the startup sells two things as its main products: carbon removal credits and the biocarbon itself.</p>
<p>CEO and co-founder Henrietta Moon said in a statement: “We have this race against time to sequester billions of tons of carbon, and we’re not fully even utilizing one of the largest drawdown mechanisms in the world, the natural carbon cycle. At Carbo Culture, we’re tapping into it with a breakthrough technology that uses the already drawn down carbon in biomass and converts it for storing away for millennia.”</p>
<p>Toni Schneider, partner at True Ventures said: &#8220;We believe venture capital should play a greater role in creating a sustainable planet, and Carbo Culture has so many of the right ingredients for solving one of earth’s most pressing problems. Demand for carbon capture is rising, and meeting this demand will require some reimagining. Henrietta and her team have the experience, technology, passion, and palpable vision to turn this big idea into a truly impactful one.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="478" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2138367" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg 1093w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=150,70 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=300,140 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=768,358 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=680,317 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Carboncycle.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Sophia Bendz, partner at Cherry Ventures said: &#8220;Carbo Culture has created one of the most effective negative emissions technologies through their patented technology and I can&#8217;t wait for them to scale up and remove significant amounts of carbon from the atmosphere. Henrietta, Chris, and their entire team have the inventiveness, technological know-how, and grit required to both scale and, most importantly, succeed in tackling the larger climate issues affecting us all. We are beyond excited to partner with this brilliant team and support them on their mission to remove CO2.”</p>
<p>Carbo Culture&#8217;s competitors include Climeworks (raised $145m) Carbon Engineering, CarbFix, Charm Industrial and CarboFex.</p>
<p>CTO and co-founder Christopher Carstens said: “We’ve managed to scale up production capacity 8x in volume, develop the system further, and begin testing with private labs, customers and universities. We’re now running our shipping container scale pilot plant in California’s Central Valley, where we can process over 200lbs of biomass per hour.&#8221;</p>
<p>The co-founders met at Singularity University’s 3-month program in 2013 at the Nasa Ames Research Center.</p>
<p>The underlying technology has been licensed from the Univerity of Hawaii, but, say the founders, it has been independently verified by <a href="http://Puro.earth">Puro.earth</a>, a carbon-negative marketplace</p>
<p>The startup recently announced its first large-scale (pre) purchase of <a href="https://www.southpole.com/news/could-humble-biochar-be-the-next-big-carbon-removal-solution-to-fight-climate-change">carbon removal credits by South Pole</a>.</p>
<p>Moon added: “Our cost to remove carbon is currently at above $600 per CO2 ton, and we’re aiming to drive the cost to $400 by the end of next year, and looking to achieve $200 by 2024. We&#8217;re building a scaled-up facility in the next 18 months, and it will become one of Europe’s largest carbon removal facilities.”</p>
<p>Carbo Culture’s additional investors include Albert Wenger, Gold&amp;Green Foods Founder Maija Itkonen, VP at Geltor Alex Patist,  alongside existing investors such as David Helgason, Moaffak Ahmed, Lifeline Ventures, and Paul and Dan Bragiel.</p>
<p>The vast majority of scientists believe the planet must curb CO2 emissions and remove carbon from the atmosphere at the same time, reaching net-zero emissions by 2050m for global warming to stay below 2C and void catastrophic climate effects.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/large-scale-co2-removal-startup-carbo-culture-raises-6-2m-seed-led-by-true-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138354</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ireland opens GDPR investigation into Facebook leak</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2136465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s lead data supervisor in the European Union has opened an investigation into whether the tech giant violated data protection rules vis-a-vis the leak of data reported earlier this month. Here&#8217;s the Irish Data Protection Commission&#8217;s statement: “The Data Protection Commission (DPC) today launched an own-volition inquiry pursuant to section 110 of the Data Protection [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s lead data supervisor in the European Union has opened an investigation into whether the tech giant violated data protection rules vis-a-vis the leak of data reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/">earlier this month</a>.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the Irish Data Protection Commission&#8217;s statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>“The Data Protection Commission (DPC) today launched an own-volition inquiry pursuant to section 110 of the Data Protection Act 2018 in relation to multiple international media reports, which highlighted that a collated dataset of Facebook user personal data had been made available on the internet. This dataset was reported to contain personal data relating to approximately 533 million Facebook users worldwide. The DPC engaged with Facebook Ireland in relation to this reported issue, raising queries in relation to GDPR compliance to which Facebook Ireland furnished a number of responses.</p>
<p>The DPC, having considered the information provided by Facebook Ireland regarding this matter to date, is of the opinion that one or more provisions of the GDPR and/or the Data Protection Act 2018 may have been, and/or are being, infringed in relation to Facebook Users’ personal data.</p>
<p>Accordingly, the Commission considers it appropriate to determine whether Facebook Ireland has complied with its obligations, as data controller, in connection with the processing of personal data of its users by means of the Facebook Search, Facebook Messenger Contact Importer and Instagram Contact Importer features of its service, or whether any provision(s) of the GDPR and/or the Data Protection Act 2018 have been, and/or are being, infringed by Facebook in this respect.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Facebook has been contacted for comment.<strong> Update</strong>: The company did not provide a statement but confirmed it&#8217;s in contact with regulators to answer their questions. <strong>Update 2: </strong>Facebook has now sent this statement: “We are cooperating fully with the IDPC in its enquiry, which relates to features that make it easier for people to find and connect with friends on our services. These features are common to many apps and we look forward to explaining them and the protections we have put in place.”</p>
<p>The move comes after the European Commission intervened to apply pressure on Ireland&#8217;s data protection commissioner. Justice commissioner, Didier Reynders, <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1381663631981617163">tweeted</a> Monday that he had spoken with Helen Dixon about the Facebook data leak.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Commission continues to follow this case closely and is committed to supporting national authorities,&#8221; he added, going on to urge Facebook to &#8220;cooperate actively and swiftly to shed light on the identified issues&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today I spoke with Helen Dixon <a href="https://twitter.com/DPCIreland?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DPCIreland</a> about the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FacebookLeak?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FacebookLeak</a>. The Commission continues to follow this case closely and is committed to supporting national authorities. We also call on <a href="https://twitter.com/Facebook?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Facebook</a> to cooperate actively and swiftly to shed light on the identified issues.</p>
<p>&mdash; Didier Reynders (@dreynders) <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1381663631981617163?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 12, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A spokeswoman for the Commission confirmed the virtual meeting between Reynders and Dixon, saying: &#8220;Dixon informed the Commissioner about the issues at stake and the different tracks of work to clarify the situation.</p>
<p>&#8220;They both urge Facebook to cooperate swiftly and to share the necessary information. It is crucial to shed light on this leak that has affected millions of European citizens.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It is up to the Irish data protection authority to assess this case. The Commission remains available if support is needed. The situation will also have to be further analyzed for the future. Lessons should be learned,&#8221; she added.</p>
<p>The revelation that a vulnerability in Facebook&#8217;s platform enabled unidentified &#8216;malicious actors&#8217; to extract the personal data (including email addresses, mobile phone numbers and more) of more than 500 million Facebook accounts up until September 2019 &#8212; when Facebook claims it fixed the issue &#8212; only emerged in the wake of the data <a href="https://twitter.com/UnderTheBreach/status/1378314424239460352">being found</a> for free download on a hacker forum earlier this month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">All 533,000,000 Facebook records were just leaked for free.</p>
<p>This means that if you have a Facebook account, it is extremely likely the phone number used for the account was leaked.</p>
<p>I have yet to see Facebook acknowledging this absolute negligence of your data. <a href="https://t.co/ysGCPZm5U3">https://t.co/ysGCPZm5U3</a> <a href="https://t.co/nM0Fu4GDY8">pic.twitter.com/nM0Fu4GDY8</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alon Gal (Under the Breach) (@UnderTheBreach) <a href="https://twitter.com/UnderTheBreach/status/1378314424239460352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Despite the European Union&#8217;s data protection framework (the GDPR) baking in a regime of data breach notifications &#8212; with the risk of hefty fines for compliance failure &#8212; Facebook did not inform its lead EU data supervisory when it found and fixed the issue. Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC) was left to find out in the press, like everyone else.</p>
<p>Nor has Facebook individually informed the 533M+ users that their information was taken without their knowledge or consent, saying last week it has no plans to do so &#8212; despite the heightened risk for affected users of spam and phishing attacks.</p>
<p>Privacy experts have, meanwhile, been swift to point out that the company has still not faced any regulatory sanction under the GDPR &#8212; with a number of investigations ongoing into various Facebook businesses and practices and no decisions yet issued in those cases by Ireland&#8217;s DPC. (It has so far only issued one cross-border decision, fining<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/"> Twitter</a> around $550k in December over a breach it disclosed back in 2019.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VFNN7Oh6QO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebooks-tardy-disclosure-of-breach-timing-raises-gdpr-compliance-questions/">Facebook&#8217;s tardy disclosure of breach timing raises GDPR compliance questions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s tardy disclosure of breach timing raises GDPR compliance questions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebooks-tardy-disclosure-of-breach-timing-raises-gdpr-compliance-questions/embed/#?secret=VFNN7Oh6QO" data-secret="VFNN7Oh6QO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Last month the European Parliament adopted a <a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/TA-9-2021-0111_EN.html">resolution</a> on the implementation of the GDPR which expressed &#8220;great concern&#8221; over the functioning of the mechanism &#8212; raising particular concern over the Irish data protection authority by writing that it &#8220;generally closes most cases with a settlement instead of a sanction and that cases referred to Ireland in 2018 have not even reached the stage of a draft decision pursuant to Article 60(3) of the GDPR&#8221;.</p>
<p>The latest Facebook data scandal further amps up the pressure on the DPC &#8212; providing further succour to critics of the GDPR who argue the regulation is unworkable under the current foot-dragging enforcement structure, given the major bottlenecks in Ireland (and Luxembourg) where many tech giants choose to locate regional HQ.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">After the <a href="https://twitter.com/EP_Justice?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@EP_Justice</a> and other EU DPAs raised concerns, the Irish Parliament is now also planning to look into the work of <a href="https://twitter.com/DPCIreland?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DPCIreland</a> in a hearing on April 27th. </p>
<p>Glad to see pro-active steps to debate how <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDPR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDPR</a> can be effectively enforced in all EU member states! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f601.png" alt="😁" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f44d.png" alt="👍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/2mDaFOwEiR">https://t.co/2mDaFOwEiR</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Max Schrems <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f1ea-1f1fa.png" alt="🇪🇺" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@maxschrems) <a href="https://twitter.com/maxschrems/status/1380794291988148230?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 10, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>On Thursday Reynders made his concern over Ireland&#8217;s response to the Facebook data leak public, <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1380182173739847681">tweeting</a> to say the Commission had been in contact with the DPC.</p>
<p>He does have reason to be personally concerned. Earlier last week <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/eu-leaders-facebook-data-leak-cybersecurity-didier-reynders/">Politico</a> reported that Reynders&#8217; own digits had been among the cache of leaked data, along with those of the Luxembourg prime minister Xavier Bettel &#8212; and &#8220;dozens of EU officials&#8221;. However the problem of weak GDPR enforcement affects everyone across the bloc &#8212; some 446M people whose rights are not being uniformly and vigorously upheld.</p>
<p>&#8220;A strong enforcement of GDPR is of key importance,&#8221; Reynders also remarked on Twitter, urging Facebook to &#8220;fully cooperate with Irish authorities&#8221;.</p>
<p>Last week <a href="https://www.gpdp.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9572143">Italy&#8217;s data protection commission</a> also called on Facebook to immediately offer a service for Italian users to check whether they had been affected by the breach. But Facebook made no public acknowledgment or response to the call. Under the GDPR&#8217;s one-stop-shop mechanism the tech giant can limit its regulatory exposure by direct dealing only with its lead EU data supervisor in Ireland.</p>
<p>A two-year Commission review of how the data protection regime is functioning, which reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/24/gdprs-two-year-review-flags-lack-of-vigorous-enforcement/">last summer</a>, already drew attention to problems with patchy enforcement. A lack of progress on unblocking GDPR bottlenecks is thus a growing problem for the Commission &#8212; which is in the midst of proposing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">a package</a> of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/europe-sets-out-the-rules-of-the-road-for-its-data-reuse-plan/">additional</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">digital regulations</a>. That makes the enforcement point a very pressing one as EU lawmakers are being asked how <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/">new digital rules</a> will be upheld if existing ones keep being trampled on?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s certainly notable that the EU&#8217;s executive has proposed a different, centralized enforcement structure for<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/"> incoming pan-EU legislation</a> targeted at digital services and tech giants. Albeit, getting agreement from all the EU&#8217;s institutions and elected representatives on how to reshape platform oversight looks challenging.</p>
<p>And in the meanwhile the data leaks continue: <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qj8dj5/facebook-phone-number-data-breach-telegram-bot">Motherboard</a> reported Friday on another alarming leak of Facebook data it found being made accessible via a bot on the Telegram messaging platform that gives out the names and phone numbers of users who have liked a Facebook page (in exchange for a fee unless the page has had less than 100 likes).</p>
<p>The publication said this data appears to be separate to the 533M+ scraped dataset &#8212; after it ran checks against the larger dataset via the breach advice site, <a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com">haveibeenpwned</a>. It also asked Alon Gal, the person who discovered the aforementioned leaked Facebook dataset being offered for free download online, to compare data obtained via the bot and he did not find any matches.</p>
<p>We contacted Facebook about the source of this leaked data and will update this report with any response.</p>
<p>In his <a href="https://twitter.com/dreynders/status/1380182173739847681">tweet</a> about the 500M+ Facebook data leak last week, Reynders made reference to the Europe Data Protection Board (EDPB), a steering body comprised of representatives from Member State data protection agencies which works to ensure a consistent application of the GDPR.</p>
<p>However the body does not lead on GDPR enforcement &#8212; so it&#8217;s not clear why he would invoke it. Optics is one possibility, if he was trying to encourage a perception that the EU has vigorous and uniform enforcement structures where people&#8217;s data is concerned.</p>
<p>&#8220;Under the GDPR, enforcement and the investigation of potential violations lies with the national supervisory authorities. The EDPB does not have investigative powers per se and is not involved in investigations at the national level. As such, the EDPB cannot comment on the processing activities of specific companies,&#8221; an EDPB spokeswoman told us when we enquired about Reynders&#8217; remarks.</p>
<p>But she also noted the Commission attends plenary meetings of the EDPB &#8212; adding it&#8217;s possible there will be an exchange of views among members about the Facebook leak case in the future, as attending supervisory authorities &#8220;regularly exchange information on cases at the national level&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EWVMCgFXv4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/">Answers being sought from Facebook over latest data breach</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Answers being sought from Facebook over latest data breach&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/embed/#?secret=EWVMCgFXv4" data-secret="EWVMCgFXv4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MPBRuNV5Yo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/">Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Europe sets out plan to boost data reuse and regulate &#8216;high risk&#8217; AIs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/19/europe-sets-out-plan-to-boost-data-reuse-and-regulate-high-risk-ais/embed/#?secret=MPBRuNV5Yo" data-secret="MPBRuNV5Yo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2136465</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday raises $24 million seed round to build a fast restaurant checkout flow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 14:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[checkout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Meet Sunday, a new startup that is going to attract some headlines as it has raised a $24 million seed round at a $140 million post-money valuation. That’s a lot of money for a company that started just a few months ago but that’s because Sunday wants to move quickly. Sunday is getting noticed because [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Meet <a href="http://sundayapp.com">Sunday</a>, a new startup that is going to attract some headlines as it has raised a $24 million seed round at a $140 million post-money valuation. That’s a lot of money for a company that started just a few months ago but that’s because Sunday wants to move quickly.</p>
<p>Sunday is getting noticed because it is founded by Victor Lugger, Tigrane Seydoux and Christine de Wendel —&nbsp;Lugger and Tigrane have been working together for several years as they’re the founders of <a href="https://www.bigmammagroup.com">Big Mamma</a>. Christine de Wendel headed <a href="https://www.zalando.fr">Zalando</a> in France before joining <a href="https://www.manomano.fr">ManoMano</a> as COO.</p>
<p>If you’re not familiar with Big Mamma, they’ve launched a dozen Italian restaurants in France. They also manage La Felicità, the food court at <a href="https://stationf.co">Station F</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Some people love those restaurants because the food is good and it’s relatively affordable. Some people hate it because Big Mamma is also particularly well known for its long queues and the fact that you always feel like you have to eat quickly for the next group. But it’s clear that it’s been working well for the past few years.</p>
<p>Managing Big Mamma during a pandemic led to Sunday, a spin-off company incorporated in the U.S. The restaurant company wanted to offer a way to check the menu and pay without touching anything. Like many restaurants, they put QR codes on the tables to that customers can scan them with their phones and load a website.</p>
<p>But Sunday didn’t stop at the menu as it also connects directly to the cash register system. Sunday supports Oracle Micros, Brinks, Tiller, Zelty, Revo, CashPad, etc. This way, clients can also scan the QR code, check their tab and pay directly from their phone. When they’re done eating, they can pay by themselves, stand up and leave.</p>
<p>After trying Sunday in Big Mamma restaurants, the company saw some encouraging results. 80% of customers chose to pay using the QR code, which means that restaurants saved 15 minutes in wait time on average leading to a better table turnover rate.</p>
<p>And this is key to understanding Sunday. It’s easy to sell a new payment system to a restaurant if it leads to more revenue. Popular restaurants that feel like they’re always looking for empty tables could greatly benefit from Sunday.</p>
<p>It also opens up some new possibilities. For instance, guests can split the bill directly at the table —&nbsp;everyone loads up Sunday and pay. Sunday is based on QR codes right now, but the company isn’t attached to QR codes specifically. You could imagine loading your bill using RFID chips, a tablet, etc.</p>
<p>The vision is clear —&nbsp;Sunday wants to build the <a href="https://www.fast.co">Fast Checkout</a> of restaurants. The startup thinks online checkout is going to merge with offline, brick-and-mortar checkout.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lPOmIpmY1E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/fast-raises-102m-as-the-online-checkout-wars-continue-to-attract-huge-investment/">Fast raises $102M as the online checkout wars continue to attract huge investment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fast raises $102M as the online checkout wars continue to attract huge investment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/fast-raises-102m-as-the-online-checkout-wars-continue-to-attract-huge-investment/embed/#?secret=lPOmIpmY1E" data-secret="lPOmIpmY1E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Sunday customers don’t pay any monthly subscription fee or setup fee. You only pay processing fees based on usage. And those fees tend to be lower than the card machine you’re currently using.</p>
<p>The startup’s seed round was led by Coatue with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/new-wave/">New Wave</a> participating. New Wave is a new European seed fund led by Pia d’Iribarne and backed by Xavier Niel. Multiple hospitality and tech investors are also participating.</p>
<p>The idea is to raise a lot of money, sign up a lot of restaurants and take over the market right now while there’s an opportunity during the pandemic. They have hired 40 people already and they’re signing deals with restaurants even though most of them are still closed in Europe.</p>
<p>Sunday isn’t a tech achievement <em>per se</em> — it’s an execution play. The company that can roll out this kind of checkout experience faster than the others is going to take over the market.</p>
<p>When restaurants are going to be open again, you may notice Sunday QR codes in France at Eataly, PNY, Paris Society, Eric Frechon, Groupe Bertrand’s restaurants (Burger King France, Hippopotamus, Groupe Flo…). Similarly, in the U.K., Sunday is partnering with JKS Group (Hoppers, Brigadiers, Gymkhana…), Corbin &amp; King and others. Sunday is also talking with companies in the U.S. and Spain.</p>
<p>Overall, there are more than a thousand restaurants currently adopting Sunday.</p>
<p>“We follow the same model as the one we used when launching restaurants with Big Mamma. Seven years ago, we invested three times more than the others to compress fixed costs and deliver a better product,” Sunday co-founder and CEO Victor Lugger told me.</p>
<p>The startup already has an ambitious product roadmap. Eventually, you could imagine having your own Sunday account that remembers your past bills, tracks your allergies, saves your favorite payment method, etc. Once again, it’ll come down to execution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/sunday-raises-24-million-seed-round-to-build-a-fast-restaurant-checkout-flow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138329</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
