<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:42:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Chaldal, Bangladesh&#8217;s largest grocery delivery platform, raises $10M Series C</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/chaldal-bangladeshs-largest-grocery-delivery-platform-raises-10m-series-c/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/chaldal-bangladeshs-largest-grocery-delivery-platform-raises-10m-series-c/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangladesh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chaldal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groceries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grocery delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on-demand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Founded in 2013, Bangladesh’s Chaldal was one of the first grocery delivery startups in the world to use the “dark&#8221; store model, picking up orders from its own warehouses instead of retail stores. Now the company says it is the country’s second-largest grocery player and the largest grocery e-commerce platform, with 27 warehouses located in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Founded in 2013, Bangladesh’s <a href="https://chaldal.com/">Chaldal</a> was one of the first grocery delivery startups in the world to use the “dark&#8221; store model, picking up orders from its own warehouses instead of retail stores. Now the company says it is the country’s second-largest grocery player and the largest grocery e-commerce platform, with 27 warehouses located in four cities. Chaldal plans to expand into 15 new cities with a recently-closed $10 million Series C. The round was led by Taavet Hinrikus, co-founder of Wise; Topia chief product officer Sten Tamkivi; and Xploration Capital, with participation from Mir Group.</p>
<p>When Chaldal launched in Dhaka eight years ago, it first picked up orders from local grocery stores. But most retailers in the city are very small and Chaldal was unable to guarantee items would be available for its customers. As a result, it decided to start building its own network of warehouses.</p>
<p>“When we started, Instacart was still the dominant model, but we took a different stand and said we want to deliver from our own warehouses because that leads to better inventory management,” co-founder and chief executive officer Waseem Alim told TechCrunch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OA0Pq4YTM1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/30/chaldal/">Chaldal Wants To Become The Amazon Fresh Of Bangladesh&#8217;s Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chaldal Wants To Become The Amazon Fresh Of Bangladesh&#8217;s Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/30/chaldal/embed/#?secret=OA0Pq4YTM1" data-secret="OA0Pq4YTM1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Now the company, a Y Combinator alum, has 27 warehouses located in four cities (Dhaka, Naryanganj, Chattogram and Jashore). It will expand to 15 new cities and plans to open 50 warehouses by the end of this year. In addition to its flagship grocery deliveries, Chaldal will expand GoGo Bangla, its on-demand logistics service for small e-commerce businesses, and the Chaldal Vegetable Network, which connects farmers directly to retailers. It also has plans to launch a direct-to-consumer pharmacy.</p>
<p>Chaldal claims that has generated $40 million in revenue and performed 2.5 million orders over the past 12 months, growing about 120% year-over-year. It currently sells about 8,500 kinds of products and wants to expand that to 30,000 SKUs by December.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202926" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202926" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2202926" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg" alt="One of Chaldal's &quot;dark&quot; stores, or warehouses" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg 2005w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Rampura_Inside1-v2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202926" class="wp-caption-text">One of Chaldal&#8217;s &#8220;dark&#8221; stores, or warehouses</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Alim says Chaldal’s core grocery operations have been profitable for a while now, and it only invests cash in building its technology or launching new verticals. One of the reasons it is able to make money is because Chaldal began batching deliveries early on, sending out riders from its full-time fleet with several orders at a time (it recently launched a part-time driver program). Batching also means Chaldal is able to offer deliveries in as little as 15 to 30 minutes.</p>
<p>Chaldal also worked closely with suppliers and manufacturers. “We are one of the most efficient online grocery retailers in the world in terms of amount of capital that has been invested in us versus our size, and that’s mainly because we have been really working with our supply chain and all those details,” Alim said.</p>
<p>For example, it sources produce directly from farms, and partners with large manufacturers like Unilever. “Walmart and stores like that don’t exist here, it’s mostly small retailers, so we’ve been able to have a huge impact on the supply chain side of things,” said Alim. “We are continuing to expand our micro-warehouse model and have started supporting, as part of the delivery mechanism we have built, a lot of small merchants,” including many sellers who signed up for GoGo Bangla during the pandemic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CFDtLz5bAS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/dija-launch/">Backed by Blossom, Creandum and Index, grocery delivery and dark store startup Dija launches in London</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Backed by Blossom, Creandum and Index, grocery delivery and dark store startup Dija launches in London&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/dija-launch/embed/#?secret=CFDtLz5bAS" data-secret="CFDtLz5bAS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/chaldal-bangladeshs-largest-grocery-delivery-platform-raises-10m-series-c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202921</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Groww in talks to raise funds at a $3 billion valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/indias-groww-in-talks-to-raise-funds-at-a-3-billion-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/indias-groww-in-talks-to-raise-funds-at-a-3-billion-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 05:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groww]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Groww, an Indian startup that is helping millennials invest in mutual funds and stocks, is in advanced stages of talks to raise a new financing round at a $3 billion valuation, according to six people familiar with the matter. The Bangalore-based startup is negotiating to close a $250 million round, the people said, requesting anonymity [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Groww, an Indian startup that is helping millennials invest in mutual funds and stocks, is in advanced stages of talks to raise a new financing round at a $3 billion valuation, according to six people familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>The Bangalore-based startup is negotiating to close a $250 million round, the people said, requesting anonymity as the matter is private. The round could close within weeks, they said.</p>
<p>Usual caveats apply: The terms of the deal may change. The startup has received several termsheets &#8212; with similar terms &#8212; in recent days. Tiger Global, Coatue, and TCV have held conversations to lead or co-lead the round, people said. And many including Insight Partners have also explored investment, the people said.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Coatue declined to comment. Groww chief executive did not respond to a request for comment. Indian news outlet CapTable <a href="https://the-captable.com/2021/09/startup-funding-record-velocity-100-million-bubble-india/">first reported</a> about Groww’s upcoming financing round.</p>
<p>Groww is tapping into a huge market. More than 200 million people in India transact money digitally, but fewer than 30 million invest in mutual funds and stocks. The startup allows users to invest in mutual funds, including systematic investment planning (SIP) and equity-linked savings, gold, as well as stocks, including those listed at U.S. exchanges. The app offers every fund that is currently available in India.</p>
<p>Investors’ growing push to back &#8212; or double down on &#8212; Groww follows several months of strong growth. The Indian startup is currently on track to clock about $35 million in ARR, two people briefed on the figure said. Groww, which counts Tiger Global and Sequoia Capital India among its existing investors, was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/investment-app-for-millennials-groww-raises-83-million-at-over-1-billion-valuation/">valued at $1 billion in April</a> this year and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/groww-an-investment-app-for-millennials-in-india-raises-30m-led-by-yc-continuity/">$250 million last September</a>.</p>
<p>The startup is also internally exploring expansion into the crypto space, but hasn’t made a firm decision on when it plans to offer such trading, one person said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new investment talks &#8212; and the surge in proposed valuation &#8212; also illustrate the level of excitement Indian startups have produced in recent quarters. More than two dozen startups in India have become a unicorn this year, up from 11 last year.</p>
<p>And that list continues to expand. Indian esports firm Mobile Premier League said on Wednesday it has raised new funds at a valuation of $2.3 billion. And Apna &#8212; which helps low-skilled workers learn and find new opportunities &#8212; and crypto trading app CoinSwitch Kuber are also in talks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/indian-crypto-exchange-coinswitch-kuber-in-talks-to-raise-funds-at-unicorn-valuation/">raise new rounds at unicorn valuations</a>, TechCrunch has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/tiger-global-in-talks-to-make-apna-indias-fastest-unicorn/">previously reported</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/indias-groww-in-talks-to-raise-funds-at-a-3-billion-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202907</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Index leads $12.2M seed in Sourceful, a data play to make supply chains greener</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/index-leads-12-2m-seed-in-sourceful-a-data-play-to-make-supply-chains-greener/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/index-leads-12-2m-seed-in-sourceful-a-data-play-to-make-supply-chains-greener/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 05:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon footprint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon offset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danny rimer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eka Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sourceful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Supply chains can be a complex logistical challenge. But they pose an even greater environmental challenge. And it&#8217;s that latter problem &#8212; global supply-chain sustainability &#8212; where UK startup Sourceful is fully focused, although it argues its approach can boost efficiency as well as shrink environmental impact. So it&#8217;s a win-win, per the pitch. Early [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Supply chains can be a complex logistical challenge. But they pose an even greater environmental challenge. And it&#8217;s that latter problem &#8212; global supply-chain sustainability &#8212; where UK startup <a href="https://www.sourceful.io">Sourceful</a> is fully focused, although it argues its approach can boost efficiency as well as shrink environmental impact. So it&#8217;s a win-win, per the pitch.</p>
<p>Early investors look impressed: Sourceful is announcing a $12.2 million seed funding round today, led by Europe&#8217;s Index Ventures (partner, Danny Rimer, is joining the board). Eka Ventures, Venrex and Dylan Field (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/30/figma-raises-50-million-series-d-led-by-andreessen-horowitz/">Figma</a> founder), also participated in the chunky raise.</p>
<p>The June 2020-founded startup says it will use the new funding to scale its operations and build out its platform for sustainable sourcing, with a plan to hire more staff across technology, sustainability, marketing and ops.</p>
<p>Its team has already grown fivefold since the start of 2021 &#8212; and it&#8217;s now aiming to reach 60 employees by the end of the year.</p>
<p>And all this is ahead of a public launch that&#8217;s programmed for early next year.</p>
<p>Sourceful&#8217;s platform is in pre-launch beta for now, with around 20 customers across a number of categories &#8212; such as food &amp; beverages (Foundation Coffee House), fashion and accessories (Fenton), healthcare (Elder), and online marketplaces (Floom and Stitched) &#8212; kicking the tyres in the hopes of making better supply chain decisions.</p>
<p>Startup watchers will know that supply chain logistics and freight forwarding has been a hotbed of activity &#8212; with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/07/flexport/">entrepreneurs making waves for years now</a>, promising efficiency gains by digitizing legacy (and often still pretty manual) legacy processes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sustainability-focused supply chain startups are a bit more of a recent development (with some <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/26/fairphone-takes-7-7m-to-push-for-change-across-the-electronics-value-chain/">category-pioneering exceptions</a>) but could be set for major uplift as the world&#8217;s attention spins toward decarbonizing. (Just this month we&#8217;ve also covered <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/portcast-gets-3-2m-to-create-more-transparent-and-sustainable-supply-chains/">Portcast</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/danish-startups-responsibly-raises-2m-to-benchmark-supply-chains-on-climate-diversity/">Responsibly</a>, for example.)</p>
<p>Sourceful joins the fray with a dual-sided promise to tackle sustainability and efficiency by mapping client requirements to vetted suppliers on its marketplace &#8212; handling the buying and shipping logistics piece (including a little warehousing) &#8212; and taking a commission on the overall price as its cut of the action.</p>
<p>At first glance it&#8217;s a curious choice of name for a sustainability startup, given the fact that sourcing (a whole lot) less is what&#8217;s ultimately going to be needed for humanity to cut its global carbon emissions enough to avert climate disaster. But maybe the intended wordplay here is &#8216;full&#8217; &#8212; in the sense of &#8216;fully optimized&#8217;.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The UK startup is attacking the supply chain sustainability problem from the perspective of doing <em>something</em> right now, </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">arguing that making a dent in consumer-driven environmental impacts of sourcing stuff (packaging, merchansize, components etc) is a lot better than letting the same old polluting status quo roll on. </span></p>
<p>However, given all the unverifiable &#8216;eco&#8217; marketing claims being attached to products nowadays &#8212; or, indeed, other forms of flagrant &#8216;greenwashing&#8217; (like bogus carbon offsets) that are cynically trying to convince consumers it&#8217;s okay to keep consuming as much as ever &#8212; there are clearly pitfalls to avoid too.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re talking about packaging &#8212; which is one of the products that Sourceful is deeply focused on, with a forthcoming design capability offering that will help businesses to customize packaging designs, pick materials, size etc based on real-time data, all with the goal of encouraging &#8216;greener&#8217; choices &#8212; less really is more.</p>
<p>Ideally, zero packaging is what your business should be aiming for (where practical, ofc). Yet Sourceful&#8217;s service will, inevitably, support demand for packaging supply and manufacture. At least in the first blush. So there&#8217;s a bit of a conundrum.</p>
<p>&#8220;You can put a carbon footprint score on packaging in general. So you could say packaging overall is this amount so the best thing you could do is not use any packaging. But the reality is, for most brands right now, especially for ecommerce, if you&#8217;re trying to deliver your product to the customer there needs to be some packaging &#8212; and so if packaging is unavoidable in its current form or in another form then the best thing you can then do is optimize that packaging,&#8221; argues CEO and co-founder Wing Chan, when we make the point that zero packaging is the most sustainable option.</p>
<p>&#8220;Right now we think the best solution is to help you optimize your packaging &#8212; the next wave will be around circular forms of packaging. Packaging that you can return back to your courier, packaging that you can reuse in another form. But we wanted to start with what is the current pain point. And the pain point is: I&#8217;m buying packaging, it&#8217;s very expensive, it&#8217;s very time-consuming and if I try and get it to be &#8216;green&#8217; I either put a marketing spin on it or I don&#8217;t know how to actually make it more sustainable.</p>
<p>&#8220;But I definitely agree with you that long term we&#8217;ve got to think about how do I get the supply chain number as close to zero and then offset whatever&#8217;s remaining.&#8221;</p>
<p>For now, then, Sourceful is <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">using data &#8212; combined with its marketplace of vetted suppliers (~40 at this stage) in the UK and China &#8212; to help companies optimize sourcing logistics and shrink their supply chains&#8217; environmental impact. </span></p>
<p>It does this by putting a &#8220;carbon footprint score&#8221; on the product choices its brand clients are making.</p>
<p>This means that instead of only being able to claim &#8220;qualitative things&#8221; &#8212; such as that a product uses less plastic or a different type of plastic &#8212; Sourceful&#8217;s customers can display an actual benchmarked carbon footprint score (in the form of a number), based on its lifecycle assessment of the stuff involved in making up the finished product.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s a lifecycle view,&#8221; says Chan. &#8220;For example if you take packaging we look at the box, we look at what is the cardboard material, where does it come from, how far has it travelled, what type of material is it, how much material gets used, how is then transported &#8212; for example is it a manufacturer in Asia all the way to the UK &#8212; so we get an overall score. So rather than it just being comparing paper and plastic we actually help the brands to see an overall quantitive outcome.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve built the [software] engine that allows you to make choices and see the actual output &#8212; so, for example, if you make your box bigger what does that actually do to your carbon footprint score?&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Sourceful has an internal climate science team to do this work. It is also building on publicly available data sources, per Chan &#8212; such as <a href="https://www.ecoinvent.org">ecoinvent</a> (&#8220;the market standard based data&#8221;) &#8212; but he says the public data available isn&#8217;t up-to-date, saying it&#8217;s also therefore working with researchers to update these key sources with the last five years of data.</p>
<p>It wants the protocol it&#8217;s devised for scoring carbon footprint via this lifecycle assessment to become a universal standard. Hence it&#8217;s currently going through an ISO certification process &#8212; hoping to have that in place before the planned public launch of its platform in Q1 next year.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s two ISO standards for doing a lifecycle assessment and normally you&#8217;d get ISO approval for a specific product but we&#8217;re getting ISO approval for the whole methodology &#8212; essentially the platform that we&#8217;ve built,&#8221; explains Chan. &#8220;There&#8217;s an independent panel of people, from universities, from other consultancies, who will be reviewing this as part of that ISO review &#8212; that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important to us that we&#8217;re doing that.&#8221;</p>
<p>The vetting of the suppliers on its marketplace is something Sourceful is doing entirely by itself, though &#8212; without any outside help. So its customers still need to trust that it&#8217;s doing a proper job of monitoring all the third parties on its marketplace.</p>
<p>But, on this, Chan argues that&#8217;s since sustainability is core to its value proposition it is incentivized to do the vetting in a more thorough and comprehensive way than any other individual player would be.</p>
<p>&#8220;The key thing for us is we combine both the data capture you would do when you&#8217;re understanding a supplier &#8212; asking all the questions about how their supply chain works and all of the laws entered by the new country &#8212; but we&#8217;re coupling that with a human visit as well. So we have a team in the UK as well as a team in Asia who actually go and visit the manufacturers. So it&#8217;s an extra layer of comfort for the brands that we&#8217;ve actually spent the time to go and meet them,&#8221; he suggests.</p>
<p>&#8220;The second thing is, as part of our marketplace build, we&#8217;re understanding how their supply chain works &#8212; in order to build the lifecycle assessment we actually understand each stage of their manufacturing process. So we have a much deeper understanding of their way of operating than all of the other platforms would have. So, yes it&#8217;s more involved, but we think that gives better accountability and a more accurate outcome.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re taking [the vetting process] to another level,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;We didn&#8217;t find anyone that was going into the same level of depth as us &#8212; so that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve done it ourselves.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pressed a little more, Chan also tells TechCrunch: &#8220;Supply chain risks never disappear but the thing is how much investment are you making to learn more about it? And for us because we&#8217;re capturing this data on lifecycle assessment it&#8217;s part of that process of understanding the supplier. So rather than it being another cost that we pay to go visit the manufacturer, we see it as part of our data gathering &#8212; a key part of the platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;So rather than it being a cost to minimize, which is why a lot of companies end up in trouble because they don&#8217;t visit [their suppliers] enough, we&#8217;re invested in making sure that data is as accurate and up-to-date as possible. And the manufacturers see that because they want to have a score that&#8217;s good, they also want to understand where their footprint could be improved. So it&#8217;s a partnership, rather than it just being a bunch of tick boxes to check &#8212; which is what a lot of the audits are&#8230; We&#8217;re here to try and understand their process better.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zooming out to look at the driving forces pressing for supply chain sustainability, Chan suggests demand for greener sourcing by businesses is being driven by consumers themselves &#8212; who are certainly more aware than ever of environmental concerns. And can, to a degree, vote with their wallet by choosing more eco products (and/or by putting direct reputational pressure on businesses, such as via social media channels).</p>
<p>There is some regulatory pressure, too &#8212; such as existing sustainability and carbon reporting requirements (typically for larger businesses). Along with the overarching &#8216;net zero&#8217; targets which governments in Europe and elsewhere have signed up for. So there should be increasing &#8216;top down&#8217; pressure on businesses to decarbonize.</p>
<p>Chan also points to another swathe of environmental laws coming in &#8212; such as those banning things like single use plastics &#8212; which he says are creating further momentum for businesses to re-evaluate their supply chains.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, he believes the biggest source of pressure for companies to decarbonize is coming from consumers themselves. So &#8212; the premise is &#8212; brands that can present the strongest story to people about what they&#8217;re doing to reduce their environmental impact &#8212; backed up by a certified lifecycle assessment (assuming Sourceful gets its ISO stamp) &#8212; stand to win the business of growing numbers of eco-minded buyers, at the same time as netting cost efficiencies by optimizing their supply chains.</p>
<p>(And, indeed, part of the team&#8217;s inspiration for Sourceful&#8217;s business was to challenge the idea that consumers are to blame for the world&#8217;s environmental problems &#8212; given the lack of choice people so often have over what they can buy, not to mention the paucity of information to inform purchasing choices.)</p>
<p>&#8220;In the absence of government regulation on [lifecycle assessment] we&#8217;re actually saying to the brand, you&#8217;ve got existing products, we&#8217;ve measured the material, production, transport, all of these things &#8212; given you a carbon footprint score, and actually when you go and look at alternatives we can quantitatively assess the difference between those options. So rather than just pandering to the latest marketing buzzword you get a quantitive view on that,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>&#8220;So what we&#8217;ve been showing is you can move to a more sustainable outcome &#8212; from a quantitative point of view &#8212; but also save money. So we&#8217;re tackling both problems. The supply chain itself is not very efficient so we can save money and the supply chain is not very transparent so we can give them better visibility into their actual carbon footprint.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Every brand that we&#8217;ve met that has been started in the last two years, their founder or their premise of the brand had sustainability involved &#8212; it&#8217;s such a hot topic that if you start a fashion brand or a beauty brand or food brand you have to have somewhere in your mission statement/founder story about your commitment to sustainability. So we thought that&#8217;s where the market is going to be. But actually we saw more established companies had the same view &#8212; that their consumers are also asking for there to be change in how they talk about their products, how they understand their lifecycle journey. So actually I think the government drive on regulation is of course important but it&#8217;s still far behind and actually consumers are driving more of a change,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Sourceful&#8217;s offering includes a warehousing &#8216;managed service&#8217; component &#8212; where it&#8217;s using a predictive algorithm to power auto-stocking so that brands can store (non-current) inventory in its warehouses (to save space etc) and have the goods shipped to them as they need them.</p>
<p>Being able to source supplies like components or packaging in bulk obviously reduces purchasing costs. But depending on how it&#8217;s done, it may also mean you can optimize things like transportation requirements, which could limit shipping emissions, so there are potentially efficiency and sustainability strands here too.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sea freight is several times more energy efficient than air freight so if we can organize more shipments to go via sea freight than air then that&#8217;s a major win. The[n] if we can fill the container up with different client orders so that you end up with one very full container, rather than lots of containers with half of it empty, you&#8217;re also going to save a lot of energy too. And so that&#8217;s another part of the journey that we do,&#8221; says Chan. &#8220;The other thing is because were aggregating orders with the manufacturer &#8212; they actually have better utilization as well, which is more efficient for them. So all of these things are really important to driving the overall cost as well sustainability score down.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The more we thought about it, the more there are so many parts of the supply chain which haven&#8217;t been optimzied,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;So many times you order 2,000 boxes it comes in these air freight shipments and someone has to courier it to you in one trip &#8212; there&#8217;s so many places where aggregating and being smarter about data you can save so much footprint.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4okCEPZw9C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/danish-startups-responsibly-raises-2m-to-benchmark-supply-chains-on-climate-diversity/">Danish startup Responsibly raises $2M to benchmark supply chains on climate, diversity</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Danish startup Responsibly raises $2M to benchmark supply chains on climate, diversity&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/danish-startups-responsibly-raises-2m-to-benchmark-supply-chains-on-climate-diversity/embed/#?secret=4okCEPZw9C" data-secret="4okCEPZw9C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a3xFfnrc9Z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/portcast-gets-3-2m-to-create-more-transparent-and-sustainable-supply-chains/">Portcast gets $3.2M to create more transparent and sustainable supply chains</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Portcast gets $3.2M to create more transparent and sustainable supply chains&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/portcast-gets-3-2m-to-create-more-transparent-and-sustainable-supply-chains/embed/#?secret=a3xFfnrc9Z" data-secret="a3xFfnrc9Z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/index-leads-12-2m-seed-in-sourceful-a-data-play-to-make-supply-chains-greener/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202058</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Glassdoor acquires Fishbowl, a semi-anonymous social network and job board, to square up to LinkedIn</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/glassdoor-fishbowl-linkedin/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/glassdoor-fishbowl-linkedin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 03:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binary Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fishbowl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glassdoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lerer hippeau ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruit holdings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Belsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While LinkedIn doubles down on creators to bring a more human, less manicured element to its networking platform for professionals, a company that has built a reputation for publishing primarily the more messy and human impressions of work life has made an acquisition that might help it compete better with LinkedIn. Glassdoor, the platform that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While LinkedIn <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/linkedin-is-launching-its-own-25m-fund-and-incubator-for-creators/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">doubles down on creators</a> to bring a more human, less manicured element to its networking platform for professionals, a company that has built a reputation for publishing <em>primarily</em> the more messy and human impressions of work life has made an acquisition that might help it compete better with LinkedIn.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.glassdoor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Glassdoor</a>, the platform that lets people post anonymous and candid feedback about the organizations they work for, has acquired <a href="https://www.fishbowlapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fishbowl</a> &#8212; an app that gives users an anonymous option also to provide frank employee feedback, as well as join interest-based conversation groups to chat about work, and search for jobs. Glassdoor, which has 55 million users, is already integrating Fishbowl content into its main platform, although Fishbowl, with its 1 million users, will also continue for now to operate as a standalone app, too.</p>
<p>Christian Sutherland-Wong, the CEO of Glassdoor, said that he sees Fishbowl as the logical evolution of how Glassdoor is already being used. Similarly, since people are already seeking out feedback on prospective employers, it makes sense to bring recruitment and reviews closer together.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’ve always been about workplace transparency,&#8221; he said in an interview. &#8220;We expect in the future that jobseekers will use Glassdoor reviews, and also look to existing professionals in their fields to get answers from each other.&#8221; Fishbowl has seen a lot of traction during the Covid-19 pandemic, growing its user base threefold in the last year.</p>
<p>The acquisition is technically being made by Recruit Holdings, the Japanese employment listings and tech giant that <a href="https://www.glassdoor.com/about-us/new-chapter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired</a> Glassdoor for $1.2 billion in 2018, and the companies are not disclosing any financial terms. San Francisco-based Fishbowl &#8212; founded in 2016 by Matt Sunbulli and Loren Appin &#8212; had raised less than $8 million, according to <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/156222-37/company/profile#industry-vertical" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PitchBook</a> data, from a pretty impressive set of investors, including Binary Capital, GGV, Lerer Hippeau Ventures, and Scott Belsky.</p>
<p>Microsoft-owned LinkedIn towers over the likes of Glassdoor in terms of size. It now has more than 774 million users, making it by far the biggest social media platform targeting professionals and their work-related content. But for many, even some of those who use it, the platform leaves something to be desired.</p>
<p>LinkedIn is a reliable go-to for putting out a profile of yourself, for the public, for those in your professional life, or for recruiters, to find. But what LinkedIn largely lacks are normal people talking about work in an honest way. To read about other&#8217;s often self-congratulatory professional developments, or to see motivational words on professional development from already hugely successful personalities, or to browse developments relative to your industry that probably have already seen elsewhere is not everyone&#8217;s cup of tea. It&#8217;s anodyne. Sometimes people just <em>want</em> tea to be spilled.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That&#8217;s where something like Glassdoor comes into the picture: the format of making comments anonymous on there turns it into something of the anti-LinkedIn. It is caustic, perhaps sometimes bitter, talk about the workplace, balanced out with positive words seem to get <a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/companies-manipulate-glassdoor-by-inflating-rankings-and-pressuring-employees-11548171977" target="_blank" rel="noopener">periodically suspected</a> of being seeded by the companies themselves. Motivational, inspirational and aspirational are generally not part of the Glassdoor lexicon; honest, illuminating, and sobering perhaps are.</p>
<p>Fishbowl will be used to augment this and give Glassdoor another set of tools now to see how it might build out its platform beyond workplace reviews. The idea is to target people who come to Glassdoor to read about what people think of a company, or to put in their own comments: they can now also jump into conversations with others; and if they are coming to complain about their employer, now they can also look for a new one!</p>
<p>In the meantime, it feels like the swing to more authenticity is also a result of the shift we&#8217;ve seen in the world of work.</p>
<p>Covid-19 mandated office closures and social distancing have meant that many professionals have been working at home for the majority of the last year and a half (and many continue to do so). That has changed how we &#8220;come to work&#8221;, with many of our traditional divides between work and non-work personas and time management blurring. That has had an inevitable impact on how we see ourselves at work, and what we seek to get out of that engagement. And it also has led many people to feel isolated and in need of more ways to connect with colleagues.</p>
<p>Glassdoor&#8217;s acquisition, it said, was in part to meet this demand. A Harris Poll commissioned by Glassdoor found that 48% of employees felt isolated from coworkers during the COVID-19 pandemic; 42% of employees felt their career stall due to the lack of in-person connection; and 45% of employees expect to work hybrid or full-time remotely going forward &#8212; all areas that Glassdoor believes can be addressed with better tools (like Fishbowl) for people to communicate.</p>
<p>Of course, it will remain to be seen whether Glassdoor can convert its visitors to use the new Fishbowl-powered tools, but if there really is a population of users out there looking for a new kind of LinkedIn &#8212; there certainly are enough who love to complain about it &#8212; then maybe this cold be one version of that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/glassdoor-fishbowl-linkedin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202791</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rivian vehicles are now ready for sale in all 50 states, following key certifications</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/rivian-vehicles-are-now-ready-for-sale-in-all-50-states-following-key-certifications/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/rivian-vehicles-are-now-ready-for-sale-in-all-50-states-following-key-certifications/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 01:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric trucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rivian vehicles have received certifications from three agencies, the final hurdle that allows the electric automaker to sell and deliver its R1T pickup truck and R1S SUV in all 50 U.S. states. Rivian confirmed to TechCrunch in an email that the vehicles are fully certified by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Environmental Protection [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Rivian vehicles have received certifications from three agencies, the final hurdle that allows the electric automaker to sell and deliver its R1T pickup truck and R1S SUV in all 50 U.S. states.</p>
<p>Rivian confirmed to TechCrunch in an email that the vehicles are fully certified by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Environmental Protection Agency and the California Air Resources Board. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-15/rivian-gets-u-s-regulatory-go-ahead-to-deliver-evs-to-customers?sref=gni836kR">Bloomberg also reported</a> that Rivian has received regulatory approval to deliver vehicles to customers.</p>
<p>Rivian has a direct sales model, in which customers can order its vehicles online. Dealer protection laws in many states prohibit companies like Rivian from having its own stores, where customers can take test drives and learn about financing options. However, there are no restrictions from customers ordering online from those states.</p>
<p>Today, 22 states allow for all vehicle manufacturers to sell vehicles to customers, <a href="https://www.nrdc.org/experts/kathy-harris/why-we-support-ev-direct-sales-or-let-drivers-buy-cars">according to the NRDC</a>. In those states, Rivian can set up stores, display vehicles, offer test rides and importantly discuss financing. Another 11 states allow for only Tesla, which also has a direct sales model, to sell vehicles, often in a limited number of locations throughout the state.</p>
<p>Rivian plans to begin deliveries of the R1T launch edition this month. Deliveries of the R1S SUV are expected to follow this year.</p>
<p>Confirmation of the certifications from the state and two federal agencies followed a trio of announcements in the past several weeks that , including the first production Rivian R1T electric pickup truck in &#8220;Rivian blue&#8221; rolling off the assembly line Tuesday morning at the company&#8217;s factory in Normal, Illinois. The company&#8217;s two vehicles also received official EPA ranges of 314 miles for the first edition version of its all-electric R1T pickup truck and 316 miles for the R1T SUV.</p>
<p>All of this follows Rivian confidentially filing paperwork with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission to go public. The company, backed by a host of institutional and strategic investors including Ford and Amazon, has not size and price range for the proposed offering.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sources familiar with Rivian&#8217;s IPO plans said the company has not yet started the &#8220;roadshow,&#8221; a process in which an underwriting firm and company management make a series of presentations to potential investors before going public.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/rivian-vehicles-are-now-ready-for-sale-in-all-50-states-following-key-certifications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202865</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Casper cuts its CMO, CTO and COO amid further layoffs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/casper-cuts-its-cmo-cto-and-coo-amid-further-layoffs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/casper-cuts-its-cmo-cto-and-coo-amid-further-layoffs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casper sleep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direct to consumer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Casper has laid off dozens of employees, including three C-Level executives: its chief marketing officer, chief technology officer and chief operating officer, sources say. The mattress company declined to comment. The round of layoffs, communicated to employees on Friday, largely impacted retail and operations teams, signaling that the business may be undergoing a broader restructuring. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Output copied to clipboard! --></p>
<p>Casper has laid off dozens of employees, including three C-Level executives: its chief marketing officer, chief technology officer and chief operating officer, sources say. The mattress company declined to comment.</p>
<p>The round of layoffs, communicated to employees on Friday, largely impacted retail and operations teams, signaling that the business may be undergoing a broader restructuring. Laid-off employees were offered severance packages.</p>
<p>Notably, the impacted executives were all fairly recent additions to the team. CTO Ben Clark has been with the company since July 2019, while former CMO Lisa Pillette joined Casper in March 2020. Casper COO Charles Liu had only been at the company for eight months before this round of layoffs.</p>
<p>Casper’s CFO remains at the startup, but that role has had some significant turnover as well. In an April 2020 business update, Casper announced that Gregory Macfarlane, its CFO and COO at the time, was leaving the company. Interim CFO Stuart Brown eventually took the role, and three months later resigned. The latest CFO, Michael Monahan, took the position effective August 31, 2021.</p>
<p>Over a year ago, Casper announced it was shutting down its European operations, cutting 21% of its global workforce. The move was then attributed to Casper’s new goal of  “achieving profitability,” which included a focus on North American operations.</p>
<p>The business hinted then that the temporary closure of its retail stores impacted its overall direct-to-consumer channel, forcing it to take steps to minimize operating costs. Now, the startup is going one step further by eliminating roles within its retail and operations teams.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One founder in the direct-to-consumer space, who spoke on the condition of anonymity due to her lack of direct knowledge with the company, said that Casper’s layoffs could also be a response to iOS 14.5, Apple’s latest software that will crack down on apps that track users’ data without permission. The setting restricts the advertising data that companies can access, making it harder to justify budget and understand the efficacy of their sales strategy.</p>
<p>“Performance marketing through paid channels, specifically Facebook and Instagram, is wonky right now,” the person said. “So, if they were really reliant on that channel that could be something that is affecting their sales.”</p>
<p>Casper priced its IPO shares at $12 and debuted at $14.50 a share just as the COVID-19 pandemic was gaining momentum in February 2020. The company dove nearly 72% from its opening price before recovering, reaching a more recent peak of nearly $11 in February 2021. Today, the company trades at just above $5, a decline of more than half from its opening.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/casper-cuts-its-cmo-cto-and-coo-amid-further-layoffs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202841</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rivian&#8217;s first production R1T electric pickup truck rolls off the line</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/rivians-first-production-r1t-electric-pickup-truck-rolls-off-the-line/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/rivians-first-production-r1t-electric-pickup-truck-rolls-off-the-line/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 22:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R1T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RJ Scaringe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first production Rivian R1T electric pickup truck in &#8220;Rivian blue&#8221; rolled off the assembly line Tuesday morning at the company&#8217;s factory in Normal, Illinois, marking a milestone more than a decade in the making for the automaker and its founder and CEO, RJ Scaringe. The company, which started in 2009 as Mainstream Motors before [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The first production Rivian R1T electric pickup truck in &#8220;Rivian blue&#8221; rolled off the assembly line Tuesday morning at the company&#8217;s factory in Normal, Illinois, marking a milestone more than a decade in the making for the automaker and its founder and CEO, RJ Scaringe.</p>
<p>The company, which started in 2009 as Mainstream Motors before adopting the Rivian name two years later, has undergone explosive growth in terms of people, backers and partners in the past few years. Today, Scaringe tweeted the news and a photo of the first production truck painted in Rivian Blue.</p>
<p>&#8220;After months of building pre-production vehicles, this morning our first customer vehicle drove off our production line in Normal,!&#8221; he wrote. &#8220;Our team&#8217;s collective efforts have made this moment possible. Can&#8217;t wait to get these into the hands of our customers!&#8221;</p>
<p>What isn&#8217;t clear is who will get this first customer vehicle.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">After months of building pre-production vehicles, this morning our first customer vehicle drove off our production line in Normal!  Our team&#39;s collective efforts have made this moment possible. Can&#39;t wait to get these into the hands of our customers! <a href="https://t.co/8ZidwTaXRI">pic.twitter.com/8ZidwTaXRI</a></p>
<p>&mdash; RJ Scaringe (@RJScaringe) <a href="https://twitter.com/RJScaringe/status/1437842808384233477?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 14, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Rivian operated in relative obscurity, aka stealth mode, for years before it revealed prototypes of its all-electric R1T truck and R1S SUV at the LA Auto Show in late 2018.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Since then, Rivian has raised billions of dollars ($10.5 billion since 2019); expanded its Normal, Illinois, factory; hired thousands of employees; landed Amazon as a commercial customer; and, most recently, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/electric-vehicle-company-rivian-has-confidentially-filed-for-an-ipo/">filed confidentially for an IPO</a>. Today, in addition to its Illinois factory, Rivian has facilities in Palo Alto and Irvine, California; and Plymouth, Michigan; and an office in the U.K.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FOM10aK0MQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/">The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The debut of electric pickups signals a new EV era&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/the-debut-of-electric-pickups-signals-a-new-ev-era/embed/#?secret=FOM10aK0MQ" data-secret="FOM10aK0MQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>When it first revealed the two electric vehicles in 2018, Rivian had about 600 employees. Today, it has 8,000.</p>
<p>Scaringe&#8217;s announcement Tuesday, which marks the official beginning of R1T production for customers, comes after at least two delays caused by the COVID-19 pandemic and global chip shortage. Earlier this summer, Scaringe wrote in a letter to customers that R1T deliveries would begin in September, with the R1S to follow “shortly.”</p>
<p>Rivian has been juggling the dueling priorities of prepping and eventually producing the R1T and R1S for consumers and commercial delivery vans for Amazon. The Illinois factory has two separate production lines producing vehicles. One is dedicated to the R1 vehicles and the other line is for its commercial vans.</p>
<p>Amazon ordered 100,000 of these vans, with deliveries starting in 2021. Earlier this year, Amazon began testing the electric delivery van in several cities, including Los Angeles and San Francisco.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="riUIH8ecFq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/amazon-begins-testing-its-rivian-electric-delivery-vans-in-san-francisco/">Amazon begins testing its Rivian electric delivery vans in San Francisco</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon begins testing its Rivian electric delivery vans in San Francisco&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/amazon-begins-testing-its-rivian-electric-delivery-vans-in-san-francisco/embed/#?secret=riUIH8ecFq" data-secret="riUIH8ecFq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Earlier this month, Rivian announced that the first edition version of the R1T pickup truck has an official EPA range of 314 miles, while its R1T SUV comes in at 316 miles.</p>
<p>The official range and fuel economy values posted on the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency website align with Rivian&#8217;s previous estimates, which it advertised as 300 miles.</p>
<p>The moment is also important because it means Rivian has the benefit of being the first electric truck on the market. Ford&#8217;s F-150 Lightning, which isn&#8217;t expected to come on the market until spring 2022, has a targeted range of 230 miles in the standard and up to 300 miles in the extended version. The EPA has not issued official ranges for the Ford Lightning.</p>
<p>Rivian&#8217;s &#8220;Launch Edition&#8221; R1T truck and R1S SUV come equipped with a 135 kWh battery pack that is branded as the &#8220;large pack.&#8221; Deliveries of the Launch Edition vehicles are slated to begin this month.</p>
<p><em>Clarification: Rivian has raised $10.5 billion since 2019, not in total. Rivian has not shared the total amount but sources have said it is around $11 billion. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/rivians-first-production-r1t-electric-pickup-truck-rolls-off-the-line/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201982</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Here’s what happened at Apple’s virtual 2021 fall event</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/daily-crunch-62/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/daily-crunch-62/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 22:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for September 14, 2021. It was an Apple day on the internets, so we’ve all spent the afternoon trying to figure out if we need a new smartphone. Answer? Probably not, but that won’t stop a good portion of the TechCrunch crew from deploying fresh Yahoo lucre into Cupertino’s market cap. We love this stuff.</p>
<p>On the TechCrunch front, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">Disrupt is in a week’s</a> time. Your humble servant is going shopping later this afternoon so that he can look slightly less disheveled. Jordan, of course, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/the-disrupt-desk-will-help-you-catch-everything-you-missed-at-disrupt-2021/">will look brilliant on the Disrupt Desk</a>. See you there! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b5cOOw5NVN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/the-disrupt-desk-will-help-you-catch-everything-you-missed-at-disrupt-2021/">The Disrupt Desk will help you catch everything you missed at Disrupt 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Disrupt Desk will help you catch everything you missed at Disrupt 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/the-disrupt-desk-will-help-you-catch-everything-you-missed-at-disrupt-2021/embed/#?secret=b5cOOw5NVN" data-secret="b5cOOw5NVN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Apple drops grip of new hardware:</strong> Anytime Apple hosts an event, it’s like time stops in the technology world. If that should still be the case is up to you, but it remains fact. Here’s our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/this-is-the-iphone-13/">rundown of iPhone news</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-watch-series-7-arrives-with-a-larger-more-rugged-display/">Apple Watch news</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-refreshes-ipad-mini-with-a-new-design-5g-and-an-8-3-inch-display/">iPad updates</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-its-event-this-morning/">a general roundup</a> in case you want to go meta. Enjoy!</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/atlantas-sundry-startups-join-in-global-vc-funding-boom/"><strong>Atlanta booming:</strong></a> TechCrunch continued its tour of U.S. cities today after hitting up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/when-vcs-turned-to-zoom-chicago-startups-were-ready-for-their-close-up/">Chicago</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/bostons-startup-market-is-more-than-setting-records-in-scorching-start-to-year/">Boston</a> in recent weeks. This time, we dug into Atlanta’s booming startup scene, which is seeing record capital inflows. We talked to some founders and investors to get the latest. Don’t forget that Atlanta <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/">just produced</a> a decacorn exit.</li>
<li>And speaking of decacorns, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/canva-raises-200-million-at-a-40-billion-valuation/"><strong>Canva just raised $200 million at a $40 billion valuation</strong></a>. In percentage terms, the Australian design software company managed to raise two bills for 0.5% of its equity value. A steal at twice the price. Why is Canva worth so much? Huge scale, as our notes regarding its revenue growth illuminate.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-fall-event-2021-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about Apple's Fall 2021 Event on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Before we dive into our usual rundown of startup news, TechCrunch did <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/heres-what-your-bnpl-startup-could-be-worth/">a dig into the value of the myriad BNPL startups</a> around the world through the lens of some recent acquisitions. I wrote it. Read it if that’s your jam.</p>
<ul>
<li>In light of the day’s Apple Fitness news, it matters that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/tonal-adds-live-classes-to-its-strength-training-workouts/"><strong>Tonal just announced live classes are coming to its service</strong></a>. Tonal competes in the hardware-and-software market against Peloton and other players. Notably it’s the <em>startups</em> of the world that are fusing hardware and software more than Apple in this case, which is mostly bundling services into its existing products. Regardless, good news for you Tonal users out there.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/1047-games-raises-100m-on-the-runaway-success-of-its-debut-title-splitgate/"><strong>1047 Games closes $100M:</strong></a><strong> </strong>If you are hot, Brian Heater writes, you are hot. And 1047 games with its hit title Splitgate is more than warm. So sweltering that it just closed a third round since May. What’s Splitgate? An FPS that includes portals. (Which frankly sounds awesome.)</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/grammarly-sdk-beta-lets-developers-embed-text-editing-into-any-web-app/">Grammarly opens up for developers:</a></strong> Grammarly is well known as a product that folks use to help tighten up their writing. But what if you wanted to bake Grammarly tech into your own product? Well, now you can. The company just announced a developer product. The finance nerd in me wonders how lucrative the new business line will prove, and if it will help the company file its damn S-1 already.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/everafter-closes-13m-to-help-companies-ride-off-into-the-sunset-with-their-customers/"><strong>EverAfter raises $13M, underscores that HRtech is still hot:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Per our own reporting, EverAfter has built a “no-code customer-facing tool that streamlines onboarding and retention.” That’s a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/soras-hr-automation-software-raises-14m-series-a/">bit like Sora</a>, a startup that TechCrunch has also written about. A few rounds focused on the same space is signal!</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/indonesian-fintech-xendit-is-now-a-unicorn-with-150m-in-fresh-funding-led-by-tiger-global/"><strong>Today’s Tiger round is Indonesian fintech Xendit:</strong></a> Xendit is now a unicorn thanks to a $150 million check led by Tiger. At this point, we reckon that every time Tiger’s managing partners go to dinner they tip $150 million. It’s the only number that they know! Regardless, the Jakarta-based fintech with a payments focus has big expansion plans that are now well financed.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Is it so bad to take money from Chinese venture funds?</h2>
<p>Are founders in fundraising mode short-sighted when it comes to working with Chinese investors?</p>
<p>Asia Business development manager for Runa Capital Denis Kalinin studied data from iTjuzi, a database of Chinese venture capitalists and found:</p>
<blockquote><p> … Chinese funds invested around $250 billion in 2020 (three times higher than the figure reported in Crunchbase). This figure puts Chinese VC investments only 30% lower than investments by U.S. funds, but three times that of U.K. funds and 12.5 times more than German funds.</p></blockquote>
<p>The pandemic, geopolitical tensions and other factors led many Chinese venture funds to reduce their international investments, but that&#8217;s largely &#8220;because during COVID, China’s economy recovered much faster than other countries,&#8221; writes Kalinin.</p>
<p>His analysis covers multiple angles: Chinese investments in Europe are catching up with those in Asia and the United States, half of China&#8217;s top cross-border investors are CVCs, and investors are particularly interested in fintech, deep tech and digital health at the moment.</p>
<p>&#8220;Chinese investors can bring value to foreign startups, but you need to study their expertise and how it can be useful for you.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L3uS78vakq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/is-it-so-bad-to-take-money-from-chinese-venture-funds/">Is it so bad to take money from Chinese venture funds?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Is it so bad to take money from Chinese venture funds?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/is-it-so-bad-to-take-money-from-chinese-venture-funds/embed/#?secret=L3uS78vakq" data-secret="L3uS78vakq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Before we get into the nitty-gritty of Big Tech news, an update from the U.S. government: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/alvaro-bedoya-ftc-biden/"><strong>&#8220;Biden’s new FTC nominee is a digital privacy advocate critical of Big Tech,&#8221;</strong></a> it turns out. That matters.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/linkedin-is-launching-its-own-25m-fund-and-incubator-for-creators/"><strong>LinkedIn pledges $25M to creators:</strong></a><strong> </strong>In case your LinkedIn feed was lacking in pizazz, the Microsoft subsidiary has plans to bolster your content influx. A $25 million “Creator Accelerator Program” has been established to encourage more, well, creation. Also LinkedIn is getting into live audio.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spacex-launches-its-first-batch-of-starlink-satellites-aimed-at-new-coverage-areas-from-california/"><strong>51 more Starlink satellites take flight:</strong></a><strong> </strong>We’re including this news item in Daily Crunch today in case you are <em>also </em>considering a move to rural Montana but need to stay employed.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spaceflight-will-be-ferrying-payloads-from-orbit-fab-geojump-to-lunar-orbit-next-year/"><strong>Spaceflight looks to fly to the moon:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Elon’s space company is not the only player looking to get humans off the plant. Spaceflight will “shuttle customers on a lunar flyby mission next year,” which is more than neat. How much for a ticket?</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We’re reaching out to startup founders to tell us who they turn to when they want the most up-to-date growth marketing practices. Fill out the survey <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">here.</a></p>
<p>Read one of the testimonials we’ve received below!</p>
<p><strong>Marketer:</strong> Andrew Race, <a href="https://www.thinkjuice.com/">Juice</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommended by: </strong>Orin Singh, <a href="https://www.merchantindustry.com/">Merchant Industry</a></p>
<p><strong>Testimonial: </strong>“We were referred to Juice by a family friend of my company&#8217;s owner, and as a personal courtesy, they said they were giving us their best guy. Naturally, we thought that is what everyone says, but they were not kidding. Andrew was singularly leagues above our previous marketing company. Having someone so knowledgeable and willing to learn a new industry proved to be the turning point for us.”</p>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2202722" style="width: 204px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://www.basicbooks.com/titles/martin-ford/rule-of-the-robots/9781541674721/"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202722" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2202722 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?w=194" alt="" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg 323w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?resize=97,150 97w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?resize=194,300 194w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ruleofrobots.jpg?resize=32,50 32w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2202722" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Basic Books</p></div></p>
<p>From planned Twitter Spaces to impromptu chats with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/equity-podcast/">Equity</a> crew, the TechCrunch team is constantly on Twitter. Tomorrow, Wednesday, September 15 at 2 p.m. PDT/5 p.m. EDT, the Disrupt Battlefield judges will be talking on Twitter Spaces. On Thursday, September 16, at 3 p.m. PDT/6 p.m. EDT, Danny Crichton will be joined by Martin Ford, author of <a href="https://www.basicbooks.com/titles/martin-ford/rule-of-the-robots/9781541674721/">“Rule of the Robots: How Artificial Intelligence Will Transform Everything.”</a> Make sure you’re following the <a href="https://twitter.com/TechCrunch">TechCrunch</a> Twitter account to stay up to date with our news and events.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/daily-crunch-62/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202710</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Logistics startup Stord raises $90M in Kleiner Perkins-led round, becomes a unicorn and acquires a company</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/logistics-startup-stord-raises-90m-in-kleiner-perkins-led-round-becomes-a-unicorn-and-acquires-another-company/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/logistics-startup-stord-raises-90m-in-kleiner-perkins-led-round-becomes-a-unicorn-and-acquires-another-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ilya Fushman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kleiner Perkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Kleiner Perkins led Stord’s $12.4 million Series A in 2019, its founders were in their early 20s and so passionate about their startup that they each dropped out of their respective schools to focus on growing the business. Fast-forward two years and Stord &#8212; an Atlanta-based company that has developed a cloud supply chain &#8212; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Kleiner Perkins led Stord’s $12.4 million Series A in 2019, its founders were in their early 20s and so passionate about their startup that they each dropped out of their respective schools to focus on growing the business.</p>
<p>Fast-forward two years and <a href="http://www.stord.com">Stord</a> &#8212; an Atlanta-based company that has developed a cloud supply chain &#8212; is raising more capital in a round again led by Kleiner Perkins.</p>
<p>This time, Stord has raised $90 million in a Series D round of funding at a post-money valuation of $1.125 billion &#8212; more than double the $510 million that the company was valued at when raising $65 million in a Series C financing just six months ago.</p>
<p>In fact, today’s funding marks Stord’s third since early December of 2020, when it raised its Series B led by Peter Thiel’s Founders Fund, and brings the company’s total raised since its 2015 inception to $205 million.</p>
<p>Besides Kleiner Perkins, Lux Capital, D1 Capital, Palm Tree Crew, BOND, Dynamo Ventures, Founders Fund, Lineage Logistics and Susa Ventures also participated in the Series D financing. In addition, Michael Rubin, Fanatics founder and founder of GSI Commerce; Carlos Cashman, CEO of Thrasio; Max Mullen, co-founder of Instacart; and Will Gaybrick, CPO at Stripe, put money in the round. Previous backers include BoxGroup, Susa Ventures, Dynamo, Revolution and Rise of the Rest Seed Fund, among others.</p>
<p>Founders Sean Henry, 24, and Jacob Boudreau, 23, met while Henry was at Georgia Tech and Boudreau was in online classes at Arizona State (ASU) but running his own business, a software development firm, in Atlanta.</p>
<p>Over time, Stord has evolved into a cloud supply chain that can give companies a way to compete and grow with logistics, and provides an integrated platform “that’s available exactly when and where they need it,” Henry said. Stord combines physical logistics services such as freight, warehousing and fulfillment in that platform, which aims to provide “complete visibility, rapid optimization and elastic scale” for its users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>About two months ago, Stord announced the opening of its first fulfillment center, a 386,000-square-foot facility, in Atlanta, which features warehouse robotics and automation technologies. “It was the first time we were in a building ourselves running it end to end,” Henry said.</p>
<p>And today, the company is announcing it has acquired Connecticut-based Fulfillment Works, a 22-year-old company with direct-to-consumer (DTC) experience and warehouses in Nevada and in its home state.</p>
<p>With FulfillmentWorks, the company says it has increased its first-party warehouses, coupled with its network of over 400 warehouse partners and 15,000 carriers.</p>
<p>While Stord would not disclose the amount it paid for Fulfillment Works, Henry did share some of Stord’s impressive financial metrics. The company, he said, in 2020 delivered its third consecutive year of 300+% growth, and is on track to do so again in 2021. Stord also achieved more than $100 million in revenue in the first two quarters of 2021, according to Henry, and grew its headcount from 160 people last year to over 450 so far in 2021 (including about 150 Fulfillment Works employees). And since the fourth quarter is often when people do the most online shopping, Henry expects the three-month period to be Stord’s heaviest revenue quarter.</p>
<p>For some context, Stord’s new sales were up “7x” in the second quarter of 2020 compared to the same period last year. So far in the third quarter, sales are up almost 10x, according to Henry.</p>
<p>Put simply, Stord aims to give brands a way to compete with the likes of Amazon, which has set expectations of fast fulfillment and delivery. The company guarantees two-day shipping to anywhere in the country.</p>
<p>“The supply chain is the new competitive battleground,” Henry said. “Today’s buying expectations set by Amazon and the rise of the omni-channel shopper have placed immense pressure on companies to maintain more nimble and efficient supply chains… We want every company to have world-class, Prime-like supply chains.”</p>
<p>What makes Stord unique, according to Henry, is the fact that it has built what it believes to be the only end-to-end logistics network that combines the physical infrastructure with software.</p>
<p>That too is one of the reasons that Kleiner Perkins doubled down on its investment in the company.</p>
<p>Ilya Fushman, Stord board director and partner at Kleiner Perkins, said even at the time of his firm’s investment in 2019, that Henry displayed “amazing maturity and vision.”</p>
<p>At a high level, the firm was also just drawn to what he described as the “incredibly large market opportunity.”</p>
<p>“It’s trillions of dollars of products moving around with consumer expectation that these products will get to them the same day or next day, wherever they are,” Fushman told TechCrunch. “And while companies like Amazon have built amazing infrastructure to do that themselves, the rest of the world hasn&#8217;t really caught up&#8230; So there’s just amazing opportunity to build software and services to modernize this multitrillion-dollar market.”</p>
<p>In other words, Fushman explained, Stord is serving as a “plug and play” or “one stop shop” for retailers and merchants so they don’t have to spend resources on their own warehouses or building their own logistics platforms.</p>
<p>Stord launched the software part of its business in January 2020, and it grew 900% during the year, and is today one of the fastest-growing parts of its business.</p>
<p>“We built software to run our logistics and network of hundreds of warehouses,” Henry told TechCrunch. “But if companies want to use the same system for existing logistics, they can buy our software to get that kind of visibility.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/logistics-startup-stord-raises-90m-in-kleiner-perkins-led-round-becomes-a-unicorn-and-acquires-another-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202757</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creative adtech is on the cusp of a revolution, and VCs should take note</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/creative-ad-tech-is-on-the-cusp-of-a-revolution-and-vcs-should-take-note/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/creative-ad-tech-is-on-the-cusp-of-a-revolution-and-vcs-should-take-note/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Marketing Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[targeted advertising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here are five reasons why VCs should consider ratcheting up their investment into adtech startups building the next generation of creative tools:]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Casey Saran</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Spaceback">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		An ad tech veteran who has logged time at Google and The Rubicon Project (now Magnite), Casey Saran is co-founder and CEO of Spaceback.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">2021 has been a good year to be an adtech investor. Valuations are <a href="https://www.adexchanger.com/online-advertising/the-trade-desk-doubles-revenue-in-a-weird-year-and-bets-the-farm-on-ctv/">surging</a>, Wall Street is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/digital-ad-opportunities-and-capital-spur-investor-interest-in-ad-tech-11625220000">happy</a> and exits are <a href="https://www.adweek.com/media/triplelift-to-sell-majority-stake-to-vista-equity-partners-for-1-4-billion/">frequent</a> and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/integral-ad-science-buys-ad-tech-company-publica-for-220-million-11628591400">satisfying</a>. It’s the perfect time to double down and invest in an area that has been largely ignored but is poised for major upside in the next few years: Digital creative ad technology.</p>
<p>Think about it. When was the last time we saw a major adtech funding round that was directed at the actual ads themselves — the messages people actually see everyday? I’d argue that now is the perfect time.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The adtech startups that can figure out how to adapt ads that can interact with the remote control, a synced smartphone or voice commands — maybe even make them shoppable — can theoretically produce a game-changer.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Here are five reasons why VCs should consider ratcheting up their investment into adtech startups building the next generation of creative tools:</p>
<h2>Creative tech is far from being saturated</h2>
<p>Consider how much has been spent over the 15 years on digital advertising mechanics such as targeting, serving, measuring and verification. Not to mention the trillions that have gone toward helping brands keep track of customer data and interactions — the marketing clouds, DMPs and CDPs.</p>
<p>Yet you can count the number of creative-centric adtech companies on one hand. This means there is a lot of room for innovation and early leaders. VideoAmp, which helps brands make ads for various social platforms, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/press-releases/2021-05-18/videoamp-raises-75m-in-committed-financing-from-capital-ip">pulled in $75 million earlier this year</a>. Given how fast platforms like TikTok and Snap are growing, it won’t be the last.</p>
<h2>Digital ad targeting is being squeezed</h2>
<p>Ads need to do more work today. Between regulation, cookies going away and Apple locking down data collection, we’ve seen a renewed interest in contextual advertising, including funding for the likes of <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/gumgum-raises-75-million-from-goldman-sachs-11618311629">GumGum</a>, as well as identity resolution firms like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/infosum-raises-65m-series-b-as-organizations-embrace-secure-data-sharing/">InfoSum</a>.</p>
<p>But the digital ad ecosystem can’t get by only using broader data-crunching techniques to replace &#8220;retargeting.&#8221; The medium is practically crying out for a creative revival that can only be sparked by scalable tech. The <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/marpipe-raises-series-a-funding-venture-capital-samsung-2021-9">recent funding</a> for creative testing startup Marpipe is a start, but more focus is needed on actual tech-driven ideation and automation.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/creative-ad-tech-is-on-the-cusp-of-a-revolution-and-vcs-should-take-note/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202137</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>App Annie and co-founder charged with securities fraud, will pay $10M+ settlement</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/app-annie-and-co-founder-charged-with-securities-fraud-will-pay-10m-settlement/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/app-annie-and-co-founder-charged-with-securities-fraud-will-pay-10m-settlement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App Annie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bertrand Schmitt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has charged App Annie, a leading mobile data and analytics firm, as well as its co-founder and former CEO and Chairman Bertrand Schmitt, with securities fraud. App Annie and Schmitt have agreed to pay over $10 million to settle the fraud charges which are related to &#8220;deceptive practices [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2021-176">has charged App Annie</a>, a leading mobile data and analytics firm, as well as its co-founder and former CEO and Chairman Bertrand Schmitt, with securities fraud. App Annie and Schmitt have agreed to pay over $10 million to settle the fraud charges which are related to &#8220;deceptive practices and making material misrepresentations about how App Annie&#8217;s alternative data was derived,&#8221; the SEC said.</p>
<p>App Annie is one of the largest sellers of mobile app performance data, offering details that are useful to developers, publishers, advertisers and marketers &#8212; like how many times an app is downloaded, how often it&#8217;s used, the revenue it generates and other competitive analysis and insights. This is what trading firms call &#8220;alternative data,&#8221; because it&#8217;s not detailed in their financial statements or other traditional data sources, the SEC explains. App Annie told app makers it would not disclose their data to third parties directly, but would rather use the data in an aggregated and anonymized way to provide app insights. Specifically, companies were told the data would be used to build a statistical model to generate estimates of app performance.</p>
<p>However, the SEC says from late 2014 through mid-2018, App Annie used non-aggregated and non-anonymized data to alter its model-generated estimates in order to make them more valuable to sell to trading firms. It also says that the company and Schmitt then misrepresented to its customers how it was able to generate the data, saying it did so with the appropriate consent from customers, and that it had effective internal controls to prevent the misuse of confidential data, ensuring it was in compliance with federal securities laws. Trading firms were making investment decisions based on this data and App Annie had even shared ideas as to how they could use the estimates to trade ahead of earnings announcements.</p>
<p>In the full complaint, the SEC further explains Schmitt had agreed to an internal policy where certain public company &#8220;Connect Data&#8221; &#8212; &#8220;Connect&#8221; being App Annies&#8217; analytics product &#8212; would be excluded from its statistical model in late 2014. But he didn&#8217;t actually direct anyone at App Annie to document this policy until April 2017. And then when it was documented, it only said to exclude app revenue data from public companies whose app revenue exceeded 5% of the company&#8217;s total revenue. It never said to exclude app download or usage data.</p>
<p>The SEC says the documented policy was never properly enforced. It wasn&#8217;t until after App Annie learned of the SEC investigation in June 2018 that it amended the policy to exclude public company Connect Data from its estimate generation process, and began to fully implement the policy.</p>
<p>The investigation also discovered that App Annie engineers in Beijing, China were directed by Schmitt to manually alter estimates that would be of most interest to the company&#8217;s highest-paying customers. It did so by looking at the confidential Connect Data, which is one of the ways its estimates were able to be more accurate than rivals. Later, in 2016, it implemented a more automated way of adjusting its model-generated estimates to match up with the actual (and confidential) revenue and download numbers. When App Annie&#8217;s Chief Data Scientist refused to implement the method, believing adjustments should only be made to the statistical model itself, Schmitt had the Beijing engineers make the changes without informing other company executives, subscribers, users or employees.</p>
<p>&#8220;The federal securities laws prohibit deceptive conduct and material misrepresentations in connection with the purchase or sale of securities,&#8221; said Gurbir S. Grewal, director of the SEC&#8217;s Enforcement Division, in a statement. &#8220;Here, App Annie and Schmitt lied to companies about how their confidential data was being used and then not only sold the manipulated estimates to their trading firm customers, but also encouraged them to trade on those estimates—often touting how closely they correlated with the companies&#8217; true performance and stock prices,&#8221; Grewal added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The SEC says App Annie and Schmitt violated the anti-fraud provisions of Section 10(b) of the Exchange Act and Rule 10b-5. App Annie, without either admitting or denying the findings, consented to a cease-and-desist order and is paying a penalty. App Annie agreed to pay a penalty of $10 million. Meanwhile, Schmitt is ordered to pay a penalty of $300,000 and is prohibited from serving as an officer or director of a public company for three years.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, App Annie&#8217;s current CEO provided a statement:</p>
<p>“Since I have taken over as CEO, we have established a new standard of trust and transparency for the newly created alternative data market. App Annie is uniquely positioned to be the first to deliver on a unified data AI vision,” said Theodore Krantz, CEO at App Annie. “Many businesses may be unknowingly leveraging data reliant on confidential public company information without explicit consent which we believe puts companies using digital/mobile market data at significant risk. It is our opinion that the entire alternative data space needs to be regulated.”</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/about/press/releases/app-annie-issues-statement-on-sec-settlement/">a newsroom post</a>, the company also pointed out that the SEC investigation does not relate to its &#8220;current products,&#8221; nor did it relate to &#8220;our current relationships with customers.&#8221; And it says in the three years since the violating practices, it has appointed a new CEO and executive team, changed how it built its data estimates, and established a company-wide &#8220;culture of compliance,&#8221; which included the appointment of a Head of Global Compliance. It also documented its procedures for ensuring confidential data is excluded from its process of generating market estimates.</p>
<p>App Annie&#8217;s mobile market data solution was one of the first to serve the growing app ecosystem when it launched in 2010. Today, its firm counts more than 1,100 enterprise clients and over a million registered users, <a href="https://www.appannie.com/en/about/press/">according</a> to its corporate website. The company earlier this summer <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/app-annie-explores-strategic-options-including-a-possible-deal-or-ipo-11625855468">was said to be</a> weighing a possible sale, IPO, or other options.</p>
<p>The details of the complaint and settlement are below.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/525320753/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-E5rzLJTF4AO9mbqd2ARp"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_525320753" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/525320753" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/app-annie-and-co-founder-charged-with-securities-fraud-will-pay-10m-settlement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202745</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX, Blue Origin awarded NASA contracts to develop moon lander concepts for future Artemis missions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spacex-blue-origin-awarded-nasa-contracts-to-develop-moon-lander-concepts-for-future-artemis-missions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spacex-blue-origin-awarded-nasa-contracts-to-develop-moon-lander-concepts-for-future-artemis-missions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artemis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dynetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human landing system program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[northrop grumman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NASA has awarded a combined $146 million in contracts to five companies, including SpaceX, Blue Origin and Dynetics, to develop lander concepts as part of the agency’s Artemis program. The awards include $26.5 million to Blue Origin; $40.8 million to Dynetics; $35.2 million to Lockheed Martin; $34.8 million to Northrop Grumman; and $9.4 million to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">NASA has awarded a combined $146 million in contracts to five companies, including SpaceX, Blue Origin and Dynetics, to develop lander concepts as part of the agency’s Artemis program.</p>
<p>The awards include $26.5 million to Blue Origin; $40.8 million to Dynetics; $35.2 million to Lockheed Martin; $34.8 million to Northrop Grumman; and $9.4 million to SpaceX. Only two companies that submitted proposals, Blue Ridge Nebula Starlines and Cook &amp; Chevalier Enterprises, did not receive contracts.</p>
<p>The contracts were awarded under NextSTEP-2 (Next Space Technologies for Exploration Partnerships) Appendix N: Sustainable Human Landing System Studies and Risk Reduction. The solicitation, released at the beginning of July, says the objective of the contract is “to engage with potential commercial partners for concept studies, sustaining HLS concept of operations (ground and flight) development, and risk reduction activities.”</p>
<p>What that means in practice is that the selected companies will develop lander design concepts, including conducting component tests, and evaluate them for things like performance and safety.</p>
<p>These awards are separate from the Human Landing System contract that was given to SpaceX earlier this year &#8212; the one that both Blue Origin and Dynetics <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/government-watchdog-rejects-blue-origins-protest-over-lunar-lander-contract/">disputed</a> to a government watchdog, and that Blue Origin later opposed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-goes-toe-to-toe-with-nasa-in-federal-court-over-award-to-spacex/">in a lawsuit against NASA</a> that’s still ongoing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0qwbsRxCvZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/feds-dismantle-blue-origin-and-dynetics-protests-of-nasas-spacex-lunar-lander-award/">Feds dismantle Blue Origin and Dynetics protests of NASA&#8217;s SpaceX lunar lander award</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Feds dismantle Blue Origin and Dynetics protests of NASA&#8217;s SpaceX lunar lander award&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/feds-dismantle-blue-origin-and-dynetics-protests-of-nasas-spacex-lunar-lander-award/embed/#?secret=0qwbsRxCvZ" data-secret="0qwbsRxCvZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>However, the outcome of this batch of awards will likely inform future lander development contracts through the rest of the decade. “The work from these companies will ultimately help shape the strategy and requirements for a future NASA’s solicitation to provide regular astronaut transportation from lunar orbit to the surface of the Moon,” the agency said in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Artemis program was established in 2020 with a number of objectives, not only to return humans to the moon for the first time since the days of Apollo but to make such travel routine by the late 2020s. NASA isn’t just stopping at the moon; the agency also wants to expand into inter-planetary exploration, including human missions to Mars.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spacex-blue-origin-awarded-nasa-contracts-to-develop-moon-lander-concepts-for-future-artemis-missions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202764</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intuit&#8217;s $12B Mailchimp acquisition is about expanding its small business focus</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/intuits-12b-mailchimp-acquisition-is-about-expanding-its-small-business-focus/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/intuits-12b-mailchimp-acquisition-is-about-expanding-its-small-business-focus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mergers and Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small businesses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At first blush, the $12 billion Intuit-Mailchimp deal might not make a heck of a lot of sense. But people tend to pigeonhole companies, and in this case they might see Intuit as purely a financial software company and Mailchimp as an email marketing firm and nothing more. If that&#8217;s as far as your perspective [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At first blush, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/">the $12 billion Intuit-Mailchimp deal</a> might not make a heck of a lot of sense. But people tend to pigeonhole companies, and in this case they might see Intuit as purely a financial software company and Mailchimp as an email marketing firm and nothing more. If that&#8217;s as far as your perspective goes, the deal is confusing. From a wider lens, however, there’s more to both companies than you might think.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start with Intuit. If you go to the company website and<a href="https://www.intuit.com/products/"> scan the product set</a>, it&#8217;s clearly all about managing finances for consumer and small businesses alike. The latter category appears to be what the company wants to exploit and expand upon with this deal.</p>
<p>Prior to yesterday&#8217;s news, Intuit&#8217;s biggest acquisition had been on the consumer side <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/intuit-credit-karma/">buying Credit Karma for $7.1 billion</a> last year. That deal gave the company&#8217;s customers a way to access their credit scores outside of the big three reporting companies: Experian, Equifax and TransUnion. Apparently not content with only that transaction, it set its sights on Mailchimp to throw some money at the business side of the house.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/intuits-12b-mailchimp-acquisition-is-about-expanding-its-small-business-focus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xbox and Special Olympics hold first &#8216;Gaming for Inclusion&#8217; esports event</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/xbox-and-special-olympics-hold-first-gaming-for-inclusion-esports-event/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/xbox-and-special-olympics-hold-first-gaming-for-inclusion-esports-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 20:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disabilities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special olympics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xbox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gaming in general is moving toward accessibility, but that&#8217;s not as much the case in esports, which like other sports are competitive and by nature somewhat exclusive. Xbox and the Special Olympics are working together on a new event that combines competition with inclusion, and it&#8217;s going on right now. This week, Special Olympics athletes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Gaming in general is moving toward accessibility, but that&#8217;s not as much the case in esports, which like other sports are competitive and by nature somewhat exclusive. Xbox and the Special Olympics are working together on a new event that combines competition with inclusion, and it&#8217;s going on right now.</p>
<p>This week, Special Olympics athletes will be competing against each other in tournaments of <em>Rocket League</em>, <em>Madden NFL 22</em> and <em>Forza Motorsport 7.</em> The prize, other than prestige and pride, is playing with one of the Special Olympics&#8217; celebrity supporters: &#8220;NBA superstar Jayson Tatum, NFL legend Jamaal Charles, and WNBA superstar Jewell Loyd, and WWE Superstars Dominik Mysterio and Ember Moon.&#8221; So many superstars!</p>
<p>&#8220;This tournament is a meaningful and important step in making esports more accessible and it empowers Special Olympics athletes with a new way to compete,&#8221; said Jenn Panattoni, head of Xbox Social Impact. &#8220;Xbox has invested in numerous accessibility features and products, like the Xbox Adaptive Controller and features like copilot or speech to text. The purpose of all this continued work is to ensure that players feel welcome and that they belong on the Xbox platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>The tournaments are being recorded right now, and will be broadcast over the rest of the week, along with the &#8220;celebrity showcase&#8221; coming Saturday with recaps. You can check out a schedule at the bottom of <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/08/10/xbox-and-the-special-olympics-gaming-for-inclusion-event/">this post</a>, but generally just keep an eye on the <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/XBOX">Xbox Twitch channel</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbgL_cannhXClCH6OKNpbJg">Special Olympics YouTube channel</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k5wGYhLDfP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/microsoft-offers-new-accessibility-testing-service-for-pc-and-xbox-games/">Microsoft offers new accessibility testing service for PC and Xbox games</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft offers new accessibility testing service for PC and Xbox games&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/microsoft-offers-new-accessibility-testing-service-for-pc-and-xbox-games/embed/#?secret=k5wGYhLDfP" data-secret="k5wGYhLDfP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>I like to highlight these events because accessibility has been on the back burner for so long in the gaming world, and now we&#8217;re seeing big moves by developers, publishers and partners to make things better. Microsoft&#8217;s XAC is a great example, as is the panoply of visual, audio and difficulty options in the latest Ratchet &amp; Clank game. Esports is definitely one of the areas that needs more diversity, though, and the participating players were glad to take part. I asked Special Olympics athletes Jose Moreno and Colton Rice for their thoughts on the matter.</p>
<p><strong>Do you think competitive gaming is getting more accessible?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rice</strong>: Competitive gaming is definitely getting more accessible. Not only are the games becoming more accessible, accessibility allows people with disabilities to become more competitive players. People with intellectual disabilities are always trying to compete at their best. We want to do what everyone else is doing, and sometimes just need a little help to make that happen.</p>
<p><strong>Moreno</strong>: I do think that competitive gaming is getting more accessible because Microsoft has started bringing out video game controllers that are accessible for people with intellectual disabilities, physical disabilities &#8212; accessible to everybody. I’m a lifelong gamer, and accessibility in esports has been game-changing. Accessible gaming wasn’t available when I was growing up. Today, it’s so much more fun to play when you can play with friends of all abilities and everybody can participate.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202634" style="width: 877px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202634" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2202634" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg" alt="" width="867" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg 867w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg?resize=300,141 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg?resize=768,361 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg?resize=680,320 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/rice-moreno.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 867px) 100vw, 867px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2202634" class="wp-caption-text">Special Olympics athletes Colton Rice, left, and Jose Moreno. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Special Olympics</p></div></p>
<p><strong>How are you experiencing that change?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Moreno</strong>: In my opinion, the more the video games industry include people with intellectual disabilities, the better the video game community is going to get to know how we love playing video games just like everybody else. And through events like Gaming for Inclusion, I’m not just able to compete &#8212; I’m included as a part of a community of gamers where I am welcomed and included.</p>
<p><strong>Rice</strong>: People with intellectual disabilities have skills and pay attention to details; when we set our minds to do something, we practice until we are the best we can be, especially when we enjoy doing it &#8212; and that includes gaming. People with disabilities just need more time to learn, but when you’re dedicated to something that you’re passionate about, you won’t stop until you succeed.</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s something you&#8217;d like to see more of, from developers, publishers, etc.?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Moreno</strong>: I would like to see more from developers or makers or publishers of video games in general or computer games to include more people with intellectual disabilities in the video game workforce. People with intellectual disabilities can play a variety of roles and provide unique perspectives on how to improve the gaming experience. Publishers and developers can get a different perspective from people with disabilities; whether that’s featuring people with intellectual disabilities represented in their storylines or seeing them in the games themselves. We’re eager to be a part of this process, and there are lots of passionate gamers with intellectual disabilities who would like to participate in focus groups or in actual jobs as creators within the industry.</p>
<p><strong>Rice</strong>: The companies who make these games are trying to make high-quality games that are enjoyable for everybody. There is still a lot that can be done to make games more accessible. For example, it can be frustrating when gamers with intellectual disabilities are learning a new game with instructions that are hard to read. It can take hours to learn how to play the new version of a game you’ve played for years. That doesn’t mean people with intellectual disabilities aren’t capable of playing or competing &#8212; it just means we need better accessibility tools to help us learn.</p>
<p>If gaming companies want to create accessible, inclusive games, they could benefit from including gamers with intellectual disabilities in the creative process to help make or test &#8220;easy read&#8221; or beginner’s instructions, or find ways to simplify navigation between different levels of a game. Gaming can build a community and reach people who feel left out. Accessibility allows everybody to have fun.</p>
<hr />
<p>This competition and other events in online gaming have been essential to keeping the Special Olympics community connected and active over a difficult couple years.</p>
<p>&#8220;Special Olympics has a long-standing partnership with Microsoft that has been incredibly valuable for the athletes and families of the Special Olympics movement,&#8221; said the organization&#8217;s chief information and technology officer, Prianka Nandy. &#8220;With the COVID-19 pandemic, our main concern has been the safety and health of our athletes, who are amongst the most vulnerable population to have an adverse or catastrophic outcome from the virus. This led to the cancellation and postponement of thousands of annual in-person events and competitions &#8212; which meant our athletes have missed out on the connections and opportunities to experience the joy of being with their teammates, coaches and friends. At this time, our goals remain to raise awareness of the Special Olympics movement and the accomplishments, hopes and dreams of our incredible athletes, and to change attitudes towards people with intellectual disabilities within the gaming community, all while remembering that gaming can be fun and inclusive for all.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/xbox-and-special-olympics-hold-first-gaming-for-inclusion-esports-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple brings macro, low-light and cinema-focused updates to the iPhone 13 Pro camera</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-brings-macro-low-light-and-cinema-focused-updates-to-the-iphone-13-pro-camera/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-brings-macro-low-light-and-cinema-focused-updates-to-the-iphone-13-pro-camera/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple fall event 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone 13]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 13 Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple continues its tradition of improving the photography capabilities of consumer devices with today&#8217;s announcement of the iPhone 13 and 13 Pro, available on September 24. Last year&#8217;s iPhone 12 had two rear camera lenses, while the iPhone 12 Pro had three; the iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 Pro follow suit. The iPhone 13 features [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple continues its tradition of improving the photography capabilities of consumer devices with today&#8217;s announcement of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/this-is-the-iphone-13/">iPhone 13 and 13 Pro</a>, available on September 24.</p>
<p>Last year&#8217;s<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/20/review-iphone-12-and-iphone-12-pro-two-gems-one-jewel/"> iPhone 12</a> had two rear camera lenses, while the iPhone 12 Pro had three; the iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 Pro follow suit. The iPhone 13 features a wide (f/1.6 aperture) and an ultra-wide (f/2.4 aperture) lens, which are the same specs as the iPhone 12. But the iPhone 13 Pro unveils an entirely new camera system.</p>
<p>Compared to the iPhone 12 Pro, the iPhone 13 Pro improves low-light performance by allowing for apertures as wide as f/1.5 on the main lens, compared to f/1.6 on the previous model. The ultra-wide lens follows the same trend, boasting f/1.8, improved from f/2.4 on the iPhone 12 Pro. These wide apertures should collect more light in darker settings like bars and concerts, hopefully leading to improved image quality. Apple claims that the ultra-wide lens will have &#8220;up to 92% improvement in low light,&#8221; but&#8230; we&#8217;ll just have to test that ourselves.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202611" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202611" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2202611" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="379" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg 2974w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?resize=768,428 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?resize=680,379 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?resize=1536,855 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?resize=2048,1140 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/cameras-iphone-13-pro.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202611" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Perhaps the most notable lens upgrade is the improvement to the telephoto lens. Though this lens has a smaller aperture than its predecessor (f/2.8 compared to f/2.0), the new telephoto lens is 77mm-equivalent, while the iPhone 12 Pro&#8217;s telephoto was 52mm. This allows users to zoom closer in on far-away scenes without sacrificing image quality. The telephoto lens also now supports night mode, which it didn&#8217;t previously.</p>
<p>Apple also announced Macro mode, which will be available on the iPhone 13 Pro. The ultra wide lens and autofocus system work together to magnify subjects as close as two centimeters away. These shots are challenging to pull off even on professional, non-phone cameras. Users can also record video and even slow-mo at this scale, which should open up some interesting options.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202623" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202623" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2202623" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="381" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png 2042w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png?resize=1536,861 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.46.48-PM.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202623" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Apple also announced Photographic Styles and Cinematic Mode, new features available on both the iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 Pro.</p>
<p>Photographic Styles applies local edits to an image in real time as the photo is rendered, so photographers can compose their shots using one of four presets and see what their end product will look like before they click the shutter button. Of course, even point-and-shoots have had real-time filters for a decade, but Apple claims these Photographic Styles are more technologically sophisticated than those, using machine learning to understand how to intelligently apply edits without compromising a subject&#8217;s skin tone.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202631" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202631" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2202631" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png 2044w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-14-at-2.53.13-PM.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202631" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Cinematic Mode allows users to shoot video, but then change the background blur and virtual focus of the clip later. This feature seems more catered toward professional filmmakers &#8212; Apple brought in Kathryn Bigelow and Greig Fraizer to demonstrate the functionality. Still, Canon and Nikon need not worry &#8212; there will always be advantages of a camera that&#8217;s a camera, as opposed to a camera that&#8217;s a phone &#8212; but hey, it&#8217;s not as though smartphone films have never <a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2017/12/iphone-sean-baker-tangerine-academy-museum-oscars-1201908946/">made a splash in the Academy</a>.</p>
<p>The iPhone 13 will start at $799 (which, for the record, is more expensive than an entry-level DSLR camera and a decent lens). The iPhone 13 Pro &#8212; telephoto lens, macro photography and all &#8212; starts at $999.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-fall-event-2021-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about Apple's Fall 2021 Event on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-brings-macro-low-light-and-cinema-focused-updates-to-the-iphone-13-pro-camera/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202524</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spaceflight will be ferrying payloads from Orbit Fab, GeoJump to lunar orbit next year</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spaceflight-will-be-ferrying-payloads-from-orbit-fab-geojump-to-lunar-orbit-next-year/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spaceflight-will-be-ferrying-payloads-from-orbit-fab-geojump-to-lunar-orbit-next-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geojump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orbit Fab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Space rideshare service provider Spaceflight Inc. is going to be shuttling customers on a lunar flyby mission next year, part of its long-term vision of giving companies easy access to lunar orbits and beyond. The Seattle-based company will be delivering payload using its propulsive transfer vehicle, Sherpa EScape, or Sherpa-ES, the latest iteration of Sherpa [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Space rideshare service provider Spaceflight Inc. is going to be shuttling customers on a lunar flyby mission next year, part of its long-term vision of giving companies easy access to lunar orbits and beyond.</p>
<p>The Seattle-based company will be delivering payload using its propulsive transfer vehicle, Sherpa EScape, or Sherpa-ES, the latest iteration of Sherpa vehicles that the company has been testing for the past few years. The Sherpa essentially acts as last-mile space transportation, deploying payload to customers&#8217; desired orbits after reaching outer space.</p>
<p>Spaceflight’s electric propulsive Sherpa-LTE flew on the SpaceX <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/spacex-delivers-88-satellites-to-orbit-lands-first-stage-onshore-for-first-time-in-2021/">Transporter-2 mission</a> in June, while Sherpa-LTC with chemical propulsion will launch later this year on Transporter-3. The company has successfully deployed 50 customer spacecraft to date.</p>
<p>The Sherpa-ES will be delivering payloads for in-orbit refueling company Orbit Fab, which just closed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/aerospace-primes-northrup-lockheed-join-in-orbit-fabs-over-10m-funding-round/">$10 million</a> in funding from two major aerospace primes, and new company GeoJump. It looks like GeoJump is also looking to get into the ridesharing business; its website bills it as <a href="https://geojump.space/">offering</a> “a new route to [geostationary orbit]” for small satellites. The mission will launch aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202655" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202655" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2202655" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png" alt="" width="1024" height="1325" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png 2550w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png?resize=768,994 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png?resize=525,680 525w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png?resize=1187,1536 1187w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png?resize=1583,2048 1583w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IM-2_Full_stack.png?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202655" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://spaceflight.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spaceflight <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The rideshare is part of a robotic lunar landing mission being undertaken by Intuitive Machines, one of a handful of companies selected by NASA to be part of its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/23/nasa-reveals-the-payloads-for-the-first-commercial-moon-cargo-deliveries/">Commercial Lunar Payload Services Program</a>. Intuitive Machines will be sending its nearly 2,000-kilogram Nova-C lander to the lunar surface for a 14-day mission. The IM-1 lander will ferry around 130 kilograms of cargo.</p>
<p>Intuitive Machines also tapped SpaceX for its second lander mission, also for 2022. The company says this will be the first object to land at the moon’s south pole, and the first object to drill on lunar ice.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e5wf5s8ccB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/aerospace-primes-northrup-lockheed-join-in-orbit-fabs-over-10m-funding-round/">Aerospace primes Northrop, Lockheed join in Orbit Fab’s over $10M funding round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aerospace primes Northrop, Lockheed join in Orbit Fab’s over $10M funding round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/aerospace-primes-northrup-lockheed-join-in-orbit-fabs-over-10m-funding-round/embed/#?secret=e5wf5s8ccB" data-secret="e5wf5s8ccB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/spaceflight-will-be-ferrying-payloads-from-orbit-fab-geojump-to-lunar-orbit-next-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canva raises $200 million at a $40 billion valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/canva-raises-200-million-at-a-40-billion-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/canva-raises-200-million-at-a-40-billion-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[melanie perkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t.rowe price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Canva is now valued at $40 billion following a fresh capital injection of $200 million (USD) in a round led by T. Rowe Price. New and existing investors participated in the round, including Franklin Templeton, Sequoia Capital Global Equities, Bessemer Venture Partners, Greenoaks Capital, Dragoneer Investments, Blackbird, Felicis and AirTree Ventures. This round solidifies Canva [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.canva.com/">Canva</a> is now valued at $40 billion following a fresh capital injection of $200 million (USD) in a round led by T. Rowe Price. New and existing investors participated in the round, including Franklin Templeton, Sequoia Capital Global Equities, Bessemer Venture Partners, Greenoaks Capital, Dragoneer Investments, Blackbird, Felicis and AirTree Ventures.</p>
<p>This round solidifies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/canva/">Canva</a> as one of the most valuable private software companies out there, and it also propels the Australian tech scene forward.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO Melanie Perkins and her team started working on Canva in 2012, and launched the product in 2013. The premise behind it was relatively simple, but the technology itself&#8230; not so much.</p>
<p>Canva allows anyone to design. Presentations, t-shirts, brochures, flyers&#8230; you name it. The first step in this is creating a truly simple user interface, where folks can simply drag and drop components into their designs, complete with hundreds of thousands of templates, without doing a lot of fine tuning. The second step is creating a massive library of content, from fonts to templates to imagery, gifs and videos. The third step is to make that product accessible to everyone, whether it&#8217;s a platform or device or language or price.</p>
<p>Going after everyone, instead of just designers, has proved incredibly fruitful for the company. To be clear, designers still use Canva to lay out components they&#8217;ve designed in other products, such as Figma and Sketch, and Canva actually plays nicely with a variety of design software products. But Canva has no intention of going head to head with Figma, Adobe or Sketch.</p>
<p>Perkins described it with the example of a business card. Designers will create the components of a business card in their design platform of choice, and then lay out the template for business cards in Canva, sharing that template with the entire organization. That way, when someone gets a title change or a new employee comes on, they can actually edit the card themselves without the help of a designer and send it to print.</p>
<p>TechCrunch asked Perkins why Canva hasn&#8217;t extended the platform more aggressively into the workflow of professional designers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We would like to replace PDF,&#8221; said Perkins. &#8220;Rather than people sending PDFs backwards and forwards between the designer and the client, designers can just create a template for organization use. It&#8217;s less important for us to absolutely excel at things like vector design because there are amazing programs on the market that may be there. We really want to focus on that collaboration piece.&#8221;</p>
<p>Though a bottoms-up enterprise strategy is relatively popular these days, Canva was an early master of the model. Canva launched as a free product, and over time the company introduced enterprise layers into the mix.</p>
<p>As of now, Canva has more than 60 million monthly active users across 190 countries, with big-name companies on the enterprise plan. This includes Salesforce, Marriott International, PayPal and American Airlines. Canva expects to exceed $1 billion in annualized revenue by the end of 2021. More than 500,000 teams are paying for the product in some capacity.</p>
<p>With a 2,000-person team, Canva will use the fresh funding to double its workforce in the next year.</p>
<p>Canva also shared its DEI numbers, with females representing 42% of the workforce. The company did not share any stats around people of color on the team.</p>
<p>Perkins explained to TechCrunch that a huge part of the company&#8217;s growth has to do with an obsession over creating a highly valuable free product.</p>
<p>&#8220;We intentionally make our free product extremely generous for a number of reasons,&#8221; said Perkins. &#8220;It&#8217;s critical both for our marketing and towards our mission of empowering people to design. But, as part of our marketing, it means that people are able to love the product, share it with their friends and family, and promote it on social media. And then that virality really rapidly fuels our growth.&#8221;</p>
<p>Alongside growing the team, Canva also has plans to further build out the product in the next year, launching website design soon. This will allow users to turn existing and new presentations and designs into a website, and even search for and buy a domain for that site.</p>
<p>Canva is also working on a new video editor and an offline mode.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ulDy54yxGQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/canva-ceo-melanie-perkins-will-tell-us-about-the-journey-to-a-15b-valuation-at-disrupt/">Canva CEO Melanie Perkins will tell us about the journey to a $15B valuation at Disrupt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Canva CEO Melanie Perkins will tell us about the journey to a $15B valuation at Disrupt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/27/canva-ceo-melanie-perkins-will-tell-us-about-the-journey-to-a-15b-valuation-at-disrupt/embed/#?secret=ulDy54yxGQ" data-secret="ulDy54yxGQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Perkins says that Canva has two goals, and that each fuels the other. The first is to become one of the world&#8217;s most valuable companies, and the other is to do the most good that it can do.</p>
<p>The company has already joined the 1% pledge and has several efforts around being a force for good, including giving the premium product to more than 130,000 nonprofits, allocating more than 45,000 volunteering hours each year and launching Print One, Plant One, which is a project that plants a tree for every single print order placed through Canva.</p>
<p>With today&#8217;s funding announcement, cofounders Perkins and Cliff Obrecht are committing the vast majority of their own equity in the company (around 30%) to doing good in the world, with plans to do this through the Canva Foundation.</p>
<p>Perkins will be joining us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=rightrail">Disrupt</a> to talk about the new funding, valuation, what&#8217;s in store for Canva, and share her broader thoughts on design as a category.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/canva-raises-200-million-at-a-40-billion-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202278</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple sheds value during iPhone event</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-sheds-value-during-iphone-event/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-sheds-value-during-iphone-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 18:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet computers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The TechCrunch crew is hard at work writing up the latest from Apple&#8217;s iPhone, iPad and Apple Watch event. They have good notes on the megacorp&#8217;s hardware updates. But what are the markets saying about the same array of products? For those of us more concerned with effective S&#38;P dividend yields than screen nit levels, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The TechCrunch crew is hard at work writing up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021/">the latest</a> from Apple&#8217;s iPhone, iPad and Apple Watch event. They have good notes on the megacorp&#8217;s hardware updates. But what are the markets saying about the same array of products?</p>
<p>For those of us more concerned with effective S&amp;P dividend yields than screen nit levels, events like Apple&#8217;s confab are more interesting for what they might mean for the value of the hosting company than how many GPUs a particular smartphone model has. And, for once, Apple&#8217;s stock may have done something a little interesting during the event!</p>
<p>Observe the following chart:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202582" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202582" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2202582 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png" alt="" width="2000" height="1291" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png?resize=300,194 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png?resize=768,496 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png?resize=680,439 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png?resize=1536,991 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AAPL_^SPXTR_^IXIC_chart.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202582" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch/Y Charts</p></div></p>
<p>This is a one-day chart, mind, so we&#8217;re looking at intraday changes. We&#8217;re zoomed in. And Apple kinda took a bit of a dive during its event that kicked off at 1 p.m. in the above chart.</p>
<p>Normally <em>nothing</em> of import happens to Apple&#8217;s shares during its presentations. Which feels weird, frankly, as Apple events detail the product mix that will generate hundreds of billions in revenue. You&#8217;d think that they would have more impact than their usual zero.</p>
<p>But today, we had real share price movement when the event wrapped around 2 p.m. ET. Perhaps investors were hoping for more pricey devices? Or were hoping Apple had more up its sleeve? How you rate that holiday Apple product lineup is a matter of personal preference, but investors appear to have weighed in slightly to the negative.</p>
<p>Worth around $2.5 trillion, each 1% that Apple&#8217;s stock moves is worth $10 billion. Apple&#8217;s loss of 1.5% today &#8212; more or less; trading continues as I write this &#8212; is worth more than Mailchimp. It&#8217;s a lot of money.</p>
<p>You can read the rest of our coverage from the Apple event <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021/">here. </a>Enjoy!</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-fall-event-2021-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about Apple's Fall 2021 Event on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-sheds-value-during-iphone-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202425</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden&#8217;s new FTC nominee is a digital privacy advocate critical of Big Tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/alvaro-bedoya-ftc-biden/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/alvaro-bedoya-ftc-biden/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 18:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biometrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lina Khan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden made his latest nomination to the Federal Trade Commission this week, tapping digital privacy expert Alvaro Bedoya to join the agency as it takes a hard look at the tech industry. Bedoya is the founding director of the Center on Privacy &#38; Technology at Georgetown&#8217;s law school and previously served as chief counsel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">President Biden made his latest nomination to the Federal Trade Commission this week, tapping digital privacy expert Alvaro Bedoya to join the agency as it takes a hard look at the tech industry.</p>
<p>Bedoya is the founding director of the <a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/privacy-technology-center/">Center on Privacy &amp; Technology</a> at Georgetown&#8217;s law school and previously served as chief counsel for former Senator Al Franken and the Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on Privacy, Technology and the Law. Bedoya has worked on legislation addressing some of the most pressing privacy issues in tech, including stalkerware and facial recognition systems.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">It is the honor of my life to be nominated to serve on the FTC. When my family landed at JFK in 1987 with 4 suitcases and a grad student stipend, this was not what we expected. Thank you <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@JoeBiden</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/linakhanFTC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@linakhanFTC</a>, thank you Sima, my love, mom, dad, Pablo, our families. Vamos.</p>
<p>&mdash; Alvaro Bedoya (@alvarombedoya) <a href="https://twitter.com/alvarombedoya/status/1437509709251190797?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In 2016, Bedoya co-authored a report titled &#8220;<a href="https://www.perpetuallineup.org/">The Perpetual Line-Up: Unregulated Police Face Recognition in America</a>,&#8221; a year-long investigation that dove deeply into the police use of facial recognition systems in the U.S. The 2016 report examined law enforcement&#8217;s reliance on facial recognition systems and biometric databases on a state level. It argued that regulations are desperately needed to curtail potential abuses and algorithmic failures before the technology inevitably becomes even more commonplace.</p>
<p>Bedoya also isn&#8217;t shy about calling out Big Tech. In a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/11/opinion/silicon-valley-lobbyists-privacy.html">New York Times op-ed a few years ago</a>, he took aim at Silicon Valley companies giving user privacy lip service in public while quietly funneling millions toward lobbyists to undermine consumer privacy. The new FTC nominee singled out Facebook specifically, pointing to the company&#8217;s efforts to undermine the Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act, a state law that serves as one of the only meaningful checks on invasive privacy practices in the U.S.</p>
<p>Bedoya argued that the tech industry would have an easier time shaping a single, sweeping piece of privacy regulation with its lobbying efforts rather than a flurry of targeted, smaller bills. Antitrust advocates in Congress taking aim at tech today seem<a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/06/09/house-democrats-announce-tech-bills-492703"> to have learned that same lesson as well</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We cannot underestimate the tech sector’s power in Congress and in state legislatures,&#8221; Bedoya wrote. &#8220;If the United States tries to pass broad rules for personal data, that effort may well be co-opted by Silicon Valley, and we’ll miss our best shot at meaningful privacy protections.&#8221;</p>
<p>If confirmed, Bedoya would join <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lina-khan-ftc-confirmed/">Big Tech critic Lina Khan</a>, a recent Biden FTC nominee who now chairs the agency. Khan&#8217;s focus on antitrust and Amazon in particular would dovetail with Bedoya&#8217;s focus on adjacent privacy concerns, making the pair a formidable regulatory presence as the Biden administration seeks to rein in some of the tech industry&#8217;s most damaging excesses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9cCEgLdwWJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lina-khan-ftc-confirmed/">Biden elevates tech antitrust crusader Lina Khan to FTC chair</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Biden elevates tech antitrust crusader Lina Khan to FTC chair&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lina-khan-ftc-confirmed/embed/#?secret=9cCEgLdwWJ" data-secret="9cCEgLdwWJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="etLi5VOgYZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/facial-recognition-ban-portland-oregon/">Portland passes expansive city ban on facial recognition tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Portland passes expansive city ban on facial recognition tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/facial-recognition-ban-portland-oregon/embed/#?secret=etLi5VOgYZ" data-secret="etLi5VOgYZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RWpmcvhPyK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/maines-facial-recognition-law-shows-bipartisan-support-for-protecting-privacy/">Maine’s facial recognition law shows bipartisan support for protecting privacy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Maine’s facial recognition law shows bipartisan support for protecting privacy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/maines-facial-recognition-law-shows-bipartisan-support-for-protecting-privacy/embed/#?secret=RWpmcvhPyK" data-secret="RWpmcvhPyK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/alvaro-bedoya-ftc-biden/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202446</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here&#8217;s everything Apple announced at its event this morning</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-its-event-this-morning/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-its-event-this-morning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 18:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s that time again! It&#8217;s September, which generally means two things: We&#8217;re blasting Earth, Wind, and Fire on repeat, and Apple will announce a new iPhone (or four). Right on schedule, Apple held a remote event this morning, streaming kinda-sorta-live from its Cupertino campus. Whether you didn&#8217;t have time to watch the entire hour-long stream [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s that time again!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s September, which generally means two things: We&#8217;re blasting Earth, Wind, and Fire on repeat, and Apple will announce a new iPhone (or four).</p>
<p>Right on schedule, Apple held a remote event this morning, streaming kinda-sorta-live from its Cupertino campus. Whether you didn&#8217;t have time to watch the entire hour-long stream or just want the highlights, we&#8217;ve got you — as usual, we&#8217;ve boiled the whole thing down to the bullet points.</p>
<h2>New iPads</h2>
<p>Both the standard iPad and the iPad mini have gotten the update treatment — here&#8217;s whats new for each:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202383" style="width: 1690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202383" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2202383 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg" alt="" width="1680" height="945" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg 1680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-new-ipad-price.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1680px) 100vw, 1680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202383" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-updates-the-entry-level-329-ipad/">New iPad</a>:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Runs the A13 Bionic chip, which Apple first introduced in 2019 with the iPhone 11. Apple says it&#8217;s 20% faster across the board compared to the last gen.</li>
<li>The front-facing camera has been bumped from 8 megapixels up to a 12 megapixel ultrawide lens.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s getting Center Stage, the feature that debuted on the iPad Pro and automatically reframes front-facing video to keep your face centered as you move around a room.</li>
<li>Starts at $329 (or $299 for schools). Orders start today, shipping next week.
<p><div id="attachment_2202387" style="width: 1690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202387" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2202387 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg" alt="" width="1680" height="945" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg 1680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ipad-mini-2021-a.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1680px) 100vw, 1680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202387" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-refreshes-ipad-mini-with-a-new-design-5g-and-an-8-3-inch-display/">New iPad mini</a>:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Redesigned with slimmer borders and rounder edges.</li>
<li>The display has been bumped up to 8.3&#8243; (from 7.9&#8243;) while keeping the overall device size the same.</li>
<li>The CPU is 40% faster, while the GPU is 80% faster.</li>
<li>USB-C!</li>
<li>There will be a 5G model.</li>
<li>The back camera has a much-improved 12 MP camera with True Tone flash, and, as with the standard iPad, the front camera is getting 12 MP ultrawide lens and Center Stage support.</li>
<li>It&#8217;ll support the second-gen Apple Pencil.</li>
<li>Starts at $499. Orders start today, shipping next week.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Apple Watch</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2202438" style="width: 1690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202438" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2202438 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg" alt="" width="1680" height="945" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg 1680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-watch-series-7-overview.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1680px) 100vw, 1680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202438" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>Apple</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Apple kicked off the Watch segment with a few new features coming to iOS 8 (like fall detection for cyclists and better algorithms for detecting calories burned when you&#8217;re on an e-bike) before announcing a new Watch — Series 7, they&#8217;re calling it.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-watch-series-7-arrives-with-a-larger-more-rugged-display/">Apple Watch Series 7</a>:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>By reducing the screen&#8217;s borders, they were able to squeeze in a display that is 20% bigger.</li>
<li>To take advantage of that bigger screen, buttons are bigger across the UI.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s got a swipe-style prediction keyboard, for easier text input on the go.</li>
<li>Apple says it&#8217;s got the strongest (most crack-resistant) display to dat, and is the first Apple Watch to be IP6X certified against dust.</li>
<li>An &#8220;updated charging architecture&#8221; and a new USB-C charger allow it to charge 33% faster.</li>
<li>Series 7 will start at $399 and start shipping &#8220;later this fall.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<h2>New iPhones</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2202557" style="width: 1230px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202557" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2202557 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/new-iphones.jpg" alt="" width="1220" height="679" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/new-iphones.jpg 1220w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/new-iphones.jpg?resize=150,83 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/new-iphones.jpg?resize=300,167 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/new-iphones.jpg?resize=768,427 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/new-iphones.jpg?resize=680,378 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/new-iphones.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1220px) 100vw, 1220px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202557" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Not one, not two, but <em>four</em> new iPhones — iPhone 13, iPhone 13 mini, iPhone 13 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro max. Faster chips, better cameras, better battery life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2202470 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg" alt="" width="1680" height="945" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg 1680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-2021-iphone-13-angle.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1680px) 100vw, 1680px" /></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/this-is-the-iphone-13/">iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 mini</a>:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Both run Apple&#8217;s new A15 Bionic chip. It&#8217;s got a six-core CPU (two high-performance cores, four high efficiency), a four-core GPU and big improvements to the neural engine that Apple taps for on-device machine learning.</li>
<li>A &#8220;ceramic shield front,&#8221; which Apple says is tougher than any other smartphone&#8217;s glass.</li>
<li>IP68 water resistance.</li>
<li>28% brighter display.</li>
<li>iPhone 13 comes in at 6.1&#8243;, while iPhone 13 mini will be 5.4&#8243;.</li>
<li>A wild new &#8220;Cinematic&#8221; mode that uses machine learning for tricks like auto-shifting the camera&#8217;s focus when one on-screen speaker looks at someone behind them.</li>
<li>The 64 GB model has finally been retired, with the base models coming with 128 GB of storage.</li>
<li>Apple says the iPhone 13 mini&#8217;s battery life has been improved by an hour and a half, while most iPhone 13 users will get two and half more hours per charge.</li>
<li>iPhone 13 will start at $799, while iPhone 13 mini starts at $699.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/the-iphone-13-pro-and-pro-max-features-120hz-display-better-cameras/">iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max</a>:</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2202587" style="width: 1004px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2202587" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2202587 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/iPhone-Pro.jpg" alt="" width="994" height="556" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/iPhone-Pro.jpg 994w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/iPhone-Pro.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/iPhone-Pro.jpg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/iPhone-Pro.jpg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/iPhone-Pro.jpg?resize=680,380 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/iPhone-Pro.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 994px) 100vw, 994px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2202587" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s getting that new &#8220;ceramic shield front,&#8221; along with an upgrade to A15, here with a five-core GPU.</li>
<li>As rumored, it&#8217;ll get a display that can adjust its refresh rate up to 120 hz for super smooth movement/scrolling.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s got three cameras on the back: a telephoto lens with 3x optical zoom, an ultrawide and a wide angle. Night Mode will now play friendly with all three cameras (including the telephoto lens, which previously didn&#8217;t support it).</li>
<li>It&#8217;ll come in two sizes: 6.1&#8243; (Pro) and 6.7&#8243; (Pro Max).</li>
<li>For those who just can&#8217;t seem to get enough storage space, they&#8217;re introducing 1 TB models!</li>
<li>Pro starts at $999, Pro Max starts at $1099. Pre-orders start September 17, shipping September 24.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Other stuff</h2>
<ul>
<li>iOS 15 will ship <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/iphone-users-will-receive-ios-15-update-on-september-20/">Monday, September 20th.</a></li>
<li>Apple&#8217;s Fitness Plus service is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-adds-fitness-updates-including-a-group-workout-feature/">rolling out in 15 new countries</a>, including Austria, Brazil, Colombia, France, Germany, Mexico and Russia. Workouts will be in English and subtitled in six languages. They&#8217;re also launching group workouts, which can be launched from iMessage or FaceTime and will let you multitask your hangouts and your workouts.</li>
<li>Apple&#8217;s MagSafe wallet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apples-new-magsafe-wallet-can-be-located-with-the-find-my-app-if-it-goes-missing/">will now be able to display its last known location</a> via the Find My app if the wallet gets separated from the phone.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-fall-event-2021-banner.jpg" alt="Read more about Apple's Fall 2021 Event on TechCrunch" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/heres-everything-apple-announced-at-its-event-this-morning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202536</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
