<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:47:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Darryl Finkton Jr. closes $200M to go from asset management to poverty eradication</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/darryl-finkton-jr-closes-200m-to-go-from-asset-management-to-poverty-eradication/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/darryl-finkton-jr-closes-200m-to-go-from-asset-management-to-poverty-eradication/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Darryl Finkton Jr. is a man on a mission. He believes there’s enough money in the world to help put an end to poverty. But only if it’s distributed differently than it is today. Earlier this year, the investor left a career in asset management to launch a $1 billion venture fund aimed at eradicating [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Darryl Finkton Jr. is a man on a mission.</p>
<p dir="ltr">He believes there’s enough money in the world to help put an end to poverty. But only if it’s distributed differently than it is today.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Earlier this year, the investor left a career in asset management to launch a $1 billion venture fund aimed at eradicating poverty. It’s an ambitious goal, but Finkton Jr. has a plan. And now he’s raised $200 million as an initial close to help execute that plan.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">Finkton aims to raise $1 billion with the fund to provide venture capital to entrepreneurs from disadvantaged and underrepresented backgrounds who are working to solve the pressing problems facing their communities. He is managing the fund, and has invested $500,000 of his own capital to launch it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Finkton grew up in housing projects in Indianapolis, Indiana, and went to Harvard to study neurobiology. He then attended Oxford as a Rhodes Scholar and got involved in economic development before founding a VC firm focused on health tech investments. Most recently, Finkton worked as a partner at a hedge fund.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But his upbringing was never far from his mind, and Finkton knew that he wanted to do more to help people who didn’t have the same opportunities or access as others.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“In my household, we often struggled to make ends meet and put food on the table. More family members than I care to count have died from the dire circumstances that extreme poverty creates,” Finkton recalls. “Although I was able to overcome obstacles and ultimately graduated from both Harvard and Oxford, I remain intimately aware of the countless difficulties one faces when your next meal is not promised.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">So earlier this year, he left his job as a hedge fund partner to promote the adoption of a universal basic income to end poverty in the U.S. with the help of venture dollars via his EPMT (End Poverty, Make Trillions) fund.</p>
<p dir="ltr">All fund profits will be reinvested into helping the country’s poorest communities, he said.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This summer, he plans to lead a 60-day tour of several dozen cities, towns and Native American reservations with “the poorest zip codes in America” with the goal of drumming up support for a universal basic income at the federal poverty guidelines (<a href="https://www.endpovertymaketrillions.com/">UBI@FPG</a>).  (He also intends to create a <a href="https://youtu.be/-6IUAiV4F6o">documentary</a> of the process).</p>
<p dir="ltr">In addition to supporting state and local efforts, Finkton is also pushing for federal legislation guaranteeing a universal basic income at or above the federal poverty guidelines.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So far, the EPMT fund has invested in 15 companies including <a href="https://www.elpidatec.com/">Elpidatec</a>, a telehealth platform aimed at treating opioid addiction; <a href="https://www.commissary.club/">Commissary Club</a>, a job site and social network for people with criminal records; <a href="http://www.snowballwealth.com/">Snowball Wealth</a>, which offers free student loan planning to help people tackle debt and <a href="https://maials.com/">Maia Life Sciences</a>, which is working to develop evidence-based, culturally-informed group interventions for underrepresented and vulnerable populations.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Finkton believes that the U.S. is spending “trillions” on perpetuating the poverty cycle through various programs such as welfare. Instead, he wants to empower people in poverty to work their way out.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“These programs treat the symptoms of poverty, not the root cause &#8212; which is not having money,” he told TechCrunch.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Finkton maintains that a universal basic income at the federal poverty guidelines (UBI@FPG) can end financial poverty.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“The economic costs of childhood poverty alone are $1 trillion a year. If we provide UBI@FPG to every American and simply tax back that income for those already well above the federal poverty guideline, the net cost for eradicating poverty drops to below $200 billion,” Finkton maintains. “That is an annual return of $800 billion. Over 10 years, UBI@FPG would generate a return of over $8 trillion, save 1.7 Million lives, and lift 34 million Americans out of poverty.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">There are some who may argue that that lower-income populations will just use any money they get to buy drugs or alcohol.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Finkton believes it’s the opposite.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“We’ve done a lot of pilots and when someone is so poor, they can’t afford food, clothing or shelter, that’s the first thing they do, when they get money,” he told TechCrunch. “These communities often use drugs as a way to cope,” he said. “Once you give them hope and opportunity, they’re not as depressed and there’s actually less alcohol, drug and tobacco use.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Chad Doe, founder and CEO of EPMT portfolio company Maia Life Sciences, tells TechCrunch that his biotech startup aims to initially investigate the potential of psychedelics to help people with substance abuse issues via facilitated group clinical trials. The ultimate goal of the three-year-old Los Angeles-based company is to receive FDA approval so that people with addictions, globally, can have more options. Those clinical trials, he said, will be conducted by mostly women of color and include participants that are not mostly white or of European descent.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In many cases, he said, trial participants and investigators “are not representative of the real world.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Doe also believes that more money is spent on surveillance, policing, and punishment tactics that disproportionately target and impact people of color, low-income people, and non-citizens rather than toward actually helping them emerge from their situations.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“The War on Drugs is really a war on the poor,” he said. “At Maia, we&#8217;re placing women and underserved populations at the center of the research and development to find effective treatments for substance use disorders.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="daBDKvusnN"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/this-250-million-growth-fund-will-divert-half-its-profits-to-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/">This $250 million growth fund will divert half its profits to historically black colleges and universities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This $250 million growth fund will divert half its profits to historically black colleges and universities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/this-250-million-growth-fund-will-divert-half-its-profits-to-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/embed/#?secret=daBDKvusnN" data-secret="daBDKvusnN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/darryl-finkton-jr-closes-200m-to-go-from-asset-management-to-poverty-eradication/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158509</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Box beats expectations, raises guidance as it looks for a comeback</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/box-beats-expectations-raises-guidance-as-it-looks-for-a-comeback/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/box-beats-expectations-raises-guidance-as-it-looks-for-a-comeback/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Levie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Box]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starboard Value]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Box executives have been dealing with activist investor Starboard Value over the last year, along with fighting through the pandemic like the rest of us. Today the company reported earnings for the first quarter of its fiscal 2022. Overall, it was a good quarter for the cloud content management company. The firm reported revenue of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/starboard-value-puts-box-on-notice-that-its-looking-to-take-over-board/">Box</a> executives have been dealing with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/as-activist-investors-loom-whats-next-for-box/">activist investor Starboard Value</a> over the last year, along with fighting through the pandemic like the rest of us. Today <a href="https://www.boxinvestorrelations.com/news-and-media/news/press-release-details/2021/Box-Reports-Strong-Fiscal-First-Quarter-2022-Financial-Results/">the company reported earnings</a> for the first quarter of its fiscal 2022. Overall, it was a good quarter for the cloud content management company.</p>
<p>The firm reported revenue of $202.4 million up 10% compared to its year-ago result, numbers that beat Box projections of between $200 million to $201 million. <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/box-gears-report-q1-earnings-154003929.html">Yahoo Finance reports</a> the analyst consensus was $200.5 million, so the company also bested street expectations.</p>
<p>The company has faced strong headwinds the past year, in spite of a climate that has been generally favorable to cloud companies like Box. A report like this was badly needed by the company as it faces<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/starboard-value-puts-box-on-notice-that-its-looking-to-take-over-board/"> a board fight with Starboard</a> over its direction and leadership.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Aaron Levie is hoping this report will mark the beginning of a positive trend. “I think you&#8217;ve got a better economic climate right now for IT investment. And then secondarily, I think the trends of hybrid work, and the sort of long term trends of digital transformation are very much supportive of our strategy,” he told TechCrunch in a post-earnings interview.</p>
<p>While Box <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/box-acquires-esignature-startup-signrequest-for-new-content-workflows/">acquired e-signature startup SignRequest</a> in February, it won’t actually be incorporating that functionality into the platform until this summer. Levie said that what’s been driving the modest revenue growth <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/21/box-introduces-box-shield-with-increased-security-controls-and-threat-protection/">is Box Shield</a>, the company’s content security product and the platform tools, which enable customers to customize workflows and build applications on top of Box.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wji0qUXXdp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/as-activist-investors-loom-whats-next-for-box/">As activist investors loom, what’s next for Box?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As activist investors loom, what’s next for Box?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/as-activist-investors-loom-whats-next-for-box/embed/#?secret=wji0qUXXdp" data-secret="wji0qUXXdp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company is also seeing success with large accounts. Levie says that he saw the number of customers spending more than $100,000 with it grow by nearly 50% compared to the year-ago quarter. One of Box&#8217;s growth strategies has been to expand the platform and then upsell additional platform services over time, and those numbers suggest that the effort is working.</p>
<p>While Levie was keeping his M&amp;A cards close to the vest, he did say if the right opportunity came along to fuel additional growth through acquisition, he would definitely give strong consideration to further inorganic growth. “We&#8217;re going to continue to be very thoughtful on M&amp;A. So we will only do M&amp;A that we think is attractive in terms of price and the ability to accelerate our roadmap, or the ability to get into a part of a market that we&#8217;re not currently in,” Levie said.</p>
<h2>A closer look at the financials</h2>
<p>Box managed modest growth acceleration for the quarter, existing only if we consider the company’s results on a sequential basis. In simpler terms, Box’s newly reported 10% growth in the first quarter of its fiscal 2022 was better than the 8% growth it earned during the fourth quarter of its fiscal 2021, but worse than the 13% growth it managed in its year-ago Q1.</p>
<p>With Box, however, instead of judging it by normal rules, we’re hunting in its numbers each quarter for signs of promised acceleration. By that standard, Box met its own goals.</p>
<p>How did investors react? Shares of the company were mixed after-hours, including a sharp dip and recovery in the value of its equity. The street appears to be confused by the results, weighing the report and working out whether its moderately accelerating growth is sufficiently enticing to warrant holding onto its equity, or more perversely if its growth is not expansive enough to fend off external parties hunting for more dramatic changes at the firm.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0fGktKJ12k"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/kkr-hands-box-a-500m-lifeline/">KKR hands Box a $500M lifeline</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;KKR hands Box a $500M lifeline&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/08/kkr-hands-box-a-500m-lifeline/embed/#?secret=0fGktKJ12k" data-secret="0fGktKJ12k" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Sticking to a high-level view of Box’s results, apart from its growth numbers Box has done a good job shaking fluff out of its operations. The company’s operating margins (GAAP and not) both improved, and cash generation also picked up.</p>
<p>Perhap most importantly, Box raised its guidance from “the range of $840 million to $848 million” to “$845 to $853 million.” Is that a lot? No. It’s +$5 million to both the lower and upper-bounds of its targets. But if you squint, the company’s Q4 to Q1 revenue acceleration, and upgraded guidance could be an early indicator of a return to form.</p>
<p>Levie admitted that 2020 was a tough year for Box. “Obviously, last year was a complicated year in terms of the macro environment, the pandemic, just lots of different variables to deal with…” he said. But the CEO continues to think that his organization is set up for future growth.</p>
<p>Will Box manage to perform well enough to keep activist shareholders content? Levie thinks if he can string together more quarters like this one, he can keep Starboard at bay. “I think when you look at the next three quarters, the ability to guide up on revenue, the ability to guide up on profitability. We think it&#8217;s a very very strong earnings report and we think it shows a lot of the momentum in the business that we have right now.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pBfb3zWcLf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/aaron-levie-we-have-way-too-many-manual-processes-in-businesses/">Aaron Levie: &#8216;We have way too many manual processes in businesses&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aaron Levie: &#8216;We have way too many manual processes in businesses&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/29/aaron-levie-we-have-way-too-many-manual-processes-in-businesses/embed/#?secret=pBfb3zWcLf" data-secret="pBfb3zWcLf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/box-beats-expectations-raises-guidance-as-it-looks-for-a-comeback/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158608</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-demand grocery startup Food Rocket launches in the Bay Area, goes up against delivery giants</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/on-demand-grocery-startup-food-rocket-launches-in-the-bay-area-goes-up-against-delivery-giants/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/on-demand-grocery-startup-food-rocket-launches-in-the-bay-area-goes-up-against-delivery-giants/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 20:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AltaIR Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goPuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gorillas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grocery delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grocery store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west coast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On-demand grocery startups like Gorillas are invading Europe right now, but although on-demand-everything is kinda old-hat in the Bay Area, a new startup thinks it might just be able to do something new. Food Rocket says it has raised a $2 million investment round from AltaIR Capital, Baring Vostok fund, and the AngelsDeck group of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On-demand grocery startups like <a href="https://gorillas.io/">Gorillas</a> are invading Europe right now, but although on-demand-everything is kinda old-hat in the Bay Area, a new startup thinks it might just be able to do something new.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.foodrocket.me/">Food Rocket</a> says it has raised a $2 million investment round from AltaIR Capital, Baring Vostok fund, and the AngelsDeck group of business angels, including Philipp Bashyan, of Russia’s Yonder, who has joined as an investor and advisor.</p>
<p>Yes, admittedly ok this tiny startup is competing with DoorDash, GoPuff, InstaCart and Amazon Fresh. Maybe let’s not into that…</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Using the company’s mobile app, users can order fresh groceries, ready-to-eat meals, and household goods that will be delivered within 10-15 minutes, says the startup, which will be servicing SoMa, South Park, Mission Bay, Japantown, Hayes Valley, and others. The company hopes to open 150 &#8216;dark stores&#8217; on the West Coast as part of its infrastructure.</p>
<p>Vitaly Aleksandrov, CEO, and co-founder of Food Rocket said: “The level of competition in this market in the U.S. is still manageable, which is why we have the opportunity to become leaders in the sphere of fast delivery of basic products and household goods. We aim to replace brick-and-mortar supermarkets and to change consumers’ current habits in regards to grocery shopping.”</p>
<p>What can we say? Good luck?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bA0d8CuhaZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/whos-building-the-grocery-store-of-the-future/">Who&#8217;s building the grocery store of the future?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Who&#8217;s building the grocery store of the future?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/whos-building-the-grocery-store-of-the-future/embed/#?secret=bA0d8CuhaZ" data-secret="bA0d8CuhaZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/on-demand-grocery-startup-food-rocket-launches-in-the-bay-area-goes-up-against-delivery-giants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158587</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FM Capital steps up automotive investments with new $150M fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/fm-capital-steps-up-automotive-investments-with-new-150m-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/fm-capital-steps-up-automotive-investments-with-new-150m-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 20:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Move Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FM Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vroom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First Move Capital, the Boulder-based venture firm that has invested in used car marketplaces Frontier Auto Group and Vroom as well as mobility-as-a-service startup Via, has closed a new $150 million fund that will focus on the automotive and transportation sectors. Existing strategic investors such as OEMs, dealers, distributors, fleet management, remarketing, insurance and software [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">First Move Capital, the Boulder-based venture firm that has invested in used car marketplaces Frontier Auto Group and Vroom as well as mobility-as-a-service startup Via, has closed a new $150 million fund that will focus on the automotive and transportation sectors.</p>
<p>Existing strategic investors such as OEMs, dealers, distributors, fleet management, remarketing, insurance and software providers as well as family offices have backed the fund. Proceeds from the round will be exclusively allocated to new investments, the company said Thursday.</p>
<p>FM Capital has already made seven investments from the oversubscribed fund, including autonomous vehicle startup Gatik, cloud-based automotive retail platform Tekion and e-commerce startup Revolution Parts.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We hit our hard cap in the max that we could raise, but have deployed a minority of that amount so we&#8217;re still very much, actively investing and will be for the next couple of years,&#8221; Managing Partner Mark Norman said in a recent interview.</p>
<p>FM Capital launched in 2012 with a $40 million fund that invested in auto commerce and dealership technologies as well as other broader retail and enterprise software startups. Its second fund, which more than doubled to $90 million, is when FM Capital became an automotive-focused VC interested in auto commerce, autonomy and sensors, connectivity, electrification and shared mobility. FM Capital typically invests between $5 million to $10 million in companies with what the partners view as &#8220;transformative solutions in transportation&#8221; typically at the Series A stage. FM Capital will sometimes do a later seed round where there&#8217;s commercial traction and revenue, said Norman, who noted that in this new fund the firm has already completed one seed deal out of the seven investments it has made so far.</p>
<p>FM Capital has backed a total of 40 companies based in North America, Europe and Tel Aviv.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VurGjqRrxL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/10-investors-predict-maas-on-demand-delivery-and-evs-will-dominate-the-post-covid-future-of-mobility/">10 investors predict MaaS, on-demand delivery and EVs will dominate mobility&#8217;s post-pandemic future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 investors predict MaaS, on-demand delivery and EVs will dominate mobility&#8217;s post-pandemic future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/10-investors-predict-maas-on-demand-delivery-and-evs-will-dominate-the-post-covid-future-of-mobility/embed/#?secret=VurGjqRrxL" data-secret="VurGjqRrxL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Looking ahead, Norman sees opportunities stemming from the rising number of EVs and other forms of propulsion besides internal combustion engines.</p>
<p>&#8220;We see there&#8217;s just a huge transformation going on with propulsion, a lot driven, of course, by government mandates around the world,&#8221; Norman said. &#8220;Alternative fuels and distribution and related service infrastructure is going through a ton of flux right now. That&#8217;s everything from the technology going into propulsion in vehicles — that shift from internal combustion to in large part, EVs — and how that affects downstream service infrastructure, how it affects marketplaces like residual values, and how you estimate that and understand what a vehicle is worth over its lifecycle.&#8221;</p>
<p>For instance, Norman pointed to FM Capital&#8217;s latest investment into a startup called Indigo Technologies, which has developed a vehicle platform with an in-wheel motor and suspension that frees up space.</p>
<p>There also continues to be a lot of software opportunities, especially as more vehicles hit the marketplace with embedded connectivity, Norman said. He also noted additional opportunities in enterprise software.</p>
<p>&#8220;What had been a very fragmented retail environment continues to consolidate — whether we&#8217;re talking about car rentals, car dealers or fleet management — and their appetite for centrally driven tools and data is also much higher than that in the past. That&#8217;s real opportunity on the enterprise software side of things.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8dKyeob1cY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/investors-clara-brenner-quin-garcia-and-rachel-holt-are-coming-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/">Investors Clara Brenner, Quin Garcia and Rachel Holt are coming to TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors Clara Brenner, Quin Garcia and Rachel Holt are coming to TC Sessions: Mobility 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/16/investors-clara-brenner-quin-garcia-and-rachel-holt-are-coming-to-tc-sessions-mobility-2021/embed/#?secret=8dKyeob1cY" data-secret="8dKyeob1cY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/fm-capital-steps-up-automotive-investments-with-new-150m-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158320</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>See what&#8217;s new from Wejo, CMC, iMerit, Plus, oVice &#038; Michigan at TechCrunch&#8217;s mobility event</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/see-whats-new-from-wejo-cmc-imerit-plus-ovice-michigan-at-techcrunchs-mobility-event/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/see-whats-new-from-wejo-cmc-imerit-plus-ovice-michigan-at-techcrunchs-mobility-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 20:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car ownership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FlashParking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[May Mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michigan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nina grooms lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving truck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: Mobility 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re in the final run-up to TC Sessions: Mobility 2021 on June 9, and the great stuff just keeps on coming. We’ve stacked the one-day agenda with plenty of programming to keep you engaged, informed and on track to build a stronger business. You’ll always find amazing speakers — some of the most innovative minds [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We’re in the final run-up to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 2021</a> on June 9, and the great stuff just keeps on coming. We’ve stacked the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">one-day agenda</a> with plenty of programming to keep you engaged, informed and on track to build a stronger business. You’ll always find amazing speakers — some of the most innovative minds out there — on the main stage and in breakout sessions.</p>
<p><strong>Dramatic pause for a pro tip:</strong> Don’t have a pass yet? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy one here now for $125</a>, before prices go up at the door.</p>
<blockquote><p>“I enjoyed the big marquee speakers from companies like Uber, but it was the individual presentations where you really started to get into the meat of the conversation and see how these mobile partnerships come to life.” — Karin Maake, senior director of communications at FlashParking.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We have another exciting bit of news. We&#8217;re hosting a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pitch session for early-stage startup founders</a> who exhibit in the expo at TC Sessions: Mobility. Each startup gets one minute to pitch to attendees in a breakout session. Remember, this conference has a global reach — talk about visibility! Want to pitch? <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy an Early Stage Startup Exhibitor Package</a> &#8212; we only have two packages left.</p>
<p>Alrighty then…let’s look at some of the breakout &amp; main stage sessions waiting for you at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: Mobility 20201</a>.</p>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>Innovating Future Mobility for Global Scale</strong></span></a></h2>
<h3>Wednesday, June 9, <span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;10:00-10:50am&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:6851,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;4&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:16773836},&quot;9&quot;:0,&quot;10&quot;:2,&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;14&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:2236962},&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Roboto, RobotoDraft, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif&quot;}">10:00 am -10:50 am PDT</span></h3>
<p>Learn how the CMC’s (<em>California Mobility Center) </em>model of bringing their clients’ new technologies to market is new and innovative, going beyond a typical demonstration or pilot program, to the point of product launch and sustaining market viability. Hear from an expert panel about how the CMC’s programming is unique, innovative and game-changing.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Neal Best, Director of Client Services, California Mobility Center (CMC)</em></li>
<li><em>Bill Brandt, Business Development Advisor, Zeus Electric Chassis</em></li>
<li><em>Mark Rawson, Chief Operating Officer, California Mobility Center (CMC)</em></li>
<li><em>Scott Ungerer, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Founder and Managing Director, EnerTech Capital</span></em></li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient">Public-Private Partnerships: Advancing the Future of Mobility and Electrification</span></strong></a></h2>
<h3>Wednesday, June 9, <span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;10:00-10:50am&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:6851,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;4&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:16773836},&quot;9&quot;:0,&quot;10&quot;:2,&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;14&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:2236962},&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Roboto, RobotoDraft, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif&quot;}">10:45 am -11:05 am PDT</span></h3>
<p>The future of mobility starts with the next generation of transportation solutions. Attendees will hear from some of the most innovative names on opportunities that await when public and private entities team up to revolutionize the way we think about technology. Trevor Pawl, Michigan’s Chief Mobility Officer, will be joined by Nina Grooms Lee, Chief Product Officer of May Mobility.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Nina Grooms Lee, Chief Product Officer, May Mobility</em></li>
<li><em>Trevor Pawl, Chief Mobility Officer, State of Michigan</em></li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>Delivering Supervised Autonomous Trucks Globally</strong></span></a></h2>
<h3>Wednesday, June 9, <span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;10:00-10:50am&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:6851,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;4&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:16773836},&quot;9&quot;:0,&quot;10&quot;:2,&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;14&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:2236962},&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Roboto, RobotoDraft, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif&quot;}">12:40 pm &#8211; 1:00 pm PDT</span></h3>
<p>Plus is applying autonomous driving technology to launch supervised autonomous trucks today in order to dramatically improve safety, efficiency and driver comfort, while addressing critical challenges in long-haul trucking — driver shortage and high turnover, rising fuel costs and reaching sustainability goals. Mass production of our supervised autonomous driving solution, PlusDrive, starts this summer. In the next few years, tens of thousands of heavy trucks powered by PlusDrive will be on the road. Plus’s COO and co-founder Shawn Kerrigan will introduce PlusDrive and our progress of deploying this driver-in solution globally. He will also share our learnings from working together with world-leading OEMs and fleet partners to develop and deploy autonomous trucks at scale.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Shawn Kerrigan, COO and Co-Founder, Plus</em></li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient">How Edge Cases and Data Will Enable Autonomous Transportation in Cities Across the U.S.</span></a></h2>
<h3>Wednesday, June 9, <span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;10:00-10:50am&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:6851,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;4&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:16773836},&quot;9&quot;:0,&quot;10&quot;:2,&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;14&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:2236962},&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Roboto, RobotoDraft, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif&quot;}">11:00 am &#8211; 11:50 am</span></h3>
<p>Data will play a vital role in solving the critical edge cases required to gain city approval and deploy autonomous transportation at scale. Pilot projects are underway across the U.S., and cities such as Las Vegas are leading the way for progressive policies, testing and adoption. But, how do these projects involving a limited number of vehicles gain city approval, expand to larger geographic areas, include more use cases and service more people? Join our expert panel discussion as we examine the progress, challenges and road ahead in harnessing data to enable multiple modes of autonomous transportation in major cities across the U.S.</p>
<ul>
<li>Chris Barker, Founder &amp; CEO, CBC</li>
<li>Radha Basu, Founder &amp; CEO, iMerit</li>
<li>Michael Sherwood, CIO, City of Las Vegas</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient"><strong>Making Mobility Data Accessible to Governmental Agencies to Meet New Transportation Demands</strong></span></a></h2>
<h3>Wednesday, June 9, <span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;10:00-10:50am&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:6851,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;4&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:16773836},&quot;9&quot;:0,&quot;10&quot;:2,&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;14&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:2236962},&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Roboto, RobotoDraft, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif&quot;}">1:45 pm &#8211; 2:05 pm</span></h3>
<p>Wejo provides accurate and unbiased unique journey data, curated from millions of connected cars, to help local, state, provincial and federal government agencies visualize traffic and congestion conditions. Unlock a deeper understanding of mobility trends, to make better decisions, support policy development and solve problems more effectively for your towns and cities.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Brett Scott, VP of Partnerships</em></li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-mobility-2021/?utm_medium=marketingpost&amp;utm_campaign=mobility2021&amp;utm_content=sponsorsessions&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=sponsorsessions&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span class="gradient-text gradient-text--green-gradient">Will Remote Work Push Japan’s Rural Mobility Forward?</span></a></h2>
<h3>Wednesday, June 9, <span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;10:00-10:50am&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:6851,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;4&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:16773836},&quot;9&quot;:0,&quot;10&quot;:2,&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;14&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:2236962},&quot;15&quot;:&quot;Roboto, RobotoDraft, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif&quot;}">1:45 pm &#8211; 2:05 pm</span></h3>
<p>With remote work becoming the new normal and the mass movement from the city to the Japanese countryside, the trend of private car ownership is growing day by day. During this session, we’ll be hearing from Sae Hyung Jung, serial entrepreneur, founder and CEO of oVice. oVice is an agile communication tool that facilitates hybrid remote and virtual meetups. Most notably, a hope that can trigger a sudden expansion in the Japanese mobility and vehicle infrastructure.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Sae Hyung Jung, Founder &amp; CEO, oVice</em></li>
</ul>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-64ce6d75b37f1ce5a159f2c8ff19c435"
			width="99%"
			height="1500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/64ce6d75b37f1ce5a159f2c8ff19c435"
			scrolling=""
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-64ce6d75b37f1ce5a159f2c8ff19c435')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-64ce6d75b37f1ce5a159f2c8ff19c435'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/see-whats-new-from-wejo-cmc-imerit-plus-ovice-michigan-at-techcrunchs-mobility-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158497</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zero-gravity space fridge could keep astronaut food fresh for years</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/zero-g-space-fridge-could-keep-astronaut-food-fresh-for-years/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/zero-g-space-fridge-could-keep-astronaut-food-fresh-for-years/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Purdue University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SBIR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Regular supply launches keep astronauts aboard the ISS supplied with relatively fresh food, but a flight to Mars won&#8217;t get deliveries. If we&#8217;re going to visit other planets, we&#8217;ll need a fridge that doesn&#8217;t break down in space — and Purdue University researchers are hard at work testing one. You may think there&#8217;s nothing to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Regular supply launches keep astronauts aboard the ISS supplied with relatively fresh food, but a flight to Mars won&#8217;t get deliveries. If we&#8217;re going to visit other planets, we&#8217;ll need a fridge that doesn&#8217;t break down in space — and Purdue University researchers are hard at work testing one.</p>
<p>You may think there&#8217;s nothing to prevent a regular refrigerator from working in space. It sucks heat out and puts cold air in. Simple, right? But refrigerators rely on gravity to distribute oil through the compressor system that regulates temperature, so in space these systems don&#8217;t work or break down quickly.</p>
<p>The solution being pursued by Purdue team and partner manufacturer Air Squared is an oil-free version of the traditional fridge that will work regardless of gravity&#8217;s direction or magnitude. It was funded by<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/how-to-access-americas-seed-fund-the-3-billion-sbir-program/"> NASA&#8217;s SBIR program</a>, which awards money to promising small businesses and experiments in order to inch them toward mission readiness. (The program is currently on its Phase II extended period award.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3HizctXprU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/how-to-access-americas-seed-fund-the-3-billion-sbir-program/">How to access &#8216;America&#8217;s Seed Fund,&#8217; the $3 billion SBIR program</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to access &#8216;America&#8217;s Seed Fund,&#8217; the $3 billion SBIR program&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/how-to-access-americas-seed-fund-the-3-billion-sbir-program/embed/#?secret=3HizctXprU" data-secret="3HizctXprU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In development for two years, the team at last assembled a flight-ready prototype, and last month was <a href="https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2021/Q2/to-give-astronauts-better-food,-engineers-test-a-fridge-prototype-in-microgravity.html">finally able to test it in microgravity</a> simulated in a parabolic plane flight.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/N0pFySXLJJA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Initial results are promising: The fridge worked.</p>
<p>&#8220;The fact that the refrigeration cycles operated continuously in microgravity during the tests without any apparent problems indicates that our design is a very good start,&#8221; said Leon Brendel, a Ph.D. student on the team. &#8220;Our first impression is that microgravity does not alter the cycle in ways that we were not aware of.&#8221;</p>
<p>Short-term microgravity (the prototype was only weightless for 20 seconds at a time) is just a limited test, of course, and it already helped shake out an issue with the device that they&#8217;re working on. But the next test might be a longer-term installation aboard the ISS, the denizens of which would no doubt like to have a working fridge.</p>
<p>While the prospect of cold drinks and frozen (but not freeze-dried) meals is tantalizing, a normal refrigerator could be used for all kinds of scientific work as well. Experiments that need cold environments currently either use complicated, small scale cooling mechanisms or utilize the near-absolute-zero conditions of space. So it&#8217;s no surprise NASA got them aboard the microgravity simulator as part of the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/centers/armstrong/features/a-space-fridge-for-long-duration-missions.html">Flight Opportunities program</a>.</p>
<p>Analysis of the data collected on the flights is ongoing, but the success of this first big test validates both the approach and execution of the space fridge. Next up is figuring out how it might work in the limited space and continuous microgravity of the ISS.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hkfqJAFBEU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/">As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/embed/#?secret=hkfqJAFBEU" data-secret="hkfqJAFBEU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/zero-g-space-fridge-could-keep-astronaut-food-fresh-for-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158519</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SaaS needs to take a page out of the crypto playbook</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/saas-needs-to-take-a-page-out-of-the-crypto-playbook/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/saas-needs-to-take-a-page-out-of-the-crypto-playbook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Chen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The idea of directly incentivizing users is a common rallying cry in the crypto community: Imagine an internet free from monopoly tech giants where users control and monetize their own data.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">John Chen</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/thejohnchen">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		John is a principal at <a href="https://www.fika.vc/">Fika Ventures</a> in Los Angeles.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/31/how-silicon-valley-should-celebrate-labor-day/">How Silicon Valley should celebrate Labor Day</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/08/26/rebuilding-employee-philanthropy-from-the-bottom-up/">Rebuilding employee philanthropy from the bottom up</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">By the time I joined Box in late 2012, the “consumerization of the enterprise” movement was well underway. The playbook was clear: The lessons and tactics from the rise of consumer apps — viral loops, social referrals, frictionless onboarding — could be distilled, packaged and ported over to enterprise.</p>
<p>And the promise was subversive — great products could galvanize a loyal user base and wrest free the fates of multimillion-dollar contracts from suited salespeople peddling unusable software behind closed doors.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			While the consumerization of SaaS has taught us how to more effectively get in front of users, this next decade will be about how to properly incentivize them to do the necessary work to have the right product experience.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>A decade later, this promise has largely proven true. The consumer playbook contributed to the meteoric rise of Slack, Zoom, Airtable and others, specifically around user acquisition and onboarding. They are beautiful products that are discovered from the bottom up, self-serve, free to start and pay as you grow.</p>
<p>But while this might seem like one of the best times to build a SaaS company, one look at <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/">Product Hunt</a> might paint a different story. For every success story like Airtable, there are a dozen lookalikes employing the same consumer-inspired playbook that are getting drowned out.</p>
<p>And for any first-mover startup in a new category thinking they’re reaching escape velocity, there are a dozen copycats in YC waiting around the corner, complete with their beautifully designed apps, and the promise of being “blazingly fast and delightfully simple.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2158206" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2158206" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2158206" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="634" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png?resize=150,93 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png?resize=300,186 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png?resize=768,475 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png?resize=680,421 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png?resize=1536,950 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-1.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2158206" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fika Ventures</p></div></p>
<p>Conventional wisdom suggests that many of these newcomer apps will fall short because they don’t clearly communicate their differentiation, or their signup process isn’t streamlined enough, or they have poor documentation and tutorial videos, or they haven’t courted the right influencers on Twitter, or just plain poor execution.</p>
<p>While some (or all) of these might be true on the individual app level, there is something bigger happening on the aggregate level, and it comes back to one insidious assumption carried over from the consumer playbook: the myth of frictionless onboarding.</p>
<p>The reality is that onboarding is never frictionless. In fact, it’s quite the opposite — it demands that the user uproot their old habits and switch to this new way of being or doing. Just like with a new fitness program, participants feel good <em>after</em> completing the workout, but it takes a lot of activation energy to start and hard work to get there. Similarly, it takes work on the user’s part to get results, and most apps expect users to do this work for free.</p>
<p>But in a crowded marketplace with infinite alternatives, the only way to capture and hold a user’s attention is to directly incentivize them to <em>experience</em> the product, not just be exposed to it. Today’s growth playbook overindexes on spending ad dollars (with diminishing returns) to get premium placement and eyeballs on Google, Facebook or Product Hunt, but very few have tried putting those dollars to work toward ensuring users are actually having the experience they are supposed to.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2158207" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2158207" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2158207" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="577" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png?resize=1536,865 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/cryptoSaaS-2.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2158207" class="wp-caption-text">2019 subscription customer acquisition cost study.<strong> Image Credits:</strong> Profitwell</p></div></p>
<p>To do this, SaaS needs to take a page out of the crypto playbook. So while the past decade of the consumerization of SaaS has taught us how to more effectively get in front of users, this next decade will be about the cryptofication of SaaS and how to properly incentivize users to do the necessary work to have the right experience with your product.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/saas-needs-to-take-a-page-out-of-the-crypto-playbook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158180</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orbiit raises seed funding to automate the interactions within an online community</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/orbiit-raises-seed-funding-to-automate-the-interactions-within-an-online-community/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/orbiit-raises-seed-funding-to-automate-the-interactions-within-an-online-community/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bread and butter ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delian Asparouhov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GGV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Alpha Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LAUNCHub Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lerer hippeau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mary grove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orbiit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spendesk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orbiit, a startup that automates the interactions within an online community, has raised a $2.7 million round led by Bread and Butter Ventures, with participation from new investors High Alpha Capital, LAUNCHub Ventures and Company Ventures. Existing investors Founders Fund, which led Orbiit’s $1 million pre-seed round, Acceleprise and other angels also participated. The capital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://orbiit.ai/">Orbiit</a>, a startup that automates the interactions within an online community, has raised a $2.7 million round led by <a href="https://www.breadandbutterventures.com/">Bread and Butter Ventures</a>, with participation from new investors <a href="https://highalpha.com/">High Alpha Capital</a>, <a href="https://launchub.com/">LAUNCHub Ventures</a> and Company Ventures. Existing investors Founders Fund, which led Orbiit’s $1 million pre-seed round, Acceleprise and other angels also participated. The capital will be used to build out the Orbiit product and engineering team.</p>
<p>Orbiit says its platform handles the communications, matching, scheduling, feedback collection and analytics for people connecting with each other in an online community. The idea is that the communities therefore learn and network better, engage more and share more knowledge.</p>
<p>CEO and co-founder Bilyana Freye said: &#8220;Tailored 1:1 connections allow members to discuss difficult topics, be vulnerable and share learnings with one another. Those 1:1 connections are the hardest to execute, but when you start investing in them, with the help of Orbiit, you see engagement feeding into all other initiatives and a vibrant, active community that truly delivers on the promise to its members.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Bread and Butter Ventures Managing Partner Mary Grove added: “This age-old question of how to leverage technology at scale to drive meaningful connections across communities both internal to an organization and across the globe is a problem we’ve been actively seeking a solution to for a decade. Orbiit brings the perfect blend of tech-enabled software with human curation to create strong connections and provide insights back to community managers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The platform is being used by startup communities at True Ventures, GGV and Lerer Hippeau; private networking groups such as Dreamers &amp; Doers; and customer communities, like the CFO community run by fintech leader Spendesk.</p>
<p>Founders Fund Principal Delian Asparouhov said: &#8220;We see Orbiit as a key platform for peer learning within companies and communities, unlocking untapped knowledge through curated matchmaking.”</p>
<p>LAUNCHub Ventures participated in the round, following <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/launchub-ventures-heading-towards-a-85m-fund-for-south-eastern-european-startups/">the recent first close</a> of its new $70 million fund.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9Jwt3S5uHX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/launchub-ventures-heading-towards-a-85m-fund-for-south-eastern-european-startups/">LAUNCHub Ventures heading towards a $85M fund for South Eastern European startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;LAUNCHub Ventures heading towards a $85M fund for South Eastern European startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/launchub-ventures-heading-towards-a-85m-fund-for-south-eastern-european-startups/embed/#?secret=9Jwt3S5uHX" data-secret="9Jwt3S5uHX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/orbiit-raises-seed-funding-to-automate-the-interactions-within-an-online-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158524</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CorrActions raises $2.7M to help avoid errors in human-machine interactions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/corractions-raises-2-7m-to-help-avoid-errors-in-human-machine-interactions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/corractions-raises-2-7m-to-help-avoid-errors-in-human-machine-interactions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CorrActions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fatigue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israeli Innovation Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neuroscience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operator partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symptoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VentureIsrael]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CorrActions, a noninvasive neuroscience startup that uses sensor data to evaluate a user&#8217;s cognitive state due to drowsiness, alcohol, fatigue and other issues, today announced that it has raised a $2.7 million seed round. Early-stage fund VentureIsrael, seed fund Operator Partners and the Israeli Innovation Authority are backing the company, which is based out of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.corractions.com/">CorrActions</a>, a noninvasive neuroscience startup that uses sensor data to evaluate a user&#8217;s cognitive state due to drowsiness, alcohol, fatigue and other issues, today announced that it has raised a $2.7 million seed round. Early-stage fund <a href="https://ventureisrael.com/">VentureIsrael</a>, seed fund <a href="https://www.operatorpartners.com/">Operator Partners</a> and the <a href="https://innovationisrael.org.il/en/">Israeli Innovation Authority</a> are backing the company, which is based out of OurCrowd&#8217;s <a href="https://www.labs02.com/">Labs/02 incubator</a>.</p>
<p>The idea here is to use touch sensors wherever humans may interact with machines, be that in a fighter jet&#8217;s cockpit, a car or anywhere else where knowing a user&#8217;s cognitive state could prevent potentially catastrophic errors. CorrActions promises that its proprietary algorithms can identify the user&#8217;s cognitive state and detect errors 150 milliseconds before they occur by &#8220;decoding unconscious brain signals through body motion monitoring.&#8221; For the most part, the system is use-case agnostic since it&#8217;s basically a generic platform that is independent of where it is implemented.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/aSiCEhfIFf8?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Using sensors that already exist in nearly every electronic device like smartwatches, smartphones and even steering wheels and joysticks, CorrActions is the first in the world to be able to read a person&#8217;s cognitive state at any given moment by analyzing micro changes in their muscular activity,&#8221; explained Eldad Hochman, the company&#8217;s co-founder and CSO. &#8220;It is enough for the person to come in contact with an electronic device for two minutes and we can accurately quantify cognitive state and even predict a rapid deterioration, which may lead to failure or accidents. We can see this coming seconds before it occurs. This means that we can quantify the level of fatigue, intoxication, exhaustion or lack of concentration at any given moment.”</p>
<p>A lot of modern cars already feature sensors that can monitor your alertness, of course, and so it&#8217;s maybe no surprise that CorrActions is already working on proofs of concept with a few players in the automotive industry. In addition, it is also working on projects with the defense industry to show that its systems can assess a pilot&#8217;s performance, for example. But Hochman also believes that the company&#8217;s algorithms may be able to alert athletes or the elderly when they may be at risk of injury and falls.</p>
<p>The company says it will use the new funding to further develop its algorithms and support its current deployment partners, especially in the automotive industry.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are developing, and already seeing significant results for a technology which has the potential to save companies man-hours and money by preventing basic operational errors,&#8221; said CorrActions co-founder and CEO Zvi Ginosar. &#8220;Moreover, the application of our platform can be used to save lives, and prevent thousands of accidents and errors. In the next months we hope to be able to report more ground-breaking results and proof of concept trials, and this funding will greatly help us reach this goal.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Uv4TO64Z2b"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/its-almost-like-placing-an-iv-brain-monitoring-electrode-receives-fda-510k-clearance/">&#8216;It&#8217;s almost like placing an IV&#8217;: Brain monitoring electrode receives FDA 510(k) clearance</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;It&#8217;s almost like placing an IV&#8217;: Brain monitoring electrode receives FDA 510(k) clearance&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/its-almost-like-placing-an-iv-brain-monitoring-electrode-receives-fda-510k-clearance/embed/#?secret=Uv4TO64Z2b" data-secret="Uv4TO64Z2b" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/corractions-raises-2-7m-to-help-avoid-errors-in-human-machine-interactions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158470</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Augmented reality NFT platform Anima gets backing from Coinbase</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/augmented-reality-nft-platform-anima-gets-backing-from-coinbase/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/augmented-reality-nft-platform-anima-gets-backing-from-coinbase/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 18:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arkansas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[augmented reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consensys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flipboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Augmented reality and non-fungible tokens, need I say more? Yes? Oh, well NFTs have certainly had their moment in 2021, but the question of what they do or what can be done with them has certainly been getting voiced more frequently as the speculative gold rush begins to cool off and people start to think [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Augmented reality and non-fungible tokens, need I say more? Yes? Oh, well NFTs have certainly had their moment in 2021, but the question of what they do or what can be done with them has certainly been getting voiced more frequently as the speculative gold rush begins to cool off and people start to think more about how digital goods can evolve in the future.</p>
<p><a href="https://anima.supply/">Anima</a>, a small creative crypto startup built by the founders of photo/video app Ultravisual, which Flipboard acquired back in 2014, is looking to use AR to shift how NFT art and collectibles can be viewed and shared. Their latest venture is an effort to help artists bring their digital creations to a bigger digital stage and help find what the future of NFTs looks like in augmented reality.</p>
<p>The startup has put together a small $500K pre-seed round from Coinbase Ventures, Divergence Ventures, Flamingo DAO, Lyle Owerko and Andrew Unger.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;As NFTs move away from being a more speculative market where it&#8217;s all about returns on your purchases, I think that&#8217;s healthy and it&#8217;s good for us specifically because we want to make things that are more approachable,&#8221; co-founder Alex Herrity says.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bYOTXbtPo3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/the-nft-craze-will-be-a-boon-for-lawyers/">The NFT craze will be a boon for lawyers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NFT craze will be a boon for lawyers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/the-nft-craze-will-be-a-boon-for-lawyers/embed/#?secret=bYOTXbtPo3" data-secret="bYOTXbtPo3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Their broader vision is finding ways for digital objects to interact with the real world, something that&#8217;s been a pretty top-of-mind concern for the AR world over the last few years, though augmented reality development has cooled more recently as creators have sunk into a wait-and-see attitude toward new releases from Apple and Facebook. Both the AR and NFT spaces are incredibly early, something Anima&#8217;s co-founders were quick to admit, but they think both spaces have matured enough that the gimmicks are out in the open.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s a context shift that happens when you see AR as a vehicle to have a tactile relationship with something that you collected or that you see is a lifestyle accessory versus the common thing now where it&#8217;s a little bit more of an experiential gimmick,&#8221; co-founder Neil Voss tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The team has <a href="https://niftygateway.com/itemdetail/primary/0x1f3e54262a3c3708ef6c0232634ba8f4df4d77f1/1">worked with</a> a couple artists already as they&#8217;ve made early experiments in bringing digital art objects into AR and they&#8217;re launching a marketplace late next month based on ConsenSys&#8217;s Palm platform, where they hope to showcase more of their future partnerships.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="a4QrvIgMIm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/consenysys-launches-a-more-energy-efficient-nft-ecosystem-with-a-project-from-artist-damien-hirst-as-its-first-drop/">ConsenSys launches a more energy-efficient NFT ecosystem with a project from artist Damien Hirst as its first drop</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ConsenSys launches a more energy-efficient NFT ecosystem with a project from artist Damien Hirst as its first drop&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/consenysys-launches-a-more-energy-efficient-nft-ecosystem-with-a-project-from-artist-damien-hirst-as-its-first-drop/embed/#?secret=a4QrvIgMIm" data-secret="a4QrvIgMIm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/augmented-reality-nft-platform-anima-gets-backing-from-coinbase/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158445</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japanese space company ispace aims to send landers to the moon</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/japanese-space-company-ispace-aims-to-send-landers-to-the-moon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/japanese-space-company-ispace-aims-to-send-landers-to-the-moon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 17:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ispace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunar lander]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunar mission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moon landing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moon mission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tokyo-based ispace has been selected to deliver rovers from Canada and Japan to the lunar surface after they launch aboard SpaceX rockets. The company will use its recently revealed Hakuto-R lander for both missions, currently scheduled for 2022 and 2023. The Canadian Space Agency selected three private Canadian companies, each with separate scientific missions, to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tokyo-based ispace has been selected to deliver rovers from Canada and Japan to the lunar surface after they launch aboard SpaceX rockets. The company will use its recently revealed Hakuto-R lander for both missions, currently scheduled for 2022 and 2023.</p>
<p>The Canadian Space Agency selected three private Canadian companies, each with separate scientific missions, to ride the lander. Mission Control Space Services, Canadensys and NGC are the first companies to receive awards under the CSA&#8217;s Capability Demonstration program, part of the agency’s Lunar Exploration Accelerator Program. LEAP, unveiled by the Canadian government in February 2020, earmarks $150 million over five years to support in-space demonstrations and science missions from Canadian private industry.</p>
<p>As part of the mission, the ispace lander will deliver the United Arab Emirates’ The Mohammed Bin Rashid Space Centre (MBRSC)&#8217;s 22-pound rover, &#8220;Rashid.&#8221; The rover will be equipped with an artificial intelligence flight computer from space robotics company Mission Control Space Services. Mission Control’s AI will use deep-learning algorithms to recognize lunar geology as the Rashid rover traverses the surface.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>ispace will carry cameras &#8220;to capture key events during the mission&#8221; for Canadensys. The Japanese company will also collect lunar imagery data for demonstration of NGC&#8217;s autonomous navigation system.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are honored that all three of the companies awarded by CSA have each entrusted ispace’s services to carry out their operations on the lunar surface,&#8221; ispace founder and CEO Takeshi Hakamada said in a statement. &#8220;We see this as a show of the trust that ispace has developed with CSA over the past years, as well as a recognition of ispace’s positive position in the North American market.&#8221;</p>
<p>ispace will also be transporting a transformable lunar robot payload to the moon for the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA), in addition to conducting operations and providing lunar data. The data collected on this mission, Mission 2, will be used to aid the design of a future crewed pressurized rover.</p>
<p>JAXA&#8217;s lunar robot will be only around 80mm in diameter before it transforms to its surface form and will weigh only around 250 grams. That mission is scheduled to take place in 2023. ispace did not disclose the financial terms of the deals.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2158430" style="width: 1002px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2158430" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2158430 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jaxa.png" alt="" width="992" height="419" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jaxa.png 992w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jaxa.png?resize=150,63 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jaxa.png?resize=300,127 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jaxa.png?resize=768,324 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jaxa.png?resize=680,287 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jaxa.png?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2158430" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://global.jaxa.jp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JAXA <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>“While the robot travels on the lunar surface, images on behavior of the regolith, and images of lunar surface taken by the robot and the camera on the lunar lander will be sent to the mission control center via the lunar lander,” JAXA said in a news release. “The acquired data will be used for evaluation of the localization algorithm and the impact of the regolith on driving performance of the crewed pressurized rover.”</p>
<p>ispace unveiled their Hakuto-R lander design in July 2020. The Hakuto project was born out of the Google Lunar XPRIZE competition, in which teams competed to be the first to send a lunar rover to the moon, have it travel 500 meters and send back to Earth photos and video. None of the five finalists, including Hakuto, were able to complete a launch, and the competition <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/23/googles-lunar-xprize-to-go-unclaimed-as-moonshot-deadline-looms/">subsequently ended</a> in 2018 without a winner.</p>
<p>The MBRSC and JAXA rovers will have different deployment mechanisms from the landers, though Hakamada did not provide further details during a media briefing Wednesday.</p>
<p>The landers are being assembled in Germany and the assembly phase has just started, Hakamada said. “So we’re very confident we will meet this schedule,” he added.</p>
<p>Using water on the lunar surface is one of ispace’s long-term objectives. The company hopes to have more capability in the future to sustain resource utilization activities, Hakamada said.</p>
<p>This is only one of several lunar missions <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/nasa-picks-spacex-falcon-heavy-for-332m-mission-to-launch-lunar-gateway-components-in-2024/">launching on SpaceX rockets</a>. NASA announced in April that the space startup was selected to send humans to the lunar surface as part of its Artemis project, at a total award value of $2.89 billion. SpaceX will also be taking payloads from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/firefly-aerospaces-lunar-lander-will-fly-to-the-moon-on-a-spacex-falcon-9-in-2023/">Firefly Aerosapce</a> to take up its lunar lander in 2023.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="T8nnmVyNp2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/">As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/embed/#?secret=T8nnmVyNp2" data-secret="T8nnmVyNp2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/japanese-space-company-ispace-aims-to-send-landers-to-the-moon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158092</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What the &#8216;nonpolitical&#8217; startup leader teaches us about company culture</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/what-the-non-political-startup-leader-teaches-us-about-company-culture/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/what-the-non-political-startup-leader-teaches-us-about-company-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 17:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basecamp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2153812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Basecamp lost about a third of its workforce after banning "societal and political discussions" at work. Meltdowns like this reflect societal change, and the startup community ought to take notice. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Deb Muller</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/debmullerhr">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Deb Muller is founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.hracuity.com/">HR Acuity</a>, which creates technology that helps organizations strategically manage employee relations. She has served in executive HR roles at numerous Fortune 500 companies like Honeywell, Citibank, and Marsh and McLennan.
	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">All eyes have recently been on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/basecamp-employees-quit-ceo-letter/">Basecamp</a>, which lost about a third of its workforce at the end of last month after banning “societal and political discussions” at work. Late last year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/09/brian-armstrongs-new-problem-60-plus/">Coinbase</a> was embroiled in a similar controversy after its CEO declared that political activism at work is a distraction, leading to a smaller but still significant employee exodus.</p>
<p>Before that, controversies erupted at Google, Facebook and other prominent tech firms, leading to virtual employee walkouts and work stoppages. We continue to see headlines that highlight tech company employee revolts over management edicts or perceived policy failures.</p>
<p>These company meltdowns reflect a societal change, and those in the startup community ought to take notice. The strife may be attributable to changing generational expectations in some cases, or an excess of “tech bro” culture in others, but the reality is that things have changed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			“Don’t discuss politics at work” used to be a standard expectation. But employee expectations have shifted, and leaders have to recognize and respond to that.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>A generation ago, it was standard policy to keep politics out of work. Today, it’s virtually impossible to separate the political from the personal, and employees are encouraged to bring their whole selves to work, which includes their backgrounds and belief systems.</p>
<p>Political and societal topics impact the everyday lives of employees and the world is more connected than ever. Startup leaders shouldn’t declare a political void &#8212; especially if they’re striving for a diverse and inclusive workforce. We’ve seen what happens when we don’t discuss these issues &#8212; systemic racism and workplace discrimination are allowed to go unchecked.</p>
<p>I’m the CEO and founder of a growing tech company, and also served as an HR executive at several Fortune 500 companies, which means I&#8217;ve seen all sides of the issues at play here.</p>
<p>That gives me some insight on the cultural problems gripping many tech businesses &#8212; and some thoughts on solutions. While companies have every right to create rules and policies on employee conduct and internal use of technology, leaders get better results when they approach these issues intentionally and transparently. As we’ve seen with Basecamp and others, banning political activities and discussions outright can result in unintended consequences.</p>
<h2>How to change policies without all the drama</h2>
<p>It’s impossible to know exactly what caused some of the recent tech company exoduses unless you were there. But most of us have experienced toxic workplace cultures, and having studied the issue extensively as an HR professional and then as a founder, my educated guess is that the recent employee actions that attracted negative media attention are symptoms of a situation that has been simmering for a long time.</p>
<p>If you’re a startup leader who wants to avoid similar controversies, how can you create or change policies without all the drama? Here are some tips to consider:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Look in the mirror and analyze culture. </strong>People who found successful companies build a culture whether they consciously set out to do that or not. One explanation for cultural growing pains at startups is that many companies unconsciously create a monoculture populated by employees of similar backgrounds, skill sets, attitudes and life experiences. As the company grows, you bring in people with different backgrounds and perspectives to join the group and strengthen the business. But it’s important to remember that company culture and policies need to evolve and mature as the organization grows as well, or conflict will inevitably arise. Leaders can avoid that by being thoughtful about every aspect of the policies they create and adjusting the culture to support all employees, not just those who started on Day One.</li>
<li><strong>Get help as your company scales.</strong> CEOs set the tone, and for an early-stage startup, policies tend to be less formal and arise directly from company values. But as the organization matures, you may need to codify practices, such as how you handle time off, parental leave and pay structures. Just as you’d turn to the board for financial advice, it’s best to turn to HR and employee relations experts for workplace guidance. Get counsel from HR on how to avoid unintended consequences and communicate changes appropriately. Depending on what kind of policies you’re putting in place, it might also be a good idea to get input from employees.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Use employee feedback to understand impact.</strong> It’s important to understand what’s going on in your organization before you make policy changes and take other actions that shape the company culture. Collecting employee feedback through surveys and open discussions will allow you to gain visibility into employee priorities and concerns and proceed with greater transparency and decisiveness. Consulting employees before making changes, and even after a policy change, will help you build trust and see if adjustments are needed. Some decisions must be made without staff input; workplaces are not democratic. If possible, try to understand where employees stand so you can better anticipate the impact. One caveat is to not take silence as approval. Just because employees stay after a controversial policy change doesn’t mean they are necessarily OK with it. Many startups put employees in golden handcuffs with benefits or stock options so attractive they “put up with it” for the future payoff. Anonymous surveys will help you understand the sentiment.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don’t capitalize on employee policies for press:</strong> It’s not unusual for tech company leaders to publicly issue policy changes to create controversy. Just recently, Coinbase announced a <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/how-coinbase-is-rethinking-its-approach-to-compensation-9aaf7d5d638e">new compensation policy</a> that eliminates negotiations, a decision that is attracting scrutiny. Generally speaking, this practice isn’t necessarily a bad thing; some leaders have used their platforms to change calcified industry standards for the better. But leaders owe it to their teams to be judicious about publicly announcing new policies that affect staff. Employees shouldn’t be used as a pawn to garner press coverage. Employees want changes and programs that are driven by authenticity and what is right for the company, not changes spurred by the news of the week. With Basecamp, the company created an employee-run DEI committee when it was the “thing to do,” but the CEO disbanded it as soon as it became uncomfortable. This type of performative employee support is a surefire way to deteriorate employee confidence and morale. Be thoughtful about decisions and be prepared to stick through it even if challenges arise.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Addressing systemic problems requires a systemic approach</h2>
<p>“Don’t discuss politics at work” used to be a standard expectation. But employee expectations have shifted, and leaders have to recognize and respond to that. There is more value to be gleaned from encouraging employees to fully be themselves at work, which helps create an inclusive environment, but it’s also important to know you can’t drop these commitments the minute they become inconvenient.</p>
<p>While startup founders play a leading role, it is also on employees and everyone within the startup community to call out bias or inappropriate behaviors in the workforce and at the leadership level. The reality is that most employees at startups are highly skilled in a job market that values technical talent, putting them in a privileged position to take a risk, speak up or just leave when an organization’s culture is toxic or discriminatory. Their voice and actions will speak volumes for millions of workers who don’t have the ability to walk out the door and risk losing their livelihood — and their next paycheck.</p>
<p>The good news is that several Basecamp employees tried to make a change by suggesting a group focused on diversity. When that effort was shut down, they used their feet to send a message. To drive change, those in positions of privilege and power mustn’t stay silent as bystanders &#8212; they have to take a stand for others who aren’t in the position to do so themselves. If all of us harness our privilege to support others who are more vulnerable, we will inevitably create more equitable, welcoming workplaces for everyone.</p>
<p>The turmoil some tech companies are experiencing really comes down to culture and ego. We need to recognize that the old-school “no politics” rule led to situations where systemic racism, sexism and other forms of bigotry festered unchecked. We have an obligation to do better.</p>
<p>Company leaders who acknowledge the direct impact politics can have on employees, engage in open discussions with staff and approach policy changes in a way that reflects the organization’s core values can thrive, even in a divisive political climate.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EUYG6UQkFG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/poor-onboarding-is-the-enemy-of-good-hiring/">Poor onboarding is the enemy of good hiring</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Poor onboarding is the enemy of good hiring&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/poor-onboarding-is-the-enemy-of-good-hiring/embed/#?secret=EUYG6UQkFG" data-secret="EUYG6UQkFG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/what-the-non-political-startup-leader-teaches-us-about-company-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153812</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This $250 million growth fund will divert half its profits to historically Black colleges and universities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/this-250-million-growth-fund-will-divert-half-its-profits-to-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/this-250-million-growth-fund-will-divert-half-its-profits-to-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 17:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Attentive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aurora Solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bain capital ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base10 Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code2040]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laura weidman powers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Include]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s been a lot of talk about racial equality in the year since George Floyd was murdered in Minneapolis, but achieving it is far easier said than done given the current state of affairs. Consider: According to the U.S. Government Accountability Office, historically Black colleges and universities have $15,000 on average in endowment per student, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There&#8217;s been a lot of talk about racial equality in the year since George Floyd was murdered in Minneapolis, but achieving it is far easier said than done given the current state of affairs. Consider: According to the <a href="https://kcpr.mxfig.com/5c538c40d7ccca0f92010099/l/Ji8w7yvbcA02ik6rE?messageId=71N7939qBJUUj1f3A&amp;rn=iM3b6l2bMBSZp5mbvNkI&amp;re=ISbvNmLjZXesR3YpJHdzBUZp5mbvNmI&amp;sc=false" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://kcpr.mxfig.com/5c538c40d7ccca0f92010099/l/Ji8w7yvbcA02ik6rE?messageId%3D71N7939qBJUUj1f3A%26rn%3DiM3b6l2bMBSZp5mbvNkI%26re%3DISbvNmLjZXesR3YpJHdzBUZp5mbvNmI%26sc%3Dfalse&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1622167730234000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHtFgP3ma-l8BEqaCitWdOeYRBsJg">U.S. Government Accountability Office</a>, historically Black colleges and universities have $15,000 on average in endowment per student, while comparable non-HBCUs have $410,000 on average in endowment per student.</p>
<p>That matters, a lot. While higher learning institutions are almost universally focused on diversifying their student base, HBCUs are largely responsible for the nation&#8217;s Black middle class, and the larger the endowment, the stronger the school and its ability to support its educators, researchers and, in the case of public HBCUs, its public service mission. Venture capitalist Jamison Hill says that his own father, who attended North Carolina A&amp;T State University in Greensboro, has long maintained that &#8220;if it weren&#8217;t for that experience, there&#8217;s no way he could have gone on to get a high-paying job, where he met my mother, who laid the foundation for the success of our family.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hill, who most recently spent more than six years with Bain Capital Ventures, is now doing something to protect that legacy, along with a kind of dream team that features Laura Weidman Powers, who has co-founded or led numerous impact-focused startups and nonprofits, including <a href="http://www.code2040.org/">Code2040</a>; and Luci Fonseca, who helped establish the Institute for Black Economic Mobility at McKinsey &amp; Co. and has focused on impact investing at Salesforce Ventures, among her other roles.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>All three have joined the four-year-old venture firm <a href="https://base10.vc/">Base10 Partners</a> to invest a new, $250 million growth-stage fund &#8212; the firm&#8217;s first later-stage vehicle &#8212; and fully half the profits from that fund will be directed to HBCUs to create student scholarships and support university endowments.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a brilliant play on the part of Base10, a Bay Area outfit that closed its second early-stage fund last year with $250 million in capital commitments. Called the Advancement Initiative, the fund has already managed to work checks into eight high-fliers &#8212; Attentive, Nubank, Brex, Plaid, Aurora Solar, Wealthsimple, CircleCI and KeepTruckin.</p>
<p>In each case, the fund participated in heavily oversubscribed rounds, but given its mission, the companies&#8217; founding teams made room for its capital, as did other investors. (As an added sweetener, Base10 has promised to create scholarships in the name of each of these portfolio companies to fund the education of HBCU STEM students. Think: The Plaid Scholarship, The Brex Scholarship, and so forth.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qBi73u5JB0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/26/now-one-of-the-largest-black-led-venture-firms-by-assets-base10-raises-250-million-second-fund/">Now one of the largest Black-led venture firms by assets, Base10 raises $250 million second fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Now one of the largest Black-led venture firms by assets, Base10 raises $250 million second fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/26/now-one-of-the-largest-black-led-venture-firms-by-assets-base10-raises-250-million-second-fund/embed/#?secret=qBi73u5JB0" data-secret="qBi73u5JB0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>A fresh take on how the venture world can help close the racial inequality gap in the U.S., it could conceivably prove even more effective than other initiatives, including that of LPs who are increasingly pushing VCs to diversify their investing ranks.</p>
<p>The fund could be particularly impactful if it inspires copycat efforts. HBCUs confer nearly half of all STEM degrees for African-American students, says Base10, yet all 107 HBCU endowments combined are equal to just 7% of Stanford&#8217;s roughly $30 billion endowment.</p>
<p>So how will it work? For now, says Hill, the idea is to operate the fund as any growth-stage fund, meaning the overarching criteria is to back companies with the potential to produce outsize returns, no matter the skin color of their founders. Ultimately, however &#8212; &#8220;our hope is that this is not one and done,&#8221; says Hill &#8212; the idea is to drive change even further by layering in requirements about who can receive a check from the outfit.</p>
<p>As for the fund&#8217;s returns, some will flow directly back to particular HBCUs because they are limited partners in the Advancement Initiative fund, including the private university Howard University in Washington, D.C. and Florida A&amp;M University in Tallahassee, Florida.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XKdhqJEYuG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/venture-capital-lps-are-the-missing-link-to-solving-silicon-valleys-diversity-problem/">Venture capital LPs are the missing link to solving Silicon Valley&#8217;s diversity problem</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture capital LPs are the missing link to solving Silicon Valley&#8217;s diversity problem&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/venture-capital-lps-are-the-missing-link-to-solving-silicon-valleys-diversity-problem/embed/#?secret=XKdhqJEYuG" data-secret="XKdhqJEYuG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Indeed, while the fund&#8217;s LPs also include earlier Base10 backers, along with organizations that serve minority communities and impact- and mission-oriented foundations, the Advancement Initiative was particularly focused on &#8220;removing any barriers to HBCUs investing,&#8221; says Weidman Powers, adding that it invited them to invest with &#8220;no fees, no minimums, no real closing date.&#8221;</p>
<p>The rest of the returns being set aside from HBCUs will be poured into a donor-advised fund that&#8217;s focused on increasing financial inclusion for the many institutions that do not currently have endowments large enough to support a private market strategy.</p>
<p>Given the late-stage of the companies it is backing &#8212; and the buzzy deals into which it&#8217;s getting &#8212; it&#8217;s likely, too, there will be profits.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve found that a lot of companies are very willing to have a conversation with us,&#8221; says Fonseca, who says the idea is to plug between $10 million and $20 million into each of the fund&#8217;s portfolio companies. &#8220;The toughest part is just getting in front of the CEO,&#8221; she adds. &#8220;Once we get in front of that person and we tell that story, we tell them the vision, they&#8217;re immediately sold.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3efeHBjhhP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/23/yale-may-have-just-turned-institutional-investing-on-its-head-with-a-new-diversity-edict/">Yale may have just turned institutional investing on its head with a new diversity edict</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Yale may have just turned institutional investing on its head with a new diversity edict&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/23/yale-may-have-just-turned-institutional-investing-on-its-head-with-a-new-diversity-edict/embed/#?secret=3efeHBjhhP" data-secret="3efeHBjhhP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/this-250-million-growth-fund-will-divert-half-its-profits-to-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158134</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Just 12 hours left to apply to Startup Battlefield at TC Disrupt 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/just-12-hours-left-to-apply-to-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/just-12-hours-left-to-apply-to-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neesha A. Tambe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 17:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Battlefield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2151734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’ve been urging you to apply to Startup Battlefield at TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 for weeks now, and you have just over 12 hours left before the application window slams shut on May 27 at 11:59 p.m. (PT). Don’t procrastinate — the experience alone, whether you win the $100,000 prize or not, can improve the trajectory [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We’ve been urging you to <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn">apply to Startup Battlefield</a> at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> for weeks now, and you have just over 12 hours left before the application window slams shut on <strong>May 27 at 11:59 p.m. (PT)</strong>. Don’t procrastinate — the experience alone, whether you win the $100,000 prize or not, can improve the trajectory of your business.</p>
<p><strong>Case in point:</strong> Mollie Breen started out as a mathematician at the National Security Agency before co-founding an IoT/OT security startup called <a href="https://perygee.com/">Perygee</a>. She and her team competed in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/startup-battlefield/">Startup Battlefield</a> last year at Disrupt 2020. Although they didn’t reach the finals, Breen has plenty to say about the experience. Here’s what she shared with us in a quick Q&amp;A.</p>
<p><strong>TC:</strong> <strong>Why did you apply to Startup Battlefield?                                             </strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>Breen:</strong> I admired the leadership and growth of other companies that, at one point, were Startup Battlefield contestants. I noticed they had similar traction to us when they applied, and their products resembled ours in their ability to disrupt the respective industry.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What was the training process like?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Breen:</strong> It was incredibly valuable both in the short term and long term. Every team gets a weekly session with the Battlefield editor. Together you rehearse and go over every iteration of the pitch line-by-line and slide-by-slide. After each session, I walked away with constructive feedback on everything — the content, the speaking style and even the font color on a particular slide.</p>
<p>This was a unique opportunity, and we put in extra hours to be ahead of schedule, sent drafts for review in the off hours and even doubled down on additional practice with Q&amp;As. As a result, we couldn’t have been more prepared for pitch day. And the training has stayed with Perygee well past the sessions and the competition.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What did it feel like to pitch at Disrupt?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Breen:</strong> Pitching at Disrupt was, in some ways, like other pitches except that you have an international audience. Since, at that point, we had practiced our pitch dozens of times, the real unknown during the competition was the Q&amp;A with the VC judges.</p>
<p>There was additional pressure to answer succinctly and convincingly within a time constraint that you wouldn’t have during a normal one-on-one pitch. But with the prep help from the TechCrunch team, I felt ready to speak in front of such a large audience. I encourage anyone who might be nervous about the big stage to go for it and trust you’ll have more than enough preparation when you get there.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What was the post-pitch impact? Did you meet investors, press or other key partners?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Breen:</strong> It helped accelerate our progress. Following Battlefield, we closed an oversubscribed fundraising round. We acquired additional beta users, including our first beta user who messaged us after reading about Perygee on TechCrunch. We also gained numerous press opportunities to share our story.</p>
<p>It’s almost a year since Startup Battlefield, and I’m still impressed by how many people start the conversation saying they watched the pitch while reading our company’s background. It’s a reminder that the opportunities created by being a TechCrunch Battlefield company continue.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Do you have any great news to share since your pitch?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Breen:</strong> At TechCrunch Battlefield we were a small team doing MVP testing and just about to start raising. Since the pitch, we have scaled on all fronts. We grew the founding team and the engineering team, and we deployed the product to enterprise networks. Some of those deployments include contacts who reached out because of TechCrunch — and we raised our seed round!</p>
<p><strong>TC: Is there anything else you’d like to share?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Breen:</strong> I’m grateful for the camaraderie and relationships we developed with the other teams. What you didn’t see on stage during the pitches was all of us cheering one another on from the group chat or social media feed. Even now, we continue to support one another through navigating business questions or promoting product launches. If it weren’t for Startup Battlefield, I would never have met this awesome group of startups.</p>
<p>You have just 24 hours left to channel your inner Mollie Breen. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/zM4H0xNn">Apply to Startup Battlefield</a> before the deadline expires on <strong>May 27 at 11:59 p.m. (PT)</strong>. Get moving!</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/just-12-hours-left-to-apply-to-startup-battlefield-at-tc-disrupt-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2151734</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The open-source Contributor Covenant is now managed by the Organization for Ethical Source</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/the-open-source-contributor-covenant-is-now-managed-by-the-organization-for-ethical-source/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/the-open-source-contributor-covenant-is-now-managed-by-the-organization-for-ethical-source/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 17:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contributor covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creative-Commons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellectual property law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruby]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Managing the technical side of open-source projects is often hard enough, but throw in the inevitable conflicts between contributors, who are often very passionate about their contributions, and things get even harder. One way to establish ground rules for open-source communities is the Contributor Covenant, created by Coraline Ada Ehmke back in 2014. Like so [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Managing the technical side of open-source projects is often hard enough, but throw in the inevitable conflicts between contributors, who are often very passionate about their contributions, and things get even harder. One way to establish ground rules for open-source communities is the <a href="https://www.contributor-covenant.org/">Contributor Covenant</a>, created by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coraline_Ada_Ehmke">Coraline Ada Ehmke</a> back in 2014. Like so many projects in the open-source world, the Contributor Covenant was also a passion project for Ehmke. Over the years, its first two iterations have been adopted by organizations like the CNCF, Creative Commons, Apple, Google, Microsoft and the Linux project, in addition to <a href="https://www.contributor-covenant.org/adopters/">hundreds of other projects</a>.</p>
<p>Now, as work is starting on version 3.0, the <a href="https://ethicalsource.dev/">Organization for Ethical Source</a> (OES), of which Ehmke is a co-founder and executive director, will take over the stewardship of the project.</p>
<p>&#8220;Contributor Covenant was the first document of its kind as code of conduct for open-source projects &#8212; and it was incredibly controversial and actually remains pretty controversial to this day,&#8221; Ehmke told me. &#8220;But I come from the Ruby community, and the Ruby community really embraced the concept and also really embraced the document itself. And then it spread from there to lots of other open-source projects and other open-source communities.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The core of the document is a pledge to &#8220;make participation in our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, visible or invisible disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, caste, color, religion, or sexual identity and orientation,&#8221; and for contributors to act in ways that contribute to a diverse, open and welcoming community.</p>
<p>As Ehmke told me, one part that evolved over the course of the last few years is the addition of enforcement guidelines that are meant to help community leaders determine the consequences when members violate the code of conduct.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the things that I try to do in this work is when people criticize the work, even if they&#8217;re not arguing in good faith, I try to see if there&#8217;s something in there that could be used as constructive feedback, something actionable,&#8221; Ehmke said. &#8220;A lot of the criticism for years for Contributor Covenant was people saying, &#8216;Oh, I&#8217;ll say one wrong thing and be permanently banned from our project, which is really grim and really unreasonable.&#8217; What I took from that is that people are afraid of what consequences project leaders might impose on them for an infraction. Put that way, that&#8217;s kind of a reasonable concern.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ehmke described bringing the Covenant to the OES as an &#8220;exit to community,&#8221; similar to how companies will often bring their mature open-source projects under the umbrella of a foundation. She noted that the OES includes a lot of members with expertise in community management and project governance, which they will be able to bring to the project in a more formal way. &#8220;I&#8217;m still going to be involved with the evolution of Contributor Covenant, but it&#8217;s going to be developed under the working group model that the organization for ethical source has established,&#8221; she explained.</p>
<p>For version 3.0, Ehmke hopes to turn the Covenant into what she described as more of a &#8220;toolkit&#8221; that will allow different communities to tailor it a bit more to their own goals and values (though still within the core ethical principles <a href="https://ethicalsource.dev/principles/">outlined by the OES</a>).</p>
<p>&#8220;Microsoft’s adoption of Contributor Covenant represents our commitment to building healthy, diverse and inclusive communities, as well as our intention to contribute and build together with others in the ecosystem,&#8221; said Emma Irwin, a program manager in Microsoft’s Open Source Program Office. &#8220;I am honored to bring this intention and my expertise to the OES&#8217;s Contributor Covenant 3.0 working group.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9pYoW1THk6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-open-source-and-dev-tools-part-1-of-2/">Where top VCs are investing in open source and dev tools (Part 1 of 2)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where top VCs are investing in open source and dev tools (Part 1 of 2)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-open-source-and-dev-tools-part-1-of-2/embed/#?secret=9pYoW1THk6" data-secret="9pYoW1THk6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/the-open-source-contributor-covenant-is-now-managed-by-the-organization-for-ethical-source/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Utah DOT pilots Blyncsy&#8217;s AI-powered road maintenance technology</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/utah-dot-pilots-blyncsys-ai-powered-road-maintenance-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/utah-dot-pilots-blyncsys-ai-powered-road-maintenance-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 16:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blyncsy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[road maintenance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[utah dot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you drive past potholes and faded lane dividers on your morning commute to work, chances are you&#8217;ll continue to see such road blemishes until someone alerts the local department of transportation to the problem by filing a complaint. Utah-based startup Blyncsy wants to help governments be a bit more preemptive than that. The movement [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you drive past potholes and faded lane dividers on your morning commute to work, chances are you&#8217;ll continue to see such road blemishes until someone alerts the local department of transportation to the problem by filing a complaint. Utah-based startup <a href="https://blyncsy.com/">Blyncsy</a> wants to help governments be a bit more preemptive than that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The movement and data intelligence company is launching an AI-powered technology, called Payver, that will use crowd-sourced video data to give transport agencies up-to-date information on which roads require maintenance and improvements. Blyncsy is offering this service to governments at a reduced cost and with no long-term commitment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Utah’s DOT will be the first to pilot the program beginning June 1, deploying Payver in the Salt Lake County region, which covers more than 350 road miles. Blyncsy will be announcing other pilots in different states over the next few weeks. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Governments are typically a bit slower to adopt new technologies, and while the </span><a href="https://www.transportation.gov/smartcity"><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.S. DOT has spent more than $250 million in public and private funds for smart city</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and advanced transportation options, much of the progress tends to revolve around making public transit in cities greener and more efficient. Blyncsy founder and CEO Mark Pittman argues inefficient road maintenance is not only unsafe, but it also causes higher carbon emissions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The inspiration for Payver came in 2017 when the UDOT executive director set a goal that it would be the first department in the country to have real-time situational awareness on our roadways, and we’ve been working on solving that problem for them,” Pittman told TechCrunch. “They want to know what’s happening and when it’s happening automatically so the public doesn’t have to be involved. So if there’s roadside debris or stop signs missing or paint lines that need to be fixed, how does the department know without the public having to call and complain or without an accident occurring?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blyncsy’s Payver technology works by collecting any kind of HD images and videos from a variety of sources, such as Nexar dash cameras, and analyzing the data sets with machine vision to deliver output to customers. The insights are available to transit agencies in a dashboard format, but Payver also integrates into the maintenance management software that determines a rank order of repair jobs.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the UDOT pilot, Payver will initially focus on monitoring paint lines, which is the basic requirement to support an autonomous environment, but may expand into potholes, construction barrels, knocked over signs and whatever else can go wrong from daily wear. UDOT has a budget of about $90,000 for this pilot, according to Rob Miles, UDOT’s director of traffic and safety.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Right now, we do a lidar scan of our roadways every two years, so we’re always out there collecting data of some sort, but it’s not at a high enough fidelity that we can manage our striping off of it,” Miles told TechCrunch. “We&#8217;re still really managing striping off of public complaints. We&#8217;re hoping with a different data collection system that we can move from that complaint-based system to something that has less opinion and more measurable data behind it.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pittman said optimizing active mobility forms by helping predict repairs needed for pedestrian crossings or safe locations for bike lanes will be a priority for Payver as the technology advances, which is important for maintaining equity and inclusion in mobility. Payver can also help bridge the racial and socioeconomic gap in road conditions, says Pittman, helping DOTs deliver equitable services to the entire public.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Pete Buttigieg recently talked about how transportation as it is has helped support systemic racism at times and pigeonhole communities because of the way we build roads often with lower income populations being closer to freeways,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The same thing is also true when you think about roadway maintenance. Lower-income populations are much less likely to complain and higher-income populations are a lot more likely to complain, but the impact of a pothole in a low-income population means a broken axle, which can determine the viability of that family surviving. That&#8217;s not true in a high-income environment.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sy9081YMeb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/investment-in-construction-automation-is-essential-to-rebuilding-us-infrastructure/">Investment in construction automation is essential to rebuilding US infrastructure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investment in construction automation is essential to rebuilding US infrastructure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/investment-in-construction-automation-is-essential-to-rebuilding-us-infrastructure/embed/#?secret=sy9081YMeb" data-secret="sy9081YMeb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/utah-dot-pilots-blyncsys-ai-powered-road-maintenance-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158102</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breinify announces $11M seed to bring data science to the marketing team</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/breinify-announces-11m-seed-to-bring-data-science-to-the-marketing-team/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/breinify-announces-11m-seed-to-bring-data-science-to-the-marketing-team/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 16:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battlefield alums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breinify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gutbrain Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PBJ Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personalization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Breinify is a startup working to apply data science to personalization, and do it in a way that makes it accessible to nontechnical marketing employees to build more meaningful customer experiences. Today the company announced a funding round totaling $11 million. The investment was led by Gutbrain Ventures and PBJ Capital with participation from Streamlined [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://home.breinify.ai/">Breinify</a> is a startup working to apply data science to personalization, and do it in a way that makes it accessible to nontechnical marketing employees to build more meaningful customer experiences. Today the company announced a funding round totaling $11 million.</p>
<p>The investment was led by Gutbrain Ventures and PBJ Capital with participation from Streamlined Ventures, CXO Fund, Amino Capital, Startup Capital Ventures and Sterling Road.</p>
<p>Breinify co-founder and CEO Diane Keng says that she and co-founder and CTO Philipp Meisen started the company to bring predictive personalization based on data science to marketers with the goal of helping them improve a customer&#8217;s experience by personalizing messages tailored to individual tastes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re big believers that the world, especially consumer brands, really need strong predictive personalization. But when you think about consumer big brands or the retailers that you buy from, most of them aren&#8217;t data scientists, nor do they really know how to activate [machine learning] at scale,&#8221; Keng told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>She says that she wanted to make this type of technology more accessible by hiding the complexity behind the algorithms powering the platform. &#8220;Instead of telling you how powerful the algorithms are, we show you [what that means for the] consumer experience, and in the end what that means for both the consumer and you as a marketer individually,&#8221; she said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fAHyC4UnMa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/klaviyo-ec1-marketing/">Marketing in 2021 is emotional and not just transactional</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Marketing in 2021 is emotional and not just transactional&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/klaviyo-ec1-marketing/embed/#?secret=fAHyC4UnMa" data-secret="fAHyC4UnMa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That involves the kind of customizations you might expect around website messaging, emails, texts or whatever channel a marketer might be using to communicate with the buyer. &#8220;So the AI decides you should be shown these products, this offer, this specific promotion at this time, [whether it&#8217;s] the web, email or SMS. So you&#8217;re not getting the same content across different channels, and we do all that automatically for you, and that&#8217;s [driven by the algorithms],&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Breinify launched in 2016 and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/12/breinify-tells-online-retailers-what-customers-want-to-buy-at-a-specific-point-in-time/">participated in the TechCrunch Disrupt Startup Battlefield</a> competition in San Francisco that year. She said it was early days for the company, but it helped them focus their approach. &#8220;I think it gave us a huge stage presence. It gave us a chance to test out the idea just to see where the market was in regards to needing a solution like this. We definitely learned a lot. I think it showed us that people were interested in personalization,&#8221; she said. And although the company didn&#8217;t win the competition, it ended up walking away with a funding deal.</p>
<p>Today the startup is growing fast and has 24 employees, up from 10 last year. Keng, who is an Asian woman, places a high premium on diversity.</p>
<p>&#8220;We partner with about four different kinds of diversity groups right now to source candidates, but at the end of the day, I think if you are someone that&#8217;s eager to learn, and you might not have all the skills yet, and you&#8217;re [part of an under-represented] group we encourage everyone to apply as much as possible. We put a lot of work into trying to create a really well-rounded group,&#8221; she said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4mI67l6AGq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/12/breinify-tells-online-retailers-what-customers-want-to-buy-at-a-specific-point-in-time/">Breinify tells online retailers what customers want to buy at a specific point in time</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Breinify tells online retailers what customers want to buy at a specific point in time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/12/breinify-tells-online-retailers-what-customers-want-to-buy-at-a-specific-point-in-time/embed/#?secret=4mI67l6AGq" data-secret="4mI67l6AGq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/breinify-announces-11m-seed-to-bring-data-science-to-the-marketing-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158293</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coda&#8217;s Shishir Mehrotra and Madrona&#8217;s S. Somasegar to talk taking on Google on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/codas-shishir-mehrotra-and-madronas-s-somasegar-to-talk-taking-on-google-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/codas-shishir-mehrotra-and-madronas-s-somasegar-to-talk-taking-on-google-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Madrona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S. Somasegar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shishir Mehrotra]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Collaborative software is so hot right now, but the space is also incredibly crowded. It can be hard to rise above the noise, but Coda has managed to do so with $140 million in funding and a valuation topping $600 million. So it should go without saying that we&#8217;re excited to hear from Coda CEO [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Collaborative software is so hot right now, but the space is also incredibly crowded. It can be hard to rise above the noise, but Coda has managed to do so with $140 million in funding and a valuation topping $600 million.</p>
<p>So it should go without saying that we&#8217;re excited to hear from Coda CEO Shishir Mehrotra and Madrona investor S. Somasegar, who invested in the company&#8217;s Series C round, on an upcoming episode of <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-madrona-and-coda">Extra Crunch Live</a>.</p>
<p>Soma is a managing director at Madrona, responsible for investments in Snowflake, UIPath, Coda, Pulumi, Seekout and more. He invests in a broad array of categories, including machine learning, next-gen cloud infrastructure, future of work, robotic process automation and more.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Before Madrona, Soma spent 27 years at Microsoft as SVP of the Developer Division. He&#8217;s got experience both as an operator and investor and will have plenty of wisdom to impart on the episode.</p>
<p>Mehrotra, for his part, has built a pretty massive business that has not only scaled well, but competes directly with giants like Google. Coda is a collaborative doc/spreadsheet software that looks to take on the G Suite. Before Coda, Mehrotra was an executive at YouTube and, prior to that, held leadership roles at Microsoft working on Windows, Office and SQL Server.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll talk to these two about fundraising for a product like Coda, what attracted Soma to the platform and how they work alongside one another today. We&#8217;ll also have an Extra Crunch Live Pitch-Off, where folks in the audience can come on &#8220;stage&#8221; and pitch their wares. Mehrotra and Soma will give their live feedback and, let&#8217;s face it, make all of us better at pitching in general.</p>
<p>The episode goes down on June 2 at 3 p.m. EDT/noon PDT and is accessible to anyone. However, only Extra Crunch members can access this episode (and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">entire ECL library</a>) on-demand. If you&#8217;re not a member yet, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">join here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-madrona-and-coda">Register here to hang out with us on the episode.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/codas-shishir-mehrotra-and-madronas-s-somasegar-to-talk-taking-on-google-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158319</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dapper Labs backs art hardware startup Infinite Objects in $6 million seed raise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/dapper-labs-backs-art-hardware-startup-infinite-objects-in-6-million-seed-raise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/dapper-labs-backs-art-hardware-startup-infinite-objects-in-6-million-seed-raise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 16:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beeple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brooklyn bridge ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christie's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courtside VC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dapper Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infinite Objects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national basketball association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nifty Gateway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Serena Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2157906</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The NFT world is all about reshaping the idea of digital ownership, but art hardware startup Infinite Objects sees a big opportunity in making physical copies of those assets as it looks to reshape digital art and collectibles. The startup makes screens that show a single video from a single artist and don&#8217;t do anything [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The NFT world is all about reshaping the idea of digital ownership, but art hardware startup <a href="https://infiniteobjects.com/">Infinite Objects</a> sees a big opportunity in making physical copies of those assets as it looks to reshape digital art and collectibles.</p>
<p>The startup makes screens that show a single video from a single artist and don&#8217;t do anything else. You can&#8217;t download apps to the screens or upload your own photos to them or check the time or weather. If you even want another piece of art from Infinite Objects, you can&#8217;t just download it, you have to actually go to their site and buy another display with that artwork on it. Each screen boasts information about the work, edition numbers and serial numbers etched on the back of it, inextricably tying the physical display to the work that it displays.</p>
<p>Infinite Objects CEO Joe Saavedra tells TechCrunch they&#8217;ve raised $6 million in seed funding from a host of backers including Courtside VC, which led the deal, and NBA Top Shot creator Dapper Labs.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For the longest time, Infinite Objects was an NFT platform without the NFTs. The company has worked with artists since 2018 to make (often limited run) series of physical display frames highlighting a specific digital work of the artist that looped forever. Sure, users could watch that looping video on the Infinite Objects website whenever they wanted, but the value was in owning an official copy of that artist&#8217;s work. Sound familiar?</p>
<p>When the wider popularity of NFTs as a speculative asset hit earlier this year, Saavedra saw a huge opportunity as internet users began discussing the future of digital art and digital scarcity. His team had already flirted with NFTs, partnering with artist Beeple back in December &#8212; months before he would spring out of relative obscurity in art circles with a $69 million sale at the Christie&#8217;s auction house &#8212; to release &#8220;physical tokens&#8221; of NFTs he was selling on the platform Nifty Gateway.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">TONIGHT 7PM EST <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/niftygateway?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@niftygateway</a> <a href="https://t.co/QeeDdBSNCv">https://t.co/QeeDdBSNCv</a> <a href="https://t.co/JyGEEUahok">pic.twitter.com/JyGEEUahok</a></p>
<p>&mdash; beeple (@beeple) <a href="https://twitter.com/beeple/status/1337409682328129542?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 11, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Saavedra sees a bigger opportunity for companies and creators in the NFT world to make their assets more approachable and understandable to a general audience with what his company is building, but he also sees a chance to transform NFTs from blind ownership to something more focused on actually appreciating the digital art that&#8217;s been purchased.</p>
<p>&#8220;When it comes to ownership, it&#8217;s exciting to be buying an NFT for $500 or $5,000, but what&#8217;s not exciting is having to open Safari on your phone to show it off,&#8221; Saavedra tells TechCrunch. &#8220;This physical vessel that we&#8217;ve designed is just so understandable for people who maybe don&#8217;t even understand what the blockchain at all, but they certainly understand limited edition physical merchandise.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tmTo7PbY6t"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/">The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NFT market is just getting started, but where is it headed?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/15/the-nft-market-is-just-getting-started-but-where-is-it-headed/embed/#?secret=tmTo7PbY6t" data-secret="tmTo7PbY6t" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Saavedra is dismissive of other digital displays that cycle through artwork and says that art owners could also just toss images of their NFTs onto the TV if they wanted to, but that they all only serve up art as &#8220;glorified screensavers.&#8221;</p>
<p>The team at Infinite Objects sees broader opportunities in the NFT world but they&#8217;ve been tight-lipped on exactly what these efforts will look like. You can see some potential hints in the list of backers in this round, including most interestingly NBA Top Shot creator Dapper Labs. The startup has been building out its own blockchain called Flow and Saavedra was quick to sing its praises in our conversation, noting that it&#8217;s more scalable and sustainable than the Ethereum network. Dapper Labs recently announced its first major third-party NFT platform, partnering with avatar startup Genies &#8212; another investor in this round &#8212; for a digital accessories storefront that&#8217;s being launched this summer.</p>
<p>Serena Ventures, Betaworks, Brooklyn Bridge Ventures, GFR Fund, Kevin Durant &amp; Rich Kleiman, Genies and Ashton Kutcher&#8217;s Sound Ventures also participated in the round.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="51y8jhQWbg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/avatar-startup-genies-scores-65-million-in-funding-round-led-by-mary-meekers-bond/">Avatar startup Genies scores $65 million in funding round led by Mary Meeker&#8217;s Bond</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Avatar startup Genies scores $65 million in funding round led by Mary Meeker&#8217;s Bond&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/avatar-startup-genies-scores-65-million-in-funding-round-led-by-mary-meekers-bond/embed/#?secret=51y8jhQWbg" data-secret="51y8jhQWbg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/dapper-labs-backs-art-hardware-startup-infinite-objects-in-6-million-seed-raise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2157906</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter Spaces will be available for the web, including accessibility features</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/twitter-spaces-will-be-available-for-web-including-accessibility-features/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/twitter-spaces-will-be-available-for-web-including-accessibility-features/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 16:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ned Segal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter Spaces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2158345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday evening, Twitter announced that Spaces &#8212; its Clubhouse competitor &#8212; will start rolling out for use on the web. Earlier this month, Twitter Spaces became available for any user with more than 600 followers on the iOS or Android apps, and around the same time, Clubhouse finally released its long-awaited Android app. Still, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Wednesday evening, Twitter announced that </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/twitter-spaces/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spaces</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; its Clubhouse competitor &#8212; will start rolling out for use on the web. Earlier this month, Twitter Spaces became available for any user with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/twitter-expands-spaces-to-anyone-with-600-followers-details-plans-for-tickets-reminders-and-more/">more than 600 followers</a> on the iOS or Android apps, and around the same time, Clubhouse finally released its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/09/clubhouse-android-app-launch/">long-awaited Android app</a>. Still, Clubhouse has yet to debut on the web, marking a success for Twitter in the race to corner the live social audio market. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even Instagram is positioning itself as a Clubhouse competitor, allowing users to “go live” </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/instagram-live-takes-on-clubhouse-with-options-to-mute-and-turn-off-the-video/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">with the ability to mute</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> their audio and video. How will each app differentiate itself? Twitter CFO Ned Segal attempted to address this at JP Morgan’s 49th Annual Technology, Media, &amp; Communications conference this week. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Twitter is where you go to find out what’s happening in the world and what people are talking about,” said Segal. “So when you come to Twitter, and you look at your home Timeline and you see a Space, it’s gonna perhaps be people who you don’t know but who are talking about a topic that’s incredibly relevant to you. It could be Bitcoin, it could be the aftershock from the Grammys, it could be that they’re talking about the NFL Draft.” </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter’s </span><a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1397688581846568961"><span style="font-weight: 400;">focus areas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the web version of Spaces include a UI that adapts to the user’s screen size and reminders for scheduled Spaces. Before joining a space, Twitter will display a preview that shows who is in a Space, and a description of the topic being discussed. Users will also be able to have a Space open on the right side of their screen while still scrolling through their Timeline.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2158349" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2158349" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2158349 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/twitterspaces-2.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="467" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/twitterspaces-2.jpeg 1292w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/twitterspaces-2.jpeg?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/twitterspaces-2.jpeg?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/twitterspaces-2.jpeg?resize=768,528 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/twitterspaces-2.jpeg?resize=680,467 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/twitterspaces-2.jpeg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2158349" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most crucially, this update lists accessibility and transcriptions as a focus area. For an audio-only platform, live transcriptions are necessary for Deaf and hard-of-hearing people to join in on the conversation. In screenshots Twitter shared of the new features, we can see how live captions will appear in Spaces. As for how accurate these transcriptions will be, the jury&#8217;s still out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter fielded </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/somehow-twitter-does-not-have-a-team-dedicated-to-accessibility/#:~:text=Twitter%20does%20not%20have%20a%20team%20dedicated%20to%20accessibility%2C%20the,developer%20alluded%20to%20the%20fact.&amp;text=That%20Twitter%20has%20no%20accessibility,features%20for%20people%20with%20disabilities."><span style="font-weight: 400;">well-deserved criticism</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last year when it failed to include captioning on its audio tweet feature. In </span><a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1273794890543935488?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1273794890543935488%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Ftechcrunch.com%2F2020%2F06%2F18%2Fsomehow-twitter-does-not-have-a-team-dedicated-to-accessibility%2F"><span style="font-weight: 400;">an apology tweet</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Twitter Support wrote, “Accessibility should not be an afterthought.” By September, Twitter launched </span><a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/making-twitter-more-accessible.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">two accessibility teams</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, accessibility has often been treated as an afterthought throughout the rise of live audio. Clubhouse does not yet support live captioning. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rq1gpNFOEu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/">Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse UX teardown: A closer look at homepage curation, follow hooks and other features&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/clubhouse-ux-teardown-a-closer-look-at-homepage-curation-follow-hooks-and-other-features/embed/#?secret=rq1gpNFOEu" data-secret="rq1gpNFOEu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/27/twitter-spaces-will-be-available-for-web-including-accessibility-features/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158345</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
