<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 14:15:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Cheltenham’s GCHQ to get a massive, cyber-oriented tech startup campus right next door</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/cheltenhams-gchq-to-get-a-massive-cyber-oriented-tech-startup-campus-right-next-door/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/cheltenhams-gchq-to-get-a-massive-cyber-oriented-tech-startup-campus-right-next-door/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 14:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2184037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the UK’s spying headquarters of GCHQ was established in the city in the 1950’s, Cheltenham has attracted large firms like IBM, Raytheon, Microsoft, BAE Systems to the region. However, startups like Truststamp, Bamboo Technologies, Ripjar, Hub8, CYNAM, have emerged out of the city, which draws on the talent that naturally gravitates to such a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Since the UK’s spying headquarters of <a href="https://www.gchq.gov.uk/">GCHQ</a> was established in the city in the 1950’s, Cheltenham has attracted large firms like IBM, Raytheon, Microsoft, BAE Systems to the region. However, startups like Truststamp, Bamboo Technologies, Ripjar, Hub8, CYNAM, have emerged out of the city, which draws on the talent that naturally gravitates to such a place, especially when you have these kinds of organisations floating around.</p>
<p>Now it appears that Cheltenham is getting its act together to more closely target entrepreneurs, investors and startups, especially now that the Covid-pandemic has seen talent thrown to the four winds, looking for better lifestyles and more access to nature. Smartly, it will be leveraging its association with the cyber-security-oriented GCHQ.</p>
<p>In 2019, Cheltenham Borough Council spent £37.5m purchasing 45 hectares of land adjacent to GCHQ. The idea being to capitalize on the burgeoning cybersecurity and technology community.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OtfPdAZ7y3A?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;start=1&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>After a year-long selection process the Council has now selected key partners as ‘preferred bidders’ to deliver it – Factory and HBD (formerly Henry Boot Developments). The ambition is to grow the area to 200 hectares, which would make it one of the biggest tech startup campuses in Europe.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.factory.com/">Factory</a>, which developed the very large scale tech campuses in Berlin and Lisbon, will partner with UK developer <a href="https://hbd.co.uk/">HBD</a> and the council to create the project currently dubbed ‘<a href="https://www.goldenvalleyuk.com/">Golden Valley</a>’.</p>
<p>The development is projected to add 12,000 new jobs, 2 million square feet of offices, and 3,700 new homes, and will be drawn on the ‘Garden City’ status, building upon the Garden City Movement established in the late 19th Century by Ebenezer Howard.</p>
<p>Jeremy Bamberg, who will be leading the project locally for Factory said: “This is a once in a lifetime project – it’s unprecedented. By embracing tech, nature, and innovation we’re working to transform the area into Europe’s most intelligent Garden District – creating an ideal alternative to chaotic city life.”</p>
<p>The first step of the project will be building, Factory Cheltenham. As with Factory’s projects in Berlin and Lisbon, the architecture and design will led by Julian Breinersdorfer, who recently joined Factory to create an in-house offering for similar buildings and districts.</p>
<p>Tim Atkins from Cheltenham Borough Council said: “We were looking for a partner to help the Council make our ambitious plans a reality. HBD and Factory have shown us how they share these goals and more importantly, how these will be transformed into a living breathing entity right here in Cheltenham that has a positive impact locally, whilst being a key part of the global cyber sector.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2184047" style="width: 705px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2184047" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg" alt="Factory Cheltenham" width="695" height="463" class="size-full wp-image-2184047" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg 695w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/F_CHLTNHM_1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 695px) 100vw, 695px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2184047" class="wp-caption-text">Factory Cheltenham</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/cheltenhams-gchq-to-get-a-massive-cyber-oriented-tech-startup-campus-right-next-door/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2184037</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth is not enough</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-is-not-enough/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-is-not-enough/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alphabet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ascap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contentful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lordstown Motors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peppy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Redwood Materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. We were a smaller team this week, with Natasha and Alex together with Grace and Chris to sort through a week that brought together both this quarter&#8217;s earnings cycle, and the Q3 IPO rush. So, it was just a little busy! Before [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/c466ab16-5d47-4cc8-b3ee-66ee9f0a4c75?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>We were a smaller team this week, with <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> together with <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/cgates123">Chris</a> to sort through a week that brought together both this quarter&#8217;s earnings cycle, and the Q3 IPO rush. So, it was just a little busy!</p>
<p>Before we get to topics, however, a note that we are having a lot of fun recording these live on Twitter Spaces. We&#8217;ve found a hacky way to capture local audio and also share the chats live. So, <a href="http://twitter.com/equitypod">hit us up on Twitter</a> so you can hang out with us. It&#8217;s fun &#8211; and we may even bring you up on stage to play guest host.</p>
<p>Ok, now, to the Great List of Subjects:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Robinhood went public!</strong> Yep, at long last, it is done. The company priced at $38 per share, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/robinhood-targets-ipo-valuation-up-to-35b-amid-warning-that-crypto-incomes-are-slipping/">the low end of its range</a>, and had a medium-weak day of trading once it started to float. In short, Robinhood seems to have deftly priced its IPO, leaving zero fat on the table. So, it is now richer than ever, and public. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/what-robinhoods-warnings-about-crypto-trading-say-about-coinbases-near-term-future/">More here</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Earnings! </strong>We took a moment to chat about earnings reports <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/alphabet-crushes-q2-earnings-estimates-as-google-cloud-cuts-losses-grows-54/">from Alphabet</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/microsoft-bests-earnings-estimates-as-azure-posts-51-growth-shares-fall/">and Microsoft</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/shopifys-q2-results-beat-estimates-as-e-commerce-shines/">and Shopify</a>. Why? Because we care lots about the cloud and platform companies. So, we took a minute to chat about public cloud results, and what Shopify got up to.</li>
<li><strong>Batteries!</strong> Tesla is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/what-teslas-bet-on-iron-based-batteries-means-for-manufacturers/">moving towards iron-based batteries</a>, and is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/tesla-bhp-ink-supply-deal-for-nickel-ahead-of-demand-surge/">looking to source other materials direct</a>. At the same time <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/redwood-materials-raises-700m-to-expand-its-battery-recycling-operation/">battery recycling is raising lots of cash</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/26/troubled-ev-company-lordstown-motors-gets-400m-lifeline-in-stock-sale-agreement/">Nikola is Not Dead</a>. We call it two truths and a lie.</li>
<li><strong>Unicorns and soon-to-be&#8217;s</strong>: Contentful <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/contenful-raises-175m-from/">raised $175M at a $3B valuation from Tiger</a> for its content delivery service, Squire, a barbershop tech platform, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/squire-a-barbershop-tech-platform-triples-its-valuation-again-with-tiger-global/">tripled its valuation (again) with Tiger Global (again)</a>, and Class squashed acquisition rumors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/class-a-zoom-only-virtual-classroom-nears-unicorn-status-after-softbank-check/">with SoftBank Vision Fund II funding</a>,</li>
<li><strong>More venture rounds!</strong> To cap off our venture roundup, two neat healthtech investments stood out, namely rounds <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/oova-raises-1-2m-to-develop-a-better-at-home-kit-for-detecting-a-womans-best-time-to-conceive/">from both Oova</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/2182193/">and Peppy.</a> Both startups agree with the idea that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/hormonal-health-is-a-massive-opportunity-where-are-the-unicorns/">hormonal health is a massive yet nascent opportunity</a>. (We did an entire show about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/the-imbalanced-landscape-of-hormonal-health/?tpcc=ECTW2020">the imbalanced world of hormone startups</a> if you&#8217;re interested).</li>
<li>We ended on a musical note, which lucky for you all, didn&#8217;t include us singing: meet <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/ascap-lab-highlights-a-quartet-of-early-stage-music-startups/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a quartet of early-stage music startups</span></a></li>
</ul>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content"><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PDT, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/growth-is-not-enough/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183798</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Platform as a service startup Porter aims to become go-to for deploying, managing cloud-based apps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/platform-as-a-service-startup-porter-aims-to-become-go-to-platform-for-deploying-managing-cloud-based-apps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/platform-as-a-service-startup-porter-aims-to-become-go-to-platform-for-deploying-managing-cloud-based-apps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethan batraski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heroku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Rhee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kubernetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soma capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[translink capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trevor Shim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Any DevOps team can use Porter to manage applications in the cloud, delivering the full flexibility of Kubernetes through a Heroku-like experience.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">By the time Porter co-founders Trevor Shim and Justin Rhee decided to build a company around DevOps, the pair were well versed in doing remote development on Kubernetes. And like other users, they were consistently getting burnt by the technology.</p>
<p>They realized that for all of the benefits, the technology was there, but users were having to manage the complexity of hosting solutions as well as incurring the costs associated with a big DevOps team, Rhee told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>They decided to build a solution externally and went through Y Combinator’s Summer 2020 batch, where they found other startup companies trying to do the same.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Today, Porter announced $1.5 million in seed funding from Venrock, Translink Capital, Soma Capital and several angel investors. Its goal is to build a platform as a service that any team can use to manage applications in its own cloud, essentially delivering the full flexibility of Kubernetes through a Heroku-like experience.</p>
<p>Why Heroku? It is the hosting platform that developers are used to, and not just small companies, but also later-stage companies. When they want to move to Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud or DigitalOcean, Porter will be that bridge, Shim said.</p>
<p>However, while Heroku is still popular, the pair said companies are thinking the platform is getting outdated because it is standing still technology-wise. Each year, companies move on from the platform due to technical limitations and cost, Rhee said.</p>
<p>A big part of the bet Porter is taking is not charging users for hosting, and its cost is a pure SaaS product, he said. They aren’t looking to be resellers, so companies can use their own cloud, but Porter will provide the automation and users can pay with their AWS and GCP credits, which gives them flexibility.</p>
<p>A common pattern is a move into Kubernetes, but “the zinger we talk about” is if Heroku was built in 2021, it would have been built on Kubernetes, Shim added.</p>
<p>“So we see ourselves as a successor’s successor,” he said.</p>
<p>To be that bridge, the company will use the new funding to increase its engineering bandwidth with the goal of “becoming the de facto standard for all startups.” Shim said.</p>
<p>Porter’s platform went live in February, and in six months became the sixth-fastest growing open-source platform download on GitHub, said Ethan Batraski, partner at Venrock. He met the company through YC and was “super impressed with Rhee’s and Shim’s vision.</p>
<p>“Heroku has 100,000 developers, but I believe it has stagnated,” Batraski added. “Porter already has 100 startups on its platform. The growth they’ve seen — four or five times — is what you want to see at this stage.”</p>
<p>His firm has long focused on data infrastructure and is seeing the stack get more complex, saying “at the same time, more developers are wanting to build out an app over a week, and scale it to millions of users, but that takes people resources. With Kubernetes it can turn everyone into an expert developer without them knowing it.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zdERUWM4rV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/4-enterprise-developer-trends-that-will-shape-2021/">4 enterprise developer trends that will shape 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 enterprise developer trends that will shape 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/4-enterprise-developer-trends-that-will-shape-2021/embed/#?secret=zdERUWM4rV" data-secret="zdERUWM4rV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/platform-as-a-service-startup-porter-aims-to-become-go-to-platform-for-deploying-managing-cloud-based-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183332</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gopuff confirms new $1B cash injection at a $15B valuation to expand its instant grocery delivery service</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gopuff-confirms-new-1b-cash-injection-at-a-15b-valuation-to-expand-its-instant-grocery-delivery-service/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gopuff-confirms-new-1b-cash-injection-at-a-15b-valuation-to-expand-its-instant-grocery-delivery-service/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gopuff, the startup that&#8217;s helped kickstart a new category of food delivery in the U.S. &#8212; &#8220;instant&#8221; delivery of essential groceries and other home goods for a flat fee of $1.95, 24 hours a day &#8212; has closed a huge tranche of funding to help it scale its service further across the country and globe. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://gopuff.com/">Gopuff</a>, the startup that&#8217;s helped kickstart a new category of food delivery in the U.S. &#8212; &#8220;instant&#8221; delivery of essential groceries and other home goods for a flat fee of $1.95, 24 hours a day &#8212; has closed a huge tranche of funding to help it scale its service further across the country and globe. It&#8217;s raised $1 billion in a Series H round that values the Philadelphia-based company at $15 billion.</p>
<p dir="ltr">New backers Blackstone’s Horizons platform, Guggenheim Investments, Hedosophia, and Adage Capital, and previous backers Fidelity Management and Research Company, Softbank Vision Fund 1, Atreides Management, and Eldridge Capital all participated in the round.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This news confirms our scoop of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/filing-instant-grocery-startup-gopuff-is-raising-750m-more-at-a-13-5b-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last week</a>, when reported on this Series H as it was still being closed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">Gopuff said it plans to use the funding to continue expanding in North America, the UK (where it has already <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210506006037/en/Gopuff-Jumpstarts-International-Expansion-with-Acquisition-of-UK-Based-Fancy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired</a> one company, Fancy, and, sources tell us, is acquiring another, Dija), and Europe; on more hiring; and to continue building out the tech platform that bridges an ecosystem that includes customers, drivers, suppliers and distribution centers.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It currently operates 450 sites across North America and the UK, with includes more than 285 dark stores (or &#8220;micro-fulfillment centers&#8221; in Gopuff&#8217;s words), plus more than 185 retailers by way of its acquisition of BevMo earlier this year.</p>
<p dir="ltr">One of the reasons that Gopuff has raised such a large sum is that building out food-based, logistics-fueled, transportation business along all of those parameters is capital-intensive.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But also, that effort to grow is coming amidst a strong surge of competition. Getir out of Turkey, backed by Sequoia and others and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/instant-grocery-startup-getir-makes-its-first-acquisition-to-expand-into-spain-and-italy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most recently valued at $7.5 billion</a>, is also aggressively expanding. And just looking at Europe, there are a wave of others such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/flink-the-german-grocery-delivery-startup-raises-240m-after-launching-just-6-months-ago/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flink</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/gorillacorn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gorillas</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/spains-glovo-picks-up-528m-as-the-food-deliver-market-continues-to-heat-up/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Glovo</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/zapp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zapp</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/dija-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cajoo</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/london-based-weezy-raises-seed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Weezy</a> also bulking up their bank accounts to throw their delivery bags into the ring. (In the U.S., established delivery giants like DoorDash will also be moving deeper into Gopuff&#8217;s territory.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Gopuff believes it can give all of these and others a run for their money. Founded back in 2013 by Rafael Ilishayev and Yakir Gola &#8212; now co-CEOs &#8212; while they were still in university to fill a gap they saw in the market for students like themselves, Gopuff has expanded well beyond that by catering to anyone looking for a quick and relatively low-cost way of getting essential goods without physically going out to get those items themselves.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In a stretch of time where many of us were either being ordered by our municipal governments, or acting on our own decisions, to stay in place to curtail the spread of Covid-19, Gopuff&#8217;s star rose quickly as an easy way of complying without compromising our consumerist tendencies.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But Companies like Getir out of Turkey &#8212; which has been around for years also building out a model of &#8220;instant&#8221; delivery of essential goods &#8212; have demonstrated that there is staying power to the concept, and that is what Gopuff is betting on, too.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“<span class="il">Gopuff</span> has quietly built a very strong business and solidified itself as the leading player, continuing to define this evolving category,” said Scott Minerd, Global Chief Investment Officer of Guggenheim Investments, in a statement. “Rafael and Yakir are focused on maintaining fiscal responsibility while having the ability to successfully execute on strategic growth opportunities. This measured approach along with <span class="il">Gopuff</span>’s impressive offering has only just scratched the surface. We are thrilled to support this incredibly strong company and look forward to being part of <span class="il">Gopuff</span>’s journey and continued expansion.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Part of Gopuff&#8217;s strategy has been to augment the basic instant delivery of essentials model with more efficient distribution along with a wider vision of what constitutes essentials.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">So in addition to building out more localized “dark” stores to more easily distribute goods to customers who buy them, that has included starting “Gopuff kitchens” to make and deliver ready-made food; buying alcohol retailer <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/05/gopuff-acquires-bevmo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BevMo for $350 million</a> in November 2020; and acquiring more logistics technology, in the form of buying <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/delivery-service-gopuff-acquires-rideos-for-115-million-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rideOS for $115 million</a>.</p>
<p>Gopuff itself has been on a fundraising tear to finance all of this. It was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/gopuff-new-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">only in March</a> that it raised $1.15 billion at an $8.9 billion valuation, which came just months after a $380 million round at a $3.8 billion valuation. Together the three most recent rounds total around $2.5 billion in funding in the space of 10 months, and the idea here seems to be that there may be more of where that came from.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“As <span class="il">Gopuff</span> continues to define the Instant Needs economy, we are thrilled to have new leading global partners onboard, along with the support of our longtime investors. This funding round is further validation of the success of our model and will enable us to continue to do what we do best: deliver an unmatched customer experience,” said Ilishayev in a statement.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;We have truly doubled down on our key business priorities, accelerating our geographic expansion by entering new markets in the US and abroad, innovating for our customers, and continuing to invest heavily in our technology, our people, and our partners. We look forward to continuing to enhance the customer experience and to bring the magic of <span class="il">Gopuff</span> to new customers around the world,&#8221; added Yakir Gola<span class="il">.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/gopuff-confirms-new-1b-cash-injection-at-a-15b-valuation-to-expand-its-instant-grocery-delivery-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183996</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Catch takes hold of $12M to provide benefits that aren&#8217;t tied to employers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/catch-takes-hold-of-12m-to-provide-benefits-that-arent-tied-to-employers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/catch-takes-hold-of-12m-to-provide-benefits-that-arent-tied-to-employers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crosslink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employee benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig workers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindred Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyca partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Innovation Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183338</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Catch is working to make sure that every gig worker has the health and retirement benefits they need.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.catch.co/">Catch</a> is working to make sure that every gig worker has the health and retirement benefits they need.</p>
<p>The company, which is in the midst of moving its headquarters to New York, sells health insurance, retirement savings plans and tax withholding directly to freelancers, contractors or anyone uncovered.</p>
<p>It is now armed with a fresh round of $12 million in Series A funding, led by Crosslink, with participation from earlier investors Khosla Ventures, NYCA Partners, Kindred Ventures and Urban Innovation Fund, to support more distribution partnerships and its relocation from Boston.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Co-founders Kristen Anderson and Andrew Ambrosino started Catch in 2019 and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/21/catch-benefits/">raised $6.1 million</a> previously, giving it a total of $18.1 million in funding.</p>
<p>It took the Catch team of 15 nearly two years to get approvals to sell its platform in 38 states on the federal marketplace. Anderson boasts that only eight companies have been able to do this, and three of them — Catch included — are approved to sell benefits to consumers.</p>
<p>“More companies are not offering healthcare, while more people are joining the creator and gig economies, which means more people are not following an employer-led model,” Anderson told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The age of an average Catch customer is 32, and in addition to current offerings, they were asking the company to help them set up income sources, like setting aside money for taxes, retirement and medical leave without having to actively save.</p>
<p>When the global pandemic hit, many of Catch’s customers saw their income collapse 40% overall across industries, as workers like hairstylists and cooks had income go down to zero in some cases.</p>
<p>It was then that Anderson and Ambrosino began looking at partnership distribution and developed a network of platforms, business facilitation tools, gig marketplaces and payroll companies that were interested in offering Catch. The company intends to use some of the funding to increase its headcount to service those partnerships and go after more, Anderson said.</p>
<p>Catch is one startup providing insurance products, and many of its competitors do a single offering and do it well, like Starship does with health savings accounts, Anderson said. Catch is taking a different approach by offering a platform experience, but going deep on the process, she added. She likens it to Gusto, which provides cloud-based payroll, benefits and human resource management for businesses, in that Catch is an end-to-end experience, but with a focus on an individual person.</p>
<p>Over the past year, the company’s user base tripled, driven by people taking on second jobs and through a partnership with DoorDash. Platform users are also holding onto five times their usual balances, a result of setting more goals and needing to save more, Anderson said. Retirement investments and health insurance have grown similarly.</p>
<p>Going forward, Anderson is already thinking about a Series B, but that won’t come for another couple of years, she said. The company is looking into its own HSA product as well as disability insurance and other products to further differentiate it from other startups, for example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/28/insurtech-startup-spot-brings-in-17-5m-equity-debt-to-fill-insurance-gaps-for-accidental-injuries/">Spot</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/meet-super-mx-the-mexico-city-based-insurtech-that-raised-7-2m-from-vcs-and-unicorn-ceos/">Super.mx</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/khosla-ventures-leads-evens-5m-seed-to-give-india-the-kind-of-healthcare-their-insurance-doesnt/">Even,</a> all of which raised venture capital this month to provide benefits.</p>
<p>Catch would also like to serve a broader audience than just those on the federal marketplace. The co-founders are working on how to do this — Anderson mentioned there are some “nefarious companies out there” offering medical benefits at rates that can seem too good to be true, but when the customer reads the fine print, they discover that certain medical conditions are not covered.</p>
<p>“We are looking at how to put the right thing in there because it does get confusing,” Anderson added. “Young people have cheaper options, which means they need to make sure they know what they are getting.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tCglsB08gP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/labor-leaders-and-startup-founders-talk-how-to-build-a-sustainable-gig-economy/">Labor leaders and startup founders talk how to build a sustainable gig economy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Labor leaders and startup founders talk how to build a sustainable gig economy&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/labor-leaders-and-startup-founders-talk-how-to-build-a-sustainable-gig-economy/embed/#?secret=tCglsB08gP" data-secret="tCglsB08gP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/catch-takes-hold-of-12m-to-provide-benefits-that-arent-tied-to-employers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183338</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airtel Africa gets an extra $200M for its mobile money business from QIA</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/airtel-africa-gets-an-extra-200m-for-its-mobile-money-business-from-qia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/airtel-africa-gets-an-extra-200m-for-its-mobile-money-business-from-qia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airtel Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qatar Investment Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommunications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TPG]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Qatar Holding LLC, an affiliate of Qatar Investment Authority, the sovereign wealth fund of Qatar, is set to invest $200 million into AMC BV through a secondary purchase of shares from Airtel Africa.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Three months ago, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/airtel-africa-receives-additional-100m-for-its-mobile-money-business-from-mastercard/">Mastercard invested $100 million</a> in Airtel Mobile Commerce BV (AMC BV) — the mobile money business of telecom</span><a href="https://airtel.africa/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Airtel Africa</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This was two weeks after it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/airtel-africa-sells-200m-mobile-money-business-stake-to-tpgs-rise-fund/">received $200 million from TPG&#8217;s Rise Fund</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the African telecoms operator said it has secured another investment for its mobile money arm. The investor? Qatar Holding LLC, an affiliate of the Qatar Investment Authority (QIA), the</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> sovereign wealth fund of the State of Qatar, with over $300 billion in assets. The Middle Eastern corporation is set to invest $200 million into AMC BV through a secondary </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">purchase</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of shares from Airtel Africa.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AMC BV is an Airtel Africa subsidiary and the holding company for several of Airtel Africa’s mobile money operations across 14 African countries, including Kenya, Uganda and Nigeria</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The mobile money arm operates one of the largest financial services on the continent. It provides</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> users access to mobile wallets, support for international money transfers, loans and virtual credit cards</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PITLIvIxMn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/airtel-africa-receives-additional-100m-for-its-mobile-money-business-from-mastercard/">Airtel Africa receives $100M for its mobile money business from Mastercard</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Airtel Africa receives $100M for its mobile money business from Mastercard&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/airtel-africa-receives-additional-100m-for-its-mobile-money-business-from-mastercard/embed/#?secret=PITLIvIxMn" data-secret="PITLIvIxMn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a statement released by the telecoms operator, the proceeds of the investment will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be used</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to reduce debt and invest in network and sales infrastructure in operating countries</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The deal will close in two tranches — $150 million invested at the first close, most likely in</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> August. The remaining $50 million will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">be invested</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at the second close.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Airtel Africa claims QIA will hold a minority stake while it continues to hold the majority stake. This transaction still values Airtel Africa at $2.65 billion on a cash and debt-free basis. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, what&#8217;s different this time is that QIA </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is entitled</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to appoint a director to AMC BV&#8217;s board and &#8220;to certain customary information and minority protection rights</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Airtel Africa&#8217;s most recent report for Q1 2021 shows signs of growth. The telecoms operator saw year-on-year revenue growth of 53.7%, pushed by 24.6% growth in customer base to 23.1 million. Transaction value went up 64.4% to $14.7 billion ($59 billion annualized), and EBITDA stood at $60 million ($240 million annualized) at a margin of 48.8%. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company also generated $124 million in revenue ($496 million annualized), while its profits before tax for Q1 2021 stood at $185 million</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mansoor bin Ebrahim Al-Mahmoud, CEO of QIA, said the sovereign wealth fund&#8217;s investment in Airtel Africa would help promote financial inclusion in sub-Saharan Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Airtel Money plays a critical role in facilitating economic activity, including for customers without access to traditional financial services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">firmly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> believe in its mission to expand these efforts over the coming years,” he added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In February, Airtel Africa first made it known that it wanted to sell a minority stake in AMC BV to raise cash and sell off some assets. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">subsequent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> month, it sold telecommunication towers in Madagascar and Malawi to Helios Towers for $119 million and raised</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $500 million from outside investors.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cnd9S1tof3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/airtel-africa-sells-200m-mobile-money-business-stake-to-tpgs-rise-fund/">Airtel Africa sells $200M mobile money business stake to TPG&#8217;s Rise Fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Airtel Africa sells $200M mobile money business stake to TPG&#8217;s Rise Fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/airtel-africa-sells-200m-mobile-money-business-stake-to-tpgs-rise-fund/embed/#?secret=cnd9S1tof3" data-secret="cnd9S1tof3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/airtel-africa-gets-an-extra-200m-for-its-mobile-money-business-from-qia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing the Open Cap Table Coalition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/introducing-the-open-cap-table-coalition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/introducing-the-open-cap-table-coalition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capitalization table]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cooley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fenwick & west]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gunderson Dettmer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orrick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183870</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If this coalition gets all the relationships right, doesn’t get greedy and understands that there is a social good component here, this could be as impactful as the SAFE was.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Aron Solomon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Aron Solomon, J.D., is the head of Strategy for<a href="https://www.esquiredigital.com/"> Esquire Digital</a> and the editor of<a href="https://todaysesquire.com/"> Today’s Esquire</a>. He has taught entrepreneurship at McGill University and the University of Pennsylvania, and was the founder of LegalX, a legal technology accelerator.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/if-you-dont-want-robotic-dogs-patrolling-the-streets-consider-ccops-legislation/">If you don&#8217;t want robotic dogs patrolling the streets, consider CCOPS legislation</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">On Tuesday, the Open Cap Table Coalition announced its launch <a href="https://medium.com/@opencaptable/announcing-the-open-cap-table-coalition-6c2764396e71">through an inaugural Medium post</a>. The goal of this project is to standardize startup capitalization table data as well as make it far more accessible, transparent and portable.</p>
<p>For those unfamiliar with a cap table, it’s a list of who owns your company’s securities, which includes your company shares, options and more. A clear and simple cap table should quickly indicate who owns what and how much of it they own. For a variety of reasons (sometimes inexperience or bad advice) too many equity holders often find companies&#8217; capitalization information to be opaque and not easily accessible.</p>
<p>This is particularly important for the small percentage of startups that survive in the long term, as growth makes for far more complicated cap tables.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A critical part of good startup hygiene is to always have a clean and updated cap table. Since there is no set format and cap tables are generally not out in the open, they are often siloed rather than collaborative.</p>
<p>Cap tables are near and dear to me as someone who has advised hundreds of startups over the past two decades as the founder of an accelerator, a venture partner and a senior adviser at a government-funded startup launchpad. I have been on the shareholder side of the equation as well and can assure you that pretty much nothing destroys trust between shareholders and startups quicker than poor communication, especially around issues such as the current status of the cap table.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			A critical part of good startup hygiene is to always have a clean and updated cap table. 					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>I really like the idea of a cap table being an open corporate record, because the value proposition to the companies is clear. From the time a startup creates a cap table, it’s prone to inaccuracy, friction and mistakes. What this means in practice is that startups may spend money on cap-table-related issues that they should be spending on other things. From a legal process perspective, the law firm that is brought in to help with these issues has to deal with tedious back-end work, so the legal time isn&#8217;t high value for either the startup or the law firm.</p>
<p>The value proposition for equity holders is equally clear. All equity holders have a general and legal interest in a company’s capitalization information. They have the right to this information, which they may need for a variety of reasons (including, if things ever get really bad, an aggrieved shareholder action). So making this information clear and easily accessible is a service to equity holders and can also encourage more investment, especially from less experienced investors.</p>
<p>When I imagine what this project could become in the next couple of years, I think back to late 2013, when Y Combinator announced the SAFE (simple agreement for future equity). I think the SAFE is a good analogy here, as no one knew what it was and people wondered if this was a nice-to-have rather than a must-have for startups. But the end result was a dramatic improvement in the early-stage capital-raising process.</p>
<p>While the coalition’s founders include Morgan Stanley’s Shareworks, LTSE Software and Carta, it’s also heavy on Big Law, with Cooley, Goodwin Procter, Wilson Sonsini Goodrich &amp; Rosati, Orrick, Gunderson Dettmer, Latham &amp; Watkins, and Fenwick &amp; West rounding out the group of 10 founding members.</p>
<p>So what’s the real motivation of seven law firms, which together saw revenue of over $10 billion in 2020 to collaborate on an open cap table product for startups? Deal flow.</p>
<p>Big Law has been trying for a couple of decades to build relationships with startups at the stage where it makes no sense for a startup to be dealing with a massive and expensive law firm. Their efforts to build startup programs have often fallen short and received mixed reviews. They have also been far too heavy on the self-serve and too light on the &#8220;we’re going to give you our regular Big Law level of services at a small fraction of the costs just in case you make it big and can one day pay our regular fees.&#8221; So these firms are trying to separate themselves from the rest of the Big Law pack by building this entrepreneur-friendly tech.</p>
<p>The coalition has already produced its initial version of the open cap table. The real question is whether this is going to be a big deal, as the SAFE was, or whether it’s going to be a vanity solution in search of a real problem. My best guess is that if this coalition gets all the relationships right, doesn’t get greedy and understands that there is a social good component at play here, this could be, reasonably quickly, as impactful as the SAFE was.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8B3M1gbv7J"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/23/before-an-exit-founders-must-get-their-employment-law-ducks-in-a-row/">Before an exit, founders must get their employment law ducks in a row</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Before an exit, founders must get their employment law ducks in a row&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/23/before-an-exit-founders-must-get-their-employment-law-ducks-in-a-row/embed/#?secret=8B3M1gbv7J" data-secret="8B3M1gbv7J" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/introducing-the-open-cap-table-coalition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183870</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Scarlett Johansson sues Disney, says streaming release of ‘Black Widow’ breaches contract</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/daily-crunch-37/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/daily-crunch-37/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for July 29, 2021. Between the IPO cycle and earnings it has been <em>quite</em> the day. And Nikola’s founder was indicted on three counts of fraud. It’s busy! Let’s get into it! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3 (OK, four, but it’s about Scarlett Johansson)</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/nikola-founder-trevor-milton-indicted-on-three-counts-of-fraud/">Nikola founder indicted on fraud charges:</a> </strong>From the <em>you saw this coming</em> files, former Nikola CEO and walking bottle of Mountain Dew Trevor Milton was indicted on three counts of fraud. Per the federal indictment unsealed by the U.S. attorney’s office in Manhattan on Thursday, the former exec “engaged in a fraudulent scheme to deceive retail investors.” Not a great day for SPACs, frankly.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/microsoft-in-talks-to-back-india-oyo/"><strong>Microsoft may invest in hotel unicorn OYO:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Here’s an odd one. Microsoft, the U.S. software giant, may invest in OYO, the India-based hotels startup that raised capital from SoftBank’s first Vision Fund. Why? Per our reporting, there may be some sort of cloud deal in the mix. Both parties are staying mum for now.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/why-latin-american-venture-capital-is-breaking-records-this-year/">The Latin American startup market is hitting its stride:</a> </strong>On the back of an epic boom in venture investment, founders in Latin America are finally getting their due, investors told TechCrunch. Between locally sourced capital, external funds and economies in the region that are increasingly digitally enabled, it’s a bullish time to build in the region.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/scarlett-johansson-files-suit-over-disney-black-widow-release/">Scarlett Johansson files suit over Disney+ ‘Black Widow’ release:</a></strong> The actress alleges Disney breached its agreement with her when it released the Marvel flick on streaming service Disney+ at the same time it landed in theaters. Johansson’s attorneys say Disney is “hiding behind COVID-19,” but with the delta variant being very much a problem, we must say we’d prefer to observe our Avengers films from our couches for the time being.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/tenderly-raises-15-3m-to-help-ethereum-developers-ship-decentralized-apps-faster/"><strong>Tenderly wants more dApps:</strong></a> Decentralized apps, or dApps, are a big category in the larger blockchain economy. And Tenderly, a startup that just raised $15.3 million, wants folks to build more of them. The company has built a “a developer platform for Ethereum devs to monitor and test the smart contracts that power their decentralized apps.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/colombias-merqueo-bags-50m-to-expand-its-online-grocery-delivery-service-across-latin-america/"><strong>Online grocery continues to attract capital:</strong></a> This time it’s Merqueo, which operates an on-demand service in Latin America. Between grocery delivery and so-called “instant” grocery startups, lots of capital is finding its way into the business of bringing food to folks’ houses. Merqueo just raised a $50 million Series C for its efforts.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/colombias-la-haus-secures-100m-in-debt-equity/">La Haus raises $100M for its online real estate marketplace:</a> </strong>La Haus is a Colombian startup, as is Merqueo. See, we told you that Latin America was busy! In this case, La Haus raised $50 million in equity capital and $50 million in debt. Per our reporting, the company saw “transactions conducted on its Mexico portal climb by nearly 10x in the second quarter of 2021 compared to the 2020 second quarter.” Not bad!</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/talkiatry-lands-20m-series-a-to-go-all-in-on-in-network-psychiatric-care/"><strong>More money for mental health:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Talkiatry announced earlier today that it has raised a $20 million Series A led by Left Lane Capital. The startup wants to make psychiatry services available through insurance providers and has partnered with a host of them. Anything to make mental health care easier and cheaper for consumers is good by us.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/hello-divorce-raises-2m-so-that-couples-can-say-good-bye-easier/"><strong>Hello Divorce raises $2M so your divorce won’t cost $2M:</strong></a> Getting divorced is about as much fun as putting broken glass in your shoe while taking a hike. At least that’s what our friends have told us. Hello Divorce wants to make the whole process better. Given that divorce is something that happens rather often to lots of folks, it certainly won’t lack for TAM.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/student-labor-marketplace-pangea-closes-2m-seed-round/"><strong>Pangea raises $2M for its student labor marketplace:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Hailing from Providence, Rhode Island, Pangea announced a seed round today. The company’s service connects digitally savvy college students with businesses looking for freelance talent. GMV is rising at the company, and now it has more capital in its accounts than ever. Let’s see how it grows the rest of the year.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/summit-invests-215m-into-odoo-an-open-source-business-management-software-developer-at-a-2-3b-valuation/"><strong>Odoo sells $215M of its stock:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Now worth over €2 billion, Odoo, an open-source business management software play, is the first unicorn out of Wallonia, a region in Belgium. The round was purely secondary, notably. The company provides most of its software for free, while charging for certain features.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/employee-engagement-platform-culture-amp-raises-100m-at-a-1-5b-valuation/"><strong>Employee-success startup CultureAmp raises $100M:</strong></a> The startup, which was founded to let companies poll their workers, is now worth $150 million. You can think of it as management analytics, providing “turnover prediction and team goal tracking,” per our own reporting.</li>
<li>In case you were looking for something entirely different, we present a <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/nothing-ear-1-review/">review of Nothing’s new earpods</a></strong>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in</h2>
<p>This year, livestream viewers in China are projected to spend more than $60 billion on digital shopping experiences where they can interact with influencers in real time.</p>
<p>Promoting everything from cosmetics to food, social media stars use Taobao, TikTok and other platforms to tout products and answer live questions.</p>
<p>On Taobao&#8217;s Single’s Day Global Shopping Festival in 2020, livestreams racked up $6 billion in sales, twice as much revenue as the year prior.</p>
<p>Sensing a trend, Western startups are getting in on the action, with companies like Whatnot and PopShop.Live raising rounds to build out their infrastructure. Looking forward, Alanna Gregory, senior global director at Afterpay, says she foresees four major trends:</p>
<ul>
<li>Networks.</li>
<li>SaaS streaming tools.</li>
<li>Host discovery and outreach tools.</li>
<li>Host marketplaces and agencies.</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8220;For brands, SaaS streaming tools will be the most impactful way to take advantage of livestream commerce trends,&#8221; Gregory writes in an Extra Crunch guest post. &#8220;All of this will be incredibly transformative.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MvDo0rUPI6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/embed/#?secret=MvDo0rUPI6" data-secret="MvDo0rUPI6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>We went a bit long on the startup side of things, so let’s be brief when it comes to Big Tech.</p>
<ul>
<li>First up, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/amazons-fire-tv-cube-now-supports-zoom-calls-on-your-tv/">Amazon’s FireTV Cube now supports Zoom</a>. Everything should support Zoom. Zoom is good. So, it’s both unsurprising and welcome that Amazon is building out greater integration with the video chat provider.</li>
<li>Next, Facebook’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/facebooks-next-product-will-be-its-long-awaited-ray-ban-smart-glasses/">next product</a> will be a collab with Ray-Ban to build smart glasses. How you feel about this bit of news will depend on what you think about Facebook, but as a former Google Glass fan I suppose I am willing to wait to make judgment.</li>
<li>PayPal <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/paypals-new-super-app-is-ready-to-launch-will-also-include-messaging/">has a super app in the wings</a>, a service that will include messaging. Do we want this? I don’t know, but super apps &#8212; mobile applications that encompass a wide range of services in a single package &#8212; are big around the world, so why not here in U.S. as well?</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We’re reaching out to startup founders to tell us who they turn to when they want the most up-to-date growth marketing practices. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Read one of the testimonials we’ve received below!</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong><a href="https://scottgraham.io/">Scott Graham</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommended by: </strong>Heather Larrabee, CMO, <a href="https://www.form.com/">FORM</a></p>
<p><strong>Testimonial: </strong>“He was referred to us and blew our socks off from his initial analysis. He’s the rare growth adviser expert at strategy and execution. He’s a servant leader, a systems thinker, integrates with the team with empathy and curiosity like he’s an internal teammate, brings a wealth of cutting-edge knowledge, and a stable of incredible partners and resources. He runs with the best and the brightest, but he’s the first one on and the last one off for the day, putting in the time to make things great. He has an uncanny ability to communicate complex concepts and make them accessible for all audiences, and he’s been a foundational game changer for our business and many others.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/daily-crunch-37/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183832</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another banner quarter as Chromebook shipments grow 75% YOY</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/another-banner-quarter-as-chromebook-shipments-grow-75-yoy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/another-banner-quarter-as-chromebook-shipments-grow-75-yoy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canalys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chromebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chromebooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChromeOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last quarter, Chromebooks saw 275% year-over-year growth up to 12 million units. The figure isn’t quite as unwieldy for Q2, but a 75% year-over-year growth is still extremely respectable, with the category hitting 11.9 million shipments, per the latest figures from research firm, Canalys. Chromebooks joined the rest of the PC market in getting an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last quarter, Chromebooks saw 275% year-over-year growth up to 12 million units. The figure isn’t quite as unwieldy for Q2, but a 75% year-over-year growth is still extremely respectable, with the category hitting 11.9 million shipments, <a href="https://www.canalys.com/newsroom/worldwide-pc-market-q2-2021?ctid=2161-0aed8a9c8d78ede020d78051fa8ee9b4">per the latest</a> figures from research firm, Canalys.</p>
<p>Chromebooks joined the rest of the PC market in getting an overall bump from the pandemic. Standard tablets and PCs saw healthy increases as consumers scrambled to create work from home setups, while Google’s OS got an even larger rise as schools implemented remote learning.</p>
<p>As schools in a number of locations have reopened more than a year into the pandemic, however, Chromebook sales are still hot. Google is certainly looking to capitalize on that success by once again attempting to extend the operating system’s reach beyond its educational foothold.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is clearly eyeing the enterprise segment, which may be welcoming of systems that are both easy to deploy and lock down.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183922" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183922" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2183922" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-29-at-5.59.17-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-29-at-5.59.17-PM.jpg 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-29-at-5.59.17-PM.jpg?resize=150,78 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-29-at-5.59.17-PM.jpg?resize=300,157 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-29-at-5.59.17-PM.jpg?resize=768,401 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-29-at-5.59.17-PM.jpg?resize=680,355 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-29-at-5.59.17-PM.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183922" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Canalys</p></div></p>
<p>“With Chrome’s hold over the education space relatively secure, Google is set to bet big on the commercial segment this year,” Canalys’ Brian Lynch said in a statement. We expect to see a strong focus on attracting small businesses with updated services, such as the new ‘Individual’ subscription tier for Google Workspace and promotions on CloudReady licenses to repurpose old PCs for deployment alongside existing Chromebook fleets.”</p>
<p>After the launch of multiple M1-based systems, Apple, too, is making a big play for business. The company recently launched a new<a href="https://www.apple.com/business/it/"> Apple at Work site</a>.</p>
<p>“Whether your organization has 10 devices or 10,000, Apple fits easily into your existing infrastructure,” the company writes of its new IT efforts. “Zero-touch deployment allows IT to configure and manage remotely, and IT can tailor the setup process to any team. So every Mac, iPad, iPhone and Apple TV is ready to go from the start.”</p>
<p>With Windows 11 arriving later this year, Microsoft will no doubt be making its own case to maintain dominance over the office — remote and otherwise.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="c9P8DdxWQ4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/forerunners-eurie-kim-and-ouras-harpreet-rai-discuss-betting-on-consumer-hardware/">Forerunner’s Eurie Kim and Oura’s Harpreet Rai discuss betting on consumer hardware</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Forerunner’s Eurie Kim and Oura’s Harpreet Rai discuss betting on consumer hardware&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/forerunners-eurie-kim-and-ouras-harpreet-rai-discuss-betting-on-consumer-hardware/embed/#?secret=c9P8DdxWQ4" data-secret="c9P8DdxWQ4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lIA4BBsMQC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/chromebook-shipments-grew-275-in-q1/">Chromebook shipments grew 275% in Q1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chromebook shipments grew 275% in Q1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/chromebook-shipments-grew-275-in-q1/embed/#?secret=lIA4BBsMQC" data-secret="lIA4BBsMQC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/another-banner-quarter-as-chromebook-shipments-grow-75-yoy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183921</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Varda Space Industries closes $42M Series A for off-planet manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/varda-space-industries-closes-42m-series-a-for-off-planet-manufacturing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/varda-space-industries-closes-42m-series-a-for-off-planet-manufacturing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 21:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delian Asparouhov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183871</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Varda Space Industries has raised a $42 million Series A to bring to manufacturing a key capability that can only be found off-world: microgravity. The eight-month-old startup is looking to establish its first manufacturing facility in space as early as 2023, and by doing so, bring back to Earth advanced products that can only be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Varda Space Industries has raised a $42 million Series A to bring to manufacturing a key capability that can only be found off-world: microgravity.</p>
<p>The eight-month-old startup is looking to establish its first manufacturing facility in space as early as 2023, and by doing so, bring back to Earth advanced products that can only be made under sustained periods of zero gravity.</p>
<p>The round was led by Khosla Ventures and Caffeinated Capital, with participation from existing investors Lux Capital, General Catalyst and Founders Fund. It pushes the company’s total raise thus far to over $50 million, including a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/space-manufacturing-startup-varda-incubated-at-founders-fund-emerges-with-9-million-in-funding/">$9 million seed round</a> last December.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://varda.com/">Varda’s</a> idea is different than that of Jeff Bezos, who said after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/blue-origins-new-shepard-carries-jeff-bezos-and-three-crew-members-to-space-and-back/">his own trip</a> to space earlier this month that he wants to “move all heavy industry and all polluting industry off Earth.” The company’s co-founders, SpaceX veteran Will Bruey and Founders Fund principal Delian Asparouhov, aren’t imagining cement mixers and steel plants in orbit. Instead, they want to open up manufacturing processes that aren’t possible on Earth, in order to make bioprinted organs, fiber-optic cables or pharmaceuticals — products that require fundamentally different conditions than what’s available on-planet.</p>
<h2>Building the space factory of the future</h2>
<p>The value of microgravity manufacturing, Bruey and Asparouhov say, can be found with the International Space Station, essentially a scientific outpost. A steady stream of research has emerged from the ISS over the last few decades showing that novel materials and products are possible in space. But until now, getting, staying in and returning from orbit has been too costly to consider scaling these findings.</p>
<p>“In a way, a lot of our R&amp;D has already been done for us in the public sector, and we&#8217;re essentially a ramp toward commercialization for that research that’s already been proven out,” Bruey told TechCrunch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e0fybT6CE5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/space-manufacturing-startup-varda-incubated-at-founders-fund-emerges-with-9-million-in-funding/">Space manufacturing startup Varda, incubated at Founders Fund, emerges with $9 million in funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Space manufacturing startup Varda, incubated at Founders Fund, emerges with $9 million in funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/space-manufacturing-startup-varda-incubated-at-founders-fund-emerges-with-9-million-in-funding/embed/#?secret=e0fybT6CE5" data-secret="e0fybT6CE5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Right now, the company is building a three-module spacecraft comprised of an off-the-shelf satellite platform, a center platform where the microgravity manufacturing will take place, and a reentry vehicle to bring the materials back to Earth. For the first 10 or so launches, Bruey said Varda would build the products itself. Once the company has established that its process is reliable and cheap, he added that in the long term the goal is to become a contract manufacturing platform for other companies wanting to build products in space.</p>
<p>Asparouhov likened it to the iPhone and the App Store: “The iPhone didn’t come out with the App Store. Apple developed the first 10 or 11 apps to share the value of that. So we&#8217;re developing those first few apps ourselves to show the value in this commercial capability that we&#8217;re bringing to market, but over time, we will start to release an app store.”</p>
<p>One key part of Varda’s plan is to make all of the manufacturing automated. By keeping humans out of the picture (at least for now), the company is able to reduce critical overhead by skipping human-rated spacecraft development (and the associated safety concerns with crewed launches).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183907" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183907" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2183907" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1760.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183907" class="wp-caption-text">Varda invited regulators and the DoD to a preliminary design review. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://www.varda.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Varda Space Industries <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>“I think that what investors, NASA and the [Department of Defense], really see as exciting about our approach is that in comparison to everyone else that&#8217;s ever discussed ‘space manufacturing,’ we&#8217;re by far the most near-term, pragmatic, commercially viable approach, launching and producing materials less than 18 months from now, as opposed to plans that are typically five years, 10 years, decades away from being viable,” Asparouhov said.</p>
<p>He added that one way to think about space manufacturing is that there is a certain dollar per unit-mass that Varda will need to spend to get things up to microgravity, and a dollar per unit-mass of value from manufacturing in microgravity. The key to profitability is finding the products that maximizes the difference between these two equations. Novel pharmaceuticals, for example, could yield massive profits if the innovation gains from zero gravity are correspondingly high.</p>
<p>The company is imagining “multiple missions” in 2023, Bruey said, and then moving to once per quarter and even imagining multiple reentry capsules returning with products per day. The Varda co-founders are convinced that the scale of demand for novel space-made products is potentially high enough to meet this kind of launch and reentry schedule.</p>
<p>Compared to a burgeoning industry like space tourism, Bruey said the space manufacturing has the potential to positively affect a much higher portion of humanity.</p>
<p>“It will touch many different parts of humanity&#8217;s experience out here on Earth, with significant improvements in quality of life,” he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OxhmMrvEA2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/">As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As launch market matures, space opportunities on the ground take off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/as-launch-market-matures-space-opportunities-on-the-ground-take-off/embed/#?secret=OxhmMrvEA2" data-secret="OxhmMrvEA2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/varda-space-industries-closes-42m-series-a-for-off-planet-manufacturing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183871</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 21:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DLP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise saas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multitenancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As companies grow, their security and reliability needs evolve. When working with large customers, having empathy for these needs will go a long way.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Prashant Pandey</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ppandey">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Prashant Pandey is the head of engineering at<a href="https://asana.com/"> Asana</a>, a leading work management platform for teams. Prior to Asana, Prashant started and led the Bay Area team building Amazon DynamoDB, a fully managed NoSQL database service.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Startups and SMBs are usually the first to adopt many SaaS products. But as these customers grow in size and complexity — and as you rope in larger organizations — scaling your infrastructure for the enterprise becomes critical for success.</p>
<p>Below are four tips on how to advance your company’s infrastructure to support and grow with your largest customers.</p>
<h2>Address your customers’ security and reliability needs</h2>
<p>If you’re building SaaS, odds are you’re holding very important customer data. Regardless of what you build, that makes you a threat vector for attacks on your customers. While security is important for all customers, the stakes certainly get higher the larger they grow.</p>
<p>Given the stakes, it’s paramount to build infrastructure, products and processes that address your customers’ growing security and reliability needs. That includes the ethical and moral obligation you have to make sure your systems and practices meet and exceed any claim you make about security and reliability to your customers.</p>
<p>Here are security and reliability requirements large customers typically ask for:</p>
<p><strong>Formal SLAs around uptime:</strong> If you’re building SaaS, customers expect it to be available all the time. Large customers using your software for mission-critical applications will expect to see formal SLAs in contracts committing to 99.9% uptime or higher. As you build infrastructure and product layers, you need to be confident in your uptime and be able to measure uptime on a per customer basis so you know if you’re meeting your contractual obligations.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			While it’s hard to prioritize asks from your largest customers, you’ll find that their collective feedback will pull your product roadmap in a specific direction.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p><strong>Real-time status of your platform:</strong> Most larger customers will expect to see your platform’s historical uptime and have real-time visibility into events and incidents as they happen. As you mature and specialize, creating this visibility for customers also drives more collaboration between your customer operations and infrastructure teams. This collaboration is valuable to invest in, as it provides insights into how customers are experiencing a particular degradation in your service and allows for you to communicate back what you found so far and what your ETA is.</p>
<p><strong>Backups:</strong> As your customers grow, be prepared for expectations around backups — not just in terms of how long it takes to recover the whole application, but also around backup periodicity, location of your backups and data retention (e.g., are you holding on to the data too long?). If you’re building your backup strategy, thinking about future flexibility around backup management will help you stay ahead of these asks.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183705</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinterest shares drop as company misses on user growth … again</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/pinterest-shares-drop-as-company-misses-on-user-growth-again/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/pinterest-shares-drop-as-company-misses-on-user-growth-again/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 21:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[active users]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Silbermann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pinterest&#8217;s shares had popped last week when Snap posted its best quarter in four years, as investors were betting Pinterest&#8217;s image-based social app would also see a return in advertiser spending. Those expectations now appear to be correct, as Pinterest beat on earnings with second-quarter revenue of $613.2 million and earnings per share of 25 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Pinterest&#8217;s shares had <a href="https://deadline.com/2021/07/roku-snap-facebook-break-out-stock-markets-1234799214/">popped</a> last week when Snap posted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/23/snap-had-its-best-quarter-in-four-years/">its best quarter</a> in four years, as investors were betting Pinterest&#8217;s image-based social app would also see a return in advertiser spending. Those expectations now appear to be correct, as Pinterest beat on <a href="https://s23.q4cdn.com/958601754/files/doc_financials/2021/q2/Q2-21-EPR-(1).pdf">earnings</a> with second-quarter revenue of $613.2 million and earnings per share of 25 cents, above analysts&#8217; estimates. However, Pinterest&#8217;s stock still tanked as the company reported monthly active user growth of just 9% to reach 454 million, when analysts were <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/29/pinterest-pins-earnings-q2-2021.html">expecting</a> 482 million.</p>
<p>Ahead of Pinterest&#8217;s announcement, Wall St. had <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/pinterest-q2-earnings-preview-1030650615">forecast</a> revenue of $562.3 million and earnings of $0.133 per share, up from a loss of $0.70 per share from the same quarter last year.</p>
<p>But while Pinterest delivered on financials, the company&#8217;s struggles with user growth sent the stock tumbling.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The image pinboard and shopping inspiration site had initially benefitted from increased engagement and user growth during the early days of the pandemic, but both <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/27/pinterest-pins-earnings-q1-2021.html">slowed in the first quarter of 2021</a> due the easing of COVID-19 restrictions, which had then sent the stock down by more than 10% after its first quarter earnings were posted.</p>
<p>Today, the stock <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/PINS?p=PINS&amp;.tsrc=fin-srch">was down</a> more than 12% in after-hours trading, shortly after earnings were announced.</p>
<p>Pinterest addressed the issues around user growth upfront on the earnings call, again blaming the COVID pandemic for declines in usage.</p>
<p>&#8220;The pandemic was an unprecedented and unique global event,&#8221; explained Pinterest CEO Ben Silbermann. &#8220;In past earnings calls, we talked about how stay-at-home orders significantly increased usage of Pinterest. And for the past year, we&#8217;ve highlighted how people came to Pinterest for inspiration to reinvent their lives during such a difficult time,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;Now, as the world opens up, we&#8217;re seeing the similar effect in the opposite direction that impacted our growth &#8212; particularly because some of the core use cases we see on our platform are less common in 2021 than they were a year ago. That shifting behavior in Q2 impacts engagement,&#8221; Silbermann said.</p>
<p>The company also noted that, as of July 27, 2021, its monthly active users in the U.S. had declined by approximately 7%, while global monthly active users gained approximately 5% year over year.</p>
<p>Pinterest said its web users tend to be less engaged and generate less revenue than those who come from mobile apps. In the second quarter, its monthly active users on mobile apps grew in U.S. and internationally, year over year, by more than 20%.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s issues with user growth and engagement indicate just how critical Pinterest&#8217;s plan to cater to the creator industry is the company&#8217;s future. Recently, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/pinterest-introduces-idea-pins-a-video-first-feature-aimed-at-creators/">launched</a> video-first Idea pins that allow creators to showcase their crafts, recipes, fashion, beauty tutorials, projects or anything else. This week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/pinterest-rolls-out-new-features-that-let-creators-make-money-from-pins/">Pinterest introduced new features</a> that will now allow creators to make money from those pins.</p>
<p>Despite user growth issues, the return of ad spending led to year-over-year revenue growth of 78% in the first quarter, and the company <a href="https://s23.q4cdn.com/958601754/files/doc_financials/2021/q1/Q1-21-EPR-(2).pdf">predicted</a> it would see even higher 105% year-over-year revenue growth in Q2. Today, it reported 125% revenue growth &#8212; above with the 116% Snap reported in its <a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/snap-q2-2021-earnings-1235025874/">record second quarter</a> &#8212; a figure Pinterest attributed to advertisers&#8217; return.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0HXOydKj4V"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/">Can advertising scale in VR?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can advertising scale in VR?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/embed/#?secret=0HXOydKj4V" data-secret="0HXOydKj4V" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/pinterest-shares-drop-as-company-misses-on-user-growth-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183834</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robinhood&#8217;s stock drops 8% in its first day&#8217;s trading</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initial public offering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once the U.S. consumer investing and trading app began to allow investors to trade its shares, they went down sharply, off more than 10% in the first hours of its life as a floating stock.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Robinhood <a href="https://investors.robinhood.com/press-releases-and-events/news/news-details/2021/Robinhood-Markets-Inc.-Announces-Pricing-of-Initial-Public-Offering/default.aspx">priced</a> its public offering at $38 per share last night, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/robinhood-targets-ipo-valuation-up-to-35b-amid-warning-that-crypto-incomes-are-slipping/">low end of its IPO range</a>. The company was worth around $32 billion at that price.</p>
<p>But once the U.S. consumer investing and trading app began to allow investors to trade its shares, they went down sharply, off more than 10% in the first hours of its life as a floating stock. Robinhood recovered some in later trading, but closed the day worth $34.82 per share, off 8.37%, per Yahoo Finance.</p>
<p>The company sold 55,000,000 shares in its IPO, generating gross proceeds of $2.1 billion, though that figure may rise if its underwriting banks purchase their available options. Regardless, the company is now well-capitalized to chart its future according to its own wishes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="h9oCthOrUQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/amidst-robinhoods-planned-service-changes-a-tension-between-growth-and-safety/">Amidst Robinhood&#8217;s planned service changes, a tension between growth and safety</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amidst Robinhood&#8217;s planned service changes, a tension between growth and safety&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/23/amidst-robinhoods-planned-service-changes-a-tension-between-growth-and-safety/embed/#?secret=h9oCthOrUQ" data-secret="h9oCthOrUQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>So, why did the stock go down? Given the hungry furor we&#8217;ve seen around many big-brand, consumer-facing tech companies in the last year, you might be surprised that Robinhood didn&#8217;t close the day up 80%, or something similar. After all, DoorDash and Airbnb <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/doordash-c3-ai-skyrocket-in-public-market-debuts/">had huge</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/">debuts</a>.</p>
<p>Thinking out loud, a few things could be at play:</p>
<ul>
<li>Robinhood made a big chunk of its IPO available to its own users. Or, in practice, Robinhood curtailed early retail demand by offering its investors and traders shares at the same price and level of access that big investors were given. It&#8217;s a neat idea. But by doing so, Robinhood may have lowered <em>unserved</em> retail interest in its shares, perhaps reshaping its early supply/demand curve.</li>
<li>Or maybe the company&#8217;s warnings that its trading volumes could decline in Q2 2021 scared off some bulls.</li>
</ul>
<p>Regardless, in the stonk and meme-stock era, Robinhood&#8217;s somewhat downward debut is a bit of a puzzler. More as the company&#8217;s stock finds its footing and we dig more deeply into investor sentiment regarding its future performance.</p>
<p><em>We have more coming on the company&#8217;s debut, including notes from an interview with the company&#8217;s CFO about its IPO coming tomorrow morning on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/extracrunch/">Extra Crunch</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/robinhoods-stock-drops-8-in-its-first-days-trading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183859</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Horizon Blockchain Games raises $4.5M for its NFT trading card game and wallet</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/horizon-blockchain-games-raises-4-5m-for-its-nft-trading-card-game-and-wallet/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/horizon-blockchain-games-raises-4-5m-for-its-nft-trading-card-game-and-wallet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horizon Blockchain Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skyweaver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Horizon Blockchain Games is — as the name implies — a company building games on the blockchain, along with tools to help others do the same. The company announced today that it has raised another $4.5 million, bringing its total raised to a little over $13 million. Horizon&#8217;s first game is Skyweaver, a competitive digital [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://horizon.io">Horizon Blockchain Games</a> is — as the name implies — a company building games on the blockchain, along with tools to help others do the same.</p>
<p>The company announced today that it has raised another $4.5 million, bringing its total raised to a little over $13 million.</p>
<p>Horizon&#8217;s first game is <a href="https://www.skyweaver.net">Skyweaver</a>, a competitive digital trading card game that taps the blockchain to give players more realistic ownership of their virtual cards. Once earned through competition with other players, cards can be sold, traded or taken out of the system and put in storage.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As I previously <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/06/horizon-raises-another-5m-to-put-virtual-items-on-the-blockchain/">wrote about Horizon here</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Horizon is working down two paths in parallel here: On one path, they’re building an Ethereum-powered platform called Arcadeum for handling in-game items — establishing who owns any specific instance of an item, and allowing that item to be verifiably traded, sold or given from player to player. Once an item is in a player’s possession, it’s theirs to use, trade or sell as they please; Horizon can’t just take it away. In time, they’ll open up this platform for other developers to build upon.</p>
<p>On the other path, the company is building out its own game — a digital trading card game called SkyWeaver — meant to thrive in its own right while simultaneously showcasing the platform.</p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;Arcadeum&#8221; mentioned above has now been rebranded as &#8220;<a href="https://sequence.build">Sequence,</a>&#8221; an easy-to-integrate wallet system that aims to hand-wave away the complexities of the blockchain. They want to let users buy and store their digital goods on the blockchain without either the user or an app&#8217;s developer really having to <em>think</em> about the blockchain. Horizon co-founder Michael Sanders tells me the rebranding comes with an overall broadening of its focus; the &#8220;Arcade&#8221; in &#8220;Arcadeum&#8221; suggested it was all about gaming, whereas the aim is to help manage all kinds of digital items, from virtual gaming goods to NFT art and beyond.</p>
<p>The Horizon team often mentions being built to support &#8220;Web3,&#8221; a term I&#8217;ve been hearing more and more lately. In short (or, at least, as best I understand it), Web3 is a category of online-but-decentralized apps, services and games built around the blockchain (Ethereum, in this case) to give individual users more control of their data. The Ethereum foundation has a <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/web2-vs-web3/">breakdown of the concept here</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183848" style="width: 1159px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183848" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183848 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/skyweaver-match.jpg" alt="" width="1149" height="647" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/skyweaver-match.jpg 1149w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/skyweaver-match.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/skyweaver-match.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/skyweaver-match.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/skyweaver-match.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/skyweaver-match.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1149px) 100vw, 1149px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183848" class="wp-caption-text">A match in Skyweaver. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Horizon Blockchain Games</p></div></p>
<p>Horizon originally intended to open Skyweaver up more broadly in 2020; as of this morning it&#8217;s still in private beta, with plans to open widely later this year. Sanders tells me they&#8217;ve let in over 66,000 players so far.</p>
<p>The company says that investors in this round (a &#8220;pre-Series A round SAFE&#8221;) include CMT Digital, The Xchange Company, BITKRAFT Ventures, Khaled Verjee and Zyshan Kaba.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4gxR9rYqy9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/will-topps-spac-led-debut-expand-the-bustling-nft-market/">Will Topps&#8217; SPAC-led debut expand the bustling NFT market?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will Topps&#8217; SPAC-led debut expand the bustling NFT market?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/will-topps-spac-led-debut-expand-the-bustling-nft-market/embed/#?secret=4gxR9rYqy9" data-secret="4gxR9rYqy9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/horizon-blockchain-games-raises-4-5m-for-its-nft-trading-card-game-and-wallet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183842</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biofourmis receives FDA breakthrough device designation for heart failure &#8220;digital therapy&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/biofourmis-receives-fda-breakthrough-device-designation-for-heart-failure-digital-therapy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/biofourmis-receives-fda-breakthrough-device-designation-for-heart-failure-digital-therapy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital therapeutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical devices]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kuldeep Singh Rajput, the founder of Boston-based Biofourmis, is imagining a future where heart failure patients go home with a prescription, a wearable sensor and an app. Today, a new FDA designation gets the company one step closer to that goal.  Founded in 2015, Biofourmis is a digital therapeutics company that develops software to “augment” [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kuldeep Singh Rajput, the founder of Boston-based Biofourmis, is imagining a future where heart failure patients go home with a prescription, a wearable sensor and an app. Today, a new FDA designation gets the company one step closer to that goal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2015, Biofourmis is a digital therapeutics company that develops software to “augment” patient care. So far, the company has raised about $145 million in funding, and has around 350 employees, Rajput estimates. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Thursday, Biofourmis BiovitalsHF, a platform designed for heart failure medication monitoring received an FDA breakthrough device designation. Breakthrough device designation doesn’t signal FDA clearance, but it does allow for an expedited review process, and gives the company access to expertise from the federal agency during development. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biofourmis has two major focus areas, says Rajput. The first is on developing digital therapies in conjunction with drug companies (apps for dosage delivery, for instance, or sensors that can monitor health). The second is on providing followup care for patients with acute conditions at home. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BiovialsHF is an example of the company’s forays into that first area of focus. So far, the company has developed digital therapies for a “pipeline” of conditions, like coronary artery disease or atrial fibrillation, and has digital therapies in the works for patients managing chemotherapy, or people dealing with chronic pain. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The BiovitalsHF system, though, is the first to receive FDA breakthrough designation, and Rajput calls it the company’s “lead digital therapy.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The BiovitalsHF product is a software platform designed manage medication for patients with heart failure. The idea is patients may initially get a certain prescription, but once they go home, they might need to adjust the levels of certain medication they’re taking. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Doctors do often treat heart failure with </span><a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/heart-failure/diagnosis-treatment/drc-20373148"><span style="font-weight: 400;">multiple medications</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and doses may need to be changed over time. Particularly in the case of two types of medication, ACE inhibitors or beta-blockers, medication may need to be titrated – a process where a patient begins treatment on a low dose, and slowly up the dosage over time to achieve the optimal “target” dose.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, titration is hard to achieve in real life – one </span><a href="https://tehj.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s43044-020-00088-8#ref-CR4"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> suggests that less than 25 percent of heart failure patients are on their optimal dosages (other studies suggest it’s </span><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30025570/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">less than one percent</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). Another 2017 </span><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5494159/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">commentary</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Cardiac Failure Review</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> estimates that just 29 percent of patients were on target doses of ACEs and 18 percent on their target beta blocker dose. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By contrast, in clinical trials, many to 50-60 percent of patients manage to obtain their optimal dosages, suggesting that there is a gap between how people take medicine in studies and how they do so in the real world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BiovitalsHF is supposed to streamline the titration process once patients </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">leave </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">hospitals by collecting and analyzing data from a wearable device. That data, in theory, could be used to titrate the medication depending on a patient’s health status. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The software tweaks medication dosage using information from the patient, a wearable, and outside lab results. The wearable device would collect data like heart rate, respiration rate, stroke volume or cardiac output. Meanwhile, a patient might report their own symptoms into an app, and a physician might input lab results. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Based on the data collected from the patients using sensors, and the mobile platform, we are able to automatically up titrate or down titrate and switch medication, so that patients are on the right, optimal dose,” says Rajput. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Patients would then receive a notification to let them know medications were going to be tweaked. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The BiovitalsHF program has only been tested in one proof-of-concept study (more on that later), but the Biovitals patient monitoring platform has been tested on other diseases as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, the Biovitals system was adapted to monitor 34 mild COVID-19 patients from the Queen Mary Hospital in Hong Kong who wore a biosensor 23 hours per day. A paper published in </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-82771-7?proof=t"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scientific Reports</span></i></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">suggested that the platform was able to predict whether a patient would deteriorate with 93 percent accuracy, and predict length of hospital stay with 78 percent accuracy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The BiovitalsHF system is slightly different. While the system does aim to monitor patients, Rajput aspires to have the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">technology itself be administered as a treatment program. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In essence, a doctor might “prescribe” you three months of BiovitalsHF program in which the software itself might monitor patient outcomes and help determine dosage on its own. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The aim is to be able to market Biovials HF not just as a decision support software, but as a treatment regimen. The distinction is subtle, but it means that the company is trying to be more than a delivery device, and more like a drug in itself. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “The label of the product for digital therapy will have actual treatment claims as compared to just a monitoring tool for clinical decision support,” says Rajput. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Naturally, you need robust results to make these claims. The company has already done some early testing of the concept in a proof-of-concept </span><a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04191330?term=Biofourmis&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">clinical trial </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">that concluded in March 2021, but will need to perform more rounds of testing in the future to prove efficacy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The study monitored 282 patients for 90 days, and compared people using BiovitalsHF to those using regular standard of care. The goal of the trial was to determine whether the platform could optimize medication dosage – which, in this case, means getting them within 50 percent of optimal dose. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Results have yet to be posted publicly from that study. However, Rajput notes that the study did meet that endpoint, and seemed to be linked with other improvements in patients&#8217; life quality and heart health. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Patients had, within three months, significant increases in quality of life, cardiac function, as well as reduction in a blood biomarker </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">NT-proBNP [a marker of heart failure]. Based on this, we submitted the data to the FDA and received the breakthrough designation,” he says. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has submitted the data for publication in a peer-reviewed journal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the breakthrough designation in hand, we might expect progress on BiovitalsHF to proceed quickly – though it’s still a long way from true FDA approval, or even a premarket approval at the moment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We will be kicking off our pivotal trial, you know, anytime now. And we expect to make a formal submission to the FDA sometime in June [or] July next year,” Rajput says. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/biofourmis-receives-fda-breakthrough-device-designation-for-heart-failure-digital-therapy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zūm wins $150M from San Francisco schools to modernize and electrify student transport</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/zum-wins-150m-from-san-francisco-schools-to-modernize-and-electrify-student-transport/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/zum-wins-150m-from-san-francisco-schools-to-modernize-and-electrify-student-transport/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric buses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rideshare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The San Francisco Unified School District (SFUSD) has awarded Zūm, a startup that wants to upgrade student transportation, a five-year $150 million contract to modernize its transport service throughout the district. Zūm, which already operates its rideshare-meets-bus service in Oakland, much of Southern California, Seattle, Chicago and Dallas, will be responsible for handling day-to-day operations, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The San Francisco Unified School District (SFUSD) has awarded Zūm, a startup that wants to upgrade student transportation, a five-year $150 million contract to modernize its transport service throughout the district.</p>
<p>Zūm, which already operates its rideshare-meets-bus service in Oakland, much of Southern California, Seattle, Chicago and Dallas, will be responsible for handling day-to-day operations, transporting 3,500 students across 150 school campuses starting this fall semester. The startup’s fleet of 206 buses, vans and cars is distributed based on specific use cases, placing students who live on busier routes on school buses and sending out cars and vans for others to increase efficiency. Zūm will also facilitate over 2,000 field trips per year for the school district.</p>
<p>Aside from Zūm’s five-year $53 million contract with Oakland Unified School District, which began in 2020, the SFUSD contract is the largest the startup has ever won. The company intends to use the funds to lease vehicles, hire drivers — salaried employees — improve customer and operational support, and research and develop product enhancements to support the contract, a spokesperson for Zūm told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Zūm’s transportation solution for SFUSD is expected to save the district $3 million per year on average, based on the cost of the incumbent’s solution.</p>
<p>“These savings are driven by our tech-driven route optimization and operations,” a spokesperson told TechCrunch. “Zūm has absorbed all the drivers who were previously serving SFUSD. The buses previously used were old and owned by the incumbent and have been moved out of the city. Zūm has deployed a new fleet of connected school buses and other vehicles, which will be converted to electric by 2025.”</p>
<p>Along with its fleet, Zūm offers school districts a cloud-based dashboard that allows them to manage operations, track movements, plan budget use and analyze performance and service data — the kind of tech that makes sense for schools to have but still seems radical given how slowly the public sector moves.</p>
<p>“A major challenge we experienced in the past was gaining visibility into the location of students and buses across the district,” said Orla O&#8217;Keefe, chief of policy and operations at SFUSD, in a statement. &#8220;We hope and expect that our families will benefit from Zūm&#8217;s student-centered technology. Families will be able to track their child&#8217;s bus in real time and … easily communicate with the driver regarding their child or any unique circumstances that may arise.”</p>
<p>Included in the contract is Zūm&#8217;s goal to help SFUSD electrify its entire fleet by 2025. Last year, the SF District Board of Education adopted a resolution to modernize its transportation in a way that would create more efficiencies, help the district meet sustainability goals and increase transparency across the system. Zūm says this contract will mark the first time SFUSD has updated its transportation solution in 40 years.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Zūm announced a partnership with AutoGrid, an energy management and distribution software company, to transform the company’s fleet of electric buses in San Francisco and Oakland into one of the world’s largest virtual power plants.</p>
<p>“These contracts are building blocks to Zūm and AutoGrid’s vision of creating a 1 gigawatt virtual power plant in the next four years,” said a Zūm spokesperson. “Oakland Unified and San Francisco Unified are the first two districts in the U.S. to commit to 100% conversion to an emission-free EV fleet. Between these two contracts, Zūm will be carrying around 60,000 kWh charge on its EV fleet battery. To put this in perspective, during a power outage this much storage energy can power around 47,000 households per hour.”</p>
<p><em>An earlier version of this article stated that Zūm would hire a mix of salaried employees and gig workers for the SFUSD contract. The company will only be hiring salaried employees, although it usually hires a mix of both. </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="X9dhVBJ78m"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/child-transpo-startup-zum-aims-to-create-1-gigawatt-of-energy-with-electric-school-buses/">Zūm wants to use its electric school buses to send power back to the electrical grid</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zūm wants to use its electric school buses to send power back to the electrical grid&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/child-transpo-startup-zum-aims-to-create-1-gigawatt-of-energy-with-electric-school-buses/embed/#?secret=X9dhVBJ78m" data-secret="X9dhVBJ78m" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/zum-wins-150m-from-san-francisco-schools-to-modernize-and-electrify-student-transport/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183493</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft in talks to back India&#8217;s Oyo</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/microsoft-in-talks-to-back-india-oyo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/microsoft-in-talks-to-back-india-oyo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian budget hotel chain Oyo may have lost a significant portion of its business to the pandemic, but it is inching closer to finding a new investor: Microsoft. Microsoft is in advanced stages of talks to invest in Oyo, valuing the Indian startup at about $9 billion, according to people with knowledge of the matter. The proposed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Indian budget hotel chain Oyo may have lost a significant portion of its business to the pandemic, but it is inching closer to finding a new investor: Microsoft.</p>
<p>Microsoft is in advanced stages of talks to invest in Oyo, valuing the Indian startup at about $9 billion, according to people with knowledge of the matter. The proposed size of the investment is unclear. A deal may close as soon as Friday, one source said.</p>
<p>Oyo was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/19/indias-oyo-valued-at-10b-after-founder-purchases-2b-in-shares/">valued at about $10 billion in 2019</a>, though SoftBank, a major investor in Oyo, had <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/056a1077-8503-4e72-a2f4-33172dd2fb03">slashed</a> the Indian startup&#8217;s valuation to $3 billion in recent quarters.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The proposed deal may also involve Oyo shifting to use Microsoft&#8217;s cloud services, one of the people said, who like everyone else requested anonymity discussing private matters.</p>
<p>Microsoft and Oyo founder and chief executive Ritesh Agarwal declined to comment Thursday evening.</p>
<p>Oyo, which is one of India&#8217;s most valuable startups, has aggressively expanded to many markets including Southeast Asia, Europe and the U.S. in recent years.  But <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/02/technology/oyo-softbank-india.html">some of its missteps</a> &#8212; &#8220;toxic culture,&#8221; lapse in governance, and relationship with many hotel owners &#8212; have scarred its growth.</p>
<p>Just as the startup was pledging to improve its relationship with hotel owners, the pandemic arrived. In response, Oyo slowed its growth and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/04/softbank-backed-indian-startup-oyo-to-cut-5000-jobs-globally/">laid off thousands of employees globally</a> earlier this year as nations across the world enforced lockdowns.</p>
<p>The pandemic hit the seven-year-old startup like a &#8220;cyclone,&#8221; Agarwal told Bloomberg TV earlier this month. &#8220;We built something for so many years and it took just 30 days for it drop by over 60%,&#8221; he said, adding that the firm had not made any decision on exploring the public markets.</p>
<p>Airbnb-backed Oyo had between $780 million to $800 million in its bank, Agarwal said at a virtual conference recently and had pared its &#8220;monthly burn&#8221; across all businesses to $4 million to $5 million. (The startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/despite-everything-oyo-still-has-1-billion-in-cash/">had about $1 billion in the bank</a> in December 2020.)</p>
<p>Earlier this month &#8212; after Agarwal&#8217;s remarks at the aforementioned conference &#8212; Oyo said it had raised $660 million in debt. That debt was used to pay off the previous debt, another person familiar with the matter told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>In a filing on Wednesday, Oyo disclosed that the term of the debt includes the option to exchange equity at a later date.</p>
<p>If the deal between the two firms materializes, it will be Microsoft&#8217;s latest investment in an Indian startup. The firm has backed a handful of startups in the South Asian market, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/google-leads-145-million-investment-in-indias-glance/">news aggregator and short-video platform DailyHunt,</a> e-commerce giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/10/flipkart-1-4-billion/">Flipkart</a>, and logistics <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-bags-13-million/">SaaS firm FarEye</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UehlIpLGS3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/india-poised-for-record-vc-year-as-unicorns-head-for-decisive-ipos/">India poised for record VC year as unicorns head for decisive IPOs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India poised for record VC year as unicorns head for decisive IPOs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/16/india-poised-for-record-vc-year-as-unicorns-head-for-decisive-ipos/embed/#?secret=UehlIpLGS3" data-secret="UehlIpLGS3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/microsoft-in-talks-to-back-india-oyo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183788</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bambuser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Influencer Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Livestreaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[omnichannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Livestreaming is a new pillar that brands must consider when building omnichannel marketing strategies, joining the trinity of in-store experiences, traditional e-commerce and social media.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Alanna Gregory</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/alannaeve">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Alanna Gregory is a marketing executive and is currently senior global director at <a href="https://www.afterpay.com/">Afterpay</a>. Previously, she was VP at Hairstory, the founder and CEO of VIVE Lifestyle, and was an AVP at Barclays.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/e-commerce-roll-ups-present-the-next-wave-of-disruption-in-consumer-packaged-goods/">E-commerce roll-ups are the next wave of disruption in consumer packaged goods</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">What comes to mind when you think of livestreaming? In the U.S., most people would name their favorite celebrity leading a Q&amp;A on Instagram or a gamer doing a speedrun on Twitch.</p>
<p>In China, it’s shopping, streamed live.</p>
<p>Livestream e-commerce has taken off in China in the last few years and is expected to yield more than<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/michellegreenwald/2020/12/10/live-streaming-e-commerce-is-the-rage-in-china-is-the-us-next/?sh=7941f41b6535"> $60 billion this year</a>. In 2019, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/michellegreenwald/2020/12/10/live-streaming-e-commerce-is-the-rage-in-china-is-the-us-next/?sh=7cd8caf16535">37% of online shoppers</a> in China (a cool 265 million people) made purchases on livestreams — and that was well before quarantine. In 2020, it’s estimated to have reached around 560 million people.</p>
<p>During Taobao’s annual Single&#8217;s Day Global Shopping Festival in 2020 (China’s Black Friday), <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurenhallanan/2020/11/16/live-streaming-drives-6-billion-usd-in-sales-during-the-1111-global-shopping-festival">livestreams accounted for $6 billion in sales</a> — nearly doubled from a year earlier.</p>
<p>Starting to see a trend? The big U.S. companies have noticed, and they’re jumping on the bandwagon faster than you can say, &#8220;Swipe up to buy now!&#8221;</p>
<p>Last December, Walmart livestreamed shopping events on TikTok. Amazon released a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/live">live platform</a> where influencers promote items and chat with customers. Instagram launched a Shop feature that encourages users to browse and buy within the app. Facebook also<a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/05/introducing-your-new-favorite-way-to-shop-live-shopping-fridays/"> kicked off Live Shopping Fridays</a> for the beauty and fashion categories.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;It’s an entertaining way for shops to tell the story behind their products. It brings buyers closer than ever to their favorite creators and allows them to have a voice in the conversation.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Startups are growing fast to keep up with the heavy hitters — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/popshop-live-raises-around-20m-at-a-100m-valuation-for-its-livestream-shopping-platform-for-hipsters/">PopShop.Live raised $20 million</a> to let people buy everything from books and toys to jewelry from sellers who livestream their offerings, and <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/whatnot-raises-50m-series-b-led-by-y-combinator-continuity-to-cement-its-leadership-as-the-largest-live-shopping-platform-in-the-us-301299025.html">Whatnot raised a $50 million</a> Series B, largely to expand its livestream commerce infrastructure. There’s also a burgeoning category of SaaS tools such as Bambuser, which is <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/klarna-launches-livestyle-a-live-fashion-show-powered-by-bambusers-live-video-shopping-301181700.html">working with brands like Klarna to test native livestream shopping</a> directly within branded apps.</p>
<p>At this pace, retailers will all welcome livestream commerce teams like they have influencer partnerships in recent years. It’ll just be part of the digital equation to stay competitive and relevant in the future of marketplaces and e-commerce.</p>
<h2>From B.C. to 5G: The evolution of shopping</h2>
<p>What is old is new again. Your grandparents spent years watching QVC because it balanced the experience of speaking with an associate with the convenience of their retirement community’s TV room. Livestream is today&#8217;s version of &#8220;shoptainment,&#8221; where hosts showcase products dynamically, interact with their audiences and build urgency with short-term offers, giveaways and limited-edition items.</p>
<p>Now, with livestream commerce, hosts can form deeper customer connections and answer questions in real time. It’s a new standard of communication that holds a longstanding truth from Istanbul’s Grand Bazaar to smartphones: People shop to kill time and are more likely to buy when they feel connected with a salesperson.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183619</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scarlett Johansson files suit over Disney+ ‘Black Widow’ release</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/scarlett-johansson-files-suit-over-disney-black-widow-release/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/scarlett-johansson-files-suit-over-disney-black-widow-release/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black widow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scarlett johansson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Update: Disney issued the following response to the suit, There is no merit whatsoever to this filing. The lawsuit is especially sad and distressing in its callous disregard for the horrific and prolonged global effects of the Covid-19 pandemic. Disney has fully complied with Ms. Johansson’s contract and furthermore, the release of Black Widow on Disney+ with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><strong>Update:</strong> Disney issued the following response to the suit,</p>
<blockquote><p>There is no merit whatsoever to this filing. The lawsuit is especially sad and distressing in its callous disregard for the horrific and prolonged global effects of the Covid-19 pandemic. Disney has fully complied with Ms. Johansson’s contract and furthermore, the release of <em>Black Widow</em> on Disney+ with Premier Access has significantly enhanced her ability to earn additional compensation on top of the $20M she has received to date.</p></blockquote>
<p>With Scarlett Johansson’s time as an Avenger seemingly in the rearview, the &#8220;Black Widow&#8221; star has filed a breach of contract suit against Marvel-owner Disney. The lawsuit, filed in Los Angeles Superior Court this week, alleges that the studio breached its agreement with the star when it released the film on Disney+ alongside its theatrical debut.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“As Ms. Johansson, Disney, Marvel, and most everyone else in Hollywood knows, a ‘theatrical release’ is a release that is exclusive to movie theatres,” the filing writes, matter of factly. “Disney was well aware of this promise, but nonetheless directed Marvel to violate its pledge and instead release the Picture on the Disney+ streaming service the very same day it was released in movie theatres.”</p>
<p>The pandemic has fundamentally transformed the way first-run movies are delivered and consumed — at least in the short term. In 2020, Disney and other studios opted to release films straight to streaming, rather than suffer perpetual delays and poor box office numbers as restrictions closed the non-essential business of movie theaters. More recently they’ve split the difference as movie theaters have reopened, offering same day streaming.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="f3RiepnpLA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/20/disney-pixar-onward-streaming/">Pixar&#8217;s &#8216;Onward&#8217; goes on sale digitally today, coming to Disney+ on April 3</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pixar&#8217;s &#8216;Onward&#8217; goes on sale digitally today, coming to Disney+ on April 3&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/20/disney-pixar-onward-streaming/embed/#?secret=f3RiepnpLA" data-secret="f3RiepnpLA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>According to a copy of the suit obtained by TechCrunch, Johansson’s concerns about streaming services pre-date the pandemic. When Disney launched the streaming service Disney+, the suit claims, Johansson’s representatives sought assurances from Disney/Marvel that the Black Widow solo film would still get a theatrical release, in spite of the company’s bids to boost subscription numbers.</p>
<p>It cites an email with Marvel’s chief counsel from May of that year:</p>
<blockquote><p>We totally understand that Scarlett’s willingness to do the film and her whole deal is based on the premise that the film would be widely theatrically released like our other pictures. We understand that should the plan change, we would need to discuss this with you and come to an understanding as the deal is based on a series of (very large) box office bonuses.</p></blockquote>
<p>“It’s no secret that Disney is releasing films like &#8220;Black Widow&#8221; directly onto Disney+ to increase subscribers and thereby boost the company’s stock price — and that it’s hiding behind COVID-19 as a pretext to do so,” the actress’s attorney John Berlinski said in a statement provided to TechCrunch. “But ignoring the contracts of the artists responsible for the success of its films in furtherance of this short-sighted strategy violates their rights and we look forward to proving as much in court. This will surely not be the last case where Hollywood talent stands up to Disney and makes it clear that, whatever the company may pretend, it has a legal obligation to honor its contracts.”</p>
<p>The statement accuses Disney of “hiding behind COVID-19,” though certainly the studio wasn’t alone in rethinking its release strategy over the past year. The question remains whether the pandemic will serve as sufficient extenuating circumstances for its release decisions. The outcome of the trial, meanwhile, could well have a profound effect on how studios release blockbusters post-pandemic.</p>
<p>We’ve reached out to Disney for comment and will update accordingly.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6T4b3vlm1N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/disney-ux-teardown-wins-fails-and-fixes/">Disney+ UX teardown: Wins, fails and fixes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disney+ UX teardown: Wins, fails and fixes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/disney-ux-teardown-wins-fails-and-fixes/embed/#?secret=6T4b3vlm1N" data-secret="6T4b3vlm1N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2ok3Ed7iPF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/black-widow-cruella-disney-plus/">&#8216;Black Widow&#8217; and &#8216;Cruella&#8217; will get Premier Access releases on Disney+</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;&#8216;Black Widow&#8217; and &#8216;Cruella&#8217; will get Premier Access releases on Disney+&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/black-widow-cruella-disney-plus/embed/#?secret=2ok3Ed7iPF" data-secret="2ok3Ed7iPF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/scarlett-johansson-files-suit-over-disney-black-widow-release/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183765</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Panic sells 20,000+ Playdate handhelds in under 20 minutes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/panic-sells-20000-playdate-handhelds-in-under-20-minutes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/panic-sells-20000-playdate-handhelds-in-under-20-minutes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playdate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2183737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we&#8217;ve known for about a week, today was the day Panic&#8217;s charming/whacky/curious/all-of-the-above Playdate gaming device (and its crank!) went up for pre-order. The buzz around the little retro-inspired handheld seemed strong — but would that translate into actual sales? The answer, it seems, is a hard yes. Panic committed to making 20,000 units for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As we&#8217;ve known <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/pre-orders-for-panics-playdate-handheld-will-open-on-july-29th/">for about a week</a>, today was the day Panic&#8217;s charming/whacky/curious/all-of-the-above Playdate gaming device (and its crank!) went up for pre-order. The buzz around the little retro-inspired handheld seemed strong — but would that translate into actual sales?</p>
<p>The answer, it seems, is a hard yes. Panic committed to making 20,000 units for 2021, selling them on a first come, first serve basis. Any orders after that would still be accepted, but those orders wouldn&#8217;t ship until sometime in 2022 at the earliest.</p>
<p>According to Panic&#8217;s shipping estimator, those first 20,000 units were gone in under 20 minutes. That first 2021 batch went real quick. (<em>We confirmed with a rep for Panic that the shipping estimator is accurate, and those first 20,000 units are spoken for.</em>)</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2183759" style="width: 1011px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183759" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183759 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/panic.jpg" alt="" width="1001" height="452" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/panic.jpg 1001w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/panic.jpg?resize=150,68 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/panic.jpg?resize=300,135 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/panic.jpg?resize=768,347 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/panic.jpg?resize=680,307 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/panic.jpg?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1001px) 100vw, 1001px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183759" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Panic</p></div></p>
<p>Like just about any much anticipated launch, the process wasn&#8217;t without its technical troubles. After a brief blink of server instability and 502 errors, Panic&#8217;s checkout system came online … only for the plug-in system they tapped to handle international shipping to come crashing down. This booted some international users out of the checkout flow and — quite unfortunately — out of their place in line and into the 2022 batch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/26a0.png" alt="⚠" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Our most sincere apologies to any international customers who had difficulty checking out this morning. Our international shipping provider’s plug-in fell over under heavy load (despite our many warnings). Many orders went through, but many didn’t. We’re investigating options.</p>
<p>&mdash; Playdate (@playdate) <a href="https://twitter.com/playdate/status/1420801880993660928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 29, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>There&#8217;s already talk, meanwhile, of a &#8220;2023 bucket&#8221; for orders, though the company notes that &#8220;it’ll take a while&#8221; before <a href="https://twitter.com/playdate/status/1420806214980567040">they get there</a>.</p>
<p>For those who&#8217;ve <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/22/panics-playmate-is-a-pint-sized-gaming-machine-with-a-season-of-12-intriguing-titles/">missed the story so far</a>: The Playdate is a kinda-sorta-experimental gaming device built by Panic (the team behind Mac apps like Transmit and Prompt, and which helped ship games like Firewatch and Untitled Goose Game) in collaboration with Teenage Engineering. Games are released to the $179 device in &#8220;seasons,&#8221; with two games (of varying length/complexity/etc.) scheduled to ship each week of its first three months. With a black-and-white screen, minimal buttons, and, yes, a <em>crank</em> (for controlling games, not charging the device), this one is less &#8220;WILL IT RUN CRYSIS?!&#8221; and more … blank canvas.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">While we&#8217;re not talking next-gen-console-level sales here, selling tens of thousands of units in no time flat is a </span><em style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">resounding </em><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">accomplishment for a software team&#8217;s first dive into gaming hardware. Now they&#8217;ve just gotta get them out the door.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/panic-sells-20000-playdate-handhelds-in-under-20-minutes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2183737</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
