<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 05:34:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Indian gaming platform Mobile Premier League valued at $945M in $95M fundraise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/indian-mobile-gaming-platform-mobile-premier-league-valued-at-945-million-in-95-million-fundraise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/indian-mobile-gaming-platform-mobile-premier-league-valued-at-945-million-in-95-million-fundraise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 05:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founder’s Circle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Go-Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Premier League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moore Strategic Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MPL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RTP Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SIG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telstra Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mobile Premier League (MPL) has raised $95 million in a new financing round, just five months after it secured $90 million as the two-and-a-half-year-old Bangalore-based esports and gaming platform looks to grow in international markets. The new $95 million round, a Series D, was led by Composite Capital and Moore Strategic Ventures and gave the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Mobile Premier League (MPL) has raised $95 million in a new financing round, just <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/20/indian-mobile-gaming-platform-mobile-premier-league-raises-90-million/">five months after it secured $90 million</a> as the two-and-a-half-year-old Bangalore-based esports and gaming platform looks to grow in international markets.</p>
<p>The new $95 million round, a Series D, was led by Composite Capital and Moore Strategic Ventures and gave the Indian startup a post-money valuation of $945 million, it said. Base Partners, RTP Global, SIG, Go-Ventures, Telstra Ventures, Founders Circle and Play Ventures also participated in the round, which brings its total to-date raise to $225.5 million.</p>
<p><a href="http://mpl.live/">MPL</a>, which counts Times Internet among its backers, operates a pure-play gaming platform that hosts a range of tournaments. The app, which has amassed more than 60 million users in India and 3.5 million users in Indonesia, also serves as a publishing platform for other gaming firms. MPL, which does not develop games of its own, hosts about 70 games across multiple sports on the app today.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“As we grow our presence and expand, this fresh round of funds will help us focus on our core value propositions &#8212; a robust platform with the best features for gamers and onboarding the best eSports titles. The esports community in India is thriving, and we believe this is the perfect time to take Indian-made games to the world as well as help Indian gamers get recognized for their talent,” said Sai Srinivas, co-founder and chief executive of MPL, in a statement.</p>
<p>The Bangalore-based startup also offers fantasy sports, a segment that has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/14/indian-fantasy-sports-app-dream11s-parent-firm-raises-225m-at-over-2-5b-valuation/">taken off in many parts of India in recent years</a>. Because fantasy sports is only one part of the business, the coronavirus outbreak that shut most real-world matches has not impeded the startup’s growth in recent quarters.</p>
<p>“We’re competing with battle-hardened, decade old companies with much, much deeper pockets but it’s incredible what the young team has achieved over the past couple of years. When we were on the Play Store, a couple of years back, MPL was the fastest app to reach a 1M DAU ever in India!” <a href="https://twitter.com/AbhishekMadhavn/status/1307903328429289474">tweeted</a> Abhishek Madhavan, SVP of Marketing at MPL, last year.</p>
<p>“We signed Virat Kohli (pictured above), when we were a 3-month old company! When we got out of the Play Store, we were told growth will be very very hard to come by, every single marketing metric would fall.”</p>
<p><em>This is a developing story. More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/indian-mobile-gaming-platform-mobile-premier-league-valued-at-945-million-in-95-million-fundraise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108647</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GajiGesa, a fintech startup serving underbanked Indonesian workers, raises $2.5 million seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/gajigesa-a-fintech-startup-serving-underbanked-indonesian-workers-raises-2-5-million-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/gajigesa-a-fintech-startup-serving-underbanked-indonesian-workers-raises-2-5-million-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 04:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earned wage access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GajiGesa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GajiGesa, a fintech company that offers Earned Wage Access (EWA) and other services for workers in Indonesia, has raised $2.5 million in seed funding. The round was co-led by Defy.vc and Quest Ventures. Other participants included GK Plug and Play, Next Billion Ventures, Alto Partners Multi-Family Office, Kanmo Group and strategic angel investors. The company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://gajigesa.com/">GajiGesa</a>, a fintech company that offers Earned Wage Access (EWA) and other services for workers in Indonesia, has raised $2.5 million in seed funding. The round was co-led by Defy.vc and Quest Ventures. Other participants included GK Plug and Play, Next Billion Ventures, Alto Partners Multi-Family Office, Kanmo Group and strategic angel investors.</p>
<p>The company was founded last year by husband-and-wife team Vidit Agrawal and Martyna Malinowska. Agrawal was <a href="https://medium.com/@mdwarriorsasia/ubers-first-employee-from-asia-vidit-agrawal-1660405a81b2">Uber’s first employee in Asia </a>and has also served in leadership positions at Carro and Stripe. Malinowska led product development at Standard Chartered’s SC Ventures and alternative credit-scoring platform LenddoEFL.</p>
<p>About<a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/intl/en-apac/future-of-marketing/machine-learning/all-eyes-e-money-race-reach-180m-unbanked-indonesians/"> 66% of Indonesia&#8217;s 260 million population is &#8220;unbanked,&#8221;</a> which means they don&#8217;t have a bank account and limited access to financial services like loans. Agrawal and Malinowska decided to launch GajiGesa in Indonesia because Malinowska worked with many unbanked workers while at LenddoEFL. While at Uber, Agrawal also worked with drivers across Southeast Asia whose average earnings were $250 USD a month (excluding Singapore), and he said the top issue they face was harassment by money lenders.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2108639" style="width: 1850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2108639" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2108639 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png" alt="Screenshots showing how GajiGesa's app works. GajiGesa is a startup that offers earned wage access and other services to Indonesian workers." width="1840" height="1037" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png 1840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png?resize=768,433 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png?resize=1536,866 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GajiGesa_Flow_Screenshots.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1840px) 100vw, 1840px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2108639" class="wp-caption-text">GajiGesa&#8217;s app</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;These hardworking Indonesians had no fair or formal sources for easy access to capital. Further, the most common reason for borrowing was short-term liquidity issues,&#8221; Agrawal told TechCrunch. &#8220;But workers were forced to borrow either long-term, high ticket size loans or short-term loans with exorbitantly high-interest rates.&#8221;</p>
<p>Having immediate access to earned wages, instead of waiting for a semi-monthly or monthly paycheck, can help alleviate financial stress and make it easier for workers to manage their income and handle emergencies. Companies that have started instant payment services for workers in other countries include <a href="https://squareup.com/us/en/press/square-payroll-on-demand-pay-instant-payments">Square</a>, London-based startup Wagestream and Gusto.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xeAOQcgtZA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/wagestream-closes-51m-series-a-to-plug-the-payday-gap-without-putting-workers-in-debt/">Wagestream closes $51M Series A to plug the payday gap without putting workers in debt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wagestream closes $51M Series A to plug the payday gap without putting workers in debt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/wagestream-closes-51m-series-a-to-plug-the-payday-gap-without-putting-workers-in-debt/embed/#?secret=xeAOQcgtZA" data-secret="xeAOQcgtZA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Since launching in October 2020, GajiGesa has added over 30 employers on its platform, serving tens of thousand of workers in total. It integrates into a company&#8217;s existing human resources management and payroll systems. Workers can get earned wages immediately, track earnings, pay bills, buy prepaid cards and access financial education resources through an app.</p>
<p>GajiGesa does not charge interest rates or require collateral, since all its users are pre-approved by their employers. Companies decide to charge fees or offer GajiGesa as part of their benefits packages, and also get access to analytics that can help them create targeted incentives or new benefits for their workforce.</p>
<p>During COVID-19, Agrawal said the startup has &#8220;seen insatiable demand and support for GajiGesa’s EWA solution from employers. This is partly attributed to the various challenges employers are facing due to the effects of COVID-19, but our platform is designed to support employers and employees in the long-term. The value of EWA and the other services we offer is not limited to the pandemic.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zXjc7rk9dc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/gusto-flexible-pay/">Disrupting the paycheck, Gusto’s Flexible Pay allows employees to pick when they get paid</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disrupting the paycheck, Gusto’s Flexible Pay allows employees to pick when they get paid&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/06/21/gusto-flexible-pay/embed/#?secret=zXjc7rk9dc" data-secret="zXjc7rk9dc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/gajigesa-a-fintech-startup-serving-underbanked-indonesian-workers-raises-2-5-million-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108637</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grab announces program to help increase COVID-19 vaccinations in Southeast Asia</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/grab-announces-program-to-help-increase-covid-19-vaccinations-in-southeast-asia/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/grab-announces-program-to-help-increase-covid-19-vaccinations-in-southeast-asia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 03:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19 vaccine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grab, the Southeast Asian ride-hailing and on-demand delivery giant, announced a program to increase access to COVID-19 vaccinations today. Its goal is to have all of its employees, as well as driver and delivery partners, vaccinated by 2022 (excluding people who are medically unable to receive shots). Grab also said it will work with governments [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://grab.com">Grab</a>, the Southeast Asian ride-hailing and on-demand delivery giant, announced a program to increase access to COVID-19 vaccinations today. Its goal is to have all of its employees, as well as driver and delivery partners, vaccinated by 2022 (excluding people who are medically unable to receive shots). Grab also said it will work with governments to provide information about vaccines through its app, and is in discussions to provide last-mile vaccine distribution, and transportation to and from vaccination centers.</p>
<p>The company currently has operations in eight Southeast Asian countries: Singapore, Cambodia, Indonesia, Malaysia, Myanmar, the Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam. Grab joins a growing roster of private companies around the world that have offered to help governments with their vaccination programs. In the United States, these include tech companies like Microsoft, Oracle, Salesforce and Epic. Meanwhile, China’s largest ride-hailing company, Didi Chuxing, is pledging $10 million to support vaccination programs in 13 countries.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RXXAa1Mmu1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/">Tech and health companies including Microsoft and Salesforce team up on digital COVID-19 vaccination records</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tech and health companies including Microsoft and Salesforce team up on digital COVID-19 vaccination records&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/tech-and-health-companies-including-microsoft-and-salesforce-team-up-on-digital-covid-19-vaccination-records/embed/#?secret=RXXAa1Mmu1" data-secret="RXXAa1Mmu1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="V2gtR0jP5S"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/didi-10-million-covid-19-fund/">Didi to subsidize trips for vaccinations with $10M global fund</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Didi to subsidize trips for vaccinations with $10M global fund&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/didi-10-million-covid-19-fund/embed/#?secret=V2gtR0jP5S" data-secret="V2gtR0jP5S" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In a statement, Russell Cohen, Grab’s group managing director of operations, said, &#8220;The quicker we can achieve herd immunity, the sooner our communities and economies can start to rebuild. Public-private partnership has been critical in taking on some of the pandemic’s biggest battles, and this collaboration should continue.&#8221;</p>
<p>For drivers and delivery partners, Grab said it will subsidize COVID-19 vaccine costs not covered by national vaccination programs. The company will also extend its Group Prolonged Medical Leave insurance policy to cover income lost by drivers as a result of potential side effects from getting vaccinated. Employees and immediate family members will have any costs not covered by national programs paid for by Grab.</p>
<p>In terms of vaccine education, the Grab app will prominently display information from governments and health authorities, and run user surveys to help them understand public sentiment about COVID-19 vaccines. The company says its app has been downloaded more than 214 million times.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="y0Nh99ZVZ6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/ride-hailing-was-hit-hard-by-covid-19-grabs-russell-cohen-on-how-the-company-adapted/">Ride-hailing was hit hard by COVID-19 &#8212; Grab&#8217;s Russell Cohen on how the company adapted</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ride-hailing was hit hard by COVID-19 &#8212; Grab&#8217;s Russell Cohen on how the company adapted&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/ride-hailing-was-hit-hard-by-covid-19-grabs-russell-cohen-on-how-the-company-adapted/embed/#?secret=y0Nh99ZVZ6" data-secret="y0Nh99ZVZ6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/grab-announces-program-to-help-increase-covid-19-vaccinations-in-southeast-asia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108626</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SquadCast adds video podcast recording</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/squadcast-adds-video-podcast-recording/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/squadcast-adds-video-podcast-recording/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 01:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squadcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zencastr]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Remote video podcasting is surprisingly still something of a Wild West these days. Given the massive sums of money currently being pumped into the category &#8212; not to mention the fact that pretty much all podcasting became remote podcasting in 2020 &#8212; you’d expect there to be a more unified solution. Many still continue to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Remote video podcasting is surprisingly still something of a Wild West these days. Given the massive sums of money currently being pumped into the category &#8212; not to mention the fact that pretty much all podcasting became remote podcasting in 2020 &#8212; you’d expect there to be a more unified solution. Many still continue to rely on catchall teleconferencing software to get the job done (full disclosure: I’ve been recording my podcasts on Zoom during the pandemic).</p>
<p>It’s not for lack of trying of course. A number of companies are vying to become the Zoom or Skype of remote podcasts, including, notably, Zencastr. SquadCast is another big name in the space. The company claims a pretty big footprint, though, again, its primary competitors are still non-specialized video calling apps.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/pirZNYmmg4E?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While those platforms are generally reliable and ubiquitous, they do have their drawbacks: namely recording quality. SquadCast’s big selling point has been higher-quality recording than those services where sound is something of an afterthought. This week, the Oakland-based company is <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210203005275/en/SquadCast%E2%80%99s-Video-Collaboration-Podcasting-to-Increase-Reach-and-Grow-Shows">adding video recording to the mix</a>.</p>
<p>“We were on an upward trajectory before COVID, but demand during the pandemic has resulted in over 280% growth in both revenue and customer acquisition,” CEO Zachariah Moreno said in a release. &#8220;Since Video recording is our most requested feature by current, past, and prospective customers, it was the natural next step to continue to move the needle in virtual recording for podcast professionals.&#8221;</p>
<p>The platform is adding the feature for existing customers starting this quarter. The latest beta version of the software records video locally as separate files at 720p. Once the recording is over, it will convert the files into MP4 or WebM.</p>
<p>SquadCast&#8217;s version 3.0 beta with Studio Quality Video Recording consumer plans start at $40/month up to $300/month. Zencastr began rolling out its own video recording feature in beta over the summer.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0q9DT5IgSl"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/zencastr-is-testing-a-video-podcasting-tool-in-limited-beta/">Zencastr is testing a video podcasting tool in limited beta</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zencastr is testing a video podcasting tool in limited beta&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/zencastr-is-testing-a-video-podcasting-tool-in-limited-beta/embed/#?secret=0q9DT5IgSl" data-secret="0q9DT5IgSl" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/squadcast-adds-video-podcast-recording/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108565</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: TikTok will downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/daily-crunch-tiktok-will-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/daily-crunch-tiktok-will-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 23:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok announces additional steps to fight misinformation, Myanmar&#8217;s military cracks down on Facebook and Google&#8217;s subsea cable goes online. This is your Daily Crunch for February 3, 2021. The big story: TikTok will downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims TikTok had already said it would try to reduce misinformation by removing videos flagged by fact checkers for including [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok announces additional steps to fight misinformation, Myanmar&#8217;s military cracks down on Facebook and Google&#8217;s subsea cable goes online. This is your Daily Crunch for February 3, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: TikTok will downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims</strong></p>
<p>TikTok had already said it would try to reduce misinformation by removing videos flagged by fact checkers for including false information. Today it announced that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/">it will go a step further</a> by flagging videos where the fact checkers&#8217; findings are inconclusive.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For example, the company said that there are cases where fact checkers cannot verify information in a video because events are still unfolding. Those &#8220;unsubstantiated&#8221; videos will then include a large banner, as well as an additional reminder prompt before users will be able to share them.</p>
<p>This feature is launching in the United States and Canada but will become available globally in &#8220;coming weeks.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/myanmar-orders-telecom-networks-to-temporarily-block-facebook/">Myanmar military government orders telecom networks to temporarily block Facebook</a> — The move comes after days of unrest in Myanmar, where earlier this week military took control of the country and declared a state of emergency for a year after detaining civilian leader Aung San Suu Kyi.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/googles-new-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-and-europe-is-now-online/">Google’s new subsea cable between the US and Europe is now online</a> — The almost 4,000-mile cable has a total capacity of 250 terabits per second.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/instagram-confirms-its-working-on-a-vertical-stories-feed/">Instagram confirms it’s working on a ‘Vertical Stories’ feed</a> — This could give the app a more TikTok-like feel.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/vivino-raises-155-million-for-wine-recommendation-and-marketplace-app/">Vivino raises $155M for wine recommendation and marketplace app</a> — The app and the company behind it have been helping people enjoy better wine since 2010.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/good-eggs-funding-2/">Good Eggs raises $100M and plans to launch in Southern California</a> — Good Eggs says that in the past year, it has grown revenue to the nine figures (more than $100 million), hired more than 400 employees and nearly doubled its customer base.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/rocket-chat-raises-19m-for-its-open-source-approach-to-integrated-enterprise-messaging/">Rocket.Chat raises $19M for its open-source approach to integrated enterprise messaging</a> — The service is used by banks, the U.S. Navy, NGOs and other organizations to set up and run any variety of secure virtual communications services from one place.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ux-teardown-spotify-group-sessions/">Spotify Group Session UX teardown: The fails and their fixes</a> — Essentially a “party mode,” the feature offers a way for participants to contribute to a collaborative playlist in real time and control what’s playing across everyone’s devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/edtech-valuations-arent-skyrocketing-but-investors-see-more-exit-opportunities/">Edtech valuations aren’t skyrocketing, but investors see more exit opportunities</a> — Thirteen VCs discuss how their deal-making has changed in the last year.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/deep-science-ais-with-high-class-and-higher-altitudes/">Deep Science: AIs with high class and higher altitudes</a> — This roundup kicks off with a study looking at the relative positions of the U.S., EU and China in the AI “race.”</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/global-smartphones-shipments-expected-to-rebound-11-this-year/">Global smartphone shipments expected to rebound 11% this year</a> — New numbers from Gartner point to a rebound to pre-2020 levels.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/todd-rundgren-clearly-human/">Todd Rundgren is about to launch a geofenced virtual tour</a> — Rundgren is staging the tour with support from NoCap, the livestreaming concert startup founded by musicians Cisco Adler and Donavon Frankenreiter.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/daily-crunch-tiktok-will-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108537</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify hints toward plans for podcast subscriptions, à la carte payments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/spotify-hints-toward-plans-for-podcast-subscriptions-a-la-carte-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/spotify-hints-toward-plans-for-podcast-subscriptions-a-la-carte-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 23:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spotify again signaled its interest in developing new ways to monetize its investments in podcasts. In the company&#8217;s fourth-quarter earnings, chief executive Daniel Ek suggested the streaming media company foresees a future where there will be multiple business models for podcasts, including, potentially, both ad-supported subscriptions and à la carte options. The company, which also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Spotify again signaled its interest in developing new ways to monetize its investments in podcasts. In the company&#8217;s <a href="https://investors.spotify.com/financials/press-release-details/2021/Spotify-Technology-S.A.-Announces-Financial-Results-for-Fourth-Quarter-2020/default.aspx">fourth-quarter earnings</a>, chief executive Daniel Ek suggested the streaming media company foresees a future where there will be multiple business models for podcasts, including, potentially, both ad-supported subscriptions and à la carte options.</p>
<p>The company, which also revealed its podcast catalog has grown to now 2.2 million programs, said it&#8217;s seen increasing demand for the audio format in recent months.</p>
<p>For example, 25% of Spotify&#8217;s monthly active users now engage with podcasts, up from 22% just last quarter. Podcast consumption is also increasing, with listening hours having nearly doubled year-over-year in the fourth quarter.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Today, podcasts on Spotify&#8217;s platform are available to both free and paid users and are monetized with ads. This is still a key focus for the company &#8212; Spotify even recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/spotify-buying-podcast-hosting-and-ad-company-megaphone-for-235m/">acquired</a> a podcast hosting and monetization platform, Megaphone, to help make streaming ad insertion technology available to its third-party publishers while also growing its targetable podcast inventory.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Cb8af2ZJbi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/spotify-buying-podcast-hosting-and-ad-company-megaphone-for-235m/">Spotify buying podcast hosting and ad company Megaphone for $235M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spotify buying podcast hosting and ad company Megaphone for $235M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/spotify-buying-podcast-hosting-and-ad-company-megaphone-for-235m/embed/#?secret=Cb8af2ZJbi" data-secret="Cb8af2ZJbi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But Spotify recently put its feelers out about different means of monetizing podcasts, too.</p>
<p>Late last year, for instance, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552822/spotify-podcast-subscription-service-survey">the company was spotted running a survey</a> that asked its customers if they would be willing to pay for a standalone podcast subscription, and if so what would it look like and how much would it cost?</p>
<p>At the time, the survey offered a few different concepts.</p>
<p>At the low end, a subscription could offer ad-supported exclusive episodes and bonus content for $3 per month. This would be similar to Stitcher Premium, which today provides exclusives from top shows and other bonus episodes. But Spotify&#8217;s suggested version included ads, while Stitcher Premium is ad-free.</p>
<p>A middle option suggested a plan that would be even closer to Stitcher Premium, with exclusive shows and bonus material but no ads. This even matched Stitcher Premium&#8217;s price of $5 per month. And at the high-end, subscribers could get early access to ad-free interviews and episodes for $8 per month.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Looks like the premium podcast plan would be ad-free and some mix of exclusive extra content at price points somewhere between $3-$8. <a href="https://t.co/ArK8xYg0CM">pic.twitter.com/ArK8xYg0CM</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Andrew Wallenstein (@awallenstein) <a href="https://twitter.com/awallenstein/status/1324746116160577536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A survey, of course, is only meant to gauge consumer demand for such a subscription, and doesn&#8217;t indicate that Spotify has a new product in the works. (Spotify said the same when asked to comment on the news at the time.)</p>
<p>However, it&#8217;s clear that investors also want to know what Spotify is thinking when it comes to recouping its sizable investments in podcasts.</p>
<p>Asked if Spotify thought customers would be willing to pay for podcasts, Ek <a href="https://seekingalpha.com/article/4403058-spotify-technology-s-spot-ceo-daniel-ek-on-q4-2020-results-earnings-call-transcript">on the earnings call</a> responded that he believed there were several new models that could be explored.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think we’re in the early days of seeing the long-term evolvement of how we can monetize audio on the internet. I’ve said this before, but I don’t believe that it’s a one-size-fits-all,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I believe, in fact, that we will have all business models, and that’s the future for all media companies &#8212; that you will have ad-supported subscriptions and à la carte sort of in the same space, of all media companies in the future.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;And you should definitely expect Spotify to follow that strategy and that pattern,&#8221; Ek added, more definitively.</p>
<p>The answer seemed to indicate that Spotify is considering some of the ideas in that recent survey &#8212; of getting consumers to pay for some podcasts, instead of accessing them all for free or having them bundled into their music subscription.</p>
<p>Of course, that would change the meaning of the word &#8220;podcasts,&#8221; which today refers to freely distributed, serialized audio programs that get distributed via RSS feeds.</p>
<p>If Spotify chooses to paywall podcasts behind subscriptions or à la carte payments, then they&#8217;re no longer <em>really</em> podcasts &#8212; they&#8217;re a new sort of premium audio program.</p>
<p>This is an area where Spotify has plenty of room to grow, considering the significant investment it has made in podcasts over the years. To date, that&#8217;s included buying up content producers like Gimlet Media, The Ringer and Parcast, as well as signing top creators like Joe Rogan, Addison Rae, Kim Kardashian West, DC Comics, Michelle Obama and The Duke and Duchess of Sussex, among others. Spotify also bought podcast tools like Anchor and other ad technology and hosting services.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="R41eJRXjgN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/spotify-signs-the-joe-rogan-experience-to-an-exclusive-multi-year-deal/">Spotify signs &#8216;The Joe Rogan Experience&#8217; to an exclusive multi-year deal</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spotify signs &#8216;The Joe Rogan Experience&#8217; to an exclusive multi-year deal&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/19/spotify-signs-the-joe-rogan-experience-to-an-exclusive-multi-year-deal/embed/#?secret=R41eJRXjgN" data-secret="R41eJRXjgN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The advantage with podcasts is that Spotify has the ability to monetize them in multiple ways at once &#8212; with ads and subscriptions or direct payments, if it chose. And, of course, there are no licensing fees or royalties to contend with, as with streaming music.</p>
<p>Spotify could also adjust the podcast payments model as needed to fit its different geographies and the way customers around the world prefer to consume and pay for podcast content.</p>
<p>None of this thinking was about near-term launches, Ek also clarified.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think it’s early days, though, to specifically kind of look at how that could play out,&#8221; he said, talking about how the different models could take shape. &#8220;But, obviously, if that were to be the case, that revenue profile would be different than how we do music.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/spotify-hints-toward-plans-for-podcast-subscriptions-a-la-carte-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CA Supreme Court denies lawsuit challenging Prop 22&#8217;s constitutionality</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ca-supreme-court-denies-lawsuit-challenging-prop-22s-constitutionality/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ca-supreme-court-denies-lawsuit-challenging-prop-22s-constitutionality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 22:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prop 22]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The California Supreme Court today shot down the lawsuit filed by a group of rideshare drivers in California and the Service Employees International Union that alleged Proposition 22 violates the state&#8217;s constitution. &#8220;We are disappointed in the Supreme Court’s decision not to hear our case, but make no mistake: we are not deterred in our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The California Supreme Court today shot down the lawsuit filed by a group of rideshare drivers in California and the Service Employees International Union that alleged Proposition 22 violates the state&#8217;s constitution.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are disappointed in the Supreme Court’s decision not to hear our case, but make no mistake: we are not deterred in our fight to win a livable wage and basic rights,&#8221; Hector Castellanos, a plaintiff in the case, said in a statement. &#8220;We will consider every option available to protect California workers from attempts by companies like Uber and Lyft to subvert our democracy and attack our rights in order to improve their bottom lines.&#8221;</p>
<p>The suit argued Prop 22 makes it harder for the state’s legislature to create and enforce a workers’ compensation system for gig workers. It also argues Prop 22 violates the rule that limits ballot measures to a single issue, as well as unconstitutionally defines what would count as an amendment to the measure. As it stands today, Prop 22 requires a seven-eighths legislative supermajority in order to amend the measure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We’re thankful, but not surprised, that the California Supreme Court has rejected this meritless lawsuit,&#8221; Jim Pyatt, a rideshare driver who advocated for Prop 22 and worked with the Yes on 22 campaign, said in a statement. &#8220;We’re hopeful this will send a strong signal to special interests to stop trying to undermine the will of voters who overwhelmingly stood with drivers to pass Proposition 22. The ballot measure was supported by nearly 60 percent of California voters across the political spectrum including hundreds of thousands of app-based drivers. It’s time to respect the vast majority of California voters as well as the drivers most impacted by Prop 22.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">How to contact TechCrunch</h4>
		
<p class="p1">Got a tip? Contact us securely using SecureDrop. Find out more <a href="https://techcrunch.com/securedrop"><span class="s1"><b>here</b></span></a>. You can also reach this author via Signal at 415-516-5243</p>
<p class="p1">	</div>
	</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Uber, Lyft and other companies have said they have their eyes on pursuing Prop 22-like legislation elsewhere. Given Uber and Lyft’s anti-gig-workers-as-employees stance, it came as no surprise when Uber and Lyft separately said they would pursue similar legislation in other parts of the country and the world.</p>
<p>Lyft, for example, has created external organizations that push for the independent contractor classification. Two of those organizations are <a href="https://twitter.com/independent_il?lang=en">Illinoisans for Independent Work</a> and <a href="https://ny4independentwork.com/">New Yorkers for Independent Work</a>. Illinoisans for Independent Work was established in June and funded by Lyft with $1.2 million, <a href="https://www.elections.il.gov/CampaignDisclosure/ItemizedDebts.aspx?FiledDocID=eUDnXycc0bZji1aAIn595w%3d%3d">according to committee filings</a>. The <a href="https://www.elections.il.gov/CampaignDisclosure/CommitteeDetail.aspx?ID=rHhufRntQEXyDkciM0QCNQ%3d%3d&amp;T=637424244424180521">stated purpose</a> of the committee is “to support candidates who share the ideology of our organization and the value of independent work.”</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/">But as we&#8217;ve previously discussed</a>, the implementation of Prop 22 doesn&#8217;t mark the end of the battle for some gig workers to achieve employee status. There is a concerted effort to keep organizing this year, and getting ready to fight back wherever the next legislative battle emerges.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ca-supreme-court-denies-lawsuit-challenging-prop-22s-constitutionality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108489</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Myanmar military government orders telecom networks to temporarily block Facebook</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/myanmar-orders-telecom-networks-to-temporarily-block-facebook/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/myanmar-orders-telecom-networks-to-temporarily-block-facebook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 21:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Myanmar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Myanmar&#8217;s new military government has ordered local telecom firms to temporarily block Facebook until February 7 midnight, days after the military seized power in the Southeast Asian nation in a military coup. Several users on Myanmar subreddit reported moments ago that Facebook was already inaccessible on their phones, suggesting that internet service providers had already [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Myanmar&#8217;s new military government has ordered local telecom firms to temporarily block Facebook until February 7 midnight, days after the military seized power in the Southeast Asian nation in a military coup.</p>
<p>Several users on <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/myanmar/">Myanmar subreddit</a> reported moments ago that Facebook was already inaccessible on their phones, suggesting that internet service providers had already started to comply with the order, which demanded compliance by midnight Wednesday. (It&#8217;s about 4.30 am Thursday in Myanmar at the time of writing.)</p>
<p>Myanmar&#8217;s new government alleges that Facebook is contributing to instability in the country and in its order has cited a section of the local telecom law that justifies many actions for the greater benefit of public and state.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>NetBlocks, which tracks global internet usage, <a href="https://twitter.com/netblocks/status/1357078197989474305">reports</a> that MPT, a state-owned telecom operator that commands the market, has blocked Facebook as well as Messenger, Instagram and WhatsApp on its network. Telenor, one of the four telecom operators in the country, said it has expressed &#8220;grave concerns regarding breach of human rights&#8221; but has complied with Myanmar&#8217;s junta order.</p>
<p>A Facebook spokesperson said the company was &#8220;aware that access to Facebook is currently disrupted for some people.&#8221; The spokesperson added: &#8220;We urge authorities to restore connectivity so that people in Myanmar can communicate with their families and friends and access important information.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">BREAKING: Myanmar’s government is now blocking Facebook (including Instagram, WhatsApp, and Messenger) until Feb 7 at midnight.</p>
<p>Over 22 million people use Facebook in Myanmar, and it’s a critical tool for citizens to share information and organize. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KeepitOn?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#KeepitOn</a> <a href="https://t.co/E5Y46xuE7P">https://t.co/E5Y46xuE7P</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Access Now (@accessnow) <a href="https://twitter.com/accessnow/status/1357083712316440577?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The move comes after days of unrest in Myanmar, where earlier this week <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/myanmar-politics-idUSKBN2A00VK">military took control of the country</a> and declared a state of emergency for a year after detaining civilian leader Aung San Suu Kyi and other democratically elected leaders of her ruling National League for Democracy. Following the coup, citizens in many parts of Myanmar had reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/31/internet-connectivity-drops-in-myanmar-after-the-military-detains-aung-san-suu-kyi-and-other-leading-politicians/">facing internet and cellular outages for several hours</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="TudZJQCMa7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/31/internet-connectivity-drops-in-myanmar-after-the-military-detains-aung-san-suu-kyi-and-other-leading-politicians/">Internet connectivity drops in Myanmar after the military detains Aung San Suu Kyi and other leading politicians</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Internet connectivity drops in Myanmar after the military detains Aung San Suu Kyi and other leading politicians&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/31/internet-connectivity-drops-in-myanmar-after-the-military-detains-aung-san-suu-kyi-and-other-leading-politicians/embed/#?secret=TudZJQCMa7" data-secret="TudZJQCMa7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Facebook, which has become synonymous with the internet for citizens in Myanmar, has long been blamed for not doing enough to curb the spread of misinformation that prompted real-world violence in the country.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/06/facebook-still-isnt-taking-myanmar-seriously/">human rights report</a> in 2018 said that Facebook was used to &#8220;foment division and incite offline violence&#8221; in Myanmar, home to over 54 million people. Later in the same year, Facebook executives agreed that they hadn&#8217;t done enough.</p>
<p>BuzzFeed News <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/tasneemnashrulla/facebook-takes-stand-myanmar-coup">reported</a> this week that Facebook executives have now pledged to take proactive content moderation steps in Myanmar, which they termed as &#8220;Temporary High-Risk Location.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/myanmar-orders-telecom-networks-to-temporarily-block-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108449</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social platform veteran Sriram Krishnan is Andreessen Horowitz&#8217;s latest general partner</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/social-platform-veteran-sriram-krishnan-is-andreessen-horowitzs-latest-general-partner/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/social-platform-veteran-sriram-krishnan-is-andreessen-horowitzs-latest-general-partner/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 21:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andreessen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clubhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[effect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Andreessen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sriram Krishnan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Andreessen Horowitz founder Marc Andreessen announced that social media product veteran Sriram Krishnan will be joining the firm as their latest general partner. Krishnan, whose previous roles include stints at Snap, Facebook and Twitter, has gained a higher profile in recent weeks from his recurring audio show &#8220;The Good Time Show&#8221; on Clubhouse. His [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today, Andreessen Horowitz founder Marc Andreessen announced that social media product veteran Sriram Krishnan will be joining the firm as their latest general partner.</p>
<p>Krishnan, whose previous roles include stints at Snap, Facebook and Twitter, has gained a higher profile in recent weeks from his recurring audio show &#8220;The Good Time Show&#8221; on Clubhouse. His recent talk with Tesla CEO Elon Musk was something of a watershed moment for the audio chat platform driving plenty of new attention to the budding app.</p>
<p>This announcement follows a report in <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/37008f">The Information</a> regarding the hire earlier this week.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Krishnan&#8217;s hire comes at an interesting point for Andreessen Horowitz, the firm is at the center of plenty of chatter among media circles regarding their &#8220;go direct&#8221; content strategy. At the same time, a16z and its leadership have played an increasingly hard-nosed role in driving a broader backlash against tech media in recent years among founders and tech enthusiasts in their orbit. Krishnan has spent much of the past couple years building out his flirtations with &#8220;tech optimism&#8221; content with his interview newsletter &#8220;The Observer Effect<em>,&#8221;</em> his Clubhouse show and his prolific Twitter usage.</p>
<p>Broader &#8220;tech pessimism&#8221; among media outlets has, I think, partially been owed to a swift and outspoken shift in thinking regarding the societal responsibilities of social media platforms to more aggressively moderate the content they are surfacing on a global scale. Some of the partners at a16z, a Facebook backer, have been among the more vocal in pushing back on these critiques even as the executives at their portfolio companies have seemed more amenable to shift their thinking.</p>
<p>In his <a href="https://a16z.com/2021/02/03/sriram-krishnan/">blog post</a>, Andreessen notes that Krishnan will be joining the firm&#8217;s consumer team to invest in areas that include social.</p>
<p>Krishnan, well-regarded in tech circles, may play an important role at the firm as they approach more social investments in a world where the effects of rapidly scaled consumer platforms have become more understood. The firm and its partners have been throwing their full support behind Clubhouse in an aggressive push to promote the platform, flexing the firm&#8217;s celebrity connections and influence along the way as the platform quickly picks up millions of new users. Krishnan&#8217;s direct operator roles engaging with the product struggles of building platforms that responsibly scale will likely be an asset as the firm faces increased competition across an increasingly frothy venture market.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I believe I&#39;m now supposed to say the words long expected of me.</p>
<p>*clears throat*</p>
<p>&quot;How can I help?&quot;</p>
<p>&mdash; Sriram Krishnan (@sriramk) <a href="https://twitter.com/sriramk/status/1357055790654185474?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/social-platform-veteran-sriram-krishnan-is-andreessen-horowitzs-latest-general-partner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108400</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Todd Rundgren is about to launch a geofenced virtual tour</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/todd-rundgren-clearly-human/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/todd-rundgren-clearly-human/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 19:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Todd Rundgren]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2108333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The idea of a virtual concert tour might seem tailor-made for the pandemic, but musician Todd Rundgren said he&#8217;s actually been thinking about something like this for years. Rundgren told me that he&#8217;d become frustrated with our &#8220;collapsing&#8221; air travel system — exacerbated by hurricanes and climate change — that increasingly left him &#8220;sitting somewhere, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The idea of a virtual concert tour might seem tailor-made for the pandemic, but musician Todd Rundgren said he&#8217;s actually been thinking about something like this for years.</p>
<p>Rundgren told me that he&#8217;d become frustrated with our &#8220;collapsing&#8221; air travel system — exacerbated by hurricanes and climate change — that increasingly left him &#8220;sitting somewhere, unable to get to my next gig.&#8221; So he was already convinced that he needed to &#8220;start imagining other ways&#8221; to reach audiences.</p>
<p>But it was in the context of COVID-19 that Rundgren finally decided to make it happen, with his <a href="https://nocapshows.com/artist?name=toddrundgren">Clearly Human Tour</a> kicking off on February 14. He&#8217;d been planning for a traditional tour, but the dates kept getting pushed back due to the pandemic, until he finally told the organizers, &#8220;You have to let me do this. I can&#8217;t be committed to you and go two years without touring.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rundgren and his band will be performing entirely from Chicago, where they&#8217;ll play songs from across his career, as well as the entirety of his album &#8220;Nearly Human.&#8221; But the tour is taking place virtually across 25 U.S. cities, starting in Buffalo on February 14 and ending on March 22 in Seattle.</p>
<p>Rundgren said he found this more appealing than the idea of performing &#8220;one show and then blast it out to everybody.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="INCrLl5Wzu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/spotify-adds-virtual-event-listings-to-its-app/">Spotify adds virtual event listings to its app</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Spotify adds virtual event listings to its app&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/15/spotify-adds-virtual-event-listings-to-its-app/embed/#?secret=INCrLl5Wzu" data-secret="INCrLl5Wzu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;People plan weeks or months in advance for this particular event, it attracts people from all over the metropolitan area or a particular region,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s a social event as much as anything else, and that&#8217;s what we are trying to do with the localization.&#8221;</p>
<p>That means performing live shows at 8 p.m., according to whatever the local time zone might be. Rundgren said the band will also try to &#8220;self-hypnotize&#8221; to get into the proper spirit: &#8220;We&#8217;ll dress all the walls with posters, sports team memorabilia &#8230; We&#8217;ll get food flown in from familiar local eateries.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other features include virtual meet and greets with local fans, as well as placing video screens around the concert venue to display virtual audience members. (There are a limited number of in-person tickets for sale as well, but obviously those attendees will need to be in Chicago.)</p>
<p>The concerts will be geofenced, although Rundgren said the approach has evolved — it&#8217;s less about limiting the Buffalo concert to Buffalo attendees, and more about enforcing geographic restrictions based on Rundgren&#8217;s contractual obligations. Or as he put it, &#8220;It&#8217;s less about enclosing an audience, and more about fencing them out.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2108386" style="width: 495px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2108386" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2108386" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trclearhuman2_fingers.jpg?w=485" alt="Clearly Human poster" width="485" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trclearhuman2_fingers.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trclearhuman2_fingers.jpg?resize=107,150 107w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trclearhuman2_fingers.jpg?resize=214,300 214w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trclearhuman2_fingers.jpg?resize=768,1078 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trclearhuman2_fingers.jpg?resize=485,680 485w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/trclearhuman2_fingers.jpg?resize=36,50 36w" sizes="(max-width: 485px) 100vw, 485px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2108386" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Todd Rundgren</p></div></p>
<p>Rundgren is staging the tour with support from <a href="https://nocapshows.com">NoCap</a>, the livestreaming concert startup <a href="https://www.billboard.com/articles/business/9414054/cisco-adler-donavon-frankenreiter-launch-concert-livestream-platform-nocap">founded by musicians Cisco Adler and Donavon Frankenreiter</a>. NoCap has been around for less than a year, and Adler said that while it sold 700 tickets for its first show, it&#8217;s now selling &#8220;30, 40, 50 thousand tickets&#8221; per show. And he predicted that virtual concerts won&#8217;t be going away when the pandemic ends.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are all these underserved markets that you can visit once every five years, if that,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The future of this becomes a hybrid model.&#8221;</p>
<p>After all, he noted that televising sports has only made them &#8220;bigger and more global.&#8221; Similarly, when Adler was thinking about livestreaming concerts, he said, &#8220;I didn’t look at it as: How do we build a Band Aid and help everyone through this gap? It was more: How do we build a bridge to the other side of what music can be?&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nuuqyXQAr4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/24/fortnite-hosted-a-psychedelic-travis-scott-concert-and-12-3m-people-watched/">Fortnite hosted a psychedelic Travis Scott concert and 12.3M people watched</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fortnite hosted a psychedelic Travis Scott concert and 12.3M people watched&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/24/fortnite-hosted-a-psychedelic-travis-scott-concert-and-12-3m-people-watched/embed/#?secret=nuuqyXQAr4" data-secret="nuuqyXQAr4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/todd-rundgren-clearly-human/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2108333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcing the TC Early Stage Pitch-Off</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/announcing-the-tc-early-stage-pitch-off/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/announcing-the-tc-early-stage-pitch-off/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neesha A. Tambe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 19:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Founders — by now you must have heard about TechCrunch Early Stage events on April 1 and 2 and July 8 and 9. The two-day founder and entrepreneur bootcamp brings together top experts to teach you how to get ahead and build a successful company. This year on the second day of each event we’re [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founders — by now you must have heard about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1">TechCrunch Early Stage</a> events on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-1">April 1 and 2</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/early-stage-2021-part-2">July 8 and 9</a>. The two-day founder and entrepreneur bootcamp brings together top experts to teach </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">you</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> how to get ahead and build a successful company. This year on the second day of each event we’re adding a twist — the </span><b>Early Stage Pitch-Off</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. TechCrunch is on the hunt to showcase 10 early-stage startups to our global audience of investors, press and tech industry leaders. <a href="https://tc692057.typeform.com/to/jNejpAvG">Apply here</a> for the April 2 Early Stage Pitch-Off by February 21.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It wouldn’t be a TC event without highlighting the best startups in the business. Here’s how it will work. Ten founders will pitch on stage for five minutes, followed by a five-minute Q&amp;A with an esteemed panel of VC judges. The top three will then proceed to the finals, pitching again but this time with a more intensive Q&amp;A and a new panel of judges. The winner will receive a feature article on TechCrunch.com, one-year free subscription to ExtraCrunch and a free Founder Pass to TechCrunch Disrupt this fall.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nervous to pitch on-stage in front of thousands? Fear not. After completing the application, selected founders will receive several training sessions during a remote mini-bootcamp, communication training and personalized pitch-coaching by the Startup Battlefield team. Selected startups will also be announced on TechCrunch.com in advance of the show. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What does it take to qualify? TechCrunch is looking for early-stage, pre-Series-A companies with limited press. The Early Stage Pitch-Off is open to companies from around the globe, consumer or enterprise and in any industry — biotech, space, mobility, impact, SaaS, hardware, sustainability and more.</span></p>
<p>Founders don&#8217;t miss your chance to pitch your company on the world&#8217;s best tech stage. <a href="https://tc692057.typeform.com/to/jNejpAvG">Apply</a> today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/announcing-the-tc-early-stage-pitch-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107836</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deep Science: AIs with high class and higher altitudes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/deep-science-ais-with-high-class-and-higher-altitudes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/deep-science-ais-with-high-class-and-higher-altitudes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 19:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2105736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Researchers are using AI to analyze MRI scans and even track elephants using satellite photography.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There&#8217;s more AI news out there than anyone can possibly keep up with. But you can stay tolerably up to date on the most interesting developments with this column, which collects AI and machine learning advancements from around the world and explains why they might be important to tech, startups or civilization.</p>
<p>Before we get to the research in this edition, however, here&#8217;s <a href="https://itif.org/publications/2021/01/25/who-winning-ai-race-china-eu-or-united-states-2021-update">a study from the ITIF</a> trade group evaluating the relative positions of the U.S., EU and China in the AI &#8220;race.&#8221; I put race in quotes because no one knows where we&#8217;re going or how long the track is — though it&#8217;s still worth checking who&#8217;s in front every once in a while.</p>
<p>The answer this year is the U.S., which is ahead largely due to private investment from large tech firms and venture capital. China is catching up in terms of money and published papers but still lags far behind and takes a hit for relying on U.S. silicon and infrastructure.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LChcDZawvN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/chinese-autonomous-vehicle-startup-pony-ai-hits-5-3-billion-valuation/">Chinese autonomous vehicle startup Pony.ai hits $5.3 billion valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chinese autonomous vehicle startup Pony.ai hits $5.3 billion valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/chinese-autonomous-vehicle-startup-pony-ai-hits-5-3-billion-valuation/embed/#?secret=LChcDZawvN" data-secret="LChcDZawvN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The EU is operating at a smaller scale, and making smaller gains, especially in the area of AI-based startup funding. Part of that is no doubt the inflated valuations of U.S. companies, but the trend is clear — and perhaps an opportunity for investors is as well, who might see this as an opportunity to get in on some high-quality startups without needing quite so much capital.</p>
<p><a href="https://www2.datainnovation.org/2021-china-eu-us-ai.pdf">The full report (PDF)</a> goes into much more detail, of course, if you&#8217;re interested in a more granular breakdown of these numbers.</p>
<p>If the authors had known about this new <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2021-01/uosc-uaa012821.php">Amazon-funded AI research center at USC</a> they probably would have pointed at it as a good example of the type of partnership that helps keep U.S. production of AI scholars up.</p>
<h2>A touch of class</h2>
<p>On the farthest possible end from monetization and practical application, we have two interesting uses of machine learning in fields where human expertise is valued in different ways.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2105800" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2105800" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2105800 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png" alt="Diagram showing different modes of music as groups of dots in a 3D space." width="1024" height="701" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png?resize=300,206 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png?resize=768,526 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png?resize=680,466 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png?resize=1536,1052 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/music-segments.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2105800" class="wp-caption-text">Each color indicates a different mode style. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> EPFL</p></div></p>
<p>At Switzerland&#8217;s EPFL, some music-minded boffins at the Digital and Cognitive Musicology lab were investigating the shift in the use of modes in classical music over the ages — major, minor, other or none at all. In an effort to objectively categorize thousands of pieces from hundreds of years and composers, they created an unsupervised machine learning system to listen to and categorize the pieces according to mode. (Some of the data and methods are available <a href="https://github.com/DCMLab/HistoryModes_DataCode">on GitHub</a>.)</p>
<p>&#8220;We already knew that in the Renaissance, for example, there were more than two modes. But for periods following the Classical era, the distinction between the modes blurs together. We wanted to see if we could nail down these differences more concretely,&#8221; <a href="https://actu.epfl.ch/news/machine-learning-helps-retrace-evolution-of-clas-2/">he explained in a university news release</a>.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/deep-science-ais-with-high-class-and-higher-altitudes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2105736</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket.Chat raises $19M for its open-source approach to integrated enterprise messaging</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/rocket-chat-raises-19m-for-its-open-source-approach-to-integrated-enterprise-messaging/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/rocket-chat-raises-19m-for-its-open-source-approach-to-integrated-enterprise-messaging/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket.Chat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chat platforms like Slack have been game-changers when it comes to what business users want and expect out of their work communications. Today, a company that&#8217;s aiming to move the goalpost again with an integrated, open-source alternative is announcing some funding to fuel its growth. Rocket.Chat, a startup and open-source-based platform of the same name [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chat platforms like Slack have been game-changers when it comes to what business users want and expect out of their work communications. Today, a company that&#8217;s aiming to move the goalpost again with an integrated, open-source alternative is announcing some funding to fuel its growth.</p>
<p><a href="http://rocket.chat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rocket.Chat</a>, a startup and open-source-based platform of the same name used by banks, the U.S. Navy, NGOs and other organizations big and small to set up and run any variety of secure virtual communications services from one place &#8212; they can include not just team chat, but also customer service, collaboration platforms covering your staff and outside partners, school classrooms, conferences and more &#8212; has raised $19 million.</p>
<p>The company plans to use the funding both to continue adding more customers, but also expanding the platform&#8217;s functionality, including more security features, a way to use the service over federated blockchain architecture, apps for marketplaces, options for bots, and more social media and omnichannel customer service integrations, and potentially facilities for virtual events.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As more business interactions have gone virtual, it has essentially opened the door for companies like Rocket.Chat building virtual communications platforms to build in an increasing number of features into what it does.</p>
<p>The Series A round of funding has four lead investors &#8212; <a href="https://valorcapitalgroup.com/">Valor Capital Group</a>, <a href="https://www.greycroft.com/">Greycroft</a>, <a href="https://monashees.com.br/pt-br/intro/">Monashees</a> and <a href="https://www.nea.com/">NEA</a> &#8212; with <a href="https://www.eventures.vc/">e.ventures</a>, <a href="https://www.graphenevc.com/">Graphene Ventures</a>, <a href="https://www.onevc.vc/">ONEVC</a> and <a href="https://www.dgf.com.br/">DGF</a> also participating. The Porto Alegre, Brazil-based startup (which is incorporated in Delaware) has now raised $27 million to date.</p>
<p>Rocket.Chat is not disclosing its valuation with this round, but it comes on the back of some significant growth in the last year. The startup now has <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">16 million registered users across 150 countries, with eight million of them monthly active users. Of that 16 million, 11.3 million users registered for the service in the past six months. It&#8217;s currently installed on some 845,000 servers, the company said, and has over 1,500 developers building on its platform.</span></p>
<p>Rocket.Chat&#8217;s funding and expanding business comes as part of a bigger focus overall for open-source platforms.</p>
<p>The promise of open source in the world of enterprise IT has been that it provides a platform to customise a service to fit with how the organization in question wants to use it, while at the same time providing tools to make sure it is robust enough in terms of security, extensibility and more for use in a business environment.</p>
<p>Over the years, it has become a big business opportunity, in line with organizations getting more sophisticated in terms of what they expect and need out of their IT services, where off-the-shelf apps may not always fit the bill.</p>
<p>Rocket.Chat positions itself as something of an all-in-one superstore for any and all communications needs, with organizations putting their own services together in whatever way works for their purposes.</p>
<p>It can either be hosted and managed by customers themselves, or used as a cloud-based SaaS, with its <a href="https://rocket.chat/pricing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pricing</a> ranging between free (for minimal, self-hosted services) to $4 per user per month, or higher, depending on which services customers want to have, whether its hosted and how much the platform is being used each month.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107947" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107947" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2107947 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="382" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png 3090w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Product-Screenshot-Team-Collaboration.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2107947" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rocket.Chat</p></div></p>
<p>As you can see in the mock-up here, its basic platform looks a little like Slack. But if you are using it for omnichannel communications for customer service, for example, you can build a platform within Rocket.Chat where you incorporate communications from any other platforms that might be used to communicate with customers.</p>
<p>Its work collaboration platform starts with Rocket.Chat&#8217;s basic chat interface, but also allows you to integrate alerts and links to other apps that you regularly use, as well as video calls and more. These and other functions built on Rocket.Chat can then be made to interact with each other &#8212; for example handing tickets off in customer service to internal tech support teams &#8212; or separately.</p>
<p>The idea is that by providing a version that can be hosted and managed by organizations themselves, it gives them more privacy and control over their electronic messaging.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Its thousands of customers reflect an interesting mix of the kinds of organizations that are looking for solutions that do just that. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Gabriel Engel, the CEO and founder, tells me the list includes several military and public sector organizations including the U.S. Navy, financial services companies like <a href="https://rocket.chat/blog/events/google-summer-of-code-2020-together-credit-suisse-and-rocket-chat-empower-the-next-generation-of-open-source-developers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Credit Suisse</a> and Citibank, as well as the likes of Cornell, Arizona State, </span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">UC Irvine, Bielefeld University and other educational institutions, and a number of other private companies. </span></p>
<p>That flexibility does not always play to Rocket.Chat&#8217;s advantage, however. Controversially, it seems that the list also includes the other end of the spectrum of organizations that want to keep their messages limited to a very specific audience: <a href="https://www.memri.org/reports/jihad-and-terrorism-threat-monitor-jttm-weekly-january-23-30-2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Islamic State</a> it turns out also hosts and runs a Rocket.Chat to disseminate messages.</p>
<p>Engel says that while this is not something that the company supports, and that it works with authorities to shut down users like these as much as it can, it&#8217;s a consequence of how the service was built:</p>
<p>&#8220;We are not able to track usage if they are running Rocket.Chat servers of their own,&#8221; he said. &#8220;There&#8217;s a reason why the U.S. Navy uses Rocket.Chat. And that&#8217;s because we cannot track and know what they&#8217;re doing. It&#8217;s isolated from any external influence, for better or worse.&#8221; He added that the company has policies so that if an illicit organization is using its SaaS version, these get taken down in cooperation with authorities. &#8220;But just as with Linux, if you download and run Rocket.Chat on your own computer, then obviously it&#8217;s out of our reach.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hearing about how a platform built with privacy by design can be abused, with seemingly little to be done about it, does seem to offset some of the benefits. The ethics of that predicament, and whether technology can ever solve it, or whether it will be up to government authorities to address, will continue to be a question not just for Rocket.Chat but for all of us.</p>
<p>In the meantime, investors are interested because of the alternative it provides to those groups that need it.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">“In today’s environment, organizations must have a secure communication platform to engage teams internally, communicate with customers and partners externally, and connect with safe interest-based communities,” said Dylan Pearce, partner at Greycroft, in a statement. “Rocket.Chat’s world-class management team and open-source community lead the industry in innovation and provide a communications platform capable of serving every person on the planet.” </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VYdIO52YnX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/facebook-messenger-lands-on-oculus-quest/">Facebook Messenger lands on Oculus Quest</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook Messenger lands on Oculus Quest&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/02/facebook-messenger-lands-on-oculus-quest/embed/#?secret=VYdIO52YnX" data-secret="VYdIO52YnX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/rocket-chat-raises-19m-for-its-open-source-approach-to-integrated-enterprise-messaging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107834</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Polytomic announces $2.4M seed to move business data where it&#8217;s needed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/polytomic-announces-2-4m-seed-to-move-business-data-where-its-needed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/polytomic-announces-2-4m-seed-to-move-business-data-where-its-needed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caffeinated capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plangrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polytomic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107891</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is so much data sitting inside companies these days, but getting data to the people who need it most remains a daunting challenge. Polytomic, a graduate of the Y Combinator Winter 2020 cohort set out to solve that problem, and today the startup announced a $2.4 million seed. Caffeinated Capital led the round with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There is so much data sitting inside companies these days, but getting data to the people who need it most remains a daunting challenge. <a href="https://www.polytomic.com/">Polytomic</a>, a graduate of the Y Combinator Winter 2020 cohort set out to solve that problem, and today the startup announced a $2.4 million seed.</p>
<p>Caffeinated Capital led the round with help from Bow Capital and a number of individual investors including the founders of PlanGrid, Tracy Young and Ralph Gootee, the company where Polytomic founders CEO Ghalib Suleiman and CTO Nathan Yergler both previously worked.</p>
<p>&#8220;We synch internal data to business systems. You can imagine your sales team living in Salesforce and would like to see who&#8217;s using your product from your customer data that lives in other internal databases. We have a no-code web app that moves internal data to the business systems of the office,&#8221; Suleiman told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Data lives in silos across every company, and Polytomic lets you build the connectors by dragging and dropping components in the Polytomic interface. This new data then shows up as additional fields in the target application. So you might have a usage percentage field added to Salesforce automatically if you were connecting to customer usage data.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RbLtbRxV8i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/stepzen-snares-8m-seed-to-build-data-integration-api/">StepZen snares $8M seed to build data integration API</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;StepZen snares $8M seed to build data integration API&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/stepzen-snares-8m-seed-to-build-data-integration-api/embed/#?secret=RbLtbRxV8i" data-secret="RbLtbRxV8i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company actually sells the product to business operations teams, who would be charged with setting up a catalogue or menu of data sources that live in Polytomic. This is usually handled by someone like a business analyst who can configure the different sources. Once that&#8217;s done, anyone can build connectors to these data sources by selecting them from the menu and then choosing where to deliver the data.</p>
<p>The founders came up with the idea for the company because when they were at PlanGrid, they faced a problem getting data to the people who needed it in the company. The problem became more pronounced as the company grew and they had ever more data and more employees who needed access to it.</p>
<p>They left PlanGrid in 2018 and launched Polytomic a year later to begin attacking the problem. The two founders joined YC as a way to learn to refine the product, and were still working on it on Demo Day, delivering their presentation off the record because they weren&#8217;t quite done with it yet.</p>
<p>They released the first iteration of the product last September and report some progress getting customers and gaining revenue. Early customers include Brex, ShipBob, Sourcegraph and Vanta.</p>
<p>The company has no additional employees beyond the two founders as of yet, but with the seed funding in the bank, they plan to begin hiring a few people this year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vZQ2YLHVWi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/jitsu-nabs-2m-seed-to-build-open-source-data-integration-platform/">Jitsu nabs $2M seed to build open-source data integration platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jitsu nabs $2M seed to build open-source data integration platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/jitsu-nabs-2m-seed-to-build-open-source-data-integration-platform/embed/#?secret=vZQ2YLHVWi" data-secret="vZQ2YLHVWi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/polytomic-announces-2-4m-seed-to-move-business-data-where-its-needed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107891</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: In My Room</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/gillmor-gang-in-my-room/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/gillmor-gang-in-my-room/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No sooner did we start developing a newsletter, the newsletter industry exploded. Twitter jumped in with a purchase of Revue, Facebook was rumored to be investigating the platform, and each new day brought further experiments. You could blame it on the post-Trump lifting of the fog of despair. The pandemic continued apace, with new variants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/INUgKm8uiqg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>No sooner did we start developing a newsletter, the newsletter industry exploded. Twitter jumped in with a purchase of Revue, Facebook was rumored to be investigating the platform, and each new day brought further experiments. You could blame it on the post-Trump lifting of the fog of despair. The pandemic continued apace, with new variants spurring distribution of vaccines and a transparency in communications with the new president and his team.</p>
<p>After years of social mining of our behavior, interests and transactions, inference has been replaced by direct evidence. The politics of data pressure mandate that we expect free software bundled with increasingly powerful hardware. The core utility of a phone culture shifted as people kept to their homes and mostly used the televisions for entertainment and news, and the phones as notifications consumers. The desktop remained the creation engine for business documents, analytics and information triage.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One year after the pandemic took hold, the outlines of the recovery are becoming visible. Because so much of our transaction history is funneled through the phone, we have left less need or incentive for teasing out indirect data and making inferences on it. Netflix is a honeypot for direct recording of choices, tagged along each customer’s timeline with the minute-by-minute social characteristics of the groups they participate in.</p>
<p>The resulting data type is beyond the bifurcation of product in the Apple hardware sense and the user as product in the Google or Facebook sense, Netflix creates a kind of social signal out of the analytics that is recycled back into the service where it impacts on the user’s behavior organically. We tap into the recommendation flow not just at the Netflix level but also the notification and conversational flows.</p>
<p>Newsletters offer a similar organic resonance, as they combine the author’s analysis of the information flow (in the form of citations) with the actual orbiting references. As with Netflix, the user leaves a breadcrumb trail along with time data as they record their choices and unread items. The maturing newsletter model is one where the authorship more correctly anticipates what has been seen by the target audience, and saves time and insight for rapid return on the investment. Group metrics synthesize this benefit into value on Netflix, where the “ratings” are based on retention and time compression. This is the newsletter opportunity.</p>
<p>If you buy the idea of media consolidation under the newsletter umbrella, how will that manifest itself? Already we’re experiencing a battle similar to the age of blogs, where individual voices built a social engagement cloud that emulated the dynamics of a magazine. Just as Apple inserted itself into the music business with playlists and MTV with top 40 radio, blogs leveraged Twitter and social to create bundles of news, features and commentary. As with playlists, the users were in charge.</p>
<p>Mobile brought notifications to the party, blending blogs with media. Initially podcasts leveraged RSS’s attachment extension to download sound and video files to iPods. But when streaming arrived, the preferred way of consuming the content was by clicking on the notification. This in turn disrupted the cable networks just as the kids went mobile and abandoned TV. During the 2020 campaign, notifications were a great way of routing around insufferable analysis in favor of the actual events.<br />
Meanwhile, Facebook Live, Periscope and YouTube gave virtually everybody a seat at the table. Podcasts democratized media, and streaming democratized distribution. I know many think podcasting is experiencing a renaissance, but personally I think streaming is inventing a new paradigm of the economics of the industry.</p>
<p>Take Clubhouse, for example. It’s distinguished by what it doesn’t do rather than what it does: no recording, therefore no replays. No video, only audio. No lurking, at least surreptitious checking out the scene. If you click on a Clubhouse notification, your name pops up for all to see. And there’s no button to Leave Loudly, just Quietly. Significantly, however, you can operate in a private room, and then go public if you want to. It’s podcasting with an invisibility mode.</p>
<p>Private rooms are just the place to hash things out. Today I had several conversations skirting these issues. One was muted, tentative, doubt mixed with an arrogant optimism. The other was supple, teeming with validation and the presence of humor to leaven the serious nature of the fleeting time we may have. Not recorded, in one case just a regular cell call. But the mulch created informs this post, with its scaffolding of intersecting items lurking in calm support. Podcasting, no.</p>
<p>It reminds me of the Hayden Planetarium, where the planets orbit and the asteroids bisect the swirling cosmos. We’re suspended in the teeming reaches of the near universe, with its fractal efficiency in the representation of the whole. The enterprise moves glacially forward, a breast stroke pace with a small wake. Somehow big things are afoot. At a minimum, they could be.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://gillmorgang.substack.com"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, January 22, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><a href="https://gillmorgang.substack.com">Subscribe to the Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/gillmor-gang-in-my-room/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107621</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify Group Session UX teardown: The fails and their fixes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ux-teardown-spotify-group-sessions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ux-teardown-spotify-group-sessions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2106350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We highlight some of Spotify Group Sessions user experience failings and offer ways to fix them, as well as a number of UX features that are done right. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In July last year, Spotify extended its shared-queue feature, Group Session, to support remote usage. Essentially a “party mode,” the feature offers a way for participants to contribute to a collaborative playlist in real-time and control what’s playing across everyone’s devices.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/28/spotifys-new-party-mode-feature-group-session-goes-remote/">As TechCrunch&#8217;s Sarah Perez explained</a>, Premium users are able to tune into the same playlist or podcast together at the same time, even if they’re not in the same place. Prompted by the coronavirus pandemic, Spotify, like a spew of other tech companies, is trying to create more shared online experiences that are lockdown-proof, and as people are being forced to spend more time indoors and online.</p>
<p>In our latest UX teardown, with the help of <a href="https://builtformars.co.uk/">Built for Mars</a> founder and UX expert Peter Ramsey, we highlight some of Spotify Group Sessions user experience failings and offer ways to fix them, as well as a number of UX features that are done right. Many of these lessons can be applied to other existing digital products or ones you are currently building, including the need to remember the difference between usernames and display names, when it makes sense to combine common actions into one, and how to use &#8220;react and explain&#8221; on-boarding.</p>
<h2>Usernames and display names</h2>
<p>Always remember the difference between user names and displays.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2106366" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2106366" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2106366" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="287" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg 1400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=150,63 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=300,127 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=768,324 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=680,287 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CompareNames.jpg?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2106366" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Built For Mars</p></div></p>
<p>The fail<span style="font-weight: 400;">: If you created a Spotify account using Facebook, then you’re arbitrarily assigned an 11-digit display name. This is then shown to everyone you invite and is totally meaningless.</span></p>
<p>The fix<span style="font-weight: 400;">: Prompt the user to set a real display name when they create their first session. It avoids confusion and creates a more real experience.</span></p>
<p><strong>Steve O&#8217;Hear: This looks really sloppy and unprofessional, as well as being useless from a usability point of view. However, I’m guessing this is technical debt of some kind; any idea what’s going on here?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Peter Ramsey:</strong> Yes, it happens when usernames go from being irrelevant (i.e., Spotify) to suddenly relevant (i.e. when they add social features). But by that point, the database/infrastructure is already in motion.</p>
<p><strong>Can you think of an example where this has been done right?</strong></p>
<p>Twitter is the perfect example of this done right. There can only be one @jack, but loads of people with the display name Jack. Otherwise basically every tweet would be by some obscure name and the world would feel like Reddit (i.e., anonymous).</p>
<h2>Combining common actions into one<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/ux-teardown-spotify-group-sessions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2106350</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok will recheck the age of every user in Italy after DPA order</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok has agreed to re-verify the age of every user in Italy and block access to users who state they are younger than 13, the country&#8217;s data protection agency said today. The video-sharing social network confirmed that from February 9 every user in Italy will be required to go through its age gate process again [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TikTok has agreed to re-verify the age of every user in Italy and block access to users who state they are younger than 13, the country&#8217;s data protection agency <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9533424#english_version">said today</a>.</p>
<p>The video-sharing social network confirmed that from February 9 every user in Italy will be required to go through its age gate process again &#8212; and only those users aged 13 and older will be allowed to continue using the app.</p>
<p>Accounts of those who say they are younger than 13 will be deleted.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The move to require all users in Italy to go through TikTok&#8217;s age-verification process again follows an emergency <a href="https://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/9524224">order</a> by Italy&#8217;s GPDP on January 22 after the death of a 10-year-old girl from Palermo who died of asphyxiation after participating in a “blackout challenge” on the social network, according to reports in local media.</p>
<p>TikTok was given a deadline of January 29 to respond to the GPDP&#8217;s order, as we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">reported earlier</a>. Today the agency confirmed the measures TikTok has agreed to take.</p>
<p>As well as asking all users in the country to re-enter their date of birth to continue using the app, the GPDP said TikTok will &#8220;consider deploying AI-based systems for age verification purposes&#8221;.</p>
<p>The Italian watchdog added that it will be monitoring the effectiveness of TikTok&#8217;s age verification process.</p>
<p>The basic age-check TikTok conducts when users sign up &#8212; which it will be pushing out again to all users in Italy in a few days &#8212; simply requires users to enter a date of birth, so is very easy to circumvent. But it&#8217;s also clear that age verification online remains a hard problem.</p>
<p>Robust identity checks to determine age beyond doubt threaten a &#8220;sledgehammer to crack a nut&#8221; scenario &#8212; potentially limiting service access in a way that&#8217;s unfair and risking harm to online anonymity and privacy, with potential knock-on impacts on other considerations like freedom of expression and data security.</p>
<p>On the flip side are growing public concerns that underage users are being exposed to inappropriate and even harmful content online.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5NWeoXLaGM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/">TikTok has until Friday to respond to Italy&#8217;s order to block users it can&#8217;t age-verify after girl&#8217;s death</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok has until Friday to respond to Italy&#8217;s order to block users it can&#8217;t age-verify after girl&#8217;s death&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/tiktok-has-until-friday-to-respond-to-italys-order-to-block-users-it-cant-age-verify-after-girls-death/embed/#?secret=5NWeoXLaGM" data-secret="5NWeoXLaGM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>While TikTok&#8217;s lead data supervisor in the European Union is Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC), the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) includes a provision that allows national DPAs to take emergency interventions to protect users &#8212; which is the route the GPDP has used here.</p>
<p>&#8220;In order to identify users below 13 years with reasonable certainty following this initial check, the company undertook to further consider the deployment of AI-based systems,&#8221; the agency said today.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since the implementation of such systems requires balancing the need for accurate verification against the children’s right to data protection, the company committed to starting a dialogue with the Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) on the use of AI for age verification purposes. Ireland is where TikTok set its main establishment in the EU,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, the Irish Data Protection Commission told TechCrunch: &#8220;The DPC is engaging with TikTok to review, in the context of the processing of personal data, the measures implemented by the company to ensure it has effective means of identifying child users on the platform and, more generally, the measures and protections to protect the most vulnerable of users in terms of risks arising from the processing of their personal data.&#8221; So it remains to be seen whether the regulator will push for more robust age checks.</p>
<p>In another change triggered by the GPDP&#8217;s intervention TikTok has implemented an in-app button to enable users to &#8220;quickly and easily&#8221; report other users that may seem to be below 13 years of age.</p>
<p>Per TikTok, these reports are reviewed by moderators and &#8220;removed as necessary&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;All the above measures supplement those already in place,&#8221; the GPDP said, adding: &#8220;TikTok undertook to also double the number of Italian moderators of platform contents.&#8221;</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Alexandra Evans, TikTok&#8217;s head of child safety, added: &#8220;Keeping people on TikTok safe is our top priority. We&#8217;ve reached an agreement with the Garante and today, we&#8217;re taking additional steps to support our community in Italy. From February 9, we&#8217;ll be sending every user in Italy through our age gate process again and only users aged 13 and over will be able to continue using the app after going through this process. We&#8217;re also rolling out a new, dedicated in-app reporting button to allow users to flag an account they believe may be under the age of 13, which will then be reviewed by our team and removed as necessary.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is no finish line when it comes to protecting our users, especially our younger ones, and our work in this important area doesn&#8217;t stop. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re continuing to invest in the people, processes and technologies that help to keep our community a safe space for positive, creative expression.&#8221;</p>
<p>TikTok&#8217;s reissued age check in Italy will also be accompanied by a local information campaign in which TikTok will aim to raise parents’ and children’s awareness of the age checks and other child-safety-related features &#8212; both via its app and in the media.</p>
<p>&#8220;An information campaign will be launched by TikTok starting on February 4 both via the app and through other channels. The company will send push alerts to users on the app before blocking their access and will inform them on the need to enter their age. Banners will also be published containing links to information on security tools and on how to change profile settings from ‘public’ to ‘private’. The information campaign both via the web and through the press will be addressed to parents and the age threshold for registration will be specifically highlighted, among other things,&#8221; the GPDP said.</p>
<p>The agency also noted that TikTok has agreed to improve the wording of the short privacy notice intended for users aged under 18 years &#8212; &#8220;to explain what data are collected and how those data are processed in an easily understandable and user-oriented manner&#8221;.</p>
<p>In addition to TikTok&#8217;s impending information campaign, the GPDP is launching a child safety awareness-raising campaign of its own on national TV channels, in cooperation with a child protection charity called Telefono Azzurro. It said this will be targeted at parents to encourage them to supervise their kids&#8217; use of the app.</p>
<p>&#8220;The campaign is aimed at calling upon parents to actively supervise and pay special attention to the situations where their children are requested to enter their age in order to access TikTok,&#8221; it said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3eN2fS3eFK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/">TikTok to flag and downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims fact checkers can&#8217;t verify</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok to flag and downrank &#8216;unsubstantiated&#8217; claims fact checkers can&#8217;t verify&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-to-flag-and-downrank-unsubstantiated-claims-fact-checkers-cant-verify/embed/#?secret=3eN2fS3eFK" data-secret="3eN2fS3eFK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/tiktok-will-recheck-the-age-of-every-user-in-italy-after-dpa-order/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107857</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clearview AI ruled &#8216;illegal&#8217; by Canadian privacy authorities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/clearview-ai-ruled-illegal-by-canadian-privacy-authorities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/clearview-ai-ruled-illegal-by-canadian-privacy-authorities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clearview ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial recognition software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terms of service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Controversial facial recognition startup Clearview AI violated Canadian privacy laws when it collected photos of Canadians without their knowledge or permission, the country&#8217;s top privacy watchdog has ruled. The New York-based company made its splashy newspaper debut a year ago by claiming it had collected over 3 billion photos of people&#8217;s faces and touting its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Controversial facial recognition startup Clearview AI violated Canadian privacy laws when it collected photos of Canadians without their knowledge or permission, the country&#8217;s top privacy watchdog has ruled.</p>
<p>The New York-based company made its splashy newspaper debut a year ago by claiming it had <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/18/technology/clearview-privacy-facial-recognition.html">collected over 3 billion photos</a> of people&#8217;s faces and touting its connections to law enforcement and police departments. But the startup has faced a slew of criticism for scraping social media sites also without their permission, prompting Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter to send cease and desist letters to demand it stops.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/opc-news/news-and-announcements/2021/nr-c_210203/?=february-2-2021">a statement</a>, Canada&#8217;s Office of the Privacy Commissioner said its investigation found Clearview had &#8220;collected highly sensitive biometric information without the knowledge or consent of individuals,&#8221; and that the startup &#8220;collected, used and disclosed Canadians&#8217; personal information for inappropriate purposes, which cannot be rendered appropriate via consent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Clearview rebuffed the allegations, claiming Canada&#8217;s privacy laws do not apply because the company doesn&#8217;t have a &#8220;real and substantial connection&#8221; to the country, and that consent was not required because the images it scraped were publicly available.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a challenge the company continues to face in court, as it faces <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/27/clearview-facial-recognition-private-companies/">a class action suit</a> citing Illinois&#8217; biometric protection laws that last year dinged Facebook to the tune of $550 million for violating the same law.</p>
<p>The Canadian privacy watchdog rejected Clearview&#8217;s arguments, and said it would &#8220;pursue other actions&#8221; if the company does not follow its recommendations, which included stopping the collection on Canadians and deleting all previously collected images.</p>
<p>Clearview said in July that it <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-clearview-ai-canada/clearview-ai-stops-offering-facial-recognition-technology-in-canada-idUSKBN2472RA">stopped providing</a> its technology to Canadian customers after the Royal Canadian Mounted Police and the Toronto Police Service were using the startup&#8217;s technology.</p>
<p>&#8220;What Clearview does is mass surveillance and it is illegal,&#8221; said Daniel Therrien, Canada&#8217;s privacy commissioner. &#8220;It is an affront to individuals&#8217; privacy rights and inflicts broad-based harm on all members of society, who find themselves continually in a police lineup. This is completely unacceptable.&#8221;</p>
<p>Doug Mitchell, an attorney for Clearview, said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Clearview AI&#8217;s technology is not available in Canada and it does not operate in Canada. In any event, Clearview AI only collects public information from the Internet which is explicitly permitted under PIPEDA. The Federal Court of Appeal has previously ruled in the privacy context that publicly available information means exactly what it says: &#8216;available or accessible by the citizenry at large.&#8217; There is no reason to apply a different standard here. Clearview AI is a search engine that collects public data just as much larger companies do, including Google, which is permitted to operate in Canada.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Updated with comment from Clearview AI.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mtQ3uVabCy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/clearview-source-code-lapse/">Security lapse exposed Clearview AI source code</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Security lapse exposed Clearview AI source code&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/clearview-source-code-lapse/embed/#?secret=mtQ3uVabCy" data-secret="mtQ3uVabCy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/clearview-ai-ruled-illegal-by-canadian-privacy-authorities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107913</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram confirms it&#8217;s working on a &#8216;Vertical Stories&#8217; feed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/instagram-confirms-its-working-on-a-vertical-stories-feed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/instagram-confirms-its-working-on-a-vertical-stories-feed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram is developing a new feature that could give its app more of a TikTok-like feel: Vertical Instagram Stories. Today, users browse through Stories through taps and horizontal swipes &#8212; a feature Instagram adopted from Snapchat. But now, Stories are passé. Even Snapchat is borrowing ideas from TikTok. Its recent launch of Spotlight, for example, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram is developing a new feature that could give its app more of a TikTok-like feel: Vertical Instagram Stories. Today, users browse through Stories through taps and horizontal swipes &#8212; a feature Instagram adopted from Snapchat. But now, Stories are passé. Even Snapchat is borrowing ideas from TikTok. Its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/23/snapchat-launches-a-tiktok-like-feed-called-spotlight-kick-started-by-paying-creators/">recent launch of Spotlight</a>, for example, is its own TikTok clone.</p>
<p>In many ways, vertical swiping feels more natural than taps and horizontal flicks. It is, after all, how users navigate much of the mobile web, as well as other key features across a variety of social apps, like Facebook&#8217;s News Feed or YouTube&#8217;s home page.</p>
<p>That said, turning Instagram Stories into a vertical feed would be a notable change, and one that could potentially set the stage for a shift away from more static content &#8212; like the photos and reshared Feed posts that still often fill the Stories section today. In a &#8220;Vertical Stories&#8221; feed, on the other hand, Instagram would likely prioritize video posts over images to better compete with TikTok, just as it&#8217;s currently tweaking its algorithms and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/instagram-redesign-puts-reels-and-shop-tabs-on-the-home-screen/">overall design</a> to prioritize Reels. (A turn of the dials that has already been leveraged by <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJfAChp/">indie</a> <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJf5mxV/">creators</a> to <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJfXGjT/">significantly</a> <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeJf5udh/">grow</a> their followings, in fact).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The &#8220;Vertical Stories&#8221; feature was spotted under development by <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1356574935024599040">Alessandro Paluzzi</a> who shared the discovery on his Twitter account.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Instagram?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Instagram</a> is working on Vertical Stories <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />Swipe up and down to browse stories. <a href="https://t.co/LDJje8l137">pic.twitter.com/LDJje8l137</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alessandro Paluzzi (@alex193a) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1356574935024599040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 2, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>His screenshot shows a simple user interface with text that reads: <em>&#8220;</em>Now you can swipe up and down to browse stories<em>&#8220;</em> and then a big, blue button labeled &#8220;Vertical Stories.&#8221;</p>
<p>Paluzzi tells TechCrunch that the feature is not yet live. Instead, he dug it up from Instagram&#8217;s code.</p>
<p>Instagram confirmed to TechCrunch the feature is being built but is not out to the public at this time.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is an early prototype and is not currently testing on Instagram,&#8221; a company spokesperson told us.</p>
<p>A prototype may never actually make it to a public launch, of course, but its existence does say something about what sort of ideas Instagram is considering as a means of offering a better challenge to TikTok.</p>
<p>Today, the company&#8217;s TikTok rival, Reels, has been shoehorned into the platform via the Instagram Explore page, where Reels sits in the top position. When you click on the Reels video here, you&#8217;re taken to a new user interface where you then vertically swipe through videos, similar to TikTok.</p>
<p>This doesn&#8217;t feel right, and the launch of the new format has added to Instagram&#8217;s clutter. Today, the app has all sorts of places users can publish their videos, including in the Feed, as Stories, as longer-form IGTV content, and now Reels. It&#8217;s too much.</p>
<p>Instagram knows this arrangement isn&#8217;t quite working. As Instagram head Adam Mosseri <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238513/instagram-adam-mosseri-reels-decoder-interview-podcast">recently told The Verge</a>, most people probably don&#8217;t even understand the difference between IGTV content and videos posted to Instagram, for example. He said the company was looking at ways to simplify and consolidate its ideas, too.</p>
<p>While his comments were focused on the confusion between Instagram&#8217;s normal video posts and IGTV, there&#8217;s also significant overlap between Instagram&#8217;s Stories&#8217; vertical video content and Reels. A &#8220;Vertical Stories&#8221; feed could allow for an eventual combination of those formats &#8212; Stories videos and Reels, perhaps.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not clear that&#8217;s at all what Instagram has in mind, though. The social network could just be looking to transition another part of its app to the more modern vertical feed, as the demand for the traditional Stories format declines.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="k3UJ2hIHLi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/facebook-and-instagrams-ai-generated-image-captions-now-offer-far-more-details/">Facebook and Instagram&#8217;s AI-generated image captions now offer far more details</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook and Instagram&#8217;s AI-generated image captions now offer far more details&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/19/facebook-and-instagrams-ai-generated-image-captions-now-offer-far-more-details/embed/#?secret=k3UJ2hIHLi" data-secret="k3UJ2hIHLi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/instagram-confirms-its-working-on-a-vertical-stories-feed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107819</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s new subsea cable between the US and Europe is now online</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/googles-new-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-and-europe-is-now-online/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/googles-new-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-and-europe-is-now-online/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subsea cable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virginia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2107855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google, together with its partner SubCom, today announced that the company&#8217;s privately owned Dunant subsea cable between Virginia Beach, Virginia and Saint-Hilaire-de-Riez on the French Atlantic coast is now operational. Google first announced this project, which was named after the first Nobel Peace Prize winner and founder of the Red Cross, Henry Dunant, back in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google, together with its partner <a href="https://www.subcom.com/">SubCom</a>, today<a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/infrastructure/googles-dunant-subsea-cable-is-now-ready-for-service"> announced</a> that the company&#8217;s privately owned Dunant subsea cable between Virginia Beach, Virginia and Saint-Hilaire-de-Riez on the French Atlantic coast is now operational.</p>
<p>Google first announced this project, which was named after the first Nobel Peace Prize winner and founder of the Red Cross, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Dunant">Henry Dunant,</a> back in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/google-builds-its-own-subsea-cable-from-the-us-to-france/">middle of 2018</a>. At the time it expected the project to go live in 2020, but besides dealing with the complications of spanning a long cable between continents, the project leaders probably didn&#8217;t budget for a pandemic at the time.</p>
<p>The almost 4,000-mile cable has a total capacity of 250 terabits per second &#8212; or enough to transmit the &#8220;entire digitized Library of Congress three times every second&#8221; (though maybe using Library of Congress data size references is starting to <a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2011/07/transferring-libraries-of-congress-of-data/">feel a bit antiquated at this point</a>?). Unlike some older cables, Dunant uses 12 fiber pairs, coupled with a number of <a href="https://www.submarinenetworks.com/en/insights/submarine-sdm-cable">technical innovations around maximizing its bandwidth</a>, to achieve these numbers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="U0L2UP4Rcq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/google-builds-its-own-subsea-cable-from-the-us-to-france/">Google builds its own subsea cable from the US to France</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google builds its own subsea cable from the US to France&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/17/google-builds-its-own-subsea-cable-from-the-us-to-france/embed/#?secret=U0L2UP4Rcq" data-secret="U0L2UP4Rcq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Google is dedicated to meeting the exploding demand for cloud services and online content that continues unabated,&#8221; said Mark Sokol, senior director of Infrastructure, Google Cloud. &#8220;With record-breaking capacity and transmission speeds, Dunant will help users access content wherever they may be and supplement one of the busiest routes on the internet to support the growth of Google Cloud. Dunant is a remarkable achievement that would not have been possible without the dedication of both SubCom and Google’s employees, partners, and suppliers, who overcame multiple challenges this year to make this system a reality.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107858" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107858" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2107858" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png" alt="" width="1000" height="502" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=768,386 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=680,341 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/gcp_subsea_cable.max-1000x1000-1.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2107858" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>With Dunant now being operational, the next Google cable to go live will be the Grace Hopper cable between New York and Europe, with landing sites in Bilbao, Spain and Bude, UK. Google first announced this new cable, which it is also building in partnership with SubCom, last July. It&#8217;s expected to go online in 2022 and will feature a total of 16 fiber pairs.</p>
<p>In addition, Google is also building the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/infrastructure/introducing-equiano-a-subsea-cable-from-portugal-to-south-africa">Equiano cable</a> from South Africa to Portugal. This cable is supposed to go online later this year.</p>
<p>In addition to its privately owned cables, Google is also a partner in a <a href="https://www.submarinenetworks.com/en/insights/complete-list-of-google-s-subsea-cable-investments">number of consortiums</a> that band together to build cable systems.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2107878" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2107878" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2107878 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png" alt="" width="1024" height="330" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png 1438w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=150,48 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=300,97 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=768,248 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=680,219 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/edgepoint.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2107878" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/03/googles-new-subsea-cable-between-the-u-s-and-europe-is-now-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2107855</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
