<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 19:46:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Could meme stocks like GameStop kill bitcoin&#8217;s rise?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/could-meme-stocks-like-gamestop-kill-bitcoins-rise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/could-meme-stocks-like-gamestop-kill-bitcoins-rise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 19:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TD Ameritrade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies, more so than most other things, are only valuable because of a shared agreement that they are valuable. Their value is a product of digital handshakes over millions of transactions firming up that consensus. For bitcoin, the trust that it has worth has turned more valuable in the past several months; it&#8217;s been on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Cryptocurrencies, more so than most other things, are only valuable because of a shared agreement that they are valuable. Their value is a product of digital handshakes over millions of transactions firming up that consensus. For bitcoin, the trust that it has worth has turned more valuable in the past several months; it&#8217;s been on a tear.</p>
<p>The (very bizarre) question is whether a new avenue of applying blind trust by brigading trashcan-level stocks and turning them into memes could threaten the appeal of cryptocurrencies for retail investors.</p>
<p>Over the past several days, we&#8217;ve seen stocks ranging from GameStop, Blockbuster and AMC make unjustifiable gains as a result of Reddit users in the r/WallStreetBets subreddit triggering a stampede towards stocks being heavily shorted by institutional investors. That in turn has led to a short squeeze troubling hedge funds, causing the price of a stock worth around $5 for the majority of 2020 to swell well above $300 today. In some ways it&#8217;s just an Occupy Wall Street protest being held on Robinhood, in other ways it&#8217;s a complete rejection of efficient markets and a reinvention of institutional trust.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I think it&#39;s time we finally classify GameStop stock as a Cryptocurrency <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24GME&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$GME</a> <a href="https://t.co/IpiYXlmuZW">pic.twitter.com/IpiYXlmuZW</a></p>
<p>&mdash; S.F (@SSSulaa) <a href="https://twitter.com/SSSulaa/status/1353766819526553600?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 25, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Bitcoin holds fundamental differences from publicly traded stocks, many of which might matter an awful lot to those betting on the coin as a currency of the future. But to retail investors who aren&#8217;t hardcore proponents, I&#8217;d imagine FOMO was one of the most intriguing pulls into the cryptocurrency space. But if Bitcoin&#8217;s purpose for the time being is merely a &#8220;store of value,&#8221; I think there&#8217;s a world where individual investors might be evolving their interests elsewhere.</span></p>
<p>Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies haven&#8217;t seen notable price movement in recent days  &#8212; Bitcoin is down around 6% in the past 24 hours, a hiccup as far as crypto moves go &#8212; but after a few weeks hovering well above $30k and peeking above $40k, the currency seems poised to dip below the $30k range soon unless its trend reverses course.</p>
<p>All that said, Bitcoin is certainly an entity of a different scale than all of these meme stocks bundled together with a market cap above $560 billion and a 24-hour trading volume of $56 billion. Bitcoin has seen stratospheric growth over the past few months so barring an outsized crash, it&#8217;s perhaps unlikely that retail investors are going to fully abandon it in favor of buying up crusty old shares of Blockbuster stock. That said&#8230;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s cheaper to trade these meme stocks and easier for retail investors to get leverage via options. In short, for investors looking to have a good time or shoot the moon, meme stock are a more fun place to be than crypto is.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">If you don&#39;t like suits, buy <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24GME&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$GME</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24AMC&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$AMC</a>. If you don&#39;t like the bankers, buy <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Cameron Winklevoss (@cameron) <a href="https://twitter.com/cameron/status/1354438507704578052?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The main thing to consider is what happens if GameStop, for no reason at all, becomes a long-term store of value? When investors collectively begin placing blind trust in more financial assets for the long-haul, does that devalue blind trust itself and the mammoth entities that had more of a monopoly on it? Most investors aren&#8217;t expecting this to happen, but stocks like Tesla are beginning to live comfortably at ridiculous premiums that analysts can&#8217;t understand. Tesla and GameStop are very different beasts, but if anything I think institutions have a better grasp of GameStop&#8217;s rise.</p>
<p>The foil to all of this is whether this pandemonium births some regulatory backlash, a possibility which of course does not exist in quite the same way for cryptocurrencies from a central governance standpoint. TD Ameritrade and Schwab are already limiting trades of some of these meme stocks tday and I think there is certainly a universe in which the SEC aims to take a pot shot at this saga by means of promoting market sanity and I am much more confident that there&#8217;s a world where Reddit is pushed to at least temporarily ban r/WallStreetBets for some unclear reason.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Biden team is &quot;monitoring the situation&quot; around GameStop.</p>
<p>&mdash; Jennifer Epstein (@jeneps) <a href="https://twitter.com/jeneps/status/1354495049397055494?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/could-meme-stocks-like-gamestop-kill-bitcoins-rise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101328</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robert Downey Jr. is launching a new &#8216;rolling&#8217; venture fund to back sustainability startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/robert-downey-jr-is-launching-a-new-rolling-venture-fund-to-back-sustainability-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/robert-downey-jr-is-launching-a-new-rolling-venture-fund-to-back-sustainability-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 19:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angellist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud Paper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[davos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nokia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sundance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Economic Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ynsect]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A little less than two years ago, when the actor, producer, and investor Robert Downey Jr. unveiled his new, sustainability focused initiative called the FootPrint Coalition at Amazon&#8217;s re:MARS conference it was little more than a static website and a subscription prompt. Jump cut to today, and the firm now has five portfolio companies, a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A little less than two years ago, when the actor, producer, and investor Robert Downey Jr. <a href="https://variety.com/2019/digital/news/robert-downey-jr-footprint-coalition-1203233371/">unveiled his new, sustainability focused initiative</a> called the <a href="https://www.footprintcoalition.com/">FootPrint Coalition</a> at Amazon&#8217;s <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/innovation/live-from-las-vegas-its-re-mars-2019">re:MARS conference</a> it was little more than a static website and a subscription prompt.</p>
<p>Jump cut to today, and the firm now has five portfolio companies, a non-profit initiative, and is launching a rolling venture fund, Footprint Coalition Ventures, at the World Economic Forum&#8217;s Digital Davos event.</p>
<p>With the new rolling fund, managed through AngelList, Downey Jr.&#8217;s initiative sits the intersection of two of the biggest ideas reshaping the world economy &#8212; the democratization of access to capital and investment vehicles and the<a href="https://www.fm-magazine.com/news/2020/jul/sustainable-business-opportunities-world-economic-forum.html"> $10 trillion opportunity to decarbonize global industry</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s another arrow in the quiver for an institution that aims to combine storytelling, investing, and non-profit commitments to combat the world&#8217;s climate crisis.</p>
<p><strong>Rolling funds and the revolution in finance</strong></p>
<p>There&#8217;s a revolution happening in finance right now, whether it&#8217;s the rise of the Redittors trying to avenge the malfeasance of short-sellers and big institutional investors that&#8217;s happening through investments in stocks like Blockbuster, Nokia, Gamestop and AMC, or the new crowdfunding sources and rolling funds that are allowing regular investors to finance early stage companies, things on Wall Street are definitely changing.</p>
<p>And while the public market gambles are undoubtably minting some new millionaires, opening up access to interesting startup investments is a thesis that&#8217;s a stark contrast to the cynicism of day-trading gambles.</p>
<p>Both could leave investors with less than zero in some cases, but with rolling funds or crowdfunding, there&#8217;s a real opportunity to build something rather than just sticking it to the man.</p>
<p>Unlike traditional venture funds, rolling funds raise new capital commitments on a quarterly basis and invest as they go, hence the “rolling”. Investors come on for a minimum one-year commitment, and invest at a quarterly cadence. In Downey Jr.&#8217;s fund that commitment amounts to $5,000 per quarter for up to 2,000 qualified investors (and a smaller number of accredited ones), according to a person with knowledge of the firm&#8217;s plans.</p>
<p>&#8220;The idea of opening [the fund] to real people, rather than the ivory tower of the institutional bigwigs&#8230; It&#8217;s a little bit more slamdance than Sundance [and] I kind of dig it,&#8221; said Downey Jr.</p>
<p><strong>A guide to recognizing FootPrint Coalition Ventures</strong></p>
<p>FootPrint Coalition Ventures will be split between early and late stage investment funds and will be looking to make six investments per year in early stage companies and four later stage deals.</p>
<p>Helping Downey Jr. manage the operations are investors like Jonathan Schulthof, who previously founded LOOM Media, which leverages smart urban infrastructure for advertising, founded Motivate International, which manages bike sharing services in cities across the U.S., and served as a managing partner for Global Technology Investments. Schulthof is joined by Steve Levin, who <span style="font-weight: 400;">co-founded Team Downey, Downey Jr.&#8217;s media production company and Downey Ventures, which invests in media and technology companies. </span></p>
<p>The firm already has four companies in its portfolio through investments it made using the founders&#8217; own capital. And while those investments were all under $1 million, the firm expects that the size of its commitments will grow as it raises additional cash. Footprint Coalition has also maintained pro-rata investment rights so that it can increase the size of its stake in businesses over time. And the investments it made to date were sized in anticipation of potential for follow-ons at much higher valuations.</p>
<p><strong>A venture fund inside of a coalition</strong></p>
<p>The initiative that Downey Jr. hopes to build is more than just an investment arm. Both he and his co-founders see the investment side as a single piece of a broader platform that leverages the massive social following Downey Jr. has created and the storytelling skills he and his team have mastered through decades spent working in the movie business.</p>
<p>That broader team includes Rachel Kropa, the former head of the CAA Foundation, who will lead scientific and philanthropic efforts and serve as the fund&#8217;s Impact Advisor and liaison to the scientific and research communities, according to a statement.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rachel Kropa, former head of the CAA Foundation who joined Footprint Coalition to lead scientific and philanthropic efforts last year, will serve as the fund’s Impact Advisor and liaison to the scientific and research communities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The idea that the content that we made can be related back to the individual is very powerful,&#8221; said Kropa. &#8220;This problem is so intractable and interconnected across the world. It does matter that the fish that you eat are made using a sustainable feed.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>Kropa is referring to a piece that the FootPrint Coalition put out around sustainable aquaculture tied to the group&#8217;s recent investment in Ÿnsect, a company that makes protein from crickets for use in animal feed and human food.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our content around <a href="https://www.footprintcoalition.com/cellularagriculture" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.footprintcoalition.com/cellularagriculture&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1611857334942000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG1dBddu-UgdorrytrUvux5JcnxZw">Cellular Agriculture,</a> exemplifies the type of content we can create in the course of taking a deep dive into a particular industry. Though we have not (yet) invested in the space, we do believe there are interesting stories to tell,&#8221; said one person who works with the company.</p>
<p>That media is additive to activate the group&#8217;s audience, and is not something that it charges for &#8212; or considers part of its investment valuation. &#8220;We’ve been creating edited video segments with Robert doing voice over and overlaying animation all of which we’ve been posting to social. We do this for free to the companies, and we don’t charge / strong-arm / cajole for warrants, advisor shares, or the like in return,&#8221; the person said.</p>
<p><strong>Weird science and sustainability</strong></p>
<p>While Ÿnsect is one example of a company that the FootPrint Coalition has backed that&#8217;s doing something which may be a little outside of the purview of most of Downey Jr.&#8217;s following, other businesses like the bamboo toilet paper company, Cloud Paper, and the new investment in the sustainability focused financial services company, Aspiration, have definite direct consumer ties.</p>
<p>That balance is something that Schulthof said the firm was looking for as it pursues not just environmental and sustainability returns, but, more concretely, profit.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We look at things that are meaningful and impactful [and] I get to be purely capitalist. The question is this a good opportunity is something that has to do with its margins, its scale, its risk profile, the people involved and fundamentally what are the terms… do we think the company will deliver value to investors,&#8221; said Schulthof. &#8220;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re looking for returns.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The opportunity for returns is enormous. <span style="font-weight: 400;">As the group noted, the ESG sector &#8211; funds that focus on the Environmental, Social and Governance issues &#8211; continues to grow rapidly Part of the broader stakeholder capitalism movement, impact investing funds have topped $250 billion, and sustainability assets have doubled in value over the past three years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We see two powerful trends working together to support the environment. First, engaging content and media distribution enable us to create a passionate community from Robert’s 100 million followers and to use that audience to access great investments. Second, a turnkey technology platform now enables us to manage a broad set of individual investors,&#8221; said Schulthof in a statement. &#8220;Venture funds traditionally have high minimums that exclude only the wealthiest individuals, or endowments and foundations. With much lower minimums and shorter investment periods, we can now offer access to these same companies to a much broader group. When these investors further ignite our passionate audience, we hope to set a positive feedback loop in motion with environmental technologies as the ultimate beneficiary.”</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/robert-downey-jr-is-launching-a-new-rolling-venture-fund-to-back-sustainability-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101204</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spin bets its scooter future on 3 wheels and remote-control tech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/spin-bets-its-scooter-future-on-3-wheels-and-remote-control-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/spin-bets-its-scooter-future-on-3-wheels-and-remote-control-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 18:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Segway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tortoise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spin, the micromobility startup acquired by Ford, has developed a new scooter with partners Segway-Ninebot and software startup Tortoise that aims to solve the sidewalk clutter problem for good. The Spin S-200 scooter not only has three wheels — a design change that helps it stand out in a crowded pool of two-wheelers — it&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Spin, the micromobility startup acquired by Ford, has developed a new scooter with partners Segway-Ninebot and software startup Tortoise that aims to solve the sidewalk clutter problem for good.</p>
<p class="p1">The Spin S-200 scooter not only has three wheels — a design change that helps it stand out in a crowded pool of two-wheelers — it&#8217;s also equipped with repositioning software that allows remote operators thousands of miles away to move vehicles off the sidewalk and into a proper parking spot. A fleet of about 300 Spin S-200 scooters will be tested in Boise, Idaho this spring. But the goal is much grander. Spin ultimately wants to roll out remotely operated scooters to cities in North America and Europe in 2021.</p>
<p class="p1">These scooters, which operate on the so-called Spin Valet platform, are equipped with front and rear-facing cameras. When combined with Tortoise&#8217;s software, the scooters can be controlled remotely.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">The remote operations team will initially use the repositioning software to move the scooters if they&#8217;re blocking a sidewalk, crosswalk or handicapped space. Eventually, users will be able to hail a scooter, which will travel up to several blocks to their location, according to Tortoise co-founder and president Dmitry Shevelenko. <i></i></p>
<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;We&#8217;re focused on making Boise wildly successful and I think if that happens, then the numbers kind of take care of themselves,&#8221; Shevelenko said in a recent interview. &#8220;If this Spin scooter gets even 25% more rentals per day than their standard fleet, they&#8217;re going to shift their fleet as quickly as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>If that happens, the only real hurdle is getting the scooters manufactured. Shevelenko said a manufacturing bottleneck is unlikely because Segway-Ninebot has the tooling in place to make this a mass-produced product. &#8220;They have a lot of conviction around it,&#8221; he added in reference to Segway.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101335" style="width: 1010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/spin_parking.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101335" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2101335 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/spin_parking.gif" alt="spin_parking scooter" width="1000" height="563" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2101335" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Spin</p></div></p>
<p>“There has been a lot of fanfare around the potential of remote-controlled e-scooters, but this partnership marks a turning point in tangible operational plans to bring them to city streets,” Spin&#8217;s chief business officer Ben Bear said in a statement. “In addition to providing reliability to consumers and more order to city streets, this could significantly improve unit economics, reducing carbon emissions and the operational work required to maintain and reposition fleets.”</p>
<p>Shevelenko said as important as the reposition is, the design of the actual scooter deserves attention as well. The S-200 is equipped with three independent braking systems — a regenerative rear brake, front and rear drum brakes — and turn signals located on handlebars and near the rear wheel.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think in some ways the three-wheeled scooter is as big of a deal,&#8221; Shevelenko said. &#8220;It&#8217;s necessary because it solves the balancing issue without a kickstand, but it&#8217;s also appealing to riders who aren&#8217;t dudes in their 20s. It&#8217;s higher up, you feel sturdier and it&#8217;s really hard to tip over and fall. And so, in terms of making sure people in their 40s and 50s and 60s feel comfortable getting on, I think this going to be very disruptive.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iCszUv8nar"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/remote-controlled-delivery-carts-are-now-working-for-the-local-los-angeles-grocer/">Remote-controlled delivery carts are now working for the local Los Angeles grocer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Remote-controlled delivery carts are now working for the local Los Angeles grocer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/25/remote-controlled-delivery-carts-are-now-working-for-the-local-los-angeles-grocer/embed/#?secret=iCszUv8nar" data-secret="iCszUv8nar" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/spin-bets-its-scooter-future-on-3-wheels-and-remote-control-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Sophie: How can I sponsor my mom and stepdad for green cards?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/dear-sophie-how-can-i-sponsor-my-mom-and-stepdad-for-green-cards/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/dear-sophie-how-can-i-sponsor-my-mom-and-stepdad-for-green-cards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 18:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dear Sophie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100941</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My biological dad passed away several years ago when I was an adult and my mom has since remarried. Can they get green cards?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sophie Alcorn</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a> is the founder of <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/">Alcorn Immigration Law</a> in Silicon Valley and 2019 Global Law Experts Awards’ “Law Firm of the Year in California for Entrepreneur Immigration Services.” She connects people with the businesses and opportunities that expand their lives.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/dear-sophie-what-are-bidens-immigration-changes/">Dear Sophie: What are Biden’s immigration changes?</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/dear-sophie-whats-up-with-h-1b-pay-to-play/">Dear Sophie: What’s the new minimum salary required for H-1B visa applicants?</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Here&#8217;s another edition of “Dear Sophie,” the advice column that answers immigration-related questions about working at technology companies.</p>
<p>“Your questions are vital to the spread of knowledge that allows people all over the world to rise above borders and pursue their dreams,” says <a href="https://crunchbase.com/person/sophie-alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a Silicon Valley immigration attorney. “Whether you’re in people ops, a founder or seeking a job in Silicon Valley, I would love to <a href="https://forms.gle/86Z8oYo32G9amDss8">answer your questions</a> in my next column.”</p>
<p>Extra Crunch members receive access to weekly “Dear Sophie” columns; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">use promo code ALCORN to purchase a one- or two-year subscription for 50% off</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Dear Sophie: </strong></p>
<p><strong>I just got my U.S. citizenship! My husband and I want to bring my mom and her husband to the U.S. to help us take care of our preschooler and toddler.</strong></p>
<p><strong>My biological dad passed away several years ago when I was an adult and my mom has since remarried. Can they get green cards?</strong></p>
<p><strong>— Appreciative in Aptos</strong></p>
<p>Dear Appreciative:</p>
<p>Congrats on becoming a citizen! That is a long road, and you did it. :) For all those out there awaiting citizenship, good news: It’s a priority for the Biden administration to speed up processing times. Other good news — the Muslim Ban is cancelled! And USCIS is going to make things a lot better for Dreamers seeking DACA.</p>
<p>We can definitely figure out a plan to support your mom and stepdad to get green cards in the U.S. As your mom married your stepdad after you turned 18, you can’t sponsor him directly. You need to sponsor your mom for a green card first, and then she can sponsor him as her husband. My law partner, Anita Koumriqian, who is an expert in family-based immigration, and I discussed getting green cards for parents and siblings in a recent <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/podcast/054bringing-your-parents-and-siblings-after-covid-19/">podcast</a>. Check it out for more details. To set clear expectations, this is a multistep process that will probably take a few years. So you may want to consider hiring a nanny if you need childcare sooner than that! ;)</p>
<p>Alternatively, to speed things up for your stepdad, if he has a daughter, son or sibling who is a U.S. citizen, any of them can sponsor him for a green card. If your mom ends up sponsoring him once she’s a permanent resident, that’s quicker than a U.S. citizen sibling sponsoring a brother, for example, but generally is not as quick as a U.S. citizen child sponsoring a parent.</p>
<p>Since your mom is abroad, she won’t be able to come to the U.S. until the U.S. embassy or consulate in her home country reopens and resumes processing routine visa and green card applications. However, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) is currently open.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="Immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn" width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a><a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>It’s possible to get started sponsoring your mom for a <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/green-cards-parents/">green card</a> now, and you can work with an attorney to streamline the process. You need to be at least 21 years of age and be a U.S. citizen. As her sponsor, you will also need to accept legal responsibility for financially supporting her.</p>
<p>You will need to initially submit to USCIS documents such as your birth certificate and proof of U.S. citizenship, and make sure that all foreign language documents have certified English translations. Currently, the USCIS California Service Center is taking about seven months to process green card applications for parents.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/dear-sophie-how-can-i-sponsor-my-mom-and-stepdad-for-green-cards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100941</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Battling algorithmic bias at TC Sessions: Justice</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/battling-algorithmic-bias-at-tc-sessions-justice/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/battling-algorithmic-bias-at-tc-sessions-justice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Megan Rose Dickey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 17:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[algorithmic bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At TC Sessions: Justice on March 3, we&#8217;re going to dive head-first into data discrimination, algorithmic bias and how to ensure a more just future, as technology companies rely more on automated processes to make decisions. Algorithms are sets of rules that computers follow in order to solve problems and make decisions about a particular [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">At <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=justice2021&amp;utm_content=algorithmbias&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=algorithmbiaspost&amp;display=TRUE">TC Sessions: Justice</a> on March 3, we&#8217;re going to dive head-first into data discrimination, algorithmic bias and how to ensure a more just future, as technology companies rely more on automated processes to make decisions.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">Algorithms are sets of rules that computers follow in order to solve problems and make decisions about a particular course of action. But there is an inherent problem with algorithms that begins at the most base level and persists throughout its adaption: human bias that is baked into these machine-based decision-makers.</p>
<p>Algorithms driven by bad data are what leads to biased arrests and imprisonment of Black people. They’re also the same kind of algorithms that Google used to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/jan/12/google-racism-ban-gorilla-black-people">label photos of Black people as gorillas</a> and that <a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/kb7zdw/microsoft-suspends-ai-chatbot-after-it-veers-into-white-supremacy-tay-and-you">Microsoft’s Tay bot used to become a white supremacist</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=justice2021&amp;utm_content=algorithmbias&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=algorithmbiaspost&amp;display=TRUE">TC Sessions: Justice</a>, we&#8217;ll hear from three experts in this field. Let&#8217;s meet them.</p>
<p><strong>Dr. Safiya Umoja Noble</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100127" style="width: 554px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100127" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100127" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?w=544" alt="" width="544" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?resize=768,960 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?resize=544,680 544w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?resize=1229,1536 1229w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?resize=1638,2048 1638w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled-1.jpg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 544px) 100vw, 544px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100127" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://safiyaunoble.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/SafiyaUmojaNoble_Credit_Stella_Kallnina-1-scaled.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stella Kallnina <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Associate Professor at University of California Los Angeles a professor at the University of Southern California and author of “Algorithms of Oppression: How Search Engines Reinforce Racism,&#8221; Noble has become known for her analyses around the intersection of race and technology.</p>
<p>In her aforementioned book, Noble discusses the ways in which algorithms are biased and perpetuate racism. She calls this data discrimination.</p>
<p>“I think that the ways in which people get coded or encoded particularly in search engines can have an incredible amount of harm,” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/27/ctrlt-podcast-artificial-intelligence-may-become-a-human-rights-issue/">Noble told me back in 2018 on an episode of TC Mixtape, formerly known as CTRL+T</a>. “And this is part of what I mean when I say data discrimination.”</p>
<p><strong>Mutale Nkonde</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100148" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100148" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2100148" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/76719636.jpeg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100148" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Via Mutale Nkonde</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to explicitly call out race in order to create just technological futures, according to Nkonde. In her research paper, &#8220;<a href="https://cyber.harvard.edu/story/2020-05/automated-anti-blackness">Automated Anti-Blackness: Facial Recognition in Brooklyn, New York</a>,&#8221; Nkonde examines the use of facial recognition, the history of the surveillance of Black people in New York and presents potential ways to regulate facial recognition in the future.</p>
<p>Nkonde is also a United Nations adviser on race and artificial intelligence and is currently working with Amnesty International to advance a global ban on facial recognition technology.</p>
<p><strong>Haben Girma</strong></p>
<p><div id="attachment_1912589" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1912589" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1912589" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg?w=680" alt="Woman walking with guide dog." width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mylo-Haben-Walking-e1573846286198.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1912589" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Courtesy of Haben Girma</p></div></p>
<p>Author of memoir &#8220;Haben: The Deafblind Woman Who Conquered Harvard Law,&#8221; and human rights lawyer, Girma focuses on advancing disability justice.</p>
<p>At <a href="https://sighttechglobal.com/session/disability-rights-and-inventing-the-accessible-future/">Sight Tech Global</a> last month, Girma spoke about how discussions around algorithmic bias as it pertains to race have become somewhat normalized, but too often do those conversations exclude the effects of algorithms on disabled people. Girma told me at that when it comes to robots, for example, the topic of algorithmic bias is lacking among developers and designers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don’t blame the robots,&#8221; she said. &#8220;It’s the people who build the robots who are inserting their biases that are causing ableism and racism to continue in our society. If designers built robots in collaboration with disabled people who use our sidewalks and blind people who would Use these delivery apps, then the robots and the delivery apps would be fully accessible. So we need the people designing the services to have these conversations and work with us.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve made it this far in the post, you&#8217;re probably wondering how to attend. Well, you can <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-justice-2021/?utm_medium=editpost&amp;utm_campaign=justice2021&amp;utm_content=algorithmbias&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=algorithmbiaspost&amp;display=TRUE">snag your ticket right here</a> for just $5.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			width="99%"
			height="500"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-97fcb02edc714d7c4ba26638f20b3954'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/battling-algorithmic-bias-at-tc-sessions-justice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100088</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stilt, a financial services provider for immigrants, raises $100 million debt facility from Silicon Valley Bank</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/stilt-a-financial-services-provider-for-immigrants-raises-100-million-debt-facility-from-silicon-valley-bank/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/stilt-a-financial-services-provider-for-immigrants-raises-100-million-debt-facility-from-silicon-valley-bank/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 17:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immigrants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stilt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2099884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stilt, a provider of financial services for immigrants in the United States, announced today it has raised a $100 million warehouse facility from Silicon Valley Bank for lending to its customers. This brings Stilt’s total debt facilities so far to $225 million, and will enable it to reach more than $350 million in annualized loan [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2100503" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100503" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2100503 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg" alt="Stilt founders Priyank Singh and Rohit Mittal" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/founder_photos_1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2100503" class="wp-caption-text">Stilt founders Priyank Singh and Rohit Mittal</p></div></p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://www.stilt.com/">Stilt</a>, a provider of financial services for immigrants in the United States, announced today it has raised a $100 million warehouse facility from Silicon Valley Bank for lending to its customers. This brings Stilt’s total debt facilities so far to $225 million, and will enable it to reach more than $350 million in annualized loan volume. The company also announced the public launch of its no-fee checking accounts, which have been in private beta since September.</p>
<p class="p1">A Y Combinator alum, Stilt was founded five years ago by Rohit Mittal and Priyank Singh. Both dealt with the challenges of accessing financial services as immigrants and wanted to created a company to serve other people without Social Security numbers or credit histories.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">For applicants without traditional credit reports, Stilt’s loan application process considers their personal information, including bank transactions, education, employment and visa status, and also uses proprietary machine-learning algorithms that draws on demographic data from a wide range of financial and non-financial sources.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eRiamscyoA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/stilt-which-provides-financial-services-for-immigrants-raises-7-5-million-seed-round/">Stilt, which provides financial services for immigrants, raises $7.5 million seed round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Stilt, which provides financial services for immigrants, raises $7.5 million seed round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/stilt-which-provides-financial-services-for-immigrants-raises-7-5-million-seed-round/embed/#?secret=eRiamscyoA" data-secret="eRiamscyoA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p1">TechCrunch last covered Stilt when it announced a $7.5 million seed round in May 2020.  During the pandemic, demand for loans increased for a wide range of reasons. Some customers sought new loans because their working hours got cut. Other borrowers’ own jobs weren’t impacted, but they needed to transfer money to family members in other countries who had lost income. Several used loans to pay for additional visa processing and many customers turned to Stilt because other financial providers shut down or reduced their loan programs over concerns about repayment.</p>
<p>Despite the economic challenges caused by the COVID-19 pandemic, Stilt’s loan performance has remained steady. Many of Stilt&#8217;s customers are using their loans to build a credit history in the United States and even borrowers who lost income because of the pandemic continued making payments on time (Stilt also created temporary programs, including waiving interest for a few months, to help those who were struggling financially).</p>
<p>Mittal said immigrants are also in general more creditworthy, because many moved to the United States to pursue educational or career opportunities. The difficulty of securing visas means &#8220;all immigrants move to the U.S. after jumping through a lot of hoops,&#8221; said Mittal. He added that &#8220;it isn’t just people coming from other countries. We also see it in DACA applicants. They tend to be the best risk-adjusted return customers. These are people who are going to school, they are working, they have seen their families work, they are helping their parents, they are doing all these things, and they understand the value of money, so they end up being a lot more financially responsible.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2100504" style="width: 393px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100504" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2100504" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?w=383" alt="Stilt's money transfer feature" width="383" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png 2560w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?resize=768,1364 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?resize=383,680 383w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?resize=865,1536 865w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?resize=1153,2048 1153w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/app-remittance-iphone.png?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 383px) 100vw, 383px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2100504" class="wp-caption-text">Stilt&#8217;s money transfer feature</p></div></p>
<p class="p1">Stilt’s new checking accounts, powered by Evolve Bank and Trust, are also designed for immigrants, with features like spot-rate remittance to about 50 countries. Users can also apply for credit lines and pre-approved loans through their accounts. Since opening to existing customers in September, the number of active checking accounts is growing 50% month over month, with many using it for direct deposits of their salaries.</p>
<p class="p1">The new debt facility from Silicon Valley Bank means Stilt will be able to provide larger loan volumes and better interest rates, said Mittal. Stilt’s average interest rate is about 12% to 14%, compared to the 30% to 100% charged by other programs, like payday loans, that people without Social Security numbers or credit reports often use.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QGn8rDPEcV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/against-all-odds-the-sheer-force-of-immigrant-startup-founders/">Against all odds: The sheer force of immigrant startup founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Against all odds: The sheer force of immigrant startup founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/against-all-odds-the-sheer-force-of-immigrant-startup-founders/embed/#?secret=QGn8rDPEcV" data-secret="QGn8rDPEcV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/stilt-a-financial-services-provider-for-immigrants-raises-100-million-debt-facility-from-silicon-valley-bank/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2099884</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Check out the amazing speakers joining us on Extra Crunch Live in February</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-february/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-february/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, we hit you with 44(!) episodes of Extra Crunch Live, a series that gives startups and founders direct insights from the experts who know best. We&#8217;re making Extra Crunch Live even better in 2021: we&#8217;ll take a look at funding deals through the eyes of the founders and investors who made them happen, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year, we hit you with 44(!) episodes of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">Extra Crunch Live</a>, a series that gives startups and founders direct insights from the experts who know best. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/06/extra-crunch-live-is-back-in-2021-connecting-founders-with-tech-giants-and-each-other/">We&#8217;re making Extra Crunch Live even better in 2021</a>: we&#8217;ll take a look at funding deals through the eyes of the founders and investors who made them happen, and those same tech leaders will go through your pitch decks and give feedback and advice. Every single Wednesday at 12 p.m. PST/3 p.m. EST!</p>
<p>Today, I&#8217;m thrilled to announce the February slate for Extra Crunch Live.</p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Gaurav Gupta (Lightspeed Venture Partners) + Raj Dutt (Grafana Labs)</h3>
<p><em><strong>February 3, 12 p.m. PST/3 p.m. EST</strong></em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Grafana Labs, the open-source platform for monitoring, visualization and metric analytics, has raised more than $75 million since its 2014 inception. Lightspeed&#8217;s Raj Dutt has partnered with the company throughout its journey, leading Grafana&#8217;s Series A and B. Hear from Gupta and Grafana co-founder Raj Dutt about how that Series A deal came together and take a look at the startup&#8217;s original Series A pitch deck on the next episode of Extra Crunch Live. And don&#8217;t forget! Gupta and Dutt will be giving live feedback to Extra Crunch members who have submitted their own pitch decks.</p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Aydin Senkut (Felicis Ventures) + Kevin Busque (Guideline)</h3>
<p><em><strong>February 10, 12 p.m. PST/3 p.m. EST</strong></em></p>
<p>In 2014, Guideline stepped into the ring with giants, launching an all-inclusive 401k platform for fast-growing businesses. Since, it&#8217;s raised nearly $140 million in funding, including a $15 million Series B round led by Felicis Ventures. Hear the behind-the-scenes story of how Guideline CEO Kevin Busque and Felicis partner Aydin Senkut came together for that deal, with a walk through the pitch deck that started it all, and get the founder/investor duo&#8217;s live feedback on your own pitch deck.</p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Steve Loughlin (Accel) + Jason Boehmig (Ironclad)</h3>
<p><em><strong>February 17, 12 p.m. PST/3 p.m. EST</strong></em></p>
<p>Steve Loughlin views the tech world through a prismatic lens. He&#8217;s been a founder, he&#8217;s been through an acquisition, and now he invests as a partner at Accel. One such investment includes Ironclad, a contract management platform that recently raised a $100 million Series D and is valued at nearly $1 billion. Hear CEO Jason Boehmig and Loughlin talk through their original Series A deal and get live feedback on your own pitch deck from the founder/investor duo.</p>
<hr />
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Matt Harris (Bain Capital) + Isaac Oates (Justworks)</h3>
<p><em><strong>February 24, 12 p.m. PST/3 p.m. EST</strong></em></p>
<p>Justworks&#8217; back-office software has garnered the attention of many investors. The company has raised $143 million from firms including FirstMark Capital, Union Square Ventures, Thrive, Redpoint and Bain Capital. Hear from Justworks founder and CEO Isaac Oates and Bain Capital Partner Matt Harris as they describe how their partnership began and get their live feedback on your own pitch deck.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is for EC members only. If you&#8217;re not already signed up, get on it right here. Registration info for each of these episodes is below. See you soon!</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/check-out-the-amazing-speakers-joining-us-on-extra-crunch-live-in-february/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100624</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How 2 startups scaled to $50M ARR and beyond</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/how-2-startups-scaled-to-50m-arr-and-beyond/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/how-2-startups-scaled-to-50m-arr-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 16:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assembly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OwnBackup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we're discussing OwnBackup and Assembly, two middle-late startups that are entering unicorn territory.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The current list of venture-backed private companies we expect to go public — and the number of companies that might say yes to a SPAC-led debut — underscore just how many large startups there are in the market.</p>
<p>After years of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/20/fintech-startups-and-unicorns-had-a-stellar-q4-2020/">rising venture capital investment</a> and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/fintech-vc-keeps-getting-later-larger-and-more-expensive/">wave of huge rounds</a>, many startups and unicorns could leave the private markets this year or the next.</p>
<p>Last year, The Exchange wrote about former startups that had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/three-new-100m-arr-club-members-and-a-call-for-the-next-generation-of-growth-stage-startups/">scaled to around the $100 million annual recurring revenue</a> (ARR) mark, or had revenues that were roughly equivalent if they didn&#8217;t sell software. But that wound up being a bit less interesting than we&#8217;d hoped, as companies that have reached that scale tend to be fully baked by the time we got them on the phone.</p>
<p>So, we&#8217;re shooting for the $50 million ARR range this year. Our goal is to see what we can ferret out from companies that are moving from the middle-late startup years and into the unicorn realm.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a>, or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>What broke during the last year? Which teams have they doubled down on? How has hiring gone? We have questions. And, happily, companies have raised their hand. Today, we&#8217;re talking about <a href="https://www.ownbackup.com/">OwnBackup</a> and <a href="https://www.withassembly.com/">Assembly</a>. Next week, it&#8217;s <a href="https://www.simplenexus.com/">SimpleNexus</a> and <a href="https://www.kaseya.com/">Kaseya</a>. And we have <a href="https://picsart.com/">Picsart</a> on deck as a company somewhat in between our two target revenue bands.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995214 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>But before we start, a final note. The following bits of journalism are more exploratory than hard-hitting. But as private companies tend to share nothing other than the occasional press release strained of personality and flavor, I&#8217;m working to bring more raw data points and observations to you even if they do not constitute the grittiest reporting you&#8217;ve ever read.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get into our first two $50 million (or around there) ARR companies.</p>
<h2>OwnBackup</h2>
<p>OwnBackup is a company you might have heard of as it raised a $50 million round last July, an event <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/07/ownbackup-lands-additional-50m-as-backup-for-salesforce-ecosystem-thrives/">TechCrunch covered</a>. The company reached out regarding our $50 million ARR series by noting that its growth had accelerated since that round, so we decided to find out more.</p>
<p>The Exchange spoke with CEO Sam Gutmann and CMO Jamie Grenney about OwnBackup&#8217;s recent growth.</p>
<p>According to the execs, OwnBackup is around $50 million ARR today. The company, as its name hints, provides cloud backup services to other companies. And it&#8217;s built atop the Salesforce platform, a service that had a good 2020 when nCino, another company that leverages the service, went public to great effect. (That debut led to TechCrunch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/16/ncino-marks-second-successful-ipo-of-company-built-on-salesforce-platform/">reporting on the trend</a> of building atop someone else&#8217;s software to IPO scale.)</p>
<p>And OwnBackup has lots of room to grow inside of its current platform home. It thinks it has around 2% penetration of the Salesforce ecosystem, meaning that its current 100% yearly growth pace can continue for quite some time without a material change in strategy.</p>
<p>Asked if OwnBackup was worried about platform risk, Gutmann and Grenney said they weren&#8217;t. Not only is Salesforce Ventures an investor, the execs noted, but the Salesforce platform is a huge SaaS ecosystem; it&#8217;s not something that could be switched off like a Google web product and consigned to the ash heap of the internet.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/how-2-startups-scaled-to-50m-arr-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100821</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Charlie launches a mobile app that &#8216;gamifies&#8217; getting out of debt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/charlie-launches-a-mobile-app-that-gamifies-getting-out-of-debt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/charlie-launches-a-mobile-app-that-gamifies-getting-out-of-debt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charlie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Charlie, a personal finance app that began as a chatbot, is relaunching today with a revamped experience focused on the larger goal of helping everyday Americans get out of debt. To do so, Charlie presents users with a full picture of their current debt and how long it will take them to pay it off. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.hicharlie.com/">Charlie</a>, a personal finance app that began as a chatbot, is relaunching today with a revamped experience focused on the larger goal of helping everyday Americans get out of debt. To do so, Charlie presents users with a full picture of their current debt and how long it will take them to pay it off. Users then connect their bank account to Charlie for personalized assistance in reducing their bills. It also &#8220;gamifies&#8221; saving money to make the process of setting money aside for paying down debt more fun.</p>
<p>According to Charlie CEO Ilian Georgiev, the idea to turn saving into more of game arose from his prior experience in the mobile gaming industry. At a company called Pocket Gems, he helped scale apps that generated millions of dollars in revenue growth from across millions of users.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101227" style="width: 369px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101227" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2101227" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?w=680" alt="" width="359" height="359" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png 1291w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/CEO-and-co-founder-Ilian-Georgiev.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2101227" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Charlie; CEO and co-founder Ilian Georgiev</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;A really well-designed mobile game gets people to obsessively manage a virtual economy,&#8221; he explains. &#8220;And what I was curious about was how do we get people to do better in the real-world economy by using the same kind of tools?&#8221;</p>
<p>To help on that front, Charlie&#8217;s team includes people with backgrounds in not only computer science and engineering, but also in psychology. Using similar psychological tricks as found in gaming &#8212; rules, progress bars and reward mechanisms &#8212; the app helps nudge its users towards saving.</p>
<p>The original version of the Charlie app, launched in 2016, worked a little differently, however. It would analyze transaction data to look for areas where the user could improve their finances. It also worked over texting and through Facebook Messenger &#8212; platforms Charlie adopted with the idea that users needed a simpler way to connect with their finances.</p>
<p>&#8220;But the thing that we kept hearing over and over again, both qualitatively and quantitatively, is that the biggest concern that our users had is &#8216;how do I get out of debt? So then we said, instead of casting this really wide net&#8230;let&#8217;s laser focus on this one particular problem,&#8221; says Georgiev.</p>
<p>Today, the chatbot still lives on as a feature inside the new Charlie app, but it&#8217;s not the core experience.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101233" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101233" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2101233" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/2.-Debt-calc-Savings.png?w=375" alt="" width="375" height="647" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/2.-Debt-calc-Savings.png 375w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/2.-Debt-calc-Savings.png?resize=87,150 87w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/2.-Debt-calc-Savings.png?resize=174,300 174w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/2.-Debt-calc-Savings.png?resize=29,50 29w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2101233" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Charlie</p></div></p>
<p>Instead, users begin by providing the app with information about their debt. Georgiev stresses that many Americans often know their debt down to the penny &#8212; whether that&#8217;s how much they have left on student loans, how much left on their car, how much credit card debt they have, and so on.</p>
<p>The app then calculates how long it would take to pay off this debt if you only made minimum payments. This number helps shock people into action, as they&#8217;ll often discover they&#8217;re going to be in debt for another 40 or 50 years.</p>
<p>&#8220;For most users, that&#8217;s an epiphany because they&#8217;ve never seen these numbers before, and the math required &#8212; even if you do it in Excel &#8212; the math required to figure that out is beyond most people,&#8221; Georgiev says.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2101232" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Custom-rules-Customize.png?w=375" alt="" width="375" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Custom-rules-Customize.png 375w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Custom-rules-Customize.png?resize=87,150 87w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Custom-rules-Customize.png?resize=175,300 175w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Custom-rules-Customize.png?resize=29,50 29w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></p>
<p>The app then encourages users to learn how they can reduce the time it would take them to get out of debt by paying more than the minimums. By clicking a button, they can visualize the what happens if you pay, for example, $20 or $50 more per month.</p>
<p>The final step is to help users find that extra cash. In part, this may come from savings the app locates on users&#8217; behalf. But it also comes from the money-saving &#8220;game.&#8221;</p>
<p>Charlie helps users create autosave rules which, when applied, auto-transfer money from the user&#8217;s connected bank account to Charlie&#8217;s digital wallet (an account held at partner bank, Evolve). These can be fun rules or even sort of ridiculous ones. For example, you could create &#8220;Guilty Pleasures&#8221; rules where Charlie will put away 10% every time you eat McDonalds, or it could save $1 for you every time a contestant on &#8220;The Bachelor&#8221; says they&#8217;re &#8220;here for the right reasons.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101229" style="width: 289px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101229" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2101229" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Autosave-Savings-So-Far.png?w=279" alt="" width="279" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Autosave-Savings-So-Far.png 375w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Autosave-Savings-So-Far.png?resize=62,150 62w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Autosave-Savings-So-Far.png?resize=123,300 123w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Autosave-Savings-So-Far.png?resize=279,680 279w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/3.-Autosave-Savings-So-Far.png?resize=21,50 21w" sizes="(max-width: 279px) 100vw, 279px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2101229" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Charlie</p></div></p>
<p>As those rules apply, money is saved and a little progress bar fills. The app rewards you with rainbow confetti as you achieve, also similar to some mobile gaming experiences.</p>
<p>At the end of the month, the user can take that saved money to make a larger payment towards their debt. Currently, Charlie doesn&#8217;t manage the bill pay aspects itself &#8212; which is a limitation. You have to transfer the funds back to your bank. But a bill pay feature is due to arrive in a couple&#8217; months time, we&#8217;re told.</p>
<p>Later this year, Charlie plans to offer debt refinancing services to users. In this case, the team believes they can give the users lower interest rates because Charlie users will have proven, through their use of the app, that they&#8217;re lower risk.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2101235" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/7-Celebration.png?w=375" alt="" width="375" height="667" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/7-Celebration.png 375w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/7-Celebration.png?resize=84,150 84w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/7-Celebration.png?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/7-Celebration.png?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></p>
<p>Further down the road, Charlie aims to move more into neobank territory by issuing a debit card to users that works with users&#8217; Charlie account. To differentiate from the growing number of neobanks, Charlie will continue to focus on paying down debt and savings.</p>
<p>Georgiev notes that the app&#8217;s business model is not built around user data collection, however. Data that&#8217;s ingested is sanitized and encrypted, and the app has a strict privacy policy. Plus, Charlie mainly helps people save money, but those funds are actually stored with a partner bank, not in Charlie itself. And because it&#8217;s involved in the act of moving money, it has to adhere to regulations around security and fraud prevention.</p>
<p>Today, Charlie charges a $4.99 per month subscription, which the company aims to make up for by helping people reduce their larger debt loads more quickly. However, even that small amount could give money-sensitive users pause, despite Charlie&#8217;s perks and successes.</p>
<p>To date, Charlie has registered a half million users for its older chatbot experience. It hopes to now grow that figure with its new tools.</p>
<p>The app is available on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/US/app/id1488679662?mt=8">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hicharlie.chat">Android</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/charlie-launches-a-mobile-app-that-gamifies-getting-out-of-debt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101213</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finesse raises $4.5M to predict fashion trends with AI</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/finesse-launch-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/finesse-launch-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Roetter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MaC Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marlon Nichols]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finesse, a startup promising to take the guesswork and waste out of fashion, is announcing that it has raised $4.5 million in seed and pre-seed funding. Founder and CEO Ramin Ahmari said the tremendous waste in the fashion industry has become a badly-kept secret, with Burberry recently facing a backlash over its practice of burning [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.finesse.us">Finesse</a>, a startup promising to take the guesswork and waste out of fashion, is announcing that it has raised $4.5 million in seed and pre-seed funding.</p>
<p>Founder and CEO Ramin Ahmari said the tremendous waste in the fashion industry has become a badly-kept secret, with <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-44885983">Burberry recently facing a backlash</a> over its practice of burning unwanted products, and the industry as a whole producing <a href="https://theprettyplaneteer.com/fashion-industry-waste/">an estimated 13 million tons of textile waste</a> each year.</p>
<p>Finesse is looking to change that, Ahmari said, in part by taking advantage of the fact that that fashion trends are moving out of the &#8220;hermetically sealed&#8221; world of catwalks and onto social media, where new products take off &#8220;on the backs and bodies and posts&#8221; of influencers like Kylie Jenner.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;This is data we have access to,&#8221; he said. Noting that he previously worked in finance, Ahmari added that the stock market is &#8220;much more unpredictable&#8221; than the fashion industry — there just hasn&#8217;t been a tech startup applying tools like natural language processing and deep learning to fashion.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the simplest terms, you can think of what we do as seeing when Kylie posts a picture on Instagram and people go crazy about it &#8230; and then you see that happen not just on Kylie&#8217;s post but across Instagram, TikTok, Google Trends,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We predict the establishing of a trend before it goes super viral.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101242" style="width: 672px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101242" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2101242" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?w=662" alt="Finesse" width="662" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=146,150 146w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=292,300 292w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=768,789 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=662,680 662w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=1495,1536 1495w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=1994,2048 1994w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Desktop-Lifestyle-1.jpg?resize=50,50 50w" sizes="(max-width: 662px) 100vw, 662px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2101242" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Finesse</p></div></p>
<p>Finesse then uses this data to design new products. Ahmari said that by taking advantage of a &#8220;very fast supply chain,&#8221; along with tools like<a href="https://www.clo3d.com"> CLO 3D modeling software</a>, Finesse can go from identifying a trend to having a product available for purchase in less than 25 days.</p>
<p>While the startup is officially launching today, it&#8217;s already been selling products through &#8220;drops,&#8221; where customers vote for and pre-order products that will only be available in limited quantities. Ahmari said Finesse focuses on selling unique pieces rather than staples, but because it&#8217;s confident about consumer demand, it can keep things much more affordable — the <a href="https://www.finesse.us/products">products currently for sale</a> range from $8 to $116.</p>
<p>And unlike most fashion companies, Ahmari said that Finesse does not need to employ a giant design department, although he suggested that team members like Vice President of Product Andrea Knopf and Head of Product Development Brittany Fleck — who work in tandem with the startup&#8217;s algorithms —are &#8220;artists in their own right.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Unless we have true AI — which we&#8217;re very far from — you are never going to have a machine that’s purely creative,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You have to have feedback cycles &#8230; What we are eliminating is the job where it’s just an intern doing grunt work, all of these people just going through Instagram to find new fashion trends.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ahmari also said that with its emphasis on sustainability and connecting with the LGBTQ community (Ahmari identifies as queer and non-binary, and all of the startup&#8217;s products are designed for any gender), Finesse is aimed squarely at Gen Z consumers who are tired of fashion dictated by &#8220;white, older, cisgender men.&#8221;</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s investors include former Twitter head of engineering Alex Roetter, Collective Health CEO Ali Diab, Hoxton Ventures, MaC Venture Capital, Mango Capital and Fab Fit Fun co-founder Sam Teller.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe that FINESSE is truly the future of fashion, from its trend prediction to sustainable supply-chain and manufacturing,&#8221; said MaC Managing Partner Marlon Nichols in a statement. &#8220;We hope other fashion brands can learn from FINESSE’s disruption in the space and we’re eager to see what’s next.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ShdsVNA3kI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/amazon-fashion-launches-a-custom-clothing-service-made-for-you/">Amazon Fashion launches a custom clothing service, Made for You</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon Fashion launches a custom clothing service, Made for You&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/amazon-fashion-launches-a-custom-clothing-service-made-for-you/embed/#?secret=ShdsVNA3kI" data-secret="ShdsVNA3kI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/finesse-launch-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ring’s new video doorbell is $60</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/rings-new-doorbell-is-60/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/rings-new-doorbell-is-60/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doorbell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart doorbell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smarthome]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The top-line feature for Ring’s latest is no doubt its price. No way around that. At $60, it’s $40 cheaper than the standard Video Doorbell – and prices from there go up significantly, with the “Elite&#8221; running $350. Perhaps the company is feeling some pressure from the race the bottom for smart home hardware pricing. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The top-line feature for Ring’s latest is no doubt its price. No way around that. At $60, it’s $40 cheaper than the standard Video Doorbell – and prices from there go up significantly, with the “Elite&#8221; running $350.</p>
<p>Perhaps the company is feeling some pressure from the race the bottom for smart home hardware pricing. Wyze, notably, has done the Wyze thing, launching a $30 doorbell along with a slew of other products in September. Though as of this writing, that device is still listed as a “pre-order.”</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/vbyzzEEIPKk?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Wyze device was expected to be available this month, but has since been pushed back to February. The Ring Video Doorbell Wired is also currently slated for next month, with a shipping date of the 24th. As the name suggests, the new product is only available in a hardwired option – which could be a deal breaker for some. Other standard features here include 1080p video with night vision, motion zones that trigger notifications and two-way audio with noise cancelation built-in. It&#8217;s also the company&#8217;s smallest doorbell to date.</p>
<p>The Amazon-owned company is, of course, not without its share of controversy. Earlier this month, we noted a security flaw that exposed the locations and home addresses of people using its Neighbors app. There has also been plenty of concern around the brand’s willingness to partner with the law enforcement. A number of civil rights penned an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/08/over-30-civil-rights-groups-demand-an-end-to-amazon-rings-police-partnerships/">open letter in 2019</a>. Earlier this year, Ring finally enabled end-to-end encryption that requires user opt-in.</p>
<p>The new doorbell will be available through Amazon (naturally) and will be a Home Depot in-store exclusively through late-March.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pNLU0VLZzq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ring-neighbors-exposed-locations-addresses/">Amazon&#8217;s Ring Neighbors app exposed users&#8217; precise locations and home addresses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon&#8217;s Ring Neighbors app exposed users&#8217; precise locations and home addresses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/ring-neighbors-exposed-locations-addresses/embed/#?secret=pNLU0VLZzq" data-secret="pNLU0VLZzq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/rings-new-doorbell-is-60/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100999</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinecone lands $10M seed for purpose-built machine learning database</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/pinecone-lands-10m-seed-for-purpose-built-machine-learning-database/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/pinecone-lands-10m-seed-for-purpose-built-machine-learning-database/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinecone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wing venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pinecone, a new startup from the folks who helped launch Amazon SageMaker, has built a vector database that generates data in a specialized format to help build machine learning applications faster, something that was previously only accessible to the largest organizations. Today the company came out of stealth with a new product and announced a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://pinecone.io">Pinecone</a>, a new startup from the folks who helped launch Amazon SageMaker, has built a vector database that generates data in a specialized format to help build machine learning applications faster, something that was previously only accessible to the largest organizations. Today the company came out of stealth with a new product and announced a $10 million seed investment led by Wing Venture Capital.</p>
<p>Company co-founder Edo Liberty says that he started the company because of this fundamental belief that the industry was being held back by the lack of wider access to this type of database. &#8220;The data that a machine learning model expects isn&#8217;t a JSON record, it&#8217;s a high dimensional vector that is either a list of features or what&#8217;s called an embedding that&#8217;s a numerical representation of the items or the objects in the world. This [format] is much more semantically rich and actionable for machine learning,&#8221; he explained.</p>
<p>He says that this is a concept that is widely understood by data scientists, and supported by research, but up until now only the biggest and technically superior companies like Google or Pinterest could take advantage of this difference. Liberty and his team created Pinecone to put that kind of technology in reach of any company.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup spent the last couple of years building the solution, which consists of three main components. The main piece is a vector engine to convert the data into this machine-learning ingestible format. Liberty says that this is the piece of technology that contains all the data structures and algorithms that allow them to index very large amounts of high dimensional vector data, and search through it in an efficient and accurate way.</p>
<p>The second is a cloud hosted system to apply all of that converted data to the machine learning model, while handling things like index lookups along with the pre- and post-processing &#8212; everything a data science team needs to run a machine learning project at scale with very large workloads and throughputs. Finally, there is a management layer to track all of this and manage data transfer between source locations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zBFk6liPax"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/tecton-ai-nabs-35m-series-b-as-it-releases-machine-learning-feature-store/">Tecton.ai nabs $35M Series B as it releases machine learning feature store</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tecton.ai nabs $35M Series B as it releases machine learning feature store&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/07/tecton-ai-nabs-35m-series-b-as-it-releases-machine-learning-feature-store/embed/#?secret=zBFk6liPax" data-secret="zBFk6liPax" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>One classic example Liberty uses is an eCommerce recommendation engine. While this has been a standard part of online selling for years, he believes using a vectorized data approach will result in much more accurate recommendations and he says the data science research data bears him out.</p>
<p>&#8220;It used to be that deploying [something like a recommendation engine] was actually incredibly complex, and [&#8230;] if you have access to a production grade database, 90% of the difficulty and heavy lifting in creating those solutions goes away, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re building this. We believe it&#8217;s the new standard,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The company currently has 10 people including the founders, but the plan is to double or even triple that number, depending on how the year goes. As he builds his company as an immigrant founder &#8212; Liberty is from Israel &#8212; he says that diversity is top of mind. He adds that it&#8217;s something he worked hard on at his previous positions at Yahoo and Amazon as he was building his teams at those two organizations. One way he is doing that is in the recruitment process. &#8220;We have instructed our recruiters to be proactive [in finding more diverse applicants], making sure they don&#8217;t miss out on great candidates, and that they bring us a diverse set of candidates,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to post-pandemic, Liberty says he is a bit more traditional in terms of office versus home, and that he hopes to have more in-person interactions. &#8220;Maybe I&#8217;m old fashioned but I like offices and I like people and I like to see who I work with and hang out with them and laugh and enjoy each other&#8217;s company, and so I&#8217;m not jumping on the bandwagon of &#8216;let&#8217;s all be remote and work from home&#8217;.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u4l5ryHLv2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/31/how-artificial-intelligence-will-be-used-in-2021/">How artificial intelligence will be used in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How artificial intelligence will be used in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/31/how-artificial-intelligence-will-be-used-in-2021/embed/#?secret=u4l5ryHLv2" data-secret="u4l5ryHLv2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/pinecone-lands-10m-seed-for-purpose-built-machine-learning-database/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100982</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SAP launches &#8216;RISE with SAP,&#8217; a concierge service for digital transformation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/sap-launches-rise-with-sap-a-concierge-service-for-digital-transformation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/sap-launches-rise-with-sap-a-concierge-service-for-digital-transformation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital transformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ERP software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SAP today announced a new offering it calls &#8216;RISE with SAP,&#8217; a solution that is meant to help the company&#8217;s customers go through their respective digital transformations and become what SAP calls &#8216;intelligent enterprises.&#8217; RISE is a subscription service that combines a set of services and product offerings. SAP&#8217;s head of product success Sven Denecken [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SAP today announced a new offering it calls &#8216;<a href="https://www.sap.com/about/events/rise-with-sap.html">RISE with SAP</a>,&#8217; a solution that is meant to help the company&#8217;s customers go through their respective digital transformations and become what SAP calls &#8216;intelligent enterprises.&#8217; RISE is a subscription service that combines a set of services and product offerings.</p>
<p>SAP&#8217;s head of product success Sven Denecken (and its COO for S/4Hana) described it as &#8220;the best concierge service you can get for your digital transformation&#8221; when I talked to him earlier this week. &#8220;We need to help our clients to embrace that change that they see currently,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Transformation is a journey. Every client wants to become that smarter, faster and that nimbler business, but they, of course, also see that they are faced with challenges today and in the future. This continuous transformation is what is happening to businesses. And we do know from working together with them, that actually they agree with those fundamentals. They want to be an intelligent enterprise. They want to adapt and change. But the key question is how to get there? And the key question they ask us is, please help us to get there.&#8221;</p>
<p>With RISE for SAP, businesses will get a single contact at SAP to help guide them through their journey, but also access to the SAP partner ecosystem.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The first step in this process, Denecken stressed, isn&#8217;t necessarily to bring in new technology, though that is also part of it, but to help businesses redesign and optimize their business processes and implement the best practices in their verticals &#8212; and then measure the outcome. &#8220;Business process redesign means that you analyze how your business processes perform. How can you get tailored recommendations? How can you benchmark against industry standards? And this helps you to set the tone and also to motivate your people &#8212; your IT, your business people &#8212; to adapt,&#8221; Denecken described. He also noted that in order for a digital transformation project to succeed, IT and business leaders and employees have to work together.</p>
<p>In part, that includes technology offerings and adopting robotic process automation (RPA), for example. As Denecken stressed, all of this builds on top of the work SAP has done with its customers over the years to define business processes and KPIs.</p>
<p>On the technical side, SAP is obviously offering its own services, including its <a href="https://www.sap.com/products/business-technology-platform.html">Business Technology Platform</a>, and cloud infrastructure, but it will also support customers on all of the large cloud providers. Also included in RISE is support for more than 2,200 APIs to integrate various on-premises, cloud and non-SAP systems, access to SAP&#8217;s low-code and no-code capabilities and, of course, its database and analytics offerings.</p>
<p>&#8220;Geopolitical tensions, environmental challenges and the ongoing pandemic are forcing businesses to deal with change faster than ever before,” said Christian Klein, SAP&#8217;s CEO, in today&#8217;s announcement. &#8220;Companies that can adapt their business processes quickly will thrive – and SAP can help them achieve this. This is what RISE with SAP is all <a name="m_-7067269608981192402__Hlk62241131"></a>about: It helps customers continuously unlock new ways of running businesses in the cloud to stay ahead of their industry.&#8221;</p>
<p>With this new offering, SAP is now providing its customers with a number of solutions that were previously available through its partner ecosystem. Denecken doesn&#8217;t see this as SAP competing with its own partners, though. Instead, he argues that this is very much a partner play and that this new solution will likely only bring more customers to its partners as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;Needless to say, this has been a negotiation with those partners,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Because yes, it&#8217;s sometimes topics that we now take over they [previously] did. But we are looking for scale here. The need in the market for digital transformation has just started. And this is where we see that this is definitely a big offering, together with partners. &#8220;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/sap-launches-rise-with-sap-a-concierge-service-for-digital-transformation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101037</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GameStop, meme stocks, and the revenge of the retail trader</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/gamestop-memestocks-and-the-revenge-of-the-retail-trader/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/gamestop-memestocks-and-the-revenge-of-the-retail-trader/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GameStop shares are set to rally 70% this morning when trading starts, and AMC shares opened up 300%, extending a run that has perplexed market observers, irked hedge funds, and generally made crypto&#8217;s recent gains appear soft and weak. Being a retail trader is mostly being a sucker, hoping to best the markets while lacking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">GameStop shares are set to rally 70% this morning when trading starts, and AMC shares opened up 300%, extending a run that has perplexed market observers, irked hedge funds, and generally made crypto&#8217;s recent gains appear soft and weak.</p>
<p>Being a retail trader is mostly being a sucker, hoping to best the markets while lacking the infrastructure, access, and information that professionals enjoy. Hell, most professional fund managers that regular folks can invest in fail to beat the market. That&#8217;s one reason why index funds and other passive investments that merely track aggregate performance have grown so much in recent years; why pay more to have someone make you less money than simply making the same returns as the S&amp;P 500?</p>
<p>Things have changed some in recent years. Robinhood <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/spurred-by-robinhood-trading-fees-fall-among-old-guard-brokers/">blew up the trading fee economy</a>, and now along with a host of similar companies &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/social-stock-trading-services-public-raises-65m-series-c/">Public.com with its social focus</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/18/fintechs-savings-and-investing-boom-isnt-just-a-domestic-affair/">Freetrade in the UK</a>, and so forth &#8212; has made retail investing far more accessible than it was before to more folks. And we&#8217;re all trapped inside. And a rude, jokey Reddit forum has gone from in-nerd joke to front-page news after its users started to push their weight around.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It&#8217;s something that was noted by none other than the founder of Reddit Alexis Ohanian who shared some thoughts on Twitter.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">And it&#39;s a perfect storm at a time when lots of people are hurting, interest rates are so low, inescapable student loan debts loom, and every major institution has caught Ls during a /global pandemic/ over the last year. This is something to believe in.</p>
<p>&mdash; Alexis Ohanian Sr. 7&#xfe0f;&#x20e3;7&#xfe0f;&#x20e3;6&#xfe0f;&#x20e3; (@alexisohanian) <a href="https://twitter.com/alexisohanian/status/1354407436732387335?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>It&#8217;s an old saw that back in the dotcom boom traders would congregate in chat rooms to share tips, lie to each other, and try to pump their own equities higher. That all still happens. But what has changed is that the combination of mature social platforms and free trading has at once boosted access to the public markets <em>while</em> Reddit and other online congregation points have provided a simpler way for retail investors, the <em>hoi polloi</em>, to fuck around and make other people find out.</p>
<p>Again, Ohanian&#8217;s thoughts on this resonate.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">A couple hundred thousand years of evolution conditioned us to believe in and rally around the immediate tribe around us. The idea of an &#8216;institution&#8217; &#8211; a faceless, nameless entity we just have to trust &#8212; is actually pretty foreign to our species,&#8221; </span><a style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px; background-color: #ffffff;" href="https://twitter.com/alexisohanian/status/1354407438473076737?s=20">the venture investor wrote on Twitter</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. &#8220;</span><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">I know they&#8217;re all &#8216;random people on the internet&#8217; but there&#8217;s a lot more empathy and community there than people realize. It&#8217;s why I&#8217;ve been saying for 15 years that (online) community is still massively undervalued.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>This is what has happened with GameStop, a company that until recently was unnotable, and stuck between a physical retail footprint, the pandemic, and its customers increasingly preferring digital game purchases. It was worth around $4 per share last summer. It started 2021 worth around $18. Now it&#8217;s $147.98 after rising 92.7% yesterday, and is up $69.02 this morning, or 46.6%.</p>
<p>How did that happen? No, the company did not get suddenly, radically stronger in short order. Instead, a coterie of Reddit users realized that GameStop was shorted by more than 100%. That means that investors had bet more shares than existed in the company that it would lose value.</p>
<p>And mostly this would have been fine, a quirk of the market; other highly-shorted stocks <a href="https://www.investors.com/etfs-and-funds/sectors/sp500-heavily-shorted-stocks-primed-for-epic-squeezes-analysts-say-gamestop/">can see a majority of their shares sold short</a>, but to see a short-percentage of greater than 100% was eyebrow-raising.</p>
<p>Then came the wager: If big investors had bet more shares than GameStop had in existence that it would lose value, what would happen if lots of individuals investors &#8212; retail interest, as they say &#8212; started <em>buying</em> the stock? That might drive its value up, forcing the hedge funds and other big capital pools to decide whether to hold onto their negative bet and take strong paper losses as GameStop rallied, or cover their short, buying the stock at a higher price than they initially paid for it, losing money. Covering shorts would require buying the stock at high prices, perhaps boosting its value yet again.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the wildest short-squeeze we can recall.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s always tension between short-sellers and investors who prefer to make positive wagers. Indeed, shorts are generally hated and the term <em>perma-bear</em>, slang for someone who is chronically worried about the price of assets to the point of distraction,<sup>1</sup> is often levied at them.</p>
<p>But <em>a boom in retail investing </em>and<em> social platforms allowing the congregation of disparate individual investors </em>can do quite a lot, it turns out. So, users of the WallStreetBets sub-Reddit started buying GameStop. And they kept doing so, pushing its price higher and higher.</p>
<p>The result was that big money got smacked in the shorts, literally. CNBC <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/26/gamestop-shares-are-jumping-again-but-short-sellers-arent-backing-down.html">reports</a> that short-sellers have lost more than $5 billion so far thanks to GameStop&#8217;s rapid appreciation on the back of becoming an internet meme.</p>
<p>But the tug-of-war between professionals betting that GameStop is not worth its inflated price, and that it will fall, is not over. Short interest remains high. So, even if some pro investors have cried uncle and exited their trade, the retail revenge on the so-called smart money is hardly a sure thing; what those excitable individuals may have done is merely set up a more enticing short position for hedge funds than had existed before.</p>
<p>GameStop has a lot further to fall from over $140 per share than it did from $18, say.</p>
<p>Of course no one knows what will happen today. The investors who have taken out more short positions during the rally are set to eat their own ties this morning when GameStop opens higher. Perhaps they will hold, and eventually their short bet will pay off. Or perhaps retail will be able to keep rallying GameStop until, well, no one really knows.</p>
<p>But while most folks have their retirement accounts in investments so boring you&#8217;ve forgotten their names &#8212; Fidelity Freedom 2060 Fund, or what have you &#8212; small-time investors are sticking it to the man. This is the political war underneath the trading scrap. Retail is generally said to be mad at being pushed around, <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/frontrunning.asp">front-run</a>, and generally speaking operating as second-class investing citizens. The GameStop gambit is, to some degree, revenge.</p>
<p>Not that it will matter, per se, in the long-term. Large investing groups will still crush retail, having access to better information and tools and the like, as we mentioned up top. But today, at least, those same concerns are going to start the day with huge paper losses on their GameStop shorts.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s hilarious, because the company is obviously overvalued and individuals simply do not give a fuck.</p>
<ol>
<li>I, Alex Wilhelm, am like this before coffee.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/gamestop-memestocks-and-the-revenge-of-the-retail-trader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101193</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Following acquisition, Episerver rebrands as Optimizely</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/episerver-rebrands-as-optimizely/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/episerver-rebrands-as-optimizely/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Atzberger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Episerver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Optimizely]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After acquiring Optimizely last fall, content management company Episerver is adopting the Optimizely name for the entire organization. CEO Alex Atzberger told me that the company will be rolling out new branding in the next coming months, as well as renaming its entire product suite to reflect the Optimizely brand. &#8220;We believe it’s no longer [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/episerver-acquires-optimizely/">acquiring Optimizely last fall</a>, content management company <a href="https://www.episerver.com">Episerver</a> is adopting the Optimizely name for the entire organization.</p>
<p>CEO Alex Atzberger told me that the company will be rolling out new branding in the next coming months, as well as renaming its entire product suite to reflect the Optimizely brand.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe it’s no longer just about personalizing the experience or driving recommendations,&#8221; Atzberger said. &#8220;The brand and word Optimizely really signifies optimal performance. Companies today of any size, any scale [need to be] much more sophisticated in terms of how they digitally connect with their customers. It&#8217;s a never-ending story.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At the same time, he emphasized that Episerver is making the change from &#8220;a position of strength,&#8221; with the combined company seeing double-digit revenue growth last year and going live with more than 250 new customers.</p>
<p>Asked whether adopting the Optimizely name was always part of the post-acquisition plan, Atzberger replied, &#8220;When we acquired Optimizely, we knew that we would be acquiring not just a great product, not just a great customer base, but also acquiring a very well-known brand. We had not yet decided on [rebranding], but it was certainly something that, for me, was part of the consideration.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to announcing the new company name, Episerver/Optimizely is also announcing a new platform that it&#8217;s calling Optimization-as-a-Service, which integrates aspects of Optimizely and Episerver products to offer web targeting, testing and recommendations. As Atzberger put it, this new platform allows customers to determine &#8220;who to show something to, what content to show and how to actually show this content.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BHvSR7pi1E"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/episerver-acquires-optimizely/">Optimizely acquired by content management company Episerver</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Optimizely acquired by content management company Episerver&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/episerver-acquires-optimizely/embed/#?secret=BHvSR7pi1E" data-secret="BHvSR7pi1E" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/episerver-rebrands-as-optimizely/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101201</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renewable investment wave continues as solar lending company Loanpal raises $800 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/renewable-investment-wave-continues-as-solar-lending-company-loanpal-raises-800-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/renewable-investment-wave-continues-as-solar-lending-company-loanpal-raises-800-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackRock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chamath Palihapitiya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief financial officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laurence Tosi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Riverstone Holdings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Sandell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarCity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White House]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Economic Forum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2100680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Days after the billionaire investor Chamath Palihapitiya announced his involvement in the $1.3 billion acquisition of the solar and home improvement lending business Sunlight Financial, a collection of investors announced a nearly $1 billion cash infusion into Loanpal, another renewable energy and home improvement lender. The $800 million commitment to Loanpal arrives alongside a flurry [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Days after the billionaire investor Chamath Palihapitiya announced his involvement in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/chamath-palihapitiyas-spac-for-sunlight-financial-is-another-sign-of-a-renewables-boom/">$1.3 billion acquisition of the solar and home improvement lending business Sunlight Financial</a>, a collection of investors announced a nearly $1 billion cash infusion into <a href="https://loanpal.com/">Loanpal</a>, another renewable energy and home improvement lender.</p>
<p>The $800 million commitment to Loanpal arrives alongside a flurry of climate commitments from some of the world&#8217;s largest investors.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Blackrock chief Larry Fink, <a href="https://www.blackrock.com/corporate/investor-relations/larry-fink-ceo-letter">released the $9 trillion investment manager&#8217;s annual letter</a> calling for more stringent accounting and reporting of climate data, and Bank of America joined 60 other companies <a href="https://newsroom.bankofamerica.com/content/newsroom/press-releases/2021/01/global-business-leaders-support-esg-convergence-by-committing-to.html">in committing to a new reporting standard for climate and sustainability</a> endorsed by the International Business Council and the World Economic Forum. Fink endorses a separate reporting scheme called the <a href="https://www.fsb-tcfd.org/">Task Force on Climate Related Financial Disclosures</a> that has the backing of some of the biggest financial investors in the world.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KWAQtajDSI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/chamath-palihapitiyas-spac-for-sunlight-financial-is-another-sign-of-a-renewables-boom/">Chamath Palihapitiya&#8217;s SPAC for Sunlight Financial is another sign of a renewables boom</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chamath Palihapitiya&#8217;s SPAC for Sunlight Financial is another sign of a renewables boom&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/chamath-palihapitiyas-spac-for-sunlight-financial-is-another-sign-of-a-renewables-boom/embed/#?secret=KWAQtajDSI" data-secret="KWAQtajDSI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>These new standards will drive more investment dollars into businesses that are reducing the greenhouse gas emissions that contribute to global climate change. And lending programs incentivizing the switch to more energy efficient appliances and renewable installations are probably the lowest of low hanging fruit for the financial services industry.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s one reason why investors like <span style="font-weight: 400;"> NEA, the WestCap Group, Brookfield Asset Management, and the giant private equity energy investment fund Riverstone Holdings are backing Loanpal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The deal, which was a secondary transaction to give strategic investors a stake in the business actually wrapped up last year. As a result Scott Sandell, the managing general partner at NEA and a longtime investor in pr and Laurence Tosi, Managing Partner of WestCap Group, have joined the company’s board of directors.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;We invited a number of players into the company,&#8221; said Loanpal&#8217;s founder, chairman and chief executive Hayes Barnard. The former chief revenue officer for SolarCity before its acquisition by Tesla, Barnard has a long history with solar energy development. At Loanpal he also had the balance sheet to take his pick among would-be investors. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re a multi-billion dollar company,&#8221; said Barnard.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101183" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101183" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2101183" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="684" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg 3500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg?resize=1536,1026 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20190826-loanpal-110-Edit.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2101183" class="wp-caption-text">Loanpal founder chairman and chief executive, Hayes Barnard. Image Credit: Loanpal</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;This was us inviting strategic investors into the company and being thoughtful about where they could help and how they could help,&#8221; Barnard said.</p>
<p>Loanpal is profitable, has zero debt and throws off monthly dividends to its financial backers. &#8220;Today we finance $400 million a month for roughly 15,000 solar systems that are combined with battery systems,&#8221; says Barnard. In all, the company has arranged $5.9 billion in consumer finance loans since its launch in 2018. Loanpal also counts around 85% of the top solar firms as vendors and has a staff of around 12,000 sales professionals.</p>
<p>Those numbers allowed the company to bring in board members like Tosi, the former chief financial officer of the multi-billion dollar financial services firm, Blackstone. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">He really understands how to bring in capital markets at scale,&#8221; said Barnard. </span></p>
<p>If anything, the attention from Blackrock, Blackstone, Riverstone and all the financial services firms without references to stones or rocks in their name shows that this is a problem of capital at scale. Decarbonizing the global economy is a $10 trillion business, according to the World Economic Forum (or, for the retail investment crowd, the equivalent of roughly 66.7 billion Gamestops <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=gamestop+share+price&amp;rlz=1C5GCEA_enUS896US897&amp;oq=gamestop+share+price&amp;aqs=chrome.0.0i131i433l2j0l6.2291j1j7&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">at yesterday&#8217;s share price</a>).</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">The near term market that we’re going to penetrate now is sustainable home solutions that’s a $100 billion market,&#8221; Barnard said. </span></p>
<p>A significant chunk of that $10 trillion is going to come from the development and integration of new consumer facing appliances and hardware to reduce the consumption of energy. &#8220;We believe the battery storage market, the smart thermostat market and the solar market are all intertwined and combined,&#8221; said Barnard. &#8220;<span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall the most important thing is that this is just technology that is better. It was going to scale regardless of who was in the White House. These pieces of technology are better, they save homeowners money.. It’s kind of an IQ test if homeowners want to do it.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/renewable-investment-wave-continues-as-solar-lending-company-loanpal-raises-800-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2100680</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lynk, a &#8220;knowledge-as-a-service&#8221; platform with more than 840,000 experts, raises $24 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/lynk-a-knowledge-as-a-service-platform-with-more-than-840000-experts-raises-24-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/lynk-a-knowledge-as-a-service-platform-with-more-than-840000-experts-raises-24-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knowledge as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lynk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lynk, a &#8220;knowledge-as-a-service&#8221; platform that connects clients with over 840,000 experts in a wide range of fields, announced today it has raised $24 million led by Brewer Lane Ventures and MassMutual Ventures, with participation from Alibaba Entrepreneurs Fund. The company uses machine learning algorithms to match users, who include investment firms, Fortune 100 companies and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><div id="attachment_2101107" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101107" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2101107 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg" alt="Lynk co-founder and chief executive officer Peggy Choi" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg 2982w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Peggy-Choi_Image-4.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2101107" class="wp-caption-text">Lynk co-founder and chief executive officer Peggy Choi</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://lynk.global/">Lynk</a>, a &#8220;knowledge-as-a-service&#8221; platform that connects clients with over 840,000 experts in a wide range of fields, announced today it has raised $24 million led by Brewer Lane Ventures and MassMutual Ventures, with participation from Alibaba Entrepreneurs Fund. The company uses machine learning algorithms to match users, who include investment firms, Fortune 100 companies and government entities, with experts on its platform, helping connect them with people they would probably not find at traditional consultancies or by searching online.</p>
<p>&#8220;At the core of it, the search is a people search based on what you know, and not just where you work, to put it very simply,&#8221; co-founder and chief executive officer Peggy Choi told TechCrunch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in 2015, Lynk has now raised a total of $30 million. It has more than 200 employees across offices in eight cities: Hong Kong, New York City, Singapore, London, Mumbai, Shanghai, Hyderabad, Toronto and Manila. Its funding will be used for product launches and to expand in North America and China, where its seen demand grow over the past twelve months.</p>
<p>Lynk&#8217;s flagship product, Lynk Answers, is currently used by about 200 enterprise clients when their employees need to do research for projects including geographical expansion, product-market fit and due diligence, with many relying on the platform for on-the-ground research in areas they can&#8217;t travel to because of the pandemic. For example, investors talk with advisors on Lynk to understand new technology or the dynamics in a sector. Over the past few years, companies have used Lynk to help them react quickly to geopolitical changes, including events that affected their supply chain. Some sought supply chain experts when shipments got stuck in customs or they wanted to diversify their manufacturing by setting up factories in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Before Lynk, Choi worked in finance, including at Silver Lake in London and TPG in San Francisco. As an investor, &#8220;every day you have to do a lot of conversations with executives and different kinds of experts to learn about new industries or companies really quickly. Through that experience, I realized that talking to the right person makes a huge difference,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>In contrast, Choi found herself at a loss when her parents wanted to launch an art gallery. &#8220;They had all these day-to-day business questions and sometimes they asked me because they thought I would know how to address it. But I don&#8217;t know either, I&#8217;m not the right person for them, so I had to find the right people,&#8221; she said. &#8220;When I saw that contrast, I thought, what about using data to organize people in a way based on what they know?&#8221;</p>
<p>Lynk, which monetizes by charging enterprise clients a subscription fee, fills the gap between traditional consultancies and consumer-oriented Q&amp;A platforms like Quora or China&#8217;s Zhihu. The platform also includes SaaS features that provide an alternative to email chains, like collaboration tools and auto-transcription for expert interviews so they can be organized, searched and referenced by a team.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Wni8hqLUIr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/how-zhihus-become-one-of-chinas-biggest-hubs-for-experts/">How Zhihu has become one of China&#8217;s biggest hubs for experts</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Zhihu has become one of China&#8217;s biggest hubs for experts&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/03/how-zhihus-become-one-of-chinas-biggest-hubs-for-experts/embed/#?secret=Wni8hqLUIr" data-secret="Wni8hqLUIr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Lynk’s experts, who the platform calls “Knowledge Partners,” include C-suite executives, independent consultants, lawyers, engineers, financial analysts and scientists, among others. The company finds them through several channels, including digital marketing, a referral program for current Knowledge Partners and partnerships with groups, associations and institutions. Lynk vets experts before they are added to the platform, where they set their own rates.</p>
<p>When users have a question, Lynk’s search engine shows them a list of experts based on criteria like domain expertise and geography. Then they ask potential experts a couple of questions to see if they are the right match. Lynk uses data from those conversations, on an anonymized basis, to refine its search technology and make matching more accurate. Once users pick experts, they work with them in different ways. Most of the time they do a question-and-answer session. Sometimes that turns into speaker and workshop engagements or longer-term projects.</p>
<p>Choi said building an inclusive roster of experts is a priority for Lynk. The company&#8217;s team and board are divided equally between women and men and represent more than 20 nationalities. It wants to build a diverse database through initiatives like outreach programs and campaigns like <a href="https://lynk.global/in-the-news/lynk-launches-lynk-elite-expert-women-for-international-womens-day-2020">Lynk Elite Expert Women</a> to recruit people, including those who haven&#8217;t done consulting before.</p>
<p>“When we were running the [Lynk Elite Expert Women] campaign, we realized that a lot of people find it a very new way of being valued,” said Choi. “Especially if they&#8217;ve spent their entire life doing something, they also want to know what people want to know about their area.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gSoRhXa5dy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/prosapient-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-smedvig-capital-to-expand-expert-network-platform/">proSapient raises $10M Series A led by Smedvig Capital to expand expert network platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;proSapient raises $10M Series A led by Smedvig Capital to expand expert network platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/18/prosapient-raises-10m-series-a-led-by-smedvig-capital-to-expand-expert-network-platform/embed/#?secret=gSoRhXa5dy" data-secret="gSoRhXa5dy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uYsKH0okK7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/18/two-sigma-leads-12m-series-a-for-expert-knowledge-network-newtonx/">Two Sigma leads $12m series A for expert knowledge network NewtonX</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Two Sigma leads $12m series A for expert knowledge network NewtonX&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/18/two-sigma-leads-12m-series-a-for-expert-knowledge-network-newtonx/embed/#?secret=uYsKH0okK7" data-secret="uYsKH0okK7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/lynk-a-knowledge-as-a-service-platform-with-more-than-840000-experts-raises-24-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101104</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Literati raises $40M for its book club platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/literati-raises-40m-for-its-book-club-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/literati-raises-40m-for-its-book-club-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adam bain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aydin Senkut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dick costolo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felicis Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founders Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Malala Yousafzai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard branson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shasta ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silverton Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stephen curry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Literati has raised a $40 million Series B to pursue an unusual startup opportunity — namely, book clubs. Founder and CEO Jessica Ewing (a former product manager at Google) explained that the Austin-based company started out with book clubs for kids, before launching its Luminary brand for adult book clubs last year. And the Luminary [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://literati.com">Literati</a> has raised a $40 million Series B to pursue an unusual startup opportunity — namely, book clubs.</p>
<p>Founder and CEO Jessica Ewing (a former product manager at Google) explained that the Austin-based company started out with book clubs for <a href="https://literati.com/kids/">kids</a>, before launching <a href="https://literati.com/book-clubs/">its Luminary brand</a> for adult book clubs last year. And the Luminary clubs live up to the name — they&#8217;re curated by notable figures such as activist and Nobel laureate Malala Yousafzai, NBA star Stephen Curry, entrepreneur and philanthropist Sir Richard Branson, journalist Susan Orlean and the Joseph Campbell Foundation.</p>
<p>When you sign up for a Literati book club, you receive a print edition of each month&#8217;s selection with a note from the curator. You also get access to the Literati app, where you can discuss the book with other readers, and where curators host author conversations. For example, Curry is leading <a href="https://literati.com/book-clubs/stephen-curry/">a book club focused on nonfiction</a> about people who &#8220;transcend expectations&#8221; (he invested in Literati as well), while <a href="https://literati.com/book-clubs/malala/">Yousafzai chooses books by women</a> &#8220;with bold ideas from around the world.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ewing told me that she&#8217;s trying to build the first &#8220;new, innovative bookseller&#8221; since Amazon launched 25 years ago. And she&#8217;s doing that by focusing on curation.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s too much choice, too many lists, it’s completely overwhelming for most people,&#8221; she said. She argued that it helps to enlist celebrities and other big names to do that curation: &#8220;Books are aspirational. No one aspires to play more video games, people aspire to read more &#8230; People want their books to be recommended by someone a little bit smarter than they are.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101249" style="width: 463px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101249" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2101249" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Jess-Ewing-credit-steven-visneau.jpg?w=453" alt="Literati CEO Jessica Ewing" width="453" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Jess-Ewing-credit-steven-visneau.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Jess-Ewing-credit-steven-visneau.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Jess-Ewing-credit-steven-visneau.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Jess-Ewing-credit-steven-visneau.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Jess-Ewing-credit-steven-visneau.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Jess-Ewing-credit-steven-visneau.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2101249" class="wp-caption-text">Literati CEO Jessica Ewing</p></div></p>
<p>Ewing&#8217;s hope for Literati is to create &#8220;the next great literary social network,&#8221; bridging the gap between celebrity-driven lists like <a href="https://www.oprah.com/app/books.html">Oprah&#8217;s Book Club</a> and <a href="https://hello-sunshine.com/book-club">Reese&#8217;s Book Club </a>and what she described as &#8220;the wine-and-cheese, super intimate model.&#8221;</p>
<p><span class="Apple-converted-space">&#8220;</span>I would love to see in-person meetups once we’re out of the COVID environment,&#8221; she added. &#8220;But I also think there&#8217;s everything in between. We&#8217;re enabling threaded discussions [in the app] right now, and it&#8217;s cool to have asynchronous conversations about the books.&#8221;</p>
<p>And on the children&#8217;s book side, Literati is also working to build personalization tools designed to recommend the best books for each child.</p>
<p>&#8220;To me, this is one of the most exciting applications: How do we make this generation of kids love reading by pairing them with the right books?&#8221; Ewing said.</p>
<p>Literati previously raised $12 million in funding from Shasta Ventures and others, <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/literati/company_financials">according to Crunchbase</a>. The new round was led by Aydin Senkut of Felicis Ventures, with participation from Dick Costolo and Adam Bain of 01 Advisors, Founders Fund, General Catalyst, Shasta, Silverton Partners, Springdale Ventures and, as previously noted, Stephen Curry.</p>
<p>&#8220;I wanted to start my own book club with <span class="il">Literati</span>, because their mission to better the world through reading naturally aligns with my values as an entrepreneur and father,” Curry said in a statement. “I was a fan before I was an investor, and am so proud to be a part of a company that works to better the lives of others, one book at a time.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Le1xPcsnik"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/">Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Gift Guide: The best books for 2020 recommended by VCs and TechCrunch writers (Part 1)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/gift-guide-the-best-books-for-2020-recommended-by-vcs-and-techcrunch-writers-part-1/embed/#?secret=Le1xPcsnik" data-secret="Le1xPcsnik" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/literati-raises-40m-for-its-book-club-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101018</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LottieFiles, a platform for the animation format, lands $9 million Series A led by M12, Microsoft&#8217;s venture fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/lottiefiles-a-platform-for-the-animation-format-lands-9-million-series-a-led-by-m12-microsofts-venture-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/lottiefiles-a-platform-for-the-animation-format-lands-9-million-series-a-led-by-m12-microsofts-venture-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lottie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LottieFiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LottieFiles, a platform for JSON-based Lottie animations, has raised a Series A of $9 million. The round was led by M12, Microsoft’s venture capital arm, with participation from returning investor 500 Startups. Based in San Francisco and Kuala Lumpur, LottieFiles was founded in 2018. The platform includes Lottie creation, editing and testing tools, and a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://lottiefiles.com/">LottieFiles</a>, a platform for JSON-based Lottie animations, has raised a Series A of $9 million. The round was led by M12, Microsoft’s venture capital arm, with participation from returning investor 500 Startups.</p>
<p>Based in San Francisco and Kuala Lumpur, LottieFiles was founded in 2018. The platform includes Lottie creation, editing and testing tools, and a marketplace for animations. It now claims about one million users from 65,000 companies, including Airbnb, Google, TikTok, Disney and Netflix, and 300% year-over-year growth. The new funding brings its total raised to about $10 million.</p>
<p>Smaller than GIF or PNG graphics, Lottie animations also have the advantage of being scalable and interactive. It was <a href="https://airbnb.design/introducing-lottie/">introduced as an open-source library</a> by Airbnb engineers six years ago and quickly became popular with app developers because Lottie files can be used across platforms without additional coding and edited after shipping.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2101125" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101125" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2101125" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?w=680" alt="An illustration from animation startup LottieFiles" width="680" height="340" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?resize=1536,768 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?resize=2048,1024 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cover-image.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2101125" class="wp-caption-text">An illustration from animation startup LottieFiles</p></div></p>
<p>LottieFiles co-founder and chief executive officer Kshitij Minglani told TechCrunch the startup originally started as a community for designers and developers, before adding tools, integrations and other resources. It launched its marketplace during the COVID-19 lockdown, with 70% of earnings going directly to creators, and also has a list of animators who are available for hire.</p>
<p>LottieFiles’ core platform and tools are currently pre-revenue, with plans to monetize later this year. &#8220;It’s not often a revolutionary format comes about and disrupts an entire industry, saving tons of precious design and development hours,&#8221; said Minglani. &#8220;We didn’t want to stunt the adoption of Lottie by monetizing early on.&#8221;</p>
<p>The new funding will be used on LottieFiles’ product roadmap, expanding its infrastructure and increasing its global user base.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/lottiefiles-a-platform-for-the-animation-format-lands-9-million-series-a-led-by-m12-microsofts-venture-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101123</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starship Technologies raises $17M to roll out more delivery bots</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/starship-technologies-raises-17m-to-roll-out-more-delivery-bots/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/starship-technologies-raises-17m-to-roll-out-more-delivery-bots/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starship technologies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2101038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A year ago, Starship Technologies had a couple hundred autonomous bots delivering burritos and pizzas to  students on college campuses and residents in a few neighborhoods. The company — with $17 million of new capital in its coffers — has expanded its fleet five-fold since COVID-19 swept through the European and North American markets that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A year ago, Starship Technologies had a couple hundred autonomous bots delivering burritos and pizzas to  students on college campuses and residents in a few neighborhoods.</p>
<p>The company — with $17 million of new capital in its coffers — has expanded its fleet five-fold since COVID-19 swept through the European and North American markets that it operates in. While COVID-19 delivered pain and chaos, including to Starship Technologies, the company has also experienced an uptick in demand as restaurants switched to a takeout and delivery-only model. Starship now has 1,000 autonomous delivery bots in its fleet.</p>
<p>Starship Technologies said last year it planned to expand to 100 universities by late summer 2021. That&#8217;s a leap from the 15 campuses it operates at today. Still, the company is expanding in just about every measurable way, including locations, volume of trips, fleet size and workforce, which now number 400 people. The company said it is bringing new college campuses on every month and has a robust pipeline that will come online as classes resume.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company&#8217;s recent $17 million raise, which was announced Tuesday, included investors TDK Ventures and Goodyear Ventures. The new investment brings Starship&#8217;s total funding to $102 million. Starship decline to share its valuation. The company also announced it has expanded to UCLA and Bridgewater State University in Massachusetts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2101058" style="width: 1746px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101058" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2101058 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg" alt="Starship infographic1_Jan2021" width="1736" height="1290" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg 1736w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg?resize=150,111 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg?resize=300,223 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg?resize=768,571 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg?resize=680,505 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg?resize=1536,1141 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Starship-infographic1_Jan2021.jpg?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1736px) 100vw, 1736px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2101058" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Starship Technologies</p></div></p>
<p>Starship Technologies, which was launched in 2014 by Skype co-founders Ahti Heinla and Janus Friis, has grown from an enterprise that completed 5,000 deliveries in 2017 to 1 million by January of this year. It&#8217;s also expanded beyond college campuses and communities like Milton Keyes, UK to more towns, including a 5,000-household area in Northhampton, UK and the California cities of Mountain View and Modesto.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/starship-technologies-raises-17m-to-roll-out-more-delivery-bots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2101038</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
