<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 20:05:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Deed raises $10M for its workplace giving platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/deed-raises-10m-for-its-workplace-giving-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/deed-raises-10m-for-its-workplace-giving-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 20:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deed]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I wrote earlier this year, Deed&#8216;s mission is a clearcut one: take the employee giving/charity/volunteer program that many big companies have, and make it better. Give it a proper home — one with a modern UI, built-in community management tools, and that hooks into your workflow (read: Slack) so as to not be forgotten. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As I<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/deed-pulls-your-employers-charity-and-volunteer-program-into-slack-to-keep-it-front-of-mind/"> wrote</a> earlier this year, <a href="https://www.joindeed.com">Deed</a>&#8216;s mission is a clearcut one: take the employee giving/charity/volunteer program that many big companies have, and make it better. Give it a proper home — one with a modern UI, built-in community management tools, and that hooks into your workflow (read: Slack) so as to not be forgotten.</p>
<p>With that they were able to quickly get some big names on board, citing the likes of Airbnb, Stripe, Box, and Adidas as customers quickly after launch. Now they&#8217;ve raised a $10M Series A to keep the ball rolling.</p>
<p>Last week I hopped on a call with Deed cofounder Deevee Kashi, who stepped away from a conference he was speaking at to catch me up on what&#8217;s new with the company. He tells me that this latest round was led by Earlybird, and backed by PruVen Capital, Y Combinator, Paua Ventures along with a few names that seem extra interesting from a strategic standpoint — like David Clarke (former CTO of the enterprise workplace management tool Workday), Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi, and Jeffrey Katzenberg&#8217;s Wndrco.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245648" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>One thing Kashi tells me is an evolving focus for Deed right now: helping companies figure out what their employees really care about, and how to shape the company&#8217;s efforts — often wrapped up under a label of &#8220;Environmental, Social, and Governance&#8221; (or ESG) — accordingly</p>
<p>&#8220;ESG investments are at record highs, right?&#8221; he says. &#8220;Companies are spending a lot of money, but they are not getting [employee] buy-in before doing so.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Our goal for Deed is really changing ESG, and the strategies around ESG, from &#8216;me&#8217; to &#8216;we&#8217;.&#8221; he adds. &#8220;Really empowering employees to take action around causes they care about, thereby allowing companies to listen to and discover what their employees actually care about.&#8221;</p>
<p>Part of making that work, he says, will involve giving individual employees — not just those in charge of a company&#8217;s social impact team— more abilities to create and manage programs, fundraisers, and volunteer campaigns. &#8220;[It&#8217;s about] empowering the employees themselves to manage the program for the company, as opposed to the companies managing the program for the employees.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The other part, he notes, is building out their data team and finding ways to &#8220;measure and report on impact&#8221; in a clear, actionable way.</p>
<p>Before this, Deed had raised $2M in a seed round in late 2020.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/deed-raises-10m-for-its-workplace-giving-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245648</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Raise and deliver</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/raise-and-deliver/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/raise-and-deliver/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 19:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Actuator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery robots]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Remember all the way back to December 2020. Where were you? What were your plans? What did you expect and hope the new year would bring? I suspect I’m not alone in feeling like I’ve spent much of the past year on a hamster wheel, with better days just over the horizon. Truth is, few [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Remember all the way back to December 2020. Where were you? What were your plans? What did you expect and hope the new year would bring? I suspect I’m not alone in feeling like I’ve spent much of the past year on a hamster wheel, with better days just over the horizon. Truth is, few of us reasonably expected the pandemic to stretch on for this long. And our expectations of “normal” have adjusted accordingly.</p>
<p>As we reflect on how the last year has played out for robotics &#8212; and the way things look, going forward &#8212; the pandemic is, once again, the primary force guiding practically every facet of the industry. As I mentioned last week, we’re going to spend these next few weeks wrapping up the year here on Actuator. This week, I want to talk about delivery robotics, a category that’s seen some of the biggest investment this past year.</p>
<p>But first, we’ll be asking some of the industry’s leading names to reflect on the year that was &#8212; and help us forecast how 2022 might look for robotics and automation.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245088" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2245095" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245095" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2245095" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="441" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg 1799w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg?resize=150,65 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg?resize=300,129 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg?resize=768,330 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg?resize=680,293 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg?resize=1536,661 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cmubd.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2245095" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> CMU/Boston Dynamics</p></div></p>
<p>First up is Matthew Johnson-Roberson, who recently became the director of CMU’s Robotics’ Institute. Johnson-Roberson served as co-director for the University of Michigan’s Ford Center for Autonomous Vehicles and co-founder of Refraction AI &#8212; which is to say, it’s not surprising that he offers some insight into how things will look for the autonomous driving industry.</p>
<p><strong>What was the defining robotics/AI/automation trend of 2021?</strong> I’m seeing increasing trends in application-specific AI companies (computer vision tasks, robotics devices to solve a problem, chat bots for x, etc.). Those seem poised to continue as the market looks for good fits for increasingly powerful algorithms.</p>
<p><strong>What will 2022 bring for these categories?</strong> In the coming year, I expect more of the large self-driving companies to continue their consolidation and more to go public as they prepare to burn capital attempting to expand and serve customers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This week we also spoke to Rob Playter, the longtime Boston Dynamics executive who was appointed CEO early last year.</p>
<p><strong>What was the defining robotics/AI/automation trend of 2021?</strong> Legged robots coming of age. 2021 saw the introduction of multiple legged robots to the market. Quadrupeds are leaving the lab and entering the workplace, and the ongoing labor shortages plaguing many industries has only intensified the need. We&#8217;ve seen strong interest for Spot around industrial use cases where mobile robots can navigate worksites that include stairs, doors and other obstacles that would foil wheeled or tracked robots. Our customers are using Spot as a dynamic sensing platform to collect reliable, repeatable data around their sites for tasks like thermal anomaly detection in industrial manufacturing, radiation mapping in nuclear facilities and digital twin modeling on construction sites. Products like Spot are proving they can add real value in the real world.</p>
<p><strong>What will 2022 bring for these categories?</strong> Operational adoption. In 2022 customers will begin deploying mobile robots like Spot at greater scale across their enterprises. We&#8217;ve seen tremendous uptake by industrial innovation teams exploring mobile robots for a wide variety of applications, and next year we expect to see customers integrating more robots into their asset management programs and day-to-day operations. But for industrial mobile robots to expand rapidly at enterprise scale, we also need to see greater reliability from the industry as a whole. We&#8217;ve seen a lot of products announced that are conceptual-only or that have only been deployed in small proof-of-concept exercises. As more and more businesses look to invest in real-world technology, the most reliable, robust and accessible products will prevail.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2195465" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2195465" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2195465" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg" alt="Nuro-Las Vegas fundraising round" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Nuro-Vegas_Announce-5.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2195465" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nuro</p></div></p>
<p>Few segments of this industry gained more traction over these past two years than delivery. Prior to the pandemic, much of the conversation around autonomous delivery centered around regulation and questions of demand. After the first several months of the pandemic brought much of the world to a standstill, leaving many afraid to venture outside the safety of their own homes, delivery services like Seamless and Uber Eats saw a sharp uptick in usage.</p>
<p>While stay-at-home orders have loosened in much of the world throughout 2021, myriad issues have continued to plague industries, leaving sharp demand for automation. These include widespread staffing shortages for food service and other blue-collar jobs, as well as global supply chain and shipping issues. That is to say that delivery issues aren’t just a matter of last- or middle-mile &#8212; it’s every segment here.</p>
<p>For those reasons (for starters, at least), it’s unsurprising that so much of this has been met with a massive uptick in investments across the board. As with so much of robotics, problems analysts expected companies would be tackling five or 10 years down the road are suddenly impossible to ignore.</p>
<p>Nuro led the way with one of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/02/nuro-lands-investment-from-google-tiger-global-in-new-600-million-round/">biggest robotics raises in recent memory</a>, led by (who else?) Tiger Global. The $600 million Series D, announced early last month, increased the company’s valuation north of 70%, to $8.6 billion. Integral to the deal is a new partnership with Google Cloud, which finds both parties pushing the service toward commercialization, as they “explore opportunities together to strengthen and transform local commerce.”</p>
<p>If you’ve spent any time near college campuses, there’s a decent chance you’ve seen delivery robots like Kiwibot out in the world. And while funding &#8212; and, in Nuro’s case, production &#8212; is ramping up, you’re almost certainly getting a majority of packages delivered to you by human beings at this point.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2241938" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2241938" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2241938" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg" alt="The Coco One sidewalk delivery robot powered by Segway on the Palisades" width="1024" height="819" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg 4653w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg?resize=150,120 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg?resize=300,240 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg?resize=768,614 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg?resize=680,544 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg?resize=1536,1229 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg?resize=2048,1638 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/COCO1-Palisades01.jpg?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2241938" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Coco</p></div></p>
<p>Speaking of campuses, UCLA spinout Coco saw a decent size round early this year with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/last-mile-robotic-delivery-firm-coco-raises-36m/">a $36 million raise</a>, bringing the company’s funding up to $43 million. Co-founder and CEO Zach Rash insisted that the time is now for such delivery technologies, noting in a release, “I strongly believe the delivery service industry in its current state is massively under-serving merchants. We have an enormous opportunity to create a better experience for hundreds of thousands of merchants and their customers, today. This is not a research program experimenting with technology to be productized at some unknown point in the future.”</p>
<p>The firm, formerly known as Cyan Robotics, doesn’t have a high-profile partner like Nuro’s Domino’s deal, thought it does list 18 partners, largely in the Los Angeles area. It’s currently operating deliveries in Santa Monica and five other LA areas. So, while it’s true that robotic deliveries are currently more the exception than the rule, if you order food in the right place at the right time, it just might be a robot on the other end.</p>
<p>This week, the company also announced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/segway-makes-its-first-foray-into-sidewalk-robot-delivery-with-coco-partnership/">a manufacturing deal with Segway</a>. The latter&#8217;s VP of global business development, Tony Ho, tells TechCrunch:</p>
<blockquote><p>This is just the beginning of our partnership. We will stay on the product side of things, and Coco will be the operators. So it’s a bit similar to the micromobility space where we provide the vehicles and hardware and they provide the relationship with the city and the staff and the whole operation behind it. Right now, we’re seeing this almost like it was with scooters in 2017, where the whole industry is booming. It’s a land grab.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2101054" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2101054" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2101054" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg" alt="Starship delivery robots" width="1024" height="654" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg 4200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg?resize=300,192 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg?resize=768,490 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg?resize=680,434 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg?resize=1536,981 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg?resize=2048,1308 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/StarshipRobotsUCLA1.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2101054" class="wp-caption-text">Starship delivery robots at UCLA campus on January 15th, 2021. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Starship/Copyright Don Liebig/ASUCLA</p></div></p>
<p>Starship, meanwhile, kicked off the year with a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/starship-technologies-raises-17m-to-roll-out-more-delivery-bots/">healthy $17 million raise</a>. The company is among those robotic delivery services focused on getting food to campuses, announcing plans to expand from 15 universities to 100.</p>
<p>Autonomous trucking had a great year, as well, citing similar concerns around staffing shortages. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/self-driving-truck-startup-kodiak-robotics-raises-125m/">Kodiak Robotics raised a $125 million Series B</a>, with plans to double its headcount, while Swedish firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/autonomous-trucking-startup-einride-raises-110m-ahead-of-expansion-into-united-states/">Einride drummed up $110 million</a>, with plans to expand into the U.S.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2119707" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2119707" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2119707" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Serve-meets-dog.jpg" alt="Serve Robotics Uber Postmates" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Serve-meets-dog.jpg 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Serve-meets-dog.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Serve-meets-dog.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Serve-meets-dog.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Serve-meets-dog.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Serve-meets-dog.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2119707" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Serve Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>And as we transition into the robotics news of the week, here’s yet another delivery raise. The $13 million Series A comes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/uber-spinout-serve-robotics-gets-13m-seed-round-to-expand-sidewalk-robot-deliveries/">courtesy of Serve Robotics</a>, which spun out from Uber’s Postmates earlier this year. “Our goal is to put robots in every major U.S. city in the next two to three years,” co-founder Ali Kashani said of the company’s grand ambitions.</p>
<p>7-Eleven’s investment wing, 7-Ventures, was involved in the round. The convenience store giant is especially bullish about robotics deliveries these days, having piloted with Nuro, among others. Delivery Hero, which also participated in the round, has worked with Starship previously.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2244494" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2244494" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2244494" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Recording-2021-12-07-at-4.23.01-PM.2021-12-07-16_24_45.gif" alt="" width="600" height="509" /><p id="caption-attachment-2244494" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Petra</p></div></p>
<p>Next, we move underground, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/petra-emerges-from-stealth-with-30m-raised-for-tunnel-boring-robot-swifty/">Petra emerges from stealth</a> to announce a $30 million Series A. The company uses thermal technology to bore tunnels into some of the strongest rock on Earth. To demonstrate this feat, the startup also announced that its robot, Swifty, successfully bored a 20-foot tunnel through Sioux Quartzite at a rate of one-inch-per-minute.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO Kim Abrams says:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’ve invented a completely new way to excavate rock and this will have profound implications on the future of tunneling. By delivering a boring solution that affordably undergrounds utilities through high-grade rock, we can finally protect communities from exposure to wildfires and ensure the safety of critical infrastructure in disaster-prone areas, especially in places like the Sierra Nevada mountains, Rocky Mountains, and coastal regions.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2245101" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245101" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2245101" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/yt1s.com-Robots-that-Evolve-like-Animals.2021-12-08-16_12_39.gif" alt="" width="640" height="360" /><p id="caption-attachment-2245101" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MIT CSAIL</p></div></p>
<p>A <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2021/system-designing-training-intelligent-soft-robots-1207" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fun bit of research from MIT CSAIL</a> to close us out this week. The lab unveiled “Evolution Gym,” a testing simulator for soft robotic designs. It’s still a simulation, of course, but it offers some interesting insights into how compliant robots can adapt to different environmental challenges.</p>
<p>CSAIL notes, “The result looks like a little robot Olympics. In addition to standard tasks like walking and jumping, the researchers also included some unique tasks, like climbing, flipping, balancing, and stair-climbing.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2191371" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2191371" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2191371" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/actuator-blue.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2191371" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p><em>Actuator is now a newsletter! <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here</a> to get it delivered to your inbox.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/raise-and-deliver/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245088</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Netflix launches a website dedicated to news about renewals, exclusive interviews and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/netflix-launches-a-website-dedicated-to-news-about-renewals-exclusive-interviews-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/netflix-launches-a-website-dedicated-to-news-about-renewals-exclusive-interviews-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 18:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netflix has launched a new website called &#8220;Tudum,&#8221; which will host consumer news about renewals, release dates and extra content featuring its TV shows and movies. The company is marketing the website as &#8220;a place to discover more about your Netflix favorites.&#8221; For a more curated experience, users can log into the website with their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Netflix has launched a <a href="http://www.netflix.com/tudum">new website</a> called &#8220;Tudum,&#8221; which will host consumer news about renewals, release dates and extra content featuring its TV shows and movies. The company is marketing the website as &#8220;a place to discover more about your Netflix favorites.&#8221; For a more curated experience, users can log into the website with their Netflix account. Netflix says the website is still currently in its early days, as it plans to continue to build it out and add new features in the future.</p>
<p>Tudum will feature extra content and information about Netflix&#8217;s TV shows and movies. For example, Netflix notes that users will be able to dig deeper into its content and use the website to find out things like where else they&#8217;ve seen the cast of &#8220;The Witcher&#8221; and whether &#8220;Maid&#8221; is based on a true story. The website includes exclusive interviews, cast breakdowns, information about content that&#8217;s popular on the platform, a trending news section, details about upcoming shows, an explore section and more.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Say hello to Tudum — a backstage pass that lets you dig deeper into the Netflix films, series, and stars you love! It’s still early days but you can expect exclusive interviews, behind-the-scenes videos, bonus features, and more. Check it out <a href="https://t.co/sYnbZ6pTzF">https://t.co/sYnbZ6pTzF</a> <a href="https://t.co/WtCCAF3B9u">pic.twitter.com/WtCCAF3B9u</a></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245575" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&mdash; Netflix (@netflix) <a href="https://twitter.com/netflix/status/1468988824588013569?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Tudum, which is named after the sound users hear when they press play on Netflix, is also the name of Netflix&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/netflix-sets-tudum-its-first-ever-virtual-global-fan-event-for-september-25/">global virtual fan</a> event that took place in September. The event included exclusive first looks and panels with stars from some of Netflix&#8217;s most popular titles. It featured conversations with the creators and stars of some of Netflix’s most popular shows, including “Stranger Things,” “Emily in Paris,” “The Witcher,” “The Crown,” “Cobra Kai” and “Bridgerton.”</p>
<p>The streaming giant&#8217;s chief marketing officer, Bozoma Saint John, announced the launch of the new website in a <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/meet-tudum-your-backstage-pass-to-the-netflix-stories-you-love">blog post</a>, stating that Netflix is &#8220;e<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">xcited to introduce Tudum for fans to dive deeper into the stories they love, fuel their obsessions and start new conversations. It’s still early days, and our launch today is just the beginning.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The new website is now accessible around the globe but is currently only available in English. It&#8217;s unknown if Netflix plans to launch the website in more languages.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/netflix-launches-a-website-dedicated-to-news-about-renewals-exclusive-interviews-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245575</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gift Guide: The best business books for 2021 recommended by VCs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/gift-guide-the-best-business-books-for-2021-recommended-by-vcs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/gift-guide-the-best-business-books-for-2021-recommended-by-vcs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 18:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gift guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gift Guide 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to part two of our venture capital-recommended book gift guide for 2021 – talking about books that do have a business theme.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome to part two of our venture capital-recommended book gift guide for 2021!</p>
<p>Yesterday we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/gift-guide-the-best-non-business-books-for-2021-recommended-by-vcs/">tackled <em>non</em>-business books</a> recommended by a raft of venture capitalists. Today we’re flipping it around and talking about books with a business theme. There were a few titles that straddled the gap, so if any of the below strike you as a modest stretch regarding how <em>businessy</em> they are, well, we hear you.</p>
<p>Regardless, keep in mind that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/">The Exchange</a> is paywall-free today again, as we’re huge book fans and wanted to keep this as accessible as possible. Oh, and <a href="https://twitter.com/abracarioca">Anna</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> will be dropping their personal recs in this weekend&#8217;s Exchange newsletter, which lots of you already receive on Saturdays, but you can <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">get here</a> if you’d like.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245444" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>A big thanks to the dozens of venture capitalists who contributed ideas to these posts, and double points to those who didn’t have an assistant handle their emailing! Oh, and we only had two books recommended by the people who wrote them, which was a lower ratio than we anticipated. Good job!</p>
<p><em>This article contains links to affiliate partners where available. When you buy through these links, TechCrunch may earn an affiliate commission.</em></p>
<h2>The most VC recommended business books of 2021</h2>
<h3><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0578895064/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0578895064&amp;linkId=d72435cad3966935830861b00591a071">The Qualified Sales Leader: Proven Lessons from a Five-Time CRO</a>, by John McMahon</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245520" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Qualified-Sales-Leader.jpg?w=438" alt="" width="438" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Qualified-Sales-Leader.jpg 509w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Qualified-Sales-Leader.jpg?resize=97,150 97w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Qualified-Sales-Leader.jpg?resize=193,300 193w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Qualified-Sales-Leader.jpg?resize=438,680 438w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Qualified-Sales-Leader.jpg?resize=32,50 32w" sizes="(max-width: 438px) 100vw, 438px" /></p>
<p>Recommended by Venrock&#8217;s <a href="https://twitter.com/vcsurferdad">Brian Ascher</a>, who said he&#8217;s &#8220;given this to many of my portfolio CEO and CROs,&#8221; as well as by <a href="https://twitter.com/chsrbrts">Chase Roberts</a>, principal at Vertex Ventures, via <a href="https://twitter.com/tessachen">Tessa Chen</a>: &#8220;Most founders that raise capital are looking to grow and scale their sales teams. They have to hire their first sales leaders, but many don&#8217;t know where to start, especially in enterprise SaaS. Chase has been sending this book rec to a few of our founders for practical tips on creating a sales motion from the ground up.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h3><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1635576059/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1635576059&amp;linkId=2b73972801d5d2d12e4b653996a529d9">This Is How They Tell Me the World Ends: The Cyberweapons Arms Race</a>, by Nicole Perlroth</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245521" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/This-is-how-they-tell-me.jpg?w=443" alt="" width="443" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/This-is-how-they-tell-me.jpg 517w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/This-is-how-they-tell-me.jpg?resize=98,150 98w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/This-is-how-they-tell-me.jpg?resize=196,300 196w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/This-is-how-they-tell-me.jpg?resize=443,680 443w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/This-is-how-they-tell-me.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 443px) 100vw, 443px" /></p>
<p>Recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/vc">Jake Chapman</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/zachcoelius">Zach Coelius</a>, this book carries blurbs from Kara Swisher and Nick Bilton, so it appears to be one that crosses the technology-media divide that we occasionally have to treat like a DMZ. The gist is that the market for zero-day cyber weapons is not what it once was. In the old days, the United States controlled the arsenal. At great expense, but who cares. Then it lost control of the zero-day world. And what comes next, people say, is staggering.</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/152473165X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=152473165X&amp;linkId=579eafaaac72a8e8debd6dd9a2b5d641">Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup</a>, by John Carreyrou</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245523" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bad-Blood.jpg?w=450" alt="" width="450" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bad-Blood.jpg 524w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bad-Blood.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bad-Blood.jpg?resize=198,300 198w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bad-Blood.jpg?resize=450,680 450w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bad-Blood.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>Daisy Garcia at <a href="https://twitter.com/JetBlueVentures">JetBlue Ventures</a> recommended it alongside Reeves Wiedeman&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Billion-Dollar-Loser-Spectacular-Neumann/dp/0316461369">Billion Dollar Loser: The Epic Rise and Spectacular Fall of Adam Neumann and WeWork</a>,&#8221; describing both books as &#8220;good reminders to invest in what you know and also fun.” Alex and Anna both read &#8220;Bad Blood,&#8221; and from our desks, this book is the rare must-read in the business book pantheon. You must read it to understand how far things can go off the startup rails, and, frankly, learn a hell of a lot about the world of business.</p>
<h2>Recommendations we’d like to read next</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062960679/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0062960679&amp;linkId=06b70681767324f114223b391894af2b">An Ugly Truth: Inside Facebook&#8217;s Battle for Domination</a>, by Cecilia Kang and Sheera Frenkel, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/amyecheetham">Amy Cheetham</a></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245524" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/An-Ugly-Truth.jpg?w=446" alt="" width="446" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/An-Ugly-Truth.jpg 520w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/An-Ugly-Truth.jpg?resize=98,150 98w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/An-Ugly-Truth.jpg?resize=197,300 197w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/An-Ugly-Truth.jpg?resize=446,680 446w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/An-Ugly-Truth.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 446px) 100vw, 446px" /></p>
<p>Next year, we’ll add a section for books that we bought and have on our shelves but have yet to start. &#8220;An Ugly Truth&#8221; is one such book. Alex bought a copy when it came out, and has been promising himself since that he will stop reading fiction and get around to it. So far, so bad, but it’s still a book that feels like a mandatory read.</p>
<p>Why? Because Facebook is hardly giving up on its long-term goals. The company is shifting its growth model somewhat, but has hardly gone through a DNA-level change regarding how it considers its political setup (one owner, led by the blind) or operational goals (all your eyes are belong to us). We should take this one off the shelf and read it. You, too.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1529038340/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1529038340&amp;linkId=056289531facaf7a71eb3c69e0dec0bf">Radical Candor: How to Get What You Want by Saying What You Mean</a> by Kim Scott, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/tamarasteffens">Tamara Steffens</a></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245525" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Radical-Candor.jpg?w=463" alt="" width="463" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Radical-Candor.jpg 535w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Radical-Candor.jpg?resize=102,150 102w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Radical-Candor.jpg?resize=204,300 204w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Radical-Candor.jpg?resize=463,680 463w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Radical-Candor.jpg?resize=34,50 34w" sizes="(max-width: 463px) 100vw, 463px" /></p>
<p>This one has been on Anna&#8217;s reading list ever since she listened to the &#8220;<a href="https://www.radicalcandor.com/candor-podcast/">Radical Candor&#8221; podcast</a>, which distills the book&#8217;s ideas in a conversational format. But whatever medium you choose, make sure you don&#8217;t stop at the title, or you might misunderstand the message. Being radically candid is not about being brutal; it is a form of kindness, because honesty beats niceness.</p>
<p>This could apply to many areas in life, but this is definitely business content, and especially relevant to the startup and tech world. Author Kim Scott is a former Apple and Google executive, and knows a thing or two about leadership &#8212; we are not surprised that VCs are reading. &#8220;The book provides great guidance on delivering effective feedback—whether it’s positive or negative,&#8221; Steffens noted. &#8220;It has helped me recommit to passing quickly when I’m not convinced of the opportunity—and to deliver that message clearly, so there’s no room for confusion.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0385545681/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0385545681&amp;linkId=f2789220bd5c888dbc08c8e9c0a16b72">Empire of Pain: The Secret History of the Sackler Dynasty</a>, by Patrick Radden Keefe, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/amyecheetham">Amy Cheetham</a></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245526" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Empire-of-Pain.jpg?w=447" alt="" width="447" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Empire-of-Pain.jpg 519w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Empire-of-Pain.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Empire-of-Pain.jpg?resize=197,300 197w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Empire-of-Pain.jpg?resize=447,680 447w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Empire-of-Pain.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 447px) 100vw, 447px" /></p>
<p>Maximizing value creation for shareholders is, at times, not a very good idea. That’s because the cost of doing so in particular situations creates such heavy societal burdens that it’s a clear net-negative for humanity. A few examples that come to mind include the oil industry hiding its knowledge of global warming for decades, the tobacco industry fighting the obvious truth that smoking is cancerous, and the recent lobbying efforts by alcohol companies to combat cannabis legalization. The impact of those actions was unchecked carbon emissions, lots of cancer deaths, and <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2021/07/america-drinking-alone-problem/619017/">miserable rates of alcoholism</a>.</p>
<p>And then there are the Sacklers. Not that we want to diminish the impact of the above shareholder-value-creating actions, but the Sacklers might have them beat. If you’re not aware, the Sackler dynasty helped foment an opioid addiction epidemic, recycling some of their ill-gotten gains into charitable donations – the standard billionaire method of hiding the source of their wealth with some media-friendly wrapping paper. We want to read this book to better understand just how things went so wrong, for so long.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1510768610/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1510768610&amp;linkId=8a81e544d83865e86e72f394f77c2cff">The Aristocracy of Talent: How Meritocracy Made the Modern World</a> by Adrian Wooldridge, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/mr_james_c">James Clark</a>   </strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245527" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aristocracy-of-Talent.jpg?w=452" alt="" width="452" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aristocracy-of-Talent.jpg 530w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aristocracy-of-Talent.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aristocracy-of-Talent.jpg?resize=199,300 199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aristocracy-of-Talent.jpg?resize=452,680 452w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aristocracy-of-Talent.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 452px) 100vw, 452px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;The Aristocracy of Talent&#8221; comes with a recommendation from Molten&#8217;s James Clark, but also with a blurb from one of Anna&#8217;s favorite thinkers, <a href="https://twitter.com/sapinker">Steven Pinker</a>. Here&#8217;s what he wrote about Adrian Wooldridge&#8217;s latest book: &#8220;This unique and fascinating history explains why the blame now being piled upon meritocracy is misplaced — and that assigning responsibilities to the people best able to discharge them really is better than the time-honored customs of corruption, patronage, nepotism, and hereditary castes. Wooldridge upends many common assumptions and provides an indispensable back story to this fraught and pressing issue.&#8221;</p>
<p>We are all for upending assumptions here, especially when the topic is so frequently brought up in our tiny bubble – and we are curious to read more.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062886142/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0062886142&amp;linkId=6c97713d571473b91180999b1cb4e5b5">The Infinite Machine</a>, by Camila Russo, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/jennylefcourt">Jenny Lefcourt</a></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245528" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Infinite-Machine.jpg?w=449" alt="" width="449" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Infinite-Machine.jpg 524w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Infinite-Machine.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Infinite-Machine.jpg?resize=198,300 198w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Infinite-Machine.jpg?resize=449,680 449w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Infinite-Machine.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 449px) 100vw, 449px" /></p>
<p>So there’s this idea in the market that the blockchain world is akin to a new internet. There are some issues with the idea, chiefly that blockchain tech runs on the internet, making it at most a layer-two effort for the web. Still, the concept that what today’s hackers are building will tear up the past and rewrite the future is strong.</p>
<p>Enter &#8220;The Infinite Machine,&#8221; which digs into the Ethereum blockchain, which some compare to an infinite computer or machine. We have our questions. For example, how did the Web3 kids manage to build a computer that costs so much money to simply access? Snark aside, it’s worth taking the time to understand precisely why some folks are so rabidly bullish about the crypto market. They might be right!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1982144432/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1982144432&amp;linkId=78de30365eb5bab8adf91ad920b54e89">The Wires of War: Technology and the Global Struggle for Power</a> by Jacob Helberg, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/vc">Jake Chapman</a>  </strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="vertical aligncenter size-large wp-image-2245529" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Wires-of-War.jpg?w=448" alt="" width="448" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Wires-of-War.jpg 521w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Wires-of-War.jpg?resize=99,150 99w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Wires-of-War.jpg?resize=198,300 198w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Wires-of-War.jpg?resize=448,680 448w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Wires-of-War.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 448px) 100vw, 448px" /></p>
<p>You may have heard about this book on TechCrunch: Our colleague Connie Loizos <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/were-now-very-much-at-war-with-china-argues-a-provocative-new-book">interviewed its author </a>a couple of months ago. Their conversation covered key themes of the book &#8212; Silicon Valley, China, Russia &#8212; and made us keen to find out more, though not particularly reassured. From Connie: &#8220;Helberg lays out how China’s &#8216;techno-totalitarian&#8217; regime may be first impacting the Chinese people (its &#8216;first victims,&#8217; he says), but why its efforts to increasingly control the software and the hardware of the internet are a real and present and fast-escalating danger to the U.S. and democracies everywhere.&#8221; Having written quite a bit about China in 2021, and being aware that it will likely play some part in 2022, this makes a great candidate from our reading list.</p>
<h2>Other recommended business books</h2>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0593237064/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0593237064&amp;linkId=ea23c973439d89cdd916f5c1609c01c0">All We Can Save: Truth, Courage, and Solutions for the Climate Crisis,</a> edited by Ayana Elizabeth Johnson and Katharine K. Wilkinson, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/evdillon">Ted Dillon</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0525573925/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0525573925&amp;linkId=cc84d06a2b220411d913cbfb53c2e5fc">Alpha Girls: The Women Upstarts Who Took On Silicon Valley&#8217;s Male Culture and Made the Deals of a Lifetime</a> by Julian Guthrie, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/JetBlueVentures">Daisy Garcia</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/047170637X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=047170637X&amp;linkId=c22ae43665f6c7fe0aa8a7728b5db0db">Cable Cowboy: John Malone and the Rise of the Modern Cable Business</a> by Mark Robichaux, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/vivekramaswami">Vivek Ramaswami</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062913689/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0062913689&amp;linkId=3d955b1a3ada528d43a972050d4a69b3">Disunited Nations: The Scramble for Power in an Ungoverned World</a> by Peter Zeihan, recommended by <a href="https://www.sandscapital.com/people/frank-m-sands-cfa/">Frank Sands</a>. Sands told TechCrunch that as the world changes rapidly, “geography and demographics explain a lot about the past. They also can predict a lot about the future. Understanding both is a critical part of successful investing.”</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0385532318/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0385532318&amp;linkId=e29e3c1304ffdba12fd7c14e30dd7e87">Gandhi: The Years That Changed The World, 1914-1948</a> by Ramachandra Guha, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/vivekramaswami">Vivek Ramaswami</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1612197493/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1612197493&amp;linkId=ea55a03a9586c187d127682d444e266a">How To Do Nothing: Resisting the Attention Economy</a> by Jenny Odell, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/MoniqueVilla">Monique Villa</a>. Villa noted that as “VCs, founders, and tech talent discover new cities to call home and build companies,” this book “challenges our pre-COVID definitions of place and how we interact with our surroundings.”</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1587991381/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1587991381&amp;linkId=1e19e2252f1ebf0e4201f1970d0c3cdc">Investing: The Last Liberal Art</a> by Roberg G. Hagstrom, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/dorirad">Irad Dor</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1119457254/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1119457254&amp;linkId=18e4c39209e4115b29686ca2a0873c77">Leading Clarity: The Breakthrough Strategy to Unleash People, Profit, and Performance</a> by Brad Deutser, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/texasvc">Aziz Gilani</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/154451980X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=154451980X&amp;linkId=205d5461439bcb714eb7e7475edf9827">Levers: The Framework for Building Repeatability into Your Business</a> by Amos Schwartzfarb and Trevor Boehm, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/texasvc">Aziz Gilani</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1984854631/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1984854631&amp;linkId=1dd8bfcaa8c3e2f669ebb899b4780ee1">Mindf*ck: Cambridge Analytica and the Plot to Break America</a> by Christopher Wylie, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/ACME">Scott Stanford</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0241435315/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0241435315&amp;linkId=9f0fd3953db9c729331f01906aa0f315">Mission Economy: A Moonshot Guide to Changing Capitalism</a> by Mariana Mazzucato, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/reedsturtevant">Reed Sturtevant</a>. A bit surprising to get a recommendation of a book that deals with societal goals, but Sturtevant said that the book helped him “think about how the public sector can bring intention and directionality to technology innovation by ‘tilting the playing field.’” He went on to explain that the author “works to define a framing of intent that is neither too broad nor too narrow and that is centered around outcomes.”</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143119419/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0143119419&amp;linkId=aaec7706625cb64147d13e88f57bb362">More Money Than God: Hedge Funds and the Making of a New Elite</a> by Sebastian Mallaby, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/texasvc">Aziz Gilani</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1400223296/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1400223296&amp;linkId=9d8f3f6884cee80981e03d29291d5bfa">R.E.D. Marketing: The Three Ingredients of Leading Brands</a> by Ken Muench, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/kipknight">Kip Knight</a>. Knight told TechCrunch that this is one of his favorite books.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1541619625/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1541619625&amp;linkId=0975752bb11ae11186a850e0e88f71da">Right Within: How to Heal from Racial Trauma in the Workplace</a> by Minda Harts, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/lolitataub">Lolita Taub</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1541768426/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1541768426&amp;linkId=f1e6631a7be28ab5aeb2b3d3162f0678">Super Founders: What Data Reveals About Billion-Dollar Startups</a> by Ali Tamaseb, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/alitamaseb?lang=en">Ali Tamaseb</a>. This title is one of two self-recommendations, but we suppose it’s fine to talk one’s own, ahem, book.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0804136718/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0804136718&amp;linkId=738d1c69f2c30dffde273d404c34d851">Superforecasting: The Art and Science of Prediction</a> by Dan Gardner and Philip E. Tetlock, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/JetBlueVentures">Daisy Garcia</a>. Garcia calls the book “informative,” adding that “we are all forecasters in work and life” in that “everyone tries to invest in things before they trend.”</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062969749/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0062969749&amp;linkId=da06df590ab6f89997d6ae2cfadc894b">The Cold Start Problem: How to Start and Scale Network Effects</a> by Andrew Chen, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/andrewchen">Andrew Chen</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/skelly_1">Shannon Kelly</a>. Our second self-recommendation. Alex has a copy of this that he started, but is still stuck somewhere in the opening Uber recollections.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0884271951/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0884271951&amp;linkId=e6b171cd08285b1df837ad055b35824f">The Goal</a> by Eliyahu Goldratt and Jeff Cox, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/rachel_a_star">Rachel Star</a>. Star told TechCrunch via email that this is her favorite book, adding that she first read for an engineering class and re-reads it yearly.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/8126563877/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=8126563877&amp;linkId=3a1fab20485a62afe5a3b0888d26fc8f">The Ideal Team Player</a> by Patrick Lencioni, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/evdillon">Ted Dillon</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1471138801/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1471138801&amp;linkId=5d49bb439e6b0629494bf7ec406b282a">The Innovators: How a Group of Hackers, Geniuses and Geeks Created the Digital Revolution</a> by Walter Isaacson, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/vivekramaswami">Vivek Ramaswami</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062996215/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0062996215&amp;linkId=7d9172042cac6876329cedcdf82877f6">The Key Man: The True Story of How the Global Elite Was Duped by a Capitalist Fairy Tale</a> by Simon Clark and Will Louch, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/texasvc">Aziz Gilani</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031653353X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=031653353X&amp;linkId=2569a4c99cf2f70bd2c6f768d4d62792">The Kill Chain: Defending America in the Future of High-Tech Warfare</a> by Christian Brose, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/bhadrasandeep">Sandeep Bhadra</a>. We like this recommendation because we agree with Bhadra that “cybersecurity is increasingly becoming the strategic battlefield in geopolitics.”</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1422121038/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1422121038&amp;linkId=d89bf50208ff0c5d1b0be60b5aacb62f">The Origin of Wealth: The Radical Remaking of Economics and What it Means for Business and Society</a> by Eric D. Beinhocker, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/seandougfan">Sean Fanning</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1422162672/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1422162672&amp;linkId=219e90cac93cb3cfe8462ec1af02591e">The Outsiders: Eight Unconventional CEOs and Their Radically Rational Blueprint for Success</a> by William N. Thorndike, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/bernovick">Bernardo Novick</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0857197681/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0857197681&amp;linkId=57e0613bda37ae4a6440f41b0fb93129">The Psychology of Money: Timeless Lessons on Wealth, Greed, and Happiness</a> by Morgan Housel, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/lolitataub">Lolita Taub</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0399592091/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0399592091&amp;linkId=9e43cfb92356e3c7f02eb9870c1ba480">The Ride of a Lifetime: Lessons Learned from 15 Years as CEO of the Walt Disney Company</a> by Robert Iger, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/vivekramaswami">Vivek Ramaswami</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735216355/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0735216355&amp;linkId=45fcea7bbcffda852655a51473939c03">Thinking in Bets: Making Smarter Decisions When You Don&#8217;t Have All the Facts</a> by Annie Duke, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/CitiVentures">Arvind Purushotham</a>. We’re surprised that more poker books didn’t make the list. But Purushotham brought one to us, so we made sure to include it. Per the investor, the book, written by “World Series of Poker champion-turned-business consultant Annie Duke, explains why it’s essential to embrace uncertainty when we make decisions.” That may seem counterintuitive, but as Purushotham noted, “whether you’re deciding which company to invest in, which product to build, or which growth strategy to follow, the key to placing the best bets is accurately assessing what you do and don’t know, and accepting that great decisions don’t always lead to great outcomes—because luck always has a hand to play.”</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/067943822X/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=067943822X&amp;linkId=f773edad3063b025f9e53b0ddc29c543">Walt Disney: The Triumph of the American Imagination</a> by Neal Gabler, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/openviewventure">Blake Bartlett</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B099G5HZDM/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B099G5HZDM&amp;linkId=aadf73d4adeac8bf73eb72318561ba04">What Great Salespeople Do: The Science of Selling Through Emotional Connection and the Power of Story</a> by Michael T. Bosworth and Ben Zoldan, recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/AstasiaMyers">Astasia Myers</a>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1250297192/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=tcgiftguide21-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=1250297192&amp;linkId=d0284aa14a26f065239f9823cbff44ec">You&#8217;re Not Listening: What You&#8217;re Missing and Why It Matters</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> by Kate Murphy, recommended by </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://twitter.com/CitiVentures">Vanessa Colella</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. Colella provided a somewhat longer-than-usual explanation for this title, which we’re including in its entirety:</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>“At Citi Ventures, we like to say that &#8216;culture is the backbone of innovation,&#8217; and as Citi’s Leadership Principles make clear, a culture of innovation begins with creating space for everyone’s insights and ideas to be shared and heard. That, in turn, starts with listening. The best-selling book &#8216;You’re Not Listening&#8217; describes how difficult true listening is, despite — or perhaps because of — our constant access to digital communication channels and engagement opportunities. The book provides an important road map for reversing this trend and can help build a strong foundation for driving empathy, innovation, and transformation at Citi.”</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/gift-guide-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/gift-guide-2021-banner.jpg" alt="TechCrunch Gift Guide 2021" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/gift-guide-the-best-business-books-for-2021-recommended-by-vcs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245444</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ledger to launch crypto debit card</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/ledger-to-launch-crypto-debit-card/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/ledger-to-launch-crypto-debit-card/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 18:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ledger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ledger Wallet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ledger is the latest crypto company working on a debit card that connects directly with a crypto wallet. The company unveiled plans to launch its own debit card called the Crypto Life card at its Ledger Op3n conference. While Ledger is better known for its hardware wallets, the company has been working hard on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.ledger.com">Ledger</a> is the latest crypto company working on a debit card that connects directly with a crypto wallet. The company unveiled plans to launch its own debit card called the Crypto Life card at its Ledger Op3n conference.</p>
<p>While Ledger is better known for its hardware wallets, the company has been working hard on the software part called <a href="https://www.ledger.com/ledger-live">Ledger Live</a>. From the Ledger Live app on desktop and mobile, users are not limited to sending and receiving crypto assets.</p>
<p>They can also buy and sell crypto assets with integrations with third-party companies. Ledger Live also supports staking and swaps through various partners, such as Changelly, Wyre, ParaSwap and 1inch. Everything remains integrated with the hardware wallet for transaction confirmations.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245586" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Ledger’s debit card has been designed with <a href="https://baanx.com">Baanx</a> and will be available in the U.K., France and Germany at some point during the first quarter of 2022. People based in the U.S. will be able to get a card in Q2 2022.</p>
<p>After receiving your card, you’ll be able to top it up from the Ledger Live app with BTC, ETH, USDT, EURT, USDC, XRP, BXX, BCH or LTC. When you use your card for a transaction, cryptocurrencies are instantly converted to the fiat amount at the time of purchase.</p>
<p>Cardholders will also be able to receive their paychecks into their card account directly. They’ll be able to convert a percentage of their paycheck into BTC and ETH every time they get paid.</p>
<p>Finally, Ledger users who want to keep most of their wealth in crypto assets will be able to open a line of credit to get cash on the card. For that feature, you have to deposit a certain cryptocurrency amount as collateral.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>DeFi lending protocols are usually overcollateralized, which means that users have to borrow less than what they have in their crypto wallet. So it’s going to be interesting to see how the Ledger credit feature works when it ships.</p>
<p>Ledger will compete with debit cards from Coinbase, Bitpanda, Binance, Crypto.com, etc. But if you’re already using Ledger products, having a card that integrates well with the Ledger ecosystem could be particularly important when choosing a debit card.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245597" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245597" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" class="size-full wp-image-2245597" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ledger_4.jpeg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2245597" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ledger</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/ledger-to-launch-crypto-debit-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245586</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Work-Bench report finds just 1.9% of venture investment going to female enterprise founders</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/work-bench-report-finds-just-1-9-of-venture-investment-going-to-female-enterprise-founders/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/work-bench-report-finds-just-1-9-of-venture-investment-going-to-female-enterprise-founders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 18:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jessica Lin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work-Bench]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new report from early-stage venture capital firm Work-Bench confirmed what you probably already know: Startups with women founders are getting a mere sliver of the overall funding pie. What&#8217;s more, the percentages are far worse in the enterprise, where Work-Bench tends to invest. The numbers, which were based on Work-Bench research along with data from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A<a href="https://docsend.com/view/zi9kfxbsc36xx3sy"> new report</a> from early-stage venture capital firm <a href="https://www.work-bench.com/">Work-Bench</a> confirmed what you probably already know: Startups with women founders are getting a mere sliver of the overall funding pie. What&#8217;s more, the percentages are far worse in the enterprise, where Work-Bench tends to invest.</p>
<p>The numbers, which were based on Work-Bench research along with data from PitchBook and Crunchbase, showed over 25% of startups receiving funding included at least one female founder, but when you looked at just enterprise software companies, the number plunged to a dismal 1.9%.</p>
<p>The fact is that research has proven these numbers make little sense. As the report authors wrote, &#8220;research has shown that female-led teams generate 35% higher return on investment than all-male-led teams.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245511" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Yet the gap persists.</p>
<p>Jessica Lin, co-founder and general partner at Work-Bench, said that one of the motivations for starting her firm was the persistent lack of female representation at the corporate level, among startup founders and particularly at VC firms that control the purse strings.</p>
<p>The first step was to build a database of female founders, which she said the firm has been working on for the past four years and updates on a regular basis. They made this database <a href="https://t.co/kngN3YniD2">publicly available</a>. &#8220;I&#8217;ve always said behavior change also requires data,&#8221; Lin told me.</p>
<p>The impetus behind the report was to put that data to work, showing investors just how pronounced the problem is and tracking progress (or lack thereof) over time. And she especially wanted to focus on the enterprise, where her firm operates, because she said there was a distinct lack of data in that area.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;So this is the first time we&#8217;ve said, &#8216;Hey, why don&#8217;t we actually put it together [into a report]?&#8217; So I would love to tell you that maybe in a year from now we can see that sub-2% number has gotten to 3%. But we just had to have a baseline somewhere,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>While the number is small, there are some areas where women are more likely to be involved in funded startups. The biggest area by far was HR/future of work with 35.1%, followed by data/AI/machine learning with 19.8%, and sales and marketing with 12.2%.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245557" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245557" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2245557" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-12.35.44-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="Work-Bench female founders report. Pie chart breaks down their participation by sector." width="680" height="409" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-12.35.44-PM.jpg 1488w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-12.35.44-PM.jpg?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-12.35.44-PM.jpg?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-12.35.44-PM.jpg?resize=768,461 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-12.35.44-PM.jpg?resize=680,409 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-09-at-12.35.44-PM.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2245557" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Work-Bench</p></div></p>
<p>Women face a number of challenges. For starters, there is still a <a href="https://www.statista.com/chart/4467/female-employees-at-tech-companies/">lack of women in leadership roles</a> at major tech companies. If more women held jobs with higher salaries, they could not only act as mentors, but participate<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/31/one-womans-mission-to-build-a-network-of-female-and-non-binary-angel-investors/"> in angel rounds</a> that could help drive more women-led startups.</p>
<p>Idit Levine runs the startup <a href="http://solo.io">Solo.io</a>, a cloud-native software company that recently landed a $135 million Series C investment on a $1 billion valuation. As Levine <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/07/solo-io-reaches-1b-valuation-with-135m-series-c-investment/">told me at the time of her funding</a>, she&#8217;s frustrated by tokenism in the tech industry:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I never asked for anybody to give me this discount because I’m a woman. Actually, sometimes it has been irritating. Oh, we want to give you a talk because you’re a woman. It pissed me off. You need me to give a talk because I am damn good.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Yet many women lack her confidence. The <a href="https://thenewstack.io/pushing-back-how-women-in-tech-overcome-imposter-syndrome/">New Stack reported</a> on a recent panel at KubeCon, where a group of women talked about the obstacles they face as an underrepresented group in cloud-native technologies. Many of the panelists expressed a common feeling among underrepresented groups of imposter syndrome &#8212; feeling like they don&#8217;t belong even though they clearly have the skills and abilities.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/4-women-in-engineering-discuss-harassment-isolation-and-perseverence/">June TechCrunch article</a> on the experience of four women engineers in tech, Yury Roa, SRE technical program manager at ADL Digital Labs in Bogota, Colombia, told me that imposter syndrome can be a real impediment for women in tech:</p>
<blockquote><p>“One barrier for us related to being the only woman in the room is that [it can lead to] impostor syndrome because it is common when you are the only woman or one of few, it can be really challenging for us. So we need to gain confidence, and in these cases, it is very important to have role models and leadership that includes women,” Roa said.</p></blockquote>
<p>Work-Bench is a small firm trying to make a big impact by providing data to illustrate inequities in the system. As Lin noted, data can drive change, but it&#8217;s going to take a full-blown systemic shift to move these numbers. That&#8217;s going to require more women being promoted as executives and investing as angels and venture capitalists.</p>
<p>Only then can we truly move the needle. Because 1.9% is not good enough. Not by a long shot.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d6r10pcfhB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/4-women-in-engineering-discuss-harassment-isolation-and-perseverence/">4 women in engineering discuss harassment, isolation and perseverence</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 women in engineering discuss harassment, isolation and perseverence&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/4-women-in-engineering-discuss-harassment-isolation-and-perseverence/embed/#?secret=d6r10pcfhB" data-secret="d6r10pcfhB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/work-bench-report-finds-just-1-9-of-venture-investment-going-to-female-enterprise-founders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245511</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Resonance brings its space-scale manufacturing OS to hardware makers with $14M A round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/first-resonance-funding-spacex-manufacturing-software/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/first-resonance-funding-spacex-manufacturing-software/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 18:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Resonance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First Resonance makes software for making hardware. The company&#8217;s Ion platform provides an all-in-one option for anyone who has to manage manufacturing lines, supply chains, engineering and design, among other things. Now, with $14M in new funding, the company aims to scale up its presence and make a full-court press on the hardware makers of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.firstresonance.io/">First Resonance</a> makes software for making hardware. The company&#8217;s Ion platform provides an all-in-one option for anyone who has to manage manufacturing lines, supply chains, engineering and design, among other things. Now, with $14M in new funding, the company aims to scale up its presence and make a full-court press on the hardware makers of the world.</p>
<p>Founded by a team of former SpaceX engineers, First Resonance was created because they felt the processes they&#8217;d helped create at the launch provider would be helpful to people making everything from drones to toys to&#8230; other rockets.</p>
<p>When we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/founded-by-former-spacex-engineers-first-resonance-pitches-tools-to-make-things-the-spacex-way/">first covered them last summer</a>, the company was just getting started. Now it has built up momentum it hopes to keep as it targets more and bigger customers.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245540" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;In 2020, First Resonance was just getting its first customers. it was a year where manufacturers and people building hardware definitely needed something to connect their people working from home with the factory, and connect multiple types of factories — it just happens that the product we&#8217;re building here perfectly suits itself to that,&#8221; said co-founder and CEO Karan Talati.</p>
<p>With 15 customers at the end of 2020 and twice that now, the Ion platform has shown that it has value to people making serious hardware: Joby Aviation, Iron Ox, Astranis, and more.</p>
<p>&#8220;The complexity of managing not just how to build such a sophisticated product, but the complexity of the part assembly and the sophisticated multi-level BOM that goes into that&#8230; What Ion is doing is helping these companies define that complexity and understand it — with a level of granularity that lets them make rapid and iterative adjustments to their design and manufacturing process,&#8221; said Talati.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245583" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245583" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2245583" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png" alt="Screenshot of the Ion operating system." width="1024" height="640" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/ION-Factory-OS-Execution-of-Work-Instructions.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245583" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> First resonance</p></div></p>
<p>A key part of that is automated but powerful tracking of parts and processes, something that their team at SpaceX got very good at while working on launch vehicle reusability.</p>
<p>&#8220;The key difference between what SpaceX has done compared with everyone else is really understanding down to what serial number, what lot number were on a given rocket. They knew which parts were exposed to a certain condition or error,&#8221; explained Talati. &#8220;That&#8217;s the exact challenge our customers are facing. Automakers spend billions on recalls because they have to recall every vehicle. But Tesla recently did a recall of only 3,000 Model Ys, because they have that level of granularity.&#8221;</p>
<p>Early customers have found this capability extremely valuable and asked for more of it. Tracking a part from purchasing to receiving, installation, servicing and beyond creates not just opportunities for savings like Tesla&#8217;s, but a database that can be mined for insights.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/53x8aYoQ6N8?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Companies have been managing this stuff for a long time, but generally using half a dozen disconnected systems, some legacy and some cutting-edge. For instance, the design work may be happening in live AR collaboration sessions and saved to the cloud, then distributed via a modern productivity suite, but it&#8217;s all held back when it goes to a factory and parts workflow that&#8217;s been the same since the &#8217;90s. It was never great, but the pressures of 2020 and 2021 may have pushed some companies over the edge.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s this mess of generic tracking tools, email templates, spreadsheets and disconnected processes. Increasingly we have customers coming off these old systems, where they procured them a long time ago and now they&#8217;re looking into digital transformation,&#8221; said Talati.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245584" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245584" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2245584" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg" alt="Co-founders COO Neal Sarraf (left) and CEO Karan Talati." width="1024" height="663" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg?resize=300,194 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg?resize=768,497 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg?resize=680,440 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg?resize=1536,995 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg?resize=2048,1326 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/First-Resonance-Founders-Neal-and-Karan.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245584" class="wp-caption-text">Co-founders COO Neal Sarraf (left) and CEO Karan Talati.</p></div></p>
<p>Even larger, richer companies that could build their own brand-new stack are opting to go with Ion, he said, imitating other successful companies that choose to bolt on a market-ready process rather than spend a year and tens of millions designing their own.</p>
<p>The $14M A round was led by Craft Ventures, with participation from Blue Bear Capital, Fika Ventures, Stage VP, and Wavemaker. The money will go towards scaling and improving the company, particularly their &#8220;go to market team.&#8221; But the product is evolving too, with the team working on integrating more sources of data into intelligence streams that produce actionable insights within seconds of changes. And embracing more factories and hardware types with an expanded SDK is also on the horizon.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our customers are really embracing that flexible, data-driven approach, and Ion fits the bill,&#8221; said Talati.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/first-resonance-funding-spacex-manufacturing-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245540</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solid Power ramps up solid-state battery race with public market debut</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/solid-power-ramps-up-solid-state-battery-race-with-public-market-debut/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/solid-power-ramps-up-solid-state-battery-race-with-public-market-debut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 17:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicle batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QuantumScape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solid power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solid state batteries]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Solid Power, the solid-state battery developer backed by Ford and BMW, is hitting the public markets running with a spike in stock price shortly after trading opened Thursday. The company is one of a handful in the electric mobility space to have gone public via a merger with a blank-check firm. Solid Power announced the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Solid Power, the solid-state battery developer backed by Ford and BMW, is hitting the public markets running with a spike in stock price shortly after trading opened Thursday.</p>
<p>The company is one of a handful in the electric mobility space to have gone public via a merger with a blank-check firm. Solid Power announced the merger with special purpose acquisition company Decarbonization Plus Acquisition Corp III in June, at a post-deal implied market <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/bmw-and-ford-backed-solid-power-will-go-public-via-spac-merger-in-1-2b-deal/">valuation of $1.2 billion</a>.</p>
<p>The deal ultimately generated around $542.9 million to Solid Power, very near to the estimated $600 million due to the notably low number of redemptions prior to the shareholder vote. The cash includes $195 million PIPE and $347.9 million of cash held in trust.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245562" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>It’s funds that the company will need, as it seeks to commercialize the world’s first solid-state battery for electric vehicles. Solid-state batteries &#8212; so named because they use a solid, rather than liquid, electrolyte &#8212; are considered by many to be the next breakthrough in battery technology. Developers say they minimize the fire risks associated with conventional batteries by eliminating the flammable electrolyte, in addition to offering superior energy density, or battery range.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FcDIxVpUCv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/">Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can solid state batteries power up for the next generation of EVs?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/can-solid-state-batteries-power-up-for-the-next-generation-of-evs/embed/#?secret=FcDIxVpUCv" data-secret="FcDIxVpUCv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Solid Power has been hard at work, expanding its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/solid-power-expands-production-capacity-to-deliver-test-batteries-to-bmw-ford-in-2022/">Colorado factory footprint</a> as it prepares pilot production of its commercial-grade, 100 ampere battery cells in early 2022. Those cells will head to investors Ford and BMW for automotive testing. Solid Power plans to use the capital from the transaction to fund operations through vehicle integration, which the company anticipates will take place in 2026.</p>
<p>The company’s long-term business plan is not to become a large-scale battery producer, like industry giants LG Chem or SK Innovation. The ultimate aim is to license out the cells to OEMs and manufacturers. “Long term, we’re a materials company,” CEO Doug Campbell told TechCrunch earlier this year. “We want to be the industry leader in solid electrolyte materials.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Solid Power is not the only solid-state battery developer to go public via SPAC, nor is it the only one to have received investment from a big automaker. Indeed, it seems that the major automotive OEMs have been picking their horses in the solid-state race, with rival QuantumScape receiving backing from Volkswagen and Stellantis and Mercedes-Benz lining up their funds behind <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/30/stellantis-mercedes-benz-invest-in-solid-state-battery-developer-factorial-energy/">newer entrant Factorial Energy</a>.</p>
<p>QuantumScape completed its own SPAC deal in November 2020. Like other mobility SPACs, it saw its fair share of stock price volatility, with shares cresting as high as $114 in December before settling around $20-25. Whether Solid Power’s stocks will face similar tumult remains to be seen. The company is trading under the ticker symbol $SLDP.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/solid-power-ramps-up-solid-state-battery-race-with-public-market-debut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245562</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to acquire customer research that shapes your go-to-market strategy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/how-to-acquire-customer-research-that-shapes-your-go-to-market-strategy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/how-to-acquire-customer-research-that-shapes-your-go-to-market-strategy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 17:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go-to-market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engines]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before you can hire a full-time marketer, you must first get to know your potential customer and what is going on in their life that will ultimately trigger them into using you.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Lucy Heskins</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/lucy_heskins">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Lucy Heskins is an early-stage startup marketing adviser and the creator of <a href="https://www.ohblimey.com/">Oh, Blimey</a>, a marketing resource for first-time founders and their teams. She focuses primarily on B2B SaaS as well as product-led startups in the HR and people tech spaces.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Before you can hire a full-time marketer, you must first get to know your potential customer and what is going on in their life that will ultimately trigger them into using you.</p>
<p>If you can get to grips with the below areas you’ll be much more prepared when deciding what type of marketing resource you want:</p>
<ul>
<li>Why would a customer subscribe to your product?</li>
<li>What triggers your customer to decide your product is the one?</li>
<li>Who else are you competing against?</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m going to introduce you to three frameworks that’ll help you get answers to the above, but more importantly, show you how to apply this to marketing and what it can help you unlock and learn. This topic is something I created a resource on: <a href="https://www.ohblimey.com/how-to-talk-to-people-and-land-your-first-customer" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to talk to people and land your first customer</span></a>.</p>
<h2>Why would a customer subscribe to your product?</h2>
<p>You may have heard a marketer refer to Jobs to Be Done (JTBD). In essence, this is something that helps you to understand what your customer is looking to achieve when ‘hiring’ your product.</p>
<p>A basic example: You don’t hire a hammer to pop a nail in the wall, you hire a hammer to hang a picture to make your room look nice. The hammer is helping you make your room appear attractive, perhaps sellable, or stylish because you want to impress others.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The same goes with a tech product. You need to work out what your product can help your customer achieve.</p>
<p><strong>The process: </strong></p>
<p>You want to interview the right customers and ask questions such as, ‘what are you ultimately trying to achieve? ‘What’s the first thing you’ll do’ or ‘Have you tried to fix this problem yourself, and if so, which products have you cobbled together?’</p>
<p>There’s certainly a science to the questions to ask, but the emphasis needs to be on <strong>what</strong> they are trying to accomplish. Take note, this can be a lengthy process because you have to really dig into interviews, but the rewards are totally worth it.</p>
<p><strong>How to apply it to your startup’s marketing: </strong></p>
<p>It can help you with targeting your customer base. There’s a chance you may identify a few potential jobs people wish to achieve. Use the findings to identify the group that will pay the most to get the ‘job’ done the best. This may help to speed up the sales cycle or identify more lucrative customer opportunities.</p>
<h2>What triggers your customer to decide your product is the one?</h2>
<p>Whilst there are many frameworks out there to help you navigate this customer research piece, the effective ones are broadly based on the work of Moesta. He suggests there are six stages a customer will go through when buying something: first thought, passive looking, active looking, deciding, onboarding and ongoing use.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/how-to-acquire-customer-research-that-shapes-your-go-to-market-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244427</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don’t miss the mission-critical insights our sponsors bring to TC Sessions: Space 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/dont-miss-the-mission-critical-insights-our-sponsors-bring-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/dont-miss-the-mission-critical-insights-our-sponsors-bring-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marquise Foster]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 17:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions Space Marketing 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2242736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With just a tad less than a week until TC Sessions: Space 2021 launches its massive knowledge payload, we’d like to take this opportunity to tip our space helmets to our sponsors. Yes, they write the checks that help make this stellar event possible, but they don’t just cut-checks-and-run. They also bring considerable subject-matter expertise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With just a tad less than a week until <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> launches its massive knowledge payload, we’d like to take this opportunity to tip our space helmets to our sponsors. Yes, they write the checks that help make this stellar event possible, but they don’t just cut-checks-and-run.</p>
<p>They also bring considerable subject-matter expertise and mission-critical insights that can help early-stage space startups take flight and maintain orbit.</p>
<p><strong>Obligatory <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">sales pitch</span> reminder:</strong> Don’t miss your opportunity to learn about the latest trends and advances in space tech. It’s prime networking territory, too. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/#tickets">Buy your pass today</a>.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2242736" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Ready to learn more about the knowledge payload waiting for you in the sponsored presentations and breakout sessions? Read on, and check <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/#24513748-ac7b-490b-ad48-4b0767bf0c58">the event agenda</a> for the specific days. <strong>Note:</strong> All listed times will automatically reflect your geographic time zone.</p>
<p><strong>Fast Money, Team Space: Company Concept, Capital and Customers</strong> — Disruptive and game-changing technology and entrepreneurial initiatives are the new space norm. However, a great technical design is not enough to sustain these entrepreneurial pursuits. Growing an idea across markets also takes capital and customers. Transitioning from concept to development phase is more likely to succeed when a company can obtain stable forms of capital and potential long-term customers. Today’s Fast Money session — with Jordan Noone (Embedded Ventures) and Chris O&#8217;Connor (Harpoon Ventures) — focuses on how a startup was able to identify the right venture partners to grow their business and secured opportunities to prototype and test their designs with the U.S. government. Presented by The Aerospace Corporation.</p>
<p><strong>Securing Space at Speed</strong> — The demand signal is clear: the U.S. government needs to spur innovative commercial capabilities to excel in an increasingly contested space domain. Hear directly from Steve Isakowitz (The Aerospace Corporation), Pete Muend (National Reconnaissance Office) and Tim Trimailo (Blackjack/CASINO, SSC/DCIR) — leaders driving government-commercial collaborations about opportunities to help usher in the next era of achievement in space. Presented by The Aerospace Corporation.</p>
<p><strong>How Tech Startups Do Business with the DoD and U.S. Space Force</strong> — Sam Riehn (SBIR Advisors Inc.) will describe the three main problems technology startups face when working with the Dept of Defense (DoD) and the U.S. Space Force. he’ll discuss how you can overcome them to win multi-million-dollar deals using the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs. Presented by SBIR Advisors Inc.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>University Showcase: New Frontiers in Space Exploration From OSAM to xGEO</strong> — As space technology gets smaller and less expensive, more and more countries, universities and people can participate. We’ve seen thousands of small satellites launched into earth orbit from numerous developers over the past decade, many of whom were new to space. What’s next for on-orbit servicing, assembly, and manufacturing (OSAM) and orbital debris clean up as small spacecraft move beyond earth orbit and the geostationary satellite belt (xGEO) into open space (cis-lunar space), and onto the lunar surface itself? We’re showcasing university trail blazers in space exploration. Meet the people working on the projects — Jonathan Black (Virginia Tech), Dr. Debra L. Emmons (The Aerospace Corporation), Kathleen C Howell (Purdue University), Moriba Jah (The University of Texas at Austin) and Ricardo Sanfelice (University of California) — find out what’s ahead, and how you can participate. Learn about the technologies that are shaping a world where OSAM, xGEO and “cis-lunar” are becoming household terms. Presented by The Aerospace Corporation.</p>
<div class="sc-dwqccx lguFVo" data-testid="description-html">
<p class="sc-kEjbQP bPFbkm hpn-Text sc-iqHYmW sc-kHNMIv sc-ehsPLh SDZjo iQSdbS npAwT"><strong>Saving the World: One Small Sat at a Time! (Sponsored by Terran Orbital)</strong> &#8211; New space companies like Terran Orbital are emerging with the capability, confidence, and financing to provide US National Security with assets that previously could only be described as conceptual. In many cases, these companies are leading the field in technology, speed, innovation, and affordability. The emerging combination of private innovation and government support is launching a new era in aerospace enterprise.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/">TC Sessions: Space 2021</a> takes place on December 14-15. Don’t miss the big value in our sponsored sessions. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-space-2021/#tickets">Buy your pass right now</a> and get ready to take away mission-critical information to help you build a better business.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TC Sessions: Space 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-054de807d08247a54a95307c1ca7ea3f'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/dont-miss-the-mission-critical-insights-our-sponsors-bring-to-tc-sessions-space-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2242736</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airplane soars with $8.5M to make creating internal tools less burdensome</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/airplane-internal-tools/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/airplane-internal-tools/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 17:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airplane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benchmark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[database]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eric vishria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groupware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Ma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Product Hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ravi Parikh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SQL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With developers in mind, the company gives engineers back the time they were spending building internal tools and away from product engineering. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.airplane.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Airplane</a> on Thursday launched runbooks, a developer tool for automating internal workflows, in private beta and on Product Hunt.</p>
<p>Runbooks enables engineers to compose tasks and built-in integrations, like SQL, REST APIs and Slack, into workflows that run JavaScript code, can feed that into a SQL database or combine data from Stripe and be accessible to non-engineering team members.</p>
<p>Airplane was founded in 2020 by Josh Ma, former CTO at Benchling, which is also backed by Benchmark, and Ravi Parikh, co-founder of digital insights startup Heap. With developers in mind, the pair wanted to give engineers back the time they were spending building internal tools and away from product engineering.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245065" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2245072" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245072" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2245072" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="332" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg 1605w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg?resize=768,375 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg?resize=680,332 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg?resize=1536,749 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Airplane-co-founders-Josh-Ma-and-Ravi-Parikh.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2245072" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Airplane / Airplane co-founders Josh Ma and Ravi Parikh</p></div></p>
<p>“We spent time brainstorming ideas, and one of the big pain points we both saw at our companies was the lack of internal tooling,” Parikh told TechCrunch. “Tools let people deal with customer data and resolve issues, like deleting data or merging accounts, but sometimes, a customer success team would ultimately have to escalate a task to engineering teams.”</p>
<p>That could mean dozens of tickets every day piling up and interrupting the engineering team, he added. Its first product was Airplane tasks, which transforms duct-taped scripts and cron jobs into safe, reusable tools, Parikh said.</p>
<p>The remote-first company has hubs in San Francisco and New York, and though it has been around for a short period of time, it already has a couple of paying customers and hundreds of users building and running on Airplane in various use cases, including administration operations, customer onboarding, approval flows and long-running tasks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The product unveiling was buoyed by $8.5 million of Series A funds in a round led by Benchmark. As part of the investment, Eric Vishria is joining Airplane’s board.</p>
<p>In the past year, the SaaS company grew into a team of 10 people across three countries. The new funding will enable Airplane to double its employee headcount and invest in product and technology development, like building self-service products.</p>
<p>“What used to take hours, days or even weeks now takes between two and five minutes with Airplane,” Parikh said. “All an engineer has to do is run a deploy command and configure the user interface. We had a customer even tell us that adoption of our product enabled them to clear out a queue of requests to zero, for the first time, that had piled up over five years.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rqOAjHoMjW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-open-source-and-dev-tools-part-2-of-2/">Where top VCs are investing in open source and dev tools (Part 2 of 2)</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where top VCs are investing in open source and dev tools (Part 2 of 2)&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/05/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-open-source-and-dev-tools-part-2-of-2/embed/#?secret=rqOAjHoMjW" data-secret="rqOAjHoMjW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/airplane-internal-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245065</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bird Buddy lands $8.5M to pursue &#8216;tech for nature&#8217; after smart bird feeder campaign takes off</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/bird-buddy-smart-bird-feeder-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/bird-buddy-smart-bird-feeder-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 16:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bird Buddy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2243787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the resounding success of several crowdfunding campaigns for its gamified smart bird feeder, Bird Buddy has raised an $8.5 million seed round. Its first product will ship in a few months, but it&#8217;s just the start of what the company hopes will be a new approach to using tech to better enjoy nature. It&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After the resounding success of several crowdfunding campaigns for its gamified smart bird feeder, Bird Buddy has raised an $8.5 million seed round. Its first product will ship in a few months, but it&#8217;s just the start of what the company hopes will be a new approach to using tech to better enjoy nature.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an ambitious statement of purpose from a company working on something as apparently trivial as a bird feeder. But co-founder and CEO Franci Zidar explained how this market is something of a sleeping giant.</p>
<p>&#8220;Birdwatching is the second biggest outdoor hobby in the U.S., and huge internationally,&#8221; he said. No doubt this trend accelerated during the pandemic, when for many people birds provided a pleasant reminder that there is indeed a world outside their windows. &#8220;We spent the first half of 2020 doing a lot of validation, and it&#8217;s something people are really passionate and active about. Every metric that came back was insane.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2243787" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Still, one wonders, if everyone loves birds so much, why other camera-equipped bird feeders haven&#8217;t become commonplace. Zidar thinks they&#8217;re coming at the whole thing from the wrong direction.</p>
<p>&#8220;They saw these original ones as something for people super into birdwatching,&#8221; he explained. &#8220;But what we realized is it&#8217;s not just about building a smart bird feeder, but a brand and a company about reconnecting people with nature. We needed the beautiful hardware piece that people will have in the yard, but a big part of it was that story of reconnecting. It speaks to people who are bird-curious but didn&#8217;t get into it because it seemed passive — so we made something that turned passivity into activity.&#8221;</p>
<p>Suddenly, although the Bird Buddy doesn&#8217;t look fundamentally different (though better designed, to be sure) from what&#8217;s out there already, and costs about the same ($200 to pre-order), it looks like a way <em>into</em> the hobby rather than something only a serious hobbyist would buy.</p>
<p>The secret is in the life-imitates-art-imitates-life fact that birds are very Pokémon-like. Obviously birdwatching existed before the popular monster collection game, but they tap into the same &#8220;collect them all&#8221; instinct that some people have. Birds are &#8220;the perfect collectible,&#8221; Zidar said, an observation which manages to be both a crucial insight and face-palmingly peak tech.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2243814" style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/birdbuddy-app.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2243814" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2243814" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/birdbuddy-app.gif" alt="Animated image of the Bird buddy interface and 'catching' a bird." width="500" height="602" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2243814" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bird Buddy</p></div></p>
<p>But being precious about how people engage with one&#8217;s hobby is the very kind of gatekeeping behavior that deters those people from even trying. A cute app with badges, notifications, points, social sharing and other modern conveniences may not be how people envisioned the birdwatching community growing, but that may be just what&#8217;s needed.</p>
<p>The feeder itself seems nicely designed — they scored Kyle Buzzard, who designed the Chromecast and various other consumer tech items, whose friendly, rounded approach shows through here as well. It also looks big enough to accommodate medium-sized birds, something roofed designs don&#8217;t always allow. (If jays don&#8217;t fit, the feeder ain&#8217;t it, as I say.)</p>
<p>Not everyone can sit by their window all day and watch the birds come and go (though I do). So being able to be aware of who stops by, and receiving a pleasant surprise in the form of a seasonal species or neighborhood regular popping up in your notifications is a great alternative.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2243813" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2243813" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2243813" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/cam-nuthatch.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2243813" class="wp-caption-text">It&#8217;s a nuthatch. I love these guys. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bird Buddy</p></div></p>
<p>Inside the app there are the sort of &#8220;New bird!&#8221; achievements and tracking you might expect, and options to share images with others in the app or on social media. Feeders can also be made public — not for constant viewing but for individual bird visits.</p>
<p>One very attractive feature still in development is identifying individual birds, not just species. This would be a huge boon for birdwatchers who care about which jay or junco exactly is visiting their feeder — you could name it, compare with a friend down the block. Is Francine the flicker coming to your yard too?</p>
<p>Of course the smart layer comes with some risks, as typified by Ring, which has attracted controversy due to acting as a police surveillance network. Zidar acknowledged this tension as one faced by a lot of smartened-up gadgets.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s very top of mind for us,&#8221; he said. &#8220;There&#8217;s no silver bullet, but knowing about the Ring fiasco gives us a lot of insight. We&#8217;ll make the device as secure as we can possibly make it, no low-hanging fruit with easy vectors of attack. Having said that, it&#8217;s your device, no one can access it unless you want to add your wife, your kids. Anyone who wants to share with the community, there will be a couple layers to that, like sharing for an hour, just sharing pictures of birds. The live thing doesn&#8217;t let you forget about it.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rAjH5h4UvlU?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>Image analysis also provides a protective layer — images with people are automatically discarded. Users will be guided during onboarding to point their feeder at bushes or trees. And there will be the usual reporting capabilities necessary to a social platform.</p>
<p>One may very well wonder why, after three successive and successful crowdfunding runs on Kickstarter, IndieGoGo and a self-hosted system, totaling some $10 million, does this company need another $8.5 million in capital?</p>
<p>&#8220;With the best of intentions, millions of dollars disappear overnight when you&#8217;re building hardware,&#8221; explained Zidar. &#8220;You have to order components, pay taxes, fulfillment, shipping, all that not counting that 2021 was the worst possible year to build hardware, right? Availability was shrinking, prices were fluctuating, we had to have redundant components becasue we weren&#8217;t sure which we would be able to get. Shipping costs have risen 6-8 times too. Even shipping in January — we were supposed to ship in September originally — is kind of a miracle.&#8221;</p>
<p>Importantly though, he continued, the investment comes from a recognition by General Catalyst that the company represents an opportunity to engage with an under-capitalized population of hobbyists who spend hundreds on binoculars but buy $30 feeders. Zidar hopes to build a company whose primary intent and brand is that &#8220;reconnecting with nature&#8221; idea mentioned before, and for which the Bird Buddy is just the first step.</p>
<p>For him and his co-founder, &#8220;we&#8217;ve both done a lot of interesting stuff&#8230; but rarely do you have a core mission you can align with, making people care about nature and wildlife. And the best way to do that is get them to engage with us — to build a huge community of people who do that. So we&#8217;re building a brand that people will love and trust.&#8221;</p>
<p>As a very amateur birder myself I find it an attractive project, but of course it all depends on the execution. Hopefully we&#8217;ll be able to test out a Bird Buddy when it ships early next year and give an informed verdict on whether the team accomplished what it set out to do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/bird-buddy-smart-bird-feeder-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2243787</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robust Intelligence raises $30M Series B to stress test AI models</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/robust-intelligence-raises-30m-series-b-to-stress-test-ai-models/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/robust-intelligence-raises-30m-series-b-to-stress-test-ai-models/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 16:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybernetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineering capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firewall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvard university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Curtius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robust Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiger global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Robust Intelligence, an AI startup that helps businesses stress test their AI models and prevent them from failing, today announced that it has raised a $30 million Series B funding round led by Tiger Global. Previous investor Sequoia, which led the company&#8217;s Series A round, as well as Harpoon Venture Capital and Engineering Capital also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.robustintelligence.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Robust Intelligence</a>, an AI startup that helps businesses stress test their AI models and prevent them from failing, today announced that it has raised a $30 million Series B funding round led by Tiger Global. Previous investor Sequoia, which led the company&#8217;s Series A round, as well as Harpoon Venture Capital and Engineering Capital also participated in this oversubscribed round.</p>
<p>The company was co-founded by Yaron Singer, a tenured professor of Computer Science and Applied Mathematics at Harvard University, and his former student Kojin Oshiba.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245438" style="width: 250px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245438" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2245438" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg?w=240" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg 1278w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg?resize=120,150 120w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg?resize=240,300 240w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg?resize=768,959 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg?resize=545,680 545w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg?resize=1230,1536 1230w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/YARON.jpeg?resize=40,50 40w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245438" class="wp-caption-text">Robust Intelligence CEO Yaron Singer. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Robust Intelligence</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2244468" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;AI has been this academic endeavor,&#8221; said Singer. &#8220;When I was doing grad school, it was an academic discipline &#8212; it was a vision. And then came the internet, data, Google and data processing &#8212; and then it realized its potential in the span of seven, eight years. Now we&#8217;re trying to be as rigorous as we are with software development, which humanity has been doing for 60 years, right? We&#8217;re trying to play catch-up with AI and it&#8217;s a whole different animal.&#8221;</p>
<p>As Singer noted, given its statistical nature, AI can exhibit unexpected behavior. At its core, the mission of Robust Intelligence then is to eliminate these AI mistakes.</p>
<p>To do so, the company offers its users what it calls the Robust Intelligence Model Engine (RIME), with what is essentially an AI firewall at its core. This firewall wraps around a company&#8217;s AI models and protects it from making mistakes by constantly stress testing these models.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you have an AI model and you have data, with a click of a button you run stress testing. We automatically test data and your AI models, both before the model goes into production, as well as while it is in production,&#8221; said Singer. The idea here is to automatically find the failure modes of any given model, but also to catch issues like data drift and related issues.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2245439" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245439" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-2245439" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="75" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg 1026w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg?resize=150,37 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/RI-logo.jpeg?resize=50,12 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245439" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Robust Intelligence</p></div></p>
<p>What&#8217;s interesting here is that the AI firewall itself is an AI model that predicts whether a data point will lead to a wrong prediction. &#8220;This is one of the hardest problems that we&#8217;re solving in AI and machine learning,&#8221; Singer explained.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was first exposed to Robust Intelligence’s capabilities in the company’s early development,&#8221; said Tiger Global partner, John Curtius. &#8220;After seeing the company and its product grow over the past year it became obvious that Robust Intelligence’s offerings are changing the face of AI reliability, and I knew Tiger Global could help provide key resources.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company plans to use the new funding to scale its sales operations, but the majority will go to product and engineering.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/robust-intelligence-raises-30m-series-b-to-stress-test-ai-models/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244468</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM locks in two deals that will bolster US rare earth magnet production</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/gm-rare-earth-magnet-us-supply-chain/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/gm-rare-earth-magnet-us-supply-chain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[General Motors has spent the past year securing a domestic supply chain for the millions of electric vehicles it plans to produce by the end of the decade, everything from battery cell manufacturing and cathode active materials to lithium and even recycling that will turn scrap into raw materials. Now it&#8217;s locking in a domestic [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">General Motors has spent the past year securing a domestic supply chain for the millions of electric vehicles it plans to produce by the end of the decade, everything from battery cell manufacturing and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/gm-to-form-new-joint-venture-with-posco-chemical-aimed-at-key-battery-component/">cathode active materials</a> to lithium and even recycling that will turn <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/gm-and-lg-chems-ultium-cells-partners-with-li-cycle-to-process-manufacturing-waste/">scrap into raw materials</a>.</p>
<p>Now it&#8217;s locking in a domestic source of rare earth minerals, alloy and finished magnets for the electric motors it will use in its upcoming barrage of EVs including the GMC Hummer EC, Cadillac Lyriq and Chevrolet Silverado EV through a partnership with MP Materials and another separate deal with Vacuumschmelze (VAC) of Germany. The upshot: two new facilities will be built in the United States, bolstering the domestic production of rare earth magnets.</p>
<p>And GM will need a lot of magnets, which are a key component of electric motors that helps create the torque that propels a vehicle&#8217;s wheels. The automaker plans to bring <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">30 new EVs to the global market by 2025 and to transition to an all zero-emission portfolio by 2035. The GMC Hummer alone may have </span>many as three motors with up to 11,500 pound-feet of torque.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245425" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Under the partnership with VAC, GM and the German company will build a plant in the U.S. that will manufacture permanent magnets for the electric motors. The agreement with VAC is non-binding at the moment. GM executives said in a briefing call Thursday that the two companies are expected to finalize definitive agreements in early 2022. The plant is expected to start production in 2024. The location of the facility will be announced at a later date, the companies said.</p>
<p>The agreement with MP Materials is more of a mines-to-magnets partnership. Rare earth materials will be mined and processed at MP Materials&#8217; mine in California, then transformed into metal and magnets in a new 200,000-square-foot facility in Fort Worth, Texas. Recycling will be integrated at both locations, according to MP.</p>
<p>The facility, pictured in a rendering below, will produce NdFeB alloy and magnets with the potential to power about 500,000 EV motors per year, the companies said. A gradual production ramp is expected to begin in 2023.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245477" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245477" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2245477 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg" alt="GM and MP Materials Fort Worth Magnet Facility" width="2000" height="1125" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/MP-Materials-Fort-Worth-Magnet-Manufacturing-Facility.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245477" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MP Materials</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The deal is a notable one for MP Materials, which owns and operates the only active and scaled rare earth production site in the United States.  The Mountain Pass site, once the world&#8217;s largest producer of rare earths, has moved through a few hands over the past several decades. Chevron sold it to a company called Molycorp in 2008. The company intended to restart and even expand the mine but eventually was forced into bankruptcy.</p>
<p>MP Materials acquired Mountain Pass in July 2017. The site wasn&#8217;t operational, according to MP and just eight employees were left to care and maintain it. MP has since restarted operations and by 2020 the Mountain Pass site, pictured below, produced more than 38,500 metric tons of rare earth contained in concentrate, representing more than 15% of global production according to the U.S. Geological Survey.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245493" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245493" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2245493 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg" alt="MP Material Mountain Pass rare earth mine" width="2000" height="820" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg?resize=150,62 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg?resize=300,123 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg?resize=768,315 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg?resize=680,279 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg?resize=1536,630 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Aerial-broll-8.jpg?resize=50,21 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245493" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MP Materials</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s also a milestone for advocates of U.S.-based rare earth production. Rare earth materials can be found all over the world and were once mined in the United States. But companies stopped mining rare earths by 2003, opting instead to buy them from China. Today, nearly all of the mining is in China .<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The development of Neodymium-iron-boron (or NdFeB) permanent magnets — which are used in electric motors — began in the United States, but today the main producers are in China, Brazil and India. China has about 90% of the sintered rare earth magnet capacity. </span></p>
<p>The Fort Worth facility will be be used to supply NdFeB alloy flake to other magnet producers to help develop a diverse and resilient U.S. magnet supply chain, GM and MP Materials said in their joint announcement. MP Materials said the Fort Worth facility will consume less than 10% of the 6,075 tonnes of NdPr oxide it expects to produce annually at Mountain Pass.</p>
<p>GM announced in October another non-binding agreement with General Electric&#8217;s clean energy arm GE Renewables to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/gm-general-electric-agree-to-develop-rare-earth-materials-used-in-ev-manufacturing/">collaborate on the supply of rare earth materials</a> and to look for ways to improve supplies of magnets, copper and electrical steel. The two companies announced intentions at the time to also explore new supply chains for copper and &#8220;eSteel,&#8221; a material composed in part of recycled materials, to be used in automotive traction motors and renewable power generation.</p>
<p>That deal still appears to be moving forward. A GM spokesperson said in an email that &#8220;collaboration is an important component of building a strong, resilient and scalable North America-focused EV supply chain. We are still in the process of finalizing definitive agreements.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/gm-rare-earth-magnet-us-supply-chain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245425</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ikigai gets $13M to build automated workflows with humans in the loop</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/ikigai-gets-13m-to-build-automated-workflows-with-humans-in-the-loop/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/ikigai-gets-13m-to-build-automated-workflows-with-humans-in-the-loop/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 15:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[8VC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foundation capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ikigai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Underscore VC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ikigai, a startup based on research out of MIT, wants to make it simple to build workflows with humans involved. Whereas traditional robotic process automation (RPA) is about building bots for repetitive tasks, this company wants to make it easier to build workflows where humans have to make a decision as part of the process. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.ikigailabs.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ikigai</a>, a startup based on research out of MIT, wants to make it simple to build workflows with humans involved. Whereas traditional robotic process automation (RPA) is about building bots for repetitive tasks, this company wants to make it easier to build workflows where humans have to make a decision as part of the process.</p>
<p>The company announced a $13 million seed round today from Foundation Capital, 8VC, Underscore VC and a variety of industry angels.</p>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Vinayak Ramesh says that he found in his research at MIT, and at his previous startup, Wellframe, a digital healthcare startup <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211207005907/en/HealthEdge-Completes-Acquisition-of-Wellframe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired this month,</a> that there were more complex workflows out there that RPA wasn&#8217;t reaching.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245455" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&#8220;What we saw is that there are use cases…[that involve] manual processes in the organizations that were extremely difficult to automate because a fundamental step involved humans making judgments or decisions with data, and where both the data and rules they&#8217;re operating on would change very often,&#8221; Ramesh explained to me.</p>
<p>Ikigai, which means &#8220;your purpose&#8221; in Japanese, wants to solve that problem with a tool that lets users create drag and drop workflows involving disparate data sources, while building in steps where humans make decisions, and then viewing the results in a dashboard/spreadsheet view. They describe this as an &#8220;AI-charged&#8221; spreadsheet.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245465" style="width: 2882px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245465" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2245465 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png" alt="Ikigai worlkflow engine with spreadsheet and data view." width="2872" height="1456" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png 2872w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png?resize=300,152 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png?resize=768,389 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png?resize=680,345 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png?resize=1536,779 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png?resize=2048,1038 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Ikigai-Screenshot.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2872px) 100vw, 2872px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2245465" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Ikigai</p></div></p>
<p>But they believe that they differ from other supercharged spreadsheet approaches like Power BI and Airtable. &#8220;[Those tools] require humans in the workflow, but they&#8217;re not decision- or data-based workflows,&#8221; he said, and he says that ability to build in decision loops is a key differentiator for their product.</p>
<p>The company currently has 20 employees, mostly engineers, with plans to double that next year. The founders definitely seem to recognize the need to build a diverse and inclusive team as they scale the company.</p>
<p>&#8220;Diversity helps make everything a much nicer place to work because you have different perspectives, different types of people coming into work every day,&#8221; Ramesh said. He also points out that many of his early employees are immigrants, and the company has worked with these folks to help them navigate the difficult process of getting visas to work in the U.S.</p>
<p>The company idea grew out of research that Ramesh was doing as a student at MIT. In fact, CTO and co-founder Devavrat Shah is a professor of Computer Science at MIT and was Ramesh&#8217;s professor. Shah also started another company called Celect, which was <a href="https://news.nike.com/news/nike-celect-acquisition" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired by Nike in 2019</a>.</p>
<p>After helping to found Wellframe, Ramesh went back to grad school, where he connected with Shah. As the idea of a product like this only became more pronounced over time, they began to research it further and built the product last year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/ikigai-gets-13m-to-build-automated-workflows-with-humans-in-the-loop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245455</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WhatsApp begins offering Novi money transfers to some users in the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/whatsapp-begins-offering-novi-money-transfers-to-some-users-in-the-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/whatsapp-begins-offering-novi-money-transfers-to-some-users-in-the-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 15:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Novi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook has announced that a limited number of people in the US will now be able to send and receive Novi payments from within WhatsApp.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mariella Moon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mariella Moon is an associate editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/spacex-launches-a-nasa-telescope-that-will-observe-black-holes/">SpaceX launches a NASA telescope that will observe black holes</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/tesla-is-reportedly-replacing-some-faulty-autopilot-cameras-for-free/">Tesla is reportedly replacing some faulty Autopilot cameras for free</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Back in October, Facebook (now Meta) <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-will-test-cryptocurrency-wallet-novi-in-small-pilot-210320677.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">launched</a> a small pilot test of its cryptocurrency wallet <a href="https://www.novi.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">Novi</a> in the US and Guatemala. Pilot testers have been able to send each other personal payments through the service since then. Now, the company has announced that a limited number of people in the US will also be able to send and receive Novi payments from within WhatsApp.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">There&#39;s a new way to try the <a href="https://twitter.com/novi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Novi</a> digital wallet. Starting today, a limited number of people in the US will be able to send and receive money using Novi on <a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WhatsApp</a>, making sending money to family and friends as easy as sending a message. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b8.png" alt="💸" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4ac.png" alt="💬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/dGz3lejri7">pic.twitter.com/dGz3lejri7</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Stephane Kasriel (@skasriel) <a href="https://twitter.com/skasriel/status/1468722859648307201?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245453" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The development doesn&#8217;t come as a surprise: Novi co-founder David Marcus <a href="https://fintechmagazine.com/financial-services-finserv/meta-bringing-fintech-wallet-novi-all-subsidiaries" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="24" data-v9y="1">previously said</a> that Meta will roll out Novi payments to all of its subsidiaries, namely Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp. For WhatsApp, sending money is almost as easy as sending a message — users won&#8217;t even need to leave the application. It&#8217;s also a simple way to send money without incurring fees. To do so, users will have to find their intended contact within WhatsApp, tap the paper clip icon on Android or the + icon on iOS in the text bar, select Payment and follow instructions on how to log into their Novi account.</p>
<div id="max-player-injector" class="vmmi-si" data-maxi="0">
<div class="vdb_player">
<div><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Head of Novi Stephane Kasriel said on Twitter: &#8220;We often hear that people use WhatsApp to coordinate sending money to loved ones, and Novi enables people to do that securely, instantly and with no fees. Payments will appear directly in people’s chat.&#8221;</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Facebook has been teasing its digital wallet and the Diem (formerly Libra) cryptocurrency it was supposed to support for years. After <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-diem-association-us-111008891.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="25" data-v9y="1">facing pushback</a>from regulators around the world, though, the Diem Association shifted its focus, and Novi ended up using a stablecoin called the Pax Dollar (USDP) that&#8217;s backed by the US dollar. On Novi, 1 USDP is equivalent to 1 USD. People won&#8217;t be buying cryptocurrency when they use it, and it&#8217;s simply money transfers that use stablecoin as an instrument. While sending USDP via Novi on WhatsApp has extremely limited availability for now, Kasriel said the service will look to expand its reach after getting feedback from users about the experience.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-novi-money-transfers-us-124027874.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/whatsapp-begins-offering-novi-money-transfers-to-some-users-in-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245453</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tinder is partnering with Spotify to launch a new &#8216;Music Mode&#8217; feature</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/tinder-is-partnering-with-spotify-to-launch-a-new-music-mode-feature/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/tinder-is-partnering-with-spotify-to-launch-a-new-music-mode-feature/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 15:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partnerships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tinder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tinder is partnering with Spotify to launch a new &#8220;Music Mode&#8221; feature where users will hear a 30-second looped preview of a potential matches&#8217; chosen song while checking out their profile. Users who link their Spotify accounts and add a chosen song, called an &#8220;Anthem,&#8221; to their Tinder profiles will be able to enter Music [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tinder is partnering with Spotify to launch a new <a href="https://www.tinderpressroom.com/Tinder-Launches-Newest-Experience-In-Explore-Music-Mode" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&#8220;Music Mode&#8221; feature</a> where users will hear a 30-second looped preview of a potential matches&#8217; chosen song while checking out their profile. Users who link their Spotify accounts and add a chosen song, called an &#8220;Anthem,&#8221; to their Tinder profiles will be able to enter Music Mode. It&#8217;s worth noting that Tinder and Spotify first partnered in 2016 to launch the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/20/tinder-taps-spotify-to-let-you-add-music-to-your-profile/">Anthem feature</a>, which allows users to add music to their dating profiles. This latest integration is a new way for users to discover their potential matches&#8217; favorite songs.</p>
<p>Music Mode will be rolling out to Tinder users globally, in all markets where Spotify is available, in the coming weeks. The new feature will be found on Tinder&#8217;s interactive &#8220;Explore&#8221; page. Tinder notes that the new feature builds on the natural ties between music and human connections by allowing users to connect through their tastes in music.</p>
<p>“Now with Music Mode, our members can experience that feeling when you’re at a party and you find out someone else loves the same songs you do,” said Kyle Miller, the vice president of product innovation at Tinder, in a press release. &#8220;Songs are deeply personal, and Music Mode is a place to spark something new through music.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245428" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company says about 40% of Gen Z Tinder users have already added Anthems to their profiles and when they do, they see nearly a 10% increase in matches.</p>
<p>This latest launch comes as Tinder has been rolling out new features to allow users to engage with others in new ways. For example, the aforementioned <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/tinder-adds-a-new-home-for-interactive-social-features-with-launch-of-tinder-explore/">new Explore section</a> features events, as well as new ways to discover matches by interests. It also allows users to dive into quick conversations with others before a match is made. The company also recently launched a new <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/14/tinder-is-releasing-a-new-plus-one-feature-to-help-users-find-a-wedding-date/">&#8220;Plus One&#8221; feature</a>. Through the feature, users are able to signal that they are either looking for a date to a wedding or are willing to be one.</p>
<p>Last month, Tinder also brought back <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/01/tinders-new-murder-mystery-themed-swipe-night-returns-november-7/">“Swipe Night,”</a> its interactive in-app event that allows its users another way to break the ice besides just matching and chatting, this time featuring a “whodunit” murder mystery. The Swipe Night feature is available in the Explore section. Also available in this section is “Hot Takes,” which lets members chat in real time in a sort of speed dating, timed experience, and “Passions,” where users can meet others with similar interests, among other things.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/tinder-is-partnering-with-spotify-to-launch-a-new-music-mode-feature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SF&#8217;s Tradeshift, a supply chain finance platform, raises $200M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/sfs-tradeshift-a-supply-chain-finance-platform-raises-200m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/sfs-tradeshift-a-supply-chain-finance-platform-raises-200m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 14:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american express ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christian lanng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embedded finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hsbc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDC Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koch Industries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tradeshift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wipro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tradeshift — the late-stage startup tackling supply chain financing — has announced a $200 million funding round in equity and debt from a combination of existing and new investors, including Koch Industries, the giant industrial conglomerate. Also participating were IDC Ventures, LUN Partners, Private Shares and Fuel Capital, which increased their existing stakes in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://Tradeshift.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tradeshift</a> — the late-stage startup tackling supply chain financing — has announced a $200 million funding round in equity and debt from a combination of existing and new investors, including Koch Industries, the giant industrial conglomerate. Also participating were IDC Ventures, LUN Partners, Private Shares and Fuel Capital, which increased their existing stakes in the company.</p>
<p>Tradeshift has a portfolio of enterprise SaaS, marketplace and fintech products serving a B2B marketplace. The company said the capital would be used to “optimize Tradeshift growth and balance sheet to continue scaling the business.” Tradeshift helps buyers and suppliers digitize their invoice processing, automate the workflows for accounts payable and scale up.</p>
<p>In a statement, Jeff Randsell, managing director and founding partner at Fuel Venture Capital Partners, said: “Tradeshift’s combined SaaS and embedded financial services offering is well positioned at the forefront of what we see as the next wave of digital transformation. Further, it is clear that digital networks are the future of B2B software, just look at Slack, LinkedIn, and GitHub to see the trend. Tradeshift has pioneered the world’s first large-scale global trade network in the cloud with impressive growth rates through the pandemic and a compelling proposition to drive future scale.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245427" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Tradeshift says the cumulative value of transactions processed across its network has “passed the $1 trillion mark, having doubled in two years.” It adds that charge volumes on Tradeshift Go are predicted to exceed $2.5 billion in 2021, a 600% year-on-year rise. It’s also launched Tradeshift Cash, a &#8220;factoring&#8221; product that helps suppliers access cash flow.</p>
<p>“Embedding financial services directly into our product unclogs the flow of working capital across supply chains, eliminating a significant pressure point in the buyer-suppliers relationship,” said Christian Lanng, CEO and co-founder, Tradeshift. “As one of the first companies to recognize the potential for embedded finance in SaaS, we have been betting on the convergence of fintech and SaaS products for a while. We’ve built the technology and distribution channels to capitalize on what is now one of the defining trends in our industry.”</p>
<p>We haven’t heard from Tradeshift since January 2020, when it took in a funding round of $240 million in equity and debt. The idea then was that it would “get on a path to profitability” after a potential IPO was put back, and after skepticism around tech IPOs at the time.</p>
<p>That was before the pandemic hit. With supply chains both booming and under pressure, it&#8217;s likely that Tradeshift&#8217;s model is tailor-made for the post-COVID world.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Based on this new round, San Francisco-based Tradeshift reportedly has a valuation of more than $2 billion. In 2018 the company said its valuation was $1.1 billion during a $250 million funding round.</p>
<p>Tradeshift also has American Express Ventures, HSBC (HSBA.L), Goldman Sachs (GS.N) and Wipro Digital as investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/sfs-tradeshift-a-supply-chain-finance-platform-raises-200m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245427</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mio raises $8.7M Series A to make enterprise messaging interoperable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/mio-raises-8-7m-series-a-to-make-enterprise-messaging-interoperable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/mio-raises-8-7m-series-a-to-make-enterprise-messaging-interoperable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 14:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capital-factory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cisco Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eniac ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldcrest Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Hadfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trillian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[two sigma ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WAN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebEX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xmpp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mio, a startup that helps enterprise teams collaborate across messaging services like Zoom Chat, Microsoft Teams, Slack and Cisco&#8217;s Webex, today announced that it has raised an $8.7 million Series A funding round. The round was led by Zoom and Cisco Investments. In total, Austin-based Mio, which was founded in 2016 and participated in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://m.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mio</a>, a startup that helps enterprise teams collaborate across messaging services like Zoom Chat, Microsoft Teams, Slack and Cisco&#8217;s Webex, today announced that it has raised an $8.7 million Series A funding round. The round was led by Zoom and Cisco Investments. In total, Austin-based Mio, which was founded in 2016 and participated in the Y Combinator Winter 2016 class, has now raised $17 million. Other investors include Goldcrest Capital, Eniac Ventures, Two Sigma Ventures, Khosla Ventures, Y Combinator and Capital Factory.</p>
<p>While being able to chat across platforms isn&#8217;t usually a problem that comes up inside a company, it does become an issue when you&#8217;re working across organizations. Traditionally, those kinds of conversations used to happen in pre-planned meetings, whether in-person or virtually, but the pandemic only accelerated the move toward enterprise messaging services for this use case, too.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245417" style="width: 837px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio4-1.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245417" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2245417" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio4-1.gif" alt="" width="827" height="461" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245417" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mio</p></div></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2244573" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>As Mio CEO and co-founder Tom Hadfield told me, you may think that the different players in this field would want to keep their walled gardens closed off from competitors, but the fact that Zoom and Cisco are investing in Mio shows that interoperability is very much on their minds. He also noted that Microsoft and Meta recently partnered on an integration between Teams and Facebook Workplace, while Slack and Teams have also long partnered around <a href="https://dispatch.m.io/connect-slack-microsoft-teams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VoIP integrations</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Microsoft Teams is akin to a Local Area Network, because Microsoft will always deliver messages between Microsoft users,&#8221; said Hadfield. &#8220;When a Teams user wants to send a message to a Slack user, it will go over the Wide Area Network for workplace communications. That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re building at <span class="il">Mio</span>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hadfield, who co-founded the company with CTO James Cundle, tells me that the team spent the last few years on addressing technical challenges like managing the basic differences between messaging clients (like Slack&#8217;s support for custom emoji) and how they handle channels, for example. Different platforms also place different limits on their users and their APIs are always in flux, too.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2245418" style="width: 778px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio1-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2245418" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2245418" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio1-1.png" alt="" width="768" height="509" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio1-1.png 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio1-1.png?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio1-1.png?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio1-1.png?resize=680,451 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Mio1-1.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2245418" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mio</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The collaboration industry has come a long way from the &#8216;multi-headed clients&#8217; like Trillian that connected AIM, ICQ, MSN and Yahoo! Messenger in the early 2000s,&#8221; explained Hadfield. &#8220;A decade ago, there was a big push for open standards like XMPP and SIP, but the standards bodies failed to keep up with the rapid pace of innovation in team collaboration. Mio solves this by federating publicly available APIs, so each platform can innovate at their own pace.&#8221;</p>
<p>Given the obvious need for a service like this, it&#8217;s no surprise that there is a bit of competition here. <a href="https://nextplane.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nextplane</a> offers somewhat similar capabilities and with Matrix, there is an open source protocol for decentralized messaging with bridges to Slack, Discord and others (but not Teams, Zoom and Webex). &#8220;We plan to work closely with Matrix and Nextplane to advance our shared vision for a unified messaging ecosystem,&#8221; said Hadfield.</p>
<p>Mio plans to use the new funds to enhance its service by adding support for additional services like Google Chat, Meta&#8217;s Workplace and Symphony. The company also plans to launch a new unified presence feature that will allow users to synchronize their presence status across services.</p>
<p>&#8220;This investment, by two of the largest players in the collaboration industry, ushers in a new era for interoperability,&#8221; said Hadfield. &#8220;It brings us one step closer to &#8216;Collaboration Nirvana&#8217; where everyone on the planet can collaborate with each other, regardless of which chat app they are using.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/mio-raises-8-7m-series-a-to-make-enterprise-messaging-interoperable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe lays out a plan to flip the odds on gig economy exploitation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/eu-gig-economy-proposal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/eu-gig-economy-proposal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 14:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fairwork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Farrer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Margrethe Vestager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minimum wage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sharing economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ursula von der Leyen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2245093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[EU lawmakers have formally proposed legislation for the gig economy they hope will improve conditions for platform workers across the bloc — including by establishing a framework to tackle the problem of bogus self-employment. The Commission&#8217;s overarching goal is to a create a level playing field between traditional businesses and gig platforms, as well as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">EU lawmakers have formally <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_21_6605" target="_blank" rel="noopener">proposed legislation</a> for the gig economy they hope will improve conditions for platform workers across the bloc — including by establishing a framework to tackle the problem of bogus self-employment.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The Commission&#8217;s overarching goal is to a create a level playing field between traditional businesses and gig platforms, as well as between different gig platforms (or &#8220;digital labor platforms&#8221; as its draft text calls them) &#8212; by enforcing minimum standards for platform workers in areas like pay, conditions and social protections.</span></p>
<p>EU lawmakers also want to improve visibility and &#8220;traceability&#8221; of platform work by bringing in obligations for platforms to declare work to authorities at a national level &#8212; to support enforcement of legal requirements across the bloc, and ensure social security contributions are being paid where the work is actually taking place.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2245093" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>They are taking steps to drive algorithmic accountability and fairness on the sector &#8212; with a package of transparency measures.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, EVP Margrethe Vestager, said: <em>“</em>With more and more jobs created by digital labour platforms, we need to ensure decent working conditions for all those deriving their income from such work. Our proposal for a Directive will help false self-employed working for platforms to correctly determine their employment status and enjoy all the social rights that come with that. Genuine self-employed on platforms will be protected through enhanced legal certainty on their status and there will be new safeguards against the pitfalls of algorithmic management. This is an important step towards a more social digital economy.”</p>
<p>The directive will need the backing of the European Parliament and Member States&#8217; governments, via the European Council, before it can become EU law. But at a press conference today the Commission noted widespread support from MEPs for  legislation to protect gig workers.</p>
<p>It also pointed out that a number of Member States have been pressing for it to act. While the text of the draft highlights one incentive for governments to get on board, predicting: &#8220;<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Member States will enjoy increased revenues in the form of additional tax and social protection contributions.&#8221;</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Once adopted, the Commission is allowing two years for Member States to transport the rules into national law &#8212; meaning application and enforcement won&#8217;t happen before 2024 at the earliest.</p>
<p>While, by 2025, the Commission expects some 43M people in the EU to be working through digital labor platforms &#8212; up from around 28M now. And accelerating growth of the gig economy is a key reason why it&#8217;s decided to act.</p>
<h2>Presumption of employment</h2>
<p>Most notably, the proposed directive (<a href="https://ec.europa.eu/social/BlobServlet?docId=24992&amp;langId=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PDF</a>) sets out a presumption of employment for workers on digital labor platforms &#8212; based on a set of defined criteria related to the facts of how work is controlled by a platform, rather than whatever relationship contracts might try to claim.</p>
<p>(And, as it happens, we&#8217;ve just seen another litigation on gig platform contracts play out in the UK courts &#8212; where <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/uk-high-court-uber-contracts-loss/">earlier this month</a> Uber lost an attempt in the High Court to have a claimed bypass from contactual liability legalized, with industry-wide ramifications for London-licensed ride-hailing platforms in that (non-EU) market.)</p>
<p>An impact assessment in the EU proposal suggests the change could result in between 1.72M and 4.1M people providing services through platforms being reclassified as workers.</p>
<p>At a press conference announcing the reform this morning, Valdis Dombrovskis, the Commission EVP responsible for trade and social protections for workers, appeared to suggest an even larger number of platform workers may be reclassified as as result.</p>
<p>&#8220;Of 28 million platform workers [in Europe currently] there may be up to 5.5M whose contractors describes them as self employed but in reality they are regularly checked and supervised &#8212; this effectively makes them employed workers,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They should have the labor and social rights that correspond to this status, such as working time and health protection, minimum wage, unemployment, sickness and old age benefits.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Our proposal address the mis-qualification of these vulnerable workers and introduces the principle of rebuttable presumption [of employment] based on a range of control criteria,&#8221; Dombrovskis added.</p>
<p>On-demand platforms such as those offering ride-hailing and food delivery have faced numerous <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/spains-top-court-rejects-glovos-classification-of-couriers-as-self-employed/">legal challenges</a> over how their classification of workers&#8217; employment status in Europe in recent years.</p>
<p>Concern over the issue has also led some Member States to consider or pass national legislation (such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/spain-agrees-on-labor-reform-that-will-recognize-delivery-platform-riders-as-employees/">Spain&#8217;s &#8216;riders law&#8217;</a> which was passed earlier this year and recognizes delivery platform workers as employees). Portugal has also said it&#8217;s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/portugals-gig-economy-workers-set-become-staff-2021-10-22/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">looking at similar legislation</a>.</p>
<p>The passing of national laws is a typical trigger for the EU&#8217;s executive to come forward with pan-EU rules to try to avoid fragmentation of the bloc&#8217;s single market.</p>
<p>Although, in this case, the EU&#8217;s legislative push is more about ensuring platforms abide by minimum standards across the region to prevent a race to the bottom on labor standards.</p>
<p>Commission president, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/07/tech-driven-change-a-key-priority-for-new-ec-president/">Ursula von der Leyen</a>, signalled an intention to dial up scrutiny of the gig economy as she took office at the end of 2019, saying she would look at ways of improving the labour conditions of platform workers, initially suggesting the approach would focus on skills and education.</p>
<p>However the coronavirus pandemic sharpened the bloc&#8217;s concern over conditions for gig workers, as the lack of social protections for many platform workers were brought into stark relief &#8212; highlighting a slew of risks around delivery services that were suddenly being relied upon in the midst of lockdowns and mobility restrictions. So the Commission appears to have stepped up its action.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/europe-kicks-off-bid-to-find-a-route-to-better-gig-work/">consultation phase</a> on the reform took place earlier this year but failed to lead to agreement between the two sides (platforms and unions) &#8212; hence the EU&#8217;s executive now stepping in with a legislative proposal.</p>
<p>The proposed framework for determining the presumption of employment has been tightly drawn by the Commission &#8212; covering factors such as whether a platform sets the level of pay for the work; puts conditions on conduct/performance; supervises the performance of work or verifies quality; puts restrictions on when/whether a worker can work; and restricts a worker from building a client base or working for third parties.</p>
<p>Here is the full list of proposed criteria:</p>
<div class="page" title="Page 35">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<blockquote>
<ol>
<li>(a) effectively determining, or setting upper limits for the level of remuneration;</li>
<li>(b)  requiring the person performing platform work to respect specific binding rules with regard to appearance, conduct towards the recipient of the service or performance of the work;</li>
<li>(c)  supervising the performance of work or verifying the quality of the results of the work including by electronic means;</li>
<li>(d)  effectively restricting the freedom, including through sanctions, to organise one’s work, in particular the discretion to choose one’s working hours or periods of absence, to accept or to refuse tasks or to use subcontractors or substitutes;</li>
<li>(e)  effectively restricting the possibility to build a client base or to perform work for any third party.</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Just two of the five criteria need to be met for the presumption of employment to kick in, per the proposal. And &#8212; at a glance &#8212; it looks like many ride-hailing platforms especially will see their workers fall under the presumption of employment.</p>
<p>Taking press questions, the Commission denied it&#8217;s trying to kill off the gig economy business model &#8212; arguing that platforms that do not want to have to reclassify scores of workers will be able to adapt their systems and tweak their models to reduce the level of control they apply so workers can be deemed genuinely self employed.</p>
<p>&#8220;Platforms may react to this by adjusting their relations with their contractors if they prefer to keep self employment status &#8212; but it means less systemic control over those independent contractors,&#8221; said Dombrovskis. &#8220;Or if they think that their specific circumstances merit it they may still challenge this presumption but at least it sets clear criteria which would be uniform criteria across the EU.&#8221;</p>
<p>As well as switching the burden of proof vis-a-vis employment status off workers and onto platforms, the proposal stipulates that any legal challenges platforms bring to try to rebut the presumption &#8220;shall not have suspensive effect on the application&#8221; &#8212; meaning that they must treat workers as employees during any period they are trying to overturn that status.</p>
<h2>Algorithmic transparency</h2>
<p>The draft directive also includes a very interesting package of measures focused on algorithmic transparency and fairness that goes further than current EU legislation which provides citizens with some protections vis-a-vis automated decisions (such as the GDPR) &#8212; putting obligations on platforms to provide workers with information about the algorithms that are used to control their labor.</p>
<p>This has also been an active area for litigation in Europe &#8212; where, for example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/uk-uber-drivers-are-taking-its-algorithm-to-court/">ride-hailing drivers and unions have been challenging Uber</a> to provide detailed information on how its algorithms profile and performance-manages them; and over its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/12/dutch-court-rejects-uber-drivers-robo-firing-charge-but-tells-ola-to-explain-algo-deductions/">use of algorithms in account terminations</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/10/ola-is-facing-a-drivers-legal-challenge-over-data-access-rights-and-algorithmic-management/">Ola has also faced similar legal challenges</a> in the EU. While, in Italy, the data protection regulator has taken action under existing EU law: This summer it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/italys-dpa-fines-glovo-owned-foodinho-3m-orders-changes-to-algorithmic-management-of-riders/">fined a food delivery platform owned by Glovo</a> over a slew of breaches of EU privacy legislation, including around issues of algorithm management of couriers, such as via a rider rating system.</p>
<p>Spain&#8217;s rider law already includes a package of measures around algorithm transparency. And the strategic importance of claiming data rights for platform workers has led to the formation of new associations, such as <a href="https://www.workerinfoexchange.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Worker Information Exchange</a>, which was founded by James Farrer &#8212; a former Uber driver who <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/uber-loses-gig-workers-rights-challenge-in-uk-supreme-court/">successfully challenged its employment classification under UK law</a> &#8212; with the goal of cracking open algorithmic blackboxes to reset the power imbalance between platform giants and the labor providers whose activity not only enables the service to function but generates data that&#8217;s fed back and used to tightly manage and control them.</p>
<p>The Commission&#8217;s proposal would accelerate this cause by requiring gig platforms to provide workers and/or their representatives with information about all AI systems and algorithms used to monitor, supervise and evaluate them; and about any automated decision-making systems that could significantly affect their working conditions (such as by terminating their account or determining the distribution of jobs etc).</p>
<p>While the GDPR (Article 22) already includes a right to information in relation to automated decisions that have a legal or similar effect on individuals, this proposal goes further in the case of platform workers &#8212; as it covers decision-making systems used to &#8220;support&#8221; decisions, rather than being limited to solely automated decisions.</p>
<p>That looks important as platforms have sought to evade legal challenges to automated decisions under the GDPR by claiming AI systems used for processes such as fraud detection (which can lead to account terminations) do not take decisions alone &#8212; arguing there&#8217;s always a layer of human review. But the question then is what constitutes a meaningful human review of an AI decision (vs a person employed to rubberstamp algorithmic assessments)?</p>
<p>The EU&#8217;s gig reform proposal looks intended to circumvent that workaround by applying far broader transparency requirements to algorithmic control systems used by gig platforms &#8212; meaning they will be obliged to keep workers informed of the systems being applied to them on an ongoing basis.</p>
<p>Notably, the proposal includes an explicit ban on platforms processing any personal data of workers that is not &#8220;intrinsically connected to and strictly necessary for the performance of the contract between the platform worker and the digital labour platform&#8221; &#8212; including an outright ban on processing data on &#8220;the emotional or psychological state of the platform worker&#8221;; and on data relating to the health of the platform worker (with some limited exceptions).</p>
<p>The Commission also specifies that platforms must not surveil the private conversations of platform workers, including exchanges with workers’ representatives.</p>
<p>Nor must they collect any personal data while the platform worker is not offering or performing platform work &#8212; implying they cannot repurpose their workforce as a freebie training pool for other AIs they might aspire to build.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Wow. Fascinating developments with the new draft EU Platform Workers Directive. Looks more stringent than either GDPR or draft AI Act re rights to explanation and contestation, bans on use of mental or health data to control. <a href="https://t.co/MyyeTNFJJ6">https://t.co/MyyeTNFJJ6</a></p>
<p>&mdash; lilian edwards (@lilianedwards) <a href="https://twitter.com/lilianedwards/status/1468678250708848643?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<h2>No cap on standards</h2>
<p>The draft directive will not prevent Member States from passing (or amending) national laws that seek to further raise standards for platform workers &#8212; so it&#8217;s definitely intended to set a floor not impose a ceiling on standards in the gig economy.</p>
<p>The Commission argues the proposed directive will introduce &#8220;very clear criteria&#8221; and &#8220;more legal security&#8221; to a heavily litigated business model, adding that it&#8217;s expecting the legislation to reduce the number of legal challenges brought over gig platform working conditions.</p>
<p>&#8220;We based &#8212; especially our criteria &#8212; on concrete experience,&#8221; said Dombrovskis, responding to a journalist&#8217;s question raising an immediate critique of the proposal by the <a href="https://www.businesseurope.eu/publications/eu-commission-proposal-ignores-diversity-platform-work" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BusinessEurope</a> industry lobby group. &#8220;These are the criteria which came up in hundreds and more cases in different European jurisdictions.</p>
<p>&#8220;That responds also to the question on fragmentation. We have now a set of common rules, of common criteria. If a platform clearly abides by the rule applicable to self employed, well, there is no problem.&#8221;</p>
<p>The commissioner also denied the proposal will prevent platforms from providing more benefits to genuinely self employed workers if they wish &#8212; saying the reform makes it clear doing so would not risk those workers being reclassified as employees.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think we have brought more clarity and that we &#8212; I would not exclude that there will be some cases in the future &#8212; but we will limit the cases because we have this objective legal criteria,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Incoming EU rules for high risk applications of AI &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/">proposed by the Commission earlier this year</a> &#8212; are also set to apply to algorithmic systems used in employment, worker management and access to self-employment.</p>
<p>And the draft gig worker directive confirms that platforms which are providers of high risk AI systems will also need to &#8220;test and document their systems appropriately&#8221; under that additional incoming pan-EU law. So there will likely be additional layers of compliance for gig platforms under the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/europe-lays-out-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-boost-trust-and-uptake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AI Act</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HuSHQL4RSP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/as-eu-eyes-balance-on-precarious-gig-work-glovo-offers-pledge-of-fairer-conditions-for-couriers/">As EU eyes &#8216;balance&#8217; on precarious gig work, Glovo offers pledge of &#8216;fairer&#8217; conditions for couriers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As EU eyes &#8216;balance&#8217; on precarious gig work, Glovo offers pledge of &#8216;fairer&#8217; conditions for couriers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/as-eu-eyes-balance-on-precarious-gig-work-glovo-offers-pledge-of-fairer-conditions-for-couriers/embed/#?secret=HuSHQL4RSP" data-secret="HuSHQL4RSP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Unsurprisingly, platforms have been lobbying hard against the proposed reform &#8212; led by some of the largest ride-hailing and food delivery platforms which are likely to face the most disruption to their businesses.</p>
<p>Uber, for example, has been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/uber-could-give-gig-workers-a-better-deal-but-its-lobbying-eu-to-lower-standards-says-fairwork/">accused of lobbying the EU to lower employment protections</a> &#8212; after it published a white paper <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/uber-lobbies-for-prop-22-style-gig-work-standards-in-the-eu/">earlier this year</a> calling for a &#8220;new standard&#8221; for platform work which critics decried as an attempt to push for a Prop-22-style carve out for gig work from European employment rights.</p>
<p>Spain&#8217;s on-demand delivery platform Glovo also pre-empted the Commission&#8217;s proposal by announcing what it couched as a &#8220;Couriers Pledge back <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/as-eu-eyes-balance-on-precarious-gig-work-glovo-offers-pledge-of-fairer-conditions-for-couriers/">in October</a> &#8212; committing its business to &#8220;fairer&#8221; standards for gig workers and tacitly accepting there are problems with conditions currently offered.</p>
<p>That may have been a last ditch attempt to try to water down the Commission proposal. Or recognition that the loophole which gig economy platforms have exploited &#8212; and which Dombrovskis referred to as &#8220;a sort of gap or lack of precision in our laws&#8221; vis-a-vis social protection and self employment &#8212; is now inexorable closing.</p>
<p>During today&#8217;s presser, the commissioner suggested that at least one large platform had written to him saying it could support the employment presumption reform. He also <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">pointed out that a number of platforms already employ workers or operate a hybrid model with some employees and some contractors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Far from [planning to kill the gig economy model] I&#8217;ve said that there are large platforms already operating today employing people, employing workers, they&#8217;re working quite well,&#8221; he suggested. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Of course we recognize the role of the platform economy which can bring to the economy &#8212; both in terms of innovation, new business models, new and better services to customers. We recognize the important role the platform economy has for employment &#8212; already 28M people working in the platform economy. At the same time we want to ensure the protection of European social model also applies to those who are working in the platform economy.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;There should not be a difference if a person works in a classical economy or a platform economy that there is a possibility to contribute to and access social protection systems,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Asked about the risks of platforms circumventing the rules via subcontracting, Dombrovskis pointed out there is already an EU directive setting standards for temporary/agency work &#8212; and arguing that if platforms seek to evade the requirements via agencies it will still lead to better conditions for workers owing to existing regulations that apply to those types of businesses.</p>
<h2>Support and opposition</h2>
<p>Asked specifically whether Uber was one of the platforms that had expressed support for the directive, Dombrovskis declined a clear answer, saying: &#8220;I had a lot of discussions also with Uber &#8212; I do not remember that Uber expressed a direct support.&#8221;</p>
<p>But in a public response today the ride-hailing giant answered the question itself &#8212; raising concerns that the proposal will put &#8220;thousands of jobs at risk, crippling small businesses in the wake of the pandemic and damaging vital services that consumers across Europe rely on&#8221;.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“<span class="il">Uber</span> is committed to improving the working conditions for the hundreds of thousands of drivers and couriers who rely on our app for flexible work. We have worked with national governments across Europe and the rest of our industry on ways to strengthen platform work without risking the flexibility independent workers say they want,&#8221; its statement added, arguing for an <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-06-16/france-considers-new-protections-for-gig-worker-invisibles" target="_blank" rel="noopener">approach being taken in France</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;As countries including France have demonstrated, there is a better way and any EU-wide rules should allow drivers and couriers to retain the flexibility we know they value most, while allowing platforms to introduce more protections and benefits.&#8221;</p>
<p>Speaking ahead of the Commission’s presentation of the proposal today, as a leaked draft was circulating, European ride-hailing startup Bolt also told us it does not support the plan to apply a presumption of employment &#8212; similarly claiming this component will lead to thousands of &#8220;job losses&#8221;.</p>
<p>Albeit, pressed on its paradoxical choice of terminology, Bolt&#8217;s head of public policy for Western Europe &amp; EU, Aurélien Pozzana, conceded it was referring to &#8220;earnings opportunities&#8221; rather than jobs in the traditional understanding of the word.</p>
<p>&#8220;Tomorrow if we had this &#8212; basically &#8212; full time employment framework we&#8217;re going to need much less drivers than today,&#8221; Pozzana predicted, arguing that more than half of the ride-hailing drivers in Europe would &#8220;not be needed anymore&#8221; &#8212; aka &#8220;close to 140,000 people&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Those who would still keep their job they actually would lose revenue,&#8221; he also claimed. &#8220;If you are employed tomorrow as a driver by a platform that&#8217;s going to be close to minimum wage. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Whereas today&#8230; [drivers] are maximising revenues by working on multiple platforms. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;So, in the end, everybody&#8217;s losing &#8212; it&#8217;s not productive. It goes against the will of the very people who are the most impacted by hitting drivers. It&#8217;s going to be harmful for platforms and especially European ones such as Bolt trying to compete with the biggest giants&#8230; And it&#8217;s going to be negative for the European citizens who are the passengers or the clients who get deliveries.&#8221; </span></p>
<p>Asked how much more tax Bolt&#8217;s business would have to pay if the reform went ahead &#8212; meaning it was required to switch to employing drivers &#8212; Pozzana said he did not have a figure to hand for that.</p>
<p>&#8220;The core concern as we speak and the focus is on the fact that generally speaking this is going to destabilize the whole industry, it will harm the drivers, it will harm the service, it will harms the clients and it goes against the will of the silent majority of the drivers,&#8221; he instead said.</p>
<p>&#8220;We strongly support what the Commission&#8217;s goal was which was to improve platform workers&#8217; working conditions. We&#8217;ve made some proposals to the Commission &#8212; more social protection and so on, better revenues &#8212; we&#8217;re very open to discuss this&#8230; We think already ride-hailing provides decent revenues to drivers throughout Europe but of course things can always be improved and there are cases where you need definitely to find solutions to issues which apply but this is not what this proposal is doing. It&#8217;s only focusing on the status of employment.&#8221;</p>
<p>TechCrunch also sought <a href="https://fair.work/en/fw/homepage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fairwork</a>&#8216;s reaction to the Commission proposal. The Oxford Research Institute research project benchmarks gig platforms against a set of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/26/flipkart-ranked-highly-for-fairness-of-working-conditions-in-india-gig-platform-study/">fairness principles</a> to encourage them to improve conditions for workers.</p>
<p>Fairwork&#8217;s Mark Graham and <span class="gD" data-hovercard-id="alessio.bertolini@oii.ox.ac.uk" data-hovercard-owner-id="106">Alessio Bertolini told us the proposal f</span><span lang="en-GB" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">or a presumption of an employment relationship will make it easier for platform workers to be reclassified as employees and therefore easier for them to enjoy the same rights as other (dependent) workers &#8212; &#8220;creating a long overdue level playing field in the platform economy&#8221;. </span></p>
<p><span lang="en-GB" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">But they warned the proposal is unlikely to go far enough in ensuring that platform workers receive</span><span lang="en-GB" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> &#8220;adequate rights and protections. </span></p>
<p><span lang="en-GB" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;As many court cases in Europe and beyond have shown, platform companies have been able to amend their contracts and slightly change their working models in response to court trials in order to circumvent current regulations and avoid their workers being reclassified as employees. It is very likely that this practice will continue in the future, leaving it again to workers to play a cat and mouse game for their rights in national courts,&#8221; they predicted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">They also highlighted growing use by platforms of &#8220;</span><span lang="en-GB" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">often complex networks of subcontracting in order to avoid employer’s responsibilities, as is also the case in many other precarious and low-paid jobs across Europe and beyond&#8221;. </span></p>
<p><span lang="en-GB" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;Even platforms which classify their workers as employees, can make use of intermediaries, including large multinational employment agencies, which dilute their direct obligations as employers and make it more difficult for workers to claim their rights. The EU proposal does not contain any relevant clause in relation to subcontracting, de facto not offering platform workers any protection against those practices, which are likely to become increasingly more common as more and more platforms move away from the independent contractor model.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Another shortfall Fairwork&#8217;s researchers highlighted is around the lack of improvements in</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> the rights and protections for workers who will continue to be classified as self-employed (regardless of whether genuinely or not), noting: &#8220;As </span><span class="il" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Fairwork</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, we want to make sure that all workers, regardless of employment classification, enjoy some basic labour standards, in line with the ILO Decent </span><span class="il" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Work</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> Agenda. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;As it stands, all platform workers which will continue to be classified as self-employed including, most likely, most platform workers in the domestic and care sector as well as cloud workers, will continue to be denied basic rights, including the right to a minimum wage, health and safety protection, transparency, due process and collective representation. More needs to be done to ensure that even those workers, who are among the most vulnerable among platform workers, are adequately covered by rights and protections and enjoy decent labour standards.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">They welcomed the inclusion of an article in the proposal</span><span lang="en-GB" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> clarifying that platforms using self-employed workers will not be at risk of employment reclassification if they offer training, health and safety and social protection to their workers &#8212; &#8220;thus overcoming an important existing regulatory barrier fo<wbr></wbr>r platforms in introducing measures to improve protections&#8221; &#8212; however here again they warned the draft legislation leaves measures &#8220;to the good will of platforms&#8221;, rather than seeking to enforce a standard. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;The on-demand model can be <span class="il">fair</span> only as long as minimum labour standards are guaranteed for all workers,&#8221; they also told us. &#8220;The on-demand model should be re-conceived and re-organised in a way that guarantees workers the basic rights and protections they should be already entitled to. This is what courts across the world have already tried to address and what some platforms are already providing in a number of countries.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fairwork have also published a blog post with a fuller response <a href="https://fair.work/en/fw/blog/fairwork-response-to-the-european-commissions-proposal-for-a-directive-on-platform-work/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<h2>On those gig industry claims&#8230;</h2>
<p>We also asked Fairwork to respond to some of the ride-hailing industry&#8217;s main lobbying arguments against the reform &#8212; such as the claims that it will lead to widespread job losses and reduced earnings for drivers, and the framing that employment automatically means reduced flexibility.</p>
<p>On earnings Fairwork queried a claim by Bolt that driver &#8220;revenues&#8221; are consistently higher than the local minimum wage.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our ratings of ride-hailing platforms across the world show that most of them are currently unable to provide adequate evidence its workers are paid above the minimum wage, once taken into account of <span class="il">work</span>-related costs, in their active hours (which should also include waiting time, according to our definition and that of many courts across the world, including the recent UK Supreme Court case against Uber). For details see <a title="https://fair.work/en/fw/ratings/#continue" href="https://fair.work/en/fw/ratings/#continue" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://fair.work/en/fw/ratings/%23continue&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1639126848416000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1REZrODTO3gBZYEBEaMnq5">our ratings</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fairwork also pointed out that platforms frequently choose to talk about &#8220;average earnings&#8221; &#8212; which excludes those who fall below the minimum wage from the discussion, emphasizing: &#8220;The point of a minimum wage&#8230; is to ensure a wage floor: To ensure that nobody can earn below the legal minimum. Even if only 5% of workers are earning below the minimum wage, it is still an exploitative system. All workers deserve decent wages.&#8221;</p>
<p>On the ride-hailing industry predictions of mass job losses following employment reclassification, Fairwork pointed out the same sorts of claims surfaced before the UK introduced its minimum wage &#8212; and resurface every time there&#8217;s debate about raising it &#8212; adding: &#8220;None of these things, of course, transpired. Research in labour market policy across the world consistently shows that the introduction of minimum pay thresholds when previously there was none, do not only help raise the pay of those previously paid below the minimum, but also of those paying closer but above that minimum, contrary to what Bolt [and Uber] is claiming<i>.&#8221;</i></p>
<p>While, on the industry&#8217;s framing of flexibility vs employment, Fairwork said its research shows that it&#8217;s possible for platforms to reconcile flexibility with <span class="il">fair</span> working conditions &#8212; although it noted that only a minority have been doing so, so far.</p>
<p><i>&#8220;</i>We don&#8217;t see any inherent contradiction between a model which guarantees flexibility and fairness at the same time,&#8221; it said. &#8220;Platforms have often claimed to refrain from providing workers with more rights and protections for fear 1) of being seen as employers, and therefore being more at risk of seeing their workers being reclassified 2) being at disadvantage compared to other platforms, and have instead engaged in a &#8216;race to the bottom&#8217; in labour standards.</p>
<p>&#8220;Now that the proposal at least partly addresses these two concerns, removing the issue of reclassification and creating a level playing field which all platforms should abide to, this should also reduce the barriers for platforms in providing &#8216;fairer&#8217; working conditions.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fairwork also agreed that platforms&#8217; claims of flexibility need far closer scrutiny &#8212; given how tightly they manage and control workers through the application of algorithms.</p>
<p><i>&#8220;</i>Our research and that of many other scholars has shown that flexibility is often fictitious for many workers, especially those relying on platform <span class="il">work</span> for a living. Though workers can appreciate the freedom to decide to <span class="il">work</span> when they want (which is something they should be able to continue to do in the future), many of these workers feel often obliged to <span class="il">work</span> long hours or accept any job in order not to earn a living or for fear of seeing their ratings reduced, and with it, future job opportunities. More importantly, we want to reiterate that there should not be, at least in principle, any reason why workers can <span class="il">work</span> flexibly, but being guaranteed at least some security.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iSzSP5DUBf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/uk-uber-drivers-are-taking-its-algorithm-to-court/">UK Uber drivers are taking the algorithm to court</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK Uber drivers are taking the algorithm to court&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/20/uk-uber-drivers-are-taking-its-algorithm-to-court/embed/#?secret=iSzSP5DUBf" data-secret="iSzSP5DUBf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/09/eu-gig-economy-proposal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245093</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
