<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 11:02:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Byju&#8217;s in talks to acquire US-based reading platform Epic</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/byjus-in-talks-to-acquire-us-based-reading-platform-epic/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/byjus-in-talks-to-acquire-us-based-reading-platform-epic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 11:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhiteHat Jr.]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Byju’s is eying acquisition of a startup that could help the biggest e-learning Indian startup deepen its footprint in the U.S. The Indian startup is in talks to acquire online reading platform Epic, a startup that offers unlimited access to over 40,000 books, videos, and quizzes from more than 250 publishers to kids aged 12 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Byju’s is eying acquisition of a startup that could help the biggest e-learning Indian startup deepen its footprint in the U.S.</p>
<p>The Indian startup is in talks to acquire online reading platform <a href="https://www.getepic.com">Epic</a>, a startup that offers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/30/epic-raises-8-million-to-keep-kids-reading-in-a-digital-age/">unlimited access to over 40,000 books, videos, and quizzes</a> from more than 250 publishers to kids aged 12 or younger, two people familiar with the matter told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The deal values Epic at &#8220;significantly&#8221; over $300 million dollars, according to one person, who like the other requested anonymity as the matter is private. The terms of the deal may change and/or the acquisition may not materialize, people warned.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>An Epic spokesperson declined to comment Monday evening, and Byju’s did not respond to a request for comment on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Epic, backed by Evolution Media, reaches <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/goodnight-ninja-knuffle-blobfish-childrens-books-get-the-algorithm-treatment-11616606893">over 50 million kids</a> in the U.S., a figure that has ballooned from <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20200316005813/en/Epic-Announces-Free-Support-for-Educators-Students-and-Families-Impacted-by-COVID-19-School-Closures">20 million last year</a>.</p>
<p>The California-based startup, which has raised over <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/epic/company_financials">$51 million to date</a>, claimed in a press release last year that over 1 million teachers across more than 90% of U.S. elementary schools use Epic.</p>
<p>On Epic, founded by Suren Markosian and Kevin Donahue, children read over <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/dereknewton/2021/01/25/reading-platform-epic-had-an-epic-year/?sh=6ddb07a31daf">a billion books last year</a>. The firm now plans to release several print versions of its original titles at Walmart, Target, and Sam’s Club later this year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131700" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131700" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2131700 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/epic-originals-1-1.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="611" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/epic-originals-1-1.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/epic-originals-1-1.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/epic-originals-1-1.jpg?resize=300,153 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/epic-originals-1-1.jpg?resize=768,391 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/epic-originals-1-1.jpg?resize=680,346 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/epic-originals-1-1.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131700" class="wp-caption-text">Some original titles released by Epic</p></div></p>
<p>Epic collects and analyzes real-time anonymized and aggregated data on how many children read a book, how deeply they engage with it, and where their interests start to fall off.</p>
<p>If the deal goes through, the startup’s offerings would align with Byju’s current playbook in the U.S. In 2019, the Indian startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/16/byjus-buys-osmo-for-120m/">acquired U.S.-based Osmo</a>, which offers “blended learning” apps to integrate offline activities for kids aged between five to 12.</p>
<p>Byju’s is separately in the middle of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/indian-edtech-giant-byjus-in-talks-to-raise-over-600-million-at-15-billion-valuation/">concluding a new funding round</a> whose size is expected to balloon over $600 million, TechCrunch reported last week. The new round is expected to value Byju&#8217;s at $15 billion.</p>
<p>The new financing round, a major tranche of which has already concluded (about <a href="https://entrackr.com/2021/03/exclusive-byjus-raises-450-mn-led-by-mc-global-edtech-investment/">$460 million at $13 billion valuation, per a filing</a>), will be used to finance the new acquisition, the source said.</p>
<p>The Indian giant, which prepares students pursuing undergraduate and graduate-level courses, has witnessed skyrocketing growth amid the pandemic after New Delhi issued a months-long lockdown and closed schools.</p>
<p>India&#8217;s second most valuable startup, which serves over 80 million users, has additionally been aggressively exploring ways to grow inorganically.</p>
<p>Byju&#8217;s, which acquired coding platform aimed at kids <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/indias-byjus-acquires-whitehat-jr-for-300-million/">WhiteHat Jr for $300 million last year</a>, is conducting due diligence to acquire <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/byjus-is-reportedly-buying-indian-brick-and-mortar-institute-aakash-for-1-billion/">decades-old Indian brick-and-mortar institute Aakash</a> and <a href="https://entrackr.com/2021/02/exclusive-byjus-set-to-acquire-toppr-in-a-150-mn-deal/">Toppr</a>, another online learning startup in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market. These two deals are being financed with the over $1 billion funds Byju&#8217;s raised last year, one person familiar with the matter said.</p>
<p>WhiteHat Jr, which sparked controversy last year when it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/22/whitehat-jrs-founder-files-2-6m-defamation-suit-against-critic/">sued two critics</a>, currently generates nearly half of its revenue from the U.S.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/byjus-in-talks-to-acquire-us-based-reading-platform-epic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131696</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MessageBird acquires 24sessions to bring video to its &#8216;omnichannel&#8217; platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/messagebird-acquisitions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/messagebird-acquisitions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2130667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MessageBird, the omnichannel cloud communications platform recently valued at $3 billion, is continuing to ramp up its M&#38;A activity. Following last year&#8217;s acquisition of Pusher, a company that provides real-time web technologies, it is announcing that it has acquired &#8220;video-first&#8221; customer engagement platform 24sessions, and customer data platform Hull. Terms of the two new deals [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.messagebird.com/">MessageBird</a>, the omnichannel cloud communications platform recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/messagebird-series-c/">valued at $3 billion</a>, is continuing to ramp up its M&amp;A activity. Following last year&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/push-it-realtime-good/">acquisition of Pusher</a>, a company that provides real-time web technologies, it is announcing that it has acquired &#8220;video-first&#8221; customer engagement platform 24sessions, and customer data platform Hull.</p>
<p>Terms of the two new deals aren&#8217;t being disclosed, although MessageBird founder and CEO Robert Vis tells me the three acquisitions add up to about $100 million in total, and we alreadly know that Pusher&#8217;s acquisition price was $35 million. I also understand that the 24sessions and Hull acquisitions saw both companies&#8217; investors exit entirely.</p>
<p>Originally seen as a European or “rest of the world” competitor to U.S.-based Twilio — offering a cloud communications platform that supports voice, video and text capabilities all wrapped up in an API — MessageBird has since repositioned itself as an “Omnichannel Platform-as-a-Service” (OPaaS). The idea is to easily enable enterprises and medium and smaller-sized companies to communicate with customers on any channel of their choosing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UZx0igMvUg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/push-it-realtime-good/">MessageBird acquires real-time notifications and in-app messaging platform Pusher for $35M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MessageBird acquires real-time notifications and in-app messaging platform Pusher for $35M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/push-it-realtime-good/embed/#?secret=UZx0igMvUg" data-secret="UZx0igMvUg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Out of the box, this includes support for WhatsApp, Messenger, WeChat, Twitter, Line, Telegram, SMS, email and voice. Customers can start online and then move their support request or query over to a more convenient channel, such as their favourite mobile messaging app, which, of course, can go with them. It’s all part of MessageBird Vis’ big bet that the future of customer interactions is omni-channel.</p>
<p>To that end, the acquisition of 24sessions adds another channel: video. This, Vis tells me, is a particularly important channel where in-person interactions are being replicated digitally. However, he says it&#8217;s not just enough to have a video option &#8212; you need one that is compliant and secure. This is especially true for regulated industries such as financial services and healthcare. In addition, 24sessions is web-based, meaning that end-users aren&#8217;t required to install an app.</p>
<p>“Bringing a safe, secure and customizable video platform into the MessageBird family is the next step in our strategic journey,&#8221; said Vis in a statement. “Our portfolio of owned services already includes SMS, voice, email, OTT, social, live chat and push. The addition of 24sessions’ video platform gives us one of the world’s most comprehensive and powerful omnichannel offerings, and is consistent with our having end-to-end control of the stack in order to create magical experiences for our customers&#8221;.</p>
<p>“By joining forces with MessageBird, we’re making a leap forward in our mission to improve personal customer contact and turn it into a smooth digital experience, without losing the human touch,” adds Rutger Teunissen, CEO of 24sessions. “Video has become a more embedded, instant, intelligent, and integrated part of the omnichannel customer experience&#8221;.</p>
<p>However, communicating with customers more efficiently doesn&#8217;t just mean interacting with them on the channels of their choosing and building backend workflows to support this, it also requires a better understanding of the customer and the context of their query. That&#8217;s where the acquisition of Hull, based in France and the U.S., comes into play.</p>
<p>Described as a customer data platform (CDP), Hull&#8217;s team and technology will be deployed to create an &#8220;in-depth analytics layer&#8221; between MessageBird&#8217;s omnichannel offering and the workflow solutions it provides to customers.</p>
<p>“We want to empower clients to have easy, frictionless conversations with customers, so it’s crucial that we understand where those customers are and how they like to communicate,” said Vis. “To do that, it’s crucial that our platform is able to collect, unify and enrich product, marketing, and sales data and synchronize it across the workflow.”</p>
<p>In total, 45 staff will join from 24sessions, and 14 will join from Hull. The combined M&amp;A brings MessageBird’s total headcount to almost 500 people across its nine hubs globally.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wbTjk9AbmS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/messagebird-series-c/">MessageBird, the &#8216;omnichannel platform-as-a-service,&#8217; raises $200M Series C at $3B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MessageBird, the &#8216;omnichannel platform-as-a-service,&#8217; raises $200M Series C at $3B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/messagebird-series-c/embed/#?secret=wbTjk9AbmS" data-secret="wbTjk9AbmS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/messagebird-acquisitions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2130667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zoomin raises $52M to help companies turn disparate product content into useful customer support data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/zoomin-raises-52m-to-help-companies-turn-disparate-product-content-into-useful-customer-support-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/zoomin-raises-52m-to-help-companies-turn-disparate-product-content-into-useful-customer-support-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[User guides, knowledge articles and community discussions form a detailed, yet very fragmented, landscape of information about a company and its products. Today, a company that&#8217;s built a platform both to organize that data, and help those who need it to tap into it more effectively, is announcing a round of funding that underscores the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">User guides, knowledge articles and community discussions form a detailed, yet very fragmented, landscape of information about a company and its products. Today, a company that&#8217;s built a platform both to organize that data, and help those who need it to tap into it more effectively, is announcing a round of funding that underscores the demand it&#8217;s seeing in the market for its technology.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.zoominsoftware.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoomin</a>, an Israeli startup that uses machine learning, natural language processing and some big data magic to help companies build self-service experiences that bring together information and answers pulled from all of the content that&#8217;s being generated by customers and the company itself across various channels, has picked up $52 million in a Series C led by General Atlantic, with previous backers Bessemer Venture Partners, Salesforce Ventures and Viola Growth also participating. The company is not disclosing the valuation.</p>
<p>Zoomin will be using the money to continue building out the functionality of its product and to double down on new customer segments.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Originally targeting tech companies and the needs of business end users &#8212; early customers included Dell and McAfee, among others &#8212; it&#8217;s found some interesting growth into other sectors like the food industry, where customers include Burger King, Tim Hortons, and Popeyes, because, as CEO and co-founder Gal Oron describes it, &#8220;your typical fast food company has a lot of franchises, and they use a lot of operating manuals. Just like ServiceNow or McAfee.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also moving into other sectors like finance and healthcare, he added, and expanding to more than just technical support, which in the B2B world is closely connected to sales support, and sales. That could see Zoomin building products that lay out the information in different ways too.</p>
<p>&#8220;Technical content is the new marketing,&#8221; Oron said. &#8220;Companies invest millions in creating marketing material, but they have hundreds of thousands of pages of HTML with all the relevant details, and their customers are interested in technical stuff.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zoomin taps into &#8220;content&#8221; &#8212; the source of its answers &#8212; in real time wherever it is being made, and those are also typically the places where Zoomin-generated answers are being delivered, too. Documentation sites, customer service portals, support communities, product applications and anywhere that people are searching for help and chatting are also the typical sources of information that get fed into the Zoomin machine.</p>
<p>The financing underscores how much attention investors (and customers) are giving to business support software these days.</p>
<p>The pandemic led to a major shift in how many of us worked and interacted with services &#8212; many more people started to work remotely and carried out all of their everyday duties online. In terms of needing assistance when something isn&#8217;t going right, all of that has also shifted online, and has put an immense amount of pressure on the infrastructure that had been built to help with that.</p>
<p>Even at the best of times, customer support is in a tough place. It&#8217;s where users go when something isn&#8217;t working correctly or when they have another complaint, so even out of the starting gate, it can be a fraught interaction. And agents don&#8217;t have it much better at the other end, either. On top of the customers and their demands, they&#8217;re also typically working under time, cost, revenue and organizational constraints from the company itself, the classic scylla and charybdis scenario. Given all of that, and the particular circumstances of the last year, tools like Zoomin&#8217;s have come into the foreground for companies as one way to cope with all of that.</p>
<p>This round comes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/16/zoomin-raises-21m-for-a-platform-to-make-fragmented-product-content-troves-easier-to-use/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just three months</a> after the startup came out of stealth with $21 million disclosed in funding since quietly opening for business in 2019. Oron said that the company has served 60.4 million answers to date to its customers (55 million in 2020): that volume grew 300% last year and its customer base doubled in the same period.</p>
<p>The company is banking on some bigger trends in the industry to see that growth continue. It notes that digital support channels &#8212; those site pages you visit that include either chatbots or intuitive search, dialogue boxes across the site, apps, and other places that don&#8217;t have live agents helping you &#8212; have grown in ubiquity, with some 60% of businesses projected to build self-service portals in the next 12 to 18 months. The proof is in the pudding, so to speak: Zoomin says that the product content that it helps surface can account for up to 70% of a company&#8217;s overall web traffic.</p>
<p>That brings up an interesting parallel between what Zoomin does and one of the major traffic controllers of modern times: the search engine. Google dominates how many of us use and discover things on the internet, and it&#8217;s been getting increasingly specific with the help that it provides to people, giving &#8220;answers&#8221; directly on search result pages &#8212; whether they are answers to questions, shopping suggestions, news, locations, videos, or any other number of end points.</p>
<p>Oron is quick to say that he has no interest in ever expanding what Zoomin does to make it a consumer-facing tool like Google&#8217;s, but it does highlight what a big and tricky problem information organization &#8212; or &#8220;knowledge orchestration&#8221;, as Zoomin refers to it &#8212; can be in our disjointed digital world, and the power of a company that can help bring order to that.</p>
<p>While Zoomin may not be interested in climbing the mountain that is competing with Google on its terms, it would be interesting to see how Google evolves its own work in site search, and whether that becomes a competitor on Zoomin&#8217;s terms. Zoomin&#8217;s terms are to get people to search on company sites themselves, not Google, for answers.</p>
<p>&#8220;The first place &#8212; a company&#8217;s site &#8212; is the right location,&#8221; Oron said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, all of the &#8220;what ifs&#8221; show is that there is indeed a lot of potential here, one reason you&#8217;re seeing companies like Salesforce investing alongside the big financial backers.</p>
<p>“We are excited to be supporting Zoomin in this important step of their growth story through an investment that marks our third-ever partnership in the burgeoning Israeli tech market. At General Atlantic, we pride ourselves on identifying category builders and growth-oriented disruptors, and view Zoomin as a natural fit given those priorities,” said Alex Crisses, MD, Global Head of New Investment Sourcing and Co-Head of Emerging Growth at General Atlantic, in a statement.</p>
<p>“Having helped build the increasingly important field of knowledge orchestration from the ground up, Zoomin is providing much-needed value to large enterprises,” added Gary Reiner, a current General Atlantic Operating Partner and previous GE Chief Information Officer. “We look forward to partnering with and supporting Zoomin as they continue to innovate the way that customers experience crucial enterprise product content.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/zoomin-raises-52m-to-help-companies-turn-disparate-product-content-into-useful-customer-support-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131461</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xiaomi joins the ranks of Chinese tech giants to work on EVs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/xiaomi-ev-subsidiary/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/xiaomi-ev-subsidiary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After weeks of rumors, Xiaomi officially confirmed that it is making a foray into the electric vehicle space. The Chinese smartphone and IoT giant will set up a wholly-owned subsidiary to operate a smart EV business, the company said in a filing on Tuesday. Xiaomi will inject an initial 10 billion yuan ($1.52 billion) into [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After weeks of rumors, Xiaomi officially confirmed that it is making a foray into the electric vehicle space. The Chinese smartphone and IoT giant will set up a wholly-owned subsidiary to operate a smart EV business, the company said in a <a href="https://www1.hkexnews.hk/listedco/listconews/sehk/2021/0330/2021033000824.pdf">filing</a> on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Xiaomi will inject an initial 10 billion yuan ($1.52 billion) into the venture with the total investment amount to reach $10 billion over the next ten years. Xiaomi founder and CEO Lei Jun will serve as the CEO of the new EV venture.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear from the filing whether Xiaomi will sell cars under its own household brand and contract manufacturers to take care of production, as it has done for most of its hardware devices. The company has long billed itself as an &#8220;internet firm&#8221; with a light-asset business model. The goal is to generate a chunk of its profits by selling services powering a myriad of price-friendly hardware products it sells.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A representative from Xiaomi said the company has no further detail to share beyond the filing.</p>
<p>Xiaomi is the latest Chinese tech company to enter the red-hot EV industry. Chinese search engine giant Baidu recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/10/baidu-electric-car-making/">announced</a> it would be making EVs with the help of automaker Geely.</p>
<p><em>More to come&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/xiaomi-ev-subsidiary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131757</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A trove of imported console games vanish from Chinese online stores</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/console-game-china-pulled-ecommerce/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/console-game-china-pulled-ecommerce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[console]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grey market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nintendo entertainment system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online marketplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taobao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video game]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the world&#8217;s largest gaming market, China, console games play a relatively small part as their revenue has been meager compared to mobile and PC games for years &#8212; at least by the official numbers (more on this later). There remains a community of hardcore console lovers, but they are finding it harder to get [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the world&#8217;s largest gaming market, China, console games play a relatively small part as their revenue has been meager compared to mobile and PC games for years &#8212; at least by the official numbers (more on this later). There remains a community of hardcore console lovers, but they are finding it harder to get hold of devices and cartridges recently.</p>
<p>A handful of grey market videogame console vendors on Taobao stopped selling and shipping this week, according to checks by TechCrunch and <a href="https://www.zhihu.com/question/451888962">online posts by gamers</a>. Before we examine what might be happening here, a bit of industry history is needed.</p>
<p>In 2000, China banned the sale and import of videogame consoles as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2013-01-30-china-console-ban.html">concerns over addiction in teenagers grew</a>. Even with the ban, imported consoles still existed in <a href="https://kotaku.com/how-to-buy-games-in-china-1238551167">the grey market</a> targeting a group of loyal players. Meanwhile, the online PC and mobile gaming industry flourished, in part thanks to their affordability and the social experience built into their mechanics.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>When China finally lifted its restriction on consoles<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/china-to-end-ban-on-videogame-consoles-1437813695"> in 2015</a>, giants like <a href="https://nikopartners.com/sony-playstation-china-console-game-market/">Sony and Microsoft</a> quickly responded by releasing Chinese editions of their products through local partners. Nintendo Switch hit the Chinese shelves in 2019 via a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/24/nintendo-switch-china-tencent/">much-anticipated partnership with Tencent</a>, which itself is the world&#8217;s largest gaming firm. But the grey market largely persisted because mainland Chinese versions of the consoles are subject to strict regulatory oversight, which limits users&#8217; choice to a <a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/news/2015/03/20/business/sonys-ps4-hits-china-but-with-few-games/">small friendly range</a> approved by censors.</p>
<p>Many Chinese players thus resort to brick-and-mortar electronics bazaars and online marketplaces to find imported editions of PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch, along with their games. These products normally enter China through parallel trading, the import of legitimate goods through unauthorized channels. The games that are brought in normally lack a Chinese gaming license, which is<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/20/china-restarts-game-approval-process/"> hard to obtain even by local publishers</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131747" style="width: 323px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131747" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2131747" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9141617080420_.pic_-e1617097739362.jpg" alt="" width="313" height="442" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9141617080420_.pic_-e1617097739362.jpg 747w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9141617080420_.pic_-e1617097739362.jpg?resize=106,150 106w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9141617080420_.pic_-e1617097739362.jpg?resize=212,300 212w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9141617080420_.pic_-e1617097739362.jpg?resize=481,680 481w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9141617080420_.pic_-e1617097739362.jpg?resize=35,50 35w" sizes="(max-width: 313px) 100vw, 313px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131747" class="wp-caption-text">Several major videogame console importers on Taobao have suspended business. Screenshot: TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear how many imported consoles and console games were taken down from Taobao and what triggered the purge. Tgbus, one of the largest console game sellers on Taobao with 462,000 followers, currently has zero product listing. When asked by TechCrunch, a customer service staff said the store has temporarily halted shipping due to &#8220;a water leak in the warehouse.&#8221; When we pressed further, the person said it was due to &#8220;an electrical-equipment failure.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other vendors keep their responses vague, citing &#8220;special reasons&#8221; for the suspended services. One seller named the &#8220;Shanghai Gaming Console Store&#8221; said it suspended its business at the request of Taobao, without elaborating further.</p>
<p>Alibaba could not be immediately reached for comment.</p>
<p>The incident appears to inflict mostly console sellers with a sizable business at this moment. Imported cartridges and console devices can still be found on smaller Taobao stores and alternative platforms like Pinduoduo by searching the right keyword.</p>
<p>Some users see the move as China further tightening its grip on what gamers get to play. Over the past year, Apple&#8217;s China App Store <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/over-2500-games-removed-from-apples-china-app-store-in-early-july-as-crackdown-begins/">removed thousands of games</a> to wipe out games <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/01/china-roundup-apple-closes-app-store-loophole/">without China&#8217;s official greenlight</a>. Other motives are politcal. Animal Crossing was pulled from grey market stores on Taobao and Pinduoduo after one of Hong Kong&#8217;s most well-known pro-democracy activists <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-nintendo-china-animalcrossing/nintendo-game-pulled-from-chinese-platforms-after-hong-kong-protest-idUKKCN21S11F">used the game as his protest ground</a>.</p>
<p>Other users point out that customs officers regularly clamp down on parallel trading, which is designed to evade import tax because goods are carried by traders who appear as regular travelers. This isn&#8217;t the first time the console grey market has been hit, either. Some grey goods manage to fly under the radar before they attract critical sales. There are signs that the new Monster Hunter Rise, a Nintendo-Switch exclusive which isn&#8217;t available on the Chinese console edition, is stoking much interest among local players in recent weeks and may have driven some imports.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mlfOX0nXTU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/20/china-restarts-game-approval-process/">Winter is ending: China to restart game approvals</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Winter is ending: China to restart game approvals&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/20/china-restarts-game-approval-process/embed/#?secret=mlfOX0nXTU" data-secret="mlfOX0nXTU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/console-game-china-pulled-ecommerce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131694</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acast expands its support for paid podcasts with Acast+</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/acast-expands-its-support-for-paid-podcasts-with-acast/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/acast-expands-its-support-for-paid-podcasts-with-acast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After partnering with Patreon last year to support patron-only podcasts, Acast has developed a full suite of subscription tools called Acast+. The company has experimented with paywalled podcasts beyond Patreon in the past, but Acast+ appears to be its most comprehensive offering yet. Podcasters who run ads from Acast will be able to introduce a variety of other paid options, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/10/patreon-and-acast-partner-for-patron-only-podcast-distribution/">partnering with Patreon last year</a> to support patron-only podcasts, <a href="https://www.acast.com/en">Acast</a> has developed a full suite of subscription tools called Acast+.</p>
<p>The company has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/01/acast-access/">experimented with paywalled podcasts</a> beyond Patreon in the past, but Acast+ appears to be its most comprehensive offering yet. Podcasters who run ads from Acast will be able to introduce a variety of other paid options, such as ad-free streams, exclusive episodes and early access to content.</p>
<p>Listeners will be able to access this content from the podcast players of their choice, including Apple Podcasts and Google Podcasts.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In exchange, Acast will take a cut of subscription revenue — Vice President of Product Matt MacDonald described this as &#8220;part of the overall package of using Acast,&#8221; with podcasters benefiting from having the full monetization experience managed within Acast. That means they can upload and manage access to all their content from a single system (rather than having separate paid and free feeds) while also getting the &#8220;full revenue picture&#8221; of both their advertising income and subscription income.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wypxVUZ5bR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/acast-acquires-radiopublic/">Acast acquires podcasting startup RadioPublic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Acast acquires podcasting startup RadioPublic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/acast-acquires-radiopublic/embed/#?secret=wypxVUZ5bR" data-secret="wypxVUZ5bR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>MacDonald said it&#8217;s also crucial that Acast is supporting subscription access across podcast players, rather than creating a listening app or destination of its own.</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8221;That’s a really clear distinction,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We want to make sure the podcaster’s listeners are their listeners. We&#8217;re just giving them a financial tool to help them build a relationship with the listeners that are supporting their show.&#8221;</p>
<p>Acast co-founder Johan Billgren also noted that podcasters can customize the experience down to the names of the subscription tiers and even what subscribers are called. He also said that after the launch of Acast+, the company will continue working with Patreon.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want to give the most options to the creator,&#8221; Billgren said. &#8220;They are in charge of their relationship, and if Patreon is the best option for them, we want to give them that option.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131603" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131603" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2131603" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?w=680" alt="Acast+" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg 13578w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?resize=1536,865 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?resize=2048,1153 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Acast.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131603" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Acast</p></div></p>
<p>More broadly, he suggested that Acast+ reflects &#8220;a big shift&#8221; as podcasts go from from being &#8220;completely free and ad-funded&#8221; to a pursuing a broader range of business models.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think that the financial relationship is an expression of the overall relationship,&#8221; MacDonald added. (Listener relationship-building was also a theme in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/19/acast-acquires-radiopublic/">Acast&#8217;s acquisition of RadioPublic last month</a>.) But certainly the financial side is important: &#8220;There are a number of times that I’ve heard podcasters say, &#8216;If I could make just a little bit more money, I could squeak out another episode.&#8217; We&#8217;re giving them the financial pathways to do that.&#8221;</p>
<p>Acast+ is currently in beta testing and <a href="https://www.acast.com/en/beta">accepting signups</a> from interested podcasters.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JzEwfG6P6u"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/13/will-podcast-ad-revenue-bounce-back-after-covid-19/">Will podcast ad revenue bounce back after COVID-19?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will podcast ad revenue bounce back after COVID-19?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/13/will-podcast-ad-revenue-bounce-back-after-covid-19/embed/#?secret=JzEwfG6P6u" data-secret="JzEwfG6P6u" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/acast-expands-its-support-for-paid-podcasts-with-acast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IBM brings its Quantum System One to the Cleveland Clinic</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ibm-brings-its-quantum-system-one-to-the-cleveland-clinic/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ibm-brings-its-quantum-system-one-to-the-cleveland-clinic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cleveland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dario gil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging-Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qubit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[IBM has installed a couple of its own Quantum System One machines across the world in recent years, but today it announced its first private-sector U.S. deployment thanks to a new ten-year partnership with the Cleveland Clinic. This not only marks IBM&#8217;s first U.S. install of one of its quantum computers outside of its own [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">IBM has installed a couple of its own Quantum System One machines across the world in recent years, but today it announced its first private-sector U.S. deployment thanks to a new ten-year partnership with the Cleveland Clinic. This not only marks IBM&#8217;s first U.S. install of one of its quantum computers outside of its own facilities, but also the first time a healthcare institute purchases and houses a quantum computer. And thanks to this deal, Cleveland will also get access to IBM&#8217;s upcoming next-gen 1,000+ qubit quantum system.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re still in the very early days of commercializing quantum computing and for most current users, having access to a system over the cloud is sufficient for the experiments they are running. But increasingly, we are seeing research institutes and even some commercial users who are looking to install on-premises quantum computers to have full access to a dedicated machine.</p>
<p>This new deal is part of a larger partnership between IBM and the Cleveland Clinic, which also involves IBM&#8217;s hybrid cloud portfolio for high-performance computing and its AI tools. The partnership also forms the foundation of Cleveland Clinic&#8217;s new Center for Pathogen Research &amp; Human Health, which is supported by <a href="https://newsroom.clevelandclinic.org/2021/01/25/through-a-500-million-partnership-with-the-state-of-ohio-jobsohio-and-ohio-development-services-agency-cleveland-clinic-forms-global-center-for-pathogen-research-human-health/">$500 million</a> in investments from the State of Ohio, Jobs Ohio and <span class="il">Cleveland</span> Clinic.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re announcing here is the first &#8212; I&#8217;m going to call them private sector or nonprofit &#8212; but still, it&#8217;s the first sort of non-government organization that is going to have not only fully dedicated systems, but what is really, really remarkable is our commitment for the decades,&#8221; Dario Gil, IBM&#8217;s SVP and Director of IBM Research, told me. &#8220;In a way, they are partnering with us for the entire roadmap. So it&#8217;s not only taking receipt and getting access to a fleet of quantum computers and the next-generation quantum computer for next year. They&#8217;re also the first ones who are signing up and says, &#8216;I want the first 1,000+ qubit system.&#8221;</p>
<p>He noted that it takes a very forward-looking organization to invest heavily in quantum computing today. It&#8217;s one thing for a nation-state to start working with this nascent technology, given the potential it has in a wide variety of fields, but it&#8217;s another for a non-profit to make a similar bet. &#8220;The level of ambition is really, really high on their end because they&#8217;re thinking about the future,&#8221; Gil said of the Cleveland Clinic&#8217;s leadership.</p>
<p>Gil noted that as part of the overall deal, Cleveland Clinic&#8217;s researchers will also get access to IBM&#8217;s entire quantum portfolio in the cloud. IBM will maintain and support the on-premises quantum computer and they will remain IBM-owned machines, similar to its deals with government research labs in Japan and Germany, he explained.</p>
<p>&#8220;Maintaining it and supporting it is really critical,&#8221; Gil said about why that&#8217;s the case. &#8220;And they need us and our expertise to be able to do that. And also, you know, we do it because it&#8217;s like one of the most sensitive technologies that we have in IBM. So we are exquisitely focused on maintaining the security and safety for the machines.&#8221;</p>
<p>As part of the overall deal, IBM and Cleveland Clinic will also work on building skills among Cleveland Clinic&#8217;s researchers in quantum computing, but also AI and high-performance computing.</p>
<p>&#8220;Through this innovative collaboration, we have a unique opportunity to bring the future to life,&#8221; said Tom Mihaljevic, M.D., President and CEO of <span class="il">Cleveland</span> Clinic. &#8220;These new computing technologies will revolutionize discovery in the life sciences and ultimately improve people’s lives. The Discovery Accelerator will enable our renowned teams to build a forward-looking digital infrastructure and transform medicine, while training the workforce of the future and growing our economy.&#8221;</p>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/ibm-brings-its-quantum-system-one-to-the-cleveland-clinic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131306</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google promises better 3D maps</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-promises-better-3d-maps/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-promises-better-3d-maps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[albertsons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zurich]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google is announcing a handful of major updates to Google Maps today that range from bringing its Live View AR directions indoors to adding weather data to its maps, but the most tantalizing news &#8212; which in typical Google fashion doesn&#8217;t have an ETA just yet &#8212; is that Google plans to bring a vastly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google is announcing a handful of major updates to Google Maps today that range from bringing its Live View AR directions indoors to adding weather data to its maps, but the most tantalizing news &#8212; which in typical Google fashion doesn&#8217;t have an ETA just yet &#8212; is that Google plans to bring a vastly improved 3D layer to Google maps.</p>
<p>Using photogrammetry, the same technology that also allows Microsoft&#8217;s Flight Simulator to render large swaths of the world in detail, Google is also building a model of the world for its Maps service.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re going to continue to improve that technology that helps us fuse together the billions of aerials, StreetView and satellite images that we have to really help us move from that flat 2D map to a more accurate 3D model than we&#8217;ve ever had. And be able to do that more quickly. And to bring more detail to it than we&#8217;ve ever been able to do before,&#8221; Dane Glasgow, Google&#8217;s VP for Geo Product Experience, said in a press event ahead of today&#8217;s announcement. He noted that this 3D layer will allow the company to visualize all its data in new and interesting ways.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2131509" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Google-Maps-3D.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131509" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2131509" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Google-Maps-3D.gif" alt="" width="800" height="450" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131509" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>How exactly this will play out in reality remains to be seen, but Glasgow showed off a new 3D route preview, for example, with all of the typically mapping data overlayed on top of the 3D map.</p>
<p>Glasgow also noted that this technology will allow Google to parse out small features like stoplights and building addresses, which in turn will result in better directions.</p>
<p>&#8220;We also think that the 3D imagery will allow us to visualize a lot of new information and data overlaid on top, you know, everything from helpful information like traffic or accidents, transit delays, crowdedness &#8212; there&#8217;s lots of potential here to bring new information,&#8221; he explained.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131510" style="width: 360px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Indoor-Live-View-2.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131510" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2131510" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Indoor-Live-View-2.gif" alt="" width="350" height="620" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131510" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>As for the more immediate future, Google announced a handful of new features today that are all going to roll out in the coming months. Indoor Live View is the flashiest of these. Google&#8217;s existing <a href="https://blog.google/products/maps/new-sense-direction-live-view/">AR Live View walking directions</a> currently only work outdoors, but thanks to some advances in its technology to recognize where exactly you are (even without a good GPS signal), the company is now able to bring this indoors. This feature is already live in some malls in the U.S. in <span style="font-weight: 400;">Chicago, Long Island, Los Angeles, Newark, San Francisco, San Jose, and Seattle, but in the coming months, it&#8217;ll come to select airports, malls and transit stations in Tokyo and Zurich as well (just in time for vaccines to arrive and travel to &#8212; maybe &#8212; rebound). Because Google is able to locate you by comparing the images around you to its database, it can also tell what floor you are on and hence guide you to your gate at the Zurich airport, for example (though in my experience, there are few places with better signage than airports&#8230;).</span></p>
<p>Also new are layers for weather data (but not weather radar) and air quality in Google Maps. The weather layer will be available globally on Android and iOS in the coming months, with the air quality layer only launching for Australia, India and the U.S. at first.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131513" style="width: 359px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131513" loading="lazy" class="vertical  wp-image-2131513" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png" alt="" width="349" height="619" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png 1127w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png?resize=85,150 85w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png?resize=169,300 169w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png?resize=768,1363 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png?resize=383,680 383w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png?resize=866,1536 866w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Air-Quality-Layer.png?resize=28,50 28w" sizes="(max-width: 349px) 100vw, 349px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2131513" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Talking about air quality, Google Maps will also get a new eco-friendly routing option that lets you pick the driving route that produces the least CO2 (coming to Android and iOS later this year), and it will finally feature support for low emission zones, a feature of many a European City. Low emission zones on Google Maps will launch in June in Germany, France, Spain and the UK on Android and iOS. More countries will follow later.</p>
<p>And to bring this all together, Google will update its directions interface to show you all of the possible modes of transportations and routing options, prioritized based on your own preferences, as well as based on what&#8217;s popular in the city you are in (think he subway in NYC or bike-sharing in Portland).</p>
<p>Also new are more integrated options for curbside grocery pickups in partnership with Instacart and Albertsons, if that&#8217;s your thing.</p>
<p>And there you have it. As is so often the case with Google&#8217;s announcement, the most exciting new features the company showed off don&#8217;t have an ETA and may never launch, but until then you can hold yourself over by getting your weather forecasts on Google Maps.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4ftldwsofm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/08/google-launches-live-view-ar-walking-directions-for-google-maps/">Google launches &#8216;Live View&#8217; AR walking directions for Google Maps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google launches &#8216;Live View&#8217; AR walking directions for Google Maps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/08/google-launches-live-view-ar-walking-directions-for-google-maps/embed/#?secret=4ftldwsofm" data-secret="4ftldwsofm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/google-promises-better-3d-maps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intranet startup Staffbase raises $145M  in growth round led by General Atlantic</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/intranet-startup-staffbase-raises-145m-in-growth-round-led-by-general-atlantic/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/intranet-startup-staffbase-raises-145m-in-growth-round-led-by-general-atlantic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 09:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Staffbase, which provides an intranet-style internal communications platform for companies, has raised a $145 million (€122 million) financing round led by General Atlantic, a growth equity firm. Existing investors Insight Partners and e.ventures also participated in the round. Started in Chemnitz in Germany in 2014, Staffbase has managed to onboard over 1,000 clients including Adidas, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://Staffbase.com">Staffbase</a>, which provides an intranet-style internal communications platform for companies, has raised a $145 million (€122 million) financing round led by General Atlantic, a growth equity firm. Existing investors Insight Partners and e.ventures also participated in the round.</p>
<p>Started in Chemnitz in Germany in 2014, Staffbase has managed to onboard over 1,000 clients including Adidas, Audi, BHP, Deutsche Post DHL, Groupon, Hitachi, Ikea, Johns Hopkins University, McKesson, Paulaner, Suncor, Viessmann, and Volvo, among others.</p>
<p>In early March this year, the company merged with Bananatag, the Canadian provider of internal communications solutions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic has of course accelerated the adoption of digital tools for companies, so Staffbase is reaping the benefits of that shift. The company&#8217;s main competitors include Dynamic Signal (raised $114.8M) and Social Chorus (raised $47M). In the category of intranets, competitors include Simpplr (raised $29.1M) and Unily (raised $68M).</p>
<p>Staffbase claims its advantages are that it brings together mobile employee apps and intranets into one platform, as well as integrating with the Microsoft 365 ecosystem, as well as the messaging platform Slack.</p>
<p>Dr. Martin Böhringer, co-founder and CEO of Staffbase, said in a statement: “We provide managers and communications specialists at enterprise companies with the leading digital platform for successful employee communications – a platform that we are expanding very rapidly. The partnership with General Atlantic will further help us achieve this and accelerate our growth, especially in North America.”</p>
<p>Dr. Christian Figge, managing director at General Atlantic, said: “Staffbase is a global pioneer and has developed software that specifically addresses the employee experience, supporting enterprises in transforming internal communications and engagement… Staffbase is a prime example of the quality of entrepreneurship and range of innovative companies with global ambitions emerging out of Germany.”</p>
<p>Staffbase has a workforce of 450 employees throughout 11 locations, including offices in London, New York, Vancouver, Amsterdam, and Berlin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/intranet-startup-staffbase-raises-145m-in-growth-round-led-by-general-atlantic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131745</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>IoT satellite network startup Hiber secures €26M in funding round led by EU’s innovation agency</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/iot-satellite-network-startup-hiber-secures-e26m-in-funding-round-led-by-eus-innovation-agency/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/iot-satellite-network-startup-hiber-secures-e26m-in-funding-round-led-by-eus-innovation-agency/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 08:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CFO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief executive officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Innovation Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european investment bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Space Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finch Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IoT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite constellation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite internet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[European satellite and communications startup, Hiber BV has secured €26 million in EU and private investment to expand its IoT satellite network.  The funding comes from the European Innovation Council Fund (EIC Fund), the EU’s innovation agency, which has a €278 million Innovation Fund. The EIC co-invested with an innovation credit provided by the Dutch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">European satellite and communications startup, <a href="https://hiber.global/">Hiber BV</a> has secured €26 million in EU and private investment to expand its IoT satellite network.  The funding comes from the European Innovation Council Fund (EIC Fund), the EU’s innovation agency, which has a €278 million Innovation Fund. The EIC co-invested with an innovation credit provided by the Dutch government and existing shareholders. Other investors include Finch Capital, Netherlands Enterprise Agency and Hartenlust Group. Hiber’s satellite constellation tracks and monitors machines and devices in harder-to-reach places.</p>
<p>At the same time co-founder of Hiber, Laurens Groenendijk, is to step aside as managing director to turn his attention to “other investment initiatives” the company said in a statement. Steven Kroonsberg joins as CFO. Roel Jansen joins as CCO. Groenendijk has been Co-founder and Chief Executive Officer at Treatwell as well as a serial investor.</p>
<p>Coen Janssen, Chief Strategy Officer and co-founder of Hiber, commented: “The €26 million funding is fantastic validation for Hiber’s success and a major boost for the European ‘New Space’ sector. It is a key step in realizing our aim of making the Internet of Things really simple and available for everyone in remote and developing regions of the world.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In particular, because it can reach out-of-the-way areas, Hiber&#8217;s network may be able to reduce losses in food production and leakages from oil wells.</p>
<p>Nicklas Bergman, European Innovation Council Fund Committee Member, commented: “I am glad to announce the EIC Fund support to this highly innovative company aiming at creating a European champion in the satellite Internet of Things sector. This equity financing will help Hiber to enable affordable and ubiquitous connectivity for the IoT solutions.”</p>
<p>Elia Montanari, Head of Management and Control at the European Space Agency, commented: “This major success has been supported at European level by collaboration of major EU bodies (EIC, EIB, ESA) fostering the Space Value Chain”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/iot-satellite-network-startup-hiber-secures-e26m-in-funding-round-led-by-eus-innovation-agency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131736</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore-based Nimbly gets $4.6M to help businesses automate their standard operating procedures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/singapore-based-nimbly-gets-4-6m-to-help-businesses-automate-their-standard-operating-procedures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/singapore-based-nimbly-gets-4-6m-to-help-businesses-automate-their-standard-operating-procedures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 08:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business operations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FMCG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and beverage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nimbly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many work teams, especially stores and restaurants, rely on manual spreadsheets to ensure their operations are running smoothly. Based in Singapore, Nimbly develops software that automates more of that process. Its features include digital checklists, inventory management and field audits that can be accessed through a mobile app. The startup announced today it has raised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Many work teams, especially stores and restaurants, rely on manual spreadsheets to ensure their operations are running smoothly. Based in Singapore, <a href="https://hellonimbly.com/">Nimbly</a> develops software that automates more of that process. Its features include digital checklists, inventory management and field audits that can be accessed through a mobile app. The startup announced today it has raised $4.6 million in pre-Series A funding, led by Insignia Ventures Partners, with participation from Sovereign’s Capital and Saison Capital.</p>
<p>Founded in 2018 by Daniel Hazman and Jonathan Keith, Nimbly is currently used by more than one hundred organizations in seven countries, including Indonesia, Singapore, Malaysia and the United States. Most of Nimbly’s users are in the retail or food and beverage industries, and include KFC, Kopi Kenangan, 7-Eleven and Under Armour. Some clients also come from the fast-moving consumer goods and agriculture sectors, like Cargill and Wilmar.</p>
<p>The new funding brings its total raised to $5.7 million and will be used for Nimbly’s Southeast Asia expansion, including a new partnership with restaurant operator Express Food Group, and adding products like more analytics, mystery shopper and employee training.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QnI0EBsZNZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/bukukas-raises-10-million-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-to-build-a-end-to-end-software-stack-for-indonesian-smes/">BukuKas raises $10 million led by Sequoia Capital India to build an &#8216;end-to-end software stack&#8217; for Indonesian SMEs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BukuKas raises $10 million led by Sequoia Capital India to build an &#8216;end-to-end software stack&#8217; for Indonesian SMEs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/11/bukukas-raises-10-million-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-to-build-a-end-to-end-software-stack-for-indonesian-smes/embed/#?secret=QnI0EBsZNZ" data-secret="QnI0EBsZNZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Nimbly is designed to replace spreadsheets, emails and messaging apps by combining their functionalities into one app. This includes checklists, audits and live video to ensure that standard operating procedures are followed across all locations. For example, restaurants may use Nimbly to see if food safety and hygiene standards are being followed. FMCG companies can use it to track inventory at stores and share information about how their sales and promotions compare to competitors, while use cases for agriculture include verifying that suppliers are following sustainability measure at their farms.</p>
<p>In a statement, Insignia Venture Partners founding managing partner Yinglan Tan said, “SaaS enterprise is an emerging vertical in Southeast Asia with more businesses of all sizes and across industries seeking to transition and even upgrade their capabilities to software tools. That makes us very excited to have partnered with Daniel, Jonathan and their team at Nimbly as they lead this space in building software stack capable of serving the operational needs of companies first in Southeast Asia, and then globally.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7VaWsquR45"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/ikala-an-ai-based-customer-engagement-platform-raises-17-million-to-expand-in-southeast-asia/">AI-based customer engagement platform iKala raises $17 million to expand in Southeast Asia</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AI-based customer engagement platform iKala raises $17 million to expand in Southeast Asia&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/ikala-an-ai-based-customer-engagement-platform-raises-17-million-to-expand-in-southeast-asia/embed/#?secret=7VaWsquR45" data-secret="7VaWsquR45" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/singapore-based-nimbly-gets-4-6m-to-help-businesses-automate-their-standard-operating-procedures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131729</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tutor marketplace GoStudent raises €70M Series B round led by new US investor Coatue</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tutor-marketplace-gostudent-raises-e70m-series-b-round-led-by-new-us-investor-coatue/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tutor-marketplace-gostudent-raises-e70m-series-b-round-led-by-new-us-investor-coatue/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 08:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vienna-based GoStudent, which connects students to tutors on a virtual learning platform, has raised a €70M Series B funding round led by new US investor Coatue. Coatue has been making &#8216;raids&#8217; into the European startup scene for the past year or so. It was joined by existing investors Left Lane Capital and DN Capital. This [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Vienna-based GoStudent, which connects students to tutors on a virtual learning platform, has raised a €70M Series B funding round led by new US investor Coatue. Coatue has been making &#8216;raids&#8217; into the European startup scene for the past year or so. It was joined by existing investors Left Lane Capital and DN Capital. This brings the total amount raised to €83.3M.</p>
<p>GoStudent competes with offline players like Schülerhilfe in Germany and Acadomia in France, which focus on small-classes in learning centers. By doing it online, GoStudent can introduce cost savings for users. It also competes where tutors advertise in traditional marketplaces like classified ads. The offering is similar to Chinese players like Zhangmen, VIPKid, TAL Education.</p>
<p>The investment will be used for growth and expansion into international markets such as Turkey and Greece. GoStudent is aiming for 15 countries across Europe and to grow its team to +800 employees and +10,000 tutors. It claims that over 250,000 tutoring sessions are booked every month on its platforms.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ePA4edVJWW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/tutor-marketplace-gostudent-takes-its-series-a-to-e13-3m-with-left-lane-capital-and-dn-capital/">Tutor marketplace GoStudent takes its Series A to €13.3M with Left Lane Capital and DN Capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Tutor marketplace GoStudent takes its Series A to €13.3M with Left Lane Capital and DN Capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/tutor-marketplace-gostudent-takes-its-series-a-to-e13-3m-with-left-lane-capital-and-dn-capital/embed/#?secret=ePA4edVJWW" data-secret="ePA4edVJWW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Felix Ohswald, co-founder and CEO of GoStudent said in a statement: “The series B investment makes us the best-funded consumer K12 education start-up in Europe! We are thrilled to receive such high confidence from existing and new investors on our way to revolutionize education worldwide. Our growth targets this year are enormous &#8211; the investment of 70 million euros will enable us to position GoStudent as the top player in Europe for making high-quality education widely accessible.”</p>
<p>Harley Miller, Managing Partner at Left Lane Capital said: “It’s been an exciting journey as an investor to see GoStudent expand so elegantly across Europe, offering affordable yet high-quality education to the masses.”</p>
<p>Nenad Marovac, Managing Partner &amp; CEO at DN Capital: “We believe that GoStudent can be the dominant winner in online tutoring in Europe, by leveraging technology GoStudent democratizes quality education to all.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/tutor-marketplace-gostudent-raises-e70m-series-b-round-led-by-new-us-investor-coatue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131730</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finch Capital acquires Wirecard Turkey</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/finch-capital-acquires-wirecard-turkey/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/finch-capital-acquires-wirecard-turkey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finch Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wirecard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finch Capital, the early-stage fintech VC with a presence in London and Amsterdam, is acquiring Wirecard Turkey, a subsidiary of Wirecard, the disgraced fintech out of Germany. The acquisition, for which terms remain undisclosed and is still subject to regulatory approval, sees Finch create a new Ireland-registered entity called Nomu Pay. After facing a huge [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.finchcapital.com/">Finch Capital</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/finch-capital-launches-third-fund/">the early-stage fintech VC</a> with a presence in London and Amsterdam, is acquiring Wirecard Turkey, a subsidiary of Wirecard, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/house-of-wirecard-insolvency/">disgraced fintech out of Germany</a>. The acquisition, for which terms remain undisclosed and is still subject to regulatory approval, sees Finch create a new Ireland-registered entity called Nomu Pay.</p>
<p>After facing a huge accounting scandal and failing to make payments on its own loans, Wirecard went into insolvency last year. Since then, various parts of its business have been bought, including one of its largest assets, Wirecard Solutions, which was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/28/railsbank-wirecard/">acquired by the U.K.&#8217;s Railsbank</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uDFyRuIKVd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/house-of-wirecard-insolvency/">Wirecard, the disgraced German payments firm backed by SoftBank, files for insolvency over €1.3B in loans coming due</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wirecard, the disgraced German payments firm backed by SoftBank, files for insolvency over €1.3B in loans coming due&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/25/house-of-wirecard-insolvency/embed/#?secret=uDFyRuIKVd" data-secret="uDFyRuIKVd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Finch&#8217;s managing partner Radboud Vlaar tells me Noma Pay’s larger plan is to invest in payments infrastructure in Turkey and the Middle East region. He says that more details will be provided on the new entity&#8217;s strategy and branding once the deal has formally closed.</p>
<p>Explains Vlaar: &#8220;We see tremendous  growth opportunities to further enhance payments for Turkey&#8217;s 80 million inhabitants. We are excited to team up with Wirecard Turkey under the leadership of its CEO Serkan Yasin and we continue to actively look for further M&amp;A opportunities in the region to accelerate its growth and development&#8221;.</p>
<p>Wirecard Turkey (Wirecard Ödeme ve Elektronik Para Hizmetleri A.Ş.) was established in Turkey in July 2008 and started its operations the following year as the country&#8217;s first &#8220;direct carrier billing&#8221; service provider. In 2014, it was wholly acquired by Wirecard Issuing &amp; Acquiring Gmbh, which is a subsidiary of Wirecard AG.</p>
<p>Today, the Turkish company provides various payment services, namely: direct carrier billing, credit card acquiring, and e-money. It has contracts with all three GSM operators and the majority of banks in Turkey, and more than 1,200 merchants.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is great talent in Turkey to build a leading next generation payments company,&#8221; adds Vlaar.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/finch-capital-acquires-wirecard-turkey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131219</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Men’s health startup Manual raises $30M Series A from US and European investors</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mens-health-startup-manual-raises-30m-series-a-from-us-and-european-investors/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mens-health-startup-manual-raises-30m-series-a-from-us-and-european-investors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 07:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antoine Nussenbaum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cherry Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[felix capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FJ Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[well being]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Men’s health and wellbeing startup Manual has raised a $30m Series A round from US-based Sonoma Brands and Waldencast, and Manual’s existing European investors Felix Capital and Cherry Ventures. FJ Labs and the GISEV Family Office also participated in the round. The cash will be used for product development and international expansion. Manual provides diagnostics, treatments [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Men’s health and wellbeing startup <a href="https://www.manual.co/">Manual</a> has raised a $30m Series A round from US-based Sonoma Brands and Waldencast, and Manual’s existing European investors Felix Capital and Cherry Ventures. FJ Labs and the GISEV Family Office also participated in the round. The cash will be used for product development and international expansion. Manual provides diagnostics, treatments and ongoing care and plans to expand across Europe, Asia and Latin America. The company has already expanded to Brazil.</p>
<p>Manual is competing with Numan (raised $13M), also from the UK (Manual launched a month earlier than them). In the US it is competing with Ro (raised $876.1M) and Hims (listed). All these brands tend to focus on issues like vitamins and erectile dysfunction, with the, often common refrain of, ‘normalizing’ the idea that men should look after themselves better, across a number of fronts and removing stigma’s around sexual health. It performs blood tests and other tests to analyze heart health, gut health, testosterone, sleep, energy, and immunity. They are pushing at a large market, as men historically avoid doctors.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131723" style="width: 779px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131723" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellbeing-Flow.jpg" alt="Manual app" width="769" height="344" class="size-full wp-image-2131723" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellbeing-Flow.jpg 769w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellbeing-Flow.jpg?resize=150,67 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellbeing-Flow.jpg?resize=300,134 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellbeing-Flow.jpg?resize=680,304 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellbeing-Flow.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 769px) 100vw, 769px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131723" class="wp-caption-text">Manual app</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>George Pallis, CEO and Founder, previously led marketing at Wise and Deliveroo. In a statement he said: “We’ve been encouraged to see men of all ages increasingly turning to Manual to solve multiple health problems, with almost half of our customers seeking help for more than one issue. It’s clear that a health concern may have more than one cause, and we can provide customers with the ability to treat their health in a more holistic way. Using different treatments to understand and improve their wellbeing.”</p>
<p>Speaking to during an interview Pallis added: “We built our own teleconsultation product and have different applications for the blood test offering. When you get your results we will offer a clinician, we&#8217;ll walk you through all the data and the learnings. We offer tools where people can monitor their progress and have regular check-ins with our medical team.”</p>
<p>Antoine Nussenbaum, co-Founder and partner of Felix Capital, commented: “There is still much work to be done to remove the taboo when it comes to men looking after their wellbeing and talking openly about health concerns. But we’re starting to see a shift happen amongst consumers.”</p>
<p>Kevin Murphy, Managing Director of Sonoma Brands, commented: “Manual exists to empower men to take better care of themselves and to live fuller lives by doing so. George and his team have the clarity of vision and the skill to make Manual a leader in this exciting and important area.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/mens-health-startup-manual-raises-30m-series-a-from-us-and-european-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131721</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>African talent recruitment company TalentQL joins Techstars to further global ambition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/african-talent-recruitment-company-talentql-joins-techstars-to-further-global-ambition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/african-talent-recruitment-company-talentql-joins-techstars-to-further-global-ambition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethiopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Techstars Toronto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[African-focused talent recruitment and outsourcing company TalentQL today announced that it has been accepted into Techstars Toronto. The company will join nine other startups in the accelerator&#8217;s class of 2021. This comes two weeks after Nigerian bus-booking platform Plentywaka announced its participation in the program as well. TalentQL was launched last November by serial entrepreneurs Adewale Yusuf, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">African-focused talent recruitment and outsourcing company</span><a href="http://talentql.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">TalentQL</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> today announced that it has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">been accepted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> into Techstars Toronto</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company will join nine other startups in the accelerator&#8217;s class of 2021. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This comes two weeks after Nigerian bus-booking platform Plentywaka <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/17/nigerias-plentywaka-gets-backing-from-techstars-plans-expansion-to-canada/">announced its participation</a> in the program as well</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TalentQL </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was launched</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> last November by serial entrepreneurs</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adewaleyusuf/?ppe=1"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Adewale Yusuf</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/opeawo"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Opeyemi Awoyemi</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="https://ng.linkedin.com/in/hacksultan"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Akintunde Sultan.</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Before TalentQL, Yusuf co-founded Nigeria-based tech media publication Techpoint Africa; Awoyemi co-founded online recruitment site Jobberman; and Sultan founded nonprofit tech accelerator DevCareer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has a &#8220;talent pool&#8221; developers join before passing through different assessments. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once the engineers pass the assessments, they can join the company&#8217;s &#8220;talent network&#8221; to access opportunities</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic accelerated the need for international companies to seek cheaper and remote talent around the world. TalentQL is hoping to tap into what it thinks is a gold mine. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to CEO Yusuf, the company, which is also U.S.-based, wants to decentralize access and democratize opportunity for Africa&#8217;s top tech talents. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For most of its local clients, TalentQL </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">mainly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> assists with recruitment. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The other model entails hiring vetted engineers for international companies, managing them, and providing tax and health insurance services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We&#8217;re coming to the market to support the talent with health insurance, some tools to work with and a community to be part of. These are some of the offerings </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> sets us apart from other companies,&#8221; Yusuf said to TechCrunch over a phone call.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But despite that, the company has faced the same challenge that has plagued the space &#8212; the lack of senior engineering talent. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When most engineers reach that level of expertise, they tend to leave the country to the U.S. and Europe for better opportunities or, better still, launch their own startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It&#8217;s a problem Andela faced in the past, resulting in the layoff of 400 junior developers “due to market demand for more senior engineering talent.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OmbLvB7dbj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/africa-focused-andela-cuts-400-staff-as-it-confirms-50m-in-revenue/">Africa-focused Andela cuts 400 staff as it confirms $50M in revenue</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Africa-focused Andela cuts 400 staff as it confirms $50M in revenue&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/17/africa-focused-andela-cuts-400-staff-as-it-confirms-50m-in-revenue/embed/#?secret=OmbLvB7dbj" data-secret="OmbLvB7dbj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yusuf says this is why the company is pursuing a Pan-African and diasporan play (Africans in the U.S. and Europe), hoping to fill in the gap with senior talent from these places</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And to further </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">consolidate</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its Pan-African ambitions, it is planning to open an office in Kenya in the coming months.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although TalentQL is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">fully</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> remote, Yusuf says this has to happen to establish the right kind of understanding between on-the-ground recruiters and the engineers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We want a situation where when we&#8217;re recruiting from other countries, our technical recruiters are from those countries</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We want them to be able to speak the language of these engineers and understand the culture of their countries,&#8221; the CEO added.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2131725" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2131725" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2131725" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TalentQL-11.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="521" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TalentQL-11.jpg 913w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TalentQL-11.jpg?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TalentQL-11.jpg?resize=300,230 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TalentQL-11.jpg?resize=768,589 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TalentQL-11.jpg?resize=680,521 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TalentQL-11.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2131725" class="wp-caption-text">The TalentQL team</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TalentQL currently has over 100 tech skills available with more than 2,000 developers on its platform. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">These developers cater to clients from the U.S., Europe, Nigeria and Kenya. The CEO says the company is also in talks with some Fortune 500 companies to execute placements for their African expansion</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p>In addition to the <a href="https://techpoint.africa/2020/11/17/talentql-raises-300k-pre-seed-zedcrest-capital/">$300,000 pre-seed secured last year</a>, the 6-month-old company will receive a $120,000 investment from Techstars. But<span style="font-weight: 400;"> besides the funding, Techstars&#8217; backing will be crucial in two ways, according to Yusuf. First is how it operates going forward in a crowded tech talent marketplace with the likes of Ethiopia&#8217;s Gebeya and Nigeria&#8217;s Decagon and Semicolon. The other would be helping the company to be a global company, not </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> an African one</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Sunil Sharma, the managing director of Techstars Toronto and an investor in five Nigerian startups, Techstars&#8217; investment in TalentQL gives the accelerator a chance to participate in the burgeoning tech talent space. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The rise of Nigeria is more </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">widely</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> appreciated now </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in terms of</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> technology sectors like finance, mobility and e-commerce, where talented Nigerians are not only bringing innovation and disruption but are doing so </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rapidly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and at scale,&#8221; he said.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8220;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Equally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as intriguing is the opportunity relating to talent itself as Nigerians and Africans across the continent are contributing more to supporting tech companies across the world, and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we think</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the start</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/african-talent-recruitment-company-talentql-joins-techstars-to-further-global-ambition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131443</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everli, the European marketplace for online grocery shopping, bags $100M Series C</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/everli/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/everli/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 05:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Everli]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2130393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everli, the European marketplace for online grocery shopping that started in Italy but now also operates in Poland, Czech Republic and France, has raised a $100 million in Series C funding. The round is led by Verlinvest, with participation from new investors Luxor, DN Capital, C4 Ventures, and Convivialité Ventures. FITEC (part of Fondo Italiano [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://everli.com/">Everli</a>, the European marketplace for online grocery shopping that started in Italy but now also operates in Poland, Czech Republic and France, has raised a $100 million in Series C funding.</p>
<p>The round is led by Verlinvest, with participation from new investors Luxor, DN Capital, C4 Ventures, and Convivialité Ventures. FITEC (part of Fondo Italiano d’Investimento), 360 Capital, Innogest, and DIP also followed on.</p>
<p>Everli, formerly called Supermercato24, says it will use the injection of capital to accelerate growth and further expand its international footprint.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded in 2014, Everli lets customers order from local supermarkets for delivery. The company uses gig economy-styled personal shoppers who go into the store and ‘pick’ the products ordered and then deliver them same-day, or for an added cost within an hour. The company charges a delivery fee to consumers, but also generates revenue from fees charged to partnering merchants, and, notably, through advertising.</p>
<p>It has become the delivery partner of some of Europe’s largest grocery brands, offering access to over 300,000 products across the 70 cities it operates in. And, like other online grocery offerings, Everli has benefited from a boost in e-commerce and a reliance on delivery services prompted by the pandemic and country lockdowns.</p>
<p>&#8220;Everli is focused specifically on the grocery space,&#8221; says Federico Sargenti, CEO at Everli. &#8220;Rather than small baskets, or picking up just the basic essentials, Everli is focused on delivering whatever you need right up to your full weekly shop, with same-day delivery and a one-hour delivery window of your choice.&#8221;</p>
<p>He says that what further differentiates Everli is its strong relationships with retailers, and the use of their existing infrastructure. &#8220;Instead of being tethered and restricted to a radius around our own expensive central warehouses, we are able to operate across a much wider geographical footprint, entering small-to-medium density areas and offering many customers their first opportunity to receive same day groceries, [all] while retaining sustainable unit economics&#8221;.</p>
<p>Sargenti describes Everli as more similar to Instacart than many other European delivery firms, including the new crop of dark stores or those that offer groceries as a secondary service to takeouts. &#8220;[This is] why we’re leading the grocery space in Europe and securing brands like Lidl, Kaufland, and Carrefour,&#8221; adds Sargenti.</p>
<p>In 2020, Everli sales almost quadrupled to $130 million. That growth is happening more and more outside Italy, with its international expansion now responsible for over 20% of orders.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are proud to have played a role in helping many people during these difficult times, but we are only getting started, as this industry will never be the same again,&#8221; says Sargenti in a statement. &#8220;The shift to online delivery is not reversing, and expectations on all sides are only increasing. We have built a model which we believe offers unparalleled value to consumers, through wide access to the retailers and products they love, even in less urban areas, and to retailers, who are now able to affordably compete online and reach a whole new consumer base&#8221;.</p>
<p>Adds Simone Sallustio, Executive Director at Verlinvest: “Everli combines its tech &amp; data excellence with the grocery retail experience of its partners and this combination provides it with the perfect position to cement itself as the European e-grocery market leader, delivering the best experience to consumers, value to retail partners, and digital activation to brands&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/everli/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2130393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Testing platform Tricentis acquires performance testing service Neotys</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/testing-platform-tricentis-acquires-performance-testing-service-neotys/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/testing-platform-tricentis-acquires-performance-testing-service-neotys/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 04:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[allianz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BNP Paribas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deutsche bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lufthansa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neotys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starbucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tricentis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131595</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you develop software for a large enterprise company, chances are you&#8217;ve heard of Tricentis. If you don&#8217;t develop software for a large enterprise company, chances are you haven&#8217;t. The software testing company with a focus on modern cloud and enterprise applications was founded in Austria in 2007 and grew from a small consulting firm [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you develop software for a large enterprise company, chances are you&#8217;ve heard of <a href="https://www.tricentis.com/">Tricentis</a>. If you don&#8217;t develop software for a large enterprise company, chances are you haven&#8217;t. The software testing company with a focus on modern cloud and enterprise applications was founded in Austria in 2007 and grew from a small consulting firm to a major player in this field, with customers like Allianz, BMW, Starbucks, Deutsche Bank, Toyota and UBS. In 2017, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/23/insight-ventures-invests-165-million-in-automated-testing-startup-tricentis/">raised</a> a $165 million Series B round led by Insight Venture Partners.</p>
<p>Today, Tricentis announced that it has acquired <a href="https://www.neotys.com/">Neotys</a>, a popular performance testing service with a focus on modern enterprise applications and a tests-as-code philosophy. The two companies did not disclose the price of the acquisition. France-based Neotys launched in 2005 and raised about €3 million before the acquisition. Today, it has about 600 customers for its NeoLoad platform. These include BNP Paribas, Dell, Lufthansa, McKesson and TechCrunch&#8217;s own corporate parent, Verizon.</p>
<p>As Tricentis CEO Sandeep Johri noted, testing tools were traditionally script-based, which also meant they were very fragile whenever an application changed. Early on, Tricentis introduced <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tricentis_Tosca">a low-code tool</a> that made the automation process both easier and resilient. Now, as even traditional enterprises move to DevOps and release code at a faster speed than ever before, testing is becoming both more important and harder for these companies to implement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;You have to have automation and you cannot have it be fragile, where it breaks, because then you spend as much time fixing the automation as you do testing the software,&#8221; Johri said. &#8220;Our core differentiator was the fact that we were a low-code, model-based automation engine. That&#8217;s what allowed us to go from $6 million in recurring revenue eight years ago to $200 million this year.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qsOdnqCSyZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/three-new-100m-arr-club-members-and-a-call-for-the-next-generation-of-growth-stage-startups/">3 new $100M ARR club members and a call for the next generation of growth-stage startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 new $100M ARR club members and a call for the next generation of growth-stage startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/24/three-new-100m-arr-club-members-and-a-call-for-the-next-generation-of-growth-stage-startups/embed/#?secret=qsOdnqCSyZ" data-secret="qsOdnqCSyZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Tricentis, he added, wants to be the testing platform of choice for large enterprises. &#8220;We want to make sure we do everything that a customer would need, from a testing perspective, end to end. Automation, test management, test data, test case design,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The acquisition of Neotys allows the company to expand this portfolio by adding load and performance testing as well. It&#8217;s one thing to do the standard kind of functional testing that Tricentis already did before launching an update, but once an application goes into production, load and performance testing becomes critical as well.</p>
<p>&#8220;Before you put it into production &#8212; or before you deploy it &#8212; you need to make sure that your application not only works as you expect it, you need to make sure that it can handle the workload and that it has acceptable performance,&#8221; Johri noted. &#8220;That&#8217;s where load and performance testing comes in and that&#8217;s why we acquired Neotys. We have some capability there, but that was primarily focused on the developers. But we needed something that would allow us to do end-to-end performance testing and load testing.&#8221;</p>
<p>The two companies already had an existing partnership and had integrated their tools before the acquisition &#8212; and many of its customers were already using both tools, too.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;We are looking forward to joining Tricentis, the industry leader in continuous testing,&#8221; said Thibaud Bussière, president and co-founder at Neotys. &#8220;Today’s Agile and DevOps teams are looking for ways to be more strategic and eliminate manual tasks and implement automated solutions to work more efficiently and effectively. As part of Tricentis, we’ll be able to eliminate laborious testing tasks to allow teams to focus on high-value analysis and performance engineering.&#8221;</p>
<p>NeoLoad will continue to exist as a stand-alone product, but users will likely see deeper integrations with Tricentis&#8217; existing tools over time, include <a href="https://documentation.tricentis.com/tricentis-analytics/130/en/content/tricentis_analytics/analytics_intro.htm">Tricentis Analytics</a>, for example.</p>
<p>Johri tells me that he considers Tricentis one of the &#8220;best kept secrets in Silicon Valley&#8221; because the company not only started out in Europe (even though its headquarters is now in Silicon Valley) but also because it hasn&#8217;t raised a lot of venture rounds over the years. But that&#8217;s very much in line with Johri&#8217;s philosophy of building a company.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of Silicon Valley tends to pay attention only when you raise money,&#8221; he told me. &#8220;I actually think every time you raise money, you&#8217;re diluting yourself and everybody else. So if you can succeed without raising too much money, that&#8217;s the best thing. We feel pretty good that we have been very capital efficient and now we&#8217;re recognized as a leader in the category &#8212; which is a huge category with $30 billion spend in the category. So we&#8217;re feeling pretty good about it.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hvgexECzIE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/23/insight-ventures-invests-165-million-in-automated-testing-startup-tricentis/">Insight Venture Partners invests $165 million in automated testing startup Tricentis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Insight Venture Partners invests $165 million in automated testing startup Tricentis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/01/23/insight-ventures-invests-165-million-in-automated-testing-startup-tricentis/embed/#?secret=hvgexECzIE" data-secret="hvgexECzIE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="ms-editor-squiggler" style="color: initial; font: initial; font-feature-settings: initial; font-kerning: initial; font-optical-sizing: initial; font-variation-settings: initial; forced-color-adjust: initial; text-orientation: initial; text-rendering: initial; -webkit-font-smoothing: initial; -webkit-locale: initial; -webkit-text-orientation: initial; -webkit-writing-mode: initial; writing-mode: initial; zoom: initial; place-content: initial; place-items: initial; place-self: initial; alignment-baseline: initial; animation: initial; appearance: initial; aspect-ratio: initial; backdrop-filter: initial; backface-visibility: initial; background: initial; background-blend-mode: initial; baseline-shift: initial; block-size: initial; border-block: initial; border: initial; border-radius: initial; border-collapse: initial; border-end-end-radius: initial; border-end-start-radius: initial; border-inline: initial; border-start-end-radius: initial; border-start-start-radius: initial; inset: initial; box-shadow: initial; box-sizing: initial; break-after: initial; break-before: initial; break-inside: initial; buffered-rendering: initial; caption-side: initial; caret-color: initial; clear: initial; clip: initial; clip-path: initial; clip-rule: initial; color-interpolation: initial; color-interpolation-filters: initial; color-rendering: initial; color-scheme: initial; columns: initial; column-fill: initial; gap: initial; column-rule: initial; column-span: initial; contain: initial; contain-intrinsic-size: initial; content: initial; content-visibility: initial; counter-increment: initial; counter-reset: initial; counter-set: initial; cursor: initial; cx: initial; cy: initial; d: initial; display: block; dominant-baseline: initial; empty-cells: initial; fill: initial; fill-opacity: initial; fill-rule: initial; filter: initial; flex: initial; flex-flow: initial; float: initial; flood-color: initial; flood-opacity: initial; grid: initial; grid-area: initial; height: 0px; hyphens: initial; image-orientation: initial; image-rendering: initial; inline-size: initial; inset-block: initial; inset-inline: initial; isolation: initial; letter-spacing: initial; lighting-color: initial; line-break: initial; list-style: initial; margin-block: initial; margin: initial; margin-inline: initial; marker: initial; mask: initial; mask-type: initial; max-block-size: initial; max-height: initial; max-inline-size: initial; max-width: initial; min-block-size: initial; min-height: initial; min-inline-size: initial; min-width: initial; mix-blend-mode: initial; object-fit: initial; object-position: initial; offset: initial; opacity: initial; order: initial; origin-trial-test-property: initial; orphans: initial; outline: initial; outline-offset: initial; overflow-anchor: initial; overflow-wrap: initial; overflow: initial; overscroll-behavior-block: initial; overscroll-behavior-inline: initial; overscroll-behavior: initial; padding-block: initial; padding: initial; padding-inline: initial; page: initial; page-orientation: initial; paint-order: initial; perspective: initial; perspective-origin: initial; pointer-events: initial; position: initial; quotes: initial; r: initial; resize: initial; ruby-position: initial; rx: initial; ry: initial; scroll-behavior: initial; scroll-margin-block: initial; scroll-margin: initial; scroll-margin-inline: initial; scroll-padding-block: initial; scroll-padding: initial; scroll-padding-inline: initial; scroll-snap-align: initial; scroll-snap-stop: initial; scroll-snap-type: initial; shape-image-threshold: initial; shape-margin: initial; shape-outside: initial; shape-rendering: initial; size: initial; speak: initial; stop-color: initial; stop-opacity: initial; stroke: initial; stroke-dasharray: initial; stroke-dashoffset: initial; stroke-linecap: initial; stroke-linejoin: initial; stroke-miterlimit: initial; stroke-opacity: initial; stroke-width: initial; tab-size: initial; table-layout: initial; text-align: initial; text-align-last: initial; text-anchor: initial; text-combine-upright: initial; text-decoration: initial; text-decoration-skip-ink: initial; text-indent: initial; text-overflow: initial; text-shadow: initial; text-size-adjust: initial; text-transform: initial; text-underline-offset: initial; text-underline-position: initial; touch-action: initial; transform: initial; transform-box: initial; transform-origin: initial; transform-style: initial; transition: initial; user-select: initial; vector-effect: initial; vertical-align: initial; visibility: initial; -webkit-app-region: initial; border-spacing: initial; -webkit-border-image: initial; -webkit-box-align: initial; -webkit-box-decoration-break: initial; -webkit-box-direction: initial; -webkit-box-flex: initial; -webkit-box-ordinal-group: initial; -webkit-box-orient: initial; -webkit-box-pack: initial; -webkit-box-reflect: initial; -webkit-highlight: initial; -webkit-hyphenate-character: initial; -webkit-line-break: initial; -webkit-line-clamp: initial; -webkit-mask-box-image: initial; -webkit-mask: initial; -webkit-mask-composite: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-x: initial; -webkit-perspective-origin-y: initial; -webkit-print-color-adjust: initial; -webkit-rtl-ordering: initial; -webkit-ruby-position: initial; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: initial; -webkit-text-combine: initial; -webkit-text-decorations-in-effect: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis: initial; -webkit-text-emphasis-position: initial; -webkit-text-fill-color: initial; -webkit-text-security: initial; -webkit-text-stroke: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-x: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-y: initial; -webkit-transform-origin-z: initial; -webkit-user-drag: initial; -webkit-user-modify: initial; white-space: initial; widows: initial; width: initial; will-change: initial; word-break: initial; word-spacing: initial; x: initial; y: initial; z-index: initial;"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/testing-platform-tricentis-acquires-performance-testing-service-neotys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131595</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jake Paul looks to knock out the venture capital world with Anti Fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/jake-paul-looks-to-knock-out-the-venture-capital-world-with-anti-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/jake-paul-looks-to-knock-out-the-venture-capital-world-with-anti-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 23:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angellist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Dixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Groupon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influencer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Andreessen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Triller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During every economic boom, there are startup investors who appear on the scene from new corners. Some churn out; others earn the respect of the old guard over time. Jake Paul would be happy to be in the latter camp. Then again, the 24-year-old didn&#8217;t become a social media star by being conventional. Little wonder [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">During every economic boom, there are startup investors who appear on the scene from new corners. Some churn out; others earn the respect of the old guard over time.</p>
<p>Jake Paul would be happy to be in the latter camp. Then again, the 24-year-old didn&#8217;t become a social media star by being conventional. Little wonder that Paul is now jumping into venture capital with an outfit that&#8217;s branded the <a href="https://angel.co/v/back/anti-fund">Anti Fund</a>. Newly formed with serial entrepreneur Geoffrey Woo, the endeavor is traditional in some ways but has a decidedly different point of view, say the two.</p>
<p>Some of the basics: Anti Fund is not a discrete pool of capital but is instead using AngelList&#8217;s Rolling Funds platform, which enables investors to raise money through a quarterly subscription from interested backers. Among those who&#8217;ve already committed capital are Marc Andreessen and Chris Dixon of Andreessen Horowitz.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Why choose a rolling fund instead of a traditional fund? For one thing, Paul and Woo were drawn to its Rule 506(c) structure, which allows issuers to broadly solicit an offering. Because Anti Fund plans to focus largely on consumer-focused opportunities and next-generation creator platforms in particular, it wants to be &#8220;able to promote and advertise our fund,&#8221; says Woo, who most recently founded a nutrition-based <a href="https://hvmn.com/">food and beverage company</a> and earlier in his career <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/01/11/groupon-acquires-realtime-location-aware-service-glassmap-to-help-you-find-deals/">sold a company</a> to Groupon.</p>
<p>Paul relatedly wants to ensure his fans can get involved if they like. &#8220;I have followers are different reasons, and they want to be involved in what I&#8217;m doing. If they&#8217;re involved in our fund, then that&#8217;s more people rooting for us and our portfolio companies to win. We almost create this army that&#8217;s pushing all of these companies forward.&#8221;</p>
<p>As for check sizes, Anti Fund plans to invest between $100,000 and $1 million in one to two startups every quarter. The goal, says Paul, is to be the &#8220;biggest rolling fund on AngelList,&#8221; investing &#8220;around $10 million to $20 million a year.&#8221;</p>
<p>Anti Fund is just the newest effort to come from the world of social media influencers. As we reported <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/mrbeasts-management-company-night-media-has-a-new-venture-fund-thats-backed-by-creators/">earlier this month</a>, the management company of another YouTube star, MrBeast, has dived into the world of venture capital with a $20 million fund it assembled with commitments from social media creators. Dispo, a photo-sharing app cofounded by YouTube star David Dobrik also attracted <a href="https://www.axios.com/scoop-david-dobriks-retro-photo-app-dispo-raises-20-million-0a056861-6ea2-46d2-92af-eda697eb179b.html">widespread attention</a> and funding earlier this year.</p>
<p>A new startup called <a href="https://getjuice.com/">Creative Juice</a> just raised funding, too, to provide <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/mrbeast-explains-his-plans-to-help-youtube-creators-raise-equity-finance">equity-based financing</a> to YouTube creators. MrBeast, whose real name is Jimmy Donaldson, is among its investors. (It make a lot of sense, suggests Woo, who says that Anti Fund believes firmly that &#8220;individuals will become their own media channels.&#8221;)</p>
<p>Roughly <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/22/style/byte-vine-short-video-apps.html">10 years</a> into the influencer phenomenon, the trend isn&#8217;t surprising. &#8220;I think a lot of creators with newfound wealth &#8212; a lot of YouTubers or Instagram models &#8212; don&#8217;t necessarily know what to do with their money,&#8221; says Paul, who has already diversified into boxing, making his professional boxing debut last year. &#8220;I&#8217;m trying to lead the way.&#8221;</p>
<p>Neither Paul nor Woo is new to startup investing. Woo has invested in roughly 20 startups on his own, including Paribus, an email widget that saved consumers money and that was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/10/06/capital-one-acquires-online-price-tracker-paribus/">acquired</a> by Capital One. Paul, meanwhile, previously cofounded another small venture outfit called <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/investor/tgz-capital">TGZ Capital</a> that he says participated in the funding rounds of 15 startups.</p>
<p>One of these is <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.getquip.com/">Quip</a>, a seven-year-old oral care company that has raised $62 million in funding, according to Crunchbase. Another company backed by Paul is <a href="https://www.triller.co/">Triller</a>, a social video app that briefly became the most-downloaded free app in the App Store <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/andreabossi/2020/08/03/triller-jumps-to-no-1-on-the-app-store-overtakes-tiktok-as-drama-continues/?sh=13bf86496d4a">last summer</a> when bigger rival TikTok was facing an uncertain future in the U.S.</p>
<p>Triller has since lost enough of that momentum that talk of going public via a special purpose acquisition vehicle has yet to lead to a tie-up, six months after the company reportedly began <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-triller-m-a-exclusive/exclusive-tiktok-rival-triller-explores-deal-to-go-public-sources-idUSKBN26W0V5">exploring the possibility</a>. Still, as a stakeholder, Paul is keeping it in the headlines, including by providing it with exclusive rights to stream a <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/jake-paul-vs-ben-askren-start-date-how-to-watch-online-press-conference-shenanigans">pay-per-view boxing match</a> between himself with former MMA wrestler Ben Asken on April 17.</p>
<p>Interestingly, it&#8217;s because Paul moved from L.A. to Miami to train for the fight that he met Woo, a Californian who visited Miami this past January for what was supposed to be a weekend trip and wound up staying. The two say they happened to hit it off at a tech event and, after establishing they had mutual friends, connected over their interest in performance nutrition, with Paul investing in Woo&#8217;s newest company, HVMN.</p>
<p>Last month, they decided to partner on Anti Fund, too.</p>
<p>Whether the two succeed as business partners will take time to learn. Certainly, they both have a strong work ethic. Woo has started three companies since graduating from Stanford with a computer science degree. Though Paul makes what seems an inordinate amount of money for creating YouTube videos, he has created thousands of them in order to amass his more than 20 million followers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also clear that, as with his social media career, Paul is taking boxing <a href="https://www.menshealth.com/entertainment/a30456685/jake-paul-pro-boxer-interview/">seriously</a>. During his most recent fight, in November, he <a href="https://www.cbssports.com/boxing/news/jake-paul-vs-nate-robinson-fight-results-highlights-paul-scores-scary-knockout-in-second-round/live/">knocked out</a> former NBA player Nate Robinson in the second round. His first boxing match, against fellow YouTuber AnEsonGib in January of last year, also ended in a knockout just minutes into the fight.</p>
<p>Many professional athletes see the fights as mere stunts, given Paul&#8217;s famous made-for-video antics, from a short-lived <a href="https://www.etonline.com/jake-paul-admits-tana-mongeau-marriage-was-fake-gives-julia-rose-relationship-update-exclusive">marriage</a>, to <a href="https://la.curbed.com/2017/7/19/16001358/jake-paul-house-neighbors-youtube">disregarding</a> the concerns of neighbors in West Hollywood, to being charged by police last June for <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/06/04/jake-paul-youtube-riot-looting/">criminal trespass and unlawful assembly</a> connected with the looting of an Arizona mall.</p>
<p>An obvious risk is that the best deal-makers in the world will see Anti Fund as a stunt, too, or else that something that Paul says or does will ruffle feathers. As industry watchers know, investors&#8217; excitement over Dobrik&#8217;s Dispo <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/spark-capital-decides-to-sever-all-ties-with-david-dobriks-dispo-app-weeks-after-leading-investment/">dissipated quickly</a> after Business Insider <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/vlog-squad-durte-dom-rape-allegation-david-dobrik-zeglaitis-video-2021-3">first detailed</a> various accusations of misconduct against members of the Dobrik&#8217;s online squad, including an accusation of rape that allegedly took place during a video shoot.</p>
<p>Paul, who finished high school online in order to pursue a career as an influencer, is well aware of the Dobrik scandal. It&#8217;s because he has grown up in plain view, in fact, that he&#8217;s not concerned about something from his past threatening his future.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s definitely [risky to be in my position]. Your life is put on display when you choose to be a celebrity and specifically a vlogger. But because I&#8217;ve lived online, everyone&#8217;s seen everything already,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>He also thinks that &#8220;VCs and people in the business world understand more and more how to work&#8221; with influencers and other celebrities who have enormous followings and are bringing them along as their careers evolve. &#8220;At the end of the day,&#8221; he says of business dealings, &#8220;if someone is a good person and you have a relationship established with them, that&#8217;s what really matters.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/jake-paul-looks-to-knock-out-the-venture-capital-world-with-anti-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131361</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LIVEKINDLY screams its way to the top of new plant brands with the close of a $335 million round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/livekindly-screams-its-way-to-the-top-of-new-plant-brands-with-the-close-of-a-335-million-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/livekindly-screams-its-way-to-the-top-of-new-plant-brands-with-the-close-of-a-335-million-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 22:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beyond Meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellular agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eat Just]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impossible foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LIVEKINDLY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LIVEKINDLY Collective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nestle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plant-based food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rabobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rise Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[s2g ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unilever]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LIVEKINDLY Collective, the shouty parent company behind a family of plant-based food brands, has snagged cash from the global impact investing arm of $103 billion investment firm TPG to close its latest round of funding at $335 million. The company&#8217;s fundraising shows that investors still have high hopes for plant-based food brands and that despite [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://thelivekindlyco.com/">LIVEKINDLY Collective</a>, the shouty parent company behind a family of plant-based food brands, has snagged cash from the global impact investing arm of $103 billion investment firm TPG to close its latest round of funding at $335 million.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s fundraising shows that investors still have high hopes for plant-based food brands and that despite the money that&#8217;s flowed to companies like Beyond Meat and Impossible Foods &#8212; and the resurgence of older brands in the category like Quorn or Kelloggs&#8217; Morningstar Farms &#8212; there&#8217;s still a healthy appetite among investors for more brands.</p>
<p>LIVEKINDLY was founded by some heavy hitters from the food industry, including Kees Kruythoff, the former president of Unilever North America; Roger Lienhard, the founder of Blue Horizon; and Jodi Monelle, the chief executive and founder of LIVEKINDLY Media. Food industry veterans like Mick Van Ettinger, a former Unilever employee, and Aldo Uva, a former Nestlé employee, round out the team.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Founded as a rollup for a number of different vegetarian and alternative protein food brands, the LIVEKINDLY Collective is now one of the largest plant-based food companies, by funding.</p>
<p>The company said it would use the money to expand into the U.S. and China and to power additional acquisitions, partnerships and investments in plant-based foods.</p>
<p>The company raised money previously from S2G Ventures and Rabo Corporate Investments, the investment arm of the giant Dutch financial services firm, Rabobank.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fundamentally, the founding investors behind LIVEKINDLY believe that the technology has a long way to go before it matures. And it&#8217;s likely that this latest round will be LIVEKINDLY&#8217;s last before an initial public offering of its own. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vbTt3EqJOd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/startups-making-meat-alternatives-are-gaining-traction-worldwide/">Startups making meat alternatives are gaining traction worldwide</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups making meat alternatives are gaining traction worldwide&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/06/startups-making-meat-alternatives-are-gaining-traction-worldwide/embed/#?secret=vbTt3EqJOd" data-secret="vbTt3EqJOd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“We are building a global pureplay in plant-based alternatives &#8212; which we believe is the future of food,” said Roger Lienhard, founder and executive chairman of Blue Horizon and founder of LIVEKINDLY Collective. “In just one year, we have raised a significant amount of capital, which testifies to the urgency of our mission and the enormous investment opportunity it represents. We believe the momentum behind plant-based living will continue to grow in both the private and public markets.”</p>
<p>As a result of <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">its investment, Steve Ellis, co-managing partner of The Rise Fund, has joined the LIVEKINDLY Collective board of directors, effective March 1, 2021.</span></p>
<p>“We are excited to work with LIVEKINDLY Collective and its ecosystem of innovative companies and world-class leaders to meet the growing global demand for healthy, plant-based, clean-label options,” said Ellis. “The company’s unique, mission-driven model operates across the entire value chain, from seed to fork, to drive worldwide adoption of plant-based alternatives and create a healthier planet for all.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/livekindly-screams-its-way-to-the-top-of-new-plant-brands-with-the-close-of-a-335-million-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131508</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Boston Dynamics shows off its next commercial robot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/daily-crunch-boston-dynamics-shows-off-its-next-commercial-robot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/daily-crunch-boston-dynamics-shows-off-its-next-commercial-robot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 22:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2131564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve got the details on Boston Dynamics&#8217; upcoming warehouse robot Stretch, Apple releases security patches and Cazoo is going public via SPAC. This is your Daily Crunch for March 29, 2021. The big story: Boston Dynamics shows off its next commercial robot Boston Robotics continues its transformation from research organization to commercial robotics company: Stretch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We&#8217;ve got the details on Boston Dynamics&#8217; upcoming warehouse robot Stretch, Apple releases security patches and Cazoo is going public via SPAC. This is your Daily Crunch for March 29, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: Boston Dynamics shows off its next commercial robot</strong></p>
<p>Boston Robotics continues its transformation from research organization to commercial robotics company: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/this-is-boston-dynamics-next-commercial-robot/">Stretch is the company&#8217;s commercial version of Handle</a>, a wheeled robot that could navigate around objects and pick up a 100-pound crate. With Stretch, the wheels have become less prominent, while the team has added a &#8220;perception mast&#8221; that allows the robot to see while it moves around and picks objects in a warehouse environment.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Stretch is currently in prototype form. The company plans to build the first units this summer and actually make it available for sale next year.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/apple-releases-iphone-ipad-watch-security-patch-to-fix-zero-day-bug-under-active-attack/">Apple releases iPhone, iPad and Watch security patches for zero-day bug under active attack</a> — Apple said the vulnerability, discovered by security researchers at Google’s Project Zero, may have been “actively exploited” by hackers.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/ibm-launches-its-first-quantum-developer-certification/">IBM launches its first quantum developer certification</a> — The “IBM Quantum Developer Certification” focuses on IBM’s own software tools.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/didi-chuxing-expands-to-south-africa-to-take-on-bolt-and-uber/">DiDi Chuxing expands to South Africa, to take on Bolt and Uber</a> — Founded in 2012, the Beijing-based company claims to serve over 550 million users in 16 countries across Asia, Europe, Latin America and Australia.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/singular-is-a-new-paris-based-vc-firm-with-265-million/">Singular is a new Paris-based VC firm with $265M</a> — Raffi Kamber and Jérémy Uzan want to build a leading European VC firm from Paris.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/28/uks-cazoo-will-list-on-the-nyse-by-way-of-a-spac-valuing-it-at-7b-and-raising-1-6b/">UK’s Cazoo will list on the NYSE by way of a SPAC, valuing it at $7B and raising $1.6B</a> — The U.K. used-car sales portal has been on a major fundraising tear in the last year.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/the-nft-craze-will-be-a-boon-for-lawyers/">The NFT craze will be a boon for lawyers</a> — Legal implications are the crux of the NFT trend.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/will-the-pandemic-spur-a-smart-rebirth-for-cities/">Will the pandemic spur a smart rebirth for cities?</a> — In this time of urban reset, which smart city technologies will transform how we live our lives?</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/27/ceo-manish-chandra-and-investor-navin-chaddha-explain-why-poshmarks-series-a-deck-sings/">CEO Manish Chandra and investor Navin Chaddha explain why Poshmark’s Series A deck sings</a> — Beyond TAM, founders should explain how they&#8217;ll reach key metrics.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/visa-supports-transaction-settlement-with-usdc-stablecoin/">Visa supports transaction settlement with USDC stablecoin</a> — Visa has announced that transactions can be settled using USD Coin, a stablecoin powered by the Ethereum blockchain.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/united-states-myanmar-sanctions-internet/">US cuts trade ties to Myanmar, leaving internet access uncertain</a> — In a statement, U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai said the trade suspension would be “effective immediately” and will remain in place “until the return of a democratically elected government.”</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/tc-early-stage-will-dive-deep-on-how-to-fundraise-for-your-startup/">TC Early Stage will dive deep on how to fundraise for your startup</a> — Take a look at the fundraising sessions going down at TC Early Stage, which takes place later this week on April 1 and 2.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/daily-crunch-boston-dynamics-shows-off-its-next-commercial-robot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2131564</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
