<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 14:27:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>1910 Genetics&#8217; Jen Nwankwo and Playground Global&#8217;s Jory Bell are joining us for Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/1910-genetics-jen-nwankwo-and-playground-globals-jory-bell-are-joining-us-for-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/1910-genetics-jen-nwankwo-and-playground-globals-jory-bell-are-joining-us-for-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 14:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playground global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2181838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live gives you the chance to hear live from entrepreneurs who have successfully raised significant rounds of venture capital -- and from the investors who believed in them.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Our Extra Crunch Live series continues with some heavy hitters in August, including Jen Nwankwo, founder and CEO at 1910 Genetics, and Playground Global general partner Jory Bell. They&#8217;ll be with us live on <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-playground-global-and-1910-genetics">August 11 at 12 p.m. PT (3 p.m. ET)</a> to tell us all about how Nwankwo and her startup won over Bell and Playground as an investor, and as we do every week on Extra Crunch Live, we&#8217;ll conduct a live pitch feedback session featuring you, the members of our audience.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live gives you the chance to hear live from entrepreneurs who have successfully raised significant rounds of venture capital &#8212; and from the investors who believed in them. We go into detail about how the deal got done, and you&#8217;ll hear from both about what it takes to pitch VCs and what industry-leading VCs look for in prospective portfolio companies.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re thrilled to have Nwankwo and Bell joining us for this episode. Nwankwo founded and leads 1910 Genetics, which takes advantage of AI to accelerate the discovery and development of new drug therapies across a wide range of disease and condition categories. She has a Ph.D. in pharmacology and experimental therapeutics from Tufts University School of Medicine and participated in drug discovery development that led to the creation of Type 2 diabetes drug Trulicity prior to her graduate school work.</p>
<p>Bell&#8217;s career includes designing and building autonomous robots for deep-sea exploration, as well as a six-year stint at Apple designing notebooks for the consumer technology leader. Bell&#8217;s venture investment work began at Playground Global in 2015; he focuses on deep tech investments, including in aerospace, genomics, synthetic biology, and AI-assisted drug discovery, as in the case of 1910 Genetics.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live also features the ECL Pitch-off, where startups in the audience can virtually “raise their hand” to pitch their startup live on our stream. Our expert guests will give their feedback on each pitch. If you want to throw your hat in the ring, you have to show up.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is accessible to everyone, but only Extra Crunch members can access the content on demand. We do these every week, so there are scores of episodes across a wide variety of startup sectors in the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ecl/">ECL Library</a>. It’s but one of many reasons to become an Extra Crunch member. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Join here.</a></p>
<p>Interested in hanging with us for this upcoming episode? <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-playground-global-and-1910-genetics">Register here for free! </a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/1910-genetics-jen-nwankwo-and-playground-globals-jory-bell-are-joining-us-for-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2181838</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How one founder bucked the data-driven trend and created a startup based on inspiration</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/how-one-founder-bucked-the-data-driven-trend-and-created-a-startup-based-on-inspiration/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/how-one-founder-bucked-the-data-driven-trend-and-created-a-startup-based-on-inspiration/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 14:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Endel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Oleg Stavitsky and his co-founders started Endel, they didn&#8217;t necessarily expect for it to become a venture-backed business with the likes of Amazon&#8217;s Alexa Fund as investors. Stavitsky and his founding team describe themselves as a &#8220;collective of imaginative creatives and artists,&#8221; and the group had previously developed a unique set of apps for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When Oleg Stavitsky and his co-founders started Endel, they didn&#8217;t necessarily expect for it to become a venture-backed business with the likes of Amazon&#8217;s Alexa Fund as investors. Stavitsky and his founding team describe themselves as a &#8220;collective of imaginative creatives and artists,&#8221; and the group had previously developed a unique set of apps for children called Bubl that were designed to foster creative development and avoid the usual tropes of character-based kid-focused entertainment.</p>
<p>Endel is a wholly different project, delivering personalized soundscapes to its users that help them achieve states of focus, relaxation and sleep. These are tailored specifically to individual users, and have more in common with meditative exercises and other wellness techniques than with traditional music. And the company has attracted a lot of big-name attention, including a partnership with Grimes that originated when she reached out because she loved using the app and wanted to see if they could work together.</p>
<p>Oleg talks to us all about his experience building Endel, and what it&#8217;s like being part of a highly unconventional founder collective building a consumer tech startup outside of Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>We loved our time chatting with Oleg, and we hope you love yours listening to the episode. And of course, we’d love if you can subscribe to <a href="http://apple.co/found">Found in Apple Podcasts</a>, on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0Dqmcq2aDrZkS9v1fITOKV?si=Hfp6dAwAQKyenJnprGxnqg">Spotify</a>, on <a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5zaW1wbGVjYXN0LmNvbS9lMmI0QU5vYg?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwiYisj3nZfwAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQCQ">Google Podcasts</a> or in <a href="https://pod.link/found">your podcast app of choice</a>. Please leave us a review and let us know what you think, or send us direct feedback either on <a href="https://twitter.com/found">Twitter </a>or via email at <a href="mailto:found@techcrunch.com">found@techcrunch.com</a>, or leave us a voicemail at (510) 936-1618. And please join us again next week for our next featured founder.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/fb4a26b5-7e87-40cd-8189-e0529267d18e?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/how-one-founder-bucked-the-data-driven-trend-and-created-a-startup-based-on-inspiration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187257</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equity Monday: Apple&#8217;s privacy flap continues as crypto regulation looms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/equity-monday-apples-privacy-flap-continues-as-crypto-regulation-looms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/equity-monday-apples-privacy-flap-continues-as-crypto-regulation-looms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 14:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canopy servicing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cornerstone ondemand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deliveroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delivery Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siemens-sqill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siga ot solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/91806333-41d2-4811-be30-cd234f2715bf?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>This is Equity Monday, our weekly kickoff that tracks the latest private market news, talks about the coming week, digs into some recent funding rounds and mulls over a larger theme or narrative from the private markets. You can follow the show on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">here</a> and me <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">here</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s going to be a busy week, with a Samsung event and a host of earnings reports that we&#8217;ll have to pay attention to. But more important there are a few stories still dominating the news cycle:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Apple&#8217;s privacy choices:</strong> The American hardware company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/apple-icloud-photos-scanning/">plans to scan iPhones for some illegal material</a> is once again raising the issue of privacy versus safety.</li>
<li><strong>China&#8217;s tech crackdown:</strong> The continued clampdown by regulators continued this weekend with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/beijing-prosecutors-file-lawsuit-against-tencent-over-wechats-youth-mode-2021-08-06/">Tencent once again under the spotlight</a>.</li>
<li><strong>The American crypto regulatory push:</strong> This is still causing waves this morning as Congress works to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/08/07/cryptocurrency-infrastructure-bill-lobby-bitcoin/">pass a major bill</a> that could include crypto regulations that are opposed by industry leaders.</li>
</ul>
<p>All that and we also riffed on the <a href="https://skift.com/2021/08/05/siemens-to-buy-rail-software-company-sqills-for-650-million/">Siemens-Sqills deal</a>, <a href="https://www.hcmtechnologyreport.com/cornerstone-ondemand-to-go-private-as-pe-firm-takes-ownership/">Cornerstone OnDemand going private</a>, and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/09/deliveroo-shares-rise-after-german-rival-takes-stake-in-the-business.html">Delivery Hero buying a piece of Deliveroo</a>.</p>
<p>And, for added flavor and fun, <a href="https://t.co/AHA16GstRU">Canopy Servicing just raised a $15 million Series A</a>, while <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/siga-secures-8-1m-series-b-to-prevent-cyberattacks-on-critical-infrastructure/">Siga OT Solutions raised a $8.1 million Series B</a>.</p>
<div class="article-content">
<p>All that, and we got to talk stocks! Hugs and love from the Equity crew — chat Wednesday!</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
<div class="container__access-control">
<div class="article__comments">
<div class="comments__openweb--locked">
<div class="comments__openweb__modal-wrapper">
<div class="comments__openweb__modal"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/equity-monday-apples-privacy-flap-continues-as-crypto-regulation-looms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon and parent of its top Indian seller Cloudtail to end relationship</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/amazons-top-indian-seller-cloudtail-to-cease-operations-after-may-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/amazons-top-indian-seller-cloudtail-to-cease-operations-after-may-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 13:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon and parent of its top Indian seller Cloudtail have decided to not continue their joint venture after May 2022, the two firms said in a statement Monday, hours after India’s top court ruled that the American e-commerce firm and Walmart’s Flipkart must face antitrust investigations in the South Asian market. Billionaire N.R. Narayana Murthy’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Amazon and parent of its top Indian seller Cloudtail have decided to not continue their joint venture after May 2022, the two firms said in a statement Monday, hours after India’s top court ruled that the American e-commerce firm and Walmart’s Flipkart must face antitrust investigations in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>Billionaire N.R. Narayana Murthy’s Catamaran, the parent firm of Cloudtail, and Amazon launched the joint venture in the country in 2014. The joint venture restructured its ownership in 2019 following India’s regulatory changes &#8212; more on this shortly.</p>
<p>The development follows India’s Supreme Court ruling earlier in the day that Amazon and Flipkart must face antitrust investigations ordered against them in the country.</p>
<p>The Indian watchdog &#8212; the Competition Commission of India &#8212; ordered an investigation into the firms last year for<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/13/india-orders-investigation-into-alleged-anti-competitive-practices-by-amazon-and-walmarts-flipkart/"> allegedly promoting select sellers</a> (those in which they own a stake) on their e-commerce platforms and using business practices that stifle competition.</p>
<p>In a statement Monday, the two firms said Cloudtail &#8212; registered as Prione Business Services &#8212; enabled over 300,000 sellers and entrepreneurs to go online and provided 4 million merchants with digital payment capabilities. The joint venture, they said, helped merchants and small businesses access millions of customers in India.</p>
<p>Cloudtail is one of the largest sellers on Amazon in India. The e-commerce group has stakes in a few more third-party sellers including Appario Retail, which is its joint venture with Patni Group.</p>
<p>“As our JV with Amazon reaches the end of its tenure, I reflect on this successful partnership that introduced the power of digitization and empowered hundreds of thousands of SMBs across big and small towns,” said M.D. Ranganath, President of Catamaran, in a statement.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The two firms did not say why they decided to end their joint venture.</p>
<p>Long-standing laws in India have restricted Amazon and other e-commerce firms from holding inventory or selling items directly to consumers. To bypass this, firms have operated through a maze of joint ventures with local companies that operate as inventory-holding firms.</p>
<p>India got around to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/27/amazon-walmart-india-e-commerce-restrictions/">fixing this loophole in late 2018</a> in a move that was widely seen as the biggest blowback to the American firm in the country at the time. Amazon and Walmart-owned Flipkart scrambled to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/01/amazon-flipkart-india-law/">delist hundreds of thousands of items</a> from their stores and made their investments in affiliated firms way more indirect.</p>
<p>In June this year, India <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/india-proposes-tougher-e-commerce-rules-following-widespread-cheating-and-unfair-trade-by-amazon-and-flipkart/">proposed even tougher e-commerce rules</a> that, among other things, prohibits Amazon, Flipkart and other e-commerce players from running their in-house / private labels. The new proposal asks e-commerce firms to ensure that none of their related and associated parties are listed on their platforms as sellers for selling to customers directly.</p>
<p>“Amazon and Catamaran entered into a JV in the early days of e-commerce in India with a shared vision of transforming hundreds of thousands of small businesses in a fast-changing digital world, by providing online capabilities enabling them to access customers both in India and globally,” said Amit Agarwal, Global Senior VP and Country Head of Amazon India, in a statement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/amazons-top-indian-seller-cloudtail-to-cease-operations-after-may-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187248</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook adds Photobucket and Google Calendar to its data portability options</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/facebook-adds-photobucket-and-google-calendar-to-its-data-portability-options/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/facebook-adds-photobucket-and-google-calendar-to-its-data-portability-options/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 13:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data portability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data transfer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Calendar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photobucket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tceng]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook announced that it has added two new destinations for when you want to move your data from the social network, including shifting images to Photobucket and event listings to Google Calendar.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Daniel Cooper</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Daniel Cooper is a senior editor at <a href="https://www.engadget.com">Engadget</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Facebook has today <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/08/improving-user-experience-in-our-transfer-your-information-tool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="17" data-v9y="1">announced</a> that it has added two new destinations for when you want to move your data from the social network. In a blog post, the company said that users will be able to move their images to Photobucket and event listings to Google Calendar. Product Manager Hadi Michel said that the tool has been “completely rebuilt” to be “simpler and more intuitive,” giving people more clarity on what they can share to which platforms. In addition, users can now launch multiple transfers, with better fine-grain control on what they’re choosing to export in any one transfer.</p>
<p>This is yet another feature piled on to the <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-07-20-google-facebook-microsoft-data-transfer-project.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="18" data-v9y="1">Data Transfer Project</a>, an open-source project developed by Google, Facebook and Microsoft. Facebook users can already send their photos to <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-google-photos-data-transfer-151513103.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="19" data-v9y="1">Google’s own image-storage service</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-photo-video-transfers-dropbox-koofr-155231493.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="20" data-v9y="1">Dropbox</a>, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-transfer-tool-google-docs-blogger-wordpress-134326907.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">Blogger, Google Documents and WordPress</a>. This is, in part, a way to address the long-in-progress <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-10-22-access-act-social-media-competition-bill.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1">ACCESS Act</a>, which would enable users to transfer their data to any competing platform. Facebook says that it calls on government to “make clearer rules about who is responsible for protecting that data as it is transferred to different services.”</p>
<p><strong>Editor’s note:</strong> <em>This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/facebook-data-transfer-photobucket-google-calendar-105303219.html">Engadget</a>.</em></p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/facebook-adds-photobucket-and-google-calendar-to-its-data-portability-options/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187251</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canopy raises $15M Series A after posting 4.5x customer growth in H1 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/canopy-raises-15m-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/canopy-raises-15m-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 13:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[500 startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxgroup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canopy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Series A]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Canopy's leaders expect focused fintech products to win out over large bundles of services.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://canopyservicing.com/">Canopy Servicing</a> announced this morning it recently closed a $15 million Series A. The startup sells software to fintechs and others, allowing customers to create loan programs and service the resulting products.</p>
<p>The company raised a $3.5 million seed round in 2020. Canaan led its Series A, with participation from Homebrew, Foundation and BoxGroup, among others. Per Canopy, its valuation grew by 5x from its seed round to its Series A.</p>
<p>The company has raised $18.5 million to date.</p>
<p>So far this reads much like any other post announcing a new startup funding round, kicking off with an array of information concerning the round and who chipped into the transaction. Next, we&#8217;d probably note the competitors, growth and what investors in the company in question have to say about their recent purchase. This morning, however, I want to riff a bit on the future of fintech and how the financial tech stack of the future may be built.</p>
<p>TechCrunch chatted with Canopy CEO <a href="https://twitter.com/mattbivons">Matt Bivons</a> last week. He has an interesting take on where fintech is headed. Let&#8217;s discuss it and work through what Canopy does.</p>
<h2>Canopy</h2>
<p>As with many startups, Canopy was built to scratch an itch. Bivons had run into issues regarding loan servicing in prior jobs. He went on to found a startup that aimed to build a student credit card. But after working on that project, Bivons and co-founder Will Hanson pivoted the company to a B2B-focused concern building loan servicing technology.</p>
<p>Behind the decision was market research undertaken by the Canopy crew that uncovered that a great number of fintech startups wanted to get into the credit market. That makes sense; credit products can provide far more attractive economics to fintech startups than, say, checking and savings accounts. Knowing that loan servicing was a bear and a half to manage, Canopy decided to focus on it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Bivons framed Canopy as a modern API for loan servicing that can be used to create and manage loans at any point in their lifecycle. He noted that what the startup is doing is akin to what several successful fintech companies have done, namely taking a piece of the fintech world and making it better for developers.</p>
<p>This is where Bivons&#8217; view of the future of fintech products comes into play. According to the CEO, in the future, companies will not buy a monolithic financial technology stack. Instead, he thinks, they will buy the best API for each slice of the fintech world that they need to implement. This matters because we could argue that Canopy is targeting too small a product space. Not that its market isn&#8217;t large &#8212; debt and its servicing are massive problem spaces &#8212; but seeing a company find a niche to focus on makes more sense when its leaders expect focused fintech products to win out over large bundles of services.</p>
<p>Bivons added that much of the fintech focus of the last five years has been on debit, citing Chime, Step and Greenlight as examples. The next decade, he said, is going to focus on credit products. That would be good news for Canopy.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187219" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187219" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2187219 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Canopy_cofounders_Matt_Bivons-Will_Hanson.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187219" class="wp-caption-text">Canopy co-founders via the company. CTO Will Hanson (left) and CEO Matt Bivons (right).</p></div></p>
<p>Critically, and for the finance nerds out there, Bivons told TechCrunch that its loan servicing technology does not require the company to take on any credit risk, and that it has gross margins of around 90%. I never trust a too-round number, but the figure indicates that what Canopy has built could grow into an attractive business.</p>
<p>Today, Canopy is a traditional SaaS, though Bivons said that it wants to move toward usage-based pricing in time. Its service costs around 50 cents per account per month, or around $6 per year in its current form. Today, around 40% of Canopy&#8217;s customers are seed and Series A-scale startups, though Bivons noted that it is moving up the customer size chart over time.</p>
<p>The resulting growth is impressive. Canopy&#8217;s customer count grew 4.5x from February to May of 2021. Of course, Canopy is a young company, so its overall customer base could not have been massive at the start of the year. Still, that&#8217;s the sort of growth that makes investors sit up and pay attention, making the Canopy Series A somewhat unsurprising.</p>
<p>Fintech growth doesn&#8217;t seem to be slackening much, meaning that the market for what Canopy is selling should expand. Provided that its view that best-of-breed, more particular fintech products will beat larger stacks in the market, it could have an interesting trajectory ahead of it. And now that it has raised its Series A, we can start to annoy it with more concrete questions about its growth from here on out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/canopy-raises-15m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187159</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CommandBar raises $4.8M to make web-based apps searchable</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/commandbar-raises-4-8m-to-make-web-based-apps-searchable/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/commandbar-raises-4-8m-to-make-web-based-apps-searchable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxgroup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CommandBar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Evans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thrive Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vince Hankes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James Evans and his co-founders at CommandBar were working on a different software product when they hit a wall while trying to find certain functionalities within the software.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">James Evans and his co-founders at <a href="https://www.commandbar.com/">CommandBar</a> were working on a software product when they hit a wall while trying to access certain functionalities within the software.</p>
<p>That’s when the lightbulb moment happened and, in 2020, the team shifted to building a product search engine add-on to make software easier to use.</p>
<p>“We thought this paradigm feels like it could be useful, but it is hard to build well, so we built it,” Evans told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>On Monday, CommandBar emerged from beta and announced its $4.8 million seed round, led by Thrive Capital, with participation from Y Combinator, BoxGroup and a group of angel investors including, AngelList’s Naval Ravikant, Worklife Ventures’ Brianne Kimmel, StitchFix president Mike Smith and others.</p>
<p>CommandBar’s business-to-business tool, referred to as “command k,” was designed to make software simpler and faster to use. The technology is a search interface that sits on top of web-based apps so that users can access functionalities by searching simple keywords. It can also be used to boost new users with recommended prompts like referrals.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187043" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187043" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2187043" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CommandBar-in-Clubhouse.png" alt="" width="1024" height="660" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CommandBar-in-Clubhouse.png 1199w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CommandBar-in-Clubhouse.png?resize=150,97 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CommandBar-in-Clubhouse.png?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CommandBar-in-Clubhouse.png?resize=768,495 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CommandBar-in-Clubhouse.png?resize=680,438 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CommandBar-in-Clubhouse.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187043" class="wp-caption-text">CommandBar in Clubhouse. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> CommandBar</p></div></p>
<p>Companies integrate CommandBar by pasting in a line of code and using configuration tools to quickly add commands relevant to their apps. The product was purposefully designed as low-code so that product and customer success teams can add configurations without relying on engineering support, Evans said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Initially, it was a difficult sell: One of the more challenging parts in the early days of the company was helping customers and investors understand what CommandBar was doing.</p>
<p>“It was hard to describe over the phone, we had to try to get people on Zoom so they could see it,” he said. “It is easier now to sell the product because they can see it being used in an app. That is where many new users come from.”</p>
<p>CommandBar is already being used by companies like Clubhouse.io, Canix and Stacker that are serving hundreds of thousands of users. The most common use case for CommandBar so far is onboarding new software users.</p>
<p>He intends to use the new funding to grow the team, hiring across engineering, sales and marketing. The beta testing was successful in receiving good feedback from the early customers, and Evans wants to reflect that in new products and functionalities that will come out later this year.</p>
<p>Vince Hankes, an investor at Thrive Capital, was introduced to CommandBar through one of its pre-seed investors.</p>
<p>His interest is in B2B software companies and applications, and one of the things that became obvious to him while looking into the space was the natural tension between the simplicity and functionality of apps.</p>
<p>Apps are sometimes hard for even a power user to navigate, he said, but CommandBar makes something as simple as resetting a password easier by being able to search for that term and go right to that page if it is configured that way by the company.</p>
<p>“The types of companies interested in their product are impressive,” Hankes said. “We began to see demand from a broad range of companies that weren’t obvious. In fact, they are using CommandBar as a tool for deeper customer engagement.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3zAMUN05CY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/time-strapped-it-teams-can-use-low-code-software-to-drive-quick-growth/">Time-strapped IT teams can use low-code software to drive quick growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Time-strapped IT teams can use low-code software to drive quick growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/time-strapped-it-teams-can-use-low-code-software-to-drive-quick-growth/embed/#?secret=3zAMUN05CY" data-secret="3zAMUN05CY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/commandbar-raises-4-8m-to-make-web-based-apps-searchable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wheel the World raises $2M to provide unlimited experiences for travelers with limited accessibility</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/wheel-the-world-raises-2m-to-provide-unlimited-experiences-for-travelers-with-limited-accessibility/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/wheel-the-world-raises-2m-to-provide-unlimited-experiences-for-travelers-with-limited-accessibility/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accessibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alvaro Silberstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camilo Navarro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chile Global Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dadneo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plug N Play Tech Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Susan Wojcicki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wheel the World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wheelchair]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Friends Alvaro Silberstein and Camilo Navarro came up with the idea for the Wheel the World travel booking site following a 2016 trip to Torres del Paine National Park in Chile.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Friends Alvaro Silberstein and Camilo Navarro came up with the idea for the <a href="https://gowheeltheworld.com/">Wheel the World</a> travel booking site following a 2016 trip to Torres del Paine National Park in Chile. Initially, they thought this type of trip would be near impossible with Silberstein in a wheelchair after a car accident as a teenager left him paralyzed.</p>
<p>Turns out it became the trip of a lifetime thanks to a successful crowdfunding campaign to finance a scouting trip and the purchase of a state-of-the-art hiking wheelchair. Silberstein said with the help of Navarro and other friends, he became the first to complete the Patagonia trek by wheelchair.</p>
<p>Then in 2018 while in graduate school at UC Berkeley, they decided to launch Wheel the World so that others in similar situations as Silberstein could find accessible travel experiences.</p>
<p>Three years later, about 1,300 people have booked trips through the Berkeley, California-based company’s website, which offers over 400 listings to more than 50 destinations. On Monday, they announced $2 million in a seed round led by Chile Global Ventures and Dadneo, with the support of Plug N Play Tech Center and YouTube CEO Susan Wojcicki.</p>
<p>“We have a clear belief and purpose to make the world accessible,” Silberstein said.</p>
<p><div style="width: 1920px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-2186933-1" width="1920" height="1080" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WTW-Anthem-30-seg.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WTW-Anthem-30-seg.mp4">https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WTW-Anthem-30-seg.mp4</a></video></div></p>
<p>Wheel the World collects over 200 data points on hotels through its Accessibility Mapping System, like hotel room measurements, and digitizes them to build its marketplace so that travelers can determine if that particular room will meet their needs. Users go on the site and build a profile, outlining their accessibility needs, and Wheel the World will recommend the best listings.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company will also work with hotels and tours to attract this new segment of travelers and how to work with people who have disabilities, which Navarro said was 1 billion people globally, along with another large population of family and friends that would be involved in trips.</p>
<p>“Tapping into this market of disability travel will be tapping into more than $100 billion globally,” Silberstein added. Indeed, in 2018 and 2019, <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/economic-impact-of-disability-travel-reaches-58-7-billion-301162417.html">travelers with disabilities took a total of 81 million trips</a>, spending $58.7 billion on their own travel alone, according to a 2020 report by Open Doors Organization, a nonprofit organization teaching businesses how to make their goods and services accessible to people with disabilities.</p>
<p>Silberstein and Navarro plan to use the new funding to build out Wheel the World’s software, make additional hires and add travel listings to the platform. Navarro expects to have over 3,000 listings by the end of 2022. The company has 23 employees today, and Silberstein is planning to double that over the next year.</p>
<p>Though the global pandemic was tough on the company, the founders said they used the time to design their system and think about their value proposition. It seems like the results paid off: The company recorded its best months ever for each of the last three months, Silberstein said.</p>
<p>“This year we are seeing travel inventory coming back, more people are vaccinated and we are pushing our inventory to grow more near where our users live so they can travel closer to home as well as far away,” he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cAvgTYvQfY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/30/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-travel-tourism-and-hospitality-tech/">Where top VCs are investing in travel, tourism and hospitality tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where top VCs are investing in travel, tourism and hospitality tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/30/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-travel-tourism-and-hospitality-tech/embed/#?secret=cAvgTYvQfY" data-secret="cAvgTYvQfY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/wheel-the-world-raises-2m-to-provide-unlimited-experiences-for-travelers-with-limited-accessibility/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wannabe &#8216;social bank&#8217; Kroo swerves VCs to raise a $24.5M Series A from HNWs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/wannabe-social-bank-kroo-swerves-vcs-to-raise-a-24-5m-series-a-from-hnws/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/wannabe-social-bank-kroo-swerves-vcs-to-raise-a-24-5m-series-a-from-hnws/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 12:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fintech startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ing group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Launched in February 2019, Kroo, the London-based consumer-facing fintech raised some seed funding last year for its prepaid card service which claims to offer more ‘social features’ in its drive towards offering full-blown banking services. Kroo’s pitch is that it removes friction from financial interactions with friends and family, and throws in some environmental initiatives [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Launched in February 2019, Kroo, the London-based consumer-facing fintech raised some seed funding <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/26/b-social-seed-2/">last year</a> for its prepaid card service which claims to offer more ‘social features’ in its drive towards offering full-blown banking services. Kroo’s pitch is that it removes friction from financial interactions with friends and family, and throws in some environmental initiatives as well, such as tree planting.</p>
<p>It’s now raised $24.5 million (£17.7 million) in a Series A funding round led by Rudy Karsan, a high-net-worth tech entrepreneur and founder of Karlani Capital. Kroo will use the funding in its drive towards a full banking license in early 2022.</p>
<p>The fund-raising is fairly unusual for a fintech startup that aspires to become a bank, given the lack of an institutional investor. However, this will give it a lot more freedom as it heads towards bank status next year.</p>
<p>Kroo currently offers a prepaid debit card plus an app to track personal and social finances, such as the ability to create payment groups with friends, track spending, and split and pay bills, removing the usual awkwardness around such things.</p>
<p>The company has also pledged to donate a percentage of profits to social causes, and launched a tree-planting referral scheme, so that every time a customer refers a friend, Kroo plants 20 trees.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187235" style="width: 826px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187235" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Andrea-De-Gottardo.png" alt="Kroo CEO Andrea de Gottardo" width="816" height="586" class="size-full wp-image-2187235" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Andrea-De-Gottardo.png 816w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Andrea-De-Gottardo.png?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Andrea-De-Gottardo.png?resize=300,215 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Andrea-De-Gottardo.png?resize=768,552 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Andrea-De-Gottardo.png?resize=680,488 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Andrea-De-Gottardo.png?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 816px) 100vw, 816px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187235" class="wp-caption-text">Kroo CEO Andrea de Gottardo</p></div><br />
CEO Andrea de Gottardo (pictured), who joined Kroo as Chief Risk Officer in 2018, said: “We want to build the world’s greatest social bank: a bank dedicated to its customers and to the world we live in. We’re going to do more than just work with Kroo customers to improve their relationship with money and provide them with access to fair loans. We’re going to offer them ways to actively take part in making our world a better place, like carbon offsetting and a tree-planting referral program.”</p>
<p>Karsan said: “The reason I’m excited about Kroo is that it has a concrete opportunity to dramatically change the way people feel about their bank, for good. Kroo has an exceptionally talented management team and a nimble tech stack that will enable the continuous delivery of banking features customers really care about.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Speaking to me over a call, de Gottardo added: “We have raised, including the series A, over £30 million through high net worth individuals and syndicated investors. So we still haven&#8217;t done an institutional round. That was a choice.”</p>
<p>He elaborated: “We’re lucky enough to have Rudy Karsan, a high net worth, and an extremely supportive pool of investors that keep following on in the rounds. It was our intention get up to a Series A without any institutions, and to be free of the pressure from VC. It’s now highly likely we will go institutional for a Series B round.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/wannabe-social-bank-kroo-swerves-vcs-to-raise-a-24-5m-series-a-from-hnws/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187230</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LawVu, a cloud-based platform for in-house legal teams, raises $17M NZD from Insight Partners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/lawvu-a-cloud-based-platform-for-in-house-legal-teams-raises-17m-nzd-from-insight-partners/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/lawvu-a-cloud-based-platform-for-in-house-legal-teams-raises-17m-nzd-from-insight-partners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 12:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australasia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LawVu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawyers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legal tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legaltech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In-house legal teams play a critical role in companies, but a lot of them don’t have the same kind of technology as their counterparts in sales or finance. Instead, they often rely on email, shared inboxes and spreadsheets. LawVu gives them a cloud-based platform to share legal advice, documents, communicate with each other or external [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In-house legal teams play a critical role in companies, but a lot of them don’t have the same kind of technology as their counterparts in sales or finance. Instead, they often rely on email, shared inboxes and spreadsheets. <a href="https://lawvu.com/">LawVu</a> gives them a cloud-based platform to share legal advice, documents, communicate with each other or external counsel and create reports for the rest of the company, including the C-suite. “LawVu is to legal what Salesforce is to sales teams,” co-founder and chief strategy officer Tim Boyne told TechCrunch in an email.</p>
<p>The Tauranga, New Zealand-based company announced today that it has raised $17 million NZD (about $11.9 million USD) in Series A funding led by Insight Partners, the venture firm known for <a href="https://www.insightpartners.com/blog/categories/scale-up/">its ScaleUp program for growth-stage startups</a>, with participation from returning investor AirTree Ventures. Its previous funding was a seed round of about $1.8 million USD led by Shasta Ventures and AirTree, <a href="https://www.privateequitywire.co.uk/2021/05/04/299583/legal-tech-startup-lawvu-closes-seed-round-led-shasta-and-airtree-ventures">announced in May</a>.</p>
<p>LawVu was founded in 2015 by Boyne, who spent over a decade working in IT and operations at law firms, and Sam Kidd, a SaaS project management expert. Since LawVu was designed for distributed teams and remote workers, adoption increased dramatically in 2020 during the COVID-19 pandemic. LawVu’s annual recurring revenue tripled in 2020 and is continuing to grow. While it has users in 30 countries, about two-thirds of its recurring revenue now comes from the United States and Australia, with clients like Telstra, AMP, Linktree, Expedia, PwC and Instacart.</p>
<p>The company plans to hire key leadership roles in the U.S. for its global go-to-market strategy and open U.S. offices as it continues developing LawVu’s technology.</p>
<p>LawVu is used by in-house legal teams ranging from one person to more than 300. Its fastest adoption is coming from teams of five to 500 legal professionals.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2hx25LkLXE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/canadas-newest-unicorn-clio-raises-110m-at-a-1-6b-valuation-for-legal-tech/">Canada&#8217;s newest unicorn: Clio raises $110M at a $1.6B valuation for legal tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Canada&#8217;s newest unicorn: Clio raises $110M at a $1.6B valuation for legal tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/canadas-newest-unicorn-clio-raises-110m-at-a-1-6b-valuation-for-legal-tech/embed/#?secret=2hx25LkLXE" data-secret="2hx25LkLXE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The startup serves in-house legal teams, instead of law firms, because “in-house lawyers have very different incentives and objectives to their private practice peers. This creates a vastly different set of needs for in-house lawyers to be effective at their jobs, particularly on the technology front,” Boyne said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For example, private practice lawyers focus on specific projects, charging clients on time spent. In contrast, in-house lawyers have to balance “reactive work,” or what their company asks for, and “proactive work,” or anticipating the business’ needs and reducing risks.</p>
<p>LawVu’s cloud platform serves as a “legal workspace” that combines all the tech tools in-house legal teams need. For example, it lets them manage matter (or legal issues that can include advice requests, contract executions, M&amp;A transactions or litigation), contracts, documents, e-billing and outsourced work.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Rk06DRM9cL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/legl-gets-7m-to-help-law-firms-upgrade-to-digital-workflows/">Legl gets $7M to help law firms upgrade to digital workflows</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Legl gets $7M to help law firms upgrade to digital workflows&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/legl-gets-7m-to-help-law-firms-upgrade-to-digital-workflows/embed/#?secret=Rk06DRM9cL" data-secret="Rk06DRM9cL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>For in-house legal teams, LawVu&#8217;s analytics helps the rest of their company understand exactly what they do by providing metrics using data that is usually tucked away in email inboxes or a salesperson’s files, Boyne said.</p>
<p>“Legal work is largely invisible. Unlike other industries, legal is at the very beginning of its data journey,” Boyne said. He added, “as lawyers migrate their work into our workspace, everything is able to be captured as data. For the first time, the legal function now has the ability to see demand, types of work, team capacity, future hiring needs, what law firms are performing well, even process areas to automate with other tools.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to helping in-house legal teams become more productive, LawVu also helps them prove their value to decision makers. Boyne explained that legal teams are often overlooked because they are viewed as cost centers which do not directly add to a company’s profit, and who come in at the end of a project or decision.</p>
<p>“Typically as a business scales really fast, the legal team can be left behind with the capacity to only fight fires and no time to engage and add much needed strategic value. If you don’t have the data to back up the value and work you are doing, it becomes very hard to get more resources when needed, be this tech or people,” Boyne said.</p>
<p>“LawVu workspace allows them to streamline their service, have information at their fingertips, deliver outcomes quickly, measure and demonstrate value, all freeing them up to truly become a valued member of the business leadership team.”</p>
<p>Insight Partners managing director Rachel Geller will join LawVu’s board. In a statement, she said, “LawVu’s global growth speaks volumes to its future as a business and ability to provide high-value outcomes to legal teams. Its combination of intuitive user experience and excellent customer feedback make LawVu stand out in the legal tech industry.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vpBqTgSXFX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/">4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 key areas SaaS startups must address to scale infrastructure for the enterprise&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/4-key-areas-saas-startups-must-address-to-scale-infrastructure-for-the-enterprise/embed/#?secret=vpBqTgSXFX" data-secret="vpBqTgSXFX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/lawvu-a-cloud-based-platform-for-in-house-legal-teams-raises-17m-nzd-from-insight-partners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187169</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Siga secures $8.1M Series B to prevent cyberattacks on critical infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/siga-secures-8-1m-series-b-to-prevent-cyberattacks-on-critical-infrastructure/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/siga-secures-8-1m-series-b-to-prevent-cyberattacks-on-critical-infrastructure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nozomi Networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phoenix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united arab emirates]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Siga OT Solutions, an Israeli cybersecurity startup that helps organizations secure their operations by monitoring the raw electric signals of critical industrial assets, has raised $8.1 million in Series B funding. Siga’s SigaGuard says its technology, used by Israel’s critical water facilities and the New York Power Authority, is unique in that rather than monitoring [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Siga OT Solutions, an Israeli <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/cybersecurity/">cybersecurity</a> startup that helps organizations secure their operations by monitoring the raw electric signals of critical industrial assets, has raised $8.1 million in Series B funding.</p>
<p>Siga’s SigaGuard says its technology, used by Israel’s critical water facilities and the New York Power Authority, is unique in that rather than monitoring the operational network, it uses <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/machine-learning/">machine learning</a> and predictive analysis to &#8220;listen&#8221; to Level 0 signals. These are typically made up of components and sensors that receive electrical signals, rather than protocols or data packets that can be manipulated by hackers.</p>
<p>By monitoring Level 0, which Siga describes as the &#8220;richest and most reliable level of process data within any operational environment,&#8221; the company can detect cyberattacks on the most critical and vulnerable physical assets of national infrastructures. This, it claims, ensures operational resiliency even when hackers are successful in manipulating the logic of industrial control system (ICS) controllers.</p>
<p>Amir Samoiloff, co-founder and CEO of Siga, says: “Level 0 is becoming the major axis in the resilience and integrity of critical national infrastructures worldwide and securing this level will become a major element in control systems in the coming years.”</p>
<p>The company’s latest round of funding — led by PureTerra Ventures, with investment from Israeli venture fund SIBF, Moore Capital, and Phoenix Contact — comes amid an escalation in attacks against operational infrastructure. Israel’s water infrastructure was hit by three known cyberattacks in 2020 and these were followed by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/decrypted-hackers-attempt-to-poison-florida-towns-water-supply/">an attack on the water system of a city in Florida</a> that saw hackers briefly increase the amount of sodium hydroxide in Oldsmar&#8217;s water treatment system.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The $8.1 million investment lands three years after the startup secured $3.5 million in Series A funding. The company said it will use the funding to accelerate its sales and strategic collaborations internationally, with a focus on North America, Europe, Asia, and the United Arab Emirates.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><strong>Read more:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/industrial-cybersecurity-startup-nozomi-networks-secures-100m-in-pre-ipo-funding/">Industrial cybersecurity startup Nozomi Networks secures $100M in pre-IPO funding</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/13/researchers-simulate-a-ransomware-attack-on-industrial-controls/">Researchers simulate a ransomware attack on industrial controls</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/01/hexane-oil-gas-telecoms-hackers/">A newly discovered hacking group is targeting energy and telecoms companies</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/dragos-series-c-industrial-systems-security/">Dragos raises $110M Series C as demand to secure industrial systems soars</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/siga-secures-8-1m-series-b-to-prevent-cyberattacks-on-critical-infrastructure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185476</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moove raises $23M to create flexible options for drivers to own cars in Africa</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/moove-raises-23m-to-create-flexible-options-for-drivers-to-own-cars-in-africa/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/moove-raises-23m-to-create-flexible-options-for-drivers-to-own-cars-in-africa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Africa is home to more than a billion people where a majority have limited or no access to vehicle financing. In fact, the continent has the lowest per capita vehicle ownership in the world. In 2019, Africa had fewer than 900,000 new vehicle sales. The U.S. sold more than 17 million new cars that same [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Africa is home to more than a billion people where a majority have limited or no access to vehicle financing. In fact, the continent has the lowest per capita vehicle ownership in the world. In 2019, Africa had fewer than 900,000 new vehicle sales. The U.S. sold more than 17 million new cars that same year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Nigeria, owning a car is a luxury very few people can afford. It is a similar case across Africa where car owners often recycle used cars between themselves because of the difficulty of accessing new ones. <a href="https://moove.africa/">Moove</a>, an African mobility company with a fintech play, wants to change that and is raising $23 million in Series A to scale </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rapidly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> across the continent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moove </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was founded by</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ladidelano?miniProfileUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afs_miniProfile%3AACoAADcQ8FABjW5jO79MRu88xUjUK_mFd4LYxFc&amp;lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_search_srp_people%3Bkt9csYDZRM2gEus%2BEO0Mow%3D%3D"> Ladi Delano</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jideodunsi">Jide Odunsi</a> in 2019. In an interview with TechCrunch, Delano said he and Odunsi, whilst trying to figure out the problems to solve in Nigeria after years of running successful businesses, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">were left</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> startled by the figures highlighted above: Less than a million new cars sold in an entire continent and over 17 million in the U.S. alone.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;It became clear to us that people aren&#8217;t buying cars in Africa because there&#8217;s no access to finance. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you look anywhere else in the world, you have financing in most parts of the developed world when you try to buy a car</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It&#8217;s that way in the UK, or Europe and the US. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that&#8217;s what&#8217;s driving mobility drive and vehicle sales,&#8221; Delano said during the interview</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The founders saw it as a huge task to address this deficit and figured that deploying an asset financing model was the go-to approach. Moove says it is democratizing vehicle ownership by employing a revenue-based vehicle financing model. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, this applies to only a subset of the driving population across the continent Moove calls mobility entrepreneurs.<br />
</span></p>
<p>These include drivers who work in the mobility space (car-hailing, ride-hailing, bus-hailing, among others). Although they make up a small part of Africans who need Moove&#8217;s services, Delano says the market for ‘mobility entrepreneurs’ is enormous.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What’s the rational behind backing ride-hailing drivers</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> instead of the overall populace? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Delano tells TechCrunch that inasmuch as Moove is changing how people have access to new cars in Africa, he wants the company to solve some of the unemployment problems facing the continent, even more so in Nigeria. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So instead of providing the service for individuals from all spheres of life who cannot guarantee a payback, why not target drivers who would use the opportunity to work and, in turn, generate income to pay back.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moove is Uber’s exclusive car financing and vehicle supply partner in sub-Saharan Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company embeds its alternative credit-scoring technology, allowing access to proprietary performance and revenue analytics to underwrite loans. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It provides loans to these drivers by selling them new vehicles and financing up to 95% of the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">purchase</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> within five days of sign up</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They can choose to pay back their loans over 24, 36, or 48 months, using a percentage of the weekly revenue generated while driving on Uber</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moove&#8217;s loan repayment process is more suitable to drivers than what </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">traditionally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> exists in the market</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Nigerian banks, for instance, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are known</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to collect a 10-50% deposit from drivers; Moove says it charges 5%. The net effective annual interest rate also differs </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">significantly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Nigerian banks charge between 20 to 25%; however</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Moove runs on an 8-13% rate. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, when you consider the tenure of a vehicle financing loan, Nigerian banks rarely give a repayment duration of more than two years</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moove&#8217;s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">maximum</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> duration is four years. In the long run, Delano says the company wants to extend the repayment duration to five years, a span with more parity to the West</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, Moove is looking to add financing to other vehicle classes and types in the coming months, including buses and trucks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D41mOqQDn3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/south-africas-flexclub-adds-5m-to-seed-round-to-scale-its-car-subscription-marketplace/">South Africa&#8217;s FlexClub adds $5M to seed round to scale its car subscription marketplace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;South Africa&#8217;s FlexClub adds $5M to seed round to scale its car subscription marketplace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/south-africas-flexclub-adds-5m-to-seed-round-to-scale-its-car-subscription-marketplace/embed/#?secret=D41mOqQDn3" data-secret="D41mOqQDn3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though Moove </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">was founded</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2019, it didn&#8217;t </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">fully</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> launch until June 2020. In a full year of operation, Moove has scaled </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">aggressively</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. With headquarters in the Netherlands, the company counts Lagos, Accra, Johannesburg as cities where it operates. Moove has 12,900 pre-approved sign-ups and its </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">financed cars have also completed over 850,000 Uber trips. Delano says the company has grown 60% month-on-month since last year</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moove raised a $5.5 million seed round last year. The majority of the funding came from the founders and Iyinoluwa Aboyeji, co-founder of Andela and Flutterwave, and a key partner at the company. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to its $23 million Series A, Moove also revealed that it raised $40 million in debt financing, bringing its total funding to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $68.5 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speedinvest and Left Lane Capital led the Series A round. Other investors like DCM, Clocktower Technology Ventures, thelatest.ventures, LocalGlobe, Tekton, FJ Labs, Palm Drive Capital, Roka Works, KAAF Investments, Class 5 Global, Victoria van Lennep, co-founder of Lendable, Verod, Kepple Africa Ventures, and one of Moove’s existing lenders, Emso Asset Management, also joined the round. Moove&#8217;s investment is the first for many of its U.S. backers in this round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With Ladi and Jide at the helm of a world-class team, and their unique approach to vehicle financing, Moove has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">quickly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> established itself as one of the most exciting tech companies in Africa,” said the general partner at Speedinvest, Stefan Klestil. “The company’s expansion to three cities in under 12 months demonstrates the huge demand for vehicle financing in Africa, where </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> five percent of new cars </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are purchased</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with financing, compared to 92 percent in Europe.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Delano and Odunsi are British-born Nigerians educated at the London School of Economics, Oxford University, and MIT. Delano has always been an entrepreneur. Odunsi, on the other hand, was an investment banker at Goldman Sachs and a management consultant at McKinsey.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both reconnected years after (since parting ways in their teens) to run a venture studio called Grace Lake Partners and</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have subsequently built three non-tech successful businesses in Africa in the past decade</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Moove is their first tech business, and Delano calls it the fastest-growing he has ever run.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Series A funding will allow Moove to grow and expand into new markets. It gives the company ammunition to develop and launch new products and services</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> geared</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> towards gaining more share in a competitive market where Nigeria&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/nigerias-autochek-raises-3-4m-for-car-sales-and-service-platform/">Autochek</a> and South Africa&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/south-africas-flexclub-adds-5m-to-seed-round-to-scale-its-car-subscription-marketplace/">FlexClub</a> are making significant strides</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Delano believes what gives Moove an edge over other companies is its trademark of getting drivers to access new cars instead of used ones. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He also adds that the company is moving towards creating electric and hybrid vehicle fleets</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He cites helping mobility entrepreneurs who need to have fuel-efficient cars and climate change as reasons for creating this new product line.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But how will EVs be affordable for the average Uber driver in Africa? Delano argues that with Moove&#8217;s strong bargaining power with its OEM partners and the debt financing raised, Moove can buy new EV cars and resell them at a lower price to thousands of drivers. The aim is to ensure that at least 60% of the vehicles it finances are electric or hybrid in the coming years. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is also trying to drive gender inclusion by increasing the number of female drivers using its platform to 50%</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One interesting bit in Moove&#8217;s imminent plans is creating wallets for drivers who do not have bank accounts to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">make and accept payments. The feature is live only in Ghana but will be coming to other markets in no distant time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Moove’s technology is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">fundamentally</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> changing access to mobility and empowering thousands to earn a new source of income,” said managing partner at Left Lane Capital, Dan Ahrens. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As we look ahead, the potential for that technology and the Moove team to expand even further is very exciting</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. They have the opportunity to become a full-service mobility fintech and expand their offerings to insurance and other financial services.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="u0mt82tXLJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/nigerias-autochek-raises-3-4m-for-car-sales-and-service-platform/">Nigeria’s Autochek raises $3.4M for car sales and service platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nigeria’s Autochek raises $3.4M for car sales and service platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/18/nigerias-autochek-raises-3-4m-for-car-sales-and-service-platform/embed/#?secret=u0mt82tXLJ" data-secret="u0mt82tXLJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/moove-raises-23m-to-create-flexible-options-for-drivers-to-own-cars-in-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187164</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s UpGrad enters unicorn club with $185 million fundraise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/india-upgrad-enters-unicorn-club-with-185-million-fundraise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/india-upgrad-enters-unicorn-club-with-185-million-fundraise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 09:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[byju's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unacademy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vedantu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UpGrad, a Bangalore-based startup that specializes in higher education and upskilling courses, hit a valuation of $1.2 billion with a $185 million funding round Monday as global investors plow record capital into firms in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market. Singapore&#8217;s Temasek led the financing round while the World Bank&#8217;s International Finance Corporation and IIFL participated. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">UpGrad, a Bangalore-based startup that specializes in higher education and upskilling courses, hit a valuation of $1.2 billion with a $185 million funding round Monday as global investors plow record capital into firms in the world&#8217;s second largest internet market.</p>
<p>Singapore&#8217;s Temasek led the financing round while the World Bank&#8217;s International Finance Corporation and IIFL participated. The first tranche of this unnamed round &#8212; about $120 million &#8212; was completed in April this year at a valuation of over $600 million.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are pleased with the investor interest ever since we opened up for fundraise, and had our maiden raise from Temasek, followed by IFC and IIFL in the last 60 days,” said Ronnie Screwvala (pictured above), co-founder and chairperson of upGrad, in a statement.</p>
<p>Six-year-old UpGrad, which in recent months has pushed for expansion in international markets, offers students over 100 courses in data science, machine learning, artificial intelligence, blockchain, finance, programming, and law in collaboration with universities such as Michigan State University, the IIT Madras and IIT Delhi, and Swiss School of Business Management, Geneva.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187198" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187198" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2187198 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/upgrad-india.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="541" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/upgrad-india.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/upgrad-india.jpg?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/upgrad-india.jpg?resize=300,158 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/upgrad-india.jpg?resize=768,406 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/upgrad-india.jpg?resize=680,359 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/upgrad-india.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187198" class="wp-caption-text">UpGrad website</p></div></p>
<p>More than a million users from over four dozen nations have accessed the platform&#8217;s courses, the startup said. On its website, UpGrad says it has over 62,000 paid students. These courses cost between $3,300 to $6,750 and run for six months to two years.</p>
<p>UpGrad is among the scores of Indian edtech startups that has reported skyrocketing growth in recent quarters as students move online following the shutting of schools due to the pandemic.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>SoftBank and Tiger Global-backed Unacademy was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/indian-edtech-unacademy-valued-at-3-44-billion-in-440-million-fundraise/">valued at $3.44 billion</a> in a $440 million fundraise it unveiled last Monday. GGV Capital-backed Vedantu is in advanced stages of talks to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/india-edtech-firms-byjus-and-vedantu-not-holding-acquisition-talks/">finalize a new round</a> that is poised to crown it the unicorn title, TechCrunch reported last week. Byju&#8217;s, which has raised over $1.5 billion in the past one year or so, is India&#8217;s most valuable startup.</p>
<p>Screwvala said UpGrad will deploy the fresh funds to explore merger and acquisition opportunities. Screwvala, who pioneered the cable television business in the South Asian market and also produced several Bollywood blockbusters, sold his entertainment conglomerate UTV to Disney at an enterprise valuation of $1.4 billion in 2013.</p>
<p>UpGrad is the 21st Indian startup to become a unicorn this year, up from 11 last year. In recent quarters, high-profile investors such as Tiger Global, SoftBank Vision Fund 2, Falcon Edge, and Temasek have doubled down on their bets on India.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/india-upgrad-enters-unicorn-club-with-185-million-fundraise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two months after its Series A, Pintu gets $35M in new funding led by Lightspeed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/two-months-after-its-series-a-pintu-gets-35m-in-new-funding-led-by-lightspeed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/two-months-after-its-series-a-pintu-gets-35m-in-new-funding-led-by-lightspeed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 07:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pintu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just two months after its last funding announcement, Indonesian crypto assets platform Pintu has closed a $35 million Series A+. The new round was led by Lightspeed Ventures, with participation from returning investors like Alameda Ventures, Blockchain.com Ventures, Castle Island Ventures, Coinbase Ventures, Intudo Ventures and Pantera Capital. Pintu’s previous funding, a $6 million Series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Just two months after its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/indonesian-crypto-exchange-pintu-gets-6m-series-a-led-by-pantera-intudo-and-coinbase-ventures/">last funding announcement</a>, Indonesian crypto assets platform <a href="https://pintu.co.id/">Pintu</a> has closed a $35 million Series A+. The new round was led by Lightspeed Ventures, with participation from returning investors like Alameda Ventures, Blockchain.com Ventures, Castle Island Ventures, Coinbase Ventures, Intudo Ventures and Pantera Capital.</p>
<p>Pintu’s previous funding, a $6 million Series A led by Pantera, Intudo and Coinbase Ventures, was announced in late May. Pintu is the latest investment app in Southeast Asia to quickly raise a much larger follow-on round as <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a869e9c8-a48b-45d2-9fde-3c57b4214c0e">interest in retail investing grows</a>. Other examples include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/bibit-raises-another-growth-round-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-this-time-for-65m/">Bibit</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/28/ajaib-raises-65m-series-a-extension-led-by-ribbit-capital-increasing-the-rounds-total-to-90m/">Ajaib</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/investment-app-syfe-raises-29-6m-series-b-led-by-returning-investor-valar-ventures/">Syfe</a>.</p>
<p>Andrew Adjiputro, Pintu’s chief operating officer, told TechCrunch that Pintu raised a Series A+, instead of a Series A extension or Series B, because its focus on product development and execution is still the same. “With the Coinbase IPO and a lot of new users onboarding, we think it’s the right time for us to raise a larger round to finance faster growth,” he said. “It’s good momentum for us to launch new products and grab the market.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ly2bQN2qsR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/indonesian-crypto-exchange-pintu-gets-6m-series-a-led-by-pantera-intudo-and-coinbase-ventures/">Indonesian crypto exchange Pintu gets $6M Series A led by Pantera, Intudo and Coinbase Ventures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Indonesian crypto exchange Pintu gets $6M Series A led by Pantera, Intudo and Coinbase Ventures&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/indonesian-crypto-exchange-pintu-gets-6m-series-a-led-by-pantera-intudo-and-coinbase-ventures/embed/#?secret=ly2bQN2qsR" data-secret="ly2bQN2qsR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Pintu plans to use its Series A+ on “aggressive” hiring for all its teams and rolling out new features and products. During the first half of 2021, Pintu says app downloads grew by 3.5x through organic growth, while active traders on the platform increased by 4x.</p>
<p>The platform currently offers trades on 16 cryptocurrencies, with plans to add more coins, including NFT tokens.</p>
<p>Adjiputro said Coinbase’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/coinbase-opens-at-381-per-share-valuing-the-crypto-exchange-at-nearly-100b/">successful initial public offering in April</a> helped fuel interest in crypto trading, especially among first-time investors.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PDvr9O3UOS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/coinbase-opens-at-381-per-share-valuing-the-crypto-exchange-at-nearly-100b/">Coinbase opens at $381 per share, valuing the crypto exchange at nearly $100B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase opens at $381 per share, valuing the crypto exchange at nearly $100B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/coinbase-opens-at-381-per-share-valuing-the-crypto-exchange-at-nearly-100b/embed/#?secret=PDvr9O3UOS" data-secret="PDvr9O3UOS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“They became curious and the bread and butter of our business is essentially education,” said Adjiputro. “We have a lot of education on our platform and it attracts this new breed of investors who want to learn more.”</p>
<p>While the rate of retail investment in Indonesia is still low, it&#8217;s <a href="https://www.thejakartapost.com/news/2020/08/27/the-rise-of-the-retail-investor-a-new-force-in-indonesias-pandemic-hit-stock-market.html">growing quickly because of a confluence of factors</a>, including people’s desire to diversify and increase their assets during the pandemic.</p>
<p>For many of Pintu’s users, the app was their first introduction to investing instead of stocks, Adjiputro said. The company recently surveyed current users, asking about the top five asset classes they invest in. Crypto came in third after mutual funds and digital gold, and before stocks at number four.</p>
<p>The preference for crypto over stocks is echoed in figures <a href="https://kr-asia.com/over-6-5-million-indonesians-bought-or-sold-crypto-in-first-5-months-of-2021-ministry-of-trade-says">released by the Indonesian Ministry of Trade</a>, which showed that as of June 2021, there were over 6.5 million crypto investors in Indonesia, or about triple the 2.2 million public equity investors in the country.</p>
<p>Pintu is a licensed crypto broker under the Indonesian Commodity Futures Trading Regulatory Agency (BAPPEBTI). It has a low minimum investment rate of 11,000 IDR, or about 75 cents USD, making it more attractive to new investors.</p>
<p>Timothius Martin, the company’s chief marketing officer, was a first-time investor when he started using Pintu. He told TechCrunch that the number one draw was accessibility. “It’s easy to start investing and also withdraw assets. In Indonesia, we are now at a stage where people have heard about crypto, about Bitcoin, are very interested and may already want to invest, but there are not many options that are easy enough for them to understand.&#8221;</p>
<p>Instead of encouraging users to make an investment when they open the app for the first time, Pintu presents them with educational materials. For example, one of its features is Pintu Academy, a collection of articles and videos. While Pintu’s target demographic is millennials, it’s also attracting older demographics, including people who have traded other assets, like stocks, but want to learn more about the fundamentals of crypto trading.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Hk8cFBZHGq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/bibit-raises-another-growth-round-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-this-time-for-65m/">Bibit raises another growth round led by Sequoia Capital India, this time for $65M</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Bibit raises another growth round led by Sequoia Capital India, this time for $65M&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/02/bibit-raises-another-growth-round-led-by-sequoia-capital-india-this-time-for-65m/embed/#?secret=Hk8cFBZHGq" data-secret="Hk8cFBZHGq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Adjiputro said Pintu’s focus on education is what differentiates it from other Indonesian crypto platforms like Indodax and Tokocrypto.</p>
<p>The company is getting ready to launch new features, like Pintu Earn, a crypto asset account that lets users earn interest on a variety of crypto assets, and e-wallet integration for easier deposits and withdrawals.</p>
<p>It’s also deciding what coins to add next. “We’re very selective in terms of the coins we introduce, because this is a platform for first-time investors and beginners, so we want to protect them, not only in terms of our UI, but also the selection of coins we have,” Martin said.</p>
<p>Pintu’s criteria for new coins include ones that have a high market cap, meaning adoption is already relatively mainstream. It also looks at how long a coin has been around and its liquidity.</p>
<p>Pintu plans to focus on expanding in Indonesia before entering other Southeast Asian markets.</p>
<p>In a statement, Lightspeed partner Hemant Mohapatra said, “Lightspeed has invested in over 17 crypto and blockchain companies globally including FTX, Blockchain.com, Offchain Labs and more. We believe crypto is at an inflection point to become an important asset class globally, and will give rise to massive companies that will become regional leaders. Pintu has created the strongest market brand, best user experience and hands down one of the strongest teams we’ve ever come across in this market.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KwOonOo5Jh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/coinbases-direct-listing-alters-the-landscape-for-fintech-and-crypto-startups/">Coinbase’s direct listing alters the landscape for fintech and crypto startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Coinbase’s direct listing alters the landscape for fintech and crypto startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/coinbases-direct-listing-alters-the-landscape-for-fintech-and-crypto-startups/embed/#?secret=KwOonOo5Jh" data-secret="KwOonOo5Jh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/two-months-after-its-series-a-pintu-gets-35m-in-new-funding-led-by-lightspeed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187176</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to claim a student discount for Extra Crunch</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/how-to-claim-a-student-discount-for-extra-crunch/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/how-to-claim-a-student-discount-for-extra-crunch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Travis Bernard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 03:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2180149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Students can get access to Extra Crunch at a discounted rate of $50/year (plus tax).  Here&#8217;s how to claim the discount: Use a .edu or university email address and send a message to our customer support team at extracrunch@techcrunch.com. Please let them know that you are seeking the student discount. The team will respond within [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Students can get access to Extra Crunch at a discounted rate of $50/year (plus tax).  Here&#8217;s how to claim the discount:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Use a .edu or university email address and send a message to our customer support team at extracrunch@techcrunch.com. Please let them know that you are seeking the student discount.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The team will respond within 24 hours with a unique link to claim your discount.</li>
</ul>
<p id="speakable-summary">If you are part of a student group like an entrepreneurial club and interested in getting access for a large number of users, reach out to <a href="mailto:travis@techcrunch.com">travis@techcrunch.com</a> to learn more about custom discounts on large groups.</p>
<p><b>What is Extra Crunch?</b></p>
<p>Extra Crunch is a members-only community from TechCrunch that helps startup teams and founders get ahead. Membership includes analysis and advice from experienced entrepreneurs on startup topics like fundraising and growth. Members can discover how successful startups operate through deep-dive interviews with founders and investors, and spot trends and opportunities with market analysis, investor surveys, and topical newsletters.</p>
<p>If you have interest in attending TechCrunch events, you can save 20% on tickets as an Extra Crunch member. Once you join Extra Crunch, reach out to our customer service team with the event name to receive a discount code for any TechCrunch event.</p>
<p>For questions about this offer, reach out to customer support at extracrunch@techcrunch.com.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/how-to-claim-a-student-discount-for-extra-crunch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2180149</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pixels, Palm readers and Pokémon problems</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/pixels-palm-readers-and-pokemon-problems/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/pixels-palm-readers-and-pokemon-problems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 14:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Week in Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends! That&#8217;s what Lucas always starts off with, right? Lucas is out for a few weeks, so I&#8217;ll be handling Week In Review until he&#8217;s back. TL;DR on me: I&#8217;m Greg, and I&#8217;ve been with TechCrunch for a long, long time. I joined around the time Twitter found the vowels in its name and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello friends! That&#8217;s what Lucas always starts off with, right?</p>
<p>Lucas is out for a few weeks, so I&#8217;ll be handling Week In Review until he&#8217;s back. TL;DR on me: I&#8217;m Greg, and I&#8217;ve been with TechCrunch for a long, long time. I joined around the time Twitter found the vowels in its name and people thought Facebook&#8217;s valuation was laughably high at $15 billion. (For reference, Facebook&#8217;s market cap broke $1 trillion last month.)</p>
<p>Enough about me! Want this in your inbox every week? Sign up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">here</a>. <strong>Oh and by the way,</strong> Sarah Perez&#8217;s popular This Week In Apps column is now a weekly newsletter. Sarah rules and does a damned good job of wrapping up everything you need to know about the world of apps, so be sure to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">sign up</a>, so you can get it in your inbox every Saturday morning.</p>
<p>And now, here&#8217;s a quick overview of what you might&#8217;ve missed this week.</p>
<h2>The Big Thing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2028970" style="width: 3010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2028970" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2028970 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg" alt="" width="3000" height="2000" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/zoom-bomb.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2028970" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Bryce Durbin / TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>While Zoom has been around since 2011, its growth in 2020 was just on a whole different level. The pandemic blasted Zoom into the product-name-as-a-verb hall of fame pretty much overnight, with &#8220;let’s Zoom next week&#8221; joining the ranks of &#8220;Xerox this for me?&#8221; or &#8220;Photoshop it&#8221; or &#8220;Google it.&#8221;</p>
<p>With rapid growth, of course, comes growing pains.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Among these pains was a significant uptick in trolling. The idea of &#8220;<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/zoombombing/">Zoombombing</a>&#8221; was born, wherein unapproved attendees crash a Zoom call and flood it with nasty images, hate speech, and whatever else they can blast out before the moderator (often unfamiliar with Zoom&#8217;s interface) figures out how to lock it down.</p>
<p>By April of 2020, Zoom had tweaked its settings to make meetings a bit less zoombomb-able by default — but by that point, a lawsuit had already been filed. <em>Fourteen</em> lawsuits were filed, in fact, and later condensed into one. The suits argued that the company hadn&#8217;t done enough to prevent Zoombombing, as well as shared user data with third parties without the user&#8217;s permission.</p>
<p>This week Zoom agreed to an $85 million settlement, along with a promise to add even more safeguards against would-be crashers. It&#8217;s an interesting example of how massive/sudden popularity can cause all new problems … but, well, considering that Zoom&#8217;s market cap went from $34 billion in March 2020 to $118 billion as of this week, I doubt anyone there is too crushed about it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qvD4mBH00s"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/zoombombing/">Beware of &#8216;ZoomBombing&#8217;: screensharing filth to video calls</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Beware of &#8216;ZoomBombing&#8217;: screensharing filth to video calls&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/zoombombing/embed/#?secret=qvD4mBH00s" data-secret="qvD4mBH00s" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Other Things</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/google-gives-the-world-its-first-glimpse-of-the-pixel-6/"><strong>Google previews the Pixel 6</strong></a></p>
<p>Google&#8217;s next flagship Android phone is coming! When? TBD. How much? Good question! The company held back an unusual number of details in its first official acknowledgement of the Pixel 6&#8217;s existence, presumably to keep the focus on the custom AI-centric system on a chip they&#8217;re building for it. We know it&#8217;s got a big ol&#8217; camera bump (or &#8220;camera bar,&#8221; as they&#8217;re calling it) and there will be two models (Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro). But beyond that, we&#8217;re stuck relying on leaked specs for now. Fortunately, said leaks have been pretty spot on thus far.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/robinhood-is-now-a-stonk/"><strong>Robinhood&#8217;s wild ride</strong></a></p>
<p>Robinhood went public this week — and, perhaps fittingly for the app that played no small role in the GameStop/AMC/etc. meme stock bonanza earlier this year, its first few days of trading have been something of a rollercoaster. It opened at $38, slipped on day one, only to rocket up to the $70s on day two. As I write this, it&#8217;s slowly heading back down to earth with a current price of around $53. As for the root cause of the volatility&#8230; as Alex Wilhelm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/robinhood-is-now-a-stonk/">put it</a>: &#8220;This happens in 2021; we just have to get used to it.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/"><strong>Pokémon Go players are mad</strong></a></p>
<p>Because the fundamental concepts of Pokémon Go (Talk to strangers! Hang out in huge groups!) don&#8217;t work as well in a pandemic, Niantic tweaked a bunch of stuff last year to make the game more playable from home. Among other things, they bumped up the real-world radius in which players could interact with in-game landmarks, allowing you to do more while moving less. This week they started rolling those changes back as a &#8220;test&#8221;&#8230; and, well, people are mad. The company presumably has some data-driven reasons to revert&#8230; but from the outside, with the pandemic still ongoing, it just looks like a bad decision. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Niantic has responded to the community uproar by forming an internal team to examine the options, promising updates by September 1st.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/whatsapp-view-once-disappearing-photos-video/"><strong>WhatsApp gets self-destructing, single-view photos</strong></a></p>
<p>This week, WhatsApp embraced its inner-Snapchat with the introduction of &#8220;view once&#8221; mode, which allows users to send photos and videos that can be viewed once before they self-destruct. Be aware, though, that you probably don&#8217;t want to go and use it to send those top-secret documents (and/or butt pics); unlike Snapchat, WhatsApp won&#8217;t even give you a heads-up if the viewer takes a screenshot.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/amazon-credit-palm-biometrics/"><strong>Amazon wants to pay you $10 to scan your palm</strong></a></p>
<p>Last year Amazon started letting customers at its checkout-free grocery stores pay for goods by waving their palm print over a biometric scanner. Now they&#8217;re paying new customers $10 to scan their print and get onboard. This story was super popular on the site this week, and I&#8217;m left wondering if it&#8217;s because people are mad about Amazon gobbling up all this biometric data or because they want the $10. Probably a bit of both.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/"><strong>Twitter kills Fleets</strong></a></p>
<p>RIP Fleets. Less than a year after Twitter decided it <em>too</em> needed to clone Snapchat Stories, the company has ditched the concept. Why? It says it hoped it would entice new users; instead, the only people using it were those who were already pretty hardcore.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/"><strong>Square buys Afterpay</strong></a></p>
<p>The buy-now, pay-later space got real big real fast, and Square wants in. This week the company announced its intent to acquire Afterpay, a company that lets you split big purchases across 6 weeks without credit checks or interest, for an earth-shattering $29 billion.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/googles-nest-cams-and-doorbell-get-a-refresh/"><strong>Google&#8217;s new Nest cams</strong></a></p>
<p>Google&#8217;s got some new Nest camera gear coming later this month, including a few things that you might be surprised they didn&#8217;t make already — like a battery-powered outdoor camera and a motion-activated floodlight camera for your porch.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/spacex-stacks-the-full-starship-launch-system-for-the-first-time-standing-nearly-400-feet-tall/"><strong>Elon&#8217;s Big Ship</strong></a></p>
<p>The fun news: This week SpaceX put together the tallest rocket ship in history, with its fully stacked Starship rocket coming together at an absurd 390 feet tall (or 475 feet if you count the launch pad). The less fun news: It&#8217;s not going anywhere for now, as this assembly was just a fit test — put it together, take it apart, make sure nothing broke. An actual launch of this mammoth configuration isn&#8217;t expected until later this year, but it should be quite the spectacle.</p>
<h2>Extra Things</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/5-factors-founders-must-consider-before-choosing-their-vc/">Five factors founders must consider before choosing their VC</a></strong></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve heard it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/angellist-ventures-avlok-kohli-on-rolling-funds-and-the-busy-state-of-vc/">on repeat</a> lately: With so much capital flooding the market, now is the time for founders to be picky about who they let invest. But what things should you consider? Agya Ventures&#8217; co-founder Kunal Lunawat has a few notes, from how well a VC understands your vision, to their background, to good ol&#8217; gut instinct.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/avoid-these-common-financial-mistakes-so-your-startup-doesnt-die-on-the-vine/"><strong>Avoid these common financial mistakes so your startup doesn&#8217;t die on the vine</strong></a></p>
<p>Startups are hard enough without trying to deal with screwed up finances. In this article, Zeni founder Swapnil Shinde outlines three different financial pitfalls that are easy to fall into, but avoidable: fragmented finances, old data, and founders that don&#8217;t know when/what to delegate.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2185974" style="width: 1310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2185974" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2185974 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1303504310.jpg" alt="Directly above view of some rotten cherry tomatoes on Yellow background" width="1300" height="868" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1303504310.jpg 1300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1303504310.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1303504310.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1303504310.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1303504310.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-1303504310.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1300px) 100vw, 1300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2185974" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Javier+Zayas+Photography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Javier Zayas Photography <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/pixels-palm-readers-and-pokemon-problems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186907</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital transformation depends on diversity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/digital-transformation-depends-on-diversity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/digital-transformation-depends-on-diversity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 14:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial general intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybernetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neural networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2185537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have an opportunity to apply AI and machine learning to propel the future and do good. That begins with diverse teams that reflect the full diversity and rich perspectives of our world.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Katia Walsh</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/katiawalsh">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		 <a href="https://www.levistrauss.com/who-we-are/leadership/katia-walsh/">Katia Walsh</a> leads strategy, data, analytics and artificial intelligence at <a href="https://www.levistrauss.com/">Levi Strauss &amp; Co</a>.
	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Across industries, businesses are now tech and data companies. The sooner they grasp and live that, the quicker they will meet their customer needs and expectations, create more business value and grow. It is increasingly important to reimagine business and use digital technologies to create new business processes, cultures, customer experiences and opportunities.</p>
<p>One of the myths about digital transformation is that it&#8217;s all about harnessing technology. It’s not. To succeed, digital transformation inherently requires and relies on diversity. Artificial intelligence (AI) is the result of human intelligence, enabled by its vast talents and also susceptible to its limitations.</p>
<p>Therefore, it is imperative for organizations and teams to make diversity a priority and think about it beyond the traditional sense. For me, diversity centers around three key pillars.</p>
<h2>People</h2>
<p>People are the most important part of artificial intelligence; the fact is that humans create artificial intelligence. The diversity of people — the team of decision-makers in the creation of AI algorithms — must reflect the diversity of the general population.</p>
<p>This goes beyond ensuring opportunities for women in AI and technology roles. In addition, it includes the full dimensions of gender, race, ethnicity, skill set, experience, geography, education, perspectives, interests and more. Why? When you have diverse teams reviewing and analyzing data to make decisions, you mitigate the chances of their own individual and uniquely human experiences, privileges and limitations blinding them to the experiences of others.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			One of the myths about digital transformation is that it&#8217;s all about harnessing technology. It’s not. 					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Collectively, we have an opportunity to apply AI and machine learning to propel the future and do good. That begins with diverse teams of people who reflect the full diversity and rich perspectives of our world.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Diversity of skills, perspectives, experiences and geographies has played a key role in our digital transformation. At Levi Strauss &amp; Co., our growing strategy and AI team doesn’t include solely data and machine learning scientists and engineers. We recently tapped employees from across the organization around the world and deliberately set out to train people with no previous experience in coding or statistics. We took people in retail operations, distribution centers and warehouses, and design and planning and put them through our first-ever machine learning bootcamp, building on their expert retail skills and supercharging them with coding and statistics.</p>
<p>We did not limit the required backgrounds; we simply looked for people who were curious problem solvers, analytical by nature and persistent to look for various ways of approaching business issues. The combination of existing expert retail skills and added machine learning knowledge meant employees who graduated from the program now have meaningful new perspectives on top of their business value. This first-of-its-kind initiative in the retail industry helped us develop a talented and diverse bench of team members.</p>
<h2>Data</h2>
<p>AI and machine learning capabilities are only as good as the data put into the system. We often limit ourselves to thinking of data in terms of structured tables &#8212; numbers and figures &#8212; but data is anything that can be digitized.</p>
<p>The digital images of the jeans and jackets our company has been producing for the past 168 years are data. The customer service conversations (recorded only with permissions) are data. The heatmaps from how people move in our stores are data. The reviews from our consumers are data. Today, everything that can be digitized becomes data. We need to broaden how we think of data and ensure we constantly feed all data into AI work.</p>
<p>Most predictive models use data from the past to predict the future. But because the apparel industry is still in the nascent stages of digital, data and AI adoption, having past data to reference is often a common problem. In fashion, we’re looking ahead to predict trends and demand for completely new products, which have no sales history. How do we do that?</p>
<p>We use more data than ever before, for example, both images of the new products and a database of our products from past seasons. We then apply computer vision algorithms to detect similarity between past and new fashion products, which helps us predict demand for those new products. These applications provide much more accurate estimates than experience or intuition do, supplementing previous practices with data- and AI-powered predictions.</p>
<p>At Levi Strauss &amp; Co., we also use digital images and 3D assets to simulate how clothes feel and even create new fashion. For example, we train neural networks to understand the nuances around various jean styles like tapered legs, whisker patterns and distressed looks, and detect the physical properties of the components that affect the drapes, folds and creases. We’re then able to combine this with market data, where we can tailor our product collections to meet changing consumer needs and desires and focus on the inclusiveness of our brand across demographics. Furthermore, we use AI to create new styles of apparel while always retaining the creativity and innovation of our world-class designers.</p>
<h2>Tools and techniques</h2>
<p>In addition to people and data, we need to ensure diversity in the tools and techniques we use in the creation and production of algorithms. Some AI systems and products use classification techniques, which can perpetuate gender or racial bias.</p>
<p>For example, classification techniques assume gender is binary and commonly assign people as “male” or “female” based on physical appearance and stereotypical assumptions, meaning all other forms of gender identity are erased. That’s a problem, and it’s upon all of us working in this space, in any company or industry, to prevent bias and advance techniques in order to capture all the nuances and ranges in people’s lives. For example, we can take race out of the data to try and render an algorithm race-blind while continuously safeguarding against bias.</p>
<p>We are committed to diversity in our AI products and systems and, in striving for that, we use open-source tools. Open-source tools and libraries by their nature are more diverse because they are available to everyone around the world and people from all backgrounds and fields work to enhance and advance them, enriching with their experiences and thus limiting bias.</p>
<p>An example of how we do this at Levi Strauss &amp; Company is with our U.S. Red Tab loyalty program. As fans set up their profiles, we don’t ask them to pick a gender or allow the AI system to make assumptions. Instead, we ask them to pick their style preferences (Women, Men, Both or Don&#8217;t Know) in order to help our AI system build tailored shopping experiences and more personalized product recommendations.</p>
<p>Diversity of people, data, and techniques and tools is helping Levi Strauss &amp; Co. revolutionize its business and our entire industry, transforming manual to automated, analog to digital, and intuitive to predictive. We are also building on the legacy of our company’s social values, which has stood for equality, democracy and inclusiveness for 168 years. Diversity in AI is one of the latest opportunities to continue this legacy and shape the future of fashion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1G0KT8L67g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/how-to-choose-and-deploy-industry-specific-ai-models/">How to choose and deploy industry-specific AI models</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to choose and deploy industry-specific AI models&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/how-to-choose-and-deploy-industry-specific-ai-models/embed/#?secret=1G0KT8L67g" data-secret="1G0KT8L67g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/digital-transformation-depends-on-diversity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2185537</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Station: An ADAS business bidding war, the gig worker fight heats up and Biden&#8217;s executive order</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/the-station-an-adas-business-bidding-war-the-gig-worker-fight-heats-up-and-bidens-executive-order/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/the-station-an-adas-business-bidding-war-the-gig-worker-fight-heats-up-and-bidens-executive-order/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOLS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veoneer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox. Hello readers: Welcome to The Station, your central hub for all past, present and future means of moving people and packages from Point A to Point B. Before [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>The Station is a weekly newsletter dedicated to all things transportation. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here — just click The Station — to receive it every weekend in your inbox</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello readers: Welcome to The Station, your central hub for all past, present and future means of moving people and packages from Point A to Point B.</p>
<p>Before you dive in, I wanted to flag one article that digs into the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/drunk-driving-provision-could-fuel-demand-for-driver-detection-technology/">drunk driving tech provision</a> inserted in the $1 trillion infrastructure bill. Rebecca Bellan looks at the companies developing driver detection technology. The industry could get a boost from the provision that would require automakers to build into new cars technology that can tell if drivers are under the influence.</p>
<p>As always, you can email me at <a href="mailto:kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com">kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com</a> to share thoughts, criticisms, offer up opinions or tips. You can also send a direct message to me at Twitter — <a href="https://twitter.com/kirstenkorosec">@kirstenkorosec</a>.</p>
<h2>Micromobbin&#8217;</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1894192 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png" alt="the station scooter1a" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/the-station-scooter1a.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start out with the latest drama with <strong>JOCO</strong>, a private docked electric bike service that&#8217;s trying really hard to fight Citi Bike&#8217;s hold over NYC. The company, which aims to provide docked e-bikes based out of private locations, is currently undergoing legal struggles with the city that says docked e-bikes are the domain of <strong>Citi Bike</strong> and no one else. Now, JOCO is pivoting its services to provide e-bikes for the NYC delivery and courier sector. Gotta make use of that hardware.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <strong>Lyft</strong>, which owns Citi Bike, is working on capturing more market share with Lyft Pink Annual, a new multimodal transportation membership that provides unlimited bikeshare benefits across Lyft-operated bikeshare systems in New York, Chicago, SF, Minneapolis, Portland, Columbus, Denver and Santa Monica. It&#8217;s $199/year, which Lyft says is $40 cheaper over the course of a year when compared to monthly. Aside from unlimited 45-minute pedal bike rides, discounted e-bike rides and unlocks and 15% off all personal rideshare rides, members get cool stuff like free food delivery with Seamless+ or Grubhub+ membership, free rental upgrades with SIXT, priority airport pickups and other transportation perks.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While we&#8217;re on the subject of e-bikes, <strong>Lime</strong> is featuring <strong>Wheels</strong>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/lime-revamps-its-app-to-include-competitors-starting-with-wheels-ebikes/">another e-bikeshare platform</a> in Seattle, on its app which will give the smaller company more visibility and business and Lime more omnipresence.</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s talk about scooters</h2>
<p>Abu Dhabi-based micromobility company <strong>Fenix</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/e-scooter-company-fenix-acquires-palm-for-5m-gains-entry-to-turkish-market/">has acquired</a> <strong>Palm</strong>, a shared e-scooter company in Turkey, for $5 million &#8212; the exact amount the company raised last November and this past February during its seed round. While Lime and Bird have a pretty big global footprint, Fenix is quickly positioning itself as the shared micromobility leader in the Middle East as it plans to continue to expand into Turkey, a country of 83 million people.</p>
<p>Speaking of the Middle East, e-scooter designer and manufacturer <strong>Inokim</strong> announced that it&#8217;s merged its business operations in Israel with its manufacturing facility in China into one business entity. The <a href="https://click.mlsend2.com/link/c/YT0xNzQzNjM5NDEyMjA3NTIwMjIwJmM9bzViMiZlPTE5MjgmYj02NzYwMzY1NzYmZD1yNHo1bzNx.8LbnOjjdmKjR3w9qSRQoDvjNoxLxmYTmEx604ePHLag">merger with a premium Chinese manufacturer</a> will provide the company with better control over the entire value chain for its electric scooters from R&amp;D to manufacturing to marketing and sales as it plans to ramp up its global expansion, the company says.</p>
<p><strong>Bird</strong> announced the launch of its <a href="https://www.bird.co/blog/bird-community-safety-zones-offer-added-pedestrian-protection/">Community Safety Zones</a>, which are geo-fenced zones around high-pedestrian areas like schools and hospitals that will automatically slow Bird&#8217;s scooters down. The zones will launch near schools in Miami, and Bird hopes to expand the program to all its partner cities.</p>
<p>Berlin-based <strong>Tier</strong>, which recently won the London e-scooter trial, is partnering with AI startup <strong>Captur</strong> to encourage riders and pedestrians to snitch on misparking, misuse and abandonment of scooters. To report an issue, people need only scan the QR code on the scooter, and a member of Tier&#8217;s Street Ranger crew will head out to solve the issue in &#8220;under ten minutes.&#8221; Snitches get incentives to report issues with the dangling carrot of points towards a donation to a charity of their choice.</p>
<p><strong>Gogoro</strong>, a Taiwanese company that runs a network of battery swapping refueling platforms for electric scooters, mopeds and motorcycles, has announced its 400,000th Gogoro Network monthly subscriber. The company says it&#8217;s surpassed 200 million battery swaps since its 2015 launch. This is a pretty major milestone in an industry (battery swapping) that hasn&#8217;t really taken off anywhere but Asia, which positions Gogoro to lead the charge when they start expanding more broadly outside the APAC region.</p>
<h2>Deal of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1896226 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png" alt="money the station" width="1600" height="400" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=1536,384 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/money-the-station.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Whoop! It&#8217;s a bidding war.</p>
<p>Remember last week when I highlighted <strong>Magna International&#8217;s </strong>plan to acquire <strong>Swedish automotive tech company Veoneer </strong>for $3.8 billion? Welp, it got a bit more interesting Thursday after <strong>Qualcomm</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/qualcomm-wants-to-buy-veoneer-for-4-6b-beating-magnas-offer/">submitted its own bid</a> for the company for $800 million more.</p>
<p>Qualcomm&#8217;s $4.6 billion offer, which comes in at $37 per share, has already received approval from the company&#8217;s board and would not need a stockholder vote. Veoneer and Magna said in July that both companies&#8217; boards had approved the acquisition.</p>
<p>Why does any of this matter? These companies might not have the name recognition of the Big Three automakers, but they&#8217;re making and supplying a lot of the tech that goes into the millions of new vehicles being sold to customers, like you, today.</p>
<p>Veoneer is a developer of advanced driver assistance systems, decision-making vehicle hardware and software that can perform a limited set of actions under certain conditions, like changing lanes on a highway or emergency braking. ADAS has become a big and growing business as the timeline to commercialize autonomous vehicle technology has lengthened.</p>
<p>The bidding war between Magna and Qualcomm suggests the companies are bullish on the future of ADAS technology, as each one seeks to stay competitive with Tier-1 ADAS suppliers Continental and Bosch. Qualcomm&#8217;s market capitalization currently sits at $164.8 billion, while Magna&#8217;s is $25.3 billion. It&#8217;s unclear whether Magna will submit a counter-bid.</p>
<p><strong>Other deals that got my attention &#8230;.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Bolt Technology</strong>, which competes with Uber in Europe and Africa, doubled its valuation to 4 billion euros ($4.8 billion) after raising 600 million euros from Sequoia Capital and Tekne Capital Management, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-02/uber-rival-bolt-lifts-valuation-to-4-8-billion-in-delivery-push?sref=gni836kR">Bloomberg reported</a>. The funds will be used to fund a grocery-delivery service that its calling Bolt Market. FYI: The Information&#8217;s Kate Clark had <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/online-checkout-startup-bolt-valued-at-4-billion">snippets of this story</a> weeks before it was officially announced.</p>
<p><strong>Bridgestone</strong> acquired fleet management platform company Azuga Holdings Inc. for $391 million. Look for an article this coming week from me that looks at how this fits into the tire company&#8217;s growth plan.</p>
<p><strong>Elroy Air</strong> raised a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/autonomous-cargo-drone-startup-elroy-air-lands-40m-series-a/">$40 million Series A</a>, including financing from Lockheed Martin&#8217;s venture capital arm, to ramp up the building, testing and validation of its inaugural autonomous cargo drone. Marlinspike Capital and Prosperity7 and existing investors Catapult Ventures, DiamondStream Partners, Side X Side Management, Shield Capital Partners and Precursor Ventures also participated. This latest round brings Elroy&#8217;s total raised to $48 million to date.</p>
<p><strong>John Deere</strong>, the agricultural equipment and technology giant agreed to acquire <strong>Bear Flag Robotics</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/john-deere-buys-autonomous-tractor-startup-bear-flag-robotics/">for $250 million</a>. That&#8217;s a huge win for Bear Flag and its backers. The startup, founded in 2017 and a member of the YC winter cohort of 2018, had raised just $12.5 million in seed funding.</p>
<p><strong>MotoRefi</strong> added another $5 million to its Series B, bringing the total to $50 million. Here&#8217;s the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/goldman-sachs-leads-45m-investment-into-auto-fintech-startup-motorefi/">original article</a> on the raise, which at the time was $45 million.</p>
<p><strong>Nuvve Holding Corp.</strong>, a vehicle-to-grid (V2G) platform company, formed a joint venture with Stonepeak Partners (specifically some its &#8220;investment vehicles&#8221; that it manages) and its portfolio company Evolve Transition Infrastructure. The $750 million venture called Levo Mobility will focus on advancing the electrification of transportation by funding V2G-enabled electric vehicle fleet deployments.</p>
<p><strong>Third Wave Automation</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/third-wave-automation-raises-40m-to-bring-its-autonomous-forklifts-to-warehouses/">raised $40 million</a> in a Series B round led by Norwest Venture Partners, including participation from prior investors Innovation Endeavors and Eclipse, along with Toyota Ventures, according to a Form D filed with regulators. Matt Howard, general partner at Norwest Venture Partners, will join Third Wave&#8217;s board of directors.</p>
<p><strong>Voi</strong>, the micromobility startup, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/micromobility-startup-voi-raises-45-million-to-end-sidewalk-riding-improve-safety/">raised $45 million</a> in a round led by The Raine Group. Existing investors including VNV Global participated alongside new investors. The company did not specify who those new investors are. Voi&#8217;s total funding to $205 million. The funds will be used to research and develop computer vision technology that will improve safety, keep users from riding on sidewalks and ensure scooters are properly parked.</p>
<h2>Notable news and other tidbits</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-1926823 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png" alt="" width="1600" height="401" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png 1600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=150,38 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=300,75 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=768,192 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=680,170 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=1536,385 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/the-station-ride-hailing1.png?resize=50,13 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></a></p>
<p>Lots to read here. Let&#8217;s go.</p>
<h3>Autonomous vehicles</h3>
<p><strong>Baidu</strong> launched Apolong II, a new generation of multi-purpose autonomous minibuses designed to be customizable for purposes like public transport, mobile policing, healthcare providers and other commercial industry scenarios. This is an upgrade from its Apolong predecessor, which means it got an upgrade in computing power and sensors.</p>
<p>The company said its Apolong series vehicles have already been deployed in 22 urban parks in Beijing, Guangzhou, Xiong&#8217;an, Chongqing and Foshan.</p>
<h3>Earnings season</h3>
<p>Since there are sooooo many new compamies going piublic, we&#8217;re beefing up our coverage in this area. We&#8217;ll be looking at the numbers and other news that come out of the earnings reports.</p>
<p><strong>Fisker</strong>: The company is pre-revenue but still managed to generate $27,000 in the second quarter from merchandise sales. It had a net loss of $46.2 million, or $0.16 per share, compared to a net loss of $176.8 million in the previous quarter. That large net loss in Q1 came from changes in how the SEC treated non-cash items and resulted in warrants liability of $138 million. The public warrants are now retired.</p>
<p>Loss from operations were $53.1 million in the second quarter compared to a loss of $33 million in the first quarter. Cash and cash equivalents were $962 million, slightly lower than the $985.1 million in the first quarter.</p>
<p>I spoke to co-founder Henrik Fisker and the interesting bits from the interview and remarks made during the earnings call centered on expectations that operating expenses will reach between $490 million and $530 million this year, a slight increase in its business outlook for the year that is driven by R&amp;D spending on prototypes for its Ocean SUV, testing and validation of advanced technology, hiring and its &#8220;accelerating&#8221; partnership with <strong>Foxconn</strong>. Read on to learn more about this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/fisker-foxconn-ev-partnership-moving-faster-than-expected-ceo-henrik-fisker-says/">relationship with Foxconn</a>.</p>
<p><strong>GM</strong>: The company&#8217;s earnings were dragged down by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/gms-earnings-dragged-down-by-chevy-bolt-recall/">$800 million in warranty expenses</a> from its twice-issued recall for 2017 to 2019 Chevrolet Bolt electric vehicles. Costs associated with fixing defective Bolt batteries make up the lion&#8217;s share of GM&#8217;s $1.3 billion in warranty expenses last quarter.</p>
<p>GM reported revenues of $34.2 billion, up $1.7 billion from the first quarter 2021, and $17.4 billion up from its year-ago quarterly result. GM also reported net income of $2.84 billion in the second quarter, up from a year-ago loss of $758 million, largely driven by the pandemic and associated economic fallout. GM&#8217;s adjusted income of $4.1 billion is inclusive of recall costs.</p>
<p>Income was boosted by used car prices, truck and SUV sales, and strong profits at GM Financial. GM&#8217;s lending arm posted net sales of $3.4 billion and adjusted income of $1.58 billion for the quarter.</p>
<p><strong>Lyft</strong>: managed to produce positive adjusted EBITDA in the quarter, a profit metric favored by technology upstarts that have yet to generate net income, a stricter method of calculating profitability. Adjusted EBITDA for the second quarter was $23.8 million.</p>
<p>Revenue was $765 million in the second quarter, more than double the $339.3 million million it brought in during the same period last year. While that is remarkable, remember last year at this time the economy and ride-hailing were getting pummeled by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Lyft&#8217;s Q2 revenue grew 25.6% over last quarter&#8217;s $609 million. That means that despite rising case counts in the United States thanks to the delta COVID-19 variant, Lyft still managed to grow. Read on for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/lyft-reaches-adjusted-profitability-milestone-despite-continuing-net-losses/">more on Lyft&#8217;s earnings</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Nikola</strong>: reported a net loss of $143 million in the second quarter, up from a $115.7 million loss in the same period last year. Its adjusted loss was 20 cents per share, which is actually better than analysts expected. The company&#8217;s cash balance at the end of the quarter was $632.6 million. Importantly, the pre-revenue company warned that supply chain constraints are causing numerous delays forcing it to slash its vehicle delivery projections in half.</p>
<p>Nikola said plans to produce 50 to 100 electric semi trucks in this year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/nikola-cuts-delivery-outlook-for-its-electric-semi-trucks/">have been lowered</a> to 25 to 50 units. The company also cut its revenue forecast for the year to $0 to $7.5 million. It was previously $15 million to $30 million.</p>
<p><strong>TuSimple</strong>: The autonomous trucking company reported $1.5 million in revenue in Q2. The bigger news from the earnings report, which <a href="https://www.freightwaves.com/news/tusimple-discloses-specifics-of-federal-ownership-probe">FreightWaves caught</a>, is that the company is waiting for the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to finish its review. Specifically, they&#8217;re looking at the the 2017 acquisition of the U.S. business of TuSimple LLC by Tusimple (Cayman) Ltd. It was assumed that the investigation was focused on China&#8217;s Sina investment in TuSimple.</p>
<p><strong>Uber</strong>: While Lyft managed to generate positive adjusted EBITDA in the second quarter, Uber did not. However, Uber did generate positive net income of $1.14 billion in the quarter thanks to its investments in other companies like Didi and Aurora Innovation.</p>
<p>Its Q2 performance was enough to keep Uber on track toward its pre-tax profitability goal. Read on for our (me and Alex Wilhelm) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/uber-shares-fall-despite-revenue-beat-as-its-core-operations-continue-to-lose-money/">closer look at Uber&#8217;s earnings</a>.</p>
<p>Also, Uber&#8217;s massive $250 million stimulus package launched in April to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/how-uber-plans-to-rebound-from-massive-q2-losses-stemming-from-driver-incentives/">incentivize drivers</a> back onto the app after a pandemic-induced shortage contributed to its losses.</p>
<p><strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong>: saw shipping and package volume fall by 14.1% year-on-year in its fiscal year 2021 third quarter as a surge in demand for package delivery services began to slow, <a href="https://www.freightwaves.com/news/postal-service-reports-3-billion-year-on-year-loss">FreightWaves reported</a>.</p>
<p>Revenue for that sector of its business fell 7.8% in the quarter. Shipping and package volume is still higher than pre-pandemic levels.</p>
<p><strong>Velodyne Lidar</strong>: Corporate DRAMA <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/the-cost-of-velodynes-internal-drama-is-starting-to-add-up/">is expensive</a>. The sensor company&#8217;s second quarter earnings show a company spending more to find new customers for its products while grappling with an increasingly expensive internal drama. Among its costs: $8 million in equity compensation for its recently resigned CEO Anand Gopalan and a 21% jump in general and administrative expenses due to increased public company and legal expenses. (The board is in a battle with its founder David Hall and wife, Marta Hall).</p>
<p>The company said it expects general and administrative expenses to increase by about 35% in 2021. The company is also investing heavily in growth, namely in sales and marketing. A large majority of operating expenses were spent on sales and marketing. Velodyne spent $47.2 million in the second quarter, which is up massively from $7.1 million in the first quarter.</p>
<h3>Electric vehicles</h3>
<p><strong>Arrival</strong> announced it will be co-developing its digital fleet and vehicle capabilities for the automotive industry with <strong>Microsoft</strong>. This cloud-based approach using Microsoft Azure will enable advanced uses of telemetry, vehicle and fleet data management across vehicle fleets, according to the company.</p>
<p><strong>GM</strong> is adding <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/gm-is-adding-to-two-new-zero-emission-commercial-vehicles-to-its-lineup/">two new zero-emissions vehicles</a> to its commercial portfolio as it looks to expand its first-to-last-mile business arm, BrightDrop. The first vehicle will be a battery electric cargo van under the Chevrolet brand that will likely be similar to the popular Chevy Express van. The second will be a medium-duty truck that CEO Mary Barra said &#8220;will put both the Ultium and Hydrotec hydrogen fuel cell technology to work.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Pen Test Partners</strong>, U.K. cybersecurity company, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/security-flaws-found-in-popular-ev-chargers/">identified several vulnerabilities</a> in six home electric vehicle charging brands and a large public EV charging network. While the charger manufacturers resolved most of the issues, the findings are the latest example of the poorly regulated world of Internet of Things devices, which are poised to become all but ubiquitous in our homes and vehicles.</p>
<p><strong>Volkswagen Group</strong> CEO Herbert Diess had a difficult time recharging his electric vehicle during a road trip. His experience isn&#8217;t unusual. When I saw his comments on LinkedIn, which were then <a href="https://europe.autonews.com/automakers/vw-ceo-blasts-ev-charging-ventures-station-after-italy-trip">picked up by media outlets</a>, I thought to myself: &#8216;this is why executives should be trying out products early!&#8217; EV charging woes are old news and Diess is just experiencing these now?</p>
<h3>EVTOLS and flight</h3>
<p><strong>Lilium</strong> is negotiating the terms for a 220-aircraft, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/lilium-in-talks-with-brazilian-airline-for-1b-order/">$1 billion order</a> with one of Brazil&#8217;s largest domestic airlines. Should the deal with Azul move forward, it would mark the largest order in Lilium&#8217;s history and its first foray into South American markets. The 220 aircraft would fly as part of a new, co-branded airline network that would operate in Brazil.</p>
<p><strong>United Airlines</strong> announced that it will require its U.S. employees to get vaccinated against COVID-19 this fall,<a href="https://thehill.com/policy/transportation/aviation/566673-united-becomes-first-major-airline-to-mandate-vaccines-for"> the Hill reports</a>. United is the first major airline to issue a vaccine mandate. Employees will be required to show proof of vaccination five weeks after the Food and Drug Administration grants the vaccines full approval, or Oct. 25, whichever comes first.</p>
<h3>Ride-hailing</h3>
<p><strong>Lyft, Uber, Doordash </strong>and <strong>Instacart</strong> are part of a coalition of app-based ride-hailing and on-demand delivery companies that filed a petition for a ballot initiative in Massachusetts that would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/gig-companies-take-worker-classification-fight-to-massachusetts-through-ballot-initiative/">keep gig economy workers classified as independent contractors</a> as the industry takes a fight it won in California on the road.</p>
<p>The ballot measure proposed by the Massachusetts Coalition for Independent Work comes nearly a year after California voters approved a similar measure known as Proposition 22 that pitted labor rights advocates against gig economy companies in a costly multimillion battle. Uber CEO <strong>Dara Khosrowshahi</strong> expressed his support also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/uber-ceo-calls-massachusetts-gig-economy-ballot-measure-the-right-answer/">expressed his support</a> for this measure during the company&#8217;s Q2 earnings call.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/08/the-station-an-adas-business-bidding-war-the-gig-worker-fight-heats-up-and-bidens-executive-order/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187167</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week in Apps: In-app events hit the App Store, TikTok tries Stories, Apple reveals new child safety plan</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/07/this-week-in-apps-in-app-events-hit-the-app-store-tiktok-tries-stories-apple-reveals-new-child-safety-plan/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/07/this-week-in-apps-in-app-events-hit-the-app-store-tiktok-tries-stories-apple-reveals-new-child-safety-plan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 19:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ADT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AfterPay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ant group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app maker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automattic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase Card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day one]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragoneer investment group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[driver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dropbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duolingo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emojipedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fintech startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gif]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyperconnect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JAM Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Mateen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kuaishou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kuda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meituan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[onstar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playdemic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean Rad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensor tower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[This Week In Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valar ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viasat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VNV Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wi-fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordpress.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zedge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zynga]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2186642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to This Week in Apps, the weekly TechCrunch series that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy. The app industry continues to grow, with a record 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also spent 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices alone. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to This Week in Apps, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/">the weekly TechCrunch series</a> that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy.</p>
<p>The app industry continues to grow, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a record</a> 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">spent</a> 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices alone. And in the U.S., app usage surged ahead of the time spent watching live TV. Currently, the average American <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">watches</a> 3.7 hours of live TV per day, but now spends four hours per day on their mobile devices.</p>
<p>Apps aren’t just a way to pass idle hours — they’re also a big business. In 2019, mobile-first companies had a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/app-stores-saw-record-204-billion-app-downloads-in-2019-consumer-spend-of-120-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">combined</a> $544 billion valuation, 6.5x higher than those without a mobile focus. In 2020, investors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">poured</a> $73 billion in capital into mobile companies — a figure that’s up 27% year-over-year.</p>
<div data-pm-slice="1 1 []" data-en-clipboard="true">This Week in Apps offers a way to keep up with this fast-moving industry in one place, with the latest from the world of apps, including news, updates, startup fundings, mergers and acquisitions, and suggestions about new apps and games to try, too.</div>
<p><em><strong>Do you want This Week in Apps in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up here: <a href="http://techcrunch.com/newsletters">techcrunch.com/newsletters</a></strong></em></p>
<h1>Top Stories</h1>
<h3>Apple to scan for CSAM imagery</h3>
<p>Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/apple-icloud-photos-scanning/">announced</a> a major initiative to scan devices for CSAM imagery. The company on Thursday announced a new set of features, arriving later this year, that will detect child sexual abuse material (CSAM) in its cloud and report it to law enforcement. Companies like Dropbox, Google and Microsoft already scan for CSAM in their cloud services, but Apple had allowed users to encrypt their data before it reached iCloud. Now, Apple&#8217;s new technology, NeuralHash, will run on users&#8217; devices, tatformso detect when a users upload known CSAM imagery &#8212; without having to first decrypt the images. It even can detect the imagery if it&#8217;s been cropped or edited in an attempt to avoid detection.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LQ0cxddXKK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/apple-icloud-photos-scanning/">Apple confirms it will begin scanning iCloud Photos for child abuse images</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple confirms it will begin scanning iCloud Photos for child abuse images&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/apple-icloud-photos-scanning/embed/#?secret=LQ0cxddXKK" data-secret="LQ0cxddXKK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Meanwhile, on iPhone and iPad, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/new-apple-technology-will-warn-parents-and-children-about-sexually-explicit-photos-in-messages/">will roll out protections</a> to Messages app users that will filter images and alert children and parents if sexually explicit photos are sent to or from a child&#8217;s account. Children will not be shown the images but will instead see a grayed-out image instead. If they try to view the image anyway through the link, they&#8217;ll be shown interruptive screens that explain why the material may be harmful and are warned that their parents will be notified.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6kWgV96mQD"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/new-apple-technology-will-warn-parents-and-children-about-sexually-explicit-photos-in-messages/">New Apple technology will warn parents and children about sexually explicit photos in Messages</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;New Apple technology will warn parents and children about sexually explicit photos in Messages&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/new-apple-technology-will-warn-parents-and-children-about-sexually-explicit-photos-in-messages/embed/#?secret=6kWgV96mQD" data-secret="6kWgV96mQD" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Some privacy advocates <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/08/05/security-researchers-alarmed-apple-csam-plans/">pushed back</a> at the idea of such a system, believing it could expand to end-to-end encrypted photos, lead to false positives, or set the stage for more on-device government surveillance in the future. But many <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/apple-csam-detection-icloud-photos-encryption-privacy/">cryptology experts believe the system</a> Apple developed provides a good balance between privacy and utility, and have offered their endorsement of the technology. In addition, Apple said reports are manually reviewed before being sent to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC).</p>
<p>The changes may also benefit iOS developers who deal in user photos and uploads, as predators will no longer store CSAM imagery on iOS devices in the first place, given the new risk of detection.</p>
<h3>In-App Events appear on the App Store</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2186990" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186990" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2186990" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-3.29.13-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="589" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-3.29.13-PM.png 1470w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-3.29.13-PM.png?resize=150,130 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-3.29.13-PM.png?resize=300,260 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-3.29.13-PM.png?resize=768,666 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-3.29.13-PM.png?resize=680,589 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-3.29.13-PM.png?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2186990" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apple</p></div></p>
<p>Though not yet publicly available to all users, those testing the new iOS 15 mobile operating system <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/03/app-store-events-ios-ipados-15/">got their first glimpse</a> of a new App Store discovery feature this week: &#8220;<a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/in-app-events/">in-app events</a>.&#8221; First <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/apple-to-introduce-a-b-testing-and-in-app-events-to-the-app-store/">announced</a> at this year&#8217;s WWDC, the feature will allow developers and Apple editors alike to showcase directly on the App Store upcoming events taking place inside apps.</p>
<p>The events can appear on the App Store homepage, on the app&#8217;s product pages or can be discovered through personalized recommendations and search. In some cases, editors will curate events to feature on the App Store. But developers will also be provided tools to submit their own in-app events. TikTok&#8217;s &#8220;Summer Camp&#8221; for creators was one of the first in-app events to be featured, where it received a top spot on the iPadOS 15 App Store.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/brahmshank/status/1422584213073588233"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2187109" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-6.32.04-PM.png?w=584" alt="" width="584" height="402" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-6.32.04-PM.png 584w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-6.32.04-PM.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-6.32.04-PM.png?resize=300,207 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-6.32.04-PM.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 584px) 100vw, 584px" /></a></p>
<h1>Weekly News</h1>
<h3>Platforms: Apple</h3>
<p><strong>Apple <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/08/student-ids-on-iphone-and-apple-watch-expand-to-canada-and-more-us-universities/">expands support</a> for student IDs on iPhone and Apple Watch</strong> ahead of the fall semester. Tens of thousands more U.S. and Canadian colleges will now support mobile student IDs in the Apple Wallet app, including Auburn University, Northern Arizona University, University of Maine, New Mexico State University and others.</p>
<p><strong>Apple <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/05/apple-promotes-scam-apps-app-store">was accused</a> of promoting scam apps in the App Store&#8217;s featured section.</strong> The company&#8217;s failure to properly police its store is one thing, but to curate an editorial list that actually includes the scams is quite another. One of the games rounded up under &#8220;Slime Relaxations,&#8221; an already iffy category to say the least, was a subscription-based slime simulator that locked users into a $13 AUD per week subscription for its slime simulator. One of the apps on the curated list didn&#8217;t even function, implying that Apple&#8217;s editors hadn&#8217;t even tested the apps they recommend.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is infuriating. How is Apple *featuring* these scams?</p>
<p>Let&#39;s take a look at one of these apps! </p>
<p>&quot;Jelly: Slime simulator, ASMR&quot;</p>
<p>1/<a href="https://t.co/lDTn8eEVfz">https://t.co/lDTn8eEVfz</a> <a href="https://t.co/VyYKUSLdJE">pic.twitter.com/VyYKUSLdJE</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Simeon (@twolivesleft) <a href="https://twitter.com/twolivesleft/status/1423115528680349700?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><strong>Tax changes hit the App Store.</strong> Apple <a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=o0uodgu7">announced</a> tax and price changes for apps and IAPs in South Africa, the U.K. and all territories using the Euro currency, all of which will see decreases. Increases will occur in Georgia and Tajikistan, due to new tax changes. Proceeds on the App Store in Italy will be increased to reflect a change to the Digital Services Tax effective rate.</p>
<p><strong>Game Center changes, too.</strong> Apple said that on August 4, a new certificate for server-based Game Center verification will be available via the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/gamekit/gklocalplayer/3516283-fetchitems">publicKeyUrl</a>.</p>
<h3>Fintech</h3>
<p><strong>Robinhood <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/03/robinhood-surges-10percent-runs-past-38-ipo-price.html">stock jumped</a> more than 24% to $46.80</strong> on Tuesday after initially falling 8% on its first day of trading last week, after which it had continued to trade below its opening price of $38.</p>
<p><strong>Square&#8217;s Cash app <a href="https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/square-booked-a-45-million-impairment-on-its-bitcoin-holdings-2021-8">nearly doubled its gross profit</a> to $546 million in Q2</strong>, but also reported a $45 million impairment loss on its bitcoin holdings.</p>
<p><strong>Coinbase&#8217;s app now lets you buy your cryptocurrency <a href="https://community.spotify.com/t5/Closed-Ideas/iOS-Airplay-2-Support-for-iOS/idc-p/5244350/highlight/true#M235171">using Apple Pay.</a> </strong>The company previously made its Coinbase Card compatible with Apple Pay in June.</p>
<h3>Social</h3>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="zMYzQALzhi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/anonymous-snapchat-app-sendit-surges-with-3-5m-installs-after-snap-bans-yolo-and-lmk/">Sendit gains 3.5M downloads after Snapchat suspends top anonymous apps YOLO and LMK</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sendit gains 3.5M downloads after Snapchat suspends top anonymous apps YOLO and LMK&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/anonymous-snapchat-app-sendit-surges-with-3-5m-installs-after-snap-bans-yolo-and-lmk/embed/#?secret=zMYzQALzhi" data-secret="zMYzQALzhi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>An anonymous app called Sendit, which relies on Snap Kit to function, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/anonymous-snapchat-app-sendit-surges-with-3-5m-installs-after-snap-bans-yolo-and-lmk/">climbing the charts</a> of the U.S. App Store after Snap suspended similar apps, YOLO and LMK.</strong> Snap was sued by the parent of child who was bullied through those apps, which led to his suicide. Sendit also allows for anonymity, and reviews compare it to YOLO. But some reviews also complained about bullying. This isn&#8217;t the first time Snap has been involved in a lawsuit related to a young person&#8217;s death related to its app. The company was <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-57522146">also sued</a> for its irresponsible &#8220;speed filter&#8221; that critics said encouraged unsafe driving. Three young men died using the filter, which captured them doing 123 mph.</p>
<p><strong>TikTok is testing Stories.</strong> As Twitter&#8217;s own Stories integrations, Fleets, shuts down, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/tiktok-confirms-pilot-test-of-tiktok-stories-is-now-underway/">TikTok confirmed it&#8217;s testing its own Stories product</a>. The TikTok Stories appear in a left-hand sidebar and allow users to post ephemeral images or video that disappear in 24 hours. Users can also comment on Stories, which are public to their mutual friends and the creator. Stories on TikTok may make more sense than they did on Twitter, as TikTok is already known as a creative platform and it gives the app a more familiar place to integrate its effects toolset and, eventually, advertisements.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4osFJDHw8B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/tiktok-confirms-pilot-test-of-tiktok-stories-is-now-underway/">TikTok confirms pilot test of TikTok Stories is now underway</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok confirms pilot test of TikTok Stories is now underway&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/tiktok-confirms-pilot-test-of-tiktok-stories-is-now-underway/embed/#?secret=4osFJDHw8B" data-secret="4osFJDHw8B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Facebook has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/oh-facebook-changed-its-privacy-settings-again/">again re-arranged its privacy settings</a>.</strong> The company continually moves around where its privacy features are located, ostensibly to make them easier to find. But users then have to re-learn where to go to find the tools they need, after they had finally memorized the location. This time, the settings have been grouped into six top-level categories, but &#8220;privacy&#8221; settings have been unbundled from one location to be scattered among the other categories.</p>
<p><strong>A VICE report <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/k78kmv/instagram-ban-restore-service-scam">details ban-as-a-service operations</a> </strong>that allow anyone to harass or censor online creators on Instagram. Assuming you can find it, one operation charged $60 per ban, the listing says.</p>
<p><strong>TikTok merged personal accounts with creator accounts.</strong> The change means now all non-business accounts on TikTok will have access to the creator tools under Settings, including Analytics, Creator Portal, Promote and Q&amp;A. TikTok shared the news directly with subscribers of its TikTok Creators newsletter in August, and all users will get a push notification alerting them to the change, the company told us.</p>
<p><strong>Discord <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/discord-custom-profiles-about-me/">now lets users customize their profile</a> on its apps.</strong> The company added new features to its iOS and Android apps that let you add a description, links and emojis and select a profile color. Paid subscribers can also choose an image or GIF as their banner.</p>
<p><strong>Twitter Spaces <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/twitter-spaces-cohosts/">added a co-hosting option</a> that allows up to two co-hosts</strong> to be added to the live audio chat rooms. Now Spaces can have one main host, two co-hosts and up to 10 speakers. Co-hosts have all the moderation abilities as hosts, but can&#8217;t add or remove others as co-hosts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">making it easier to manage your Space…introducing co-hosting!</p>
<p>&#8211; hosts have two co-host invites they can send<br />&#8211; the table just got bigger: 1 host, 2 co-hosts, and 10 speakers<br />&#8211; co-hosts can help invite speakers, manage requests, remove participants, pin Tweets and more! <a href="https://t.co/s76JFbhTL2">pic.twitter.com/s76JFbhTL2</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Spaces (@TwitterSpaces) <a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1423333566675628039?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<h3>Messaging</h3>
<p><strong>Tencent <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-05/tencent-resumes-new-wechat-user-signups-after-upgrades?sref=gni836kR">reopened new user sign-ups</a> for its WeChat messaging app, after having suspended registrations last week for unspecified &#8220;technical upgrades.&#8221;</strong> The company, like many other Chinese tech giants, had to address new regulations from Beijing impacting the tech industry. <a href="https://supchina.com/2021/08/02/chinas-big-tech-crackdown-a-guide/">New rules address</a> how companies handle user data collection and storage, antitrust behavior and <a href="https://pekingnology.substack.com/p/politburo-meeting-calls-for-reinforcing">other checks</a> on capitalist &#8220;excess.&#8221; The gaming industry <a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3143754/chinas-video-game-crackdown-state-backed-industry-group-plays-down">is now worried</a> it&#8217;s next to be impacted, with regulations that would <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/03/tencent-netease-shares-tank-after-chinese-media-calls-gaming-opium.html">restrict gaming for minors</a> to fight addiction.</p>
<p><strong>WhatsApp is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/whatsapp-view-once-disappearing-photos-video/">adding a new feature</a> that will allow users to send photos and videos that disappear after a single viewing.</strong> The Snapchat-inspired feature, however, doesn&#8217;t alert you if the other person takes a screenshot &#8212; as Snap&#8217;s app does. So it may not be ideal for sharing your most sensitive content.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QmHhkMDNUF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/whatsapp-view-once-disappearing-photos-video/">WhatsApp photos and videos can now disappear after a single viewing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WhatsApp photos and videos can now disappear after a single viewing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/whatsapp-view-once-disappearing-photos-video/embed/#?secret=QmHhkMDNUF" data-secret="QmHhkMDNUF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Telegram&#8217;s <a href="https://telegram.org/blog/video-1000">update</a> expands group video calls to support up to 1,000 viewers.</strong> It also announced video messages can be recorded in higher quality and can be expanded, regular videos can be watched at 0.5 or 2x speed, screen sharing with sound is available for all video calls, including 1-on-1 calls, and more.</p>
<h3>Streaming &amp; Entertainment</h3>
<p><strong>American Airlines <a href="https://news.aa.com/news/news-details/2021/American-Airlines-Takes-TikTok-to-New-Heights-with-Free-Inflight-Access-for-Customers-MKG-OB-08/default.aspx">added free access to TikTok</a> aboard its Viasat-equipped aircraft.</strong> Passengers will be able to watch the app&#8217;s videos for up to 30 minutes for free and can even download the app if it&#8217;s not already installed. After the free time, they can opt to pay for Wi-Fi to keep watching. Considering how easy it is to fall into multi-hour TikTok viewing sessions without knowing it, the addition of the addictive app could make long plane rides feel shorter. Or at least less painful.</p>
<p><strong>Chinese TikTok rival Kuaishou <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-05/kuaishou-craters-after-lockup-expired-widening-tech-rout?sref=gni836kR">saw stocks fall by more than 15%</a> in Hong Kong, the most since its February IPO.</strong> The company is another victim of an ongoing market selloff triggered by increasing investor uncertainty related to China&#8217;s recent crackdown on tech companies. Beijing&#8217;s campaign to rein in tech has also impacted Tencent, Alibaba, Jack Ma&#8217;s Ant Group, food delivery company Meituan and ride-hailing company Didi. Also related, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/bytedance-rival-kuaishou-shuts-down-controversial-short-video-app-zynn-in-us/">Kuaishou shut down its controversial app Zynn</a>, which had been paying users to watch its short-form videos, including those stolen from other apps.</p>
<p><strong>Twitch overtook YouTube in consumer spending per user in April 2021,</strong> and now sees $6.20 per download as of June compared with YouTube&#8217;s $5.60, Sensor Tower <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/state-of-photo-video-apps-report-2021">found</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2186812" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186812" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2186812" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg 2304w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitch-youtube-rpd-comparison-q2-2021.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2186812" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Spotify<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607203/spotify-plus-ad-supported-tier-unlimited-skips-on-demand-listening"> confirmed tests</a> of a new ad-supported tier called Spotify Plus, which is only $0.99 per month</strong> and offers unlimited skips (like free users get on the desktop) and the ability to play the songs you want, instead of only being forced to use shuffle mode.</p>
<p><strong>The company also <a href="https://community.spotify.com/t5/Closed-Ideas/iOS-Airplay-2-Support-for-iOS/idc-p/5244350/highlight/true#M235171">noted in a forum posting</a> that it&#8217;s no longer working on AirPlay2 support,</strong> due to &#8220;audio driver compatibility&#8221; issues.</p>
<p><strong>Mark Cuban-backed audio app Fireside <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/30/22601191/fireside-app-mark-cuban-falon-fatemi-libsyn-rode-invest">asked its users to invest</a> in the company</strong> via an email sent to creators which didn&#8217;t share deal terms. The app has yet to launch.</p>
<p><strong>YouTube <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/youtubes-100-million-shorts-fund-to-challenge-tiktok-goes-live/">kicks off</a> its $100 million Shorts Fund aimed at taking on TikTok</strong> by providing creators with cash incentives for top videos. Creators will get bonuses of $100 to $10,000 based on their videos&#8217; performance.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9XmMyiMr5I"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/youtubes-100-million-shorts-fund-to-challenge-tiktok-goes-live/">YouTube&#8217;s $100 million Shorts Fund to challenge TikTok goes live</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;YouTube&#8217;s $100 million Shorts Fund to challenge TikTok goes live&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/youtubes-100-million-shorts-fund-to-challenge-tiktok-goes-live/embed/#?secret=9XmMyiMr5I" data-secret="9XmMyiMr5I" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Dating</h3>
<p><strong>Match Group announced during its Q2 <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/match-sales-grow-faster-than-expected-as-u-s-dating-scene-recovers-but-earnings-miss-hits-stock-11628021471">earnings</a> it plans to add to several of the company’s brands over the next 12 to 24 months <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/">audio and video chat</a>, including group live video, and other livestreaming technologies.</strong> The developments will be powered by innovations from Hyperconnect, the social networking company that this year became Match’s biggest acquisition to date when it bought the Korean app maker for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/match-hyperconnect-acquisition/">a sizable $1.73 billion.</a> Since then, Match was spotted testing group live video on Tinder, but says that particular product is not launching in the near-term. At least two brands will see Hyperconnect-powered integrations in 2021.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eY5Vq9qgHv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/">Match Group to add audio and video chat, including group live video, to its dating app portfolio</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Match Group to add audio and video chat, including group live video, to its dating app portfolio&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/match-group-to-add-live-audio-and-video-to-its-dating-app-portfolio-starting-in-2021/embed/#?secret=eY5Vq9qgHv" data-secret="eY5Vq9qgHv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Photos</h3>
<p><strong>The Photo &amp; Video category on U.S. app stores saw strong growth in the first half of the year, <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/state-of-photo-video-apps-report-2021">a Sensor Tower report</a> found.</strong> Consumer spend among the top 100 apps grew 34% YoY to $457 million in Q2 2021, with the majority of the revenue (83%) taking place on iOS.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2186809" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2186809" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2186809" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg 2304w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/photo-video-app-spending-growth-q2-2021.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2186809" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<h3>Gaming</h3>
<p><strong>Epic Games <a href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/fortnite-ariana-grande-rift-tour-concert-start-time-schedule-how-to-watch">revealed</a> the host of its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/fortnite-ariana-grande-rift-tour/">in-app Rift Tour event</a> is Ariana Grande, in the event that runs August 6-8.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Pokémon GO influencers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures">threatened to boycott the game</a> after Niantic removed the COVID safety measures</strong> that had allowed people to more easily play while social distancing. Niantic&#8217;s move seemed ill-timed, given the Delta variant is causing a new wave of COVID cases globally.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iDLK7L5ZjW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/">Pokémon GO influencers threaten a boycott after Niantic removes COVID safety measures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pokémon GO influencers threaten a boycott after Niantic removes COVID safety measures&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/pokemon-go-influencers-threaten-a-boycott-after-niantic-removes-covid-safety-measures/embed/#?secret=iDLK7L5ZjW" data-secret="iDLK7L5ZjW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Health &amp; Fitness</h3>
<p><strong>Apple <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/apple-removes-anti-vaxx-covid-dating-app-unjected-app-store-2021-8">kicked out an app called Unjected</a> from the App Store.</strong> The new social app <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-31/anti-vax-app-squares-off-with-google-apple-over-misinformation?sref=gni836kR">billed itself as a community</a> for the unvaccinated, allowing like-minded users to connect for dating and friendships. Apple said the app violated its policies for COVID-19 content.</p>
<p><strong>Google Pay <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/08/05/google-pay-now-lets-aussies-save-vaccination-cards-on-their-phones/">expanded support</a> for vaccine cards.</strong> In Australia, Google&#8217;s payments app now allows users to add their COVID-19 digital certification to their device for easy access. The option is available through Google&#8217;s newly updated Passes API which lets government agencies distribute digital versions of vaccine cards.</p>
<p><strong>COVID Tech Connect, a U.S. nonprofit initially dedicated to collecting devices like phones and tablets for COVID ICU patients, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/as-the-delta-variant-surges-a-non-profit-app-lets-hospital-patients-call-home-for-free-on-any-device/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">has now launched its own app</a>.</strong> The app, TeleHome, is a device-agnostic, HIPAA-compliant way for patients to place a video call for free at a time when the Delta variant is again filling ICU wards, this time with the unvaccinated &#8212; a condition that sometimes <a href="https://www.axios.com/covid-vaccines-low-income-poor-workers-58698275-0451-4158-a967-37189dbf673c.html">overlaps with being low-income</a>. Some among the working poor have been hesitant to get the shot because they can&#8217;t miss a day of work, and are worried about side effects. Which is why <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/21/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-call-on-all-employers-to-provide-paid-time-off-for-employees-to-get-vaccinated-after-meeting-goal-of-200-million-shots-in-the-first-100-days/">the Biden administration offered a tax credit to SMBs</a> who offered paid time off to staff to get vaccinated and recover.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uVEnGQ0G8w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/as-the-delta-variant-surges-a-non-profit-app-lets-hospital-patients-call-home-for-free-on-any-device/">As the delta variant surges, a nonprofit app lets hospital patients call home for free on any device </a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As the delta variant surges, a nonprofit app lets hospital patients call home for free on any device &#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/as-the-delta-variant-surges-a-non-profit-app-lets-hospital-patients-call-home-for-free-on-any-device/embed/#?secret=uVEnGQ0G8w" data-secret="uVEnGQ0G8w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Popular journaling app Day One, which was recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/wordpress-com-owner-automattic-acquires-journaling-app-day-one/">acquired</a> by WordPress.com owner Automattic, rolled out a <a href="https://dayoneapp.com/blog/concealed-journals">new &#8220;Concealed Journals&#8221; feature</a> </strong>that lets users hide content from others&#8217; viewing. By tapping the eye icon, the content can be easily concealed on a journal by journal basis, which can be useful for those who write to their journal in public, like coffee shops or public transportation.</p>
<h3>Edtech</h3>
<p><strong>Recently IPO&#8217;d language learning app Duolingo is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/duolingo-is-working-on-a-math-app-for-kids/">developing a math app for kids</a></strong>. The company says it&#8217;s still &#8220;very early&#8221; in the development process, but will announce more details at its annual conference, Duocon, later this month.</p>
<p><strong>Educational publisher Pearson <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/54fd50fe-f15f-47c0-965d-797573c5ec9c">launched an app</a> that offers U.S. students access to its 1,500 titles for a monthly subscription of $14.99.</strong> the Pearson+ mobile app (ack, another +), also offers the option of paying $9.99 per month for access to a single textbook for a minimum of four months.</p>
<h3>News &amp; Reading</h3>
<p><strong>Quora<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/creators-can-now-monetize-their-expertise-on-quora/"> jumps into the subscription economy</a>.</strong> Still not profitable from ads alone, Quora announced two new products that allow its expert creators to monetize their content on its service. With Quora+ ($5/mo or $50/yr), subscribers can pay for any content that a creator paywalls. Creators can choose to enable a adaptive paywall that will use an algorithm to determine when to show the paywall. Another product, Spaces, lets creators write paywalled publications on Quora, similar to Substack. But only a 5% cut goes to Quora, instead of 10% on Substack.</p>
<h3>Utilities</h3>
<p><strong>Google Maps on iOS <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/google-maps-on-ios-adds-live-location-sharing-in-imessage-home-screen-widget-and-dark-mode/">added a new live location-sharing feature</a> for iMessage users,</strong> allowing them to more easily show your ETA with friends and even how much battery life you have left. The feature competes with iMessage&#8217;s built-in location-sharing feature, and offers location sharing of 1 hour up to 3 days. The app also gained a dark mode.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4TwMkcbuEL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/google-maps-on-ios-adds-live-location-sharing-in-imessage-home-screen-widget-and-dark-mode/">Google Maps on iOS adds live location sharing in iMessage, home screen widget, dark mode</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google Maps on iOS adds live location sharing in iMessage, home screen widget, dark mode&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/google-maps-on-ios-adds-live-location-sharing-in-imessage-home-screen-widget-and-dark-mode/embed/#?secret=4TwMkcbuEL" data-secret="4TwMkcbuEL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Security &amp; Privacy</h3>
<p><strong>Controversial crime app Citizen <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/controversial-crime-app-citizen-launches-20-month-protect-service/">launched</a> a $20 per month &#8220;Protect&#8221; service that includes live agent support (who can refer calls to 911 if need be).</strong> The agents can gather your precise location, alert your designated emergency contacts, help you navigate to a safe location and monitor the situation until you feel safe. The system of live agent support is similar to in-car or in-home security and safety systems, like those from ADT or OnStar, but works with users out in the real world. The controversial part, however, is the company behind the product: Citizen has been making headlines for launching <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/v7evbx/citizen-app-private-security-leaked-emails">private security fleets</a> outside law enforcement, and recently <a href="https://twitter.com/cerisecastle/status/1393797781056225280">offered a reward</a> in a manhunt for an innocent person based on unsubstantiated tips.</p>
<h1>Funding and M&amp;A</h1>
<p><b><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Square <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/">announced</a> its acquisition of the &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; giant AfterPay in a $29 billion deal </b>that values the Australian firm at more than 30% higher than the stock&#8217;s last closing price of AUS$96.66. AfterPay has served over 16 million customers and nearly 100,000 merchants globally, to date, and comes at a time when the BNPL space is heating up. Apple has also gotten into the market recently with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-03/apple-affirm-to-join-on-buy-now-pay-later-for-canada-purchases?sref=gni836kR">an Affirm partnership</a> in Canada.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BIgcavogPR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/">Why Square is shelling out $29B to snag BNPL player Afterpay</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Square is shelling out $29B to snag BNPL player Afterpay&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/embed/#?secret=BIgcavogPR" data-secret="BIgcavogPR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Gaming giant Zynga <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/08/05/zynga-acquires-starlark-studio-and-golf-rival-game-for-525m/">acquired</a> Chinese game developer StarLark, the team behind the mobile golf game Golf Rival, from Betta Games for $525 million</strong> in both cash and stock. Golf Rival is the second-largest mobile golf game behind Playdemic&#8217;s Golf Clash, and EA is in the process of buying that studio for $1.4 billion.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />  U.K.-based Humanity <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/humanity-launches-slow-your-aging-app-in-the-uk-and-raises-5m-more-from-heath-investors/">raised an additional $2.5 million</a> for its app that claims to help slow down aging</strong>, bringing the total raise to date to $5 million. Backers include Calm&#8217;s co-founders, MyFitness Pal&#8217;s co-founder and others in the health space. The app works by benchmarking health advice against real-world data, to help users put better health practices into action.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> YELA, a Cameo-like app for the Middle East and South Asia, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/yela-secures-2m-to-reproduce-cameos-celebrity-success-with-an-app-for-the-middle-east/">raised</a> $2 million</strong> led by U.S. investors that include Tinder co-founder Justin Mateen and Sean Rad, general partner of RAD Fund. The app is focusing on signing celebrities in the regions it serves, where smartphone penetration is high and over 6% of the population is under 35.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> London-based health and wellness app maker Palta <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/health-and-wellness-apps-maker-palta-raises-100m-series-b-led-by-vnv-global/">raised a $100 million</a></strong> Series B led by VNV Global. The company&#8217;s products include Flo.Health, Simple Fasting, Zing Fitness Coach and others, which reach a combined 2.4 million active, paid subscribers. The funds will be used to create more mobile subscription products.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Emoji database and Wikipedia-like site Emojipedia <a href="https://blog.emojipedia.org/emojipedia-joins-zedge/">was acquired by</a> Zedge</strong>, the makers of a phone personalization app offering wallpapers, ringtones and more to 35 million MAUs. Deal terms weren&#8217;t disclosed. Emojipedia says the deal provides it with more stability and the opportunity for future growth. For Zedge, the deal provides<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f928.png" alt="🤨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />&#8230;.um, a popular web resource it thinks it can better monetize, we suspect.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Mental health app Revery <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/revery-gets-2m-to-improve-mental-health-with-mobile-gaming-techniques/">raised $2 million</a></strong> led by Sequoia Capital India’s Surge program for its app that combines cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia with mobile gaming concepts. The company will focus on other mental health issues in the future.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> London-based Nigerian-operating fintech startup Kuda <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/kuda-the-african-challenger-bank-raises-55m-at-a-500m-valuation/">raised a $55 million</a></strong> Series B, valuing its mobile-first challenger bank at $500 million. The inside round was co-led by Valar Ventures and Target Global.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Vietnamese payments provider VNLife <a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Startups/Vietnam-s-fintech-VNLife-says-valuation-now-well-over-1bn">raised $250 million</a> </strong>in a round led by U.S.-based General Atlantic and Dragoneer Investment Group. PayPal Ventures and others also participated. The round values the business at over $1 billion.</p>
<h1>Downloads</h1>
<h3>Mastodon for iPhone</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2186912" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="346" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png 2034w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png?resize=300,153 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png?resize=768,391 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png?resize=680,346 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png?resize=1536,782 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-08-06-at-2.23.35-PM.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Fans of decentralized social media efforts <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/30/22602275/mastodon-decentralized-social-network-official-ios-app-launches">now have a new app</a>. The nonprofit behind the open source decentralized social network Mastodon released an <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/mastodon-for-iphone/id1571998974">official iPhone app</a>, aimed at making the network more accessible to newcomers. The app allows you to find and follow people and topics; post text, images, GIFs, polls, and videos; and get notified of new replies and reblogs, much like Twitter.</p>
<p><strong>Xingtu</strong></p>
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" style="max-width: 605px; min-width: 325px;" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@_666eve/video/6992923897586846981" data-video-id="6992923897586846981">
<section><a title="@_666eve" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@_666eve" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@_666eve</a>ITS SO COOL FRFR do u guys want a tutorial? <a title="fypシ" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp%E3%82%B7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#fypシ</a> <a title="醒图" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/%E9%86%92%E5%9B%BE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#醒图</a> <a title="醒图app" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/%E9%86%92%E5%9B%BEapp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#醒图app</a><a title="♬ original sound - Ian Asher" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6988668796454210309" target="_blank" rel="noopener">♬ original sound &#8211; Ian Asher</a></section>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"></script></p>
<p>TikTok users are teaching each other how to switch over to the Chinese App Store in order <a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMdwsFTQo/">to get ahold of the Xingtu app</a> for iOS. (An Android <a href="https://modgameapk.net/xingtu-%E9%86%92-%E5%9B%BE-apk/">version</a> is also available.) The app offers advanced editing tools that let users edit their face and body, like FaceTune, apply makeup, add filters and more. While image-editing apps can be controversial for how they can impact body acceptance, Xingtu offers a variety of artistic filters which is what&#8217;s primarily driving the demand. It&#8217;s interesting to see the lengths people will go to just to get a few new filters for their photos &#8212; perhaps making a case for Instagram to finally update its Post filters instead of pretending no one cares about their static photos anymore.</p>
<h1>Tweets</h1>
<p><em>Facebook still dominating top charts, but not the No. 1 spot:  </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The most downloaded app worldwide for July 2021 was <a href="https://twitter.com/tiktok_us?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@tiktok_us</a> with more than 63M installs. <a href="https://twitter.com/Facebook?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Facebook</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/instagram?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@instagram</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/messenger?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@messenger</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WhatsApp</a> rounded out the top 5: <a href="https://t.co/H9RMR5Pg9P">https://t.co/H9RMR5Pg9P</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/tiktok?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#tiktok</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/topapps?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#topapps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mobileapps?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#mobileapps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mobilegrowth?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#mobilegrowth</a> <a href="https://t.co/srlDI07FeD">pic.twitter.com/srlDI07FeD</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Sensor Tower (@SensorTower) <a href="https://twitter.com/SensorTower/status/1423380936830472200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><em>Not cool, Apple: </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Apple promoting these slime apps again.</p>
<p>A few of them have $10+ weekly subscriptions.</p>
<p>One of them doesn’t even do anything.<a href="https://t.co/d0dKLCkiVF">https://t.co/d0dKLCkiVF</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Beau Nouvelle (@BeauNouvelle) <a href="https://twitter.com/BeauNouvelle/status/1422941988349825027?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><em>This user acquisition strategy: </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Great feedback, wanna use/test <a href="https://twitter.com/FlightyApp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FlightyApp</a>? Looks like you fly some based on your profile, and good feedback is my lifeblood.</p>
<p>&mdash; Ryan Jones (@rjonesy) <a href="https://twitter.com/rjonesy/status/1423014128952791040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><em>Maybe Stories don&#8217;t work everywhere: </em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">if you see a Fleet no you didn&#39;t <a href="https://t.co/4rKI7f45PL">https://t.co/4rKI7f45PL</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Twitter (@Twitter) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitter/status/1422609438557491205?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1952542" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="93" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=768,105 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=680,93 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=1536,210 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/07/this-week-in-apps-in-app-events-hit-the-app-store-tiktok-tries-stories-apple-reveals-new-child-safety-plan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2186642</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Building vulnerability into your workflow</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/07/building-vulnerability-into-your-workflow/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/07/building-vulnerability-into-your-workflow/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 18:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I spoke to my editor this week about the usual: upcoming stories, the future of the podcast and the existential dread of imposter syndrome amid a year-and-a-half of extreme change. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><i data-stringify-type="italic">Thanks for reading Startups Weekly. Want the weekly digest in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">here</a>. </i></p>
<p>I spoke to <a href="https://twitter.com/Pickavet">my editor</a> this week about the usual: upcoming stories, the future of the podcast and the existential dread of imposter syndrome amid a year-and-a-half of extreme change. The last bit took up the majority of the conversation. Go figure!</p>
<p>Our conversation was helpful because it put words to stresses that often sit in between the lines and gave weight to small things that get hidden during a pandemic-sized year. Don’t worry, I won’t bore you with my thought loops, but I will extract a few lessons that I think are broadly applicable to Startups Weekly readers, because based on your clicks, I know you’re into tips (and earnest ones, at that):</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Give yourself grace.</strong> The pandemic has been confusing, imbalanced and brought a lot of loss to a lot of people. If you feel like you’re operating at anything less than 100% right now, remember that you are operating during a time when the world feels like it’s depending on a frayed lightbulb for guidance. Before you are hard on yourself for not being productive, think about where your productivity standards are coming from, and if they are even fair in the first place.</li>
<li><strong>Your problems are not unique.</strong> While we all are diverse, nuanced individuals, we aren’t alone in a lot of what makes us human. Everyone overthinks, everyone soul searches, everyone has personal and professional insecurities that bubble up in non-obvious ways. By believing that your problems are not entirely unique, I think you’ll find yourself feeling more in control of turbulence. Which brings me to my next point …</li>
<li><strong>Vulnerability is everything. </strong>Vulnerability was front and center in the first inning of the pandemic, where we were all brought into each other&#8217;s living rooms and home offices and backyards through Zoom. That vibe has somewhat faded as we’ve adapted more and more to distributed work, but it doesn’t mean we can’t try to find ways to be more vulnerable with each other. Let yourself have a voice, even in moments where it’s easier to stay quiet, because you will feel closer at the end of it.</li>
</ol>
<p>Take what you will from the above advice (or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/10-ways-founders-can-manage-their-mental-health-while-fundraising/">see these tips</a> from a fellow entrepreneur), but I think it all boils down to a belief that we should be humans first, and <em>insert job role here</em> second. It’s truly (still) an unprecedented time in this world, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/ending-the-mental-health-stigma-in-the-tech-community/">ending mental health stigma</a> in general is a worthwhile goal.</p>
<p>The rest of this newsletter is about a cyberattack on a VC firm, AfterSquare, and an EC-1 about 911. Before we get on with it, we’re excited to announce that TechCrunch is launching another newsletter! This Week in Apps by the inimitable Sarah Perez launches this Saturday morning, August 7. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">Sign up here</a> to be in the know about all the apps. As always, you can find me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">@nmasc_. </a></p>
<h2>Cybercriminals target VC firm</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2073743" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2073743" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2073743" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="623" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg 5400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg?resize=768,467 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg?resize=680,414 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg?resize=1536,935 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg?resize=2048,1247 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/cyber_attack_grenade_on_yellow_background-1.jpeg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2073743" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Advanced Technology Ventures, a Silicon Valley venture capital firm with $1.8 billion in assets, was hit by a ransomware attack. Cybercriminals <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/atv-venture-capital-ransomware/">stole personal information on some 300 of ATV’s limited partners</a>, also known as the people who have put millions of millions into its fund, according to <a href="https://twitter.com/zackwhittaker/status/1422615456167366663">a scoop by Zack Whittaker. </a></p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>This particular attack stole key information on a hush-hush part of how venture money works. VC firms often do not disclose all of their LPs due to competitive advantage and secrecy. The firm may not want competitors to know who is backing them, while a limited partner may not want others to know where their money is going. As ransomware groups “continue to go big-game hunting,” per Whittaker, LP lists are a part of that — and other VC firms should take note.</p>
<p><em>The money behind the money:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/08/27/why-founders-should-care-where-their-vcs-get-their-money/">Why founders should care where their VCs get their money</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/venture-capital-lps-are-the-missing-link-to-solving-silicon-valleys-diversity-problem/">Venture capital LPs are the missing link to solving Silicon Valley’s diversity problem</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/05/two-new-efforts-push-to-transform-more-people-into-limited-partners-of-vc-funds/">Two new efforts could widen the pool of people investing directly in venture funds</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>After Square pays</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1753376" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1753376" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1753376" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png" alt="" width="1024" height="544" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png 3200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=768,408 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=680,361 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=1536,816 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=2048,1088 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/in-app-purchase.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1753376" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Bryce Durbin/TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>Fintech lit up this week after Square <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/">bought ‘buy now, pay later’ giant Afterpay for $29 billion</a>. The deal, which is expected to go through next year, will see Afterpay integrate its services into Square’s Seller and Cash Pay ecosystems. <a href="https://twitter.com/bayareawriter">Mary Ann Azevedo reported the news</a> amid the sector’s heat up, and Alex Wilhelm shared <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/02/why-square-is-shelling-out-29b-to-snag-bnpl-player-afterpay/?tpcc=ECTW2020">why he thinks Square landed on that magic number. </a></p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know:</strong> Everyone is building their own in-house BNPL service, from Shopify (!), to PayPal to, reportedly, Apple. So, while the &#8220;Shopify should buy Affirm&#8221; theories were aplenty, reporter Ryan Lawler gave more context<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/what-squares-acquisition-of-afterpay-means-for-startups/"> on what this deal means for startups.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.baincapitalventures.com/team/matth/">Matthew Harris</a> of Bain Capital Ventures told TechCrunch that, as the BNPL space fills up, he doesn’t see “a lot of headroom/new angles in the consumer BNPL space … scale matters and it will be hard for new entrants to achieve escape velocity.”</p>
<p>Instead, he thinks there is opportunity for BNPL models to break into the B2B space, where companies can “replace/enhance traditional invoice financing and trade credit.”</p>
<p><em>Friends of fintech:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/neobanks-moves-toward-profitability-could-be-the-path-to-public-markets/">Neobanks’ moves toward profitability could be the path to public markets</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/robinhood-is-now-a-stonk/">Robinhood is now a stonk</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/avoid-these-common-financial-mistakes-so-your-startup-doesnt-die-on-the-vine/">Avoid these common financial mistakes so your startup doesn’t die on the vine</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>The 411 on 911</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2182305" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2182305" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2182305" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="686" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg?resize=768,515 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg?resize=680,456 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg?resize=1536,1029 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg?resize=2048,1372 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5197223192-NSussman_Techcrunch_RapidSOS-FINAL_q2-L.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2182305" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nigel Sussman</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch Managing Editor Danny Crichton dove into the heart of 911 and emergency response in our latest EC-1 on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/rapidsos-ec1/">RapidSOS.</a> The company, which has raised more than $190 million, has built an emergency response data platform that helps first responders access a firehose of data in high-intensity situations. It processes more than 150 million emergencies every year, and per Crichton, it’s almost certainly integrated into your smartphone right now.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know:</strong> From the smoking-pizza-oven early years to its pivot without product design, RapidSOS’ story shows how much you can get done in a decade of stagnation from Capitol Hill.</p>
<p><em>The four-part series:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Part 1: Origin story “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/rapidsos-ec1-origin/">Smoking pizza ovens and pilfered dollar bills, or the early story of RapidSOS</a>” (2,700 words/11 minutes)</li>
<li>Part 2: Product and business “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/rapidsos-ec1-business/">RapidSOS learned that the best product design is sometimes no product design</a>” (3,700 words/15 minutes)</li>
<li>Part 3: Partnerships “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/rapidsos-ec1-partnerships/">How RapidSOS used creative tactics to build partnerships and a BD engine at scale</a>” (4,000 words/16 minutes)</li>
<li>Part 4: Next-generation 911 “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/rapidsos-ec1-future/">After a decade, Congress might finally bring 911 into the internet age”</a> (2,000 words/8 minutes)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Around TC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/ryanlawler">Ryan Lawler</a> has returned to TechCrunch! He&#8217;s working with the ExtraCrunch team to bring you some deeper analysis of what&#8217;s happening in the fintech world. He&#8217;s particularly interested in the B2B side of fintech, including everything from startups building infrastructure and developer tools for companies deploying their own financial services to corporate cards, startup banking and spend management services TechCrunch readers are likely to use. If you work at a relevant company in the space, have invested in one of those companies, or are a customer or partner of one of those companies, he&#8217;d love to get your perspective on what&#8217;s interesting and what&#8217;s happening. You can email him at <a href="mailto:ryanlawler.techcrunch@gmail.com">ryanlawler.techcrunch@gmail.com</a>.</li>
<li>I haven’t given you a discount code in a while, so use code<em> EQUITY</em> for a good deal on your Extra Crunch subscription.</li>
<li><a href="https://t.co/gWY2tEKTJC?amp=1">The Disrupt Agenda is alive and breathing</a>, so check out who is joining our virtual stage in September and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/?promo=disruptagendapost&amp;display=true">buy your tickets. </a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<h3>Seen on TechCrunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/venture-capital-probably-isnt-dead/">Venture capital probably isn’t dead</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/06/the-first-zambian-startup-to-get-into-yc-is-developing-africas-first-card-issuing-api/">The first Zambian startup to get into YC is developing Africa’s first card-issuing API</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/as-edtech-evolves-latam-reskilling-platforms-raise-millions-to-bring-outcomes-into-the-mix/">As edtech evolves, LatAm reskilling platforms raise millions to bring outcomes into the mix</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/duolingo-is-working-on-a-math-app-for-kids/">Duolingo is working on a math app for kids</a></li>
</ul>
<h3>Seen on Extra Crunch</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/founders-must-learn-how-to-build-and-maintain-circles-of-trust-with-investors/">Founders must learn how to build and maintain circles of trust with investors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/30/kodiak-robotics-founder-says-tight-focus-on-autonomous-trucks-is-working/">Kodiak Robotics’ founder says tight focus on autonomous trucks is working</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/greylocks-mike-duboe-explains-how-to-define-growth-and-build-your-team/">Greylock’s Mike Duboe explains how to define growth and build your team</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Talk soon,</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/07/building-vulnerability-into-your-workflow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187063</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
