<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:21:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Faction raises $4.3M to deploy 3-wheeled EVs for driverless delivery</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/faction-raises-4-3m-to-deploy-3-wheeled-evs-for-driverless-delivery/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/faction-raises-4-3m-to-deploy-3-wheeled-evs-for-driverless-delivery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autonomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faction Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starsky robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Faction Technology founder and CEO Ain McKendrick didn&#8217;t have the $1 billion or the time that a typical automotive program might need to design and manufacture an EV that could be used for driverless delivery. So, he turned to power sports to fulfill his vision of a micro-logistics service that can be used for driverless [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Faction Technology founder and CEO Ain McKendrick didn&#8217;t have the $1 billion or the time that a typical automotive program might need to design and manufacture an EV that could be used for driverless delivery.</p>
<p>So, he turned to power sports to fulfill his vision of a micro-logistics service that can be used for driverless delivery or rented and operated by a human for jaunts around the city. Now, with prototypes built and an ambition to scale, McKendrick has raised $4.3 million in seed funding led by Trucks VC and Fifty Years.</p>
<p>&#8220;We keep doing the same things over and over again,&#8221; said McKendrick, who was previously vp of engineering at the now shuttered self-driving truck startup Starsky Robotics. &#8220;We keep taking legacy vehicles and trying to retrofit them for driverless technologies. Rather than do the same stuff over and over again, how about we do it a little bit differently?&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.factionmoto.com/">Faction</a>, which launched last year and graduated this winter from the Y Combinator accelerator program, started with a three-wheel motorcycle platform. While the company is building the chassis from the ground up, McKendrick says it can be accomplished at a fraction of the cost of manufacturing an automobile. The vehicle costs about $30,000 in all, which McKendrick said has a payback period of two years.</p>
<p>These are motorcycle class vehicles, which means they are legal for city streets and highways but don&#8217;t have some of the same requirements that passenger vehicles do.</p>
<p>The vehicles can deliver cargo, which is accomplished through a combination of autonomy and a remote worker using teleoperations to assist. Faction, which is about a 10-person team, is working with other companies for the autonomous vehicle stack. However, it has developed a core platform with safety features that will step in if the autonomous system fails.</p>
<p>&#8220;The core technology that we&#8217;re building for these vehicles is actually something we aspire to bring to other vehicle formats, as the company grows over time,&#8221; he said, adding that they have developed a digital vehicle architecture and a teleoperation system, which work together.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2160183" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2160183" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2160183 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Faction_T1_Delivery.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2160183" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Faction Technology</p></div></p>
<p>Delivery, or micro-logistics as McKendrick calls it, is the first focus of the company. However, the founder also sees an opportunity to build out fleets of its 3-wheeled vehicles and rent them out to people who want to use them for three- to five-mile trips around cities, or even longer distance from a city to a nearby suburb. These vehicles would be nearly the same with a few key differences like a glass canopy for the human operator versions. The delivery vehicles would have an opaque canopy.</p>
<p>McKendrick envisions users being able to hail one of its vehicles through an app. The vehicle would then drive itself to the user. Once they step inside, it would be manually operated by the human driver.</p>
<p>McKendrick&#8217;s pitch is that users get all the convenience of a scooter or bike share, but have weather protection and highway capability.</p>
<p>&#8220;So if you need to run from say, San Francisco down to San Francisco Airport, this is the perfect format of vehicle to do it for you, as opposed to trying to do more four-door sedans and larger format vehicles.&#8221;</p>
<p>Under the driverless delivery applications, the user would be charged on a per-mile basis. McKendrick said they may charge by the hour for the vehicle rentals.</p>
<p>The company is working now to form partnerships with manufacturers of light electric vehicles to scale operational fleets and plans to announce the first customer trials later this year. McKendrick said the goal is to deploy a small fleet of about 50 vehicles for the micro-logistics pilot and start some early rider trials by the fourth quarter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/faction-raises-4-3m-to-deploy-3-wheeled-evs-for-driverless-delivery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159696</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joby Aviation targets parking garages for its aerial ridesharing network</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/joby-aviation-targets-parking-garages-for-its-aerial-ridesharing-network/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/joby-aviation-targets-parking-garages-for-its-aerial-ridesharing-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric aircraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joby Aviation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[REEF Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban air mobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joby Aviation is partnering with one of the country’s largest parking garage operators and a real estate acquisition company to build out its network of vertiports, with an initial focus on Los Angeles, Miami, New York and the San Francisco Bay Area, the company said Wednesday. The partnership with REFF Technology and Neighborhood Property Group [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Joby Aviation is partnering with one of the country’s largest parking garage operators and a real estate acquisition company to build out its network of vertiports, with an initial focus on Los Angeles, Miami, New York and the San Francisco Bay Area, the company said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The partnership with REFF Technology and Neighborhood Property Group will give Joby “access to an unparalleled range of rooftop locations across all key metropolitan areas in the US, as well as a mechanism to fund the acquisition and development of new skyport sites,” Joby said in a statement.</p>
<p>Building out a convenient, accessible and large network of locations to hitch a ride on an air taxi will likely be a key factor determining which companies succeed in attracting would-be riders to their service. The current infrastructure to support helicopters is limited, especially in urban areas, where electric vertical take-off and landing (eVTOL) companies intend to launch.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The deal will give Joby exclusive access to the sites for a period, during which it said it can secure long-term leases within REEF’s real estate network.</p>
<p>Until now little has been known about the electric aircraft giant’s intentions regarding its aerial ridesharing network, although founder and CEO JoeBen Bevirt has publicly talked about the benefits of using existing parking garages.</p>
<p>Such structures are typically in dense areas, they’re large, and they’re built out of robust material that can support multiple small aircraft. But perhaps most importantly, parking garages already house cars, another form of transportation that will likely work hand-in-hand with air taxis in serving first- and last-mile segments of a journey.</p>
<p>REEF, which began as parking lot management and servicing company ParkJockey, now operates around 4,500 mobility and logistics hubs that it says reaches 70% of the North American urban population. REEF <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/reef-technology-raises-1-billion-from-softbank-and-others-to-remake-parking-lots/">raised $700 million</a> from SoftBank, the Mubadala Corp. and others last November.</p>
<p>In addition to the new partnership, Joby said its vertiport network will use existing heliport and regional airport locations.</p>
<p>“This is a landmark deal on Joby’s path to building a transformational ridesharing service in our skies,” Bevirt said in a statement. “NPG and REEF have an unbeatable network of sites across the US and we’re excited to be working with them to identify sites that will become the backbone of our future service.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/joby-aviation-targets-parking-garages-for-its-aerial-ridesharing-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160168</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Expensify hacked its way to a robust, scalable tech stack</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/expensify-ec1-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/expensify-ec1-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bedrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate expense management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Barrett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expense management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expense reporting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expense reports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expensify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expensify EC-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[React Native]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relational database]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Take a close look at any ambitious startup and you'll find pugnacity nestled in its core. Stubbornness and a bullheaded belief in the worth of what a company wants to bring to fruition is often the biggest driver of its success.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Take a close look at any ambitious startup and you&#8217;ll find pugnacity nestled in its core. Stubbornness and a bullheaded belief in the worth of what a company wants to bring to fruition is often the biggest driver of its success, and the people at such companies also tend to share this quality.</p>
<p>So it wouldn&#8217;t be too far off the mark to say the people at Expensify are a stubborn lot — to the company&#8217;s ultimate benefit. This <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/expensify-ec1-origin/">group of P2P pirates/hackers</a> that set out to build an expense management app stuck to their gut, made their own rules. They asked questions few thought of, like: Why have lots of employees when you can find a way to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/expensify-ec1-culture/">get work done and reach impressive profitability with a few</a>? Why work from an office in San Francisco when the internet lets you work from anywhere, even <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/expensify-ec1-expansion/">a sailboat in the Caribbean?</a></p>
<p>It makes sense in a way: If you&#8217;re a pirate, to hell with the rules, right? And even more so when nobody can explain the rules in the first place.</p>
<p>With that in mind, one could assume Expensify decided to ask itself: Why not build our own totally custom tech stack? Indeed, Expensify has made several tech decisions that were met with disbelief — from having an open-source frontend and cross-platform mobile development to hiring contractors to train its AI and recruiting open-source contributors — but its belief in its own choices has paid off over the years, and the company is <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210503005265/en">ready to IPO</a> any day now.</p>
<p>How much of a tech advantage Expensify enjoys owing to such choices is an open question, but one thing is clear: These choices are key to understanding Expensify and its roadmap. Let&#8217;s take a look.</p>
<h2>Built on Bedrock</h2>
<p>I think another question Expensify also decided to ask in its early days was something like: Why not have our database on top of a technology that&#8217;s built for small-scale application software?</p>
<p>It may sound incredible, but Expensify actually runs on a custom database built on top of SQLite. This is surprising, because despite being one of the <a href="https://sqlite.org/mostdeployed.html">most widely deployed database engines</a>, SQLite is known for running on small, embedded systems like smartphones and web browsers, not powering enterprise-scale databases.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			It may sound incredible, but Expensify actually runs on a custom database built on top of SQLite.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>This custom database is called <a href="https://bedrockdb.com/">Bedrock</a>, and its architecture is as unique as they come. <a href="https://finovate.com/videos/findevr-silicon-valley-2016-expensify/">Expensify</a> explains it as an &#8220;RDBMS optimized for self-healing replication across relatively slow, relatively unreliable WAN (internet) connections, enabling extremely high availability/high performance multi-datacenter deployments without any single point of failure.&#8221; RDBMS means relational database management system, describing SQLite and other row-based databases where entries are interconnected with each other.</p>
<p>But why would Expensify build this instead of going for any number of widely available enterprise database solutions?</p>
<p>To answer that question, we need to go back to the early days of the company, which was originally a side project for its founder and CEO, David Barrett. His initial idea was to develop a prepaid card for the homeless, but this required putting a server on the Visa network, which brought several strict requirements and challenges. &#8220;I would say one of the most difficult [parts] was that I needed the ability to automatically replicate and failover,&#8221; Barrett told TechCrunch when we interviewed him a couple of months ago.</p>
<p>This was no easy feat in 2007, but Barrett was up for the challenge. &#8220;I just hit a moment where the technology available off the shelf just wasn&#8217;t that good. And I happened to be a peer-to-peer software developer who had tons of spare time and really wanted to build this thing to put on the Visa backend,&#8221; he said. The P2P aspect was important, as Barrett had the skills to make it work. His first hires for Expensify, P2P engineers he had worked with at Red Swoosh and Akamai, were also unusually suited for the job.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/expensify-ec1-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159252</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>JOKR launches in New York with a different take on on-demand delivery</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/jokr-launches-in-new-york-with-a-different-take-on-on-demand-delivery/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/jokr-launches-in-new-york-with-a-different-take-on-on-demand-delivery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For years now, the world of retail has been evolving. Whether it&#8217;s next-day delivery with Amazon Prime or subscription D2C services or on-demand delivery from Postmates, we&#8217;re growing increasingly accustomed to being able to buy something and have it arrive at our door relatively quickly. Today, a new startup is launching in New York with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">For years now, the world of retail has been evolving. Whether it&#8217;s next-day delivery with Amazon Prime or subscription D2C services or on-demand delivery from Postmates, we&#8217;re growing increasingly accustomed to being able to buy something and have it arrive at our door relatively quickly.</p>
<p>Today, a new startup is launching in New York with a fresh take on on-demand delivery.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.jokr.it/">JOKR</a>, founded by Ralf Wenzel (the same guy who founded FoodPanda, which later merged with DeliveryHero) promises delivery in 15 minutes or less, with no order minimums, and a selection of products that you might find in the local deli or convenience store.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The approach is centered around what JOKR calls micro-hubs, which are really just various storefronts on side streets in denser areas. The company uses data to forecast what customers will want, when, and where, to strategically organize these micro-fulfillment centers for speed.</p>
<p>For end users, there are no order minimums and no delivery fees.</p>
<p>data is the key ingredient of how we build the business to identify what customers need and put an emphasis of also on only what they need, but also when they need it. And what point of time, which day, which week which month, whether it&#8217;s in the morning or in the evening, and built a dynamic inventory and catalog management system is able to rotate inventory, provide inventory and pre forecast in suggests for customers, those type of consumer goods, and the corresponding time and if you presented and forecast the time.</p>
<p>JOKR procures the goods sold on the app directly from brands, manufacturers and wholesalers. In other words, you can think of the service as a sort of ghost kitchen for groceries and every day items.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are a platform that is not relying on any type of consumer charges,&#8221; said Wenzel. &#8220;Hence, the business is predominantly a business that generates revenue out of the respective product costs. Our ability to procure directly, and cut out middlemen in terms of wholesalers, distributors, supermarkets themselves, allows us to tap into a margin pool that is higher than that of traditional online marketplaces, which would only pick a product from existing stores, supermarkets, and then need to apply a delivery fee in order to make their proposition work.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company is working to increase its inventory, which currently includes more than 1,500 items.</p>
<p>In terms of the workforce, JOKR delivery people are full time employees.</p>
<p>JOKR has been operating in Latin America (Brazil, Lima, and Mexico City) and is now expanding into the U.S. market with its NYC launch.</p>
<p>According to TheRealDeal, JOKR has funding from SoftBank, as well as HV Capital and Tiger Global. It&#8217;s unclear how much the startup has raised.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/jokr-launches-in-new-york-with-a-different-take-on-on-demand-delivery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160116</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stemma launches with $4.8M seed to build managed data catalogue</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/stemma-launches-with-4-8m-seed-to-build-managed-data-catalogue/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/stemma-launches-with-4-8m-seed-to-build-managed-data-catalogue/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amundsen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stemma]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As companies increasingly rely on data to run their businesses, having accurate sources of data becomes paramount. Stemma, a new early stage startup, has come up with a solution, a managed data catalogue that acts as an organization&#8217;s source of truth. Today the company announced a $4.8 million seed investment led by Sequoia with assorted [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As companies increasingly rely on data to run their businesses, having accurate sources of data becomes paramount. <a href="http://stemma.ai">Stemma</a>, a new early stage startup, has come up with a solution, a managed data catalogue that acts as an organization&#8217;s source of truth.</p>
<p>Today the company announced a $4.8 million seed investment led by Sequoia with assorted individual tech luminaries also participating. The product is also available for the first time today.</p>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Mark Grover says the product is actually built on top of the open source <a href="https://www.amundsen.io/">Amundsen</a> data catalogue project that he helped launch at Lyft to manage its massive data requirements. The problem was that with so much data, employees had to kludge together systems to confirm the data validity. Ultimately manual processes like asking someone in Slack or even creating a Wiki failed under the weight of trying to keep up with the volume and velocity.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I saw this problem first-hand at Lyft, which led me to create the open source Amundsen project with a team of talented engineers,&#8221; Grover said. That project has 750 users at Lyft using it every week. Since it was open sourced, 35 companies like Brex, Snap and Asana have been using it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hpPArB2IoI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/toro-snags-4m-seed-investment-to-monitor-data-quality/">Toro snags $4M seed investment to monitor data quality</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Toro snags $4M seed investment to monitor data quality&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/toro-snags-4m-seed-investment-to-monitor-data-quality/embed/#?secret=hpPArB2IoI" data-secret="hpPArB2IoI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>What Stemma offers is a managed version of Amundsen that adds additional functionality like using intelligence to show data that&#8217;s meaningful to the person who is searching in the catalogue. It also can add metadata automatically to data as it&#8217;s added to the catalogue, creating documentation about the data on the fly, among other features.</p>
<p>The company launched last fall when Grover and co-founder and CTO Dorian Johnson decided to join forces and create a commercial product on top of Amundsen. Grover points out that Lyft was supportive of the move.</p>
<p>Today the company has five employees, in addition to the founders and has plans to add several more this year. As he does that, he is cognizant of diversity and inclusion in the hiring process. &#8220;I think it&#8217;s super important that we continue to invest in diversity, and the two ways that I think are the most meaningful for us right now is to have early employees that are from diverse groups, and that is the case within the first five,&#8221; he said. Beyond that, he says that as the company grows he wants to improve the ratio, while also looking at diversity in investors, board members and executives.</p>
<p>The company, which launched during COVID is entirely remote right now and plans to remain that way for at least the short term. As the company grows, they will look at ways to build camaraderie like organizing a regular cadence of employee offsite events.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LSCKQaFOTL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/">How to ensure data quality in the era of Big Data</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to ensure data quality in the era of Big Data&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/how-to-ensure-quality-in-the-era-of-big-data/embed/#?secret=LSCKQaFOTL" data-secret="LSCKQaFOTL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/stemma-launches-with-4-8m-seed-to-build-managed-data-catalogue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160159</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reading the IPO market&#8217;s tea leaves</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/reading-the-ipo-markets-tea-leaves/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/reading-the-ipo-markets-tea-leaves/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marqeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeta Global]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today's dissection of the public offering market paints a generally positive picture of the IPO market for venture-backed companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Although it&#8217;s a truncated holiday week here in the United States, there&#8217;s been a bushel of IPO news. This morning, we&#8217;re going to sort through the updates and come up with a series of sentiment calls regarding these public offerings.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money.  </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Here&#8217;s what&#8217;s in our basket of news items this morning:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/inside-marqetas-fascinating-fintech-ipo/">Marqeta</a>&#8216;s first IPO price range (fintech)</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/29/1stdibs-the-high-end-online-marketplace-just-nabbed-76-million-series-d-financing/">1st Dibs</a>&#8216; first IPO price range (e-commerce)</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/zeta-globals-ipo-filing-uncovers-modest-growth-strong-adjusted-profitability/">Zeta Global</a>&#8216;s IPO pricing (martech)</li>
<li>The start of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/12/2021-a-spac-odyssey/">SoFi</a> trading post-SPAC (fintech)</li>
<li>The latest from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/07/22/tc-cribs-a-trip-to-barkbox-hq-where-dogs-rule/">BarkBox</a> (e-commerce)</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1995214" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-red.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>A brief note on why we care to do all this work:</p>
<p>We care because it&#8217;s worth knowing what current demand is for venture-backed shares on the public markets. The third quarter is expected by many in the private markets to be an active period for exits. So, for founders, investors, and a host of technology startup employees, we&#8217;re gearing up for a busy period.</p>
<p>And today&#8217;s IPO climate could be the on-ramp to that rush of unicorn liquidity. So let&#8217;s understand where we&#8217;re starting through the prism of debut updates en masse.</p>
<h2>Marqeta</h2>
<ul>
<li>First IPO price range: <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1522540/000119312521177861/d64065ds1a.htm">$20 to $24 per share</a></li>
<li>Max IPO raise: $1,254,545,448</li>
<li>Implied simple valuation range: $10.6 billion to $12.7 billion</li>
</ul>
<p>The last known private-market value of Marqeta was set in May 2020, when the company raised $150 million at what <a href="http://pitchbook.com">PitchBook</a> estimates was a $4.3 billion valuation. From that perspective, the company could up to triple its final private valuation in its public debut. There was some other money sloshing around the company since that May round, however, so its pricing could have shifted some in the intervening months.</p>
<p><strong>Our read is that even if Marqeta does not raise its IPO range, its pricing is bullish</strong>, and if it <em>does</em> raise its range, it could become even more so. At a flat $12 billion price, the company&#8217;s Q1 2021 run rate puts it on a 27.8x revenue multiple. That&#8217;s rich.</p>
<h2>1st Dibs</h2>
<ul>
<li>First IPO price range: <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1600641/000119312521179144/d244039ds1a.htm">$18 to $21 per share</a></li>
<li>Max IPO raise: $138,862,500<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/reading-the-ipo-markets-tea-leaves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160030</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Huawei officially launches Android alternative HarmonyOS for smartphones</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/huawei-officially-launches-android-alternative-harmonyos-for-smartphones/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/huawei-officially-launches-android-alternative-harmonyos-for-smartphones/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rita Liao]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluetooth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HarmonyOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meizu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Think you&#8217;re living in a hyper-connected world? Huawei&#8217;s proprietary HarmonyOS wants to eliminate delays and gaps in user experience when you move from one device onto another by adding interoperability to all devices, regardless of the system that powers them. Two years after Huawei was added to the U.S. entity list that banned the Chinese [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Think you&#8217;re living in a hyper-connected world? Huawei&#8217;s proprietary HarmonyOS wants to eliminate delays and gaps in user experience when you move from one device onto another by adding interoperability to all devices, regardless of the system that powers them.</p>
<p>Two years after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/why-startups-need-to-be-careful-about-export-licenses-and-the-huawei-ban/">Huawei was added to the U.S. entity list</a> that banned the Chinese telecom giant from accessing U.S. technologies, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/18/huawei-uncertainties-new-us-chip-rules-tsmc/">core chipsets</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/20/huawei-responds-android/">Android developer services from Google</a>, Huawei&#8217;s alternative smartphone operating system was unveiled.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Huawei officially launched its proprietary operating system HarmonyOS for mobile phones. The firm began building the operating system in 2016 and made it open-source for tablets, electric vehicles and smartwatches last September. Its flagship devices such as Mate 40 could upgrade to HarmonyOS starting Wednesday, with the operating system gradually rolling out on lower-end models in the coming quarters.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>HarmonyOS is not meant to replace Android or iOS, Huawei said. Rather, its application is more far-reaching, powering not just phones and tablets but an increasing number of smart devices. To that end, Huawei has been trying to attract hardware and home appliance manufacturers to join its ecosystem.</p>
<p>To date, more than 500,000 developers are building applications based on HarmonyOS. It&#8217;s unclear whether Google, Facebook and other mainstream apps in the West are working on HarmonyOS versions.</p>
<p>Some Chinese tech firms have answered Huawei&#8217;s call. Smartphone maker Meizu <a href="https://weibo.com/2683843043/KhxyFlAd3?from=page_1006062683843043_profile&amp;wvr=6&amp;mod=weibotime&amp;type=comment">hinted</a> on its Weibo account that its smart devices might adopt HarmonyOS. Oppo, Vivo and Xiaomi, who are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/apple-record-china-2021/">much larger players than Meizu</a>, are probably more reluctant to embrace a rival&#8217;s operating system.</p>
<p>Huawei&#8217;s goal is to collapse all HarmonyOS-powered devices into one single control panel, which can, say, remotely pair the Bluetooth connections of headphones and a TV. A game that is played on a phone can be continued seamlessly on a tablet. A smart soymilk blender can customize a drink based on the health data gleaned from a user&#8217;s smartwatch.</p>
<p>Devices that aren&#8217;t already on HarmonyOS can also communicate with Huawei devices with a simple plug-in. Photos from a Windows-powered laptop can be saved directly onto a Huawei phone if the computer has the HarmonyOS plug-in installed. That raises the question of whether Android, or even iOS, could, one day, talk to HarmonyOS through a common language.</p>
<p>The HarmonyOS launch arrived days before Apple&#8217;s annual developer event scheduled for next week. A recent job posting from Apple mentioned a seemingly new concept, homeOS, which may have to do with Apple&#8217;s smart home strategy, as <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/06/02/apple-homeos-mentioned-in-job-listing/">noted</a> by Macrumors.</p>
<p>Huawei denied speculations that HarmonyOS is a derivative of Android and said no single line of code is identical to that of Android. A spokesperson for Huawei declined to say whether the operating system is based on Linux, the kernel that powers Android.</p>
<p>Several tech giants have tried to introduce their own mobile operating systems to no avail. Alibaba built AliOS based on Linux but has long stopped updating it. Samsung<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/12/31/all-of-samsungs-new-smart-tvs-will-run-its-tizen-operating-system/"> flirted with its own Tizen</a> but the operating system is limited to powering a few Internet of Things like smart TVs.</p>
<p>Huawei may have a better shot at drumming up developer interest compared to its predecessors. It&#8217;s still <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/apple-record-china-2021/">one of China&#8217;s largest smartphone brands</a> despite losing a chunk of its market after the U.S. government cut it off critical chip suppliers, which could hamper its ability to make cutting-edge phones. HarmonyOS also has a chance to create an alternative for developers who are disgruntled with Android, if Huawei is able to capture their needs.</p>
<p>The U.S. sanctions do not block Huawei from using Android&#8217;s open-source software, which major Chinese smartphone makers use to build their third-party Android operating system. But the ban was like a death knell for Huawei&#8217;s consumer markets overseas as its phones abroad lost access to Google Play services.</p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
<p><audio style="display: none;" controls="controls"></audio></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/huawei-officially-launches-android-alternative-harmonyos-for-smartphones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159206</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jeeves emerges from stealth with $131M in debt and equity and a16z as a lead investor</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/fintech-jeeves-emerges-from-stealth-with-131m-in-debt-equity-from-a16z-yc-and-a-bunch-of-unicorn-ceos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/fintech-jeeves-emerges-from-stealth-with-131m-in-debt-equity-from-a16z-yc-and-a-bunch-of-unicorn-ceos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andressen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angela Strange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brazil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clocktower Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel Vogel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Velez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expense management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaguar Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeeves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Football League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nfl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payment card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[profile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rappi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[runa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stanford University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncorrelated Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Innovation Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Hockey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159732</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jeeves, which is building an “all-in-one expense management platform” for global startups, is emerging from stealth today with $131 million in total funding, including $31 million in equity and $100 million in debt financing.  The $31 million in equity consists of a new $26 million Series A and a previously unannounced $5 million seed round. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jeeves, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">which is building an “all-in-one expense management platform” for global</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">startups</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, is emerging from stealth today with $131 million in total funding, including $31 million in equity and $100 million in debt financing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The $31 million in equity consists of a new $26 million Series A and a previously unannounced $5 million seed round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) led the Series A funding, which also included participation from</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> YC Continuity Fund, Jaguar Ventures, Urban Innovation Fund, Uncorrelated Ventures, Clocktower Ventures, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stanford University, 9 Yards Capital and BlockFi Ventures.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">high-profile group of angel investors also put money in the round, including NFL wide receiver Larry Fitzgerald and the founders of five LatAm unicorns — Nubank CEO David Velez, Kavak CEO Carlos Garcia, Rappi co-founder Sebastian Mejia, Bitso CEO Daniel Vogel and Loft CEO Florian Hagenbuch. Justo’s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ricardo Weder also participated in this round and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plaid co-founder William Hockey put money in the $5 million seed funding that closed in 2020 after the company completed the YC Summer 2020 batch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The “fully remote” Jeeves describes itself as the first “cross country, cross currency” expense management platform. The startup’s offering is currently live in Mexico — its largest market — as well as Colombia, Canada and the U.S., and is currently beta testing in Brazil and Chile. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dileep Thazhmon and Sherwin Gandhi founded Jeeves last year under the premise that startups have traditionally had to rely on financial infrastructure that is local and country-specific. For example, a company with employees in Mexico and Colombia would require multiple vendors to cover its finance function in each country &#8212; a corporate card in Mexico and one in Colombia and another vendor for cross-border payments.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2159750" style="width: 676px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159750" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2159750 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_v3_Jeeves.jpg" alt="" width="666" height="325" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_v3_Jeeves.jpg 666w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_v3_Jeeves.jpg?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_v3_Jeeves.jpg?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Founders_v3_Jeeves.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 666px) 100vw, 666px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159750" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Left to right: Jeeves co-founders Dileep Thazhmon and Sherwin Gandhi</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jeeves claims that by using its platform, any company can spin up their finance function “in minutes” and get access to 30 days of credit on a true corporate card, noncard payment rails, as well as cross-border payments. Customers can also pay back in multiple currencies, reducing FX (foreign transaction) fees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We&#8217;re building an all-in-one expense management platform for startups in LatAm and global markets &#8212; cash, corporate cards, cross-border &#8212; all run on our own infrastructure,” Thazhmon said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re really building two things &#8212; an infrastructure layer that sits across banking institutions in different countries. And then on top of that, we&#8217;re building the customer-, or end user-facing app,” he added. “What gives us the ability to launch in countries much quicker is that we own part of that stack ourselves, versus what most fintechs would do, which is plug into a third-party provider in that region.” </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2159753" style="width: 427px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159753" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2159753 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg?w=417" alt="" width="417" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg 1226w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg?resize=92,150 92w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg?resize=184,300 184w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg?resize=768,1253 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg?resize=417,680 417w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg?resize=942,1536 942w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Jeeves-WithCard1.jpg?resize=31,50 31w" sizes="(max-width: 417px) 100vw, 417px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159753" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Jeeves</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indeed, the company has seen rapid early growth. Since launching its private beta last October, Jeeves says it has grown its transaction volume (GTV) by 200x and increased revenue by 900% (albeit from a small base). In May alone, Jeeves says it processed more transaction volume than the entire year to date, and more than doubled its customer base. It says that “hundreds of companies,” including Bitso, Belvo, Justo, Runa, Worky, Zinboe, RobinFood and Muncher, “actively” use Jeeves to manage their local and international spend. On top of that, it says, the startup has a waitlist of more than 5,000 companies &#8212; which is part of why the company sought to raise debt and equity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The shift to remote work globally due to the COVID-19 pandemic has played a large role in why Jeeves has seen so much demand, according to Thazhmon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Every company is now becoming a global company, and the service to employees in two different countries requires two different systems,” he said. “And then someone&#8217;s got to reconcile that system at the end of the month. This has been a big reason why we’re growing so fast.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of Jeeves’ biggest accomplishments so far, Thazhmon said, has been receiving approval to issue cards from its own credit BIN (bank identification number) in Mexico. It can also run SPEI payments directly on its infrastructure. (SPEI </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is a system developed and operated by Banco de </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">México</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that allows the general public to make electronic payments.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This gives us a lot of flexibility and allows us to offer a truly unique product to our customers,” said Thazhmon, who previously co-founded PowerInbox, a<br />
Battery Ventures-backed MarTech company that he says grew to $40 million in annual revenue in three years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jeeves says it will use the fresh capital to onboard new companies to the platform from its waitlist, scale its infrastructure to cover more countries and currencies as well as do some hiring and expand its product line.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A16z General Partner Angela Strange, who is joining Jeeves’ board as part of the investment, is extremely bullish on the startup’s potential.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strange says she met Thazhmon about a year ago and was immediately intrigued.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Not only were they working to provide the financial operating system within a country, starting in Mexico, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">they were designing their software platform to scale across multiple countries,” she said. “Finally &#8212; a multicountry/currency expense management &amp; payouts platform, where increasingly companies have employees and operations in multiple countries from the start and can use a single company to manage their financials.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strange, who has been investing in Latin America for the past few years, notes that most </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">companies in the region are unable to get a corporate credit card.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OPlhpt0tsX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/fintechs-could-see-100-billion-of-liquidity-in-2021/">Fintechs could see $100 billion of liquidity in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintechs could see $100 billion of liquidity in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/25/fintechs-could-see-100-billion-of-liquidity-in-2021/embed/#?secret=OPlhpt0tsX" data-secret="OPlhpt0tsX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“That’s only the tip of the iceberg,” she told TechCrunch. “It&#8217;s cumbersome for companies to make bank to bank payouts, handle wires, and they usually also have expenses in the U.S. (and often other countries) so there is also FX. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">And </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">they manage multiple bank accounts. Not only is paying hard, reconciliation on the backend takes weeks.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As such, Strange said, with every country having their own bank transfer system, rules around who can issue a credit card, approved payment processors, currencies and bank accounts &#8212; payments and expense management across countries can be complex.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jeeves, according</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to Strange, “gets as close to the networks/payment rails as possible” since it has its own issuing credit BIN versus needing to connect through legacy players.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Providing an orchestration layer on top of all the rails gives Jeeves the ability “to handle all the payment and reconciliation complexity” so “their customers don&#8217;t have to think about it,” she added.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/fintech-jeeves-emerges-from-stealth-with-131m-in-debt-equity-from-a16z-yc-and-a-bunch-of-unicorn-ceos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159732</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why sports tech is bigger than a game</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/why-sports-tech-is-bigger-than-a-game/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/why-sports-tech-is-bigger-than-a-game/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. For this week’s deep dive, Alex and Natasha dug into the burgeoning of sports media, sports gaming, and fantasy sports world today through the lens of some early-stage startups. Naturally, the Equity team is what comes to mind when you consider [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/d1036e85-36cf-4f46-8b89-56a0816aeaca?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>For this week’s deep dive, <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> dug into the burgeoning of sports media, sports gaming, and fantasy sports world today through the lens of some early-stage startups. Naturally, the Equity team is what comes to mind when you consider the correct and right people to discuss sports. We are here to back up your priors.</p>
<p>Jokes aside, we had a good time digging into the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/women-led-sports-media-startup-the-gist-raises-1m-to-challenge-sports-reporting-norms/">THE GIST raised $1 million</a>. Both Natasha and Alex were very bullish on the company&#8217;s product, focus, and market. Especially in light of some recent media deals that have kept our hearts aflutter over the last few quarters.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/fantasy-fantasy-sport-blaseball-developers-score-3m-seed-funding-to-go-mobile/">Blaseball raised $3 million</a>. Whether it is blah-ZAY-ball, or BLACE-ball, the Equity team thinks that having <em>fantasy</em> fantasy sports is meta, good fun, and perhaps appeal-broadening the larger, somewhat hoary world of baseball. Also baseball could use more whimsy in general.</li>
<li>And the fantasy talk continued as we got to cricket, which is a massively adored and obsessed over sport in India especially. Earlier this year, Dream11&#8217;s parent firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-admin/post.php?post=2159664&amp;action=edit">raised $225 million at an over $2.5 billion valuation </a>to build an end-to-end sports tech company around the sport.</li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;d venture out to say we are probably the only tech podcast this week that found an angle to riff on within sports and donuts, which is why we love our jobs and why we hope you love the show. Surprises keep things fun, and much love to our producers, <a href="https://twitter.com/CGates123">Chris</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a>, for constantly sourcing creative material that may have flown under the radar otherwise.</p>
<p>Back Friday!</p>
<p><em>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/why-sports-tech-is-bigger-than-a-game/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159622</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking Lyft’s new e-bike for a spin</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/taking-lyfts-new-e-bike-for-a-spin/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/taking-lyfts-new-e-bike-for-a-spin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bikesharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The bike had none of the usual signage when I took it for a spin around the chaotic and construction-filled streets of Manhattan. It very much looked like a prototype, with visible soldering on the joints and a not-quite-complete AV system. But it handled well, when merging in and out of traffic &#8212; and at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The bike had none of the usual signage when I took it for a spin around the chaotic and construction-filled streets of Manhattan. It very much looked like a prototype, with visible soldering on the joints and a not-quite-complete AV system. But it handled well, when merging in and out of traffic &#8212; and at the end of the day, that’s the most important thing.</p>
<p>Pilots for Lyft’s new e-bike begin this month. The ride-hailing service will begin offering units in cities where it operates, starting with San Francisco, then Chicago and New York. The locations will be somewhat randomized, as a kind of “Easter egg” system where users will randomly stumble on the shiny new electric bicycles. If you’re lucky enough to experience one in the wild, Lyft will shoot you an email, asking how your experience was.</p>
<p>Mine was pretty good, all told &#8212; but for that moment I got clipped by a delivery driver. But that’s life in the big city &#8212; and I was probably making too wide a turn, my first time on the 80-pound e-bike (20 pounds more than their predecessor). The weight of the thing (owing primarily to a massive new battery on the downtube) concerned me at first, but the bike handles surprisingly well. The pedal assist is smooth and seamless. At a cruising speed, I found that I only had to pump a few times per block.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2158958" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2158958" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2158958" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg 5472w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/PressKit_DayView_Side_HighRes.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2158958" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Lyft</p></div></p>
<p>The ride was limited &#8212; almost entirely on flat ground, meaning I didn’t get to experience many of the automated gear shifts, nor really put the pedal assist to test riding up a bridge on ramp or one of San Francisco’s notorious hills. All told, the gears shifted probably two or three times during the ride. It was noticeable, but fairly smooth.</p>
<p>The new bikes arrive not long after Lyft deployed their last e-bike fleet (though those were <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21142346/citi-bike-electric-ebike-nyc-return-brake-malfunction">not without incident</a>). Still, the company says it essentially built these from scratch.</p>
<p>“There are a ton of mom and pop as well as large-scale consumer vendors for e-bikes. But a fleet e-bike is a drastically different thing,” product manager Gary Shambat told TechCrunch. “They might look similar on the outside, but the wear and tear and the vandalism cases are so supremely different that you can’t just take an existing product, patch it up in a few ways, throw on a connected module and call it a day.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2158967" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2158967" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2158967" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg 8192w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg?resize=2048,1366 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210501_Lyft_Ebike_Building_0709.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2158967" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Lyft</p></div></p>
<p>The pedal assist is powered by a 500W motor and a pretty massive battery the company says is capable of a 60-mile range &#8212; meaning it should be able to get through a couple of rides without needing a full charge. All of that is monitored by a system of sensors designed to send out alerts when there’s an issue with the battery or breaks.</p>
<p>The white body is reflective and there’s an LED ring light up front that can change colors. The company says it’s testing different applications, beyond a simple headlight and bike locator. The ring is segmented and can turn various colors, so something like turn signals could make sense going forward. There are nice little touches throughout, as well &#8212; like the hand-bar grip, which is designed to look like tiny mustaches as a nod to that odd accoutrement from the service’s early days.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2158975,2158973,2158972,2158971,2158969,2158967,2158963,2158962,2158961,2158960,2158959,2158958,2158957"]</p>
<p>Lyft currently operates bike-sharing in nine markets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Nk1z92P3HU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/02/its-official-lyft-bikes-is-now-a-thing/">Lyft Bikes is now a thing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Lyft Bikes is now a thing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/07/02/its-official-lyft-bikes-is-now-a-thing/embed/#?secret=Nk1z92P3HU" data-secret="Nk1z92P3HU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/taking-lyfts-new-e-bike-for-a-spin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159030</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Synctera raises $33M Series A to pair fintechs with banks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/fin-vc-leads-33m-series-a-for-synctera-which-wants-to-pair-fintechs-with-banks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/fin-vc-leads-33m-series-a-for-synctera-which-wants-to-pair-fintechs-with-banks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking-as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fdic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greenlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marqeta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter Hazlehurst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[player]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plexo capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richie serna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Synctera, which aims to serve as a matchmaker for community banks and fintechs, has raised $33 million in a Series A round of funding led by Fin VC. The raise comes just under six months after the fintech raised $12.4 million in a seed round of funding. New investors Mastercard and Gaingels also participated in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.synctera.com/"><b>Synctera</b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">which aims to serve as a matchmaker for community banks and fintechs, has raised $33 million in a Series A round of funding led by Fin VC.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The raise comes just under six months after the fintech raised $12.4 million in a seed round of funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">New investors Mastercard and Gaingels also participated in the latest round, which included follow-on investments from Lightspeed Venture Partners, Diagram Ventures, SciFi Ventures and Scribble Ventures. Several angel investors put money in the Series A including Omri Dahan, Marqeta’s Chief Revenue Officer, Feedzai Chairman and CEO Nuno Sebastiao and Greenlight co-founder and CEO Tim Sheehan. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alongside the Series A, Synctera is also announcing its commitment to the</span><a href="http://captablecoalition.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> new </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cap Table Coalition</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – which includes funding from Gaingels, Neythri Futures Fund, Plexo Capital and over 20 angels – alongside other startups by allocating 10% of all funding rounds to “traditionally marginalized,” or underrepresented, investors via an SPV. (Fellow fintech Finix </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/fintech-startup-finix-closes-on-3m-in-black-and-latinx-investor-led-spv/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">led the initiative</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> earlier this year before forming this coalition but more on that later).</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HDx5uHGUaF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/fintech-startup-finix-closes-on-3m-in-black-and-latinx-investor-led-spv/">Fintech startup Finix closes on $3M in Black and Latinx investor-led SPV</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech startup Finix closes on $3M in Black and Latinx investor-led SPV&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/fintech-startup-finix-closes-on-3m-in-black-and-latinx-investor-led-spv/embed/#?secret=HDx5uHGUaF" data-secret="HDx5uHGUaF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This has exposed us to find great folks who we otherwise might not have known,” said </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Synctera’s co-founder and CEO Peter Hazlehurst. “That’s why we pledge to reserve 10% of this round and all future rounds to diverse investors.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a nutshell, San Francisco-based Synctera has developed a platform designed to help facilitate partnership banking. It was founded on the premise that some community banks and credit unions are actually turning down deals with young fintechs because the relationships can be too complicated or time-consuming to manage. Synctera’s goal is to connect community banks and fintechs to streamline the process with its “Banking-as-a-Service” (BaaS) platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch recently caught up with Hazlehurst, who most recently served as former head of Uber Money and previously also led development of Google Wallet</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and products related to its payments system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put simply, Synctera wants to make it easier for community banks and fintechs to partner with each other. It examines banks’ needs and then sets them up with a fintech that is best suited to meet those needs. It claims to “do the work for both parties,” managing the partnership from its back-end platform, while dealing with issues like regulatory compliance, which can be a deterrent for some companies. The process of managing, reconciling and billing banks can result in “a lot of operational overhead and complexity,” according to the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company says it’s built a “diverse” marketplace of banks and fintech companies so that it can apply a “personalized touch to each match” and make sure that the parties “align on geography, brand ethos, and desired business goals.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So far, Synctera has signed three banks with plans to sign on three more this month. The startup has already paired Coastal Community Bank – a local bank serving the greater Puget Sound community – with One, a new digital banking platform, and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ellevest</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a new fintech. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By using Synctera’s platform, the company claims, banks can more freely allow their fintech counterparts to offer FDIC-insured mobile checking, debit cards, savings accounts or innovations in payments to their prospective customers, the company claims. They can also make more money doing so, Hazlehurst said, by bringing in more revenue beyond interchange fees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Like most small businesses, community banks have been hit hard by COVID-19,” he added. “We hope to further diversify community banks’ revenue streams.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Banks can also more easily manage multiple relationships with various fintechs as the companies agree to adopt Synctera’s tech stack, the company claims.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We build a single dashboard for a bank, so there’s a consolidated position across all fintechs,” Hazlehurst told me at the time of the company’s last raise. “It’s all about visibility for the bank.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently Synctera has about 50 employees, including about two dozen engineers, most of whom are located in Canada, Hazlehurst said. The company plans to ramp up to 160 employees by year’s end with a focus on engineering, sales, marketing and customer success staff.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, Hazlehurst predicts that the fourth quarter will be “all about support for small business fintechs.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> want to create a neobank for gig economy workers, and want to add lending as a service,” he said. “But our next big phase is to onboard a lot of fintechs, and learn from them.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Logan Allin, managing general partner and founder at Fin VC, believes that </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Banking-as-a-Service in general will transform legacy national and regional banks, credit unions, fintecs, corporate tech and retailers alike “as these players either seek to vertically integrate financial services or accelerate their digitization process.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Synctera, he adds, has taken an approach with its tech stack that allows for integration with legacy community banks and their respective cores. This, Allin believes, will help ensure a “cloud native and scalable model” and made it an attractive investment. (Fin VC has also backed the likes of other fintechs such as Pipe and SoFi).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Synctera&#8217;s peers are simply abstracting bank cores and serving as ‘API wrappers’ in a kludgy short-term approach and having come from the legacy bank and modern fintech worlds, we recognized that these players had not built sufficiently strong bridges across the ecosystem,” Allin told TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For his part, Finix Founder Richie Serna is thrilled that other startups are following his lead in the pledge to make their cap tables more diverse.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“After Finix announced our special purpose vehicle for Black and Latinx investors, the response was overwhelmingly positive,” he told TechCrunch. “Startups in every sector and at every stage have asked us how to recreate our SPV. In response, we started the Cap Table Coalition to make it as easy as possible for more high-growth startups, like Synctera, to take control over their cap tables,&#8221; said Richie Serna, CEO and co-founder of Finix. &#8220;We see this as an inflection point that will completely upend how the VC world functions.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, Synctera is not the only player trying to help banks and fintechs forge partnerships. Last week, TechCrunch reported on </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Visa said it has </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">expanded its Visa Fintech Partner Connect program</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is designed to help financial institutions quickly connect with a “vetted and curated” set of technology providers. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qxYJG8GtPE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/visa-takes-a-swipe-in-fintech-builds-new-online-marketplace/">Visa takes a swipe in fintech, builds new online marketplace</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Visa takes a swipe in fintech, builds new online marketplace&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/visa-takes-a-swipe-in-fintech-builds-new-online-marketplace/embed/#?secret=qxYJG8GtPE" data-secret="qxYJG8GtPE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/fin-vc-leads-33m-series-a-for-synctera-which-wants-to-pair-fintechs-with-banks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159908</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coatue direct deposits $20M into Pinwheel, a payroll API for neobanks</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/coatue-direct-deposits-20m-into-pinwheel-a-payroll-api-for-neobanks/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/coatue-direct-deposits-20m-into-pinwheel-a-payroll-api-for-neobanks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curtis Lee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[payroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinwheel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the most strategically important financial relationships for neobanks is becoming the account destination for a user’s paycheck. If you’re a bank and you own that specific relationship, users will increasingly use that account for everything from daily spending to saving (after all, that’s where their money is going). That activity in turn leads [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One of the most strategically important financial relationships for neobanks is becoming the account destination for a user’s paycheck. If you’re a bank and you own that specific relationship, users will increasingly use that account for everything from daily spending to saving (after all, that’s where their money is going). That activity in turn leads to expansive opportunities to upsell users to other financial products and generate the kinds of fees that banks love to make.</p>
<p>It just so happens though that users are often baffled in how to change their direct deposit instructions. To do so, they still have to go into ancient payroll systems, fill out account and routing data, verify that it’s correctly setup and more — all steps that can fluster users who will just give up.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinwheelapi.com">Pinwheel</a> is a “payroll connectivity” API designed to bridge this divide. It helps neobanks and other clients connect into a users’s payroll information system, offering everything from direct-deposit switching to income verification (a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/income-verification-is-white-hot-right-now-and-plaid-wants-in/">hot space these days</a>), and paycheck-linked lending.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>It’s proven very popular, particularly in the midst of the pandemic that saw millions switch jobs as well as neobanks reaching stratospheric growth as account holders searched for cheaper and more flexible banking options. The company saw 11x revenue growth last quarter and claims neobank Current and mobile payment service Square Cash as clients.</p>
<p>That early traction has drawn a new round of capital. Michael Gilroy of Coatue led a $20 million Series A round into the company. Gilroy, who came to Coatue about two years ago from Canaan, has long been interested in fintech, recently investing in companies like B2B receivables platform Melio, financial transaction API Quanto, and teenage neobank Step.</p>
<p>In addition to Coatue, Primary Ventures and Semper Virens newly joined the round, and seed investors First Round Capital and Upfront Ventures re-joined as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/pinwheel-is-the-api-platform-for-income-verification-that-every-fintech-and-neobank-needs/">We last profiled Pinwheel a year ago with its $7 million seed round</a>, exploring how the founders migrated from offering payroll benefits to solving the more fundamental problem of payroll connectivity. Co-founder Curtis Lee, who was then executive chairman and also a venture partner at Primary Ventures, has since moved full-time to become chairman and president of the startup. He said that the company has doubled down particularly on direct-deposit switching as a gateway to the rest of its API offerings.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="raLvYPUSx6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/pinwheel-is-the-api-platform-for-income-verification-that-every-fintech-and-neobank-needs/">Pinwheel is the API platform for income verification that every fintech and neobank needs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pinwheel is the API platform for income verification that every fintech and neobank needs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/pinwheel-is-the-api-platform-for-income-verification-that-every-fintech-and-neobank-needs/embed/#?secret=raLvYPUSx6" data-secret="raLvYPUSx6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“For us, it was really about picking one of those and using it as a wedge and then augmenting from there,” Lee said. “Direct-deposit switching was the most urgent and top priority for all of our customers, mostly since there wasn’t much of an alternative.” According to him, the company is becoming a market leader in that strategic niche. “In a quarter, we will be doing close to half of all direct-deposit switches in the neobank market,” he said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2160040" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2160040" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2160040" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg 3595w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pinwheel-Founders-by-Jinnifer-Douglass-015.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2160040" class="wp-caption-text">Pinwheel co-founders Anish Basu (CTO), Curtis Lee (chairman and president) and Kurt Lin (CEO). Image Credits: Pinwheel</p></div></p>
<p>Once a client starts with direct deposits they start to migrate to other offerings like paycheck-linked lending. As low-fee neobanks build up their consumer bases, they are frantically seeking revenue streams to cover their massive growth. Lending is one rich target, and having direct access to payroll data can make it significantly easier to underwrite a loan.</p>
<p>Pinwheel has been aggressively growing its team, expanding from a small coterie a year ago to about 40 people. The company is reopening its office today in the Flatiron District in New York City, and Lee noted that the company is “remote-friendly” and has about a third of its staff outside the NYC metro.</p>
<p>Among notable hires, Lauren Crossett, formerly of Plaid and Quovo, has joined the company as head of commercial. The company has also signed a VP of Engineering, who will join in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>In addition to the institutional funds, a litany of individual investors joined the round, including Gokul Rajaram, Adam Nash, Jackie Reses, Raj Date, Tony Xu, Shishir Mehotra, Amit Agarwal and Shiva Rajaraman.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/coatue-direct-deposits-20m-into-pinwheel-a-payroll-api-for-neobanks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160037</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify rolls out new personalized experiences and playlists, including a mid-year review and a blended mix with a friend</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/spotify-rolls-out-new-personalized-experiences-and-playlists-including-a-mid-year-review-and-a-blended-mix-with-a-friend/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/spotify-rolls-out-new-personalized-experiences-and-playlists-including-a-mid-year-review-and-a-blended-mix-with-a-friend/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personalization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playlist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spotify today is expanding its investment in personalization features with the launch of dedicated in-app experience called Only You, which focuses on your favorite music and how you listen. The experience is similar to Spotify&#8217;s popular annual review, Spotify Wrapped, as it highlights the artists, songs, genres and other aspects of your music listening experience [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Spotify today is expanding its investment in personalization features with the <a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-06-02/celebrate-your-unique-listening-style-with-spotifys-only-you-in-app-experience/">launch</a> of dedicated in-app experience called Only You, which focuses on your favorite music and how you listen. The experience is similar to Spotify&#8217;s popular annual review, Spotify Wrapped, as it highlights the artists, songs, genres and other aspects of your music listening experience that are important to you, which can then be shared across social media, just as Wrapped is. The company is also today debuting Blend, a new way to create a personalized playlist with a friend.</p>
<p>The Only You hub will live alongside the existing Made for You hub on the Search page inside the Spotify app. In Made for You, you&#8217;ll find your other personalized playlists like Discover Weekly, Release Radar, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/27/spotify-daily-mix/">Daily Mixes</a>, and others, liek Your Time Capsule or Summer Rewind, for example, as well as the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/spotify-adds-three-new-types-of-personalized-playlists-with-launch-of-spotify-mixes/">more recently added trio of playlist sets, Spotify Mixes</a>.</p>
<p>From now through the end of the month, Only You will be a separate hub in the Spotify app, but it will ultimately be relocated to live inside the Made for You hub.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2159404" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159404" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2159404" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_04_Birth-Chart.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159404" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Spotify</p></div></p>
<p>The new Only You experience, meanwhile, will help you discover new trends beyond what you might see in your personalized playlists. This includes &#8220;Your Audio Birth Chart,&#8221; where the Sun is the top artist you listened to over the last 6 months, Rising is your most recent discovery, and the Moon is an artist you listen to that shows your emotional side; &#8220;Your Dream Dinner Party,&#8221; where you pick 3 favorite artists for a custom, frequently updated Spotify Mix featuring favorite songs and fresh picks; and &#8220;Your Artist Pairs,&#8221; which features unique pairings you&#8217;ve listened to recently, like those spanning genres.</p>
<p>It will also contain other personalized insights like the different time periods of music you&#8217;ve enjoyed, the music or podcasts you listen to at what time of day, and your favorite music genres and podcast topics.</p>
<p>For example, your &#8220;Song Year&#8221; will show how you&#8217;ve traveled through different periods of time, based on the tracks you listened to throughout the year. The first year that will pop up here is the year you&#8217;ve streamed the most, while the second year that appears will represent the earlier release year that you&#8217;ve listened to. The third year is the most recent song year that&#8217;s been streamed.</p>
<p>To gather all this data, Only You looks at your Spotify in-app listening experience over the last 6 months (Dec. 2020 &#8211; May 2021). Users must have streamed 30 tracks across 5 different artists over the past 6 months in order to be eligible for the new experience. Spotify says the data isn&#8217;t being used for ad targeting purposes. (And despite astrology&#8217;s connection to birth months and years, the &#8220;Your Audio Birth Chart&#8221; isn&#8217;t asking for users&#8217; birth year to create this experience.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2159410" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159410" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2159410" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_02_Artist-Dissonance_Olivia_GretaVanFleet-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159410" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Spotify</p></div></p>
<p>Another key part of the Only You campaign is the launch of Blend, currently in beta.</p>
<p>This feature will sit on the &#8220;Made for Two&#8221; shelf within the Only You hub, allowing you to invite any other Spotify user to create a playlist with you. Using similar mixing technology that powers Spotify&#8217;s Family Mix and Duo Mix in their respective plans, Blend lets you invite any other Spotify user (free user or paid subscriber) to merge their musical tastes with yours to create a curated playlist featuring songs you both like.</p>
<p>This playlist is updated daily and will grow with users over time as their listening habits change, Spotify says.</p>
<p>Because it works with free accounts, Blend could encourage more users to try Spotify so they can create a playlist with a significant other, best friend, family member or others, even if they&#8217;re not on a shared plan.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2159421" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159421" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2159421" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg 4001w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Blend-Beta-Image-1.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159421" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Spotify</p></div></p>
<p>Both the Only You experience and Blend build on technology Spotify had already developed to power other features, like Wrapped and various multi-user blended mixes, rather than creating something entirely new. But the bigger message Spotify wants to convey here is that it&#8217;s far ahead of competitors when it comes to personalization features. Even if rivals are duping its playlists, it wants to be the forerunner when it comes to personalized music.</p>
<p>Of course, that&#8217;s not always the case. The newer Spotify Mixes, for instance, were a lot like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/28/pandora-takes-on-spotify-with-dozens-of-personalized-playlists-built-using-its-music-genome/">a feature Pandora had launched years prior</a>, which created custom playlists across a number of attributes, including genre and mood. But where Spotify succeeds is its continual release of new personalization features, as it works to make its app customized to the end user. By doing so, the switching costs increase &#8212; that is, users will find it harder to jump to rival services due to how many custom playlists they may have on hand.</p>
<p>Spotify will begin heavily marketing the launch of Only You with a number top artists by creating sets of stats for various fandoms, including those for Harry Styles, Selena Gomez, Lil Nas X, Doja Cat, Justin Bieber, SZA and others. The campaign will run through June 30.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/spotify-rolls-out-new-personalized-experiences-and-playlists-including-a-mid-year-review-and-a-blended-mix-with-a-friend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159398</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FlixMobility raises $650M+ at a $3B valuation to double down on buses and other transport in the US</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/flixmobility-raises-650m-at-a-3b-valuation-to-double-down-on-buses-and-other-transport-in-the-us/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/flixmobility-raises-650m-at-a-3b-valuation-to-double-down-on-buses-and-other-transport-in-the-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As consumers around the world slowly start to get moving again &#8212; and fingers crossed that new waves of Covid-19 cases do not set that back &#8212; one of the big players in on-demand mass transportation services is announcing a growth round to move with them. FlixMobility, the parent company of the FlixBus coach network [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As consumers around the world slowly start to get moving again &#8212; and fingers crossed that new waves of Covid-19 cases do not set that back &#8212; one of the big players in on-demand mass transportation services is announcing a growth round to move with them. <a href="https://global.flixbus.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FlixMobility</a>, the parent company of the FlixBus coach network and the FlixTrain rail service, has closed more than $650 million in a Series G round of funding that values the Munich-based company at over $3 billion.</p>
<p>Jochen Engert, who co-founded and co-leads the company with André Schwämmlein, described the round in a press call earlier today as a &#8220;balanced&#8221; mix of equity and debt, and said that the plan will be to use the funds to both expand its network in the U.S. market as well as across Europe.</p>
<p>New backer Canyon Partners, existing investors General Atlantic, Permira, TCV, HV Capital, Blackrock, Baillie Gifford and SilverLake, and the founders all participated in this round, which was oversubscribed, the company said, perhaps one reason why it&#8217;s not putting an exact figure on it since it could grow; the other reason is that, with debt, typically companies can easily borrow more if needed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The size of the round and the raised valuation &#8212; it&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/08/08/flixmobility-extends-series-f-at-2b-valuation-as-it-gears-up-to-add-cars-to-its-bus-and-train-network/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">gone up by $1 billion</a> since FlixMobility last raised in 2019 &#8212; are bold signs of how FlixMobility is coming out of the pandemic swinging, with investors backing its ambitions. Like others in the transportation and tourism industries, FlixMobility saw business essentially grind to a halt last year, putting it into a holding pattern to await brighter days. It&#8217;s telling that the figures it provides on its size &#8212; 62 million passengers traveled with the company in 2019 &#8212; predate the pandemic.</p>
<p>&#8220;The COVID-19 [pandemic] has been the most tremendous, the most challenging time for any mobility company,&#8221; said Schwämmlein in a conversation with journalists, &#8220;and obviously this also affected our business very heavily.&#8221; The company put safety measures in place, and even expanded some routes in select countries like Portugal and the UK, but mainly had to reduce or completely stop services in the last year. &#8220;We can be very proud on what we have delivered to our customers,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>However, he continued that the company has been trying to focus instead on &#8220;the famous light at the end of the tunnel.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We see the pandemic situation is improving, vaccinations are picking up more and more, and it&#8217;s time for us to switch back to offense,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;The US is leading at the moment we are already above pre-COVID numbers in bookings in the U.S., EU and on the whole, European markets are picking up now following with a delay of one to two months. Therefore we are very optimistic on a travel and mobility rebounded summer effects nations proceed well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pierre Gourdain, MD of FlixBus USA said that the company is aiming to add more buses to its U.S. fleet and expects that by July 4 it will be bigger than FlixBus was pre-pandemic in the country.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s less clear is what shape the new FlixBus will take. The company, back in 2019, talked about how its network &#8212; which some have described as the &#8220;Uber&#8221; for busses and trains, in that FlixMobility itself does not own the vehicles that run under its services, served some 29 countries and worked with 300 independent bus and train partners, creating some 350,000 daily connections to more than 2,000 destinations. With some of those partners inevitably disappearing in the last year, one big question will be whether FlixMobility, now armed with lots of debt capital, will be trying to take a firmer role in operating vehicles, alongside its primary objective of filling spaces on them.</p>
<p><em>More to come.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/flixmobility-raises-650m-at-a-3b-valuation-to-double-down-on-buses-and-other-transport-in-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160059</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon to stop screening employees for marijuana</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/amazon-to-stop-screening-employees-for-marijuana/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/amazon-to-stop-screening-employees-for-marijuana/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannabis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marijuana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amazon in brief blog post announced it will no longer include marijuana on its drug screening program. In short, the company is now treating weed like alcohol, which means off-work employees can partake in a beer or a spliff without fear of repercussions. Of course, just like with alcohol, Amazon says it will continue to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Amazon in brief blog post announced it will no longer include marijuana on its drug screening program. In short, the company is now treating weed like alcohol, which means off-work employees can partake in a beer or a spliff without fear of repercussions. Of course, just like with alcohol, Amazon says it will continue to do impairment checks and screen for drugs after on-the-job incidents.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The only exception mentioned involves positions regulated by the Department of Transportation — read: truck drivers and heavy equipment operators. Applicants for those jobs will still be screened for the marijuana.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This change comes as America is quickly warming to federal legalization of cannabis. Voters across the country, including conservative strongholds, are increasing passing measures granting citizens access to the plant. From medical to recreational use, America is waking up to legal pot and Amazon doesn&#8217;t want to be on the wrong side of history.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">Amazon, <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/operations/update-on-our-vision-to-be-earths-best-employer-and-earths-safest-place-to-work">in its statement</a> written by Dave Clark, CEO of Worldwide Consumer at Amazon, acknowledges the changing political landscape, which is opening doors to legal weed and criminal expungement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1">And because we know that this issue is bigger than Amazon, our public policy team will be actively supporting The Marijuana Opportunity Reinvestment and Expungement Act of 2021 (MORE Act)—federal legislation that would legalize marijuana at the federal level, expunge criminal records, and invest in impacted communities. We hope that other employers will join us, and that policymakers will act swiftly to pass this law.</p>
</blockquote>
<p id="speakable-summary">This updated policy is one of the latest steps Amazon is making <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/amazon-defeats-warehouse-union-push-challenges-expected/">as its workforce is drawing closer to unionization</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tbbnbmf6r5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/jim-belushi-is-chasing-the-magic-in-cannabis/">Jim Belushi is chasing the magic in cannabis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jim Belushi is chasing the magic in cannabis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/jim-belushi-is-chasing-the-magic-in-cannabis/embed/#?secret=tbbnbmf6r5" data-secret="tbbnbmf6r5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aPSXCLnTPk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/cannabis-banking-act-passes-u-s-house-with-bipartisan-support/">Cannabis banking act passes US House with bipartisan support</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cannabis banking act passes US House with bipartisan support&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/cannabis-banking-act-passes-u-s-house-with-bipartisan-support/embed/#?secret=aPSXCLnTPk" data-secret="aPSXCLnTPk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/amazon-to-stop-screening-employees-for-marijuana/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160103</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guild Education valued at $3.75 billion with newest round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/guild-education-valued-at-3-75-billion-with-newest-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/guild-education-valued-at-3-75-billion-with-newest-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guild Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rachel Carlson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Guild Education, which pairs employees with employer-sponsored learning opportunities, has raised $150 million in a Series E round. The financing event, funded by Bessemer Venture Partners, Cowboy Ventures, D1, Emerson Collective, General Catalyst, GSV, Harrison Metal, ICONIQ, Redpoint, and Salesforce Ventures, values the company at $3.75 billion. With the money, Guild plans to grow its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.guildeducation.com/">Guild Education,</a> which pairs employees with employer-sponsored learning opportunities, has raised $150 million in a Series E round. The financing event, funded by Bessemer Venture Partners, Cowboy Ventures, D1, Emerson Collective, General Catalyst, GSV, Harrison Metal, ICONIQ, Redpoint, and Salesforce Ventures, values the company at $3.75 billion.</p>
<p>With the money, Guild plans to grow its coaching team, expand its learning marketplaces with more short-term certificate opportunities, and double down on its outreach with historically Black colleges and universities. The cash comes at a time where lifelong learning &#8211; the concept that students learn and up-skill beyond early adulthood &#8211; is becoming <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/12-investors-say-lifelong-learning-is-taking-edtech-mainstream/">more mainstream</a> of a concept in edtech.</p>
<p>But Guild CEO and co-founder Rachel Carlson, who started the company in 2015 with classmate Brittany Stich, warned that lifelong learning post-pandemic isn’t a simple goal.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2q2FEllaNn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/mapping-out-one-edtech-companys-200m-bet-on-lifelong-learning/">Mapping out one edtech company’s $200M bet on lifelong learning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mapping out one edtech company’s $200M bet on lifelong learning&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/19/mapping-out-one-edtech-companys-200m-bet-on-lifelong-learning/embed/#?secret=2q2FEllaNn" data-secret="2q2FEllaNn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>“I&#8217;m sort of tone deaf to the buzz because I think there are just cyclical, weird spins that happen in Silicon Valley tied to attention span on big critical issues like health care, climate and education,” she said. “But the challenge is, and I even hesitate to call it an opportunity because it&#8217;s really more of the problem, is insane.”</p>
<p>Carlson estimates that there will be 3 million cashiers out of work, 2.5 million women who dropped out of work, and 3 million baby boomers who dropped out before retirement age because of lack of skills. Factoring in other disadvantaged populations such as low-income students or rural communities, the founder thinks that the “buzz” around lifelong learning isn’t solving its core issue.</p>
<p>“I&#8217;m really worried that America needs to wake up to the problem,” she said.</p>
<p>Guild works with three different stakeholders: employees, employers, and colleges. The up-skilling platform partners with large employers, such as Walmart, Chipotle and The Walt Disney Company, as well low-cost universities, bootcamps, and learning providers. Then, it offers a marketplace for students to choose content, giving them optionality to pick which skills will best prepare them for the future.</p>
<p>Guild’s landing page for Walmart advertises the <a href="https://walmart.guildeducation.com/partner?auth_redirect=true">low-cost of school for working adults, </a>emphasizing the company’s education benefit and possible impact it can have on career trajectory. In Walmart’s case, the workers are asked to make a $365 annual contribution toward tuition, or pay $1 a day. At Chipotle, another Guild customer, <a href="https://chipotle.guildeducation.com/partner?auth_redirect=true">100% of tuition</a> is covered by the employer.</p>
<p>A platform like Guild helps employers keep talent in the pipeline and offer a solid benefit: paid education for their employees. The startup connects employers with these learning providers, and then takes a cut of tuition revenue as its core business model.</p>
<p>While Carlson declined to share revenue or profitability, she did confirm that Guild has more than doubled its revenue since COVID began last March. She estimates that over 4 million Americans have access to the Guild through their employer.</p>
<p>The up-skilling world is crowded, with platforms like Udemy, Coursera, Degreed and others all competing to help students get better employment opportunities. Guild sits in a niche spot, by helping those employed, stay employed. Or as Carlson puts it, taking people out of today’s job, for tomorrow&#8217;s job.</p>
<p>While the competition is steep, the co-founder thinks their angle prepares them well for the lifelong learning movement and changing tides of employment in the country,</p>
<p>“The data that&#8217;s flowing through our pipes is helping us have a more robust picture of the working adult learner than anyone else in the country,” she said. “We have more of a robust picture about the data that sits on both the education and the employment side of the aisle.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/guild-education-valued-at-3-75-billion-with-newest-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160093</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celonis snares $1B Series D on $11B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/celonis-snares-1b-series-d-on-11b-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/celonis-snares-1b-series-d-on-11b-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celonis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Franklin Templeton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t.rowe price]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2160032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Celonis, the late stage process mining software startup, announced a $1 billion Series D investment this morning on an eye-popping $11 billion valuation, up from $2.5 billion in its Series C in 2019, quadrupling its value in just two years. Durable Capital Partners LP and T. Rowe Price Associates co-led the round with participation from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://celonis.com">Celonis</a>, the late stage process mining software startup, announced a $1 billion Series D investment this morning on an eye-popping $11 billion valuation, up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/21/celonis-a-leader-in-big-data-process-mining-for-enterprises-nabs-290m-on-a-2-5b-valuation/">from $2.5 billion in its Series C</a> in 2019, quadrupling its value in just two years.</p>
<p>Durable Capital Partners LP and T. Rowe Price Associates co-led the round with participation from new investors Franklin Templeton, Splunk Ventures and existing investors Arena Holdings. Other unnamed existing investors also participated.</p>
<p>While it was at it, the company announced it was naming experienced financial pro Carlos Kirjner as CFO. Kirjner&#8217;s most recent job was at Google where he led finance for ads and other key product areas, according to the company.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9sSI7kdpwY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/28/celonis-moves-beyond-process-discovery-into-automated-workflow-tooling/">Celonis pushes beyond process mining into automated workflow tooling</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Celonis pushes beyond process mining into automated workflow tooling&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/28/celonis-moves-beyond-process-discovery-into-automated-workflow-tooling/embed/#?secret=9sSI7kdpwY" data-secret="9sSI7kdpwY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The presence of institutional investors like T. Rowe Price and Franklin Templeton and the huge influx of capital could be a signal that this is the last private fund raise for the company before it goes public, and Celonis CEO and co-founder Alexander Rinke did not shy away from IPO talk when asked about it.</p>
<p>&#8220;It could be, yeah. It&#8217;s kind of tough to predict the future, but look we&#8217;re very bullish about the growth and our prospects both as a private &#8212; and down the road &#8212; a public company, and obviously we now have backers that can invest capital in both [public and private markets],&#8221; Rinke told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>Rinke says what&#8217;s driving this interest is the tremendous potential of the market even beyond process mining, which he sees as just a starting point for a much larger market. &#8220;Process mining where we originated from is really just the gateway to build new processes and better processes for organizations, and as you think about that that&#8217;s a much much bigger market that we&#8217;re addressing,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uFvLPc5xnH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/celonis-announces-significant-partnership-with-ibm-to-sell-its-process-mining-software/">Celonis announces significant partnership with IBM to sell its process mining software</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Celonis announces significant partnership with IBM to sell its process mining software&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/celonis-announces-significant-partnership-with-ibm-to-sell-its-process-mining-software/embed/#?secret=uFvLPc5xnH" data-secret="uFvLPc5xnH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company&#8217;s processing mining software sits at the beginning of the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/">process automation food chain</a>, which includes robotic process automation, no-code workflow and other tools to bring more automated workflows to companies. It&#8217;s quite possible that the company could develop other pieces of this or use the new capital to buy talent and functionality, something that Rinke acknowledges is possible now with this much capital behind the company.</p>
<p>Celonis started out by mapping out exactly how work flows through an organization, something that used to take high-priced human consultants months to figure out sitting with employees and watching how work flows. Once a company knows how work moves through an organization, it&#8217;s easier to find inefficiencies and places that are ripe for using automation tools. Speeding up that first part of the operation with technology can bring down the cost and accelerate innovation and change.</p>
<p>The company made <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/celonis-announces-significant-partnership-with-ibm-to-sell-its-process-mining-software/">a huge deal with IBM recently</a> where IBM plans on training 10,000 consultants worldwide to use Celonis tooling. That brings the power of a company the size of IBM to one that is still relatively small in comparison &#8212; Rinke thinks they&#8217;ll reach 2000 employees by year end &#8212; and that could be at least part of the reason investors were willing to pump so much capital into the company.</p>
<p>The company, which recently turned 10, currently has 1000 enterprise customers including Uber, Dell, Splunk (which is also an investor), L&#8217;Oreal and AstraZeneca.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AZgndiLN2f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/">No code, workflow and RPA line up for their automation moment</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;No code, workflow and RPA line up for their automation moment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/embed/#?secret=AZgndiLN2f" data-secret="AZgndiLN2f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/celonis-snares-1b-series-d-on-11b-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2160032</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kabuto releases a larger version of its smart suitcase</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/kabuto-releases-a-larger-version-of-its-smart-suitcase/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/kabuto-releases-a-larger-version-of-its-smart-suitcase/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kabuto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart suitcase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suitcase]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kabuto, the French startup that designs and sells smart suitcases, is releasing a new suitcase today. Called the Kabuto Trunk, this is the company’s biggest suitcase to date. Unlike smart suitcases from other brands, this isn’t just a suitcase with a battery in it. In particular, there’s a fingerprint reader located at the top of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://mykabuto.com">Kabuto</a>, the French startup that designs and sells smart suitcases, is releasing a new suitcase today. Called the Kabuto Trunk, this is the company’s biggest suitcase to date. Unlike smart suitcases from other brands, this isn’t just a suitcase with a battery in it.</p>
<p>In particular, there’s a fingerprint reader located at the top of the suitcase. You can save up to 10 different fingerprints. After that, it works pretty much like a fingerprint reader on a smartphone —&nbsp;you put your finger on the reader and it unlocks your suitcase.</p>
<p>In that case, it unlocks the zippers. If somebody else is using your suitcase or the battery is dead, you can also open the suitcase with a traditional key.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Kabuto Trunk features a hard-shell design with a capacity of 95 liters. It has metal bearing wheels and real tires. Users can choose between two batteries — a 10,000mAh battery and a bigger 20,000mAh battery. Basically you have to choose between weight and battery capacity as bigger batteries tend to be heavier.</p>
<p>Customers can also choose to buy a backpack that magnetically attaches to the suitcase. Designed with travel in mind, that backpack is expandable and can double in thickness from 9 liters to 18 liters.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2159552" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159552" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Backpack-Expandable.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" class="size-full wp-image-2159552" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Backpack-Expandable.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Backpack-Expandable.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Backpack-Expandable.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Backpack-Expandable.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Backpack-Expandable.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Backpack-Expandable.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159552" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kabuto</p></div></p>
<p>The suitcase currently costs $629 and the backpack $299 — the company plans to raise prices once the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/kabuto/kabuto-fingerprint-locked-trunk-expandable-backpack">Kickstarter campaign</a> is over.</p>
<p>As always with Kabuto products, this isn’t a product for everyone. They tend to be more expensive than what you’d normally pay for a suitcase. But some people like to pack things in a very specific way so that important items remain available. The startup has previously <a href="https://business.lesechos.fr/entrepreneurs/actu/030977787329-xtend-la-valise-qui-simplifie-la-vie-des-voyageurs-317073.php">raised</a> $1 million (€900,000) from Frédéric Mazzella, Michel &amp; Augustin, Bpifrance, Fabien Pierlot and others.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2159554" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159554" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="1536" class="vertical size-full wp-image-2159554" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Trunk-Handle.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159554" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Kabuto</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/kabuto-releases-a-larger-version-of-its-smart-suitcase/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159549</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DealHub raises $20M Series B for its sales platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/dealhub-raises-20m-series-b-for-its-sales-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/dealhub-raises-20m-series-b-for-its-sales-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[austin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distribution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DocuSign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[israel growth partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DealHub.io, an Austin-based platform that helps businesses manage the entire process of their sales engagements, today announced that it has raised a $20 million Series B funding round. The round was led by Israel Growth Partners, with participation from existing investor Cornerstone Venture Partners. This brings DealHub&#8217;s total funding to $24.5 million. The company describes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://dealhub.io/">DealHub.io</a>, an Austin-based platform that helps businesses manage the entire process of their sales engagements, today announced that it has raised a $20 million Series B funding round. The round was led by <a href="https://www.igpcapital.com/">Israel Growth Partners</a>, with participation from existing investor <a href="https://cornerstonevp.com/">Cornerstone Venture Partners</a>. This brings DealHub&#8217;s total funding to $24.5 million.</p>
<p>The company describes itself as a &#8216;revenue amplification&#8217; platform (or &#8216;RevAmp,&#8217; as DealHub likes to call it) that represents the next generation of existing sales and revenue operations tools. It&#8217;s meant to give businesses a more complete view of buyers and their intent, and streamline the sales processes from <a href="https://dealhub.io/platform/sales-proposals/">proposal</a> to <a href="https://dealhub.io/platform/cpq/">pricing quotes</a>, <a href="https://dealhub.io/platform/cpq/">subscription management</a> and (electronic) signatures.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">&#8220;Yesterday’s siloed sales tools no longer cut it in the new Work from Anywhere era,&#8221; said Eyal Elbahary, CEO &amp; Co-founder of <span class="il">DealHub</span>.io. &#8220;Sales has undergone the largest disruption it has ever seen. Not only have sales teams needed to adapt to more sophisticated and informed buyers, but remote selling and digital transformation have compelled them to evolve the traditional sales process into a unique human-to-human interaction.&#8221;</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p dir="ltr">The platform integrates with virtually all of the standard CRM tools, including Salesforce, Microsoft Dynamics and Freshworks, as well as e-signature platforms like DocuSign.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">The company didn&#8217;t share any revenue data, but it notes that the new funding round follows &#8220;continued multi-year hyper-growth.&#8221; In part, the company argues, demand for its platform has been driven by sales teams that need new tools, given that they &#8212; for the most part &#8212; can&#8217;t travel to meet their (potential) customers face-to-face.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">&#8220;Revenue leaders need the agility to keep pace with today’s fast and ever-changing business environment. They cannot afford to be restrained by rigid and costly to implement tools to manage their sales processes,&#8221; said Uri Erde, General Partner at Israel Growth Partners. &#8220;RevAmp provides a simple to operate, intuitive, no-code solution that makes it possible for sales organizations to continuously adapt to the modern sales ecosystem. Furthermore, it provides sales leaders the visibility and insights they need to manage and consistently accelerate revenue growth. We’re excited to back the innovation <span class="il">DealHub</span> is bringing to the world of revenue operations and help fuel its growth.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/dealhub-raises-20m-series-b-for-its-sales-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159894</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DHL will deploy 2,000 Locus Robotics units by 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/dhl-will-deploy-2000-locus-robotics-units-by-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/dhl-will-deploy-2000-locus-robotics-units-by-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dhl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Locus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[locus robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2159802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DHL today announced that it will be expanding an ongoing partnership with Locus Robotics. Last year, the logistics giant announced plans to deploy 1,000 of the Massachusetts-based startup’s robots. The number is effectively doubling to 2,000 by 2022 &#8212; a deal that would make DHL Locus’ largest customer by a wide margin. The two have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">DHL today announced that it will be expanding an ongoing partnership with Locus Robotics. Last year, the logistics giant announced plans to deploy 1,000 of the Massachusetts-based startup’s robots. The number is effectively doubling to 2,000 by 2022 &#8212; a deal that would make DHL Locus’ largest customer by a wide margin.</p>
<p>The two have been piloting robotics together since 2021, but interest in automation has picked up significantly during the pandemic. The reasons are myriad, but among them are the fact that robots can help keep things running amid a shutdown and are less likely to serve as a potential vector during a global pandemic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gOLjgdunDj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/dhl-will-deploy-1000-robots-from-locus-robotics-for-delivery-fulfillment/">DHL will deploy 1,000 robots from Locus Robotics for delivery fulfillment</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;DHL will deploy 1,000 robots from Locus Robotics for delivery fulfillment&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/11/dhl-will-deploy-1000-robots-from-locus-robotics-for-delivery-fulfillment/embed/#?secret=gOLjgdunDj" data-secret="gOLjgdunDj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>DHL’s Global Supply Chain COO/CIO Markus Voss breaks down the figures accordingly:</p>
<blockquote><p>So far, more than 500 assisted picking robots are already in industrial use in our warehouses in the USA, Europe and the UK. By the end of 2021, another 500 robots are to be added in a total of more than 20 locations. The collaborative picking technology has clearly proven its effectiveness and reliability in modern warehousing. More locations have already been identified with concrete implementation roadmaps for the remaining robots, which we will deploy in 2022. However, the overall potential for assisted picking robots in our DHL warehouses is much bigger, so we are confident that we will meet the targets we have set ourselves together with Locus Robotics.</p></blockquote>
<p>Locus is one of several DHL robotics partners. In late 2018, the company announced a planned $300 million investment in the category, and as of last year, it said it had deployed more than 200,000 robots in warehouses across the U.S. It’s a figure that rivals &#8212; or event bests &#8212; that of Amazon’s robotics efforts.</p>
<p>In addition to these deals, Locus has seemingly had little issue shoring up cash support. In February, it announced a $150 million Series E that valued the company at $1 billion.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1dj8JgQYG5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/locus-robotics-has-raised-a-150m-series-e/">Locus Robotics has raised a $150M Series E</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Locus Robotics has raised a $150M Series E&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/locus-robotics-has-raised-a-150m-series-e/embed/#?secret=1dj8JgQYG5" data-secret="1dj8JgQYG5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BQUm3xMKoW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/top-vcs-discuss-how-covid-19-is-impacting-robotics/">Top VCs discuss how COVID-19 is impacting robotics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Top VCs discuss how COVID-19 is impacting robotics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/07/top-vcs-discuss-how-covid-19-is-impacting-robotics/embed/#?secret=BQUm3xMKoW" data-secret="BQUm3xMKoW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/02/dhl-will-deploy-2000-locus-robotics-units-by-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2159802</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
