<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 07:04:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Twitter appoints resident grievance officer in India to comply with new internet rules</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/twitter-appoints-resident-grievance-officer-in-india-to-comply-with-new-internet-rules/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/twitter-appoints-resident-grievance-officer-in-india-to-comply-with-new-internet-rules/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 06:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter india]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter has appointed a resident grievance officer in India days after the American social media firm said to have lost the liability protection on user-generated content in the South Asian nation over non-compliance with local IT rules. On Sunday, Twitter identified Vinay Prakash as its new resident grievance officer and shared a way to contact [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter has appointed a resident grievance officer in India days after the American social media firm said to have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/twitter-has-lost-liability-protection-in-india-government-says/">lost the liability protection</a> on user-generated content in the South Asian nation over non-compliance with local IT rules.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Twitter <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/report-twitter-abuse-india">identified</a> Vinay Prakash as its new resident grievance officer and shared a way to contact him as required by India’s new IT rules, which was unveiled in February this year and went into effect in late May. Twitter has also published a compliance report, another requirement listed in the new rules.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, the Indian government had told a local court that Twitter had lost the liability protection on user generated content in the country as it had failed to appoint compliance, grievance, and a so-called nodal contact officials to address on-ground concerns.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Other internet giants including Facebook, Google, and Telegram have already appointed these local compliance officers in India.</p>
<p>Internet services enjoy what is broadly referred to as “safe harbor” protection that say that tech platforms won’t be held liable for the things their users post or share online. If you insult someone on Twitter, for instance, the company may be asked to take down your post (if the person you have insulted has approached the court and a takedown order has been issued) but it likely won’t be held legally responsible for what you said or did.</p>
<p>Without the protection, Twitter — which according to mobile insight firm App Annie, has over 100 million users in India — is on paper responsible for everything those users say on its platform. Indian police have already filed at least five cases against the company or its officials in the country over a range of issues.</p>
<p>The new development should help assuage the tension between Twitter and the Indian government. A special squad of Delhi police made a surprise visit to two of Twitter’s offices in late May in what many perceived as an intimidation tactic. Twitter said at the time that it was “concerned by recent events regarding our employees in India and the potential threat to freedom of expression for the people we serve” and requested the Indian government to grant it three additional months to comply with the new IT rules.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Twitter told an Indian court that it was working to &#8220;fully comply&#8221; with the new rules.</p>
<p>More countries are formulating similar requirements for tech giants in their nations. Russia President Vladimir Putin signed a law that mandates foreign social media giants to open offices in Russia. Any social firm with a daily user base of 500,000 people or more is required to comply with the new law.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4AejhKhEsH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/india-it-ravi-shankar-prasad-and-broadcasting-minister-javadekar-resign/">India&#8217;s IT and Broadcasting ministers resign</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;India&#8217;s IT and Broadcasting ministers resign&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/india-it-ravi-shankar-prasad-and-broadcasting-minister-javadekar-resign/embed/#?secret=4AejhKhEsH" data-secret="4AejhKhEsH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/twitter-appoints-resident-grievance-officer-in-india-to-comply-with-new-internet-rules/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175890</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch live as Virgin Galactic&#8217;s first passenger flight takes off with Richard Branson on board</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/watch-live-as-virgin-galactics-first-passenger-flight-takes-off-with-richard-branson-on-board/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/watch-live-as-virgin-galactics-first-passenger-flight-takes-off-with-richard-branson-on-board/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 22:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic is set to launch its first passengers to space tomorrow morning, and you can watch the whole thing right here. The launch is scheduled for 6 AM Pacific, with streaming festivities (including commentary by Stephen Colbert) starting on the hour. This launch is the 22nd for VSS Unity, Virgin Galactic&#8217;s first spacecraft to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Virgin Galactic is set to launch its first passengers to space tomorrow morning, and you can watch the whole thing right here. The launch is scheduled for 6 AM Pacific, with streaming festivities (including commentary by Stephen Colbert) starting on the hour.</p>
<p>This launch is the 22nd for VSS Unity, Virgin Galactic&#8217;s first spacecraft to leave the atmosphere. As before, Unity will leave the Spaceport attached to the belly of VMS Eve, which will take it up out of the thickest part of the atmosphere.</p>
<p>Unity will drop off and ignite its rocket engine, reaching speeds approaching Mach 3 until it reaches the 80 kilometer mark, the lowest altitude considered to be in space. When the engines shut off, the pilots and passengers will enjoy a short period of weightlessness and of course stunning views.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ryy1zHrOX5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/branson-aims-to-beat-bezos-to-orbit-in-final-stretch-of-billionaire-space-race/">Branson aims to beat Bezos to orbit in final stretch of billionaire space race</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Branson aims to beat Bezos to orbit in final stretch of billionaire space race&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/branson-aims-to-beat-bezos-to-orbit-in-final-stretch-of-billionaire-space-race/embed/#?secret=ryy1zHrOX5" data-secret="ryy1zHrOX5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The whole thing will be livestreamed, from the ground and, connectivity permitting, from the craft itself. When they return safely there will be a triumphant press conference and, remarkably, live music from Khalid.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be there on the ground, but you can see what I see by tuning in to the official stream below:</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RTpWYWIfP7Y?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/watch-live-as-virgin-galactics-first-passenger-flight-takes-off-with-richard-branson-on-board/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175881</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week in Apps: Android ad prices jump, TikTok resumes, Google Play&#8217;s antitrust lawsuit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/this-week-in-apps-android-ad-prices-jump-tiktok-resumes-google-plays-antitrust-lawsuit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/this-week-in-apps-android-ad-prices-jump-tiktok-resumes-google-plays-antitrust-lawsuit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Arcade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[play store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[This Week In Apps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2173608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to This Week in Apps, the weekly TechCrunch series that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy. The app industry continues to grow, with a record 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also spent 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to This Week in Apps, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/">the weekly TechCrunch series</a> that recaps the latest in mobile OS news, mobile applications and the overall app economy.</p>
<p>The app industry continues to grow, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a record</a> 218 billion downloads and $143 billion in global consumer spend in 2020. Consumers last year also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">spent</a> 3.5 trillion minutes using apps on Android devices alone. And in the U.S., app usage surged ahead of the time spent watching live TV. Currently, the average American <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">watches</a> 3.7 hours of live TV per day, but now spends four hours per day on their mobile devices.</p>
<p>Apps aren’t just a way to pass idle hours — they’re also a big business. In 2019, mobile-first companies had a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/15/app-stores-saw-record-204-billion-app-downloads-in-2019-consumer-spend-of-120-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">combined</a> $544 billion valuation, 6.5x higher than those without a mobile focus. In 2020, investors <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/app-stores-saw-record-218-billion-downloads-in-2020-consumer-spend-of-143-billion/">poured</a> $73 billion in capital into mobile companies — a figure that’s up 27% year-over-year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This Week in Apps offers a way to keep up with this fast-moving industry in one place with the latest from the world of apps, including news, updates, startup fundings, mergers and acquisitions, and suggestions about new apps and games to try, too.</p>
<p><em><strong>This Week in Apps will soon be a newsletter! Sign up here: <a href="http://techcrunch.com/newsletters">techcrunch.com/newsletters</a></strong></em></p>
<h1>Top Stories</h1>
<h3>Android ad prices jump in wake of privacy updates on iOS</h3>
<p>The Wall St. Journal reported this week how Apple&#8217;s privacy changes are changing the world of mobile advertising &#8212; in this case, ad pricing across platforms. The news outlet has been covering the broader impact of Apple&#8217;s decision to let users block apps from tracking them, noting how <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/publishers-brace-for-impact-from-apples-new-privacy-controls-11598565920">ad sales</a>, including <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apples-privacy-change-will-hit-facebooks-core-ad-business-heres-how-11611938750">Facebook&#8217;s ad business</a>, would be affected. (And how Apple&#8217;s <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apples-privacy-changes-are-poised-to-boost-its-ad-products-11619485863">own ad business</a> would gain.)</p>
<p>This week, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/after-apple-tightens-tracking-rules-advertisers-shift-spending-toward-android-devices-11625477401?mod=djemalertNEWS">The WSJ says</a> most users are declining tracking on iOS (less than 33% opt in), and as a result, mobile ad prices on iOS have fallen. The outlet cites data from ad measurement firm Tenjin which notes that spending on iOS mobile ads has dropped around one-third between June 1 and July 1. Around the same time, Android spending rose 10% &#8212; an indication that, for the time being, some portion of the ad market has just shifted platforms. Facebook ad spend also shifted to Android, with year-over-year growth of 46% for Android users in May to 64% in June.</p>
<p>The news follows a story this week <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/c79a5f6a-0827-47a4-9b3b-622a81fcc75a">from The FT</a>, which noted that Chinese tech giants&#8217; plan to route around the IDFA changes with CAID (the Chinese Advertising ID), had failed. Apple blocked updates to apps using CAID, which led to it losing support and the project&#8217;s failure.</p>
<p>For most app users, the ability to block tracking is a welcome change, as far too much user data had been shared behind-the-scenes without users&#8217; informed consent. But the full impacts of how the update will impact app monetization long-term &#8212; and ultimately which companies then choose to build on iOS &#8212; still remain to be seen.</p>
<p><strong>37 AGs target Google Play in an antitrust lawsuit</strong></p>
<p>A group of 37 attorneys general <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">filed a second major antitrust lawsuit against Google</a>, accusing the company of using its market power to stifle competition. The suit takes aim at Google&#8217;s Play Store, which requires users to pay for apps and in-app purchases using Google&#8217;s own payments system &#8212; which gives Google a percentage of the revenue. In addition, the suit alleges that Google makes misleading security claims about the need for a walled garden app store like Google Play, in order to maintain its dominant position.</p>
<p>Google <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/lawsuit-ignores-choice-android-and-google-play/">responded by calling the lawsuit</a> &#8220;meritless&#8221; and noting that it ignores the openness of the Android platform, which permits other app stores and sideloading.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wcGTIHVmRB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/">Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/embed/#?secret=wcGTIHVmRB" data-secret="wcGTIHVmRB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>First Look: Pok Pok&#8217;s award-winning kids&#8217; app Pok Pok Playroom shows off its sound design</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2174772" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174772" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2174772" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg 6016w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Pinecone.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174772" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Pok Pok</p></div></p>
<p>Recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/11/snowman-the-studio-behind-altos-adventure-and-others-launches-a-kids-app-company-pok-pok/">launched Pok Pok Playroom</a> from Pok Pok, a spinout from app maker Snowman (Alto&#8217;s Adventure, Alto&#8217;s Odyssey, Skate City), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/apple-announces-its-2021-apple-design-award-winners/">just took home an Apple Design Award</a> in the &#8220;Delight and Fun&#8221; category for its app launched just months ago. Unlike other kids&#8217; apps, Pok Pok promises an app that&#8217;s more of a digital &#8220;toy&#8221; that encourages real and imaginative play, not a mobile kids game. Now the company is sharing some of the techniques that helped it build this award-winning experience.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CDJoyaec63U?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>The company says it wanted to make sure there were no annoying sounds or repetitive music in the app that would bother parents or get stuck in kids&#8217; heads. So it worked with its sound designer, Matt Miller, to ensure all the sounds in Pok Pok Playroom were sensory accessible and not overstimulating.</p>
<p>Miller often uses what he calls &#8220;found sounds&#8221; &#8212; that is, sounds he created by finding things to record &#8212; like a soup can, a vintage toy sourced from a local thrift shop, birds chirping, a spoon knocking on a pinecone and more. These give Pok Pok Playroom a more natural feel than other toys, which can sometimes feature loud or electronic-sounding noises that are overstimulating for kids and disruptive to those around them.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zFP0ggObhMM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<h1>Weekly News</h1>
<h3>Platforms</h3>
<p>A <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22549338/apple-google-apps-comscore-study-facebook">new Comscore study offers</a> a look at how much people use their preinstalled apps from Apple and Google. Not surprisingly, these built-in utilities and services &#8212; like email, notes, messaging, maps, photos, clocks and more &#8212; dominate people&#8217;s app usage. 75% of the top 20 most-used apps on iPhone were made by Apple, and 60% of the top Android apps were made by Google, but here&#8217;s the funny thing: The study was paid for by Facebook, a company that&#8217;s looking for any angle to make it seem like it&#8217;s not a monopoly. So of course it had to find the only other bigger apps it could &#8212; the ones that ship with your smartphone.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2174675" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174675" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2174675" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="494" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg 2170w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?resize=150,109 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?resize=300,218 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?resize=768,558 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?resize=680,494 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1116 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1487 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.08.00-PM.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174675" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> comscore</p></div></p>
<p><strong>OnePlus <a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/oneplus-9-pro-performance-throttling-popular-apps/">confirmed</a> it&#8217;s throttling a number of popular apps on the OnePlus 9 and OnePlus 9 Pro</strong> in order to improve battery life. Apps such as Chrome, Twitter, Zoom, WhatsApp, Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, YouTube, Discord, Microsoft’s Office apps, Firefox and Samsung Internet, were affected. The issue was discovered due to inconsistent benchmarks in testing.</p>
<h3>Fintech</h3>
<p><strong>PayPal was the most downloaded P2P payments app globally during the first half of 2021</strong>, according to <a href="https://blog.apptopia.com/-most-downloaded-p2p-payment-apps-in-the-world-h1-2021">Apptopia</a>. Rounding out the top 10 were Google Play, Alipay, PhonePe, Cash App, Paytm, Venmo, Zelle, Western Union and Remitly.</p>
<p><strong>Personal finance app Charlie launched a redesign and a new feature called Direct Pay, which allows users to add their credit cards to the app to make extra payments toward their debt at their own pace</strong>. Or they can let the app recommend when it&#8217;s best to make payments toward their credit card debt. The company notes its users are now saving $66 monthly, which has added up to $30K+ of interest saved over the lifetime of their loans.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Lq2YeAdSPe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/charlie-launches-a-mobile-app-that-gamifies-getting-out-of-debt/">Charlie launches a mobile app that &#8216;gamifies&#8217; getting out of debt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Charlie launches a mobile app that &#8216;gamifies&#8217; getting out of debt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/charlie-launches-a-mobile-app-that-gamifies-getting-out-of-debt/embed/#?secret=Lq2YeAdSPe" data-secret="Lq2YeAdSPe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h3>Social</h3>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/2728.png" alt="✨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> TikTok is <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/find-a-job-with-tiktok-resumes">piloting a new program</a> that will allow U.S. users to apply for jobs using a TikTok video as a resume</strong>. Video applicants are asked to showcase their skillsets and experiences on video, then add <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/tiktokresumes">#TikTokResumes</a> to their caption. Pilot testers include a number of employers &#8212; like Chipotle, Target, WWE, Alo Yoga, Shopify, Contra, Movers + Shakers and others. The question is, will TikTokers feature these videos on the same account where they&#8217;ve posted personal content, dances and trends, or will this give way to a rise in Rinsta and <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/finsta#:~:text=A%20Finsta%20is%20a%20shortened,hundreds%20or%20thousands%20of%20followers.">Finsta</a>-like TikTok accounts, where personal and more public content remains separated?</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qTGoRSXZLM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/tiktok-resumes-job-applications/">TikTok wants you to send video resumes directly to brands to land your next gig</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok wants you to send video resumes directly to brands to land your next gig&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/tiktok-resumes-job-applications/embed/#?secret=qTGoRSXZLM" data-secret="qTGoRSXZLM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>TikTok is also testing its own version of Cameo</strong>. The company was <a href="https://adage.com/article/digital-marketing-ad-tech-news/tiktok-tests-cameo-rival-pays-creators-shoutouts/2348626">spotted</a> testing a new feature that allows fans to pay for a shout-out video from their favorite creators directly in the app. According to <a href="https://twitter.com/iamfabianbern/status/1411675433238683652">screenshots</a> of the feature, fans can request birthday wishes, pep talks and other messages, then pay using TikTok&#8217;s in-app currency.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">TikTok launches Shoutouts &#8211; fans can request birthday wishes, pep talks and other messages from their favourite creators. </p>
<p>Fans can directly pay in-app, through TikTok’s in-apps currency (also used for live-stream gifting). <a href="https://t.co/i5zQJKNfP5">pic.twitter.com/i5zQJKNfP5</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Fabian (Bern) Ouwehand 法比安 (@iamfabianbern) <a href="https://twitter.com/iamfabianbern/status/1411675433238683652?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 4, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p><strong>Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/twitter-shares-its-ideas-around-new-privacy-features-including-a-way-to-hide-your-account-from-searches/">shared a few more ideas</a> it’s thinking about in terms of new features around conversation health and privacy.</strong> This includes a one-stop “privacy check-in” feature that would introduce Twitter’s newer conversation controls options to users, and others that would allow people to be more private on the service, or to more easily navigate between public and private tweets or their various accounts.</p>
<p><strong>TikTok on Tuesday <a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/tiktok-down-outage-1235012787/">experienced</a> a widespread technical outage that lasted for over five hours</strong> before services were restored. U.S. users found that many videos were not loading during this time.</p>
<p><strong>TikTok parent company ByteDance <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/bed7cba1-db7a-49c7-9d57-06fd19e14e10">launched</a> a new business arm called <a href="https://www.byteplus.com/en">BytePlus</a></strong>, which will license the company&#8217;s various technologies to other businesses. This includes its AR effects, computer vision and machine translation tools, analytics and testing tools, and its<a href="https://www.byteplus.com/en/product/recommend"> recommendation engine</a> that supports over 1.5 billion users. The company&#8217;s tools are being used by GOAT, Wego, Chilibeli, GamesApp, Webuy, Lark, and others, in addition to TikTok.</p>
<p><strong>Trump has now <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/trump-lawsuit-tech-companies">sued</a> Facebook, Twitter and Google for being &#8220;censored.&#8221;</strong> The companies enforced their terms of service in taking down Trump&#8217;s account across top social media platforms in the wake of the Jan. 6 attack on the Capitol. Trump&#8217;s lawsuit claims his First Amendment rights are being violated. The First Amendment applies to government censorship, not actions taken by businesses, however. Trump likely knows this but wanted to stir up some headlines.</p>
<h3>Photos</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2174615" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174615" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2174615" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Image_6-1536x762-1.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="337" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Image_6-1536x762-1.png 780w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Image_6-1536x762-1.png?resize=150,74 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Image_6-1536x762-1.png?resize=300,148 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Image_6-1536x762-1.png?resize=768,380 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Image_6-1536x762-1.png?resize=680,337 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Image_6-1536x762-1.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174615" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Picsart</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Popular photo-editing app PicsArt <a href="https://picsart.com/blog/post/new-chapter-for-picsart">launched</a> a brand refresh</strong> that includes a new name (Picsart), new logo, and a fresh new look across web and mobile, and more creator-friendly design flows. The app today has over 150 million monthly active users worldwide.</p>
<p>Everyone <a href="https://stratechery.com/2021/instagrams-evolution/">has thoughts</a> on Instagram Head Adam Mosseri&#8217;s latest <a href="https://www.instagram.com/tv/CQwNfFBJr5A/">comments</a> where he declared Instagram is &#8220;no longer&#8221; a photo-sharing app. His post was meant to alert users to upcoming tests that will see Instagram doing more experiments around how to better feature video in the app, but some are taking it as a sign that Instagram is more fully pivoting to a video-first experience.</p>
<h3>Streaming &amp; Entertainment</h3>
<p><strong>Reese Witherspoon&#8217;s media company, Hello Sunshine, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/reese-witherspoons-media-company-hello-sunshine-is-exploring-a-sale-11625605587">is looking for an acquirer</a>.</strong> The company has reportedly been in talks with multiple suitors, including Apple, The WSJ said. While the larger part of Hello Sunshine is it TV and movie film business, the company also operates the book club app, <a href="https://reesesbookclub.com/">Reese&#8217;s Book Club</a>, which serves as a place where many of the movie/TV deals are initially sourced.</p>
<p><strong>More Spotify Premium users are reporting <a href="https://www.imore.com/spotify-finally-rolling-out-offline-playback-apple-watch-all-users">having gained access</a> to the new feature, announced in May, that will allow them to download music to their Apple Watch</strong> so they can listen offline. The feature had been graduating rolling out, but appears to now be reaching a global audience.</p>
<h3>Gaming</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2174029" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174029" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2174029" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/global-first-half-year-player-spending-in-pokemon-go-2021.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="431" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/global-first-half-year-player-spending-in-pokemon-go-2021.jpg 1450w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/global-first-half-year-player-spending-in-pokemon-go-2021.jpg?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/global-first-half-year-player-spending-in-pokemon-go-2021.jpg?resize=300,190 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/global-first-half-year-player-spending-in-pokemon-go-2021.jpg?resize=768,487 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/global-first-half-year-player-spending-in-pokemon-go-2021.jpg?resize=680,431 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/global-first-half-year-player-spending-in-pokemon-go-2021.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174029" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sensor Tower</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Pokémon Go revenue from player spending has topped $5 billion</strong> as the game celebrates its five-year anniversary. According to <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/pokemon-go-five-billion-revenue">Sensor Tower,</a> the AR game now generates $1 billion on average per year, putting it at the op of the Geolocation AR category globally, ahead of others like Dragon Quest Walk and Square Enix.</p>
<p><strong>The Alto&#8217;s Adventure series from Snowman is getting a new installment</strong> in the form of an upcoming Apple Arcade release called Alto&#8217;s Odyssey: The Lost City. The game is like a special edition of Alto&#8217;s Odyssey (the sequel to Alto&#8217;s Adventure), as it include extra features and content that&#8217;s deeply integrated, not just tacked on, including a new location called the Lost City. The game arrives on Apple Arcade on July 16th.</p>
<h3>Health &amp; Fitness</h3>
<p><strong>Amazon launched a new, employee-only app called <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1573989315">Amazon WorkingWell</a> for its health and wellness program</strong> that includes Associate-facing support, education and safety-prevention information across text content, videos, podcasts, and more.</p>
<p><strong>Vaccine passport apps have hit 10 million global downloads,</strong> according to data from <a href="https://blog.apptopia.com/vaccine-passport-app-downloads-global">Apptopia</a>. The firm analyzed the downloads for top apps including NHS, VeriFLY, NYS Excelsior, and CommonPass.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2174670" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174670" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2174670" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.04.43-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="567" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.04.43-PM.jpg 1422w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.04.43-PM.jpg?resize=150,125 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.04.43-PM.jpg?resize=300,250 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.04.43-PM.jpg?resize=768,641 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.04.43-PM.jpg?resize=680,567 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-07-at-1.04.43-PM.jpg?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174670" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Apptopia</p></div></p>
<h3>Government &amp; Policy</h3>
<p><strong>Chinese ride-hailing giant<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/04/didi-app-pulled-from-app-stores-after-suspension-order/"> Didi was pulled from several apps stores</a> in China, including Apple&#8217;s App Store</strong>. According to Chinese regulators, the app was illegally collecting users&#8217; personal info. Didi said it was making &#8220;corrections&#8221; and is halting new user sign-ups, but the app for existing users remained operational. China&#8217;s cybersecurity watchdog <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chinese-regulators-suggested-didi-delay-its-u-s-ipo-11625510600?mod=djemalertNEWS">also suggested</a> the company delay its IPO, and the app was removed <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/07/didi-removed-from-tencent-wechat-and-ant-group-alipay-apps.html">from China&#8217;s WeChat and Alipay apps</a> for new users.</p>
<h3>Security &amp; Privacy</h3>
<p><strong>9 Android apps with 5.8 million combined downloads were <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/07/google-boots-google-play-apps-for-stealing-users-facebook-passwords/">caught stealing users&#8217; Facebook passwords</a></strong>. A security firm found apps offering photo editing, exercise, horoscopes and utilities that were tricking users into entering their Facebook credentials with the promise of removing ads from the app after signing into Facebook. Google has banned all the apps and their developers from the Play Store.</p>
<p><strong>10 opioid addiction treatment apps <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/opioid-addiction-treatment-apps-found-sharing-sensitive-data-with-third-parties/">were found sharing sensitive data</a> with third parties</strong>, including a unique identifier on Android, unique device identifiers, phone numbers, and lists of installed apps. The apps have 180K combined downloads.</p>
<p><strong>Google released its <a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/116327269/google-android-pixel-security-update-july-2021">July 2021 security update</a> for Pixel which patches a few &#8220;high&#8221;-priority (but not critical) vulnerabilities</strong>. The update is rolling out to a range of Pixel devices.</p>
<h1>Funding and M&amp;A (and a SPAC)</h1>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Publishing platform Hiber raised $15 </strong><b>million</b> for its web platform that allows people to create user-generated games, similar to Roblox. The company also offers a creation app for Android devices and allows players to use Safari to create games on iOS.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Juni, a neobanking app for e-commerce and online marketing companies, </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/juni-a-vertical-neobank-for-e-commerce-and-online-marketing-companies-raises-21-5m/"><strong>raised $21.5 million</strong></a> in Series A funding. The round was co-led by DST Global and Felix Capital. The banking app has signed up 3,000 businesses on its waitlists, of which 200 have now joined.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4c8.png" alt="📈" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Neighborhood social networking app Nextdoor <a href="https://investors.nextdoor.com/news/news-details/2021/Nextdoor-the-neighborhood-network-to-become-a-publicly-traded-company-through-merger-with-Khosla-Ventures-Acquisition-Co.-II/default.aspx">said</a> it&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/nextdoors-spac-investor-deck-paints-a-picture-of-sizable-scale-and-sticky-users">going public via a SPAC</a>.</strong> The company plans to merge with Khosla Ventures Acquisition Co. II, taking itself public at the same time. The transaction will value the business at approximately $4.3 billion, up from its 2019 valuation of $2.17 billion. The app has 27 million weekly active users across the U.S.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Pleo, a startup offering smart company cards for SMBs that automate expense reports,</strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/pleo-raises-150m-at-a-1-7b-valuation-for-its-new-approach-to-managing-expenses-for-smbs/"><strong> raised $150 million</strong></a> at a $1.7 billion valuation for its service that works across web and mobile.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Popshop Live <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/popshop-live-raises-around-20m-at-a-100m-valuation-for-its-livestream-shopping-platform-for-hipsters/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">raised $20 million</a> in Series A funding at a $100 million valuation</strong> for its livestream shopping service, available on web and mobile. The round was led by Benchmark, and comes after 500% growth of the number of sellers on the platform in the last 3 months.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Live video shopping startup Talkshoplive <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/live-video-shopping-startup-talkshoplive-brings-in-another-6m/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">raised $6 million</a> in a seed extension</strong> round led by Raine Ventures. The company publishes<a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/talkshop-live/id1279832503"> an app</a> that sellers can use with its live stream shopping platform.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> </strong>I<strong>ndian social commerce startup DealShare, which began as an e-commerce platform on WhatsApp, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/indian-social-commerce-dealshare-raises-144-million-eyes-international-expansion/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">raised $144 million</a></strong> in Series D funding led by Tiger Global. The round values the company at $455 million post-money and will be used to help fund international expansion.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Indian edtech Teachmint <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/indian-edtech-teachmint-raises-20-million-to-expand-to-new-categories-and-geographies/">raised $20 million</a></strong> in a &#8220;pre-Series B&#8221; round led by Learn Capital for its mobile-first, video-first tech platform.</p>
<p><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f4b0.png" alt="💰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> European neobank Bunq, which offers a bank account you control from a mobile app, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/european-challenger-bank-bunq-raises-228-million-at-1-9-billion-valuation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">raised $228 million </a></strong>in Series A funding that values the business at $1.9 billion. The round was led by Pollen Street Capital and is the largest round for a European fintech.</p>
<h1>Downloads</h1>
<h3>Rec Room (Android launch)</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2173972" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2173972" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2173972" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png 2208w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/recroom.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2173972" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rec Room</p></div></p>
<p>Social gaming platform Rec Room, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/rec-room-raises-at-1-25b-valuation-from-sequoia-and-index-as-vcs-push-to-find-another-roblox/">recently</a> became the first VR unicorn, has launched on the Google Play Store. The platform originally targeted only the VR market but expanded to other platforms as VR headset sales remained slow. Similar to Roblox and others, Rec Room allows players to dress up their avatars and play games built by other creators. To date, the app had been available on iOS, PlayStation 4 and 5; Xbox Series X and Xbox One, PC (via Steam), Oculus Quests and other VR headsets. It&#8217;s now live on Android to serve the larger global market.</p>
<h3>OnMail (Android launch)</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2174682" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174682" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2174682" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="340" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg?resize=1536,768 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/onmail-android.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174682" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> OnMail</p></div></p>
<p>Email service <a href="https://www.onmail.com/">OnMail</a>, which has previously been available on iOS, <a href="https://www.onmail.com/blog/onmail-releases-new-android-app">launched</a> its app on the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.easilydo.onmail">Google Play Store.</a> The app aims to solve users&#8217; biggest problems with email, including those with unwanted mail, email trackers, and more. As on iOS, OnMail lets you accept or reject senders before they hit your mailbox, blocks spy pixels, nudges you to follow up on emails, automatically organizes mail into smart folders (shopping, travel, packages, events), offers easy unsubscribe, monitors for refunds, checks grammar, makes it easier to send large attachments, and a lot more.</p>
<h3>SwoonMe</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2173605" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2173605" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2173605" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg 6000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/SwoonMe-iPhone.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2173605" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SwoonMe</p></div></p>
<p id="speakable-summary">A new startup called <a href="https://www.swoonmedating.com/">SwoonMe</a> aims to fix the problem with superficial dating apps, where users primarily make decisions based on how someone looks in their photos. Instead, on SwoonMe, you take a selfie which the app converts into an avatar. This is what others will see when they come to your profile. You then record a voice clip to tell others about yourself and what you’re looking for in a partner. The result is that when people scroll through SwoonMe, they’re not making snap decisions based on what they’re seeing, but are rather making more thoughtful decisions based what they hear. When two people match, the app encourages them to continue to get to know each other using voice messages and soon, icebreaker games — not texting and photo-sharing. As they communicate, their avatar will slowly unveil their real photo.</p>
<h3>Slide</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2173986" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2173986" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2173986" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="347" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg 2004w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg?resize=300,153 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg?resize=768,392 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg?resize=680,347 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg?resize=1536,783 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-06-at-11.05.18-AM.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2173986" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Raise.com</p></div></p>
<p>A new app from gift card marketplace Raise.com, <a href="https://getslide.com/">Slide</a>, offers users 4% cash back on their purchases online and at over 150 popular stores, including Lowe&#8217;s, Petco, ULTA, Office Depot, Bed Bath &amp; Beyond, Chipotle, Panera Bread, Chili&#8217;s, DoorDash, Domino&#8217;s, Aeropostale, Express, H&amp;M, Foot Locker, Loft, REI, GameStop, AMC, Groupon, Southwest Airlines, Uber, AutoZone, and others. To use Slide and get 4% back, users open the app at checkout, choose their store, and enter their exact purchase amount. They&#8217;ll then show the barcode to the cashier, or if paying online, enter the code. The cash back can be transferred to Venmo or PayPal or saved for a future purchase.</p>
<p>Users should be aware the additional cash comes at a price: the data Slide collects from users will allow companies to retarget them with ads and offers across devices, according to the app&#8217;s <a href="https://getslide.com/privacy-policy">Privacy Policy</a>. The app is free on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/slide-pay-earn-cash-back/id1500372264">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.raise.slide&amp;hl=en_US">Android</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/this-week-in-apps/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1952542" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="93" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=150,21 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=300,41 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=768,105 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=680,93 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=1536,210 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/this-week-in-apps-banner2.png?resize=50,7 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/this-week-in-apps-android-ad-prices-jump-tiktok-resumes-google-plays-antitrust-lawsuit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2173608</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 36 questions that lead to love (but with your co-founder)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/the-36-questions-that-lead-to-love-but-with-your-co-founder/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/the-36-questions-that-lead-to-love-but-with-your-co-founder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups Weekly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After months of beta testing, Y Combinator has launched a co-founder matching platform. The platform invites entrepreneurs to create profiles, which include information about themselves and preferences for a co-founder, such as location and skill sets. It digests that information and offers a number of potential candidates that fit those needs — kind of like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After months of beta testing, Y Combinator has <a href="https://blog.ycombinator.com/co-founder-matching/">launched a co-founder matching platform</a>. The platform invites entrepreneurs to create profiles, which include information about themselves and preferences for a co-founder, such as location and skill sets. It digests that information and offers a number of potential candidates that fit those needs — kind of like Tinder for co-founders. To date, the accelerator says it has made 9,000 matches across 4,500 founders.</p>
<p>Y Combinator is obviously well positioned to execute this tool. The accelerator offers the popular Startup School, a free online program with resources and lectures surrounding how to start a company, to anyone who wants to start a company. The school has cultivated a community of 230,000 founders in 190 countries. A matching tool is thus an easy jump to make, one that could help the partners there move even earlier in aggregating and eavesdropping on nascent talent. Notably, two companies who met through the matching platform are part of the YC Summer 2021 batch. Yay ecosystems!</p>
<p>Here’s my hot take, though: The tool may appear as a neat, in-demand and simplistic tool that connects people to each other, but this is far harder to execute in a meaningful way than one may think — even if you’re an accelerator as famed and well known as YC. What follows is a list of suggestions, or rather wishes, for the tool, put together after I spoke to January Ventures co-founder Jennifer Neundorfer for her thoughts as well.</p>
<ol>
<li>Co-founder matching tools are best for founders who don’t have built-in networks and need ways to find collaborators in their earliest days. Startup School is indeed a wide net, but because Y Combinator struggles with diversity and representation of minorities in its batches, it will need to find ways to make sure that doesn’t get compounded when matching founders with each other. Can there be a filter for gender or ethnic background? Should there be? It’s a slippery slope.</li>
<li>YC told me here that “we don&#8217;t ask for demographic information from Startup School participants with the exception of a recent open text box for gender; and a large percentage have yet to fill this out. Right now, we&#8217;re using this info within co-founder matching — if you&#8217;re a woman, we let you mark that you&#8217;re seeking a woman co-founder and we increase the chances the co-founder candidates you see are women.&#8221;</li>
<li>Adverse selection is a real thing. Neundorfer told me that in the past, co-founder matching tools<em> only</em> attracted founders without networks, which didn’t do much good once they combined their backgrounds and still couldn’t get meetings with VCs. How does a co-founder matching tool find its Goldilocks situation — attracting the star PM at a hot startup thinking about entrepreneurship <em>and</em> the ambitious post-graduate with a love for code but absolutely no connections to people in the Valley.</li>
<li>It’s never as easy as swiping right. Can YC figure out a way to help co-founders within the matching service learn easy ways to vet compatibility? A riff on <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/09/style/no-37-big-wedding-or-small.html">36 questions that lead to love</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, as popularized by the</span> NY Times, but with your co-founder would be perfect.</li>
</ol>
<p>In a blog post announcing the tool, YC addressed this last point. “You probably shouldn’t marry someone after just one date, and similarly, it’ll take more than one video call to decide whether to co-found a company with someone,” it reads. “We encourage matched co-founders to meet and, when appropriate, work together on a time-boxed trial project with clear expectations and goals in order to vet co-founder compatibility.”</p>
<p>All in all, I’m rooting for this because, well, who wouldn’t? As Neundorfer puts it, “founder matching tools are an interesting way to expand the supply of founders and diversify the base of founders.” It just matters that the tools are built with diversity and accessibility in mind.</p>
<p>In the rest of this newsletter, we’ll get into a rare executive shuffle at a pre-IPO company, an EC-1 that digs into the modern web delivery tech stack and Didi. You can find me at Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">@nmasc_</a> and DM me for my Signal for tips (no pitches, please).</p>
<h2>The Instacart shuffle</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2175265" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175265" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175265" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg 1953w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Fidji-Simo-For-Newswire.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175265" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instacart</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/instacart-hires-facebook-executive-as-new-ceo-ahead-of-expected-ipo/">Instacart has hired Facebook executive</a> Fidji Simo as its new CEO ahead of an expected IPO. The grocery delivery company, last valued at $39 billion, will transition current CEO and founder Apoorva Mehta to executive chairman.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>A major executive shuffle ahead of a public debut is as rare as it is questionable. Instacart’s Mehta is leaving his original role before taking the company he founded nearly 10 years ago public. But, per The Information, Simo’s new job is yet another example of <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/instacart-ceo-hire-is-part-of-monthslong-raid-of-facebook-staff?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=page">Instacart’s long-going “talent raid” of Facebook.</a> The publication estimates that in 2021, Instacart has hired at least 55 engineers, product managers, recruiters, designers and data scientists from Facebook. Of course, Simo’s new job means that Facebook has lost one of its highest-ranking female executives, which is not a good look for a company that already struggles with diversity.</p>
<p>Speaking of chief executive drama:</p>
<ul>
<li>Why <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/2-ceos-are-better-than-1/">2 CEOs are better than 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/02/3-guiding-principles-for-ceos-who-post-on-twitter/">3 guiding principles for CEOs who post on Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/">3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy’s top priorities as Amazon’s new CEO?</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>The NS1 EC-1</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2172156" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2172156" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2172156" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="686" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg 8209w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg?resize=300,201 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg?resize=768,515 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg?resize=680,456 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg?resize=1536,1029 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg?resize=2048,1372 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/NSussman_Techcrunch_NS1-FINAL_q1_L.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2172156" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nigel Sussman</p></div></p>
<p>Say that subhead five times fast. The latest EC-1, our deep dive into a company from origin to execution to challenges ahead, is all about NS1, which launched with a plan to disrupt the core of the modern web delivery tech stack.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know</strong>: It’s a key read even for those of us who aren’t the biggest nerds on IT and enterprise infrastructure. Why? Because the story talks about how a startup competes in a matured space full of well-funded Big Tech companies and VC-backed heavyweights — and why the need for a reengineering of internet traffic isn’t a niche one.</p>
<p><em>The breakdown:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Origin story “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/">1 napkin and 22 lines of code, or how NS1 rewrote the rules of internet infrastructure</a>” (2,700 words/11 minutes)</li>
<li>Product development and roadmap “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-product/">WTF is NS1? It’s DNS, DDI, and maybe other TLAs</a>” (2,700 words/11 minutes)</li>
<li>Competitive landscape “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-competition/">The fight for the future of DNS is white hot</a>” (2,300 words/9 minutes)</li>
<li>Customer development “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-customers/">Outages, pandemics and the reengineering of traffic on the internet</a>” (2,600 words/10 minutes)</li>
</ul>
<h2>And finally, Didi</h2>
<p>The Equity team <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/mmhmm-its-the-most-ridiculous-story-weve-ever-heard/">had an especially amazing episode this week</a> — and I wasn’t even in it, so you can take my semi-less-biased word.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what to know: </strong>The most interesting part of the episode was the conversation around <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/will-didis-regulatory-problems-make-it-harder-for-chinese-startups-to-go-public-in-the-us/">Didi, and its impact on Chinese companies listing in the United States.</a> Regulatory problems have a way of lessening investor interest, and Didi isn’t the only example that we’ve had to point to in recent weeks.</p>
<p><em>Other things in the show via Alex’s notes:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>What’s going on with facial recognition tech? With <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/anyvision-the-controversial-facial-recognition-startup-has-raised-235m-led-by-softbank-and-eldridge/">AnyVision raising a $235 million round</a>, Danny and Alex tangled over the future of privacy, and what counts as good enough when it comes to keeping ourselves to ourselves.</li>
<li>Nextdoor is going public: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/nextdoors-spac-investor-deck-paints-a-picture-of-sizable-scale-and-sticky-users/">Via a SPAC, mind</a>, but the transaction had our tongues wagging about its history, growth and how hard it can be to build a social network.</li>
<li>Dataminr buys WatchKeeper: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/dataminr-watchkeeper-acquisition/">In its first acquisition, </a>Dataminr bought a smaller company to help it better visualize the data it collects. It’s a neat deal, and especially fun given that Dataminr should go public sooner rather than later.</li>
<li>Two new venture capital funds: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/acrylic-debut-crypto-fund/">Acrylic has put together a $55 million fund</a> for moonshot crypto work, while <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/renegade-partners-rolls-out-its-much-anticipated-debut-fund-with-100-million/">Renegade Partners has a $100 million fund</a> for early-and-mid-stage generalist investments. Plus, an honorable mention to my scoop on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/peter-boyce-stellation-capital/">GC’s Peter Boyce II leaving to start a new, $40 million fund.</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Around TC</h2>
<ul>
<li>Make sure to use code “STARTUPSWEEKLY” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">for a discount on ExtraCrunch</a>, our premium subscription business where most of our deep analysis lives. The investment will break open access to some of the most interesting tidbits on the site, and support our team!</li>
<li>Big shout out to all the amazing founders and builders who attended TC Early Stage this past week. For those who didn’t attend, recap posts are coming in the next weeks, so keep your eyes out for them.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Across the week</h2>
<h3>Seen on TechCrunch</h3>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/clearco-gets-the-softbank-stamp-of-approval-in-new-215m-round/">Clearco gets the SoftBank stamp of approval in new $215M round</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/indian-startups-fundraise-spree/">Dispatch from Bangalore</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/mmhmm-raises-100m-which-is-a-fun-thing-to-say-to-people-who-dont-follow-tech/">Mmhmm raises $100M, which is a fun thing to say to people who don’t follow tech</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/north-summit-fund-alibaba-cloud-scientist/">Why former Alibaba scientist wants to back founders outside the Ivory Tower</a></p>
<h3>Seen on Extra Crunch</h3>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/what-i-learned-the-hard-way-from-naming-30-startups/">What I learned the hard way from naming 30+ startups</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/vcs-discuss-the-opportunities-and-challenges-of-the-pittsburgh-startup-ecosystem/">VCs discuss the opportunities — and challenges — in Pittsburgh’s startup ecosystem</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/">Startups have never had it so good</a></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/pakistans-growing-tech-ecosystem-is-finally-taking-off/">Pakistan’s growing tech ecosystem is finally taking off</a></p>
<p>And that’s a wrap! This is my first dispatch from San Francisco in over a year, so if you’re in town, happy to be neighbors yet again :)</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">N</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/the-36-questions-that-lead-to-love-but-with-your-co-founder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175809</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trillion-dollar horses, surfeit funding rounds and Future’s future</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/trillion-dollar-horses-surfeit-funding-rounds-and-futures-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/trillion-dollar-horses-surfeit-funding-rounds-and-futures-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter for your weekend enjoyment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Welcome back to The TechCrunch Exchange, a weekly startups-and-markets newsletter. It’s inspired by what the weekday </span></i><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exchange column</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> digs into, but free, and made for your weekend reading. </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want it in your inbox every Saturday? Sign up </span></i><a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i></p>
<p>It’s the end of a short week, but instead of not having much to chat about we have a lot. But it’s all very good fun, so let’s enjoy ourselves!</p>
<p>First, let’s talk about expensive four-legged beasts.</p>
<h2>Trillion-dollar horse?</h2>
<p>The Exchange started digging into the Q2 2021 venture capital market this week. Thanks to Anna’s help <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/">our first piece</a> came out pretty well, I think. We have a lot more coming soon. But the unicorn stats really grabbed me by the nape. Consider:</p>
<ul>
<li>136 unicorns were minted in Q2 2021, an all-time record.</li>
<li>As <a href="https://www.cbinsights.com/reports/CB-Insights_Venture-Report-Q2-2021.pdf">CB Insights notes</a>, that’s <em>“nearly 6x the 23 unicorns born a year ago in Q2&#8217;20, and already higher than the 128 unicorns born in all of 2020.”</em></li>
</ul>
<p>The result of this boom in the horned equestrian population is that there are now 750 unicorns in the world. When former TechCruncher and excellent human Katie Roof <a href="https://twitter.com/Katie_Roof/status/1413543145883721738">tweeted</a> that stat, my first thought was <em>shit, that means unicorns are worth more than $1 trillion</em>.</p>
<p>I was <em>way</em> off. The real number is nearly $2.4 trillion (CB Insights data). Which is a shatteringly high figure. In comparative terms, the un-exited unicorn population of the world is worth nearly precisely what Apple is worth today &#8212; $2.42 trillion, per Yahoo Finance.</p>
<p>Perhaps I am overreacting to the amount of unicorn equity that is currently sitting, largely frozen, in the private markets. Especially when unicorn exits are up. But are even today’s elevated exit levels enough to clear this particular ledger over time? No, I don’t think so. Not when we are minting 1.5 unicorns per day in Q2, counting weekends and the like and the unicorn count is ever-increasing.</p>
<h2>Funding rounds</h2>
<p>I only wrote about one funding round this week &#8212; this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/r2c-raises-27m-to-scale-its-security-focused-code-analysis-service/">r2c round</a> that was pretty interesting &#8212; mostly because I had a bunch of other things to chew through. But I’ve also seen my inbound venture capital round pitches slow <a href="https://alexwrites.substack.com/p/a-few-thoughts-on-funding-rounds">since declaring</a> that I’d not cover rounds that didn’t include more detailed financial information.</p>
<p>It is not clear yet if pitch volume is down due to the holiday week, or if I have scared everyone off. But I do use my inbound volume of funding round pitches both in aggregate, and in <em>sector</em>&#8211;<em>directional </em>terms to help gauge what’s going on. So, here’s hoping that (1) people will send me stuff and (2) they will do so and also share a lot more information at the same time.</p>
<h2>SPACs in space</h2>
<p>Y Combinator is a neat entity. One of its recent companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/satellite-imagery-startup-albedo-closes-10m-seed-round/">was Albedo</a>, a startup that is hoping to build a network of low-orbit satellites that will take super high-res photos of the planet. To do so is hard <em>af</em>, as <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> would say, but perhaps possible thanks to off-the-shelf (kinda) satellite parts, in-orbit refueling and a bunch of other new stuff.</p>
<p>Albedo and its ilk are why I still trot out every year to watch Demo Day. I get to see what could be coming, and that’s very good, illustrative fun.</p>
<p>All that’s to say that when two satellite imaging companies announced that they were going public via SPACs this week I was intrigued. Turns out they are not really in competition with what Albedo wants to do, as they offer lower-resolution images. But they are … notable for other reasons.</p>
<p>Satellogic for having this <a href="https://satellogic.com/wp-content/themes/satellogic-theme/Satellogic_InvestorPresentation_July6-2021__(full).pdf">simply artful series of charts</a> (be sure to observe the dates in each chart):</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175755" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175755" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175755" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_satellogic_7_10.png" alt="" width="1024" height="511" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_satellogic_7_10.png 1057w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_satellogic_7_10.png?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_satellogic_7_10.png?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_satellogic_7_10.png?resize=768,383 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_satellogic_7_10.png?resize=680,339 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_satellogic_7_10.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175755" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Satellogic</p></div></p>
<p>And Planet <a href="https://www.planet.com/investors/presentations/2021/investor-presentation-20210707.pdf">for the following</a>, namely a look into how the economics of satellite tech are pretty heavily weighted toward the future:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175757" style="width: 617px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175757" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175757" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_planet_7_10.png" alt="" width="607" height="413" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_planet_7_10.png 607w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_planet_7_10.png?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_planet_7_10.png?resize=300,204 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/exchange_planet_7_10.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 607px) 100vw, 607px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175757" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Planet</p></div></p>
<p>The company’s long-term gross margin target is 80% to 85% (COGS of 15%-20%, per the deck), but you can see how long it takes to get there. This poses an interesting issue for the venture capital world.</p>
<p>Namely that companies like Albedo are going to need a lot of time and money to build out their constellations and get to scale. And, I presume, to scale to the sort of gross margins that software companies can generate from their first day selling product.</p>
<p>This is one reason why there is so much money chasing software products with even a hint of durable growth; high-margin recurring revenue is the business equivalent of a cheat code when it comes to value creation. Thus every investor wants to shovel money into it. Satellite tech, while <em>super fucking critical in general</em>, simply is more expensive and slower-burn.</p>
<p>My question: Is software so good at generating venture capital returns that other forms of startup work will struggle to compete for attention and capital? Are they already?</p>
<h2>Future</h2>
<p>Finally, <a href="http://future.com">Future</a>. Or more precisely, Future’s future. I am curious about the a16z publication.</p>
<p>Since it launched I’ve checked in a few times each week, hoping to see what was coming out of the venture capital firm’s collective mind. I do so not only because I am a huge dweeb &#8212; I am! &#8212; but also because after all the hand-wringing that I’ve had to read about how the media hates tech &#8212; <a href="https://alexwrites.substack.com/p/tech-media-and-what-journalism-is">nope!</a> &#8212; I was curious what a cosmically well-funded venture group would build. It has <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/andreessen-horowitz-expands-its-in-houses-media-operations-2021-1">hired some great people</a>, after all.</p>
<p>It appears that we are in between publishing cycles at the Future blog. The last pieces of Main Content came out nearly a month ago, and its most recent entry is <a href="https://future.a16z.com/future-com-welcome-what-now-next/">dated June 25th</a>. And that piece is just a note promising more content in July.</p>
<p>It all feels a bit flat? Given the budget, promise, fancy domain and number of people in the a16z world who should have things to say? Why not make more words appear? Let’s see what July brings.</p>
<p>Ok that’s enough from me for the week. Hugs, and talk to you Monday morning on the pod.</p>
<p>Your friend,</p>
<p>&#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/trillion-dollar-horses-surfeit-funding-rounds-and-futures-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175740</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The case for funding fusion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/the-case-for-funding-fusion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/the-case-for-funding-fusion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 16:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy consumption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fusion power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainable energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now is the time to go all-in on decarbonization. Funding fusion with its breakthrough potential must be part of that effort.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Albert Wenger</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/albertwenger">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Albert Wenger is a managing partner at <a href="https://www.usv.com/">Union Square Ventures</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Digital technologies have disrupted the structure of markets with unprecedented breadth and scale. Today, there is yet another wave of innovation emerging, and that is the decarbonization of the global economy.</p>
<p>While governments still lack the conviction necessary to truly fight the climate crisis, the overall direction is clear. The carbon price in Europe rose from below $10 to over $50 per ton. Shell was handed a resounding defeat by a Dutch court. The major blackout in Texas at the beginning of the year revealed the fragility of the existing energy supply even in a highly industrialized country. We must urgently invest more into developing and deploying reliable, clean electricity generation technologies to make decarbonization a reality.</p>
<p>Forward-thinking investors understand this. Global investment in low-carbon technologies climbed to $500 billion in 2020, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-19/spending-on-global-energy-transition-hits-record-500-billion">according to Bloomberg</a>. Renewable energy accounted for around $300 billion of that, followed by electrification of transport ($140 billion) and heating ($50 billion).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>However, we remain far from the finish line. <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/global-energy-review-2021">According to the International Energy Agency</a>, global emissions of CO2 this year are set to jump 1.5 billion tons over 2020 levels. And more than 80% of global energy consumption is <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/world-energy-balances-overview">still made up of coal, oil and gas</a>.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Fusion, the process that powers the stars, could be the cleanest energy source for humanity.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>That’s why we need to continue backing new technologies with breakthrough potential. Of particular promise is nuclear fusion. Fusion, the process that powers the stars, could be the cleanest energy source for humanity. We are already indirectly harvesting the power of fusion through solar energy. Being able to build fusion reactors would give us an “always on” version, independent of weather conditions.</p>
<p>But why fund fusion at all, given that we don’t yet know how to do it? First, this isn’t an either-or proposition. We can afford to build out renewable energy and investigate new forms of energy production at the same time because the latter — at least at this early stage of development — will require a comparatively trivial amount of money. The U.S. government&#8217;s latest <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/31/fact-sheet-the-american-jobs-plan/">plan</a> is to spend $174 billion over 10 years on the electrification of car transport alone, so to invest $2 billion to create a fusion power plant seems doable.</p>
<p>Second, we are about to need a lot more electricity than we ever have. The global demand for carbon-free energy sources is set to triple by 2050, driven by increasing urbanization, the electrification of industrial processes, the loss of biodiversity and the increase in energy consumption in emerging markets.</p>
<p>Third, there’s been tremendous progress in the necessary supporting technologies. Superconducting magnets for the magnetic-confinement approach to fusion have become much cheaper, lasers for inertial confinement fusion have become much more powerful, and breakthroughs in material science have made nanostructured targets available, which enable the use of completely new approaches to fusion, such as the low-neutronic fuel pB11.</p>
<p>Thankfully, there is a growing number of entrepreneurial efforts from world-class teams to try and build fusion. At least 25 startups around the world are targeting fusion right now, approaching the problem with a wide range of technologies. The amount invested in private fusion companies across the world increased tenfold to almost $1 billion in 2020, according to Crunchbase.</p>
<p>The upside of successful fusion is nearly unlimited. The clean energy generation market represents a trillion-dollar opportunity. An estimated 26 TW of primary energy capacity needs to be built globally from 2030 to 2050 to serve the rising global energy needs, according to Materials Research Society. Just 1 TW of capacity will generate $300 billion in revenue, and a 15% market share from 2030 to 2050 would yield more than $1 trillion in annual revenue.</p>
<p>We need many shots on goal here, which is why Susan Danziger and I have personally invested in three different fusion startups already (Zap Energy and Avalanche in the United States and Marvel Fusion in Germany).</p>
<p>But it is not primarily the potential for financial upside that motivates us: There is an opportunity to make an indelible difference in the trajectory of human history. If even a small fraction of the large wealth accumulated by entrepreneurs and investors in the last couple of decades is invested here, the likelihood of successful fusion rises dramatically. That, in turn, will unlock much more investment from both venture funds and governments.</p>
<p>Now is the time to go all-in on decarbonization. Funding fusion with its breakthrough potential must be part of that effort.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NzWVZnWklB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/">What SOSV&#8217;s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What SOSV&#8217;s Climate Tech 100 tells founders about investors in the space&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/what-sosvs-climate-tech-100-tells-founders-about-investors-in-the-space/embed/#?secret=NzWVZnWklB" data-secret="NzWVZnWklB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/10/the-case-for-funding-fusion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175218</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond &#8216;Netflix Party&#8217;: startups and their VCs bet we&#8217;ll browse more of the web together</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/beyond-netflix-party-startups-and-their-vcs-bet-well-browse-more-of-the-web-together/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/beyond-netflix-party-startups-and-their-vcs-bet-well-browse-more-of-the-web-together/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Calacanis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launch Accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, during the pandemic, a free browser extension called Netflix Party gained traction because it enabled people trapped in their homes to connect with far-flung friends and family by watching the same Netflix TV shows and movies simultaneously. It also enabled them to dish about the action in a side bar chat. Yet that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year, during the pandemic, a free browser extension called Netflix Party gained traction because it enabled people trapped in their homes to connect with far-flung friends and family by watching the same Netflix TV shows and movies simultaneously. It also enabled them to dish about the action in a side bar chat.</p>
<p>Yet that company &#8212; later renamed <a href="https://www.netflixparty.com/">Teleparty </a>&#8212; was just the beginning, argue two young companies that have raised seed funding. One, a year-old upstart in London that launched in December, just closed its round this week led by Craft Ventures. The other, a four-year-old, Bay Area-based startup, has raised $3 million in previously undisclosed seed funding, including from 500 Startups.</p>
<p>Both believe that while investors have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">thrown money</a> at virtual events and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/us-edtech-investments-surpass-2020-total-32b-first-half-tony-wan/">edtech</a> companies, there is an even bigger opportunity in developing a kind of multiplayer browsing experience that enables people to do much more together online. From watching sports to watching movies to perhaps even reviewing X-rays with one&#8217;s doctor some day, both say more web surfing together is inevitable, particularly for younger users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rPsGm0EP1i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/">Hopin confirms $400M raise at $5.65B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hopin confirms $400M raise at $5.65B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/hopin-confirms-400m-raise-at-5-65b-valuation/embed/#?secret=rPsGm0EP1i" data-secret="rPsGm0EP1i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The companies are taking somewhat different approaches. The startup on which Craft just made a bet, leading its $2.2 million seed round, is <a href="https://giggl.app/">Giggl</a>, a year-old, London-based startup that invites users of its web app to tap into virtual sessions. It calls these &#8220;portals&#8221; to which they can invite friends to browse content together, as well as text chat and call in. The portals can be private rooms or switched to &#8220;public&#8221; so that anyone can join.</p>
<p>Giggl was founded by four teenagers who grew up together, including its 19-year-old chief product officer, Tony Zog. It only recently graduated from the LAUNCH accelerator program. Still, it already has enough users &#8212; roughly 20,000 of whom use the service on an active monthly basis &#8212; that it&#8217;s beginning to build its own custom server infrastructure to minimize downtime and reduce its costs.</p>
<p>The bigger idea is to build a platform for all kinds of scenarios and to charge for these accordingly. For example, while people can chat for free while web surfing or watching events together like Apple Worldwide Developers Conference, Giggl plans to charge for more premium features, as well as to sell subscriptions to enterprises that are looking for more ways to collaborate. (You can check out a demo of Giggl&#8217;s current service below.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7GZCJ2aNc5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/google-opens-workspace-to-everyone/">Google opens Workspace to everyone</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google opens Workspace to everyone&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/14/google-opens-workspace-to-everyone/embed/#?secret=7GZCJ2aNc5" data-secret="7GZCJ2aNc5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><a href="https://hearo.live/">Hearo.live</a> is the other &#8220;multiplayer&#8221; startup &#8212; the one backed by 500 Startups, along with numerous angel investors. The company is the brainchild of Ned Lerner, who previously spent 13 years as a director of engineering with Sony Worldwide Studios and a short time before that as the CTO of an Electronic Arts division.</p>
<p>Hearo has a more narrow strategy in that users can&#8217;t browse absolutely anything together as with Giggl. Instead, Hearo enables users to access upwards of 35 broadcast services in the U.S. (from NBC Sports to YouTube to Disney+), and it relies on data synchronization to ensure that every user sees the same original video quality.</p>
<p>Hearo has also focused a lot of its efforts on sound, aiming to ensure that when multiple streams of audio are being created at the same time &#8212; say users are watching the basketball playoffs together and also commenting &#8212; not everyone involved is confronted with a noisy feedback loop.</p>
<p>Indeed, Lerner says, through echo cancellation and other &#8220;special audio tricks&#8221; that Hearo&#8217;s small team has developed, users can enjoy the experience without &#8220;noise and other stuff messing up the experience.&#8221; (&#8220;Pretty much we can do everything Clubhouse can do,&#8221; says Lerner. &#8220;We&#8217;re just doing it as you&#8217;re watching something else because I honestly didn&#8217;t think people just sitting around talking would be a big thing.&#8221;)</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RWiMmhLRm1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/clubhouse/">Clubhouse closes an undisclosed $4B valuation Series C round, as tech giants&#8217; clones circle</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse closes an undisclosed $4B valuation Series C round, as tech giants&#8217; clones circle&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/clubhouse/embed/#?secret=RWiMmhLRm1" data-secret="RWiMmhLRm1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Like Giggl, Hearo Lerner envisions a subscription model; it also anticipates an eventual ad revenue split with sports broadcasters and says it&#8217;s already working with the European Broadcasting Union on that front. Like Giggl, Hearo&#8217;s users numbers are conservative by most standards, with 300,000 downloads to date of its app for iOS, Android, Windows, and macOS, and 60,000 actively monthly users.</p>
<p>It begs the question of whether &#8220;watching together online&#8221; is a huge opportunity, and the answer doesn&#8217;t yet seem clear, even if Hearo and Giggl have more compelling tech and viable paths to generating revenue.</p>
<p>The startups aren&#8217;t the first to focus on watch-together type experiences. <a href="https://www.scener.com/">Scener</a>, an app founded by serial entrepreneur Richard Wolpert, says it has 2 million active registered users and &#8220;the best, most active relationship with all the studios.&#8221; But it markets itself a virtual movie theater, which is a slightly different use case.</p>
<p>Rabbit, a company founded in 2013, enabled people to more widely browse and watch the same content simultaneously, as well as to text and video chat. It&#8217;s closer to what Giggl is building. But Rabbit eventually ran aground.</p>
<p>Lerner says that&#8217;s because the company was screen-sharing other people&#8217;s copyrighted material and so couldn&#8217;t charge for its service. (&#8220;Essentially,&#8221; he notes, &#8220;you can get away with some amount of piracy if it&#8217;s not for your personal financial benefit.&#8221;) But it&#8217;s probably fair to wonder if there will ever be massive demand for services like his, particularly as the coronavirus fades into the distance and people reengage more actively in the physical world.</p>
<p>For his part, Lerner isn&#8217;t worried. He points to a generation that is far more comfortable watching video on a phone than elsewhere. He also notes that screen time has become &#8220;an isolating thing,&#8221; and predicts it will eventually become &#8220;an ideal time to hang out with your buddies,&#8221; akin to watching a game on the couch together.</p>
<p>There is a precedent, in his mind. &#8220;Over the last 20 years, games went from single player to multiplayer to voice chats showing up in games so people can actually hang out,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Because mobile is everywhere and social is fun, we think the same is going to happen to the rest of the media business.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zog thinks the trends play in Giggl&#8217;s favor, too. &#8220;It&#8217;s obvious that people are going to meet up more often&#8221; as the pandemic winds down, he says. But all that real-world socializing &#8220;isn&#8217;t really going to be a substitute&#8221; for the kind of online socializing that&#8217;s already happening in so many corners of the internet.</p>
<p>Besides, he adds Giggl wants to &#8220;make it so that being together online is just as good as being together in real life. That&#8217;s the end goal here.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QnJSLyqsZ-M?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/beyond-netflix-party-startups-and-their-vcs-bet-well-browse-more-of-the-web-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175847</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth marketing roundup: cool SaaS, marketing lies, VR ads and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/growth-marketing-roundup-cool-saas-marketing-lies-vr-ads-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/growth-marketing-roundup-cool-saas-marketing-lies-vr-ads-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miranda Halpern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 05:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucy Heskins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programmatic advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reporter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[start ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[start-up]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is searching for the best growth marketers for founders to work with. Click through to learn about some of our favorites.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One might think that a short week due to a U.S. holiday calls for a short weekly recap, but we have plenty to share about growth marketing from our coverage over the week. With the help of your recommendations, this week we were able to interview Peep Laja and Lucy Heskins, and publish multiple guest columns on growth-related topics including homepage testing, marketing lies to watch out for, VR ad opportunities, company-naming and ad compliance.</p>
<p>TechCrunch is collecting responses <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">in this survey</a> to find the best growth marketer for founders to work with. We’ve included some of our favorites, below the links.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/this-early-stage-marketing-expert-says-b2b-saas-is-actually-very-very-cool-now/?tpcc=ECTW2020">This early-stage marketing expert says ‘B2B SaaS is actually very, very cool now’</a>: Extra Crunch reporter Anna Heim interviews Wales-based growth marketer Lucy Heskins about her experience working with start-ups, how content marketing is best used, and more!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/navigating-ad-fraud-and-consumer-privacy-abuse-in-programmatic-advertising/">Navigating ad fraud and consumer privacy abuse in programmatic advertising</a>: Did you know that “ad fraud exceeded $35 billion last year, a figure expected to rise to $50 billion by 2025”? Jalal Nasir, CEO of marketing compliance startup Pixalate, lends his thoughts about how business leaders and brands can ensure they don’t fall victim to the problem.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/to-stay-ahead-of-your-competitors-start-building-your-narrative-on-day-one/?tpcc=ECTW2020">To stay ahead of your competitors, start building your narrative on day one</a>: Anna also sat down with Peep Laja to discuss the importance of a startup being the one to write their own narrative and how it can mature with the company.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/demand-curve-how-to-double-conversions-on-your-startups-homepage/">Demand Curve: How to double conversions on your startup’s homepage</a>: Head of content Nick Costelloe looks at when it’s good to be unique, and when it’s best to stick to the status quo when working to double conversions on your homepage.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/">(Extra Crunch) Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</a>: For subscribers, Costelloe goes through 10 lies you’ve heard about marketing, and what to try instead to create better results.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/">(Extra Crunch) Can advertising scale in VR?</a>: Have you been on the fence about VR advertising for your company? AR/VR analyst Michael Boland lists out the pros and cons in this article.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/what-i-learned-the-hard-way-from-naming-30-startups/">(Extra Crunch) What I learned the hard way from naming 30+ startups</a>: Naming a start-up might require more thought than you imagined. Marketing executive Drew Beechler takes us through what should be considered when picking out a name, like strategic alignment.</p>
<p>As always, please let us know if you can recommend a top-tier growth marketer who works with startups by <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">filling out this quick survey</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Marketer: </strong>Nikita Vorobyev</p>
<p><strong>Recommender: </strong>Ruby Club</p>
<p><strong>Testimonial:</strong> “Nikita &amp; his company, <a href="https://buildrbrand.com/">Buildrbrand</a>, have worked tirelessly to bring my idea to life and did everything in his power to get it to the level it is today. He &amp; his team created a world-class conditional quiz visual experience that I think would be really cool for him to share with the industry. He doesn&#8217;t know I nominated him, but I definitely wanted to give back to him in any way I can since I believe his agency creates some of the best brands going viral online right now.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer:</strong><a href="https://maxvandeningh.com/"> Max van den Ingh</a>, <a href="https://www.unmuted.com/">Unmuted</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommender:</strong> Harry Willis, <a href="https://www.shoppop.com/">ShopPop</a></p>
<p><strong>Testimonial:</strong> “They [have] shown considerable and demonstrable growth marketing success at various companies. One of them being MisterGreen, a Dutch Tesla-leasing company that had grown 10x under Max’s leadership.”</p>
<p><strong>Marketer:</strong> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pspiller/">Patricia (Patty) Spiller</a>, <a href="https://www.chief.com/">Chief</a></p>
<p><strong>Recommender:</strong> <a href="https://hello.livongo.com/GEN/TLD">Livongo</a></p>
<p><strong>Testimonial:</strong> “Hired her to lead Product Marketing and she identified the opportunity to do growth in a much different way, which could significantly accelerate our company&#8217;s growth. So, she founded the Growth Marketing team and scaled the team from 1 person to 30 people in less than 2 years, based on all the success they had in growing our member base.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/growth-marketing-roundup-cool-saas-marketing-lies-vr-ads-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175813</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: European Union demands $1B penalty from VW, BMW for hiding emissions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/daily-crunch-29/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/daily-crunch-29/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 22:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for July 9, 2021. We’ve made it to Friday, y’all, be proud. But we can’t relax just yet &#8212; there’s quite a lot to get through today. From deceitful auto companies now posing as tech companies to the current venture capital frenzy, we have it all. Let’s go! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/"><strong>Startups have never had it so good:</strong></a><strong> </strong>That’s our read of the Q2 2021 venture capital market. Records were smashed around the world, a record number of unicorns were born and valuations ticked up. If you are a founder considering raising capital, now is probably a good time to do so.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/biden-executive-order-tech-antitrust/"><strong>Biden takes on megacorps:</strong></a><strong> </strong>We jokingly call the public-company section of this newsletter Big Tech because, well, the most famous technology companies are freakin’ massive. And that has a lot of folks worried that some firms have become so large that they should be broken up to engender more competition. Tech companies disagree, naturally. Regardless, the noise from the U.S. government regarding goliath companies is starting to result in action.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/germanys-vc-industry-is-ready-to-take-off-but-bureaucrats-need-to-release-the-handbrake/">What’s ahead for European startups?</a></strong> We usually reserve these three slots for the biggest news of the day, but I wanted to share an essay written by a German venture capitalist about his country. The investor is bullish, but has two ideas regarding where the country could do better: employee stock options and regulations regarding spinoffs. It’s worth reading if you want to consider why some countries wind up with more active startup communities than others.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p><strong>First, key startup news:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/kurly-the-korean-grocery-startup-raises-200m-on-a-2-2b-valuation-after-shifting-ipo-plans-away-from-the-nyse/"><strong>Korean grocery startup Kurly raises $200M:</strong></a> The online grocer is now worth more than $2 billion. Even more, its plans for an IPO in the United States are kaput. Instead, the company will look to list locally in the future. Chop from the Didi mess or something else? Whatever the case, the company is one to keep an eye on.</li>
<li><strong>Today’s Tiger round? </strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/brazilian-hr-startup-flash-raises-22m-in-a-tiger-global-led-series-b-round-of-funding/"><strong>Brazilian HR startup Flash:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The company just put together a $22 million Series B that the hyper-caffeinated venture capital group led. The São Paulo-based startup provides a new way to offer benefits in the country.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/temasek-and-warburg-pincus-invest-500-million-in-ola/"><strong>$500M more for Ola:</strong></a><strong> </strong>The ride-hailing market’s insatiable appetite for capital was fed another half-billion today with news that India’s Ola has raised new funds from “Temasek and an affiliate of Warburg Pincus,” per TechCrunch. Maybe the Didi fiasco is being viewed by investors as a one-off, at least when it comes to the world of on-demand rides.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Second, from the venture capital side of the market:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/the-artemis-fund-focuses-on-women-founders-in-underserved-communities/">TechCrunch’s Ron Miller wrote a profile of The Artemis Fund</a></strong>, which is worth reading. The investing group, which was founded by women and often invests in women, has “ invested in 11 companies with plans to invest in 4-5 more [before raising its] the next fund.”</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/europes-dn-capital-launches-its-new-350m-fund-after-a-knock-out-year-for-its-portfolio/"><strong>DN Capital has raised a $350 million fund</strong></a> after several of the startups that it backed went public. The firm invests mostly in Europe as opposed to the U.K., a market where its partners say more U.S.-based venture capitalists show up.</li>
<li>Three venture capitalists banded together to write up some tips for robotics-focused startups. So, if you are building hardware that moves, <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/5-fundraising-imperatives-for-robotics-startups/">this is for you.</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy’s top priorities as Amazon’s new CEO?</h2>
<p>Now that he&#8217;s stepping away from AWS and taking over for Jeff Bezos, what are the biggest challenges facing incoming Amazon CEO Andy Jassy?</p>
<p>Enterprise reporter Ron Miller reached out to three analysts to get their take:</p>
<ul>
<li>Robin Ody, Canalys</li>
<li>Sucharita Kodali, Forrester</li>
<li>Ed Anderson, Gartner</li>
</ul>
<p>Amazon is listed second in the Fortune 500, but it&#8217;s not all sunshine and roses — maintaining growth, unionization, and the potential for antitrust regulation at home and abroad are just a few of his responsibilities.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think the biggest to-do is to just continue that momentum that the company has had for the last several years.,&#8221; said Kodali. &#8220;He has to make sure that they don’t lose that. If he does that, I mean, he will win.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L9ghl3wcgw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/">3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy&#8217;s top priorities as Amazon&#8217;s new CEO?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy&#8217;s top priorities as Amazon&#8217;s new CEO?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/embed/#?secret=L9ghl3wcgw" data-secret="L9ghl3wcgw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Wrapping up the newsy portion of today’s missive, two final entries. First, a dig into why the EU just fined a number of automakers. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/eu-fines-bmw-vw-1b-for-running-emissions-cartel-since-the-90s/">Rebecca reports</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>As environmental issues really came of age in the 1990s, certain German automakers were meeting in secret groups to make sure their cars would continue to industriously contribute to greenhouse gas emissions. According to the European Union, Volkswagen, Audi, Porsche, BMW and Mercedes-Benz parent company Daimler have been illegally colluding to restrict competition in emission cleaning for new diesel passenger cars, essentially slowing the deployment of cleaner emissions tech.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yes, you can be very mad about that.</p>
<p>Finally, from the world of Facebook, good news for all you WhatsApp users out there. You will be able to select an option to send higher-quality images and videos, getting around <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/whatsapp-is-adding-a-best-quality-setting-for-sending-photos-and-videos/">what TechCrunch called</a> the service’s “iffy image compression.” See, not all news is bad news!</p>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>We’re reaching out to startup founders to tell us who they turn to when they want the most up-to-date growth marketing practices. <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Read one of the recommendations we’ve received below!</p>
<p><strong>Name of marketer: </strong>Nikita Vorobyev</p>
<p><strong>Name of recommender: </strong>Ruby Club</p>
<p><strong>Recommendation: </strong>“Nikita and his company, <a href="https://buildrbrand.com/">Buildrbrand</a>, have worked tirelessly to bring my idea to life and did everything in his power to get it to the level it is today. He and his team created a world-class conditional quiz visual experience that I think would be really cool for him to share with the industry. He doesn&#8217;t know I nominated him, but I definitely wanted to give back to him in any way I can since I believe his agency creates some of the best brands going viral online right now.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/daily-crunch-29/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cloud security platform Netskope boosts valuation to $7.5B following $300M raise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/cloud-security-platform-netskope-boosts-valuation-to-7-5b-following-300m-raise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/cloud-security-platform-netskope-boosts-valuation-to-7-5b-following-300m-raise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 21:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netskope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netskope, focused on Secure Access Service Edge architecture, announced Friday a $300 million investment round on a post-money valuation of $7.5 billion.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.netskope.com/">Netskope</a>, focused on Secure Access Service Edge architecture, announced Friday a $300 million investment round on a post-money valuation of $7.5 billion.</p>
<p>The oversubscribed insider investment was led by ICONIQ Growth, which was joined by other existing investors, including Lightspeed Venture Partners, Accel, Sequoia Capital Global Equities, Base Partners, Sapphire Ventures and Geodesic Capital.</p>
<p>Netskope co-founder and CEO Sanjay Beri told TechCrunch that since its founding in 2012, the company’s mission has been to guide companies through their digital transformation by finding what is most valuable to them — sensitive data — and protecting it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“What we had before in the market didn’t work for that world,” he said. “The theory is that digital transformation is inevitable, so our vision is to transform that market so people could do that, and that is what we are building nearly a decade later.”</p>
<p>With this new round, Netskope continues to rack up large rounds: it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/06/netskope-nabs-340m-on-nearly-3b-valuation-for-cloud-security-platform/">raised $340 million</a> last February, which gave it a valuation of nearly $3 billion. Prior to that, it was a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/13/netskope-raises-168-7m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-its-cloud-security-platform/">$168.7 million round</a> at the end of 2018.</p>
<p>Similar to other rounds, the company was not actively seeking new capital, but that it was “an inside round with people who know everything about us,” Beri said.</p>
<p>“The reality is we could have raised $1 billion, but we don’t need more capital,” he added. “However, having a continued strong balance sheet isn’t a bad thing. We are fortunate to be in that situation, and our destination is to be the most impactful cybersecurity company in the world.</p>
<p>Beri said the company just completed a “three-year journey building the largest cloud network that is 15 milliseconds from anyone in the world,” and intends to invest the new funds into continued R&amp;D, expanding its platform and Netskope’s go-to-market strategy to meet demand for a market it estimated would be valued at $30 billion by 2024, he said.</p>
<p>Even pre-pandemic the company had strong hypergrowth over the past year, surpassing the market average annual growth of 50%, he added.</p>
<p>Today’s investment brings the total raised by Santa Clara-based Netskope to just over $1 billion, according to Crunchbase <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/netskope">data</a>.</p>
<p>With the company racking up that kind of capital, the next natural step would be to become a public company. Beri admits that Netskope could be public now, though it doesn’t have to do it for the traditional reasons of raising capital or marketing.</p>
<p>“Going public is one day on our path, but you probably won’t see us raise another private round,” Beri said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="C2xxMS27Sn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/">To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/embed/#?secret=C2xxMS27Sn" data-secret="C2xxMS27Sn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eJwkjgCAvh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/06/netskope-nabs-340m-on-nearly-3b-valuation-for-cloud-security-platform/">Netskope hauls in another $340M investment on nearly $3B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Netskope hauls in another $340M investment on nearly $3B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/06/netskope-nabs-340m-on-nearly-3b-valuation-for-cloud-security-platform/embed/#?secret=eJwkjgCAvh" data-secret="eJwkjgCAvh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/cloud-security-platform-netskope-boosts-valuation-to-7-5b-following-300m-raise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175804</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is the US labor shortage the big break AI needs?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/is-the-us-labor-shortage-the-big-break-ai-needs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/is-the-us-labor-shortage-the-big-break-ai-needs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural language processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supply chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unemployment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2171794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Misconceptions about AI in the workplace have long been a barrier to widespread adoption — but companies experiencing labor shortages should consider where it can make their employees' lives better.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Chetan Dube</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ipsoft">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chetan-dube-13315940">Chetan Dube</a> is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://amelia.com/">Amelia</a>, a former assistant professor at New York University and an expert on autonomics, cognitive computing and the future impact of a digital workforce.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">The tectonic shifts to American culture and society due to the pandemic are far from over. One of the more glaring ones is that the U.S. labor market is going absolutely haywire.</p>
<p>Millions are unemployed, yet companies — from retail to customer service to airlines — can’t find enough workers. This perplexing paradox behind <a href="https://www.curbed.com/2021/06/uber-lyft-expensive-new-york-city.html">Uber price surges</a> and waiting on an endless hold because your flight was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/06/20/business/american-airlines-flights-canceled-labor-shortages/index.html">canceled</a> isn’t just inconvenient &#8212; it’s a loud and clear message from the post-pandemic American workforce. Many are underpaid, undervalued and underwhelmed in their current jobs, and are willing to change careers or walk away from certain types of work for good.</p>
<p>It’s worth noting that low-wage workers aren’t the only ones putting their foot down; white-collar quits are also at an <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/06/quitting-your-job-economic-optimism/619242/">all-time high</a>. Extended unemployment benefits implemented during the pandemic may be keeping some workers on the sidelines, but employee burnout and job dissatisfaction are also primary culprits.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We have a wage problem and an employee satisfaction problem, and Congress has a long summer ahead of it to attempt to find a solution. But what are companies supposed to do in the meantime?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Adopting AI in manufacturing accelerated during the pandemic to deal with volatility in the supply chain, but now it must move from “pilot purgatory” to widespread implementation.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>At this particular moment, businesses need a stopgap solution either until September, when COVID-19 relief and unemployment benefits are earmarked to expire, or something longer term and more durable that not only keeps the engine running but propels the ship forward. Adopting AI can be the key to both.</p>
<p>Declaring that we’re on the precipice of an AI awakening is probably nowhere near the most shocking thing you’ve read this year. But just a few short years ago, it would have frightened a vast number of people, as advances in automation and AI began to transform from a distant idea into a very personal reality. People were (and some holdouts remain) genuinely worried about losing their job, their lifeline, with visions of robots and virtual agents taking over.</p>
<p>But does this &#8220;AI takes jobs&#8221; storyline hold up in the cultural and economic moment we&#8217;re in?</p>
<h2>Is AI really taking jobs if no one actually likes those jobs?</h2>
<p>If this &#8220;labor shortage&#8221; unveils any silver lining, it&#8217;s our real-world version of the <a href="https://harrypotter.fandom.com/wiki/Sorting_Hat">Sorting Hat</a>. When you take money out of the equation on the question of employment, it&#8217;s opening our eyes to what work people find desirable and, more evidently, what’s <em>not</em>. Specifically, the manufacturing, retail and service industries are taking the <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/labor-shortage-manufacturing-retail-transportation-51623247411">hardest</a> labor hits, underscoring that tasks associated with those jobs — repetitive duties, unrewarding customer service tasks and physical labor — are driving more and more potential workers away.</p>
<p>Adopting AI in manufacturing accelerated during the pandemic to deal with volatility in the supply chain, but now it must move from “<a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/ai-machine-learning/research-on-ai-trends-in-manufacturing">pilot purgatory</a>” to widespread implementation. The best use cases for AI in this industry are ones that help with supply chain optimization, including quality inspection, general supply chain management and risk/inventory management.</p>
<p>Most critically, AI can predict when equipment might fail or break, reducing costs and downtime to almost zero. Industry leaders believe that AI is not only beneficial for business continuity but that it can <em>augment </em>the work and efficiency of existing employees rather than displace them. AI can assist employees by providing real-time guidance and training, flagging safety hazards, and freeing them up to do less repetitive, low-skilled work by taking on such tasks itself, such as detecting potential assembly line defects.</p>
<p>In the manufacturing industry, this current labor shortage is not a new phenomenon. The industry has been facing a perception <a href="https://www.industryweek.com/leadership/article/22026565/manufacturing-has-a-serious-image-problem">problem</a> in the U.S. for a long time, mainly because young workers think manufacturers are “low tech” and low paying. AI can make existing jobs more attractive and directly lead to a better bottom line while also creating new roles for companies that attract subject-matter talent and expertise.</p>
<p>In the retail and service industries, arduous customer service tasks and low pay are <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/retail-workers-leaving-quit-over-nightmare-customers-low-pay-2021-5">leading</a> many employees to walk out the door. Those that are still sticking it out have their hands tied because of their benefits, even though they are <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/retail-workers-leaving-quit-over-nightmare-customers-low-pay-2021-5">unhappy</a> with the work. Conversational AI, which is AI that can interact with people in a human-like manner by leveraging natural language processing and machine learning, can relieve employees of many of the more monotonous customer experience interactions so they can take on roles focused on elevating retail and service brands with more cerebral, thoughtful human input.</p>
<p>Many retail and service companies adopted scripted chatbots during the pandemic to help with the large online volumes only to realize that chatbots operate on a fixed decision tree — meaning if you ask something out of context, the whole customer service process breaks down. Advanced conversational AI technologies are modeled on the human brain. They even learn as they go, getting more skilled over time, presenting a solution that saves retail and service employees from the mundane while boosting customer satisfaction and revenue.</p>
<p>Hesitancy and misconceptions about AI in the workplace have long been a barrier to widespread adoption — but companies experiencing labor shortages should consider where it can make their employees&#8217; lives better and easier, which can only be a benefit for bottom-line growth. And it might just be the big break that AI needs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QlrxiAyfC5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/deep-science-keeping-ai-honest-in-medicine-climate-science-and-vision/">Deep Science: Keeping AI honest in medicine, climate science and vision</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deep Science: Keeping AI honest in medicine, climate science and vision&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/25/deep-science-keeping-ai-honest-in-medicine-climate-science-and-vision/embed/#?secret=QlrxiAyfC5" data-secret="QlrxiAyfC5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/is-the-us-labor-shortage-the-big-break-ai-needs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2171794</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extra Crunch roundup: NS1 EC-1, Pakistan&#8217;s tech ecosystem, SPACs bonanza</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/extra-crunch-roundup-ns1-ec-1-pakistans-tech-ecosystem-spacs-bonanza/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/extra-crunch-roundup-ns1-ec-1-pakistans-tech-ecosystem-spacs-bonanza/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 19:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alex wilhelm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief data officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lux capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MassRobotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special-purpose acquisition company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wavemaker partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just like NYC's flooded subway system, internet infrastructure doesn't attract much attention until there's a notable failure.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Did you see the viral videos of yesterday&#8217;s flooding in New York City subways?</p>
<p>In one, riders waded through brown, waist-deep water; another video showed a cascade rushing down a flight of stairs to a subway platform where passengers waited for a train.</p>
<p>Infrastructure doesn&#8217;t attract much attention until it fails. Domain name services (DNS), the system that directs readers to techcrunch.com when they say or speak it into their web browser, are much the same way.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>For the latest entry in a series of longform articles that explore the inner workings of notable startups, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/">we looked at NS1</a>, an internet infrastructure company best known for its software-defined DNS.</p>
<p>Since its founding in 2013, NS1 has raised more than $100 million to build an engineering team and robust product portfolio that&#8217;s expanded to include DDI, which helps companies manage internal networks.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how NS1 transformed &#8220;a slumbering and dreary yet reliable aspect of the internet&#8221; into &#8220;a strategic moat and an enterprise win&#8221; in just eight years, read on.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full Extra Crunch articles are only available to members.<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>ECFriday</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription.</i></p>
<hr />
<p>Part 1: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/">Origin story</a>: how three engineers decided to rebuild the internet&#8217;s core addressing system.</p>
<p>Part 2: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-product/">Product development and roadmap</a>: experimentation, open-source efforts and expanding beyond DNS.</p>
<p>Part 3: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-competition/">Competitive landscape</a>: a look at the broader internet infrastructure market.</p>
<p>Part 4: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-customers/">Customer development</a>: how their top competitor&#8217;s stumble became &#8220;the gift that kept on giving.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thanks very much for reading Extra Crunch — have a great weekend!</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Senior Editor, TechCrunch<br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/yourprotagonist">@yourprotagonist</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qlnqGjfOAW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/">The NS1 EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NS1 EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/embed/#?secret=qlnqGjfOAW" data-secret="qlnqGjfOAW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Startups have never had it so good</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996010" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996010" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996010" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3-ORNG.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996010" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim didn&#8217;t mince words in today&#8217;s Exchange.</p>
<p>&#8220;The venture capital market is racing ahead, foot on the gas, middle finger out the window, hair on fire.&#8221;</p>
<p>That&#8217;s their hot take after analyzing the Q2 data released so far about how much money VCs deployed across the globe between April and the end of June.</p>
<p>Leaning on data from CB Insights, Crunchbase News and FactSet, Alex and Anna walk through the data from the U.S. and a few other regions &#8212; and promise deeper regional dives next week.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nNgwGfEz6N"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/">Startups have never had it so good</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startups have never had it so good&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/embed/#?secret=nNgwGfEz6N" data-secret="nNgwGfEz6N" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>What I learned the hard way from naming 30+ startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2173980" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2173980" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2173980" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1149872763-e1625595735846.jpg" alt="Image of a pink toy dinosaur holding a name tag on a yellow background." width="1024" height="672" /><p id="caption-attachment-2173980" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Juj+Winn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Juj Winn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>If you’re starting a company, choosing a name can feel like a fraught choice. But actually, as long as you follow some basic guidelines, it shouldn’t lead to paralysis.</p>
<p>“The truth is that business names fall on a bell curve — you have a small number of outliers that actively contribute to your success and a small number of outliers that actively impair your ability to succeed,” Drew Beechler, who’s named more than 30 software startups, writes in a guest column. “The vast majority, though, fall somewhere in the middle in their impact on your business.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="39uBdskXiF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/what-i-learned-the-hard-way-from-naming-30-startups/">What I learned the hard way from naming 30+ startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What I learned the hard way from naming 30+ startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/what-i-learned-the-hard-way-from-naming-30-startups/embed/#?secret=39uBdskXiF" data-secret="39uBdskXiF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Nextdoor’s SPAC investor deck paints a picture of sizable scale and sticky users</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1964701" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1964701" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1964701" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg" alt="American Suburban Neighborhood Tilt-shift Aerial Photo" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-1042569440-bw.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1964701" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong>jhorrocks / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>The SPAC parade continued apace this week as Nextdoor announced it would go public via a blank-check company, with the community social network making its pitch based on scale, claiming users in one in three U.S. households.</p>
<p>Alex Wilhelm u<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">npacks Nextdoor’s “clear-eyed look into [its] financial performance in both historical terms and in terms of what it might accomplish in the future,” noting that “our usual mockery of SPAC charts mostly doesn’t apply.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kCbr56gWVM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/nextdoors-spac-investor-deck-paints-a-picture-of-sizable-scale-and-sticky-users/">Nextdoor&#8217;s SPAC investor deck paints a picture of sizable scale and sticky users</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nextdoor&#8217;s SPAC investor deck paints a picture of sizable scale and sticky users&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/nextdoors-spac-investor-deck-paints-a-picture-of-sizable-scale-and-sticky-users/embed/#?secret=kCbr56gWVM" data-secret="kCbr56gWVM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Pakistan’s growing tech ecosystem is finally taking off</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2174588" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174588" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2174588" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg" alt="Image of the Karachi, Pakistan, skyline." width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-977612988.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174588" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits: </strong><a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=shan.shihan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shan.shihan <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a>/ Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>So far this year, startups in Pakistan are on track to raise more than in the previous five years combined, according to Mikal Khoso, an early-stage investor at Wavemaker Partners.</p>
<p>&#8220;Even more excitingly, a large portion of this capital is coming from international investors from across Asia, the Middle East and even famed investors from Silicon Valley,&#8221; he notes in a guest post for Extra Crunch.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s identified three factors that are fueling investor interest: rapidly expanding mobile connectivity, an improved security situation, and critical legal and regulatory changes that are making the country more startup- and VC-friendly.</p>
<p>Drawing a map of Pakistan&#8217;s tech ecosystem, Khoso identifies local companies trying to grab a slice of grocery delivery, e-commerce, ride-hailing and other sectors before examining the challenges still in place.</p>
<p>&#8220;The segments in Pakistan that are likely to attract the best entrepreneurs and most investor capital in the years to come will be fintech, e-commerce and edtech,&#8221; says Khoso.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CFov7TJj2e"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/pakistans-growing-tech-ecosystem-is-finally-taking-off/">Pakistan&#8217;s growing tech ecosystem is finally taking off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pakistan&#8217;s growing tech ecosystem is finally taking off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/pakistans-growing-tech-ecosystem-is-finally-taking-off/embed/#?secret=CFov7TJj2e" data-secret="CFov7TJj2e" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Investors find European unicorns reluctant to join SPAC boom</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996007" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996007" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996007" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_RD.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The nonstop news of startups partnering up with SPACs in the United States had Alex Wilhelm and Anna Heim wondering if the blank-check boom expanded to other countries.</p>
<p>“Unicorns are hardly unique to the U.S. startup ecosystem,” they write. “Are we seeing similar SPAC interest in Europe?”</p>
<p>Anna and Alex talked to investors to see why &#8212; or why not &#8212; European startups would take the SPAC path to become a public company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UH7EArvet0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/investors-find-european-unicorns-reluctant-to-join-spac-boom/">Investors find European unicorns reluctant to join SPAC boom</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors find European unicorns reluctant to join SPAC boom&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/investors-find-european-unicorns-reluctant-to-join-spac-boom/embed/#?secret=UH7EArvet0" data-secret="UH7EArvet0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>For successful AI projects, celebrate your graveyard and be prepared to fail fast</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2174133" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174133" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2174133" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg" alt="Image of an origami crane and several crumpled pieces of paper to represent success from failure." width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg 4608w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-677910608.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174133" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Wachiwit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wachiwit <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>When you’ve invested a lot of time and energy in a project, it can be difficult to decide to shelve it &#8212; or worse, kill it.</p>
<p>But for AI projects, teams should be prepared to fail fast, Sandeep Uttamchandani, the chief data officer of Unravel Data, writes in a guest column.</p>
<p>“In order to fail fast, AI initiatives should be managed as a conversion funnel analogous to marketing and sales funnels,” he writes. “Projects start at the top of the five-stage funnel and can drop off at any stage, either to be temporarily put on ice or permanently suspended and added to the AI graveyard.”</p>
<p>Uttamchandani walks through the five stages of the funnel and offers suggestions for when to start digging a hole for your project in the graveyard.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VyzWcBac8o"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/for-successful-ai-projects-celebrate-your-graveyard-and-be-prepared-to-fail-fast/">For successful AI projects, celebrate your graveyard and be prepared to fail fast</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;For successful AI projects, celebrate your graveyard and be prepared to fail fast&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/for-successful-ai-projects-celebrate-your-graveyard-and-be-prepared-to-fail-fast/embed/#?secret=VyzWcBac8o" data-secret="VyzWcBac8o" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Circle is a good example of why SPACs can be useful</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1996006" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1996006" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1996006" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg 2880w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/NSussman_Techcrunch_Exchange_v3_GRY.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1996006" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.nigelsussman.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nigel Sussman <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Yes, we’re all a bit over-SPAC-ed at this point. It’s just been a nonstop torrent of startups linking up with blank-check companies.</p>
<p>But Circle, a Boston-based technology company that provides API-delivered financial services and a stablecoin, is just “the sort of business that is correct for a SPAC-led debut,” Alex Wilhelm writes in The Exchange.</p>
<p>“It could not go public in a traditional manner in its current state of maturity,” he writes.</p>
<p>“But a SPAC can get it a huge slug of cash at a price that it has locked in, allowing it to complete its growth into corporate adulthood while public. A gamble, sure, but one that will be very fun to watch.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N6JXmwvsZi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/circle-is-a-good-example-of-why-spacs-can-be-useful/">Circle is a good example of why SPACs can be useful</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Circle is a good example of why SPACs can be useful&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/circle-is-a-good-example-of-why-spacs-can-be-useful/embed/#?secret=N6JXmwvsZi" data-secret="N6JXmwvsZi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Can advertising scale in VR?</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2175202" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175202" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175202" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg" alt="Image of a person wearing a VR headset and two 3D orbs in front of his hands." width="1024" height="658" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg 7952w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg?resize=150,96 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg?resize=300,193 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg?resize=768,493 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg?resize=680,437 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg?resize=1536,986 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg?resize=2048,1315 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1187160851.jpg?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175202" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=da-kuk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">da-kuk <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>It’s not hard to imagine how advertising could be valuable in VR: billboards on streetscapes, magazine covers on newsstands, cereal boxes in virtual kitchens.</p>
<p>But Facebook’s stab at experimental VR ads didn’t last very long; after an onslaught of negative feedback from players, the test was quickly scuttled.</p>
<p>That said, VR advertising has a ton of untapped potential — but it’s going to take a minute to reach profitable scale.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SePhDOnOHd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/">Can advertising scale in VR?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Can advertising scale in VR?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/embed/#?secret=SePhDOnOHd" data-secret="SePhDOnOHd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Achieving digital transformation through RPA and process mining</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2175241" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175241" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175241" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg" alt="concept of machine learning or digital transformation, wireframe hand pointing with key finger" width="1024" height="640" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg 2190w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg?resize=2048,1280 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1282119894.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175241" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Jackie+Niam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jackie Niam <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>“Robots are not coming to replace us,” Alp Uguray is quick to note in a guest column about robotic process automation. “They are coming to take over the repetitive, mundane and monotonous tasks that we’ve never been fond of.”</p>
<p>That’s the good news. But RPA is still in the early stages, despite rapid growth through IPOs, acquisitions and funding rounds.</p>
<p>“Adoption of RPA and process mining in your organization will define the operational excellence of your firm,” he writes. “If you are behind in this race, just think of how your enterprise can continue to compete with fully digital peers. Your organization won’t want to be in the back of this race.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WDkMn9REud"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/achieving-digital-transformation-through-rpa-and-process-mining/">Achieving digital transformation through RPA and process mining</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Achieving digital transformation through RPA and process mining&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/achieving-digital-transformation-through-rpa-and-process-mining/embed/#?secret=WDkMn9REud" data-secret="WDkMn9REud" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2174760" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174760" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2174760" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg" alt="Image of an advertiser speaking in front of a podium with a shadow of a long nose to represent lies." width="1024" height="740" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg 5535w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg?resize=150,108 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg?resize=300,217 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg?resize=768,555 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg?resize=680,491 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg?resize=1536,1110 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg?resize=2048,1480 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-1206146301.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174760" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Abscent84" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Abscent84 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>In a guest column, Nick Costelloe, the head of content for Demand Curve, notes that the content you stumble across in a Google search might not be “intentionally misleading,” it might not lead you in the right direction.</p>
<p>Here, he debunks 10 common myths about marketing &#8212; and offers suggestions for what to do instead.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mcbEvgyr03"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/">Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/embed/#?secret=mcbEvgyr03" data-secret="mcbEvgyr03" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>5 fundraising imperatives for robotics startups</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2175288" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175288" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175288" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg" alt="Image of a robot hand holding a fistful of cash to represent funding for robotics startups." width="1024" height="724" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg 4961w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?resize=300,212 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?resize=768,543 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?resize=680,481 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?resize=1536,1086 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?resize=2048,1448 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175288" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=Paper+Boat+Creative" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paper Boat Creative <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>This guest post from three contributors from Next47, MassRobotics and Lux Capital looks at best practices for robotics startups looking to raise cash.</p>
<p>&#8220;There has never been a better time to pursue funding for robotics startups, but you are more likely to succeed if you build a fundraising strategy that is marked by the same sophistication and informed understanding you already bring to many other aspects of your new business,&#8221; the writers say.</p>
<p>Here, they lay out five strategies to ensure robotics startups get the funding they need.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WVXF55AjMw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/5-fundraising-imperatives-for-robotics-startups/">5 fundraising imperatives for robotics startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 fundraising imperatives for robotics startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/5-fundraising-imperatives-for-robotics-startups/embed/#?secret=WVXF55AjMw" data-secret="WVXF55AjMw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/extra-crunch-roundup-ns1-ec-1-pakistans-tech-ecosystem-spacs-bonanza/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175411</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This early-stage marketing expert says &#8216;B2B SaaS is actually very, very cool now&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/this-early-stage-marketing-expert-says-b2b-saas-is-actually-very-very-cool-now/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/this-early-stage-marketing-expert-says-b2b-saas-is-actually-very-very-cool-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 19:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b saas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucy Heskins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["There’s a bias for wanting to use what worked previously, but people forget … your customers and markets are totally different. You can’t just replicate."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Doing more with less: This is what marketers get asked for when they join an early-stage startup. British consultant <a href="https://twitter.com/lucy_heskins">Lucy Heskins</a> knows firsthand how overwhelming that can be, which is why her services can both replace and complement early in-house marketing staff. Either way, it often involves educating the founders about the job to be done.</p>
<p>&#8220;Too many people fail to realize that marketing is the process of understanding your customers, building appropriate channels to reach them and ultimately meeting their needs (profitability),&#8221; she wrote on her site, <a href="https://www.ohblimey.com/">Oh, blimey</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>TechCrunch is asking founders who have worked with growth marketers to share a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this survey</a>. We’ll use your answers to find more experts to interview.</em></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Having earned &#8220;scars and stripes&#8221; at various startups, Heskins recently joined &#8220;tech for good&#8221; company Big Lemon as a part-time head of growth, but still offers her services to other teams as a SaaS and early-stage startup marketing consultant. If you are a marketer yourself or thinking of hiring one, read on: She shared some compelling insights with TechCrunch.</p>
<p><em>(This interview has been edited for length and clarity.)</em></p>
<p><strong>How do you collaborate with the startups you work with as a consultant?</strong></p>
<p>Typically I will work with startups in two ways. The first will be project-based. So for example, when they want to explore a potential new customer market or introduce a freemium strategy.</p>
<p>The other way is as a mentor or extension to their marketer. Often I will work with marketers who’ve never worked in a startup and they can bounce ideas or strategies off me. It helps speed up their learning and time to deliver results.</p>
<p><strong>How do your roles as an employee and as a consultant nourish each other?</strong></p>
<p>I’ve experienced the very real pains/challenges/opportunities a startup presents, especially as an early-stage employee. I’ve come in, helped change business models, explored things like freemium and repositioned brands. It’s tough. So as a consultant, I can pass on my learnings (and mistakes). And I get to work with some great startups who are open to trying new things. Plus, having worked in four startups now, I <em>get</em> the pressure they’re facing and can adjust my approach accordingly. There’s a lot of plates spinning, and I get that.</p>
<p><strong>What do early-stage startups typically misunderstand and need to know about startup marketers like you?</strong></p>
<p>In my experience, there are a few mistakes startups often make.</p>
<p>The first is hiring a marketer too soon. I’ve come into startups, thinking I was coming in to set up their in-house function. However, very quickly you realize that they’ve jumped the gun and think they’ve got product-market fit when they are nowhere near it. This can cause conflict because the startup’s expecting one thing (say, revenue) but the marketer is missing a few basics to be effective (value proposition, an idea of how &#8220;painful&#8221; the problem is that they are solving, lack of involvement in areas like pricing).</p>
<p>The next mistake is not trusting their marketer. All too often I hear of marketers who’ve gone into a startup only to learn that their ideas are put on the back burner because the founder(s) &#8212; and this is typically first-time founders &#8212; don’t quite understand marketing and will push them to deliver short-term results (leads).</p>
<p>Lastly and probably the biggest mistake is applying what worked at a previous business. When joining a startup, you’re starting from scratch &#8212; new customers, new markets, go-to-market strategy. There’s a bias for wanting to use what worked previously, but people forget … your customers and markets are totally different. You can’t just replicate.</p>
<p><strong>What should be the main focus of a startup&#8217;s first in-house marketer?</strong></p>
<p>Of course, it depends really on the stage of the startup; however, whatever stage you’re at, it needs to be customer research/development. I’d be very wary of a marketer who doesn’t suggest this as one of their first activities.</p>
<p>You need to unlock why customers buy or subscribe to the startup’s product. This will determine your traction channels, your proposition, your pricing model &#8212; everything.</p>
<p><strong>Why should startups consider hiring a freelancer or agency to help with their marketing instead of doing everything in-house?</strong></p>
<p>I think it’s a great idea to outsource until the startup understands (1) if there’s an actual problem that needs solving and (2) whether there’s a market big enough to actually turn it into a business.</p>
<p>Whilst you’re in this period, you can’t afford to learn new skills &#8212; even though it may seem attractive/&#8221;cheap&#8221; to do it in-house, it really isn’t. It can actually set you back. Outsource the specifics and focus on what you do best. Once you’ve got a better idea of validation, then you can start to see which skills to bring in-house.</p>
<hr />
<p><em>Have you worked with a talented individual or agency who helped you find and keep more users?</em></p>
<p><em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/help-techcrunch-find-the-best-growth-marketers-for-startups/">Respond to our survey</a> and help us find the best startup growth marketers!</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Why have you decided to focus on SaaS startups? What makes them different when it comes to marketing?</strong></p>
<p>I love working in SaaS, especially B2B SaaS. What makes it different, for me, is that the role becomes part marketing, part product, part commercial. You get to look at the entire customer experience, and because many SaaS products are trial/subscription-based, your focus needs to be on retention. You’re only as good as your last month, so it forces you to work and think harder.</p>
<p>Plus, B2B SaaS is actually very, very cool now. Just because you work in B2B marketing doesn’t mean you need to be boring!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1eM3RGPmM4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/freemium-isnt-a-trend-its-the-future-of-saas/">Freemium isn’t a trend &#8212; it’s the future of SaaS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Freemium isn’t a trend &#8212; it’s the future of SaaS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/06/freemium-isnt-a-trend-its-the-future-of-saas/embed/#?secret=1eM3RGPmM4" data-secret="1eM3RGPmM4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>What are some key takeaways from your <a href="https://www.ohblimey.com/the-early-stage-startup-marketing-playbook">Early-Stage Startup Marketing Playbook</a>?</strong></p>
<p>I created the playbook because I sat in a board meeting and, when an investor was asking about the go-to-market strategy, I realized that there wasn’t a clear toolkit for helping early-stage startups to map out the market, nor think about the steps leading up to launching a product.</p>
<p>There are many takeaways, but I think the main one and the most valuable is providing clarity as to what specific steps go into a go-to-market strategy and how it all works together.</p>
<p>I talk you through how to speak to the customers who’ll actually buy from you &#8212; not those who tell you they love your product but run a mile when it’s time to pay &#8212; and how to determine which market channel is best to reach them.</p>
<p><strong>What is customer-led growth? And how can it help startups adapt post-COVID?</strong></p>
<p>Customer-led growth is a strategy that combines product, marketing and sales. It views your product through the lens of a customer with the aim of working out how value is delivered to them &#8220;whenever, wherever and however they need it.&#8221; It’s something I learned and studied from the co-founders of <a href="https://forgetthefunnel.com/">Forget the Funnel</a>.</p>
<p>The idea is that you look at the entire customer journey, from the struggle stage right through to when they’re a customer, and you break each section down to where there’s an opportunity for growth. It’s really helpful for startups &#8212; especially post-COVID because chances are, your customers’ needs have changed.</p>
<p>How your customers derive value from your product changes all the time. This framework gives you a starting point.</p>
<p><strong>How is content marketing best used?</strong></p>
<p>I often say to startups, stop creating content for the sake of it. A lot of content that’s created doesn’t allow for where your customer may be in the buying process. It doesn’t consider what’s motivating them to solve their problem.</p>
<p>As a result, the results you get are skewed. Things take much longer than they should. Customers get confused about what it is your business actually is/does. Everyone starts to lose respect for marketing.</p>
<p>Again, you need to take it back to the customer and their journey and identify what content they need to overcome that particular problem that’s getting in the way of signing up/using your product.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RWTL5ZwZCj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/we-throw-away-80-of-our-content-ideas-and-you-should-too/">We throw away 80% of our content ideas, and you should too</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;We throw away 80% of our content ideas, and you should too&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/27/we-throw-away-80-of-our-content-ideas-and-you-should-too/embed/#?secret=RWTL5ZwZCj" data-secret="RWTL5ZwZCj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Why is alignment with sales important, and what does it involve?</strong></p>
<p>I’ve worked in startups that have been sales-led (so, complex products, long lead time) and it’s important to understand what sales needs to uncover to help move a customer to the next stage. Likewise, marketing can help sales to really dig into the proposition and understand what channels are best to convert leads.</p>
<p>I think when you work in a startup as a marketer, you have to roll up your sleeves and get involved in sales. It’ll help improve the content, strategy and revenue in the end.</p>
<p>So if you are working with a salesperson whose ultimate aim is to secure a call with a prospect, you can’t just go in and expect a prospect to say yes, immediately. There are a series of steps you and the salesperson need to go through in order to nurture and open up this relationship. It’s all about proving a set of hypotheses about your customer. Do they really hang out on LinkedIn? Are they bombarded with companies offering the same? Which proposition is working enough to get someone to agree to a call? Is that calendar link putting off prospects altogether?</p>
<p>I truly believe people do love to help, but it’s about working out what’s in it for them and how your product will make their life just that little bit easier.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/this-early-stage-marketing-expert-says-b2b-saas-is-actually-very-very-cool-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175292</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Despite the hype, construction tech will be hard to disrupt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/despite-the-hype-construction-tech-will-be-hard-to-disrupt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/despite-the-hype-construction-tech-will-be-hard-to-disrupt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 18:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[construction software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Real Estate and Proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katerra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[project management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research and development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Construction technology users are more like general consumers. This means the technology ideally must be easy to use on the first try and adaptable to a wide variety of job site protocols.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">David Ward</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/davidbrianward">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		David Ward is a 30-year tech industry veteran, entrepreneur and the CEO and founder of <a href="https://safesitecheckin.com/">Safe Site Check In</a>. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">From the outside looking in, the construction industry appears ripe for tech innovation. The industry represents <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/226361/us-construction-spending-relative-to-gdp/">6.3%</a> of the U.S. GDP. There are close to 1 million general contractors (GCs) in the country, and anywhere between 3 million and 5 million workers on job sites every day.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there’s a common (if somewhat justified) belief that construction firms are slow to adopt technology and are behind the digital curve.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Success in construction tech will come down to proving the need for the technology, delivering immediate ROI, and ensuring workers know how to use it on the first try.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>But not every construction company is a technology laggard. While GCs are historically slower to adopt new technologies, this doesn’t necessarily make them behind the times. About 60% of construction companies have R&amp;D departments for new technology, and the largest construction firms have substantial R&amp;D budgets. Yet 35.9% of employees are hesitant to try new technology, according to JB Knowledge.</p>
<p>One way to interpret this is that there is a strong interest and need to take advantage of newer construction-centric technologies, but only if they’re easy to use, easy to deploy or access while on a job site, and improve productivity almost immediately.</p>
<p>These factors have made construction tech appealing to investors, who have poured <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/16/investor-momentum-builds-for-construction-tech/">at least $3 billion</a> into the sector. Is construction tech the “it” place right now? Is it ripe for disruption, the way VC investors find attractive? If that’s true, what went <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/softbank-backed-construction-giant-katerra-said-to-be-shutting-down-after-raising-billions/">wrong at Katerra</a>? Is Procore justified in <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/construction-tech-unicorn-procore-drops-s-1-revealing-sharply-rising-revenue-net-losses/">losing</a> $1 for every $4 in revenue? And why does so little investment go into improving productivity at the job site where GC money is made &#8212; or lost &#8212; compared to back-office operations?</p>
<p>My experience to date says that construction is different from other sectors because of the significant variation among projects that originates in the way projects are financed, how risks are managed and the factors that drive variation among projects. Construction’s differences are not easily mitigated via data processing, as compared to fintech, for example, where all money is data-amenable to software processing. Addressing project variations will be key to succeeding in construction tech beyond the back office. Here are the critical factors to consider.</p>
<p><strong>Project financing makes capital investment more difficult. </strong>While the Commerce Department reported that construction spending in the U.S. reached a record high of $1.459 trillion in November 2020, this doesn’t mean there are unlimited opportunities for construction tech. The reality is that GCs make few capital investments because they must fund investments in technology out of operating cash flow.</p>
<p>Construction projects are typically funded incrementally in phases as the project demonstrates progress. Delays or accidents can have a huge effect on cash flow. Overhead and G&amp;A cost burdens are hated. Asking a GC to license technology as a capital purchase doesn’t always make sense.</p>
<p><strong>GC ownership and business structure also make large capital investment more difficult.</strong> Most GC firms were founded by tradespeople and either started as, or remain, family-owned firms. Borrowing what’s considered the “family’s money” is a much more risk-averse decision compared to the way larger corporations evaluate productivity investments and put assets at risk.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/despite-the-hype-construction-tech-will-be-hard-to-disrupt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175295</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This startup just created a fast, accurate COVID test that only needs saliva and links to an app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/this-startup-just-created-a-fast-accurate-covid-test-which-only-needs-saliva-and-links-to-an-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/this-startup-just-created-a-fast-accurate-covid-test-which-only-needs-saliva-and-links-to-an-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 18:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotechnology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hoxton Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julia Hawkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knownow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oxford university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Kniaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re entering a phase in the COVID-19 pandemic where transmission is going to go through the roof because of the Delta variant. But as vaccinations ramp up around the world, the main cost to society now will not be the health services being overwhelmed, but mass disruption to businesses as staff are forced to self [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">We&#8217;re entering a phase in the COVID-19 pandemic where transmission is going to go through the roof because of the Delta variant. But as vaccinations ramp up around the world, the main cost to society now will not be the health services being overwhelmed, but mass disruption to businesses as staff are forced to self isolate by track and trace systems. Thus, biosecurity in the workplace (or any other setting for that matter) is going to matter a lot.</p>
<p>The paragraph you just read above is in fact a paraphrase <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(21)01589-0/fulltext?s=08">of the recent open letter</a> sent by a number of eminent UK scientists to the government about the next phase of the pandemic.</p>
<p>So if it’s the case that workplace biosecurity is going to have to be much more efficient, then faster, better forms of testing are going to be needed. Now, a UK startup thinks it may have cracked the problem.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Bio-security company <a href="https://www.knownow.com/">Vatic</a> has come up with its &#8216;KnowNow&#8217; test for CoVID-19 which it claims is more accurate than lateral flow tests, is faster, easier (only a swab from your mouth is needed), allows test data sharing, and even produces a ‘Passport’ QR code to enable someone to access services or workplaces.</p>
<p>Vatic has now raised $6.37 million to deliver its at-home tests, starting with the one tailored to COVID-19.</p>
<p>The seed funding round was led by London-based VCs LocalGlobe and Hoxton Ventures.</p>
<p>Founded in 2019, Vatic has built a saliva-based test that is about generating data in the home. The company says the test takes fewer than 15 minutes and can identify people who are actually infectious at that moment, rather than get a false positive because the body has fought off the infection. Existing antigen tests can have a false positive rate of 1 in 200.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175732" style="width: 943px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175732" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Vatic-1.jpg" alt="Vatic test" width="933" height="1206" class="size-full wp-image-2175732" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Vatic-1.jpg 933w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Vatic-1.jpg?resize=116,150 116w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Vatic-1.jpg?resize=232,300 232w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Vatic-1.jpg?resize=768,993 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Vatic-1.jpg?resize=526,680 526w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Vatic-1.jpg?resize=39,50 39w" sizes="(max-width: 933px) 100vw, 933px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175732" class="wp-caption-text">Vatic test</p></div></p>
<p>The company says its test identifies infectious viruses by mimicking the surface of a human cell, effectively redesigning how lateral flow tests are built and “enhancing their accuracy”.</p>
<p>Its KnowNow saliva-only rapid antigen test for COVID-19 is in fact now being used in the UK after receiving CE mark approval. It pairs its saliva test with an app that makes it possible to share at-home test results with health or other platforms instantly. The saliva self-swabbing technique is obviously much easier to do and less uncomfortable than current Lateral Flow Tests that require swabbing the back of the throat and nasal passages. Vatic is also now doing clinical trials in the US to secure Emergency Use Authorisation from the FDA.</p>
<p>Alex Sheppard, co-founder and CEO of Vatic, explained: “One reason for the recent decline in the uptake of rapid Covid-19 tests is the sampling technique – it’s currently very uncomfortable and difficult for people to use. We need to take the pain out of mass testing if we’re to return to normal to minimize the disruption caused by future COVID-19 outbreaks, whether in offices, schools, or hospitality venues. That’s why we’ve built supportive biosecurity technology that sits  alongside the test, allowing users to generate their own unique QR codes to facilitate safe venue entry.”</p>
<p>How does it work? Vatic says its technology searches for the ‘spike’ on the virus as a measure of infectivity, but also says it is immune to potential mutations of the virus, making it able to test for COVID-19 no matter the variant.</p>
<p>Sheppard said the Vatic test is only the first iteration. It can also detect other infectious viruses by mimicking the surface of a human cell.</p>
<p>“We selected the part of the Coronavirus that uses its spike to enter human cells, almost like a hypodermic needle,&#8221; Sheppard told me. &#8220;That&#8217;s the bit that essentially interacts on our test, and so, effectively, we&#8217;re mimicking a human cell on our test, which is completely unique. It&#8217;s got a completely different engine to a normal Lateral Flow Test, because the chemistry that&#8217;s powering it is totally different.”</p>
<p>The other aspect of the Vatic test is that it employs an app linked to the saliva swap test. Once the test is done it produces an encrypted QR code.</p>
<p>“It’s not altogether dissimilar to what we see on the NHS tests,” Sheppard said, “but it&#8217;s a completely trust-based system, so you don&#8217;t have to compromise your health data. You&#8217;re not writing your home address into a government website. Of course, it does synchronize with the government requirements of reporting a notifiable disease, but it&#8217;s designed to ensure that you know you&#8217;re not giving away too much health data. It’s secure.”</p>
<p>Sheppard and his co-founder Mona Omir met at Oxford University, at the accelerator program Entrepreneur First in September 2019 and have gone on to raised money from both London investors and grant support from the Oxford Foundry / University of Oxford and Innovate UK.</p>
<p>Julia Hawkins, partner at LocalGlobe, commented: “Vatic’s technology is the future of testing. It’s fantastic to hear how many top UK organizations are taking the initiative and putting employee testing at the forefront of their business recovery plan. This new round of investment will be key in ensuring the successful roll-out of KnowNow tests across the UK and internationally and getting economies moving again with minimal interruptions.”</p>
<p>Rob Kniaz, partner at Hoxton Ventures, added: “A saliva-only swab is a true breakthrough in the world of uncomfortable and tricky rapid testing and the speed that the Vatic team have got it to market is very impressive. Excitingly for the business, this test is just the start of their journey &#8211; the opportunities to innovate in the at-home testing market are endless.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/this-startup-just-created-a-fast-accurate-covid-test-which-only-needs-saliva-and-links-to-an-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175696</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Artemis Fund focuses on women founders in underserved communities</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/the-artemis-fund-focuses-on-women-founders-in-underserved-communities/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/the-artemis-fund-focuses-on-women-founders-in-underserved-communities/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female founders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Artemis Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Artemis Fund is a Houston-based firm built by three women with the goal of encouraging more women-led startups. The company launched in 2019 and has raised a $15 million initial fund, which closed earlier this year. Diana Murakhovskaya, who launched the firm with Stephanie Campbell and Leslie Goldman, says that the three women met [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.theartemisfund.com/">The Artemis Fund</a> is a Houston-based firm built by three women with the goal of encouraging more women-led startups. The company launched in 2019 and has raised a $15 million initial fund, which closed earlier this year.</p>
<p>Diana Murakhovskaya, who launched the firm with Stephanie Campbell and Leslie Goldman, says that the three women met over a mutual interest in investing in startups, one that didn&#8217;t just write a check and walk away, but that was really involved in helping these companies grow and thrive.</p>
<p>&#8220;We launched the fund in 2019, and we were looking to raise a micro VC to invest in about 15 companies, and keep a concentrated portfolio where we can really help these companies,&#8221; she said. The LPs in the fund are split 50/50 between men and women with an equal capital share among them, she said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The women recognized that female founders faced an up-hill battle when it came to getting funding. In fact, in 2019 <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/eoy-2019-diversity-report-20-percent-of-newly-funded-startups-in-2019-have-a-female-founder/">Crunchbase research found</a> that just 13% percent of VC money went to startups with at least one female founder with all female founding teams accounting for just 3% of that.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ytSGYuZewF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/indy-vc-firm-sixty8-capital-launches-20m-fund-aimed-at-underrepresented-founders/">Indy VC firm Sixty8 Capital launches $20M fund aimed at underrepresented founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Indy VC firm Sixty8 Capital launches $20M fund aimed at underrepresented founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/10/indy-vc-firm-sixty8-capital-launches-20m-fund-aimed-at-underrepresented-founders/embed/#?secret=ytSGYuZewF" data-secret="ytSGYuZewF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>At the same time, as the women came together in the Houston investing scene, they couldn&#8217;t help but notice that it was mostly dominated by older white men. Murakhovskaya, whose background is engineering, connected with Campbell, who has an MBA and they wanted to know why more women weren&#8217;t getting involved.</p>
<p>&#8220;I said, &#8216;Where are all the women?&#8217; [ … ] And so we started doing these dinners to bring together women and asking them why they&#8217;re not investing, what they&#8217;re doing and, and these were all corporate women [who had the money to invest].&#8221;</p>
<p>What they found was that either women had never been invited to invest, or like them they were looking to do it, but found angel investing less than satisfying. About this time, they met Goldman, who was a lawyer, and was on the board at the Houston Angel Network. &#8220;She&#8217;s an active angel in about 50 companies and 11 funds and similarly had this thesis of shifting all of her investing to female founders at the time,&#8221; Murakhovskaya said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="FTn8LIcted"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/building-paths-to-funding-for-black-female-founders/">Building paths to funding for Black female founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Building paths to funding for Black female founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/03/building-paths-to-funding-for-black-female-founders/embed/#?secret=FTn8LIcted" data-secret="FTn8LIcted" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The three women with distinctly different professional backgrounds decided to come together and the idea for The Artemis Fund began to take shape. &#8220;We thought it was the perfect [mix] &#8212; kind of what happens when an engineer, an MBA and a lawyer get together. So, we find that our backgrounds are unique, and that helps a lot of our portfolio companies in a lot of different ways,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>That meant they wanted to be involved with the founders and help them grow the businesses. &#8220;And so that was one thing we wanted to make sure that differentiates us from the other female-focused VCs. We would invest nationally, we would lead or co-lead most of our rounds and really help the companies along the capital stack. And that meant running a much more concentrated portfolio.&#8221;</p>
<p>The fund focuses on startups with female founders, who are in large potential markets, but ones that conventional male-dominated VCs might not see the potential in. Among the portfolio companies is UNest, a company that helps families take advantage of tax-exempt college savings accounts to save money for their kids&#8217; college education and Upgrade, a maker of custom wigs and extensions. These businesses checked each of these boxes of being run by a woman in a large market that had been mostly ignored by the traditional investment community.</p>
<p>Murakhovskaya says so far the firm has invested in 11 companies with plans to invest in 4-5 more and then raise the next fund. She says while it&#8217;s about helping nurture and build these companies, it&#8217;s also about finding companies that continue to grow into their Series A, B and beyond, while delivering a good return for the company&#8217;s partners.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is not a charity or philanthropy. We really believe that women and diverse teams in particular will outperform, on top of bringing together a different set of companies and products and services that are just not being met for the consumers that they&#8217;re trying to serve.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sp6jMmaPq0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/pandemics-impact-disproportionately-reduced-vc-funding-for-female-founders/">Pandemic&#8217;s impact disproportionately reduced VC funding for female founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pandemic&#8217;s impact disproportionately reduced VC funding for female founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/02/pandemics-impact-disproportionately-reduced-vc-funding-for-female-founders/embed/#?secret=sp6jMmaPq0" data-secret="sp6jMmaPq0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/the-artemis-fund-focuses-on-women-founders-in-underserved-communities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden&#8217;s sweeping executive order takes on Big Tech&#8217;s &#8216;bad mergers,&#8217; ISPs and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/biden-executive-order-tech-antitrust/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/biden-executive-order-tech-antitrust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 17:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Communications Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet service providers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lina Khan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White House]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden administration just introduced a sweeping, ambitious plan to forcibly inject competition into some consolidated sectors of the American economy — the tech sector prominent among them — through executive action. &#8220;Today President Biden is taking decisive action to reduce the trend of corporate consolidation, increase competition, and deliver concrete benefits to America’s consumers, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Biden administration just introduced a sweeping, ambitious plan to forcibly inject competition into some consolidated sectors of the American economy — the tech sector prominent among them — through executive action.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today President Biden is taking decisive action to reduce the trend of corporate consolidation, increase competition, and deliver concrete benefits to America’s consumers, workers, farmers, and small businesses,&#8221; a new <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">White House fact sheet</a> on the forthcoming order states.</p>
<p>The order, which Biden will sign Friday, initiates a comprehensive &#8220;whole-of-government&#8221; approach that loops in more then twelve different agencies at the federal level to regulate monopolies, protect consumers and curtail bad behavior from some of the world&#8217;s biggest corporations.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In the fact sheet, the White House lays out its plans to take matters to regulate big business into its own hands at the federal level. As far as tech is concerned, that comes largely through emboldening the FTC and the Justice Department — two federal agencies with antitrust enforcement powers.</p>
<p>Most notably for Big Tech, which is already bracing for regulatory existential threats, the White House explicitly asserts here that those agencies have legal cover to &#8220;challenge prior bad mergers that past Administrations did not previously challenge&#8221; — i.e., unwinding acquisitions that built a handful of tech companies into the behemoths they are today. The order calls on antitrust agencies to enforce antitrust laws &#8220;vigorously.&#8221;</p>
<p>Federal scrutiny will prioritize &#8220;dominant internet platforms, with particular attention to the acquisition of nascent competitors, serial mergers, the accumulation of data, competition by &#8216;free&#8217; products, and the effect on user privacy.&#8221; Facebook, Google and Amazon are particularly on notice here, though Apple isn&#8217;t likely to escape federal attention either.</p>
<p>&#8220;Over the past 10 years, the largest tech platforms have acquired hundreds of companies — including alleged &#8216;killer acquisitions&#8217; meant to shut down a potential competitive threat,&#8221; the White House wrote in the fact sheet. &#8220;Too often, federal agencies have not blocked, conditioned, or, in some cases, meaningfully examined these acquisitions.&#8221;</p>
<p>The biggest tech companies have regularly defended their longstanding strategy of buying up the competition by arguing that because those acquisitions went through without friction at the time, they shouldn&#8217;t be viewed as illegal in hindsight. In no uncertain terms, the new executive order makes it clear that the Biden administration isn&#8217;t having any of it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e6SPeqtr9p"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/">Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/embed/#?secret=e6SPeqtr9p" data-secret="e6SPeqtr9p" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The White House also specifically singles out internet service providers for scrutiny, ordering the FCC to prioritize consumer choice and institute broadband &#8220;nutrition labels&#8221; that clearly state speed caps and hidden fees. The FCC began working on the labels in the Obama administration but the work was scrapped after Trump took office.</p>
<p>The order also directly calls on the FCC to restore net neutrality rules, which were stripped in 2017 to the widespread horror of open internet advocates and most of the tech industry outside of the service providers that stood to benefit.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NAYEPhlvhZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/14/the-fcc-just-repealed-net-neutrality-what-happens-next/">The FCC just repealed net neutrality. What happens next?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The FCC just repealed net neutrality. What happens next?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/14/the-fcc-just-repealed-net-neutrality-what-happens-next/embed/#?secret=NAYEPhlvhZ" data-secret="NAYEPhlvhZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SOu65KK2yz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/01/court-says-fccs-unhinged-net-neutrality-repeal-cant-stop-state-laws/">Court says FCC&#8217;s &#8216;unhinged&#8217; net neutrality repeal can&#8217;t stop state laws</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Court says FCC&#8217;s &#8216;unhinged&#8217; net neutrality repeal can&#8217;t stop state laws&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/01/court-says-fccs-unhinged-net-neutrality-repeal-cant-stop-state-laws/embed/#?secret=SOu65KK2yz" data-secret="SOu65KK2yz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The White House will also tell the FTC to create new privacy rules meant to guard consumers against surveillance and the &#8220;accumulation of extraordinarily amounts of sensitive personal information,&#8221; which free services like Facebook, YouTube and others have leveraged to build their vast empires. The White House also taps the FTC to create rules that protect smaller businesses from being preempted by large platforms, which in many cases abuse their market dominance with a different sort of data-based surveillance to out-compete up-and-coming competitors.</p>
<p>Finally, the executive order encourages the FTC to put <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/04/massachusetts-voters-pass-a-right-to-repair-measure-giving-them-unprecedented-access-to-their-car-data/">right-to-repair rules</a> in place that would free consumers from constraints that discourage DIY and third-party repairs. A new White House Competition Council under the director of the National Economic Council will coordinate the federal execution of the proposals laid out in the new order.</p>
<p>The antitrust effort from the executive branch mirrors parallel actions in the FTC and Congress. In the FTC, Biden has installed a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/lina-khan-ftc-confirmed/">fearsome antitrust crusader in Lina Khan</a>, a young legal scholar and fierce Amazon critic who proposes a philosophical overhaul to the way the federal government defines monopolies. Khan now leads the FTC as its chair.</p>
<p>In Congress, a bipartisan flurry of bills intended to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/klobuchar-antitrust-law-enforcement-reform-act-booker-markey/">rein in the tech industry</a> are slowly wending their way toward becoming law, though plenty of hurdles remain. Last month, the House Judiciary Committee debated the six bills, which were crafted separately to help them survive opposing lobbying pushes from the tech industry. These legislative efforts could modernize antitrust laws, which have failed to keep pace with the modern realities of giant, internet-based businesses.</p>
<p>&#8220;Competition policy needs new energy and approaches so that we can address America’s monopoly problem,&#8221; Sen. Amy Klobuchar, a prominent tech antitrust hawk in Congress, said of the executive order. &#8220;That means legislation to update our antitrust laws, but it also means reimagining what the federal government can do to promote competition under our current laws.&#8221;</p>
<p>Citing the acceleration of corporate consolidation in recent decades, the White House argues that a handful of large corporations dominates across industries, including healthcare, agriculture and tech and consumers, workers and smaller competitors pay the price for their outsized success. The administration will focus antitrust enforcement on those corners of the market as well as evaluating the labor market and worker protections on the whole.</p>
<p>&#8220;Inadequate competition holds back economic growth and innovation … Economists find that as competition declines, productivity growth slows, business investment and innovation decline, and income, wealth, and racial inequality widen,&#8221; the White House wrote.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DARGcwuyWx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/24/meet-the-anti-antitrust-startup-club/">Meet the anti-antitrust startup club</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Meet the anti-antitrust startup club&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/24/meet-the-anti-antitrust-startup-club/embed/#?secret=DARGcwuyWx" data-secret="DARGcwuyWx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DtQa7EIt5x"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/klobuchar-antitrust-law-enforcement-reform-act-booker-markey/">New antitrust reform bill charts one possible path for regulating big tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;New antitrust reform bill charts one possible path for regulating big tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/klobuchar-antitrust-law-enforcement-reform-act-booker-markey/embed/#?secret=DtQa7EIt5x" data-secret="DtQa7EIt5x" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/biden-executive-order-tech-antitrust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175644</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 analysts weigh in: What are Andy Jassy&#8217;s top priorities as Amazon&#8217;s new CEO?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 17:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Jassy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We asked several analysts to identify the top problems he will have to address in his new role.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s not easy following a larger-than-life founder and CEO of an iconic company, but that&#8217;s what former AWS CEO Andy Jassy faces <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/today-is-day-1-for-andy-jassy-as-former-aws-ceo-moves-to-amazon-corner-office/">this week as he takes over for Jeff Bezos</a>, who moves into the executive chairman role. Jassy must deal with myriad challenges as he becomes the head honcho at the No. 2 company on the Fortune 500.</p>
<p>How he handles these challenges will define his tenure at the helm of the online retail giant. We asked several analysts to identify the top problems he will have to address in his new role.</p>
<h2>Ensure a smooth transition</h2>
<p>Handling that transition smoothly and showing investors and the rest of the world that it&#8217;s business as usual at Amazon is going to be a big priority for Jassy, said Robin Ody, an analyst at Canalys. He said it&#8217;s not unlike what Satya Nadella faced <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/02/04/microsofts-new-ceo-is-officially-satya-nadella/">when he took over as CEO</a> at Microsoft in 2014.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Handling the transition smoothly and showing investors and the rest of the world that it&#8217;s business as usual at Amazon is going to be a big priority for Jassy.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>&#8220;The biggest task is that you&#8217;re following Jeff Bezos, so his overarching issue is going to be stability and continuity. … The eyes of the world are on that succession. So managing that I think is the overall issue and would be for anyone in the same position,&#8221; Ody said.</p>
<p>Forrester analyst Sucharita Kodali said Jassy&#8217;s biggest job is just to keep the revenue train rolling. &#8220;I think the biggest to-do is to just continue that momentum that the company has had for the last several years. He has to make sure that they don&#8217;t lose that. If he does that, I mean, he will win,&#8221; she said.</p>
<h2>Maintain company growth</h2>
<p>As an online retailer, the company has thrived during COVID, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/shelleykohan/2021/02/02/amazons-net-profit-soars-84-with-sales-hitting-386-billion/?sh=5af104ba1334">generating $386 billion in revenue in 2020</a>, up more than $100 billion over the prior year. As Jassy takes over and things return to something closer to normal, will he be able to keep the revenue pedal to the metal?<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/3-analysts-weigh-in-what-are-andy-jassys-top-priorities-as-amazons-new-ceo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175215</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WhatsApp is adding a &#8216;best quality&#8217; setting for sending photos and videos</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/whatsapp-is-adding-a-best-quality-setting-for-sending-photos-and-videos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/whatsapp-is-adding-a-best-quality-setting-for-sending-photos-and-videos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Henry Pickavet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 17:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WhatsApp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kris Holt Contributor Share on Twitter Kris Holt is a contributing writer at Engadget. WhatsApp is working on a setting that will let users more easily bypass its iffy image compression and send photos and videos in the highest available fidelity. The &#8220;best quality&#8221; option will likely join &#8220;auto&#8221; and &#8220;data saver&#8221; choices in a future [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Kris Holt</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://www.twitter.com/krisholt">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Kris Holt is a contributing writer at <a href="https://www.engadget.com/">Engadget</a>. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tag/whatsapp" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="21" data-v9y="1">WhatsApp</a> is working on a setting that will let users more easily bypass its iffy image compression and send photos and videos in the highest available fidelity. The &#8220;best quality&#8221; option will likely join &#8220;auto&#8221; and &#8220;data saver&#8221; choices in a future version of the app.</p>
<p>It appears users will eventually have the choice of whether to compress photos and videos to perhaps save on their data allowance, send them in the best available quality or let WhatsApp automatically select the optimal level of compression for files.</p>
<p>The settings are present in an update WhatsApp submitted to the Google Play Beta Program, as spotted by <a href="https://wabetainfo.com/whatsapp-beta-for-android-2-21-14-16-whats-new/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="22" data-v9y="1"><em>WABetaInfo</em></a>. The options will probably arrive in the public Android build of the app, though it&#8217;s not clear when — they&#8217;re currently in development. It&#8217;s likely the additional image quality options will come to iOS as well, since WhatsApp generally maintains the same features across both platforms.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This could come as welcome news for those who don&#8217;t use the stock messaging apps on iOS or Android and often share photos and videos of their loved ones (Apple Messages retains the original image quality most of the time). Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-multi-device-support-soon-132418897.html" data-ylk="elm:context_link;itc:0" data-rapid_p="23" data-v9y="1">multi-device support</a> is also on the way to WhatsApp.</p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong><em> This post originally appeared on <a href="https://www.engadget.com/whatsapp-photo-video-best-quality-settings-143506690.html">Engadget</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/whatsapp-is-adding-a-best-quality-setting-for-sending-photos-and-videos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175714</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Didomi raises $40 million to help you manage customer consent</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/didomi-raises-40-million-to-help-you-manage-customer-consent/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/didomi-raises-40-million-to-help-you-manage-customer-consent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 16:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Didomi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romain Gauthier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Didomi has raised a $40 million Series B funding round led by Elephant and Breega. The company manages consent flows for web publishers and app developers. Didomi is already doing well in Europe with billions of consent interactions per month — it plans to expand to the U.S. with today’s funding round. “Jawad, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.didomi.io/">Didomi</a> has <a href="https://blog.didomi.io/en/didomi-series-b">raised</a> a $40 million Series B funding round led by Elephant and Breega. The company manages consent flows for web publishers and app developers. Didomi is already doing well in Europe with billions of consent interactions per month — it plans to expand to the U.S. with today’s funding round.</p>
<p>“Jawad, Raphaël and I have co-founded Didomi to make privacy easier for everyone and an obvious choice for companies. This fundraising is a major milestone on our journey to deliver on this mission,” co-founder and CEO Romain Gauthier said in a statement.</p>
<p>“We look forward to helping brands and publishers make customer journeys more transparent and trustworthy through a delightful consent and preferences management experience,” he added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In recent years, many regulators have implemented new privacy-focused frameworks. You might think about GDPR in Europe for instance.</p>
<p>And if you live in a country that is affected by those changes, you are now well aware that you’ll get a consent popup or banner whenever you visit a new website or open an app for the first time.</p>
<p>I wouldn’t say that these popups are “delightful” as the best consent popup is the one that doesn’t exist because the site you’re visiting doesn’t collect and share personal data. But that’s not always possible and there are different reasons why you may need to collect data — including on this current site techcrunch dot com.</p>
<p>In that case, a product like Didomi can be really helpful. Taking those consent flows seriously is extremely important as you don’t want to mess up the implementation and get fined. Didomi is a developer-focused consent platform that works across many different devices. You can configure your consent flow for a desktop website, a mobile website, a mobile app or a connected TV.</p>
<p>Having a unified solution also means that you don’t have to ask for permission over and over again. Didomi can store and synchronize preferences across devices. Everything is auditable in case regulators want to see how you’re collecting consent.</p>
<p>With today’s funding round, the company wants to make its product even more developer friendly with open APIs and open-source SDKs. It doesn’t mean that Didomi is for everyone as the company focuses on premium clients in particular. Clients include Rakuten, Orange, Giphy and Weight Watchers International.</p>
<p>The company will also hire more people with local marketing and sales teams for different markets. Didomi plans to open offices in Germany, Spain and the U.S.</p>
<p>At the same time, the landscape is quickly evolving. Web browsers are gradually blocking third-party trackers and Apple now even asks you if an app can track you at the operating system level. It’s going to be interesting to see how Didomi evolves with user expectations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MJQXHyIAW7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/whos-funding-privacy-tech/">Who&#8217;s funding privacy tech?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Who&#8217;s funding privacy tech?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/whos-funding-privacy-tech/embed/#?secret=MJQXHyIAW7" data-secret="MJQXHyIAW7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/didomi-raises-40-million-to-help-you-manage-customer-consent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175684</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
