<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 05:42:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Oxbotica raises $47M to deploy its autonomous vehicle software in industrial applications</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/oxbotica-raises-47m-to-deploy-its-autonomous-vehicle-software-in-industrial-applications/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/oxbotica-raises-47m-to-deploy-its-autonomous-vehicle-software-in-industrial-applications/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bp ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oxbotica Ltd]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While the world continues to await the arrival of safe, reliable and cost-effective self-driving cars, one of the pioneers in the world of autonomous vehicle software has raised some substantial funding to double down on what it sees as a more immediate opportunity: providing technology to industrial companies to build off-road applications. Oxbotica, the Oxford, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While the world continues to await the arrival of safe, reliable and cost-effective self-driving cars, one of the pioneers in the world of autonomous vehicle software has raised some substantial funding to double down on what it sees as a more immediate opportunity: providing technology to industrial companies to build off-road applications.</p>
<p><a href="http://oxbotica.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oxbotica</a>, the Oxford, England startup that builds what it calls &#8220;universal autonomy&#8221; &#8212; flexible technology that it says can power the navigation, perception, user interfaces, fleet management and other features needed to run self-driving vehicles in multiple environments, regardless of the hardware being used &#8212; has picked up $47 million in a Series B round of funding from an interesting mix of strategic and financial investors.</p>
<p>Led by bp ventures, the investing arm of oil and gas giant <a href="http://bp.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bp</a>, the round also includes BGF, safety equipment maker Halma, pension fund HostPlus, IP Group, Tencent, Venture Science and funds advised by Doxa Partners.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/oxbotica-ltd" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="oxbotica-ltd">Oxbotica <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> said it plans to use the capital to fuel a raft of upcoming deployments &#8212; several that will be coming online this year, according to its CEO &#8212; for clients in areas like mining, port logistics and more, with its lead investor bp an indication of the size of its customers and the kinds of projects that are in its sights.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The question, CEO Ozgur Tohumcu said in an interview, is &#8220;Where is the autonomy needed today? If you go to mines or ports, you can see vehicles in use already,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We see a huge transformation happening in the industrial domain.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>The funding and focus on industry are interesting turns for Oxbotica. The startup has been around since about 2014, originally as a spinout from Oxford University co-founded by academics Paul Newman and Ingmar Posner &#8212; Newman remains at the startup as its CTO, while Posner remains an AI professor at Oxford.</p>
<p>Oxbotica has been associated with a number of high-profile projects &#8212; early on, it <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a52821f6-d368-11e6-b06b-680c49b4b4c0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">provided sensor technology</a> for Nasa&#8217;s Mars Rover, for example.</p>
<p>Over time, it has streamlined what it does to two main platforms that it calls Selenium and Caesium, covering respectively navigation, mapping, perception, machine learning, data export and related technology; and fleet management.</p>
<p>Newman says that what makes Oxbotica stand out from other autonomous software providers is that its systems are lighter and easier to use.</p>
<p>&#8220;Where we are good is in edge compute,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Our radar-based maps are 10 megabytes to cover a kilometer rather than hundreds of megabytes&#8230; Our business plan is to build a horizontal software platform like Microsoft&#8217;s.&#8221; That may underplay the efficiency of what it&#8217;s building, however: Oxbotica also has worked out how to efficiently transfer the enormous data loads associated with autonomous systems, and is <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/oxbotica-and-cisco-to-solve-autonomous-vehicle-data-challenge-with-pioneering-openroaming-platform-301012266.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">working with companies like Cisco</a> to bring these online.</p>
<p>In recent years Oxbotica has been synonymous with some of the more notable on-road self-driving schemes in the U.K. But, as you would expect with autonomous car projects, not everything has panned out as expected.</p>
<p>A self-driving pilot <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/21/addison-lee-and-oxbotica-ink-self-driving-deal-will-offer-autonomous-car-services-in-london-by-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oxbotica kicked off with London-based car service Addison Lee in 2018 projected that it would have its first cars on the road by 2021</a>. That project was quietly shut down, however, when <a href="https://www.addisonlee.com/addlib/a-new-chapter-for-alg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Addison Lee was sold on by Carlyle last year</a> and the company abandoned costly moonshots. Another effort, the publicly backed <a href="https://www.projectendeavour.uk/partners" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Project Endeavour</a> to build autonomous car systems across towns in England, appears to still be in progress.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NI2vCPgujO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/21/addison-lee-and-oxbotica-ink-self-driving-deal-will-offer-autonomous-car-services-in-london-by-2021/">Addison Lee and Oxbotica ink self-driving deal, will offer autonomous car services in London by 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Addison Lee and Oxbotica ink self-driving deal, will offer autonomous car services in London by 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/21/addison-lee-and-oxbotica-ink-self-driving-deal-will-offer-autonomous-car-services-in-london-by-2021/embed/#?secret=NI2vCPgujO" data-secret="NI2vCPgujO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The turn to industrial customers, Newman said, is coming alongside those more ambitious, larger-scale applications. &#8220;Industrial autonomy for off-road refineries, ports and airports happens on the way to on-road autonomy,&#8221; he said, with the focus firmly remaining on providing software that can be used with different hardware. &#8220;We’ve always had this vision of &#8216;no atoms, just software,&#8217; &#8221; he said. &#8220;There is nothing special about the road. Our point is to be agnostic, to make sure it works on any hardware platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>It may claim to have always been interested in hardware- and application-agnostic autonomy, but these days it&#8217;s being joined by others that have tried the other route and have decided to follow the Oxbotica strategy instead. They include FiveAI, another hyped autonomous startup out of the U.K. that originally wanted to build its own fleet of self-driving vehicles but instead last year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/five-the-self-driving-startup-raises-41m-and-pivots-into-b2b-away-from-building-its-own-fleet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pivoted</a> to providing its software technology on a B2B basis for other hardware makers.</p>
<p>Oxbotica has now raised about $80 million to date, and it&#8217;s not disclosing its valuation but is optimistic that the coming year &#8212; with deployments and other new partnerships &#8212; will bear out that it&#8217;s doing just fine in the current market.</p>
<p>“bp ventures are delighted to invest in Oxbotica &#8211; we believe its software could accelerate the market for autonomous vehicles,&#8221; said Erin Hallock, bp ventures managing partner, in a statement. &#8220;Helping to accelerate the global revolution in mobility is at the heart of bp’s strategy to become an integrated energy company focused on delivering solutions for customers.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SoKKQFshIR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/five-the-self-driving-startup-raises-41m-and-pivots-into-b2b-away-from-building-its-own-fleet/">Five, the self-driving startup, raises $41M and pivots into B2B, away from building its own fleet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Five, the self-driving startup, raises $41M and pivots into B2B, away from building its own fleet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/03/five-the-self-driving-startup-raises-41m-and-pivots-into-b2b-away-from-building-its-own-fleet/embed/#?secret=SoKKQFshIR" data-secret="SoKKQFshIR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/oxbotica-raises-47m-to-deploy-its-autonomous-vehicle-software-in-industrial-applications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092507</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google to add App Store privacy labels to its iOS apps as soon as this week</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/google-to-add-app-store-privacy-labels-to-its-ios-apps-as-soon-as-this-week/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/google-to-add-app-store-privacy-labels-to-its-ios-apps-as-soon-as-this-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 23:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Contrary to reports, Google is not delaying updates to its iOS apps because it doesn&#8217;t want to comply with Apple&#8217;s recently announced App Store Privacy Labels policy. The new policy, a part of the company&#8217;s larger privacy push, requires developers to disclose how data is collected from App Store users and used to track them. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Contrary <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90591066/googles-ios-apps-havent-been-updated-in-weeks-apples-privacy-labels-could-be-the-reason-why">to reports</a>, Google is not delaying updates to its iOS apps because it doesn&#8217;t want to comply with Apple&#8217;s recently announced <a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=em8fm29e">App Store Privacy Labels policy</a>. The new policy, a part of the company&#8217;s larger privacy push, requires developers to disclose how data is collected from App Store users and used to track them. TechCrunch confirmed Google is not taking a stand against the labels. It is, in fact, preparing to roll out privacy labels across its sizable iOS app catalog as soon as this week or the next.</p>
<p>TechCrunch looked into the situation with Google&#8217;s apps following a story by<a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90591066/googles-ios-apps-havent-been-updated-in-weeks-apples-privacy-labels-could-be-the-reason-why"> Fast Company</a> today that speculated that Google&#8217;s slowdown on releasing iOS app updates could be because it was not ready to be transparent about the data it collects from its users. The report stated that <em>&#8220;not a single one&#8221;</em> of Google&#8217;s apps had been updated since December 7, 2020 &#8212; coincidentally, just one day before <a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=em8fm29e">Apple&#8217;s new privacy label requirements</a> went into effect on the App Store.</p>
<p>It went on to suggest the late November to early December time frame when many of Google&#8217;s iOS apps were updated was another indication that Google was trying to squeeze in a few last updates before the app privacy label deadline.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>There are a few problems with speculation, however.</p>
<p>For starters, Google actually did update two of its apps after the deadline &#8212; but those updates didn&#8217;t include privacy labels.</p>
<p>Google Slides, the slideshow presentation app and one of Google&#8217;s more significant apps in the productivity space, was updated on December 14, 2020. And Socratic by Google, a homework helper and the No. 7 free app in the Education category, was updated on December 15. (We fact-checked this data with Sensor Tower&#8217;s assistance, as Google&#8217;s iOS catalog is nearing 100 iPhone apps!)</p>
<p>While it may seem Google is skirting Apple&#8217;s new rules, we must also be careful about reading too much into the update timing. A slowdown in December app updates isn&#8217;t unusual by any stretch. Nor is it suspicious to see app changes pushed out to the public in the weeks before Christmas and New Year&#8217;s because the Apple&#8217;s App Store itself shuts down over the holidays. This year, The App Store closed from December 23 through December 27, 2020 for its annual break.</p>
<p>And like other large companies, Google goes on a code freeze in late December through early January, so as not to cause major issues with its products and services over the holidays when staff is out.</p>
<p>Google also isn&#8217;t the only major app publisher that delayed an immediate embrace of app privacy labels. Amazon and Pinterest haven&#8217;t yet updated with privacy labels as of the time of writing, for example.</p>
<p>Of course, none of this is to say that app privacy labels aren&#8217;t a concern for Google, given its primary business is advertising. In fact, they&#8217;re being taken quite seriously &#8212; with execs attending meetings to discuss that sort of thing.</p>
<p>Apple may or may not have given Google some leeway on the matter in terms of Google&#8217;s apps being updated after the deadline without submitting the privacy label information.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, a Google spokesperson confirmed the company has a plan to add privacy labels across its app catalog. They also confirmed the labels are expected to begin rolling out as soon as this week or next week, though an exact date is not yet available.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/google-to-add-app-store-privacy-labels-to-its-ios-apps-as-soon-as-this-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092547</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI&#8217;s DALL-E creates plausible images of literally anything you ask it to</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/openais-dall-e-creates-plausible-images-of-literally-anything-you-ask-it-to/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/openais-dall-e-creates-plausible-images-of-literally-anything-you-ask-it-to/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 23:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gpt-3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenAI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OpenAI&#8217;s latest strange yet fascinating creation is DALL-E, which by way of hasty summary might be called &#8220;GPT-3 for images.&#8221; It creates illustrations, photos, renders or whatever method you prefer, of anything you can intelligibly describe, from &#8220;a cat wearing a bow tie&#8221; to &#8220;a daikon radish in a tutu walking a dog.&#8221; But don&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://openai.com/blog/dall-e/">OpenAI&#8217;s latest strange yet fascinating creation is DALL-E</a>, which by way of hasty summary might be called &#8220;GPT-3 for images.&#8221; It creates illustrations, photos, renders or whatever method you prefer, of anything you can intelligibly describe, from &#8220;a cat wearing a bow tie&#8221; to &#8220;a daikon radish in a tutu walking a dog.&#8221; But don&#8217;t write stock photography and illustration&#8217;s obituaries just yet.</p>
<p>As usual, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/openai" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="openai">OpenAI&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> description of its invention is quite readable and not overly technical. But it bears a bit of contextualizing.</p>
<p>What researchers <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/11/openai-makes-an-all-purpose-api-for-its-text-based-ai-capabilities/">created with GPT-3</a> was an AI that, given a prompt, would attempt to generate a plausible version of what it describes. So if you say &#8220;a story about a child who finds a witch in the woods,&#8221; it will try to write one — and if you hit the button again, it will write it again, differently. And again, and again, and again.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Some of these attempts will be better than others; indeed, some will be barely coherent while others may be nearly indistinguishable from something written by a human. But it doesn&#8217;t output garbage or serious grammatical errors, which makes it suitable for a variety of tasks, as startups and researchers are exploring right now.</p>
<p>DALL-E (a combination of Dali and WALL-E) takes this concept one further. Turning text into images has been done for years by AI agents, with varying but steadily increasing success. In this case the agent uses the language understanding and context provided by GPT-3 and its underlying structure to create a plausible image that matches a prompt.</p>
<p>As OpenAI puts it:</p>
<blockquote><p>GPT-3 showed that language can be used to instruct a large neural network to perform a variety of text generation tasks. Image GPT showed that the same type of neural network can also be used to generate images with high fidelity. We extend these findings to show that manipulating visual concepts through language is now within reach.</p></blockquote>
<p>What they mean is that an image generator of this type can be manipulated naturally, simply by telling it what to do. Sure, you could dig into its guts and find the token that represents color, and decode its pathways so you can activate and change them, the way you might stimulate the neurons of a real brain. But you wouldn&#8217;t do that when asking your staff illustrator to make something blue rather than green. You just say, &#8220;a blue car&#8221; instead of &#8220;a green car&#8221; and they get it.</p>
<p>So it is with DALL-E, which understands these prompts and rarely fails in any serious way, although it must be said that even when looking at the best of a hundred or a thousand attempts, many images it generates are more than a little&#8230; off. Of which later.</p>
<p>In the OpenAI post, the researchers give copious interactive examples of how the system can be told to do minor variations of the same idea, and the result is plausible and often quite good. The truth is these systems can be very fragile, as they admit DALL-E is in some ways, and saying &#8220;a green leather purse shaped like a pentagon&#8221; may produce what&#8217;s expected but &#8220;a blue suede purse shaped like a pentagon&#8221; might produce nightmare fuel. Why? It&#8217;s hard to say, given the black-box nature of these systems.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092558" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dall-e-1.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092558" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2092558 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dall-e-1.gif" alt="" width="800" height="451" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092558" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: OpenAI</p></div></p>
<p>But DALL-E is remarkably robust to such changes, and reliably produces pretty much whatever you ask for. A torus of guacamole, a sphere of zebra; a large blue block sitting on a small red block; a front view of a happy capybara, an isometric view of a sad capybara; and so on and so forth. You can play with all the examples at the post.</p>
<p>It also exhibited some unintended but useful behaviors, using intuitive logic to understand requests like asking it to make multiple sketches of the same (non-existent) cat, with the original on top and the sketch on the bottom. No special coding here: &#8220;We did not anticipate that this capability would emerge, and made no modifications to the neural network or training procedure to encourage it.&#8221; This is fine.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vfYdIF41gN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/here-are-a-few-ways-gpt-3-can-go-wrong/">Here are a few ways GPT-3 can go wrong</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Here are a few ways GPT-3 can go wrong&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/07/here-are-a-few-ways-gpt-3-can-go-wrong/embed/#?secret=vfYdIF41gN" data-secret="vfYdIF41gN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Interestingly, another new system from OpenAI, CLIP, was used in conjunction with DALL-E to understand and rank the images in question, though it&#8217;s a little more technical and harder to understand. <a href="https://openai.com/blog/clip/">You can read about CLIP here</a>.</p>
<p>The implications of this capability are many and various, so much so that I won&#8217;t attempt to go into them here. Even OpenAI punts:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the future, we plan to analyze how models like DALL·E relate to societal issues like economic impact on certain work processes and professions, the potential for bias in the model outputs, and the longer term ethical challenges implied by this technology.</p></blockquote>
<p>Right now, like GPT-3, this technology is amazing and yet difficult to make clear predictions regarding.</p>
<p>Notably, very little of what it produces seems truly &#8220;final&#8221; — that is to say, I couldn&#8217;t tell it to make a lead image for anything I&#8217;ve written lately and expect it to put out something I could use without modification. Even a brief inspection reveals all kinds of AI weirdness (<a href="https://aiweirdness.com/">Janelle Shane&#8217;s specialty</a>), and while these rough edges will certainly be buffed off in time, it&#8217;s far from safe, the way GPT-3 text can&#8217;t just be sent out unedited in place of human writing.</p>
<p>It helps to generate many and pick the top few, as the following collection shows:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092586" style="width: 875px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092586" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092586" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png" alt="AI-generated illustrations of radishes walking dogs." width="865" height="701" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png 865w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png?resize=150,122 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png?resize=300,243 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png?resize=768,622 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png?resize=680,551 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/greatjob.png?resize=50,41 50w" sizes="(max-width: 865px) 100vw, 865px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092586" class="wp-caption-text">The top eight out of a total of X generated, with X increasing to the right. Image Credits: OpenAI</p></div></p>
<p>That&#8217;s not to detract from OpenAI&#8217;s accomplishment here. This is fabulously interesting and powerful work, and like the company&#8217;s other projects it will no doubt develop into something even more fabulous and interesting before long.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4VEAkRedfV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/othersideai-raises-2-6m-to-let-gpt-3-write-your-emails-for-you/">OthersideAI raises $2.6M to let GPT-3 write your emails for you</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;OthersideAI raises $2.6M to let GPT-3 write your emails for you&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/othersideai-raises-2-6m-to-let-gpt-3-write-your-emails-for-you/embed/#?secret=4VEAkRedfV" data-secret="4VEAkRedfV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/openais-dall-e-creates-plausible-images-of-literally-anything-you-ask-it-to/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092540</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: NYSE won&#8217;t delist Chinese telcos</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/daily-crunch-nyse-wont-delist-chinese-telcos/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/daily-crunch-nyse-wont-delist-chinese-telcos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 23:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The New York Stock Exchange reverses course, Nintendo acquires a game studio and an Indian electronics and lifestyle startup raises $100 million. This is your Daily Crunch for January 5, 2021. The big story: NYSE won&#8217;t delist Chinese telcos The New York Stock Exchange is reversing a recent decision to delist China&#8217;s three major telecom [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The New York Stock Exchange reverses course, Nintendo acquires a game studio and an Indian electronics and lifestyle startup raises $100 million. This is your Daily Crunch for January 5, 2021.</p>
<p><strong>The big story: NYSE won&#8217;t delist Chinese telcos</strong></p>
<p>The New York Stock Exchange is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/nyse-reverses-plans-to-delist-chinas-three-big-telcos/">reversing a recent decision to delist China&#8217;s three major telecom operators</a> — China Mobile, China Unicom and China Telecom — which was supposed to be part of a Trump administration policy to block investment in companies that supply and support China&#8217;s military.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The exchange said the reversal is taking place “in light of further consultation with relevant regulatory authorities,&#8221; and that shares will be traded while NYSE officials evaluate how the executive order applies.</p>
<p>If the delisting does occur, it would be largely symbolic, since only a small percentage of the telecoms&#8217; total shares are traded in New York.</p>
<p><strong>The tech giants</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/nintendo-buys-canadian-game-studio-in-rare-acquisition/">Nintendo buys Canadian game studio in rare acquisition</a> — Nintendo is acquiring Canada-based Next Level Games, which developed Luigi’s Mansion 3.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/04/jack-ma-missing/">Jack Ma’s absence from public eye sparks Twitter discussions</a> — The world’s attention is on Jack Ma’s whereabouts after reports noted the billionaire founder of Alibaba and Ant Group had been absent from public view since late October.</p>
<p><strong>Startups, funding and venture capital</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/pg-terminates-plan-to-acquire-razor-startup-billie-following-ftc-lawsuit/">P&amp;G terminates plan to acquire razor startup Billie following FTC lawsuit</a> — In December, the FTC sued to block P&amp;G’s acquisition of Billie.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/indian-electronics-and-lifestyle-brand-boat-raises-100-million-from-warburg-pincus/">Indian electronics and lifestyle brand Boat raises $100M from Warburg Pincus</a> — The round gives Boat a post-money valuation of about $300 million.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/divvy-raises-165m-as-the-spend-management-space-stays-red-hot/">Divvy raises $165M as the spend management space stays red-hot</a> — Divvy’s market (corporate cards and software that help firms manage and limit expenses) is incredibly active.</p>
<p><strong>Advice and analysis from Extra Crunch</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/affirm-targets-up-to-38-per-share-in-ipo-pushing-its-valuation-above-9b/">Affirm targets up to $38 per share in IPO, pushing its valuation above $9B</a> — The new S-1 follows a late-December filing of a similar nature.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/8-investors-discuss-social-gamings-biggest-opportunities/">8 investors discuss social gaming’s biggest opportunities</a> — Investors expressed excitement around the widening entertainment ambitions of social platforms.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/how-segment-redesigned-its-core-systems-to-solve-an-existential-scaling-crisis/">How Segment redesigned its core systems to solve an existential scaling crisis</a> — Segment was just beginning to take off in 2015 when it ran into a scaling problem.</p>
<p>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which aims to democratize information about startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">You can sign up here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>Everything else</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/fbi-nsa-says-hacks-on-us-federal-agencies-likely-russian-in-origin/">FBI, NSA say ongoing hacks at US federal agencies ‘likely Russian in origin’</a> — The U.S. government says hackers “likely Russian in origin” are responsible for breaching the networks of at least 10 federal agencies and several major tech companies.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/c-by-ge-gets-rebranded-under-new-ownership-readies-non-lighting-products/">C by GE gets rebranded under new ownership, expands beyond lighting</a> — Back in May, General Electric sold off its more than 100-year-old GE Lighting division to smart home company Savant.</p>
<p><em>The Daily Crunch is TechCrunch&#8217;s roundup of our biggest and most important stories. If you&#8217;d like to get this delivered to your inbox every day at around 3pm Pacific, you can <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1764565 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="191" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=150,42 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=300,84 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Dk-_nQ.png?resize=50,14 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/daily-crunch-nyse-wont-delist-chinese-telcos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092577</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sources: Hinge Health has raised $310M Series D at a $3B valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/hinge-healthy-d/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/hinge-healthy-d/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve O'Hear]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 23:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bessemer Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coatue Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hinge Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead Edge Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physical therapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surgery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hinge Health, the San Francisco-based company that offers a digital solution to treat chronic musculoskeletal (MSK) conditions — such as back and joint pain — has closed a $310 million in Series D funding, according to sources. The round is led by Coatue and Tiger Global, and values 2015-founded Hinge at $3 billion post-money, people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://hingehealth.com/">Hinge Health</a>, the San Francisco-based company that offers a digital solution to treat chronic musculoskeletal (MSK) conditions — such as back and joint pain — has closed a $310 million in Series D funding, according to sources.</p>
<p>The round is led by Coatue and Tiger Global, and values 2015-founded Hinge at $3 billion post-money, people familiar with the investment tell me. It comes off the back of a 300% increase in revenue in 2020, with investors told to expect revenue to nearly triple again in 2021 based on the company&#8217;s booked pipeline.</p>
<p>I also understand that Hinge&#8217;s founders &#8212; Daniel Perez and Gabriel Mecklenburg &#8212; retain voting control of the board. I&#8217;ve reached out to CEO Perez for comment and will update this post should I hear back.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Hinge&#8217;s existing investors include <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/bessemer-venture-partners" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="bessemer-venture-partners">Bessemer Venture Partners, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> which backed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/hinge-health-series-c/">the company&#8217;s $90 million Series C</a> round in February, along with Lead Edge Capital, Insight Partners (which led the Series B), Atomico (which led the Series A), 11.2 Capital, Quadrille Capital and Heuristic Capital.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="q8ARjNaoLv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/hinge-health-series-c/">Hinge Health, the digital solution for chronic back and joint pain, closes $90M Series C</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hinge Health, the digital solution for chronic back and joint pain, closes $90M Series C&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/hinge-health-series-c/embed/#?secret=q8ARjNaoLv" data-secret="q8ARjNaoLv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Originally based in London, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/hinge-health" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="hinge-health">Hinge Health <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> primarily sells into U.S. employers and health plans, billing itself as a digital healthcare solution for chronic MSK conditions. The platform combines wearable sensors, an app and health coaching to remotely deliver physical therapy and behavioral health.</p>
<p>The basic premise is that there is plenty of existing research to show how best to treat chronic MSK disorders, but existing healthcare systems aren’t up to the task due to funding pressures and for other systematic reasons. The result is an over tendency to use opioid-based painkillers or surgery, with poor results and often at even greater cost. Hinge wants to reverse this through the use of technology and better data, with a focus on improving treatment adherence.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Hinge&#8217;s jump in valuation is significant. According to sources, the company&#8217;s February round produced a valuation of around $420 million, so the new valuation is more than a 6x increase.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/hinge-healthy-d/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook will turn all US political advertising off again after Georgia runoffs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/facebook-political-ad-ban-returns-after-ga-runoffs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/facebook-political-ad-ban-returns-after-ga-runoffs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 23:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook Misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misinformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Political Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[political campaigning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Georgia is the only state in the U.S. right now where Facebook allows political ads to run, but after Tuesday&#8217;s polls close that&#8217;s set to change. According to Facebook&#8217;s site detailing changes to its ad policies and a story from Axios, the company will no longer allow political and social issue ads anywhere in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Georgia is the only state in the U.S. right now where <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/facebook" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="facebook">Facebook <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> allows political ads to run, but after Tuesday&#8217;s polls close that&#8217;s set to change.</p>
<p>According to Facebook&#8217;s site detailing changes to its ad policies and a story from <a href="https://www.axios.com/facebook-resume-political-ad-ban-georgia-df566911-7b7a-4d42-94a2-37b42d44c67f.html?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=organic&amp;utm_content=1100">Axios</a>, the company will no longer allow political and social issue ads anywhere in the country, Georgia included, beginning early tomorrow.</p>
<p>Facebook told TechCrunch that the decision to toggle political ads in Georgia off again brings that state in line with its current &#8220;nationwide pause&#8221; on social issue, election and politics ads. A Facebook spokesperson declined to say when political ads will again be allowed or if permanently blocking them from the platform is under consideration.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company first hit pause on those ad categories November 4 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/facebook-election-ad-ban-delegitimize-election-results/">as a precaution</a> designed to reduce misinformation in the U.S. presidential election. On December 16, the company re-allowed political ads in Georgia, inviting eager campaigns to pay to get their messages in front of Facebook users. It appears that some politicians, <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/ted-cruz-is-pocketing-the-money-hes-raising-for-georgia-gopers-hes-not-alone">Sen. Ted Cruz (R-TX) among them</a>, pounced on Facebook&#8217;s Georgia loophole to raise money for themselves in spite of restrictions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="LxOJJihqoJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/facebook-election-ad-ban-delegitimize-election-results/">Facebook won&#8217;t accept ads that &#8216;delegitimize&#8217; US election results</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook won&#8217;t accept ads that &#8216;delegitimize&#8217; US election results&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/facebook-election-ad-ban-delegitimize-election-results/embed/#?secret=LxOJJihqoJ" data-secret="LxOJJihqoJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">When political ads came flooding back in for Georgians, they edged out mainstream news sources, according to </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://themarkup.org/citizen-browser/2021/01/05/in-georgia-facebooks-changes-brought-back-a-partisan-news-feed">new reporting from The Markup</a><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">. While that result is fairly intuitive, it does underline the outsized influence of targeting political advertising in Facebook&#8217;s information ecosystem.</span></p>
<p>Plenty of politicians and political groups are likely eager to get back to fundraising on Facebook. The company&#8217;s decision to keep the pause in place suggests that it&#8217;s still evaluating how — and perhaps if — it wants to handle political ads in the future. But Facebook also might be waiting for the storm to pass in light of the misinformation that plagued November&#8217;s drawn-out process of calculating election results.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also worth noting that Facebook&#8217;s head of advertising integrity Rob Leathern <a href="https://twitter.com/robleathern/status/1345133179263475714">left the company</a> at the end of December, calling his team&#8217;s work on the 2020 U.S. election the &#8220;culmination of a huge amount of effort over several years.&#8221; Leathern helped sculpt the company&#8217;s policies around political advertising — decisions that were often controversial due to the prevalence of paid misinformation sweeping through the platform throughout 2020.</p>
<p>Because they will decide control of the Senate, the unusual pair of runoff races in a state that just flipped blue are high-stakes for both political parties. With a Democratic Senate, the Biden administration&#8217;s ambitious plans for things like COVID relief and the climate crisis will have a much better shot at becoming a reality. And for Republicans looking to stymie the president-elect&#8217;s policy priorities, extended control of the Senate would put a powerful barrier in Biden&#8217;s way.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WQhbIC6LGE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/facebook-political-ad-pause/">Facebook extends its temporary ban on political ads for another month</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook extends its temporary ban on political ads for another month&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/11/facebook-political-ad-pause/embed/#?secret=WQhbIC6LGE" data-secret="WQhbIC6LGE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/facebook-political-ad-ban-returns-after-ga-runoffs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092532</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remembering TechCrunch Japan&#8217;s Hirohide Yoshida (1971-2020)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/remembering-techcrunch-japans-hirohide-yoshida-1971-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/remembering-techcrunch-japans-hirohide-yoshida-1971-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hirohide Yoshida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch japan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On New Year’s Eve, TechCrunch Japan’s Editor-in-Chief Hirohide Yoshida passed away at age 49. In addition to being a tremendously valuable member of our international team who helped build the site’s presence on the international stage, Hiro-san was a thoughtful, warm and kind colleague who impacted the lives of those of us who had the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">On New Year’s Eve, TechCrunch Japan’s Editor-in-Chief Hirohide Yoshida passed away at age 49. In addition to being a tremendously valuable member of our international team who helped build the site’s presence on the international stage, Hiro-san was a thoughtful, warm and kind colleague who impacted the lives of those of us who had the pleasure to work with him.</p>
<p>I worked alongside Hiro-san at two consecutive TechCrunch Tokyo events. The size and scope of the shows were impressive testaments to the team he led, as well as his own passion for technology. Throughout it all, he was an ideal ambassador for an electric startup community and tech journalism &#8212; a passion evident in every aspect of his work and life. He continued that vision as he helped transform the conference into a virtual event amid the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>He is survived by his wife, two young children and a site and staff that will continue to bear his mark for a long time to come.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>TechCrunch Japan published its own reflections on the life and career of Hirohide Yoshida <a href="https://jp.techcrunch.com/2021/01/03/yoshidasan-mataaimasyou/">that you can read here</a>. We’ve asked the site’s editor, Takya Kimura, to share additional thoughts below:</p>
<blockquote><p>He started his career at KADOKAWA / ASCII. He had been writing articles about Apple and tech companies for over 20 years. With his deep knowledge, he became Editor-in-Chief of<em> MacPeople</em>, a magazine for Apple fans, and <em>ASCII Weekly</em>, publications he led for eight years.</p>
<p>In 2018, he became Editor-in-Chief of TechCrunch Japan. He was an incredibly hard worker, with long term vision, who never voiced a complaint about work. As Editor-in-Chief of TCJ, his team ran TechCrunch Tokyo, the biggest startup event in Japan for three consecutive years, including its first online event &#8220;TechCrunch Startup Battle Online 2020.&#8221;</p>
<p>Until the last moment, he loved his wife, his newborn twins, his cat and TechCrunch Japan. After his long journey, he now rests in peace, wearing his beloved TechCrunch Japan t-shirt.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_2092551" style="width: 970px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092551" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092551" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/75429636_10157000855538737_3463149473566294016_n.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/75429636_10157000855538737_3463149473566294016_n.jpg 960w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/75429636_10157000855538737_3463149473566294016_n.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/75429636_10157000855538737_3463149473566294016_n.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/75429636_10157000855538737_3463149473566294016_n.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/75429636_10157000855538737_3463149473566294016_n.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/75429636_10157000855538737_3463149473566294016_n.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2092551" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch Japan</p></div></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/remembering-techcrunch-japans-hirohide-yoshida-1971-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092513</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Any San Francisco teacher who needs a second monitor can get one, via Two Screens for Teachers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/any-san-francisco-teacher-who-needs-an-second-monitor-can-get-one-via-two-screens-for-teachers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/any-san-francisco-teacher-who-needs-an-second-monitor-can-get-one-via-two-screens-for-teachers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philanthropy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[two screens for teachers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Any teacher in the San Francisco Unified School District who needs a second monitor can request one free of charge from Two Screens for Teachers, the nonprofit that recently extended a similar privilege to Seattle educators. If you&#8217;re a teacher in SF, you can sign up here. Having a second monitor may sound like a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Any teacher in the San Francisco Unified School District who needs a second monitor <a href="https://www.sfusd.edu/about/news/sfusd-teachers-offered-gift-second-screen-support-distance-teaching">can request one free of charge</a> from Two Screens for Teachers, the nonprofit that recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/two-screens-for-teachers-will-outfit-all-educators-in-seattle-public-schools-with-a-second-monitor/">extended a similar privilege to Seattle educators.</a> If you&#8217;re a teacher in SF, <a href="https://www.twoscreensforteachers.org/request-monitor">you can sign up here</a>.</p>
<p>Having a second monitor may sound like a power user move or luxury to some, but for teachers, whose days are essentially one giant group call, it&#8217;s a huge benefit to be able to put the call on one screen while the lesson and other tools are on another.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/jjk8w61ryHY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/two-screens-for-teachers" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="two-screens-for-teachers">Two Screens for Teachers <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> was started in September by Walk Score&#8217;s Matt Lerner and Mike Mathieu, and the first effort of simply <a href="https://www.twoscreensforteachers.org/buy-monitor">connecting teachers in need to people who had a hundred bucks to spare</a> quickly grew into something larger.</p>
<p>By tapping local businesses and VCs, they were able to secure enough money that any teacher in Seattle had a monitor available for the asking. Turns out it&#8217;s more efficient to do it that way. Lerner and his team have negotiated bulk pricing with Dell and others, which significantly lowers the necessary amounts for a given district.</p>
<p>San Francisco was a natural next location to try to get enough dollars together, and they&#8217;ve now collected enough for that city as well as Oakland, Redwood City and Contra Costa County. (San Jose is still a little short.)</p>
<p>This remarkable map, both hopeful and terrifying, shows the scale of what&#8217;s needed versus what&#8217;s been accomplished.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092533" style="width: 846px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092533" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092533" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png" alt="" width="836" height="565" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png 836w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png?resize=768,519 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png?resize=680,460 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/help-teachers.png?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 836px) 100vw, 836px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092533" class="wp-caption-text">A map showing where and how many teachers need a second monitor. Image Credits: Two Screens for Teachers</p></div></p>
<p>Yet even though the idea of hooking up more than 150,000 teachers with monitors seems gargantuan, it must be pointed out that in the few months since its humble beginnings, Two Screens for Teachers has rustled up more than 20,000, for both big cities and tiny towns. One order of magnitude is nothing!</p>
<p>The final cost for equipping teachers across the country with essential equipment is about $23 million. It seems an almost ridiculously low number for a single billionaire, perhaps one of the many whose net worth has grown by 10 times that amount in the last year, to provide with a single check. Here&#8217;s something with which one could buy genuine cross-country goodwill, cheap at the price.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092530" style="width: 993px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092530" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092530" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png" alt="" width="983" height="685" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png 983w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png?resize=300,209 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png?resize=768,535 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png?resize=680,474 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cmon-jeff.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 983px) 100vw, 983px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092530" class="wp-caption-text">Do it, Jeff</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.twoscreensforteachers.org/partners">Here&#8217;s the link, guys!</a></p>
<p>For those of you not in the three (going on four) comma club, it&#8217;s still possible to help out in a smaller way either by donating or <a href="https://www.twoscreensforteachers.org/buy-monitor">following the instructions here</a> to ship a monitor to a teacher in need.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HCmWakAjAt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/two-screens-for-teachers-will-outfit-all-educators-in-seattle-public-schools-with-a-second-monitor/">Two Screens for Teachers will outfit all educators in Seattle Public Schools with a second monitor</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Two Screens for Teachers will outfit all educators in Seattle Public Schools with a second monitor&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/13/two-screens-for-teachers-will-outfit-all-educators-in-seattle-public-schools-with-a-second-monitor/embed/#?secret=HCmWakAjAt" data-secret="HCmWakAjAt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/any-san-francisco-teacher-who-needs-an-second-monitor-can-get-one-via-two-screens-for-teachers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092492</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Minecraft Earth will shut down in June</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/minecraft-earth-will-shut-down-in-june/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/minecraft-earth-will-shut-down-in-june/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mojang]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout 2019, Microsoft experimented with building a real-world, augmented reality Minecraft game designed in the same vein as Pokémon GO. Called Minecraft Earth, they finally opened it up to everyone in November of 2019. In just a few months, it&#8217;ll shut down and all player data will be deleted. So what happened? Writes the Minecraft [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Throughout 2019, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/microsoft" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="microsoft">Microsoft <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> experimented with building a real-world, augmented reality Minecraft game designed in the same vein as Pokémon GO. Called Minecraft Earth, they finally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/12/minecraft-earth-is-live-so-get-tapping/">opened it up to everyone</a> in November of 2019.</p>
<p>In just a few months, it&#8217;ll shut down and all player data will be deleted.</p>
<p>So what happened? Writes the Minecraft Earth team:</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<blockquote><p>Minecraft Earth was designed around free movement and collaborative play – two things that have become near impossible in the current global situation. As a result, we have made the difficult decision to re-allocate our resources to other areas that provide value to the Minecraft community and to end support for Minecraft Earth in June 2021.</p></blockquote>
<p>In other words: This game just isn&#8217;t going to work in a pandemic. Pokémon GO might be doing just fine thanks to a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/">strong foundation of super-dedicated players</a> and a steady stream of curious newcomers, but it&#8217;d be pretty damned hard to go from zero to 60 with a real-world game when everyone is supposed to be staying at home.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N9bx9qK8U3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/12/minecraft-earth-is-live-so-get-tapping/">Minecraft Earth is live, so get tapping</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Minecraft Earth is live, so get tapping&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/12/minecraft-earth-is-live-so-get-tapping/embed/#?secret=N9bx9qK8U3" data-secret="N9bx9qK8U3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>What happens next:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The team is releasing one final patch that removes all in-app purchases and makes all in-game mechanics easier/faster to make the most of any remaining play time.</li>
<li>On June 30th, the game shuts down. Even if you&#8217;ve got it installed already, it&#8217;ll stop working.</li>
<li>On July 1st, they&#8217;re deleting all player data.</li>
<li>Anyone who has spent any money in Minecraft Earth is getting a free copy of Minecraft Bedrock version, and players who have unused paid Minecraft Earth rubies will get an unspecified amount of Minecoins that&#8217;ll work in Minecraft-proper&#8217;s marketplace.</li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s a disappointing end to what was really a pretty cool concept — but if they&#8217;re announcing its shutdown barely a year after launch, the data probably suggest there&#8217;s not much else they can do.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">This will be our last update, so we made it a good one! Please enjoy and thank you for being a part of the community!</p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f3c6.png" alt="🏆" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Introducing the Super Season<br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f3a9.png" alt="🎩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> New Character Creator items<br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/23f1.png" alt="⏱" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Reduced time for crafting &amp; smelting<br /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f411.png" alt="🐑" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f404.png" alt="🐄" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f416.png" alt="🐖" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f407.png" alt="🐇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f413.png" alt="🐓" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> So many new mobs</p>
<p>↣ <a href="https://t.co/OBpzUcz2Ck">https://t.co/OBpzUcz2Ck</a> ↢ <a href="https://t.co/Dnl9R9HQLP">pic.twitter.com/Dnl9R9HQLP</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Minecraft Earth (@minecraftearth) <a href="https://twitter.com/minecraftearth/status/1346517320647241728?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 5, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vOU0OWWgDO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/">How Niantic evolved Pokémon GO for the year no one could go anywhere</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Niantic evolved Pokémon GO for the year no one could go anywhere&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/28/how-niantic-evolved-pokemon-go-for-the-year-no-one-could-go-anywhere/embed/#?secret=vOU0OWWgDO" data-secret="vOU0OWWgDO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/minecraft-earth-will-shut-down-in-june/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virgin Orbit targets launch window opening January 10 for next orbital flight attempt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/virgin-orbit-targets-launch-window-opening-january-10-for-next-orbital-flight-attempt/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/virgin-orbit-targets-launch-window-opening-january-10-for-next-orbital-flight-attempt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LauncherOne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small satellite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Orbit is wasting no time in 2021 getting back to active flight testing: The company has a window for its next orbital demonstration launch attempt that opens on Sunday, January 10, and that continues throughout the rest of the month. This follows an attempt last year made in May, which ended before the LauncherOne [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/virgin-orbit" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="virgin-orbit">Virgin Orbit <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is wasting no time in 2021 getting back to active flight testing: The company has a window for its next orbital demonstration launch attempt that opens on Sunday, January 10, and that continues throughout the rest of the month. This follows an attempt last year made in May, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/25/virgin-orbits-first-orbital-test-flight-cut-short-after-rocket-released-from-carrier-aircraft/">ended before the LauncherOne rocket reached orbit</a> &#8212; shortly after it detached from the Cosmic Girl carrier aircraft, in fact.</p>
<p>While that mission didn&#8217;t go exactly as Virgin Orbit had hoped, it was a significant milestone for the small satellite launch company, and helped gather a significant amount of data about how the vehicle performs in flight. LauncherOne was able to briefly light its rocket booster before safety systems on board automatically shut it down. The company had been looking to fly this second test before the end of last year, but issues including COVID-19 meant that they only got as far as the wet dress rehearsal (essentially a run-through of everything leading up to the flight with the vehicles fully fueled).</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dQtYloDrAj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/25/virgin-orbits-first-orbital-test-flight-cut-short-after-rocket-released-from-carrier-aircraft/">Virgin Orbit&#8217;s first orbital test flight cut short after rocket released from carrier aircraft</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Virgin Orbit&#8217;s first orbital test flight cut short after rocket released from carrier aircraft&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/25/virgin-orbits-first-orbital-test-flight-cut-short-after-rocket-released-from-carrier-aircraft/embed/#?secret=dQtYloDrAj" data-secret="dQtYloDrAj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This next mission will once again attempt an orbital launch, and this time, the stakes are somewhat higher because actual customer payloads from NASA are on board. They include a number of small satellite science experiments and demonstrations, and while they&#8217;re specifically selected for the mission profile (meaning it&#8217;s not a tremendous loss if the launch fails), it still would make everyone happiest to actually get them to their target destination.</p>
<p>The nature of the launch window means that Virgin Orbit will likely wait for conditions to be as good as possible before taking off from the Mojave Air and Space Port in California, so take that January 10 date as the earliest possible launch time, but not necessarily the most likely. If successful, Virgin Orbit will join a select group of private small launch vehicles that have made it to orbit, so the industry will definitely be watching the next time Cosmic Girl takes off with LauncherOne attached.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/virgin-orbit-targets-launch-window-opening-january-10-for-next-orbital-flight-attempt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dell monitors embrace video calls with pop-up webcams and Teams buttons built in</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/dell-monitors-embrace-video-calls-with-pop-up-webcams-and-teams-buttons-built-in/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/dell-monitors-embrace-video-calls-with-pop-up-webcams-and-teams-buttons-built-in/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 21:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ces 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Teams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monitors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dell&#8217;s latest monitors reflect the growing need for simple, solid solutions to video conferencing needs, with a clever pop-up camera and a perhaps too clever by half Teams integration. The new displays integrate a number of advanced features — but they&#8217;re still made strictly with offices in mind. The new Dell 24, 27 and 34 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/dell" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="dell">Dell&#8217;s <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> latest monitors reflect the growing need for simple, solid solutions to video conferencing needs, with a clever pop-up camera and a perhaps too clever by half Teams integration. The new displays integrate a number of advanced features — but they&#8217;re still made strictly with offices in mind.</p>
<p>The new Dell 24, 27 and 34 Video Conferencing Monitors are clearly meant to be a turnkey solution to the need at many companies for video-capable setups that don&#8217;t cost a fortune.</p>
<p>The most interesting feature is a pop-up camera at the top; this isn&#8217;t the first one of these by far (we&#8217;ve seen them going back a few years) or even the first by Dell, but it is the first of theirs in a monitor as opposed to an all-in-one system, and it is probably the best one yet.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2092432" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dell-popup.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092432" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092432" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dell-popup.gif" alt="Dell's monitor has a pop-up camera." width="800" height="434" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092432" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dell</p></div></p>
<p>The five-megapixel camera (which translates to somewhat more than 1080p, likely around 3K) won&#8217;t blow any minds, so if you want things like optical background blur and improved lighting, you&#8217;ll have to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/how-to-get-your-nice-camera-set-up-as-a-high-quality-webcam/">build your own setup</a>. But it should be perfectly fine for work calls and having it slip away when not in use is reassuring to the privacy-conscious.</p>
<p>An additional, nonobvious reason to like this setup is it means the camera isn&#8217;t confined to the bezel of the monitor itself, possibly allowing for a better lens and bigger sensor. I&#8217;ve asked Dell for the detailed specs and I don&#8217;t expect anything extraordinary, but it&#8217;s always better to have space than to pack the camera module into the margins.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WgjaYhZsxT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/how-to-get-your-nice-camera-set-up-as-a-high-quality-webcam/">How to set up your nice camera as a high-quality webcam in 5 minutes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to set up your nice camera as a high-quality webcam in 5 minutes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/10/how-to-get-your-nice-camera-set-up-as-a-high-quality-webcam/embed/#?secret=WgjaYhZsxT" data-secret="WgjaYhZsxT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>At the bottom of these new screens is a pleasantly felted speaker bar, with just enough wattage for calls to sound fine — it won&#8217;t work for bangers, though.</p>
<p>But on the left side of that speaker are some interesting, if not entirely practical, new buttons. Most prominent is a dedicated <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/microsoft" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="microsoft">Microsoft <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Teams button, along with call, volume and mute buttons.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092441" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092441" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092441" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg" alt="Close up of Teams button on Dell monitor." width="1024" height="589" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg 1457w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg?resize=300,173 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg?resize=768,442 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg?resize=680,391 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/teams-button.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092441" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Dell</p></div></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know about you, but I wouldn&#8217;t want one of those. And not just because we don&#8217;t use Teams.</p>
<p>Maybe this is just me, but I don&#8217;t like the idea of reaching forward and whacking my monitor, which I&#8217;ve carefully positioned, every time I want to adjust the volume or answer a call, or mute myself — good luck doing it subtly when the whole view shakes every time. Even if I did, I wouldn&#8217;t want a button dedicated specifically to a single brand of video conferencing. Seems limiting when so many video platforms are in play.</p>
<p>I would be far more likely to pay for a puck with those controls on it as well as a mono speaker for voices and mic that&#8217;s closer to me. And by the way, it might be better to leave noise cancellation to the software side of things — calling apps often integrate their own, and who knows how built-in noise blocking interacts with those.</p>
<p>No doubt this is a simpler product solution, of course, and also presumably one that Microsoft and Dell worked together on. The pop-up webcam also has an IR camera that works with Windows Hello, the face-recognition login method I didn&#8217;t realize existed until very recently.</p>
<p>Obviously this is Dell and Microsoft going after enterprise customers who are already in their ecosystem. But as a Dell monitor lover myself, I wouldn&#8217;t mind having a pop-up camera — minus the unnecessary sound bar and Teams button. Where&#8217;s the love, Dell?</p>
<p>The new video conferencing monitors will be available next month, starting at $520 for a 24-inch, then going up to $720 for the 27-inch and $1,150 for the (curved) 34-inch.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/ces-2021/"><img src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ces-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/dell-monitors-embrace-video-calls-with-pop-up-webcams-and-teams-buttons-built-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092425</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FBI, NSA say ongoing hacks at US federal agencies &#8216;likely Russian in origin&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/fbi-nsa-says-hacks-on-us-federal-agencies-likely-russian-in-origin/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/fbi-nsa-says-hacks-on-us-federal-agencies-likely-russian-in-origin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FireEye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[network management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. government says hackers &#8220;likely Russian in origin&#8221; are responsible for breaching the networks of at least 10 U.S. federal agencies and several major tech companies, including FireEye and Microsoft. In a joint statement published Tuesday, the FBI, the NSA and Homeland Security&#8217;s cybersecurity advisory unit, CISA, said that the government was &#8220;still working [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The U.S. government says hackers &#8220;likely Russian in origin&#8221; are responsible for breaching the networks of at least 10 U.S. federal agencies and several major tech companies, including <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/fireeye" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="fireeye">FireEye <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Microsoft.</p>
<p>In a joint statement published Tuesday, the FBI, the NSA and Homeland Security&#8217;s cybersecurity advisory unit, CISA, said that the government was &#8220;still working to understand the scope&#8221; of the breach, but that the breaches are likely an &#8220;intelligence gathering effort.&#8221;</p>
<p>The compromises are &#8220;ongoing,&#8221; the statement said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The statement didn&#8217;t name the breached agencies, but the Treasury, State and the Department of Energy are among those <a href="https://www.fedscoop.com/solarwinds-recap-federal-agencies-caught-orion-breach/">reported to be affected</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a serious compromise that will require a sustained and dedicated effort to remediate,&#8221; the statement said. &#8220;The [joint agency effort] will continue taking every necessary action to investigate, remediate, and share information with our partners and the American people,&#8221;</p>
<p>News of the widespread espionage campaign emerged in early December after cybersecurity giant FireEye, normally the first company that cyberattack victims call, discovered its own network <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/cybersecurity-firm-fireeye-says-it-was-hacked-by-a-nation-state/">had been breached</a>. Soon after, it was reported that several government agencies had also been infiltrated.</p>
<p>All of the victims are customers of U.S. software firm <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/solarwinds" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="solarwinds">SolarWinds, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> whose Orion network management tools are used across the U.S. government and Fortune 500 companies. FireEye <a href="https://www.fireeye.com/blog/threat-research/2020/12/evasive-attacker-leverages-solarwinds-supply-chain-compromises-with-sunburst-backdoor.html">said that hackers</a> broke into SolarWinds&#8217; network and pushed a tainted software update to its customers, allowing the hackers to easily break into any one of thousands of companies and agencies that installed the backdoored update.</p>
<p>Some 18,000 customers downloaded the backdoored software update, but the government&#8217;s joint statement said that it believes only a &#8220;much smaller number have been compromised by follow-on activity on their systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>Several news outlets have previously reported that the hacks were carried out by a Russian intelligence group known as APT 29, or Cozy Bear, which has been linked to several espionage-driven attacks, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/17/russian-cyberops-are-targeting-covid-19-vaccine-rd-intelligence-agencies-warn/">attempting to steal coronavirus vaccine research</a>.</p>
<p>Tuesday&#8217;s joint statement would be the first time the government acknowledged the likely culprit behind the campaign.</p>
<p>Russia had previously denied involvement with the hacks.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xmc1JWdXHt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/">Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Just how bad is that hack that hit US government agencies?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/17/fireeye-breach-solarwinds-federal-agencies/embed/#?secret=xmc1JWdXHt" data-secret="xmc1JWdXHt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/fbi-nsa-says-hacks-on-us-federal-agencies-likely-russian-in-origin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092443</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>P&#038;G terminates plan to acquire razor startup Billie following FTC lawsuit</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/pg-terminates-plan-to-acquire-razor-startup-billie-following-ftc-lawsuit/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/pg-terminates-plan-to-acquire-razor-startup-billie-following-ftc-lawsuit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 19:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Billie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p&g]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Procter &#38; Gamble will not acquire women&#8217;s beauty products startup Billie, as previously planned, following action taken by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission to stop the deal from proceeding. In December, the FTC sued to block P&#38;G&#8217;s acquisition of the New York-based startup Billie, a maker of women&#8217;s razors and other beauty products, on the grounds [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Procter &amp; Gamble will not acquire women&#8217;s beauty products startup Billie,<a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20200108005827/en/PG-Announces-Plans-to-Acquire-Billie-Inc."> as previously planned</a>, following action taken by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission to stop the deal from proceeding. In December, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/ftc-sues-to-block-pgs-acquisition-of-billie-a-razor-startup-for-women/">the FTC sued to block P&amp;G&#8217;s acquisition</a> of the New York-based startup Billie, a maker of women&#8217;s razors and other beauty products, on the grounds that the merger would eliminate competition in the wet shave razor market.</p>
<p>Today, P&amp;G and Billie issued a joint statement, expressing their regret over the FTC&#8217;s decision to attempt to block their merger, which led to the deal&#8217;s termination:</p>
<blockquote><p>We were disappointed by the FTC’s decision and maintain there was exciting potential in combining Billie with P&amp;G to better serve more consumers around the world. However, after due consideration, we have mutually agreed that it is in both companies’ best interests not to engage in a prolonged legal challenge, but instead to terminate our agreement and refocus our resources on other business priorities.</p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Billie had made a name for itself in the women&#8217;s razor market by offering to eliminate the so-called &#8220;pink tax,&#8221; which refers to how women&#8217;s products are often marked up at higher price points compared with similar products aimed at men. It later expanded into the broader beauty market with a focus on more natural products that are free of additives and chemicals, including sulfates, parabens, formaldehydes, GMOs, drying alcohols, synthetic dyes, fragrances, cheap foaming agents, unstable silicones and BHT.</p>
<p>The startup was also particularly successful in capturing the interest of a younger, Gen Z to millennial-aged consumer, who responded to its mission as well as its modern, and often even progressive, marketing across social media and the web. In its advertisements, Billie would <a href="https://mybillie.com/pages/projectbodyhair">show women with body hair</a> &#8212; a message that went against the grain of traditional societal expectations, where women are often shown in marketing messages &#8212; including razor ads &#8212; as already hairless and smooth.</p>
<p>Billie&#8217;s message was that women should feel free to do what they want about their body hair &#8212; but for those who prefer to shave, it would be happy to sell them an affordably priced razor.</p>
<p>What also made Billie interesting was its business model. The company offers to ship replacement blades on a subscription basis to its customers, which helped it grow revenues and customer loyalty.</p>
<p>Ahead of the P&amp;G acquisition, Billie was planning to expand into physical retail stores, which would have made the brand a more direct competitor to P&amp;G products, the FTC had said.</p>
<p>&#8220;As its sales grew, Billie was likely to expand into brick-and-mortar stores, posing a serious threat to P&amp;G,&#8221; noted Ian Conner, director of the FTC’s Bureau of Competition, in a statement issued last month. &#8220;If P&amp;G can snuff out Billie’s rapid competitive growth, consumers will likely face higher prices,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>As a result of the FTC&#8217;s actions, the companies chose to put an end to their plans to merge as opposed to pursuing further legal action.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2021/01/statement-ian-conner-director-ftcs-bureau-competition-regarding">FTC praised this decision in a release issued today</a>. Reuters also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-billie-m-a-p-g-idUSKBN29A1RA">reported</a> on the companies&#8217; decision to terminate.</p>
<p>&#8220;Procter &amp; Gamble’s abandonment of the acquisition of Billie is good news for consumers who value low prices, quality, and innovation,&#8221; the FTC statement reads. &#8220;Billie is a direct-to-consumer company whose advertising targets customers who are tired of paying more for comparable razors. The FTC voted to challenge this merger because it would have eliminated dynamic competition from Billie.&#8221;</p>
<p>The FTC lawsuit was the second antitrust suit the agency filed in 2020 after it previously sued to block Edgewell Personal Care&#8217;s (maker of Schick razors) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/09/edgewell-acquires-harrys/">$1.37 billion deal to acquire the razor startup Harry&#8217;s, Inc</a>., another direct-to-consumer brand. As a result, that deal fell through, too.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4TlhLm4t68"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/ftc-sues-to-block-pgs-acquisition-of-billie-a-razor-startup-for-women/">FTC sues to block P&#038;G&#8217;s acquisition of Billie, a razor startup for women</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FTC sues to block P&#038;G&#8217;s acquisition of Billie, a razor startup for women&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/08/ftc-sues-to-block-pgs-acquisition-of-billie-a-razor-startup-for-women/embed/#?secret=4TlhLm4t68" data-secret="4TlhLm4t68" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/pg-terminates-plan-to-acquire-razor-startup-billie-following-ftc-lawsuit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092401</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coral Vita cultivates $2M seed to take its reef restoration mission global</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/coral-vita-cultivates-2m-seed-to-take-its-reef-restoration-mission-global/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/coral-vita-cultivates-2m-seed-to-take-its-reef-restoration-mission-global/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 19:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coral vita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ocean solutions accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainable ocean alliance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Coral reefs all over the world are struggling to survive, with millions of people and billions of dollars in business that rely on them at risk — on top of the fundamental tragedy of losing such a crucial ecosystem. Coral Vita aims to modernize both coral restoration techniques and the economy surrounding them, and has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Coral reefs all over the world are struggling to survive, with millions of people and billions of dollars in business that rely on them at risk — on top of the fundamental tragedy of losing such a crucial ecosystem. <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/coral-vita" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="coral-vita">Coral Vita <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> aims to modernize both coral restoration techniques and the economy surrounding them, and has raised a $2 million seed round to kick things off in earnest.</p>
<p>I wrote about Coral Vita late in 2019 when I encountered co-founder Gator Halpern on the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/in-the-accelerator-over-the-sea/">Sustainable Ocean Alliance&#8217;s Accelerator at Sea</a>. At the time, the operation was both smaller and under siege by Hurricane Dorian, which wiped out the team&#8217;s coral farm in the Bahamas — and then, of course, the pandemic arrived just in time to spoil the team&#8217;s 2020 plans along with everyone else&#8217;s.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Dirpvp7WwN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/in-the-accelerator-over-the-sea/">In the Accelerator over the Sea</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In the Accelerator over the Sea&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/in-the-accelerator-over-the-sea/embed/#?secret=Dirpvp7WwN" data-secret="Dirpvp7WwN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>But despite the general chaos of the last year, Coral Vita managed to start and at last close a $2 million round, with the intention to come back bigger and better and demonstrate a new global model for the field.</p>
<p>&#8220;We decided rather than just rebuilding our pilot farm to that pilot level, we&#8217;d just take the next step forward in our journey. We really believe this is an opportunity to jump start a restoration economy,&#8221; said Sam Teicher, co-founder and chief reef officer.</p>
<p>To picture how reef restoration looks today, imagine (as Teicher invited me to) an underwater garden near the shore, with floating ropes and structures on which grow coral fragments that are occasionally harvested and transported to the area in need of young, healthy corals.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092389" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092389" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092389" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg" alt="Corals grow in a tank at Coral Vita in the Bahamas." width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-2.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092389" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Coral Vita</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;But when you think about the scale of the problem — half the world&#8217;s reefs are dead and 90 percent of the other half are predicted to die in the next 30 years — relying on underwater facilities alone isn&#8217;t possible,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The plan Coral Vita has is to transition away from ocean-based farms to land facilities that allow for much improved yield and survivability, and employ advanced techniques to speed up coral&#8217;s growth and increase its survival rate. One such technique is coral microfragmenting, developed by the restoration community at large, in which corals are broken up into tiny pieces, which can grow as much as 50 times faster in aggregate. And by doing so on land they can exert much more control over the coral&#8217;s attributes.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve got tanks on land with clean sea water pumping through and the ability, among other things, to control conditions,&#8221; he explained. &#8220;So if you think of what it&#8217;ll be like off the coast of Grand Bahama in 40-50 years, we can essentially simulate that to harden the corals against those conditions. Up front, an ocean-based nursery is much cheaper, but when you start thinking about the need to grow millions or billions of corals around the world, land-based facilities start to look a lot more realistic. The cost goes down with scale, too — ocean-based nurseries go to about $30-$40 per coral; we can get it down to $10 as we get up to a hundred or a thousand tanks.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092393" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092393" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2092393 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg" alt="Onlookers view the coral growing tanks at Coral Vita" width="1024" height="511" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg 1928w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg?resize=768,383 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg?resize=680,339 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg?resize=1536,766 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-1.jpeg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092393" class="wp-caption-text">On the left, a Bahamanian tourism official (far left) listens to Sam Teicher. On the right, Gator Halpern (center) talks with others before the pandemic. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Coral Vita</p></div></p>
<p>Not only is the physical scale limited at present, but the income sources are as well: Often it&#8217;s government money instead of the inexhaustible well of private cash. Coral Vita hopes to be able to change that by increasing and diversifying supply and income, and going directly to those affected.</p>
<p>As the world starts to open back up, Coral Vita hopes to be able to rely again on eco-tourism, with people coming by the coral farm as they might go to a hatchery or wildlife reserve. That helps balance far-flung income and projects with more local ones (and connects the company to smaller communities like those where it&#8217;s based).</p>
<p>While things were still locked down, the company took the opportunity to allow distant support for its local operations, however, by expanding its <a href="https://coralvita.co/adopt-a-coral">&#8220;adopt a coral&#8221; campaign</a>. Anyone who&#8217;s contributed to one of these for an endangered animal or ravaged forest will be familiar with how it works, but until earlier this year Coral Vita hadn&#8217;t actively pursued the concept.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ipTvcx0jok"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/10/3d-printed-bionic-corals-mimic-a-reefs-powers-of-photosynthesis/">3D-printed &#8216;bionic corals&#8217; mimic a reef&#8217;s powers of photosynthesis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3D-printed &#8216;bionic corals&#8217; mimic a reef&#8217;s powers of photosynthesis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/10/3d-printed-bionic-corals-mimic-a-reefs-powers-of-photosynthesis/embed/#?secret=ipTvcx0jok" data-secret="ipTvcx0jok" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re trying to transform the space away from grants and aid — we&#8217;re selling to customers that depend on the ecosystems of reefs,&#8221; Teicher said. &#8220;If you&#8217;re a hotel that relies on scuba or snorkel tourists, if you&#8217;re a coastal property owner or insurer, a government, a development bank, a cruise line, you can hire Coral Vita to restore the reefs that you depend on.&#8221;</p>
<p>This superficially mercenary business model where commercially important reefs get priority wouldn&#8217;t be necessary, of course, if governments and industry hadn&#8217;t systematically neglected these reefs to begin with. Not that privately funded projects are somehow fundamentally tainted, but this type of restoration work tends to be seen as the milieu of nonprofits and government agencies. One might consider this approach a direct, if late, tax that cuts out the government middle man.</p>
<p>The fact is this is globally crucial work that needs to start <em>now</em>, not in five or 10 years when the correct conservation funds are organized by concerned parties. Every month counts when reefs are actively deteriorating, and private money is the only realistic option to scale up fast and do what needs to be done. Plus, as the process becomes cheaper, it becomes easier to fund projects without commercial backing.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092392" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092392" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2092392" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg" alt="Corals grow in a tank at Coral Vita in the Bahamas." width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg 6321w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/coral-vita-imgs-4.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2092392" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Coral Vita</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;On top of that is the ability to innovate,&#8221; added Teicher. &#8220;What we&#8217;re trying to do with this round is to make advances to the science and engineering, including 3D printing and robotics in the process. We&#8217;re launching R&amp;D projects not just for restoration but protection.&#8221;</p>
<p>He cited Tom Chi, co-founder of Google X and an early advisor and investor, as someone who has pushed on the automation side, comparing the industry to agriculture, where robotics is currently having a transformative effect.</p>
<p>Proving out the scalable land-based farms opens up the possibility of a global presence, as well — lowering costs and lead times for corals to be brought to where they&#8217;re needed.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re at a point where we need to rethink adaptation and how to fund it,&#8221; said Teicher. &#8220;The two-year plan is to launch more farms in other countries — ultimately we want them in every nation with reefs and for this to be the biggest coral farm that ever existed.&#8221;</p>
<p>Of course he, like most, would rather that restoration never had to happen in the first place. If people would stop the practices that kill reefs, it would certainly help — though as with most of these global-scale problems, stopping the behavior doesn&#8217;t mean the problem disappears. Coral farming will still be crucial for recovery, just as other mitigations and contributions will be needed to help nature reestablish balance, or at least something approaching balance.</p>
<p>Leading the $2 million round was the environment-focused Builders Collective, with participation from Apollo Projects&#8217; Max Altman and baseball&#8217;s Max and Erica Scherzer. Earlier investors (in a pre-seed or &#8220;seed one&#8221; round) include the <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sustainable-ocean-alliance" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sustainable-ocean-alliance">Sustainable Ocean Alliance, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> Tom Chi as mentioned, Adam Draper, Yale University, and Sven and Kristin Lindblad.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CD3j5zDCRT"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/ocean-solutions-accelerators-third-wave-tackles-a-new-set-of-aquatic-challenges/">Ocean Solutions Accelerator&#8217;s third wave tackles a new set of aquatic challenges</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ocean Solutions Accelerator&#8217;s third wave tackles a new set of aquatic challenges&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/05/ocean-solutions-accelerators-third-wave-tackles-a-new-set-of-aquatic-challenges/embed/#?secret=CD3j5zDCRT" data-secret="CD3j5zDCRT" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/coral-vita-cultivates-2m-seed-to-take-its-reef-restoration-mission-global/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092039</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nintendo buys Canadian game studio in rare acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/nintendo-buys-canadian-game-studio-in-rare-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/nintendo-buys-canadian-game-studio-in-rare-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 19:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luigi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metroid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[next level games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While gaming giants Sony and Microsoft have made M&#38;A a critical part of their strategic growth plans, Nintendo has always seemed to be more reluctant to bring outside talent into the fold of its video game empire. Today, the company announced that it will be acquiring the developer behind Luigi&#8217;s Mansion 3, Canada-based Next Level [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While gaming giants <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/sony" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="sony">Sony <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and Microsoft have made M&amp;A a critical part of their strategic growth plans, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/nintendo" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="nintendo">Nintendo <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has always seemed to be more reluctant to bring outside talent into the fold of its video game empire. Today, the company announced that it will be acquiring the developer behind Luigi&#8217;s Mansion 3, Canada-based Next Level Games.</p>
<p>Nintendo&#8217;s announcement is the first studio acquisition for the company since their 2007 purchase of <em>Xenoblade Chronicles</em> developer Monolith Soft.</p>
<p><a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/next-level-games" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="next-level-games">Next Level Games <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> has been working on Nintendo-licensed IP exclusively for the better part of the last decade, crafting a number of titles across some of the company&#8217;s second tier of intellectual property including the Super Mario Strikers series as well as mobile iterations of Metroid Prime and Luigi&#8217;s Mansion.</p>
<p>The Vancouver-based studio&#8217;s recent Luigi&#8217;s Mansion 3 title for the Nintendo Switch has been a pretty huge success for the company which has had pretty light offerings of first-party IP since the system&#8217;s launch. In a recent earnings report, Nintendo shared that Luigi&#8217;s Mansion 3 had sold nearly 8 million copies, earning it a spot as one of the system&#8217;s top-selling titles.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pOvTU6mLgv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/8-investors-discuss-social-gamings-biggest-opportunities/">8 investors discuss social gaming&#8217;s biggest opportunities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 investors discuss social gaming&#8217;s biggest opportunities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/8-investors-discuss-social-gamings-biggest-opportunities/embed/#?secret=pOvTU6mLgv" data-secret="pOvTU6mLgv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/nintendo-buys-canadian-game-studio-in-rare-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092387</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Affirm targets up to $38 per share in IPO, pushing its valuation above $9B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/affirm-targets-up-to-38-per-share-in-ipo-pushing-its-valuation-above-9b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/affirm-targets-up-to-38-per-share-in-ipo-pushing-its-valuation-above-9b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 19:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today Affirm, a fintech startup that offers payment options to e-commerce customers, released a new S-1/A filing. The new document follows a late-December filing of a similar nature, though that update focused on changing the language of Affirm&#8217;s reported results, tweaking its language to remove some adjusted metrics and hewing closer to generally accepted accounting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today <a href="https://www.affirm.com/">Affirm</a>, a fintech startup that offers payment options to e-commerce customers, released a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1820953/000110465921000697/tm2026663-15_s1a.htm">new S-1/A filing</a>. The new document follows a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1820953/000110465920138534/tm2026663-13_s1a.htm">late-December filing</a> of a similar nature, though that update focused on <a href="https://twitter.com/alex/status/1341750729774682120">changing the language of Affirm&#8217;s reported results</a>, tweaking its language to remove some adjusted metrics and hewing closer to generally accepted accounting principles, or GAAP.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s more recent filing details what could be its first IPO price interval, indicating that <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/affirm" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="affirm">Affirm <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> may price its shares between $33 and $38 per share in its IPO. If Affirm raises its estimates, expect that price range to tighten.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s calculate Affirm&#8217;s valuation marks at its new price range before digging into what we think of the company&#8217;s estimated worth against its most recent performance.</p>
<h2>Valuation</h2>
<p>There are two ways to calculate a company&#8217;s IPO valuation. The first takes into account only shares that will exist after the offering. The second, the so-called diluted valuation, takes into account shares that are available for exercise or conversion, but have yet to be. To avoid choosing sides today, we&#8217;ll calculate both.</p>
<p>The first, simple valuation is a doddle to tally:</p>
<ul>
<li>Affirm shares outstanding post-IPO, <em>including</em> its underwriters&#8217; option: 246,436,771.</li>
<li>Affirm IPO price interval: $33 to $38 per share.</li>
<li>Affirm simple IPO valuation range: $8.1 billion to $9.4 billion.</li>
</ul>
<p>Affirm&#8217;s fully diluted valuation involves a larger share count, so it generates larger results. Doing our own math, here&#8217;s how it shakes out (Bloomberg came up with slightly different numbers):</p>
<ul>
<li>Affirm fully diluted shares outstanding post-IPO, <em>including</em> its underwriters&#8217; option: 318,865,246<sup>1</sup>.</li>
<li>Affirm IPO price interval: $33 to $38 per share.</li>
<li>Affirm fully diluted IPO valuation range: $10.5 billion to $12.1 billion.</li>
</ul>
<p>At the time of its April, 2019 Series F, Affirm was worth $2.9 billion after the capital was raised, according <a href="https://pitchbook.com/">to PitchBook</a>. The company also raised a $500 million Series G in September of 2020. That final round sold shares at $19.93 apiece, along with some convertible notes, per today&#8217;s filing; investors in that transaction are set to do very well in under a year.</p>
<p>Those who put money in even earlier will do even better.</p>
<h2>Do those numbers make sense?</h2>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/affirm-targets-up-to-38-per-share-in-ipo-pushing-its-valuation-above-9b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian electronics and lifestyle startup Boat raises $100 million from Warburg Pincus</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/indian-electronics-and-lifestyle-brand-boat-raises-100-million-from-warburg-pincus/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/indian-electronics-and-lifestyle-brand-boat-raises-100-million-from-warburg-pincus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 18:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warburg pincus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Boat, an electronics and lifestyle startup in India, has raised $100 million in a new financing round that many independent investors termed as the most successful hardware startup story to date in the world’s second-largest internet market. An affiliate of Warburg Pincus, a New York-headquartered private equity firm, financed the entire Series B round for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Boat, an electronics and lifestyle startup in India, has raised $100 million in a new financing round that many independent investors termed as the most successful hardware startup story to date in the world’s second-largest internet market.</p>
<p>An affiliate of <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/warburg-pincus" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="warburg-pincus">Warburg Pincus, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a New York-headquartered private equity firm, financed the entire Series B round for the four-year-old Indian startup, which sells low-cost, durable headphones, earphones and other mobile accessories.</p>
<p>The round gives <a href="https://www.boat-lifestyle.com/">Boat</a>, which had raised about $3 million in equity and debt financing prior to the new round, a post-money valuation of about $300 million, a person familiar with the matter told TechCrunch. Executives of Boat declined to comment on the valuation, other than saying that Warburg Pincus had bought a &#8220;significant minority stake&#8221; in the startup.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>An investor who did not want to be named said Boat has grown to be an anomaly case among hardware startups in India. There aren&#8217;t many hardware startups in India in the first place. Among those that do exist, very few have been able to raise much money. (Technically, I suppose you could squint your eyes hard enough to see smartphone vendors Micromax and Lava International as hardware startups, but neither of them have raised $100 million.) <span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Boat has made things even more interesting by achieving an additional rare milestone: profitability, said Sameer Mehta, co-founder of the startup, in an interview with TechCrunch.</span></p>
<p>The secret sauce of Boat, at least in part, is that it has managed to keep the price points of its accessories low while also making them aesthetically appealing. The startup counts the young generation as its target audience who want good-looking accessories at low prices but also tend to upgrade every few months.</p>
<p>Another possible reason why things worked out for Boat, which had only one institutional investor prior to the new round (Fireside Ventures), is that it showed up at the right time. The startup began its journey with selling charging cables and power adapters. Its beginning coincided with the Indian smartphone market hitting a tipping point, where millions of people had started to buy a handset each month.</p>
<p>A few months into its journey, India&#8217;s richest man (Mukesh Ambani) further accelerated the smartphone market with the launch of telecom network Reliance Jio, which offered 4G data at no price for several months, suddenly giving tens of millions of people in the country yet another reason to upgrade to a smartphone.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2092473" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2092473" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2092473 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/L-R-Aman-Gupta-and-Sameer-Mehta-Founders-boAt.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/L-R-Aman-Gupta-and-Sameer-Mehta-Founders-boAt.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/L-R-Aman-Gupta-and-Sameer-Mehta-Founders-boAt.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/L-R-Aman-Gupta-and-Sameer-Mehta-Founders-boAt.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/L-R-Aman-Gupta-and-Sameer-Mehta-Founders-boAt.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/L-R-Aman-Gupta-and-Sameer-Mehta-Founders-boAt.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/L-R-Aman-Gupta-and-Sameer-Mehta-Founders-boAt.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2092473" class="wp-caption-text">Founders of Boat Lifestyle Sameer Mehta (left) and Aman Gupta pose for a picture. (Image Credits: Boat Lifestyle)</p></div></p>
<p>Boat has expanded into several categories in recent years, and followed the same strategy that made it stand out in the first place. Its fitness wearable starts at Indian rupees 1,799 ($24.50), smartwatches at $34, charging cables at $3.40, home theatre soundbars at $54, wireless speakers at $13.50, headphones at $5.50 and AirPod-like earbuds at $27.</p>
<p>According to marketing research firm IDC, Boat commands over 30% of the wearable market in India and is the fifth-largest brand globally in the category.</p>
<p>The startup &#8212; which clocked revenue of more than $95 million in the financial year that ended in March last year and expects to double this by the current financial year &#8212; sells its products through both online and offline retail channels. Its devices are available through Flipkart, Amazon India and Reliance Retail, as well as Tata Cliq, Croma and Vijay Sales. Analysts at HDFC bank estimated in a note last month that Boat Lifestyle&#8217;s products are available through more than 5,000 retail stores across India, and it plans to enter global markets &#8212; something it would have done much sooner if the pandemic hadn&#8217;t occurred.</p>
<p>&#8220;We see a compelling growth story in <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/boat" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="boat">boAt <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> and believe the company is well-poised to build upon the strong leadership position it has carved out within the industry and stands to benefit from the secular tailwinds of e-commerce growth in India. Warburg Pincus is excited to partner with the management team of boAt led by Aman &amp; Sameer in this journey and we look forward to supporting them through the next phase of the company’s growth,&#8221; said Vishal Mahadevia, managing director and head of Warburg Pincus India, in a statement.</p>
<p>Mehta said Boat has also been lucky with the way it marketed its products. Instead of following the traditional way of advertising, the startup signed up a handful of top young celebrities and cricketers who promoted Boat products. It helped that some of the people it counted on very early on &#8212; such as the cricketer Hardik Pandya (pictured in the lead image) &#8212; have also grown to be more successful in recent years.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear who Boat&#8217;s rivals are today. Certainly smartphone vendors such as Xiaomi and Realme that have expanded their accessories businesses pose a threat. Retailers like Croma, Flipkart and Amazon have also expanded their in-house private labels to launch earphones and other mobile accessories in recent years. Mehta suggested that the market in which Boat operates is not a zero-sum game yet. &#8220;Everyone is growing at the same time,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>An investor who has backed several D2C brands, but not Boat, in India said that it&#8217;s true that many customers of Boat might consider buying Amazon Basics products, but he cautioned that Amazon Basics products are not necessarily the most aspirational items. &#8220;People are buying Boat because their products carry a premium feeling,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Another investor added that Amazon Basics items are also not as aggressively priced in India, as unlike other markets, Amazon is yet to scale its Amazon Basics catalog in the country.</p>
<p>Boat will deploy the fresh capital to shift more of its manufacturing from China to India, and expand to more categories, including gaming keyboards and mice, Mehta said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/indian-electronics-and-lifestyle-brand-boat-raises-100-million-from-warburg-pincus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092262</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Segment redesigned its core systems to solve an existential scaling crisis</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/how-segment-redesigned-its-core-systems-to-solve-an-existential-scaling-crisis/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/how-segment-redesigned-its-core-systems-to-solve-an-existential-scaling-crisis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 18:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Data Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[segment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technical debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2091666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The systemic issues became apparent the way they often do -- when customers began complaining.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://segment.com">Segment</a>, the startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/11/twilio-is-buying-customer-data-startup-segment-for-between-3b-and-4b/">Twilio bought last fall for $3.2 billion</a>, was just beginning to take off in 2015 when it ran into a scaling problem: It was growing so quickly, the tools it had built to process marketing data on its platform were starting to outgrow the original system design.</p>
<p>Inaction would cause the company to hit a technology wall, managers feared. Every early-stage startup craves growth and <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/segment-io" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="segment-io">Segment <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> was no exception, but it also needed to begin thinking about how to make its data platform more resilient or reach a point where it could no longer handle the data it was moving through the system. It was &#8212; in a real sense &#8212; an existential crisis for the young business.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The project that came out of their efforts was called Centrifuge, and its purpose was to move data through Segment&#8217;s data pipes to wherever customers needed it quickly and efficiently at the lowest operating cost.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Segment&#8217;s engineering team began thinking hard about what a more robust and scalable system would look like. As it turned out, their vision would evolve in a number of ways between the end of 2015 and today, and with each iteration, they would take a leap in terms of how efficiently they allocated resources and processed data moving through its systems.</p>
<p>The project that came out of their efforts was called Centrifuge, and its purpose was to move data through Segment&#8217;s data pipes to wherever customers needed it quickly and efficiently at the lowest operating cost. This is the story of how that system came together.</p>
<h2>Growing pains</h2>
<p>The systemic issues became apparent the way they often do &#8212; when customers began complaining. When Tido Carriero, Segment&#8217;s chief product development officer, came on board at the end of 2015, he was charged with finding a solution. The issue involved the original system design, which like many early iterations from startups was designed to get the product to market with little thought given to future growth and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/23/when-choosing-a-tech-stack-look-before-you-leap/">the technical debt payment</a> was coming due.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;We had [designed] our initial integrations architecture in a way that just wasn&#8217;t scalable in a number of different ways. We had been experiencing massive growth, and our CEO [Peter Reinhardt] came to me maybe three times within a month and reported various scaling challenges that either customers or partners of ours had alerted him to,&#8221; said Carriero.</span></p>
<p>The good news was that it was attracting customers and partners to the platform at a rapid clip, but it could all have come crashing down if the company didn&#8217;t improve the underlying system architecture to support the robust growth. As Carriero reports, that made it a stressful time, but having <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/15/why-dropbox-decided-to-drop-aws-and-build-its-own-infrastructure-and-network/">come from Dropbox</a>, he was actually in a position to understand that it&#8217;s possible to completely rearchitect the business&#8217;s technology platform and live to tell about it.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the things I learned from my past life [at Dropbox] is when you have a problem that&#8217;s just so core to your business, at a certain point you start to realize that you are the only company in the world kind of experiencing this problem at this kind of scale,&#8221; he said. For Dropbox that was related to storage, and for Segment it was processing large amounts of data concurrently.</p>
<p>In the build-versus-buy equation, Carriero knew that he had to build his way out of the problem. There was nothing out there that could solve Segment&#8217;s unique scaling issues. &#8220;Obviously that led us to believe that we really need to think about this a little bit differently, and that was when our Centrifuge V2 architecture was born,&#8221; he said.</p>
<h2>Building the imperfect beast</h2>
<p>The company began measuring system performance, at the time processing 8,442 events per second. When it began building V2 of its architecture, that number had grown to an average of 18,907 events per second.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/how-segment-redesigned-its-core-systems-to-solve-an-existential-scaling-crisis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2091666</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Extra Crunch Perks: 20% discount on all TechCrunch 2021 events</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/extra-crunch-perks-20-discount-on-all-techcrunch-2021-events/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/extra-crunch-perks-20-discount-on-all-techcrunch-2021-events/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Travis Bernard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 18:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscriptions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2092308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve announced our slate of 2021 events, and we’d like to take this time to remind you that annual or two-year Extra Crunch members can receive a 20% discount on all TechCrunch 2021 virtual events. How to get the discount If you’re an annual or two-year subscriber, contact extracrunch@techcrunch.com to request your event ticket discount [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;ve announced our slate of 2021 events, and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">we’d like to take this time to remind you that annual or two-year Extra Crunch members can receive a 20% discount on </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/announcing-techcrunchs-2021-event-calendar/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">all TechCrunch 2021 virtual events.</span></a></p>
<p><b>How to get the discount</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re an annual or two-year subscriber, contact </span><a href="mailto:extracrunch@techcrunch.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">extracrunch@techcrunch.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to request your event ticket discount code. Our customer service team typically responds with the code within 24 hours. Some exclusions of ticket types may apply, and monthly members are not eligible for TechCrunch event ticket discounts.  </span></p>
<p><b>What else is included with an annual Extra Crunch membership?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extra Crunch is a membership program from TechCrunch that helps you spot technology trends and opportunities, build better startups and stay connected. It features thousands of articles, including weekly investor surveys, daily private market analysis and expert interviews on fundraising, growth, monetization and other work topics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extra Crunch members can also find answers to burning questions about startups and investing through </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/announcing-the-extra-crunch-live-event-series/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extra Crunch Live</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and stay informed with our members-only Extra Crunch newsletters. Other benefits include an improved TechCrunch.com experience and </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/15/extra-crunch-members-save-money-with-partner-perks-and-event-discounts/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">savings on software services</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typeform, DocSend, Crunchbase and more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Please contact </span><a href="mailto:extracrunch@techcrunch.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">extracrunch@techcrunch.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> if you have any additional questions or if you are interested in upgrading your membership to an annual or two-year plan.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/extra-crunch-perks-20-discount-on-all-techcrunch-2021-events/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2092308</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GitHub alumni are building Rewatch, a solution for your Zoom fatigue</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/rewatch-seed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/rewatch-seed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 18:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haystack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rewatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videoconferencing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2090478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The rise of distributed teams in response to the coronavirus has led to more video-conferencing meetings for all of us. As offices remain closed, distributed work is forcing companies to figure out a better way than Zoom or Google Hangouts to meet with employees across time zones and teams. Rewatch wants to make meetings more [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><!-- Copy and paste the converted output. --></p>
<p><!-- Copy and paste the converted output. --></p>
<p>The rise of distributed teams in response to the coronavirus has led to more video-conferencing meetings for all of us. As offices remain closed, distributed work is forcing companies to figure out a better way than Zoom or Google Hangouts to meet with employees across time zones and teams.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://rewatch.tv/">Rewatch</a> wants to make meetings more efficient, and maybe even shorter. Co-founded by<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/connors"> Connor Sears</a> and<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/scottjg/"> Scott Goldman</a>, Rewatch creates and organizes private video channels for companies to store meetings so employees can sift through them on their own time.</p>
<p>And at its core, <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/rewatch" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="rewatch">Rewatch <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> is a counterintuitive play: The startup thinks it can combat &#8220;Zoom fatigue&#8221; by giving employees more ways to watch video-conferencing calls.</p>
<p>The product works like this: Companies can record their meetings, over Google Hangouts or Zoom, and then Rewatch archives the meetings into a database. Using tags and notes, the videos become more searchable and easier to find. For example, you can tag a co-worker in a meeting in which they got an unexpected shout-out. Or you can search for the last time a manager brought up the project you’re working on.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2090486 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png" alt="" width="879" height="753" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png?resize=150,128 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png?resize=300,257 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png?resize=768,657 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png?resize=680,582 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png?resize=1536,1315 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Home.png?resize=50,43 50w" sizes="(max-width: 879px) 100vw, 879px" /></p>
<p>The video libraries, which the company describes as “mini-YouTube channels,” also include transcriptions of all meetings. Rewatch is turning synchronous meetings into asynchronous bulletins and documents.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2090487 aligncenter" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png" alt="" width="676" height="559" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png?resize=150,124 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png?resize=300,248 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png?resize=768,635 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png?resize=680,562 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png?resize=1536,1270 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Collaboration.png?resize=50,41 50w" sizes="(max-width: 676px) 100vw, 676px" /></p>
<p>“In the past, the only way to scale a meeting was just to have a longer meeting, or more meetings,” Sears said.</p>
<p>If Rewatch works, the founders hope to see meetings shift from squares of muted floating heads to interactive across various teams and time zones with text and annotations.</p>
<p>Sears first had the idea for Rewatch when he was an employee at <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/github" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="github">GitHub, <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> a space for developers. GitHub, which is fully distributed, created an internal YouTube channel to enable employees across time zones to work with one another. Now, the two co-founders are trying to take one of GitHub’s internally loved features and bring it, and more, to the mainstream.</p>
<p>So far, the startup has been able to land a number of customers, including GitHub, although it wouldn’t disclose total numbers. When it launches, the company will charge a subscription fee, but Sears and Goldman have not disclosed the pricing yet.</p>
<p>One of Rewatch’s competitors is Google Drive, which has lagged in creativity around storing and structuring video content. The startup competes with the tool by adding more search-friendly features for video like live transcriptions. Other competitors include Berlin-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/21/acapela/">Acapela</a>, which is working on asynchronous meetings, and Storyboard, a podcast company that helps directors publish <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20201216005187/en/Storyboard-Raises-4.5-Million-Round-Led-by-CRV-to-Bring-the-Consumer-Podcast-Boom-to-the-Enterprise">on-demand audio content to their stakeholders</a>. Both companies have recently raised millions of dollars.</p>
<p>While innovation around how meetings are held certainly feels important, Rewatch and others are betting that employees will turn to these content repositories on a semi-often basis and engage with them in a meaningful way. But how many of us watch the standup we missed while on vacation? The business is contingent on that singular consumer habit.</p>
<p>This reality doesn&#8217;t mean innovation isn’t welcome. It just means that a huge shift in consumer habits needs to change in order for this startup, and many others, to be successful. And that too-early-to-know reality makes the fact that investors have put millions into the startup<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/startup-cynicism/"> even more compelling</a>.</p>
<p>Rewatch has convinced a number investors on its vision. The startup tells TechCrunch that it has raised a $2 million pre-seed round led by Semil Shah at <a class="crunchbase-link" href="https://crunchbase.com/organization/haystack-5" target="_blank" data-type="organization" data-entity="haystack-5">Haystack <span class="crunchbase-tooltip-indicator"></span></a> with participation from Kent Goldman at Upside Partnership. Other investors include Gumroad CEO Sahil Lavingia, GitHub CTO Jason Warner and SVP of Zendesk Jason Smeale.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QQlq15wewg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/startup-cynicism/">Startup cynicism and Substack, or Clubhouse, or Miami or …</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Startup cynicism and Substack, or Clubhouse, or Miami or …&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/29/startup-cynicism/embed/#?secret=QQlq15wewg" data-secret="QQlq15wewg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/05/rewatch-seed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2090478</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
