<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 18:59:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Roc Nation&#8217;s VC Neil Sirni lays out his investment strategy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/neil-sirni-arrive-interview/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/neil-sirni-arrive-interview/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 18:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arrive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roc nation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jay-Z&#8217;s Roc Nation announced in 2017 that it was forming a venture investment arm called Arrive. And the firm has been busy since then — co-founder and President Neil Sirni said Arrive has made 29 investments thus far. At the same time, Sirni hasn&#8217;t really said much about those investments publicly, or about the broader [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Jay-Z&#8217;s <a href="https://www.rocnation.com">Roc Nation</a> announced in 2017 that it was <a href="https://www.billboard.com/articles/columns/hip-hop/7710322/jay-z-roc-nation-arrive-start-up-platform">forming a venture investment arm</a> called <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/arrivevc/">Arrive</a>. And the firm has been busy since then — co-founder and President Neil Sirni said Arrive has made 29 investments thus far.</p>
<p>At the same time, Sirni hasn&#8217;t really said much about those investments publicly, or about the broader strategy. So he reached out to me a few months ago, suggesting that he was ready to provide more details about Arrive.</p>
<p>&#8220;We’re now three years, 29 investments in and expanding – so it felt like the right time to start opening up a bit,&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Over the course of a few back-and-forth emails, we discussed how Arrive fits into the larger aims of Roc Nation, how Sirni (a former Goldman Sachs executive) makes investment decisions and where he&#8217;s focusing next. (Spoiler: Southeast Asia is a big part of that answer.)</p>
<p>He was also eager to provide testimonials from Arrive&#8217;s portfolio companies — for example, Outlier.org founder Aaron Rasmussen said that &#8220;when Arrive commits to your mission, they commit,&#8221; while Helm co-founder and CEO Giri Sreenivas said that the firm &#8220;brings something that I don’t see in traditional institutional investors &#8211; legitimate operational expertise around brand and marketing.&#8221;</p>
<p>You can read our email Q&amp;A, lightly edited for length and style, below.</p>
<p><strong>What is Arrive and how does it fit into the larger Roc Nation umbrella?</strong></p>
<p>Arrive is Roc Nation’s venture platform. Roc Nation is a full-service music and sports management, music publishing and entertainment company founded by Jay-Z. Roc Nation and its affiliated companies have built a diversified business that employs several hundred people. These businesses include artist and athlete representation, a portfolio of spirit brands, an apparel line, a philanthropy division that manages four charitable organizations, a content streaming service, a digital team that oversees social media accounts with over 1.4 billion followers, a sales and marketing division that works on countless partnerships with Fortune 500 companies, communications, video production and live event production, among others.</p>
<p>The Roc Nation infrastructure can add value to many different types of businesses across various stages, which is why we created Arrive. For consumer-facing businesses, Arrive leverages the Roc Nation infrastructure to help companies with branding, creative, marketing, communications, and other services. For enterprise, we use our broad network of B2B relationships to help with business development.</p>
<p>Being a strategic venture investor on the cap table of a portfolio company is not only about the investment but also how much human capital a fund can deploy to drive long-term, real and unique value for entrepreneurs and their businesses. So, we’re leveraging the broader Roc Nation platform to help portfolio companies and, in turn, receiving access to great entrepreneurs.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fYRexTCV6W"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/outlier-series-b/">MasterClass co-founder&#8217;s Outlier.org raises $30M for affordable, virtual college courses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MasterClass co-founder&#8217;s Outlier.org raises $30M for affordable, virtual college courses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/outlier-series-b/embed/#?secret=fYRexTCV6W" data-secret="fYRexTCV6W" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>What kinds of investments do you normally make — types of companies, size of investment, etc?</strong></p>
<p>We’re relatively sector and stage agnostic. We have dedicated capital in an early-stage fund that tends to focus on Series A to Series C, but we’ve also started to SPV growth and pre-IPO investments as we lay the foundation for a dedicated growth vehicle later this year.</p>
<p><strong>How do you make investment decisions? Is Jay-Z involved in the process?</strong></p>
<p>We gravitate toward companies that we can provide meaningful assistance to but that are outside of Roc Nation’s core industries of music and traditional sports. Thanks to our platform, that is an extremely broad opportunity set. To date, we’ve made 29 investments under the Arrive umbrella in everything from fintech, insurtech, edtech, health &amp; wellness, social, and gaming. Geographically, we’re investing roughly 80% in North America, primarily the US, and 20% across Southeast Asia, namely, Singapore, Indonesia, and Vietnam. As a strategic investor, we never lead deals and always co-invest.</p>
<p>Our long-term focus is on driving real and unique value for our portfolio companies. If we remain hyper-focused on this mission, we believe we have the opportunity to build an enduring brand as a top tier strategic investor.</p>
<p>Jay-Z approves every Arrive opportunity; he, Juan Perez, and Desiree Perez are overwhelmingly supportive of Arrive and what we’re collectively trying to accomplish.</p>
<p><strong>TechCrunch: What&#8217;s your biggest success story so far?</strong></p>
<p>Neil Sirni: I’m very proud of being co-founder of Arrive and what it took to get here. In the grand scheme of things, we’re just getting started, but I’ve been an entrepreneur — after leaving a large public company — for over 10 years now. It’s been a roller coaster with many sacrifices, but I can understand and relate to our founders and their journey which makes this experience even more rewarding. The founders of Roc Nation have built their businesses brick by brick as well, so the entire organization is united by this entrepreneurial mindset. I still consider myself a founder and operator first, whose business happens to be making investments.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1607815" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1607815" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-1607815" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="408" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg 2600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?resize=768,461 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?resize=680,408 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?resize=1536,922 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?resize=2048,1229 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-496615428.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1607815" class="wp-caption-text">NEW YORK, NY &#8211; OCTOBER 20: Jay Z performs during Tidal X: 1020 at Barclays Center on October 20, 2015 in the Brooklyn borough of New York City. (Photo by Taylor Hill/FilmMagic)</p></div></p>
<p><strong>Given that Arrive has been around for a few years, what made you feel like this is the time to start talking more openly about the fund?</strong></p>
<p>When Arrive launched a few years ago, I hated the idea of talking about what we’re going to do. Instead, we wanted to quietly actually go do it; learn, improve, build and, in the process, demonstrate that we’re not, and never will be, tourists in the venture ecosystem. We’re now three years, 29 investments in and expanding – so it felt like the right time to start opening up a bit.</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s an example of an investment where working with Arrive/Roc Nation led to gains beyond the financial investment?</strong></p>
<p>Arrive functions like many other investors in that we spend time understanding a company’s vision and then try to provide them meaningful levers to pull to help drive their success. Our toolkit is unique thanks to the Roc Nation platform and network. We’ve found that both our portfolio companies and their other investors, typically traditional venture funds, find those levers complementary and additive to the cap table.</p>
<p>Arrive typically works with portfolio companies across three main areas. The first is creative and brand marketing.  The second is business development and partnerships. The third is communications.</p>
<p>Communications efforts are generally focused on driving short-term or immediate awareness. Many of our portfolio companies receive broader press coverage when we invest in them. That initial attention typically dies down within a week or two although those news stories remain as searchable assets that the company might not otherwise have. While this can be of some value, especially for consumer businesses, we believe it’s at the bottom of the list compared to the long-term benefits that can be derived from Roc Nation’s underlying infrastructure in brand marketing and business development.</p>
<p>In terms of creative and brand marketing, we’ve likely saved our earlier stage portfolio, in aggregate, over a million dollars by providing brand and agency work at no cost.  Examples of this include campaign ideation, graphic design, video production, hosting live events, and product integrations, among other activities.</p>
<p>For business development and partnerships support, we have leveraged our network to help portfolio companies launch their own internal philanthropic platforms, leveraged our B2B relationships to introduce new partners and customers, brought in other strategic investors in a targeted way, helped companies navigate endorsement deals, and recruited non-technical executive talent to join their companies.</p>
<p>We don’t pretend to be a magic bullet, no investor can be, but we’re focused on continuously improving and building on the services that we provide to our portfolio companies. The founder journey is never a straight line and we pride ourselves on being willing to do whatever we can on their behalf. Stephen Francis, SVP at Arrive, and I are accessible to our portfolio companies any day and time.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aZ3LkFdOP7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/">10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/embed/#?secret=aZ3LkFdOP7" data-secret="aZ3LkFdOP7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>Do you see these investments as primarily strategic for Roc Nation, or are you focused on financial returns?</strong></p>
<p>‘Strategic’ investor, in the context of Arrive, refers to the strategic value that we bring to the cap table of a portfolio company.  We leverage that strategic value to get into deals and form relationships with entrepreneurs in whom we have high conviction.  Our ultimate goal is financial return and Arrive’s investments are not meant to be strategic in nature for Roc Nation as an operating company. Instead, an investment from Arrive is meant to be strategic for the portfolio company.</p>
<p><strong>You said you&#8217;re stage agnostic with capital devoted to different stages. Can you say anything more what the breakdown is in terms of early stage vs. later growth deals, and how that might change with the new growth fund?</strong></p>
<p>Of our 29 investments, I would classify 25 as early stage and 4 as growth.  In regards to percentage of capital, the 4 growth investments account for a little over 35% of total capital deployed. When we do have a dedicated growth fund, I expect the volume of growth investments to pick up to roughly 3 – 6 per year.</p>
<p><strong> What are your priorities for 2021?</strong></p>
<p>At a high level our priorities are to build out a larger team to ensure that we’re staying very engaged with the portfolio as we scale and to continue being aggressive in deploying more capital to back great companies.</p>
<p>On a more granular level I’m looking forward to physically getting back to Southeast Asia, namely Singapore, Indonesia and Vietnam, on a regular basis. We’re really bullish on the region and believe it’s only a matter of time before more venture funds deploy significant capital there. We started to invest a lot of time there in 2019 as part of our plan to deploy roughly 30% of our early-stage fund in the region. That expansion has been hindered by COVID-19. However, I’ll make quarterly trips once travel normalizes. There is nothing like in-person interaction to build relationships and trust, especially internationally.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vwxTZI77Lg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/how-vcs-invested-in-asia-and-europe-in-2020/">How VCs invested in Asia and Europe in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How VCs invested in Asia and Europe in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/22/how-vcs-invested-in-asia-and-europe-in-2020/embed/#?secret=vwxTZI77Lg" data-secret="vwxTZI77Lg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/neil-sirni-arrive-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146297</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Y Combinator-backed Uiflow wants to accelerate no-code enterprise app creation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/y-combinator-backed-uiflow-wants-to-accelerate-no-code-enterprise-app-creation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/y-combinator-backed-uiflow-wants-to-accelerate-no-code-enterprise-app-creation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 18:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uiflow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch recently caught up with recent Y Combinator graduate Uiflow, a startup that is building a no-code enterprise app creation service. If you are thinking wait, don&#8217;t a number of companies already do that?, the answer is yes. But what Quickbase, Smartsheet and others are working on isn&#8217;t quite the same thing, at least from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch recently caught up with recent Y Combinator graduate <a href="https://www.uiflow.com/">Uiflow</a>, a startup that is building a no-code enterprise app creation service.</p>
<p>If you are thinking <em>wait, don&#8217;t a number of companies already do that?</em>, the answer is yes. But what <a href="https://www.quickbase.com/">Quickbase</a>, <a href="https://www.smartsheet.com/">Smartsheet</a> and others are working on isn&#8217;t quite the same thing, at least from the startup&#8217;s perspective.</p>
<p>Uiflow, a Bay Area-based concern that has been alive for far less than a year, has built an app creation tool that works with whatever backend a large company currently employs, and helps its development team build apps collaboratively. As the startup explained in <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/uiflow-studio">a public posting</a>, customer developers can import Figma files while their engineers can use existing UI libraries, and product managers can quickly vet an app&#8217;s logic.</p>
<p>The service is akin to a &#8220;cross between Unity and Figma,&#8221; Uiflow <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/uiflow">says</a>.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what its own user interface looks like, per a screenshot the company provided to TechCrunch after an interview:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2146281" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="383" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image-42.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p>Per Y Combinator, the company has closed a pre-seed round of more than $500,000. The company told TechCrunch that it has been talking to investors lately &#8212; as essentially every Y Combinator-backed startup does after their public unveiling &#8212;  but appears to be holding off raising more capital until it fully launches self-service of its product; the company may also accelerate its hiring efforts once its self-serve GTM motion is more broadly available.</p>
<p>The startup told TechCrunch that after its Product Hunt <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/uiflow-studio">launch</a> it picked up around 1,200 signups. It&#8217;s vetting the group and letting in some as pilot customers. Those customers currently pay the company, so it has revenue, although the startup is more product-focused at the moment than centered around boosting its short-term revenues.</p>
<p>Uiflow thinks that its target customers are companies with 250 or more workers, the scale at which a company begins to start thinking about its own UI elements. However, Uiflow is talking to companies with 100 to 1,000 customers, it said.</p>
<p>The five-person team is building a service in a market that is more than active at the moment. As TechCrunch has explored, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/22/five-vcs-talk-about-how-no-code-is-going-horizontal-across-the-worlds-industries/">private-market investors are bullish on the no-code space</a>, especially after the COVID-19 pandemic bolstered the pace at which companies large and small moved toward digital solutions. No-code and low-code services came into greater demand as accelerating digital transformation efforts met the market&#8217;s general dearth of available developer talent.</p>
<p>TechCrunch has covered the no-code space <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/22/creatio-raises-68m-as-the-low-code-space-keeps-attracting-huge-checks/">extensively in recent quarters</a>, given both rising market demand for its products and what seemed to be growing investor demand for shares in startups pursuing the model. All that&#8217;s to say that there&#8217;s a reasonable chance that we&#8217;ll hear from Uiflow soon regarding a fresh capital raise. Let&#8217;s see how long that takes.</p>
<p>In the meantime, here&#8217;s a photo of the Uiflow team. In 2021-style, it&#8217;s a Zoom shot:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146301" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146301" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2146301 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="255" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg 2123w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?resize=150,56 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?resize=300,112 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?resize=768,288 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?resize=680,255 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?resize=1536,576 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?resize=2048,768 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/uiflow-team-march-2020-1.jpg?resize=50,19 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146301" class="wp-caption-text">From upper left, clockwise: Michael Tildahl, Eric Rowell (CTO and co-founder), Brian Lichliter, Rocco Cataldo and D. Sol Eun (CEO and co-founder). Via the company.<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> </span></p></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GVVtST3KWY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/22/five-vcs-talk-about-how-no-code-is-going-horizontal-across-the-worlds-industries/">Five VCs discuss how no-code is going horizontal across the world’s industries</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Five VCs discuss how no-code is going horizontal across the world’s industries&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/22/five-vcs-talk-about-how-no-code-is-going-horizontal-across-the-worlds-industries/embed/#?secret=GVVtST3KWY" data-secret="GVVtST3KWY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/y-combinator-backed-uiflow-wants-to-accelerate-no-code-enterprise-app-creation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146267</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pitch your startup to seasoned tech leaders, and a live audience, on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/pitch-your-startup-to-seasoned-tech-leaders-and-a-live-audience-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/pitch-your-startup-to-seasoned-tech-leaders-and-a-live-audience-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 17:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ECL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[court cunningham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pitch-off]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rick heitzmann]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TechCrunch is known for its pitch-offs. We&#8217;ve had them in cities all over the world, and heard from hundreds of startups who have shared the story of their company on our stages. We&#8217;re excited to be bringing the pitch-off to Extra Crunch Live. Anyone in the audience on an episode of Extra Crunch Live can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">TechCrunch is known for its pitch-offs. We&#8217;ve had them in cities all over the world, and heard from hundreds of startups who have shared the story of their company on our stages.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re excited to be bringing the pitch-off to Extra Crunch Live.</p>
<p>Anyone in the audience on an episode of Extra Crunch Live can virtually &#8220;raise their hand&#8221; to be selected to pitch in front of the audience and get feedback from our all-star guests.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>On ECL, pitch-off startups will have two minutes to tell us about their company. This is the equivalent of an elevator pitch — imagine running into a VC or potential customer at a tech conference like Disrupt or bumping into them at a park. As such, no visual aids are allowed, including decks, videos, demoes, etc.</p>
<p>Essentially, what can you convey with your words, in a short time frame, to get people to both understand your startup and be excited about it?</p>
<p>This is a critical skill, and we&#8217;re creating the space for founders to practice and improve.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m amped to have Firstmark&#8217;s Rick Heitzmann and Orchard founder Court Cunningham as guests on Extra Crunch Live on May 5. This founder/investor duo know exactly what it takes to deliver a great pitch. Do you have what it takes? <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-firstmark-capital-and-orchard">You can register here for free!</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nyvfsoxLqB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/hear-how-to-raise-big-funding-and-use-it-well-from-firstmarks-rick-heitzmann-and-orchards-court-cunningham/">Hear how to raise big funding (and use it well) from FirstMark&#8217;s Rick Heitzmann and Orchard&#8217;s Court Cunningham</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Hear how to raise big funding (and use it well) from FirstMark&#8217;s Rick Heitzmann and Orchard&#8217;s Court Cunningham&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/hear-how-to-raise-big-funding-and-use-it-well-from-firstmarks-rick-heitzmann-and-orchards-court-cunningham/embed/#?secret=nyvfsoxLqB" data-secret="nyvfsoxLqB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>To be selected for the pitch-off, you must be present in the audience during the live show. Instructions on how to raise your hand will come at the top of the show, so don&#8217;t be late!</p>
<p>See you on Wednesday!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CHqnjhUb9B"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/">11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/embed/#?secret=CHqnjhUb9B" data-secret="CHqnjhUb9B" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/pitch-your-startup-to-seasoned-tech-leaders-and-a-live-audience-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ByteDance CFO assumes role as new TikTok CEO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/bytedance-cfo-assumes-role-as-tiktok-ceo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/bytedance-cfo-assumes-role-as-tiktok-ceo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lucas Matney]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 17:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief financial officer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Mayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[li auto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanessa Pappas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zhang Yiming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zhongguancun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eight months after former TikTok CEO Kevin Mayer quit in the midst of a full-court press from the Trump administration against the Chinese-owned social media giant, TikTok finally has a new permanent leader. ByteDance&#8217;s recently hired CFO Shouzi Chew will be assuming the role as TikTok CEO while still holding the CFO role at its [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Eight months after former TikTok CEO Kevin Mayer quit in the midst of a full-court press from the Trump administration against the Chinese-owned social media giant, TikTok finally has a new permanent leader.</p>
<p>ByteDance&#8217;s recently hired CFO Shouzi Chew will be assuming the role as TikTok CEO while still holding the CFO role at its parent organization, the company <a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/tiktok-names-ceo-and-coo">announced</a> Friday morning. It&#8217;s a bold move, likely signaling that the company believes that the worst of its tussles with the U.S. executive branch are over as President Biden has seemed uninterested in picking up former President Trump&#8217;s pet project.</p>
<p>Vanessa Pappas, who was serving as interim CEO, will take the role of COO going forward.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;The leadership team of Shou and Vanessa sets the stage for sustained growth,&#8221; ByteDance CEO Yiming Zhang said in a press release. &#8220;Shou brings deep knowledge of the company and industry, having led a team that was among our earliest investors, and having worked in the technology sector for a decade. He will add depth to the team, focusing on areas including corporate governance and long-term business initiatives.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prior to joining ByteDance earlier this year, Chew was an executive at Xiaomi, with stints at DST and Goldman Sachs earlier in his career.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ih0DocJIGF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/tiktok-ceo-kevin-mayer-resigns/">TikTok CEO Kevin Mayer resigns after 100 days</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok CEO Kevin Mayer resigns after 100 days&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/26/tiktok-ceo-kevin-mayer-resigns/embed/#?secret=ih0DocJIGF" data-secret="ih0DocJIGF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Xhbddfugya"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/how-tiktok-decides-who-to-make-famous/">How TikTok decides who to make famous</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How TikTok decides who to make famous&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/17/how-tiktok-decides-who-to-make-famous/embed/#?secret=Xhbddfugya" data-secret="Xhbddfugya" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/bytedance-cfo-assumes-role-as-tiktok-ceo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Riot Games updates its privacy notice to start developing voice comms moderation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/riot-games-updates-its-privacy-notice-to-start-developing-voice-comms-moderation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/riot-games-updates-its-privacy-notice-to-start-developing-voice-comms-moderation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 17:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Riot Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone who has played a video game with voice chat in the past decade knows that there is some risk involved. You might be greeted by friendly teammates, but you may also hear some of the most toxic language you&#8217;ve ever heard in your life. Riot Games, the game developer behind ultra popular titles like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Anyone who has played a video game with voice chat in the past decade knows that there is some risk involved. You might be greeted by friendly teammates, but you may also hear some of the most toxic language you&#8217;ve ever heard in your life.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.riotgames.com/en">Riot Games</a>, the game developer behind ultra popular titles like League of Legends and Valorant, is thinking hard about this. And taking action.</p>
<p>The developer is today announcing changes to its privacy notice that allow for it to capture and evaluate voice comms when a report is submitted around disruptive behavior. The changes to the policy are Riot-wide, meaning that all players across all games will need to accept those changes. However, the only game that is scheduled to utilize these new abilities is Valorant, as it is the most voice chat-heavy game from Riot.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The plan here is to store relevant audio data in the account&#8217;s registered region and evaluate it to see if the behavior agreement was violated. This process is triggered by a report being submitted, and is not an always-on system. If a violation has occurred, the data will be made available to the player in violation and will ultimately be deleted once there is no further need for it following reviews. If no violation is detected, the data will be deleted.</p>
<p>Before we go any further, let me just say that this is a big fucking deal. Publishers and developers have long known that toxicity in gaming is not only a terrible user experience, but it&#8217;s actively preventing large swaths of potential gamers from dedicating themselves to it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Players are experiencing a lot of pain in voice comms and that pain takes the form of all kinds of different disruption in behavior and it can be pretty harmful,&#8221; said Head of Players Dynamics Weszt Hart. &#8220;We recognize that, and we have made a promise to players that we will do everything that we could in this space.&#8221;</p>
<p>Voice chat often makes games much richer and more fun. Particularly during the pandemic, people are craving more human connection. But in a tense environment like competitive games, that connection can turn sour.</p>
<p>As a gamer myself, I can safely say that some of the most hurtful experiences of my life have been while playing video games with strangers.</p>
<p>To be clear, Riot isn&#8217;t getting specific with how exactly this voice chat moderation will work. The first step is the update to its privacy notice, which gives players a heads up and gives the company the right to start evaluating voice comms.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s incredibly difficult to police voice comms. Not only do you need to be transparent with users and update any legal documents (which is arguably the easiest step, and the one Riot is taking today), but you must develop the right technology to do this, all while protecting player privacy.</p>
<p>I spoke with Hart and Data Protection Officer and CISO Chris Hymes about the changes. The duo said that the actual system for detecting behavior violations within voice comms is still under development. It may focus on automated voice-to-text transcription, and go through the same system as text chat moderation, or it may rely more heavily on machine learning to actually detect an infringement via voice alone.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re looking at the technologies and we&#8217;re trying to land on the one that we want to launch with,&#8221; said Hart. &#8220;We&#8217;ve been putting a lot of time and effort into space and we have a pretty good idea of the direction that we&#8217;re going to take. But what we want to do is to have some audio to work with, to better understand if any other approaches that we&#8217;re looking at are going to be the best. To do this, we need to be able to process something real, and not just make a good guess.&#8221;</p>
<p>To get to that answer as quickly as possible, he added, the first step of updating the privacy notice had to go into effect.</p>
<p>Hart and Hymes also said that some layer of human moderation will be involved to ensure that whatever system is being developed is working properly and can ultimately be rolled out to other languages and other titles, as the system is initially being developed for Valorant in North America.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8XRwRxUkxE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/vcs-discuss-gamings-biggest-infrastructure-investment-opportunities-in-2021/">VCs discuss gaming&#8217;s biggest infrastructure investment opportunities in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;VCs discuss gaming&#8217;s biggest infrastructure investment opportunities in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/08/vcs-discuss-gamings-biggest-infrastructure-investment-opportunities-in-2021/embed/#?secret=8XRwRxUkxE" data-secret="8XRwRxUkxE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Advances in machine learning and natural language processing are making that development easier than it was 10, or even two, years ago. But even in a world where a machine learning algorithm could accurately detect hate speech, with all its nuances, there is yet another hurdle.</p>
<p>Gamers, even from one title to the next, have their own language. There is a whole lexicon of words and terms used by gamers that aren&#8217;t used in every day life. This adds yet another complication to the process of developing this system.</p>
<p>Still, this is a critical step in ensuring that Riot Games titles, and hopefully other titles as well, become an inclusive environment where anyone who wants to game feels safe and able to do so.</p>
<p>And Riot is careful to understand that developing games is a holistic endeavor. Everything from game design to anti-cheating measures to behavior guidelines and moderation have an effect on the overall experience of the player.</p>
<p>Alongside this announcement, the company is also introducing an update to its terms of service with an updated global refund policy and new language around anti-cheat software for current and future Riot titles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/riot-games-updates-its-privacy-notice-to-start-developing-voice-comms-moderation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146170</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cloud gaming service Shadow taken over by OVHcloud founder</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/cloud-gaming-service-shadow-taken-over-by-ovhcloud-founder/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/cloud-gaming-service-shadow-taken-over-by-ovhcloud-founder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BLADE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jean-Baptiste Kempf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Octave Klaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OVH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OVHcloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shadow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blade, the French startup behind cloud gaming service Shadow, has been acquired by Octave Klaba’s fund following a commercial court order. Klaba is better known as the founder of OVHcloud, a French cloud hosting company. He’s acquiring Blade (and Shadow) through his investment fund Jezby Ventures — not OVHcloud. Shadow is a cloud computing service for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blade, the French startup behind cloud gaming service <a href="https://shadow.tech">Shadow</a>, has been acquired by Octave Klaba’s fund following a commercial court order. Klaba is better known as the founder of <a href="https://www.ovhcloud.com">OVHcloud</a>, a French cloud hosting company. He’s acquiring Blade (and Shadow) through his investment fund Jezby Ventures — not OVHcloud.</p>
<p>Shadow is a cloud computing service for gamers. People can pay a monthly subscription fee and gain access to a gaming PC in a data center. You can connect to this PC from your computer, a smartphone, a tablet or a smart TV. You can see a video stream of what’s happening on the screen and your actions are relayed to the server.</p>
<p>Unlike Google Stadia, Amazon Luna or even Nvidia GeForce Now, you can install whatever you want on your server. You get a full Windows 10 instance so it supports anything from Steam to Photoshop and Excel.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While the French startup has raised more than $100 million across multiple funding rounds, the company couldn’t keep up with pre-orders, didn’t generate enough revenue to be self-sustainable and couldn’t find cash to expand its service. Despite attracting 100,000 paid users, <a href="https://www.nextinpact.com/article/46289/blade-shadow-est-dans-situation-financiere-difficile-dans-attente-dun-repreneur">Next INpact reported</a> that the company had no choice but to go into administration with the commercial court.</p>
<p>Several companies and a group of people <a href="https://www.nextinpact.com/article/46539/blade-shadow-que-proposent-quatre-candidats-a-reprise">submitted takeover bids</a>. In particular, Blade CTO Jean-Baptiste Kempf teamed up with other employees, while Octave Klaba submitted his own offer. Klaba plans to keep all employees except Jean-Baptiste Kempf.</p>
<p>Now, it’s going to be interesting to see how the service changes over the coming weeks. Subscriptions currently start at €12.99 per month in Europe or $11.99 per month in the U.S. It’s unclear whether Shadow will remain available at this price point, how specifications are going to evolve and if the company is going to spin up more servers to attract new clients.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="fr" dir="ltr">Très heureux d’avoir été retenu par le Tribunal de Commerce de Paris pour le 1UP de <a href="https://twitter.com/Shadow_France?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Shadow_France</a> ! </p>
<p>L’ambition est simple : bâtir la meilleure offre du Cloud Gaming au Monde ! On a désormais tout dans 1 seule boite: équipe talentieuse, aucun souci de CAPEX, le marché mondial ! <a href="https://t.co/Yz3RlV02dy">pic.twitter.com/Yz3RlV02dy</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Octave Klaba (@olesovhcom) <a href="https://twitter.com/olesovhcom/status/1388136051076734983?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 30, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RaN7L8uQyR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/cloud-gaming-platform-shadow-gets-a-new-ceo-and-cto/">Cloud gaming platform Shadow gets a new CEO and CTO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cloud gaming platform Shadow gets a new CEO and CTO&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/cloud-gaming-platform-shadow-gets-a-new-ceo-and-cto/embed/#?secret=RaN7L8uQyR" data-secret="RaN7L8uQyR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tndhI9XHpn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/cloud-gaming-platforms-were-2020s-most-overhyped-trend/">Cloud-gaming platforms were 2020&#8217;s most overhyped trend</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Cloud-gaming platforms were 2020&#8217;s most overhyped trend&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/cloud-gaming-platforms-were-2020s-most-overhyped-trend/embed/#?secret=tndhI9XHpn" data-secret="tndhI9XHpn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/cloud-gaming-service-shadow-taken-over-by-ovhcloud-founder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146232</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia&#8217;s Mike Vernal will share how to iterate with tempo at TC Early Stage in July</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/sequoias-mike-vernal-will-share-how-to-iterate-with-tempo-at-tc-early-stage-in-july/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/sequoias-mike-vernal-will-share-how-to-iterate-with-tempo-at-tc-early-stage-in-july/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 16:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Vernal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TC Early Stage is back in July and we have a fantastic lineup in store that&#8217;s laser-focused on marketing and fundraising. That includes, but is not limited to, Sequoia&#8217;s Mike Vernal, whose portfolio companies include Citizen, PicsArt, Whisper, Threads, Houseparty and more. Vernal will be leading a discussion on tempo and product-market fit. The chat [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=sequoiapost">TC Early Stage</a> is back in July and we have a fantastic lineup in store that&#8217;s laser-focused on marketing and fundraising. That includes, but is not limited to, Sequoia&#8217;s Mike Vernal, whose portfolio companies include Citizen, PicsArt, Whisper, Threads, Houseparty and more.</p>
<p>Vernal will be leading a discussion on tempo and product-market fit. The chat stems from Vernal&#8217;s experience as an investor, sharing the lesser-known keys to success to not only secure early investment, but to use it to secure a later-stage investment.</p>
<p>In essence, tempo is everything. At the earliest stage, investors are looking more at the team than the product, knowing that the likelihood of the product changing and evolving is high. That means that the ability to adapt — including the systems in place to collect feedback and willingness to continue iterating — are incredibly important factors.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Vernal will not only stress the importance of tempo and product iteration (and how it relates to fundraising success), he&#8217;ll also share how both enterprise and consumer companies should go about creating these feedback loops with customers and how to iterate quickly.</p>
<p>Vernal joined Sequoia as a partner in 2016. He currently sits on the boards of Citizen, Jumpstart, rideOS, PicsArt, Rockset, Threads and Whisper. Before Sequoia, Mike was VP at Facebook, where he led a variety of product and engineering teams. He co-created Facebook Login and the Graph API.</p>
<p>In other words, he&#8217;s seen and participated in success, and has done the work of product iteration himself.</p>
<p>Vernal joins a stellar lineup of speakers at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=sequoiapost">TC Early Stage</a> in July, including Norwest Venture Partners&#8217; Lisa Wu, Greylock&#8217;s Mike Duboe and Cleo Capital&#8217;s Sarah Kunst, among many others that are soon to be announced.</p>
<p>One of the great things about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=sequoiapost">TC Early Stage</a> is that the show is designed around breakout sessions, with each speaker leading a chat around a specific startup core competency (like fundraising, designing a brand, mastering the art of PR and more). Moreover, there is plenty of time for audience Q&amp;A in each session.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=sequoiapost&amp;display=true">Pick up your ticket for the event</a>, which goes down July 8 and 9, right here. And if you do it before the end of the day today, you&#8217;ll <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/?promo=sequoiapost&amp;display=true">save a cool $100 off</a> of your registration.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			width="99%"
			height="1010"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/sequoias-mike-vernal-will-share-how-to-iterate-with-tempo-at-tc-early-stage-in-july/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145264</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimism reigns at consumer trading services as fintech VC spikes and Robinhood IPO looms</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/optimism-reigns-at-consumer-trading-services-as-fintech-vc-spikes-and-robinhood-ipo-looms/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/optimism-reigns-at-consumer-trading-services-as-fintech-vc-spikes-and-robinhood-ipo-looms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 16:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Index Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robinhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You could be excused for expecting the boom in consumer asset trading to keep going up and to the right. But will it? There are data in both directions.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">With the </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/coinbases-direct-listing-alters-the-landscape-for-fintech-and-crypto-startups/">Coinbase direct listing</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> behind us and the </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/robinhood-files-confidentially-to-go-public/">Robinhood IPO</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> ahead, it’s a heady time for consumer-focused trading apps. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Mix in the impending </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/18/what-etoros-investor-presentation-and-10b-valuation-tells-us-about-robinhood/">SPAC-led debut of eToro</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, general bullishness in the cryptocurrency space, record highs for some equities markets, and recent rounds from </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://public.com/">Public.com</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.m1finance.com/">M1 Finance</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> and U.K.-based </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://freetrade.io/">Freetrade</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, and you could be excused for expecting the boom in consumer asset trading to keep going up and to the right.</span></p>
<p>But will it? There are data in both directions. While recent information could indicate that some of the most lucrative trading activity at companies like Robinhood could be slowing, there’s also encouraging app download information that paints a more bullish picture regarding the durability of the boom in consumer interest regarding savings and investing, which The Exchange has had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/25/will-fading-yolo-sentiment-impact-robinhood-coinbase-and-other-trading-platforms/">an eye on</a> for some time.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Our question today is this: How bullish are companies in the space about continued consumer interest in equities and other asset trading? And why? We’ll also put similar questions to their backers.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995213 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>We’ve compiled notes from <a href="https://accel.com/">Accel</a>’s <a href="https://twitter.com/skg_accel">Sameer Gandhi</a> about views concerning Public as one of its backers and <a href="https://www.indexventures.com/">Index</a>’s <a href="https://twitter.com/janatindex">Jan Hammer</a> about Robinhood and its market, as well as comments from Public.com and M1 Finance about what they see regarding consumer trading interest in the future. Thoughts from <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-le">Robert Le, </a><a href="https://pitchbook.com/">PitchBook&#8217;s</a> senior emerging technology analyst, cap things off.</p>
<p>We’ll start with a short look at some data to help ground ourselves regarding where consumer trading demand appears to be today, then consider what the companies in the ring and their backers are thinking. We’ll close with a synthesis of all the perspectives to come up with hype-adjusted expectations for the rest of 2021.</p>
<h2>Bullish data, bearish data</h2>
<p>Coinbase executed its direct listing on the back of one of the most impressive quarters we’ve ever seen in the realm of business results, meaning it began to trade when it looked just about as good as a company can. Will the same hold true for Robinhood and company?</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/optimism-reigns-at-consumer-trading-services-as-fintech-vc-spikes-and-robinhood-ipo-looms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146147</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heirlume raises $1.38M to remove the barriers of trademark registration for small businesses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/heirlume-raises-1-38m-to-remove-the-barriers-of-trademark-registration-for-small-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/heirlume-raises-1-38m-to-remove-the-barriers-of-trademark-registration-for-small-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 15:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heirlume]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellectual property law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trademark]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Platforms like Shopify, Stripe and WordPress have done a lot to make essential business-building tools &#8212; like running storefronts, accepting payments and building websites &#8212; accessible to businesses with even the most modest budgets. But some very key aspects of setting up a company remain expensive, time-consuming affairs that can be cost-prohibitive for small businesses [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Platforms like Shopify, Stripe and WordPress have done a lot to make essential business-building tools &#8212; like running storefronts, accepting payments and building websites &#8212; accessible to businesses with even the most modest budgets. But some very key aspects of setting up a company remain expensive, time-consuming affairs that can be cost-prohibitive for small businesses — but that, if ignored, can result in the failure of a business before it even really gets started.</p>
<p>Trademark registration is one such concern, and Toronto-based startup <a href="https://www.heirlumeco.com/">Heirlume</a> just raised $1.7 million CAD (~$1.38 million) to address the problem with a machine-powered trademark registration platform that turns the process into a self-serve affair that won&#8217;t break the budget. Its AI-based trademark search will flag if terms might run afoul of existing trademarks in the U.S. and Canada, even when official government trademark search tools, and even top-tier legal firms, might not.</p>
<p>Heirlume&#8217;s core focus is on leveling the playing field for small business owners, who have typically been significantly out-matched when it comes to any trademark conflicts.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m a senior-level IP lawyer focused in trademarks, and had practiced in a traditional model, boutique firm of my own for over a decade serving big clients, and small clients,&#8221; explained Heirlume co-founder Julie MacDonell in an interview. &#8220;So providing big multinationals with a lot of brand strategy, and in-house legal, and then mainly serving small business clients when they were dealing with a cease-and-desist, or an infringement issue. It&#8217;s really those clients that have my heart: It&#8217;s incredibly difficult to have a small business owner literally crying tears on the phone with you, because they just lost their brand or their business overnight. And there was nothing I could do to help because the law just simply wasn&#8217;t on their side, because they had neglected to register their trademarks to own them.&#8221;</p>
<p>In part, there&#8217;s a lack of awareness around what it takes to actually register and own a trademark, MacDonell says. Many entrepreneurs just starting out seek out a domain name as a first step, for instance, and some will fork over significant sums to register these domains. What they don&#8217;t realize, however, is that this is essentially a rental, and if you don&#8217;t have the trademark to protect that domain, the actual trademark owner can potentially take it away down the road. But even if business owners do realize that a trademark should be their first stop, the barriers to actually securing one are steep.</p>
<p>&#8220;There was an an enormous, insurmountable barrier, when it came to brand protection for those business owners,&#8221; she said. &#8220;And it just isn&#8217;t fair. Every other business service, generally a small business owner can access. Incorporating a company or even insurance, for example, owning and buying insurance for your business is somewhat affordable and accessible. But brand ownership is not.&#8221;</p>
<p>Heirlume brings the cost of trademark registration down from many thousands of dollars to just under $600 for the first, and only $200 for each additional after that. The startup is also offering a very small business-friendly &#8220;buy now, pay later&#8221; option supported by Clearbanc, which means that even businesses starting on a shoestring can take the step of protecting their brand at the outset.</p>
<p>In its early days, Heirlume is also offering its core trademark search feature for free. That provides a trademark search engine that works across both U.S. and Canadian government databases, which can not only tell you if your desired trademark is available or already held, but also reveal whether it&#8217;s likely to be able to be successfully obtained, given other conflicts that might arise that are totally ignored by native trademark database search portals.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146160" style="width: 1553px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146160" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2146160 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg" alt="Heirlume search tool comparison" width="1543" height="797" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg 1543w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg?resize=150,77 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg?resize=300,155 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg?resize=768,397 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg?resize=680,351 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg?resize=1536,793 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/screenshot-2021-04-30-at-11.05.43-AM.jpg?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1543px) 100vw, 1543px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2146160" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Heirlume</p></div></p>
<p>Heirlume uses machine learning to identify these potential conflicts, which not only helps users searching for their trademarks, but also greatly decreases the workload behind the scenes, helping them lower costs and pass on the benefits of those improved margins to its clients. That&#8217;s how it can achieve better results than even hand-tailored applications from traditional firms, while doing so at scale and at reduced costs.</p>
<p>Another advantage of using machine-powered data processing and filing is that on the government trademark office side, the systems are looking for highly organized, curated data sets that are difficult for even trained people to get consistently right. Human error in just data entry can cause massive backlogs, MacDonell notes, even resulting in entire applications having to be tossed and started over from scratch.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are all sorts of data sets for those [trademark requirement] parameters,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Essentially, we synthesize all of that, and the goal through machine learning is to make sure that applications are utterly compliant with government rules. We actually have a senior-level trademark examiner that came to work for us, very excited that we were solving the problems causing backlogs within the government. She said that if Heirlume can get to a point where the applications submitted are perfect, there will be no backlog with the government.&#8221;</p>
<p>Improving efficiency within the trademark registration bodies means one less point of friction for small business owners when they set out to establish their company, which means more economic activity and upside overall. MacDonell ultimately hopes that Heirlume can help reduce friction to the point where trademark ownership is at the forefront of the business process, even before domain registration. Heirlume has a partnership with Google Domains to that end, which will eventually see indication of whether a domain name is likely to be trademarkable included in Google Domain search results.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PRI69AVIWA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/22/how-tech-companies-measure-legal/">How tech companies measure &#8216;legal&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How tech companies measure &#8216;legal&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/22/how-tech-companies-measure-legal/embed/#?secret=PRI69AVIWA" data-secret="PRI69AVIWA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This initial seed funding includes participation from Backbone Angels, as well as the Future Capital collective, Angels of Many and MaRS IAF, along with angel investors including Daniel Debow, Sid Lee&#8217;s Bertrand Cesvet and more. MacDonell notes that just as their goal was to bring more access and equity to small business owners when it comes to trademark protection, the startup was also very intentional in building its team and its cap table. MacDonell, along with co-founders CTO Sarah Ruest and Dave McDonell, aim to build the largest tech company with a majority female-identifying technology team. Its investor make-up includes 65% female-identifying or underrepresented investors, and MacDonnell says that was a very intentional choice that extended the time of the raise, and even led to turning down interest from some leading Silicon Valley firms.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want underrepresented founders to be to be funded, and the best way to ensure that change is to empower underrepresented investors,&#8221; she said. &#8220;I think that we all have a responsibility to actually do something. We&#8217;re all using hashtags right now, and hashtags are not enough [&#8230;] Our CTO is female, and she&#8217;s often been the only female person in the room. We&#8217;ve committed to ensuring that women in tech are no longer the only woman in the room.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/heirlume-raises-1-38m-to-remove-the-barriers-of-trademark-registration-for-small-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146109</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early-bird price ends tonight: Buy your pass to TC Early Stage 2021 and save $100</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/early-bird-price-ends-tonight-buy-your-pass-to-tc-early-stage-2021-and-save-100/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/early-bird-price-ends-tonight-buy-your-pass-to-tc-early-stage-2021-and-save-100/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 15:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Early Stage 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing and Fundraising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2144584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last call, founders. Today is your last chance to save $100 on a pass to TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &#38; Fundraising. Our last founder bootcamp event of the year takes place July 8-9, and it’s time to call on Saint Expeditus — the patron saint of procrastinators and programmers alike. He’ll help you kick [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last call, founders. Today is your last chance to save $100 on a pass to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/">TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a>. Our last founder bootcamp event of the year takes place July 8-9, and it’s time to call on Saint Expeditus — the patron saint of <a href="https://liturgy.life/2018/04/saint-expeditus-a-saint-for-procrastinators/">procrastinators</a> and <a href="https://www.wired.com/2004/11/patron-saint-of-the-nerds/">programmers</a> alike. He’ll help you kick procrastination to the curb, save some cash and gain access to a bevy of top-tier investors, famous founders, marketing magicians, financial wizards and other startup savants. And they all want to help you build a better startup. But you need to<strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/#tickets">buy your pass</a> by 11:59 p.m. (PT) today, April 30</strong>.</p>
<p>This TC Early Stage experience goes deep on fundraising and marketing fundamentals. On day one, you’ll choose from a range of presentations and breakout sessions — all interactive, with plenty of time for Q&amp;As. Plus video on demand, available after the event ends, means you don’t have to worry about schedule conflicts.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/#3e01330b-4bf1-4206-b038-769db50898a0">Speakers at Early Stage</a> bring a wealth of experience, coupled with authenticity. You’ll walk away with actionable advice for immediate use and an unvarnished look at what it takes to build a startup. No sugar-coating here.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Vlad Magdalin, founder of Webflow, was very candid about the challenges he faced on his journey to success. &#8220;You always hear about startups that raise millions of dollars, but you don&#8217;t necessarily hear about the ups and downs it takes to get to that point. It’s important for early founders to see that side, too.&#8221;</p>
<p>We recently added <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/norwest-venture-partners-lisa-wu-to-teach-founders-how-to-think-like-a-vc-at-tc-early-stage/">Lisa Wu</a>, a partner at Norwest Venture Partners, to our speaker roster, and we can&#8217;t wait to hear why she thinks founders should think like a VC. We’re adding more amazing speakers every week, and the full agenda is coming soon!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="47I78wLH9f"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/norwest-venture-partners-lisa-wu-to-teach-founders-how-to-think-like-a-vc-at-tc-early-stage/">Norwest Venture Partners&#8217; Lisa Wu to teach founders how to think like a VC at TC Early Stage</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Norwest Venture Partners&#8217; Lisa Wu to teach founders how to think like a VC at TC Early Stage&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/norwest-venture-partners-lisa-wu-to-teach-founders-how-to-think-like-a-vc-at-tc-early-stage/embed/#?secret=47I78wLH9f" data-secret="47I78wLH9f" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>On day two, get ready for the Early Stage Pitch-off. Applications open next week! Throw your hat in the ring and maybe you’ll be one of the 10 early-stage startup founders chosen to pitch live in front of a panel of VC judges and all the Early Stage attendees around the world. Valuable exposure and pitch feedback for all competitors and special prizes for the winner. Stay tuned!</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cwzIMyP9m9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/">11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;11 words and phrases to cut from your VC pitch deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/11-words-and-phrases-to-cut-from-your-vc-pitch-deck/embed/#?secret=cwzIMyP9m9" data-secret="cwzIMyP9m9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Read about <a href="https://www.nalagenetics.com/#/">Nalagenetics</a>, the April TC Early Stage Pitch-off winner <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/02/dont-miss-the-pitch-off-today-at-tc-early-stage-2021/">right here</a>.</p>
<p>You procrastinated, dragged your feet and delayed taking action on this one simple, opportunity-filled task. For the love of Saint Expeditus, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/#tickets">buy your pass</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-early-stage-2021-part-2/">TC Early Stage 2021: Marketing &amp; Fundraising</a> <strong>before 11:59 pm (PT) tonight</strong>, save $100 and build a better startup.</p>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Early Stage 2021 – Marketing &amp; Fundraising? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			width="99%"
			height="1010"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-5411631f4bb18bf52c73b95079bc13e0'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/early-bird-price-ends-tonight-buy-your-pass-to-tc-early-stage-2021-and-save-100/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2144584</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sorbet raises $6M seed led by Viola Ventures to tackle the thorny financials of paid time off</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/sorbet-raises-6m-seed-led-by-viola-ventures-to-tackle-the-thorny-financials-of-paid-time-off/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/sorbet-raises-6m-seed-led-by-viola-ventures-to-tackle-the-thorny-financials-of-paid-time-off/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global founders capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sorbet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viola Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A U.S./Israeli startup, Sorbet — which is tackling what companies do with the financial risks as employees accrue paid time off (PTO) — has raised $6 million in a seed funding round led by Viola Ventures, with participation by Global Founders Capital and Meron Capital. The economics of paid time off is relatively hidden in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A U.S./Israeli startup, <a href="http://www.getsorbet.com">Sorbet</a> — which is tackling what companies do with the financial risks as employees accrue paid time off (PTO) — has raised $6 million in a seed funding round led by Viola Ventures, with participation by Global Founders Capital and Meron Capital.</p>
<p>The economics of paid time off is relatively hidden in the business world, but essentially, Sorbet takes on the burden of this PTO from employers and then allows employees to spend it. This gives the employers far more control over the whole process and the ability to forecast its impact on the business.</p>
<p>Sorbet says that in the U.S., employees use only 72% of PTO balances, even though it’s the most sought-after benefit. But this, effectively, comes out at 768 million unused days off a year, worth around $224 billion. This creates a difficult problem for CFOs and accountants because its creates balance sheet liabilities on the company’s books, says Sorbet. If the employee doesn’t use all of their PTO, the employer can end up owing them a lot of money, which creates a cash flow liability on the company’s books. So Sorbet buys out these PTO liabilities from employees, then loads the cash value of the PTO on prepaid credit cards for the employees.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Speaking to me on a call, CEO and co-founder Veetahl Eilat-Raichel, said: “We researched this whole idea of paid time off and found this huge, massive market failure and inefficiency around the way that PTO is constructed. It&#8217;s kind of one of those things where, on the face of it, there&#8217;s this boring bureaucratic payroll item that turns into a boring balance sheet item. But under it is a $224 billion problem for U.S. businesses… If you think about it, employers are borrowing money from their employees at the worst terms possible and employees aren’t benefitting either. So everyone&#8217;s hurting here.”</p>
<p>She said: “Sorbet assumes the liability on ourselves and so then we can allow the company to control their cash flow and decide when they want to pay us back. They gain a lot of financial value because we are able to be very, very attractive on our funding. So it saves costs, it provides them with complete control of their cash flow and it allows them to give out amazing financial benefits to employees at a time where we can all use some extra cash right now.”</p>
<p>The platform Sorbet has built will, it says, sync with calendars, HR and payroll systems, identify habits and then proactively suggest personalized, pre-approved 3-6 hour “Micro Breaks”, 1-4 day “Micro Vacations” and +1 week Vacations. This, says the startup, increases PTO used by as much as 15%.</p>
<p>Employers can constantly renegotiate the terms of the loan with Sorbet, thus matching future cash flow, insulating themselves against salary raises (wage inflation), and take advantage of other benefits.</p>
<p>The co-founders are Eilat-Raichel, who previously worked at L’Oréal, Lockheed Martin and a fintech entrepreneur; Eliaz Shapira, co-founder and CPO; and Rami Kasterstein, co-founder and board member.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EPnhhTzb9F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/5-emerging-use-cases-for-productivity-infrastructure-in-2021/">5 emerging use cases for productivity infrastructure in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 emerging use cases for productivity infrastructure in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/5-emerging-use-cases-for-productivity-infrastructure-in-2021/embed/#?secret=EPnhhTzb9F" data-secret="EPnhhTzb9F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/sorbet-raises-6m-seed-led-by-viola-ventures-to-tackle-the-thorny-financials-of-paid-time-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146151</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cloud infrastructure market keeps rolling in Q1 with almost $40B in revenue</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/cloud-infrastructure-market-keeps-rolling-in-q1-with-almost-40b-in-revenue/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/cloud-infrastructure-market-keeps-rolling-in-q1-with-almost-40b-in-revenue/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 14:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud infrastructure market share]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synergy Research]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Conventional wisdom over the last year has suggested that the pandemic has driven companies to the cloud much faster than they ever would have gone without that forcing event, with some suggesting it has compressed years of transformation into months. This quarter&#8217;s cloud infrastructure revenue numbers appear to be proving that thesis correct. With The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Conventional wisdom over the last year has suggested that the pandemic has driven companies to the cloud much faster than they ever would have gone without that forcing event, with some suggesting it has compressed years of transformation into months. This quarter&#8217;s cloud infrastructure revenue numbers appear to be proving that thesis correct.</p>
<p>With The Big Three &#8212; Amazon, Microsoft and Google &#8212; all reporting this week, the market generated almost $40 billion in revenue, <a href="https://www.srgresearch.com/articles/amazon-and-microsoft-maintain-their-grip-market-others-are-also-growing-rapidly">according to Synergy Research data</a>. That&#8217;s up $2 billion from last quarter and up 37% over the same period last year. Canalys&#8217;s numbers were slightly higher at $42 billion.</p>
<p>As you might expect if you follow this market, AWS led the way with $13.5 billion for the quarter, up 32% year over year. That&#8217;s a run rate of $54 billion. While that is an eye-popping number, what&#8217;s really remarkable is the yearly revenue growth, especially for a company the size and maturity of Amazon. The law of large numbers would suggest this isn&#8217;t sustainable, but the pie keeps growing and Amazon continues to take a substantial chunk.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Overall AWS held steady with 32% market share. While the revenue numbers keep going up, Amazon&#8217;s market share has remained firm for years at around this number. It&#8217;s the other companies down market that are gaining share over time, most notably Microsoft, which is now at around 20% share &#8212; good for about $7.8 billion this quarter.</p>
<p>Google continues to show signs of promise under Thomas Kurian, hitting $3.5 billion, good for 9% as it makes a steady march toward double digits. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/ibm-breaks-latest-revenue-losing-streak-as-cloud-revenue-shows-modest-growth/">Even IBM had</a> a positive quarter, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/red-hat-ceo-looks-to-maintain-double-digit-growth-in-second-year-at-helm/">led by Red Hat</a> and cloud revenue, good for 5% or about $2 billion overall.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146138" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146138" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2146138" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image002-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Synergy Research cloud infrastructure bubble map for Q1 2021. AWS is leader, followed by Microsoft and Google." width="680" height="448" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image002-1.jpg 975w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image002-1.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image002-1.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image002-1.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image002-1.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/image002-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146138" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Synergy Research</p></div></p>
<p>John Dinsdale, chief analyst at Synergy, says that even though AWS and Microsoft have firm control of the market, that doesn&#8217;t mean there isn&#8217;t money to be made by the companies playing behind them.</p>
<p>&#8220;These two don’t have to spend too much time looking in their rearview mirrors and worrying about the competition. However, that is not to say that there aren’t some excellent opportunities for other players. Taking Amazon and Microsoft out of the picture, the remaining market is generating over $18 billion in quarterly revenues and growing at over 30% per year. Cloud providers that focus on specific regions, services or user groups can target several years of strong growth,&#8221; Dinsdale said in a statement.</p>
<p>Canalys, another firm that watches the same market as Synergy, <a href="https://www.canalys.com/newsroom/global-cloud-market-Q121">had similar findings</a> with slight variations, certainly close enough to confirm one another&#8217;s findings. They have AWS with 32%, Microsoft 19% and Google with 7%.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146139" style="width: 591px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146139" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2146139" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-3-1.png?w=581" alt="Canalys market share chart with Amazon with 32%, Microsoft 19% and Google 7%" width="581" height="327" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-3-1.png 581w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-3-1.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-3-1.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-3-1.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 581px) 100vw, 581px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146139" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Canalys</p></div></p>
<p>Canalys analyst Blake Murray says that there is still plenty of room for growth, and we will likely continue to see big numbers in this market for several years. &#8220;Though 2020 saw large-scale cloud infrastructure spending, most enterprise workloads have not yet transitioned to the cloud. Migration and cloud spend will continue as customer confidence rises during 2021. Large projects that were postponed last year will resurface, while new use cases will expand the addressable market,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The numbers we see are hardly a surprise anymore, and as companies push more workloads into the cloud, the numbers will continue to impress. The only question now is if Microsoft can continue to close the market share gap with Amazon.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3jD0B4yYOj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/the-cloud-infrastructure-market-hit-129b-in-2020/">The cloud infrastructure market hit $129B in 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The cloud infrastructure market hit $129B in 2020&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/the-cloud-infrastructure-market-hit-129b-in-2020/embed/#?secret=3jD0B4yYOj" data-secret="3jD0B4yYOj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="52Ew5OcKkR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/billion-dollar-b2b-cloud-first-enterprise-tech-behemoths-have-massive-potential/">Billion-dollar B2B: Cloud-first enterprise tech behemoths have massive potential</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Billion-dollar B2B: Cloud-first enterprise tech behemoths have massive potential&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/billion-dollar-b2b-cloud-first-enterprise-tech-behemoths-have-massive-potential/embed/#?secret=52Ew5OcKkR" data-secret="52Ew5OcKkR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/cloud-infrastructure-market-keeps-rolling-in-q1-with-almost-40b-in-revenue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146126</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer vision inches toward &#8216;common sense&#8217; with Facebook&#8217;s latest research</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/computer-vision-inches-towards-common-sense-with-facebooks-latest-research/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/computer-vision-inches-towards-common-sense-with-facebooks-latest-research/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 14:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Machine learning is capable of doing all sorts of things as long as you have the data to teach it how. That&#8217;s not always easy, and researchers are always looking for a way to add a bit of &#8220;common sense&#8221; to AI so you don&#8217;t have to show it 500 pictures of a cat before [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Machine learning is capable of doing all sorts of things as long as you have the data to teach it how. That&#8217;s not always easy, and researchers are always looking for a way to add a bit of &#8220;common sense&#8221; to AI so you don&#8217;t have to show it 500 pictures of a cat before it gets it. <a href="https://ai.facebook.com/blog/dino-paws-computer-vision-with-self-supervised-transformers-and-10x-more-efficient-training">Facebook&#8217;s newest research</a> takes a big step toward reducing the data bottleneck.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s formidable AI research division has been working for years now on how to advance and scale things like advanced computer vision algorithms, and has made steady progress, generally shared with the rest of the research community. One interesting development Facebook has pursued in particular is what&#8217;s called &#8220;semi-supervised learning.&#8221;</p>
<p>Generally when you think of training an AI, you think of something like the aforementioned 500 pictures of cats — images that have been selected and labeled (which can mean outlining the cat, putting a box around the cat or just saying there&#8217;s a cat in there somewhere) so that the machine learning system can put together an algorithm to automate the process of cat recognition. Naturally if you want to do dogs or horses, you need 500 dog pictures, 500 horse pictures, etc. — it scales <em>linearly</em>, which is a word you never want to see in tech.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Semi-supervised learning, related to &#8220;unsupervised&#8221; learning, involves figuring out important parts of a data set without any labeled data at all. It doesn&#8217;t just go wild, there&#8217;s still structure; for instance, imagine you give the system a thousand sentences to study, then showed it 10 more that have several of the words missing. The system could probably do a decent job filling in the blanks just based on what it&#8217;s seen in the previous thousand. But that&#8217;s not so easy to do with images and video — they aren&#8217;t as straightforward or predictable.</p>
<p>But Facebook researchers have shown that while it may not be easy, it&#8217;s possible and in fact very effective. The DINO system (which stands rather unconvincingly for &#8220;DIstillation of knowledge with NO labels&#8221;) is capable of learning to find objects of interest in videos of people, animals and objects quite well without any labeled data whatsoever.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146017" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/segmentation-gif2.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146017" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2146017" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/segmentation-gif2.gif" alt="Animation showing four videos and the AI interpretation of the objects in them." width="800" height="483" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2146017" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>It does this by considering the video not as a sequence of images to be analyzed one by one in order, but as a complex, interrelated set, like the difference between &#8220;a series of words&#8221; and &#8220;a sentence.&#8221; By attending to the middle and the end of the video as well as the beginning, the agent can get a sense of things like &#8220;an object with this general shape goes from left to right.&#8221; That information feeds into other knowledge, like when an object on the right overlaps with the first one, the system knows they&#8217;re not the same thing, just touching in those frames. And that knowledge in turn can be applied to other situations. In other words, it develops a basic sense of visual meaning, and does so with remarkably little training on new objects.</p>
<p>This results in a computer vision system that&#8217;s not only effective — it performs well compared with traditionally trained systems — but more relatable and explainable. For instance, while an AI that has been trained with 500 dog pictures and 500 cat pictures will recognize both, it won&#8217;t really have any idea that they&#8217;re similar in any way. But DINO — although it couldn&#8217;t be specific — gets that they&#8217;re similar visually to one another, more so anyway than they are to cars, and that metadata and context is visible in its memory. Dogs and cats are &#8220;closer&#8221; in its sort of digital cognitive space than dogs and mountains. You can see those concepts as little blobs here — see how those of a type stick together:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146016" style="width: 630px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fb-concepts.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146016" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2146016" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fb-concepts.gif" alt="Animated diagram showing how concepts in the machine learning model stay close together." width="620" height="604" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2146016" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Facebook</p></div></p>
<p>This has its own benefits, of a technical sort we won&#8217;t get into here. If you&#8217;re curious, there&#8217;s more detail in the papers linked in Facebook&#8217;s blog post.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also an adjacent research project, a training method called PAWS, which further reduces the need for labeled data. PAWS combines some of the ideas of semi-supervised learning with the more traditional supervised method, essentially giving the training a boost by letting it learn from both the labeled and unlabeled data.</p>
<p>Facebook of course needs good and fast image analysis for its many user-facing (and secret) image-related products, but these general advances to the computer vision world will no doubt be welcomed by the developer community for other purposes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PYiRJiU2V5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/13/wtf-is-computer-vision/">WTF is computer vision?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WTF is computer vision?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/13/wtf-is-computer-vision/embed/#?secret=PYiRJiU2V5" data-secret="PYiRJiU2V5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bT3VYZPg5M"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/enhanced-computer-vision-sensors-raise-manufacturing-stakes-for-robots-as-a-service/">Enhanced computer vision, sensors raise manufacturing stakes for robots as a service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enhanced computer vision, sensors raise manufacturing stakes for robots as a service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/enhanced-computer-vision-sensors-raise-manufacturing-stakes-for-robots-as-a-service/embed/#?secret=bT3VYZPg5M" data-secret="bT3VYZPg5M" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/computer-vision-inches-towards-common-sense-with-facebooks-latest-research/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145953</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The second shot is kicking in</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/booooooo-private-equity-leave-us-alone/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/booooooo-private-equity-leave-us-alone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banana capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greenlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MasterClass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Step]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekend Fund]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. First and foremost, Equity was nominated for a Webby for “Best Technology Podcast”! Drop everything and go Vote for Equity! We’d appreciate it. A lot. And even if we lose, well, we’ll keep doing our thing and making each [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/4fd8c30b-2291-451f-bda5-c748fc77e164?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>First and foremost, Equity was nominated for a Webby for “Best Technology Podcast”! Drop everything and go <a href="https://vote.webbyawards.com/PublicVoting#/2021/podcasts/general-series/technology">Vote for Equity</a>! We’d appreciate it. A <em>lot</em>. And even if we lose, well, we’ll keep doing our thing and making each other laugh. (Note: We are in last place, which is, well, <em>something</em>.)</p>
<p>Regardless, the Equity team got together once again this week to not only go over the news of the week, but also to do a little soul searching. You see, some news broke yesterday, so we figured that we had to talk about it in our usual style. So, here&#8217;s the rundown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do you want to buy TechCrunch? <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/verizon-explores-sale-of-media-assets-11619642003">Apparently you can</a>? Albeit probably along with a few billion dollars&#8217; worth of other assets &#8212; whatever is left of Yahoo and AOL &#8212; you can now own an NFT. A non-fungible TechCrunch. What is ahead for us? We don&#8217;t know. So if you do know, tell us. Until then we&#8217;ll just yo-yo gently between panic and optimism, as per usual.</li>
<li>We also dug into the latest All Raise venture capital data, and <a href="https://allraise.org/assets/all-raise-annual-report-2020.pdf">the results were abysmal. </a></li>
<li>Next up was the news that fintech startups are setting records in 2021, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145633&amp;preview=true">raising more capital than ever before</a>. That brought us to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/brex-raises-425m-at-a-7-4b-valuation-as-the-corporate-spend-war-rages-on/">the latest from Brex</a>.</li>
<li>And then there was a suspicious trend when three fintech companies focused on teen banking raised in one exhale. We talk <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/teen-banking-service-step-raises-100m-series-c-announces-steph-currys-investment/">Step</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/kids-focused-fintech-greenlight-raises-260m-in-a16z-led-series-d-nearly-doubles-valuation-to-2-3b/">Greenlight</a> and<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/mobile-bank-current-raises-220-million-series-d-triples-valuation-to-2-2b/"> Current.</a></li>
<li>Natasha talked about her last Startups Weekly post, in which she unpacked <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/24/what-the-masterclass-effect-means-for-edtech/">The MasterClass effect&#8217;s impact on edtech.</a></li>
<li>And to close, we discussed the latest cool-kid venture capital funds. Sure memes are cool, but did you know that they can help you raise a $10 million fund? They can!</li>
</ul>
<p>We are back Monday morning with our weekly kick-off show. Have a great weekend!</p>
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 AM PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wmwPPBxXiO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/fintech-startups-set-vc-records-as-the-2021-fundraising-market-continues-to-impress/">Fintech startups set VC records as the 2021 fundraising market continues to impress</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fintech startups set VC records as the 2021 fundraising market continues to impress&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/fintech-startups-set-vc-records-as-the-2021-fundraising-market-continues-to-impress/embed/#?secret=wmwPPBxXiO" data-secret="wmwPPBxXiO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/booooooo-private-equity-leave-us-alone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145890</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Geothermal technology has enormous potential to power the planet and Fervo wants to tap it</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/geothermal-technology-has-enormous-potential-to-power-the-planet-and-fervo-wants-to-tap-it/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/geothermal-technology-has-enormous-potential-to-power-the-planet-and-fervo-wants-to-tap-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alternative energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berkeley lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bp ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakthrough Energy Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Capricorn Investment Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chevron Technology Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiber Optic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geothermal energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Houston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Skoll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewable energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rice University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schlumberger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stanford University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temasek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vickers Venture Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tapping the geothermal energy stored beneath the Earth&#8217;s surface as a way to generate renewable power is one of the new visions for the future that&#8217;s captured the attention of environmentalists and oil and gas engineers alike. That&#8217;s because it&#8217;s not only a way to generate power that doesn&#8217;t rely on greenhouse gas emitting hydrocarbons, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tapping the geothermal energy stored beneath the Earth&#8217;s surface as a way to generate renewable power is one of the new visions for the future that&#8217;s captured the attention of environmentalists and oil and gas engineers alike.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s because it&#8217;s not only a way to generate power that doesn&#8217;t rely on greenhouse gas emitting hydrocarbons, but because it uses the same skillsets and expertise that the oil and gas industry has been honing and refining for years.</p>
<p>At least that&#8217;s what drew the former completion engineer (it&#8217;s not what it sounds like) Tim Latimer to the industry and to launch<a href="https://www.fervoenergy.com/"> Fervo Energy</a>, the Houston-based geothermal tech developer that&#8217;s picked up funding from none other than Bill Gates&#8217; Breakthrough Energy Ventures (that fund&#8230; is so busy) and former eBay executive, Jeff Skoll&#8217;s <a href="https://capricornllc.com/">Capricorn Investment Group</a>.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With the new $28 million cash in hand, Fervo&#8217;s planning on ramping up its projects, which Latimer said would &#8220;bring on hundreds of megawatts of power in the next few years.&#8221;</p>
<p>Latimer got his first exposure to the environmental impact of power generation as a kid growing up in a small town outside of Waco, Texas near the Sandy Creek coal power plant, one of the last coal-powered plants to be built in the U.S.</p>
<p>Like many Texas kids, Latimer came from an oil family, and got his first jobs in the oil and gas industry before realizing that the world was going to be switching to renewables and the oil industry &#8212; along with the friends and family he knew &#8212; could be left high and dry.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s one reason he started working on Fervo, the entrepreneur said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;What’s most important, from my perspective, since I started my career in the oil and gas industry, is providing folks that are part of the energy transition on the fossil fuel side to work in the clean energy future,&#8221; Latimer said. &#8220;I’ve been able to go in and hire contractors and support folks that have been out of work or challenged because of the oil price crash&#8230; And I put them to work on our rigs.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146120" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146120" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2146120" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Tim-Latimer-at-Fervo-Operations-Site.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146120" class="wp-caption-text">Fervo Energy chief executive, Tim Latimer, pictured in a hardhat at one of the company&#8217;s development sites. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fervo Energy</p></div></p>
<p>When the Biden administration talks about finding jobs for employees in the hydrocarbon industry as part of the energy transition, this is exactly what they&#8217;re talking about.</p>
<p>And geothermal power is no longer as constrained by geography, so there are a lot of abundant resources to tap and the potential for high-paying jobs in areas that are already dependent on geological services work, Latimer said (late last year, <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/10/21/21515461/renewable-energy-geothermal-egs-ags-supercritical">Vox published a good overview of the history and opportunity presented by the technology</a>).</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">&#8220;A large percentage of the world’s population actually lives next to good geothermal resources,&#8221; Latimer said. &#8220;[There are] 25 countries today that have geothermal installed and producing and another 25 where geothermal is going to grow.&#8221; </span></p>
<p>Geothermal power production actually has a long history in the Western U.S. and in parts of Africa where naturally occurring geysers and steam jets pouring from the earth have been obvious indicators of good geothermal resources, Latimer said.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span class="il">Fervo</span>’s technology unlocks a new class of geothermal resource that is ready for large-scale deployment. <span class="il">Fervo</span>’s geothermal systems use novel techniques, including horizontal drilling, distributed fiber optic sensing and advanced computational modelling, to deliver more repeatable and cost effective geothermal electricity,&#8221; Latimer wrote in an email. &#8220;<span class="il">Fervo</span>’s technology combines with the latest advancements in Organic Rankine Cycle generation systems to deliver flexible, 24/7 carbon-free electricity.&#8221;</p>
<p>Initially developed with a grant from the TomKat Center at Stanford University and a fellowship funded by Activate.org at the Lawrence Berkeley National Lab&#8217;s Cyclotron Road division, Fervo has gone on to score funding from the DOE&#8217;s Geothermal Technology Office and ARPA-E to continue work with partners like Schlumberger, Rice University and the Berkeley Lab.</p>
<p>The combination of new and old technology is opening vast geographies to the company to potentially develop new projects.</p>
<p>Other companies are also looking to tap geothermal power to drive a renewable power-generation development business. Those are startups like Eavor, which has the backing of energy majors like bp Ventures, Chevron Technology Ventures, Temasek, BDC Capital, Eversource and Vickers Venture Partners; and other players including <a href="https://www.greenfireenergy.com/">GreenFire Energy</a> and <a href="https://www.sagegeo.com/">Sage Geosystems.</a></p>
<p>Demand for geothermal projects is skyrocketing, opening up big markets for startups that can nail the cost issue for geothermal development. As Latimer noted, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">from 2016 to 2019 there was only one major geothermal contract, but in 2020 there were 10 new major power purchase agreements signed by the industry. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o6ydGDb50Z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/24/climatetech-is-the-new-hot-space-for-investors-in-a-warming-planet/">ClimateTech is the new hot space for investors in a warming planet</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;ClimateTech is the new hot space for investors in a warming planet&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/24/climatetech-is-the-new-hot-space-for-investors-in-a-warming-planet/embed/#?secret=o6ydGDb50Z" data-secret="o6ydGDb50Z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For all of these projects, cost remains a factor. Contracts that are being signed for geothermal that are in the $65 to $75 per megawatt range, according to Latimer. By comparison, solar plants are now coming in somewhere between $35 and $55 per megawatt, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514902/solar-energy-cost-historic-low-energy-agency-outlook-2020">as The Verge reported last year</a>. </span></p>
<p>But Latimer said the stability and predictability of geothermal power made the cost differential palatable for utilities and businesses that need the assurance of uninterruptible power supplies. As a current Houston resident, the issue is something that Latimer has an intimate experience with from this year&#8217;s winter freeze, which left him without power for five days.</p>
<p>Indeed, geothermal&#8217;s ability to provide always-on clean power makes it an incredibly attractive option. In a recent Department of Energy study, geothermal could meet as much as 16% of the U.S. electricity demand, and other estimates put geothermal&#8217;s contribution at nearly 20% of a fully decarbonized grid.</p>
<p>“We’ve long been believers in geothermal energy but have waited until we’ve seen the right technology and team to drive innovation in the sector,” said Ion Yadigaroglu of Capricorn Investment Group, in a statement. “Fervo’s technology capabilities and the partnerships they’ve created with leading research organizations make them the clear leader in the new wave of geothermal.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146121" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146121" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2146121" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg 2016w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Fervo-Operations-.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146121" class="wp-caption-text">Fervo Energy drilling site. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fervo Energy</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/geothermal-technology-has-enormous-potential-to-power-the-planet-and-fervo-wants-to-tap-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146082</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rapchat tunes into $2.3M as its music-making app hits 7M users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/rapchat-tunes-into-2-3m-as-its-music-making-app-hits-7m-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/rapchat-tunes-into-2-3m-as-its-music-making-app-hits-7m-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adjacent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music creation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sony music entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[YouTube, Snapchat, Twitter, TikTok and Facebook&#8217;s Instagram have upended the film and TV industries, with a new wave of cinematographers, directors and actors leveraging innovations in technology to create new work and connect directly with billions of consumers to see it. Today, a startup is announcing some funding as it looks to make a similar [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">YouTube, Snapchat, Twitter, TikTok and Facebook&#8217;s Instagram have upended the film and TV industries, with a new wave of cinematographers, directors and actors leveraging innovations in technology to create new work and connect directly with billions of consumers to see it. Today, a startup is announcing some funding as it looks to make a similar impact in the world of music.</p>
<p><a href="https://rapchat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rapchat</a>, an app that lets people create music tracks &#8212; raps, as its name suggests, or something else &#8212; using a platform that crowdsources beats and lets people put vocals on top of them, has raised $2.3 million.</p>
<p>Co-led by Sony Music Entertainment and NYC VC firm Adjacent, this is an extension to Rapchat&#8217;s seed round of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/23/rapchat-raises-1-6-million-to-help-you-make-and-share-your-def-jams/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$1.7 million back in 2018</a>, and CEO and co-founder Seth Miller tells me it&#8217;s coming as the startup is getting ready for a bigger Series A.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>With no connection to Snapchat &#8212; not now at least, except that founders Seth Miller and Pat Gibson did think it was a funny pun at the time that they were first conceiving of the company as a side hustle while still in university in 2015 &#8212; Rapchat has already gone quite some way in scaling.</p>
<p>The company today has some 7 million registered users, and at the moment some 250,000 songs are being created around a catalog of about 100,000 beats by 500,000 active users on the platform <em>each month</em>. Engagement is hovering right now at 35 minutes per day on average, a mix not just of people making tunes, but through the beginnings of a social graph: people coming onto the app to discover and share those tracks.</p>
<p>Rapchat plans to use the funding to continue expanding the scope of what you can create on its platform, including growing the prize pools for Rapchat’s &#8220;Challenges&#8221; competition series; expand to have more artists, producers and industry executives on the platform for mentoring; and to extend that platform&#8217;s reach to integrate more deeply with the likes of TikTok, Snapchat, Spotify and Apple Music &#8212; platforms where creators are already making a lot of content, and where music is figuring strongly in that effort.</p>
<p>Rapchat&#8217;s growth not only speaks to how the startup has pulled off its ambition to make it easier to make music, but it also speaks to an appetite, an itch, in the creator economy: There is a big, wide world of music-making out there, and more want to see if they can strike the right note.</p>
<p>Rapchat is definitely not the only, nor the first, company to think of how to address music creators within the bigger creator economy.</p>
<p>Another app called <a href="https://www.voisey.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Voisey</a> had conceived of a similar idea but focused primarily on letting people create and record shorter clips rather than full music tracks before sharing them to other platforms. It has not quite become a household name, but it did have some small success in bringing attention to new artists, and interestingly, it was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/20/snap-acquired-voisey-an-app-to-create-music-tracks-overlaying-your-own-vocals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">quietly acquired by Snap last year</a> (and for now, Snap&#8217;s kept Voisey&#8217;s app up).</p>
<p>TikTok&#8217;s parent ByteDance has also made an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/23/it-looks-like-titok-has-acquired-jukedeck-a-pioneering-music-ai-uk-startup/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquisition of another music creation app, Jukedeck</a>. As with Snap&#8217;s acquisition, so far we&#8217;re not fully clear on how and where that acquisition is going, but we&#8217;ve heard through the grapevine that TikTok is working on a new music service that sounds like it might let more content get plugged into TikTok&#8217;s music layer, so perhaps watch this space.</p>
<p>And in perhaps the most trend-endorsing act of all, Rapchat has been cloned &#8212; by Facebook, no less. NPE, the social networking behemoth&#8217;s in-house skunkworks team, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/facebook-launches-bars-a-tiktok-like-app-for-creating-and-sharing-raps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in February rolled out BARS</a> (all caps! stand out!) &#8212; which is, yes &#8212; an app on which you can create your own rap music.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GGKGlymqD5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/facebook-launches-bars-a-tiktok-like-app-for-creating-and-sharing-raps/">Facebook launches BARS, a TikTok-like app for creating and sharing raps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook launches BARS, a TikTok-like app for creating and sharing raps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/26/facebook-launches-bars-a-tiktok-like-app-for-creating-and-sharing-raps/embed/#?secret=GGKGlymqD5" data-secret="GGKGlymqD5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Miller, at least for now, is about as laid back as you could be, considering all of the above, confident that at least for now, he is very happy with the engagement Rapchat is seeing, including around tests it has been running offering new premium features &#8212; the app is free to use right now, but it has plans to offer creators more production tools and better ways of sharing their work and helping build a business out of it. Key to that will be never demanding licensing fees on music: creators keep the royalties, with Rapchat&#8217;s value lying in helping them make and track how that music gets used with the metadata that it holds on those tracks.</p>
<p>Some of the low-key approach might well come from the fact that Rapchat and its founders are somewhat outside of the startup fray. The idea for the app first came up in 2013, Miller said, when he and Gibson were students at Ohio University in Columbus.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were coming of age when everyone in college was using apps like Snapchat and Instagram,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We loved them for video, but saw there was nothing like them for creating music. So we pitched the idea during a Startup Weekend competition: snapping like Snapchat but for rap. Someone said, &#8216;Rapchat&#8217; and we liked it.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">They went full-time on the idea in 2015 when they got into 500 Startups with the app, but even so it&#8217;s taken them years to build up the business, get attention from investors and raise money. Why? Partly because music is hard, and frankly the main game in town for years has been streaming services, rather than creation services. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Miller and Gibson persisted: &#8220;</span>I knew that this market was huge. It just made so much sense to me,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The advent of the mobile devices the moment that apps like Instagram, VSCO and Snapchat have turned people into photographers and video makers, and Substack is turning people into writers.&#8221; And now Rapchat wants to tap the world for rappers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Rapchat has created a music studio that fits into your pocket,” said Nico Wittenborn, lead Investor at venture capital firm Adjacent, in a statement. “It decreases the friction of creativity by allowing anyone, anywhere in the world to record and publish music straight from their phones. This mobile-enabled democratization of technology is what Adjacent is all about, and I am super excited to support the team in building out this next-level music platform.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vr2ICAWDq9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/covid-19-is-driving-demand-for-low-code-apps/">COVID-19 is driving demand for low-code apps</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;COVID-19 is driving demand for low-code apps&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/covid-19-is-driving-demand-for-low-code-apps/embed/#?secret=vr2ICAWDq9" data-secret="vr2ICAWDq9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/rapchat-tunes-into-2-3m-as-its-music-making-app-hits-7m-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146083</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The health data transparency movement is birthing a new generation of startups</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/the-health-data-transparency-movement-is-birthing-a-new-generation-of-startups/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/the-health-data-transparency-movement-is-birthing-a-new-generation-of-startups/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drug discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Market Map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Drug Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The recent movement toward data transparency is birthing a new generation of innovation and startups that could ultimately make healthcare better and more transparent for all of us.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Ariel Katz</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/H1co_">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Ariel Katz is the founder and CEO of <a href="http://www.h1insights.com">H1</a>, a global healthcare platform that helps life sciences companies, hospitals, academic medical centers and health systems connect with providers, find clinical research, locate industry experts and benchmark their organization.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In the early 2000s, Jeff Bezos gave a seminal TED Talk titled “<a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/jeff_bezos_the_electricity_metaphor_for_the_web_s_future?language=en">The Electricity Metaphor for the Web’s Future</a>.” In it, he argued that the internet will enable innovation on the same scale that electricity did.</p>
<p>We are at a similar inflection point in healthcare, with the recent movement toward data transparency birthing a new generation of innovation and startups.</p>
<p>Those who follow the space closely may have noticed that there are twin struggles taking place: a push for more transparency on provider and payer data, including anonymous patient data, and another for strict privacy protection for personal patient data. What’s the main difference?</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			This sector is still somewhat nascent &#8212; we are in the first wave of innovation, with much more to come.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Anonymized data is much more freely available, while personal data is being locked even tighter (as it should be) due to regulations like GDPR, CCPA and their equivalents around the world.</p>
<p>The former trend is enabling a host of new vendors and services that will ultimately make healthcare better and more transparent for all of us.</p>
<p>These new companies could not have existed five years ago. The Affordable Care Act was the first step toward making anonymized data more available. It required healthcare institutions (such as hospitals and healthcare systems) to publish data on costs and outcomes. This included the release of detailed data on providers.</p>
<p>Later legislation required biotech and pharma companies to disclose monies paid to research partners. And every physician in the U.S. is now required to be in the <a href="https://npiregistry.cms.hhs.gov/">National Practitioner Identifier</a> (NPI), a comprehensive public database of providers.</p>
<p>All of this allowed the creation of new types of companies that give both patients and providers more control over their data. Here are some key examples of how.</p>
<h2>Allowing patients to access all their own health data in one place</h2>
<p>This is a key capability of patients’ newly found access to health data. Think of how often, as a patient, providers aren’t aware of treatment or a test you’ve had elsewhere. Often you end up repeating a test because a provider doesn’t have a record of a test conducted elsewhere.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/the-health-data-transparency-movement-is-birthing-a-new-generation-of-startups/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roku removes YouTube TV from its channel store following failed negotiations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/roku-removes-youtube-tv-from-its-channel-store-following-failed-negotiations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/roku-removes-youtube-tv-from-its-channel-store-following-failed-negotiations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube TV]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this week, Roku warned customers that the YouTube TV app may be removed from its streaming media players and TVs, and alleged that Google was leveraging its monopoly power during contract negotiations to ask for unfair terms. Today, Roku is announcing the deal has fallen through &#8212; meaning YouTube TV will no longer be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this week, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/roku-alleges-google-is-using-its-monopoly-power-in-youtube-tv-carriage-negotiations/">Roku warned customers</a> that the YouTube TV app may be removed from its streaming media players and TVs, and alleged that Google was leveraging its monopoly power during contract negotiations to ask for unfair terms. Today, Roku is announcing the deal has fallen through &#8212; meaning YouTube TV will no longer be available to new Roku subscribers. However, the company says it has taken steps to ensure existing subscribers can continue to use the YouTube TV app.</p>
<p>Roku had argued that as a part of its attempts to renew the carriage agreement for YouTube TV, Google was asking for special treatment, including a preferential ranking of YouTube content in search results, and even the permission to override Roku customers&#8217; default settings when the YouTube app was open. That is, if a customer used the voice search button to ask for music, Google wanted YouTube Music to play the request &#8212; even if the customer had set another app, like Pandora, as their default.</p>
<p>The company also alleged that Google was asking for customer data that was &#8220;outside the realm&#8221; of industry standard practices and more than Roku offered other customers. And it said Google threatened to increase the hardware spec requirements for YouTube TV, which would ensure Roku&#8217;s low-end and competitively priced players wouldn&#8217;t be able to access it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Google, however, disputed the claims were as Roku said. It pointed the finger back at Roku for turning to customers to help sway the negotiations in its favor. The company also said it had been working in &#8220;good faith&#8221; to reach an agreement and all its requests were about providing a good user experience. Notably, Google also said it made &#8220;no requests to access user data or interfere with search results.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XmPKzfCYd4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/roku-alleges-google-is-using-its-monopoly-power-in-youtube-tv-carriage-negotiations/">Roku alleges Google is using its monopoly power in YouTube TV carriage negotiations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Roku alleges Google is using its monopoly power in YouTube TV carriage negotiations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/roku-alleges-google-is-using-its-monopoly-power-in-youtube-tv-carriage-negotiations/embed/#?secret=XmPKzfCYd4" data-secret="XmPKzfCYd4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Roku today offered a statement on the decision to pull YouTube TV, as the agreement has not been renewed. A Roku spokesperson said the following:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>We are disappointed that Google has allowed our agreement for the distribution of YouTube TV to expire. Roku has not asked for one dollar of additional financial consideration from Google to renew YouTube TV. ​</em></p>
<p><em>We have only asked Google for four simple commitments. First, not to manipulate consumer search results. Second, not to require access to data not available to anyone else. Third, not to leverage their YouTube monopoly to force Roku to accept hardware requirements that would increase consumer costs. Fourth, not to act in a discriminatory and anticompetitive manner against Roku. ​</em></p>
<p><em>​Because our contract has expired, we have removed YouTube TV from our channel store. To continue to provide our users with a great streaming experience, we are taking the extra step to continue to offer existing subscribers access to YouTube TV on the Roku platform unless Google takes actions that require the full removal of the channel. Because of Google&#8217;s conduct, new subscriptions will not be available going forward until an agreement is reached. ​</em></p>
<p><em>​It is well past time for Google to embrace the principles that have made streaming so popular for millions of users by giving consumers control of their streaming experience, by embracing fair competition and by ceasing anticompetitive practices. We believe consumers stand to benefit from Google and Roku reaching a fair agreement that preserves these principles and we remain committed to trying to achieve that goal.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>An email was also sent to customers informing them of these details.</p>
<p>Google later today responded in full to Roku&#8217;s allegations, turning the tables to state the Roku chose to use the YouTube TV carriage negotiations as a way to renegotiate a separate deal for the main YouTube app. Google also stuck up for its technical requirements, noting Roku wanted exceptions that would &#8220;break the YouTube experience&#8221; or limit YouTube&#8217;s ability to update its app. It again stated it has never made requests to access user data or interfere with search results, saying those claims were &#8220;baseless.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We understand the concern members may have about this and we don’t take this lightly,&#8221; <a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/update-our-youtube-tv-members-roku/">a Google blog post read</a>. &#8220;We are committed to ensuring our members continue to have access to YouTube TV and will continue advocating on behalf of our members.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/roku-removes-youtube-tv-from-its-channel-store-following-failed-negotiations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146100</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Developer-focused video platform Mux achieves unicorn status with $105M funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/mux-series-d/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/mux-series-d/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mux]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Barely more than eight months after announcing a $37 million funding round, Mux has another $105 million. The Series D was led by Coatue and values the company at more than $1 billion (Mux isn&#8217;t disclosing the specific valuation). Existing investors Accel, Andreessen Horowitz and Cobalt also participated, as did new investor Dragoneer. Co-founder and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Barely more than eight months after <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/mux-raises-37m-series-c-as-its-api-based-video-streaming-service-scales/">announcing a $37 million funding round</a>, <a href="https://mux.com">Mux</a> has another $105 million.</p>
<p>The Series D was led by Coatue and values the company at more than $1 billion (Mux isn&#8217;t disclosing the specific valuation). Existing investors Accel, Andreessen Horowitz and Cobalt also participated, as did new investor Dragoneer.</p>
<p>Co-founder and CEO Jon Dahl told me that Mux didn&#8217;t need to raise more funding. But after last year&#8217;s Series C, the company&#8217;s leadership kept in touch with Coatue and other investors who&#8217;d expressed interest, and they ultimately decided that more money could help fuel faster growth during &#8220;this inflection moment in video.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Building on the thesis popularized by a16z co-founder Marc Andreessen, Dahl said, &#8220;I think video’s eating software, the same way software was eating the world 10 years ago.&#8221; In other words, where video was once something we watched at our desks and on our sofas, it&#8217;s now everywhere, whether we&#8217;re scrolling through our social media feeds or exercising on our Pelotons.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DvNRACgnvr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/mux-raises-37m-series-c-as-its-api-based-video-streaming-service-scales/">Mux raises $37M Series C as its API-based video streaming service scales</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mux raises $37M Series C as its API-based video streaming service scales&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/10/mux-raises-37m-series-c-as-its-api-based-video-streaming-service-scales/embed/#?secret=DvNRACgnvr" data-secret="DvNRACgnvr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;We’re at the early days of a five- or 10-year major transition, where video is moving into being a first-class part of every software project,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Dahl argued that Mux is well-suited for this transition because it&#8217;s &#8220;a video platform for developers,&#8221; with an API-centric approach that results in faster publishing and reliable streaming for viewers. Its first product was a monitoring and analytics tool called Mux Data, followed by its streaming video product Mux Video.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you&#8217;re going to build a video platform and do it data-first, you need heavy data and monitoring and analytics,&#8221; Dahl explained. &#8220;We built the data layer [and then] we built the streaming platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>Customers include Robinhood, PBS, ViacomCBS, Equinox Media and VSCO — Dahl said that while Mux works with digital media companies, &#8220;our core market is software.&#8221; He suggested that back when the company was founded in 2015, video was largely seen as a &#8220;niche,&#8221; or &#8220;something you needed if you were ESPN or Netflix.&#8221; But the last few years have illustrated that &#8220;video is a fundamental part of how we communicate&#8221; and that &#8220;every software company should have video as a core part of its products.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2146090" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2146090" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2146090" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Mux-Founder-Shot.jpeg?w=680" alt="Mux founders Adam Brown, Steven Heffernan, Matt McClure and Jon Dahl" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Mux-Founder-Shot.jpeg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Mux-Founder-Shot.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Mux-Founder-Shot.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Mux-Founder-Shot.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Mux-Founder-Shot.jpeg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Mux-Founder-Shot.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2146090" class="wp-caption-text">Mux founders Adam Brown, Steven Heffernan, Matt McClure and Jon Dahl. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mux</p></div></p>
<p>Not surprisingly, demand increased dramatically during the pandemic. During the past year, on-demand streaming via the Mux platform grew by 300%, while live video streaming grew 3,700% and revenue quadrupled.</p>
<p>&#8220;Which is a lot of work,&#8221; Dahl said with a laugh. &#8220;We definitely spent a lot of the last year ramping and scaling and investing in the platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>This new funding will allow Mux (which has now raised a total of $175 million) to continue that investment. Dahl said he plans to grow the team from 80 to 200 employees and to explore potential acquisitions.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were impressed by Mux’s laser focus on the developer community, and saw impressive customer retention and expansion indicative of the strong value their solutions provide,&#8221; said Coatue General Partner David Schneider in a statement. &#8220;This funding will enable Mux to continue to build on their customer-centric platform and we are proud to partner with Mux as it leads the way to this hybrid future.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="czKge9SYNd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/">10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 VCs say interactivity, regulation and independent creators will reshape digital media in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/9-vcs-say-interactivity-regulation-and-independent-creators-will-reshape-digital-media-in-2021/embed/#?secret=czKge9SYNd" data-secret="czKge9SYNd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/mux-series-d/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146084</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>As concerns rise over forest carbon offsets, Pachama&#8217;s verified offset marketplace gets $15 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/as-concerns-rise-over-forest-carbon-offsets-pachamas-verified-offset-marketplace-gets-15-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/as-concerns-rise-over-forest-carbon-offsets-pachamas-verified-offset-marketplace-gets-15-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Shieber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 12:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aglaé Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Gates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakthrough Energy Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon offset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Sacca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate pledge fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fabrice Grinda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impossible foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Beshara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff bezos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joe gebbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lowercarbon Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lvmh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pachama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paul graham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ryan graves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite imagery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Belsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Serena Williams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Softbank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweet capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim O\'reilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xplorer Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2146064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Restoring and preserving the world&#8217;s forests has long been considered one of the easiest, lowest-cost and simplest ways to reduce the amount of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere. It&#8217;s by far the most popular method for corporations looking to take an easy first step on the long road to decarbonizing or offsetting their industrial operations. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Restoring and preserving the world&#8217;s forests has long been considered one of the easiest, lowest-cost and simplest ways to reduce the amount of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s by far the most popular method for corporations looking to take an easy first step on the long road to decarbonizing or offsetting their industrial operations. But in recent months the efficacy, validity and reliability of a number of forest offsets have been called into question thanks to some blockbuster reporting from Bloomberg.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s against this uncertain backdrop that investors are coming in to shore up financing for <a href="https://pachama.com/">Pachama</a>, a company building a marketplace for forest carbon credits that it says is more transparent and verifiable thanks to its use of satellite imagery and machine learning technologies.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That pitch has brought in $15 million in new financing for the company, which co-founder and chief executive Diego Saez Gil said would be used for product development and the continued expansion of the company&#8217;s marketplace.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/03/pachama-launches-to-support-global-reforestation-through-carbon-markets/">Launched only one year ago</a>, Pachama has managed to land some impressive customers and backers. No less an authority on things environmental than Jeff Bezos (given how much of a negative impact Amazon operations have on the planet), <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/2020-letter-to-shareholders">gave the company a shoutout</a> in his last letter to shareholders as Amazon&#8217;s outgoing chief executive. And the largest e-commerce company in Latin America, Mercado Libre, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/mercado-libre-taps-pachama-to-monitor-and-manage-its-8-million-investment-in-latin-american-rainforest-restoration/">tapped the company to manage an $8 million offset project</a> that&#8217;s part of a broader commitment to sustainability by the retailing giant.</p>
<p>Amazon&#8217;s Climate Pledge Fund is an investor in the latest round, which was led by Bill Gates&#8217; investment firm Breakthrough Energy Ventures. Other investors included Lowercarbon Capital (the climate-focused fund from über-successful angel investor, Chris Sacca), former Uber executive Ryan Graves&#8217; Saltwater, the MCJ Collective, and new backers like Tim O&#8217;Reilly&#8217;s OATV, Ram Fhiram, Joe Gebbia, Marcos Galperin, NBA All-star Manu Ginobili, James Beshara, Fabrice Grinda, Sahil Lavignia and Tomi Pierucci.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="DMXOOjfrz1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/03/pachama-launches-to-support-global-reforestation-through-carbon-markets/">Pachama launches to support global reforestation through carbon markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pachama launches to support global reforestation through carbon markets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/03/pachama-launches-to-support-global-reforestation-through-carbon-markets/embed/#?secret=DMXOOjfrz1" data-secret="DMXOOjfrz1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>That&#8217;s not even the full list of the company&#8217;s backers. What&#8217;s made Pachama so successful, and given the company the ability to attract top talent from companies like Google, Facebook, SpaceX, Tesla, OpenAI, Microsoft, Impossible Foods and Orbital Insights, is the combination of its climate mission applied to the well-understood forest offset market, said Saez Gil.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Restoring nature is one of the most important solutions to climate change. Forests, oceans and other ecosystems not only sequester enormous amounts of CO</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">2 </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">from the atmosphere, but they also provide critical habitat for biodiversity and are sources of livelihood for communities worldwide. We are building the technology stack required to be able to drive funding to the restoration and conservation of these ecosystems with integrity, transparency and efficiency” said Saez Gil. “We feel honored and excited to have the support of such an incredible group of investors who believe in our mission and are demonstrating their willingness to support our growth for the long term.” </span></p>
<p>Customers outside of Latin America are also clamoring for access to Pachama&#8217;s offset marketplace. Microsoft, Shopify and SoftBank are also among the company&#8217;s paying buyers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s another reason that investors like<span style="font-weight: 400;"> Y Combinator, Social Capital, Tobi Lutke, Serena Williams, Aglaé Ventures (LVMH’s tech investment arm), Paul Graham, AirAngels, Global Founders, ThirdKind Ventures, Sweet Capital, Xplorer Capital, Scott Belsky, Tim Schumacher, Gustaf Alstromer, Facundo Garreton and Terrence Rohan were able to commit to backing the company&#8217;s nearly $24 million haul since its 2020 launch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Pachama is working on unlocking the full potential of nature to remove CO2 from the atmosphere,” said Carmichael Roberts from BEV, in a statement. “Their technology-based approach will have an enormous multiplier effect by using machine learning models for forest analysis to validate, monitor and measure impactful carbon neutrality initiatives. We are impressed by the progress that the team has made in a short period of time and look forward to working with them to scale their unique solution globally.” </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xKYtDcHEUU"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/">Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Corporate sustainability initiatives may open doors for carbon offset startups&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/01/corporate-sustainability-initiatives-may-open-doors-for-carbon-offset-startups/embed/#?secret=xKYtDcHEUU" data-secret="xKYtDcHEUU" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/30/as-concerns-rise-over-forest-carbon-offsets-pachamas-verified-offset-marketplace-gets-15-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2146064</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
