<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 12:09:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Scalapay raises $155M at a $700M valuation as buy-now, pay-later services continue to boom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/scalapay-raises-155m-at-a-700m-valuation-as-buy-now-pay-later-services-continue-to-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/scalapay-raises-155m-at-a-700m-valuation-as-buy-now-pay-later-services-continue-to-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 12:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scalapay, a buy-now, pay-later (BNPL) technology provider that has made significant headway with retailers and consumers in Europe and in categories like fashion, has closed a round of funding that it will be using to fuel its expansion ambitions. The startup has raised $155 million at a $700 million valuation. Tiger Global is leading this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.scalapay.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scalapay</a>, a buy-now, pay-later (BNPL) technology provider that has made significant headway with retailers and consumers in Europe and in categories like fashion, has closed a round of funding that it will be using to fuel its expansion ambitions. The startup has raised $155 million at a $700 million valuation.</p>
<p>Tiger Global is leading this round, with new backers Baleen Capital and Woodson Capital also participating, alongside Fasanara Capital and Ithaca Investments, which had backed Scalapay in its previous <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/scalapay-raises-48m-to-scale-its-buy-now-pay-later-service-in-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$48 million round earlier this year</a>. (Scalapay has now raised $203 million in total.)</p>
<p>This is a sizable round of funding given Scalapay&#8217;s age: the company is only two years old and this is a Series A. Ramping up in this way underscores just how hot the BNPL market is right now, and also how the startup has been faring within that.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s service is based around being tightly integrated with online retailers&#8217; check-out process and offering users an interest-free, three-installment way to pay for anything they purchase. It now works with 3,000 merchants in Europe &#8212; specifically Italy, France, Germany, Spain, Portugal, Finland, Belgium, Netherlands and Austria &#8212; and it has yet to move into huge markets like the U.S. and U.K.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we launched, we saw between 5% and 10% of all transactions for our customers go through Scalapay,&#8221; CEO Simone Mancini, who co-founded the company with Johnny Mitrevski, said in an interview. &#8220;Now we are at 15%-20% and its growing. In luxury fashion we&#8217;re accounting for 30%-50% of all transactions, and in some cases more than half. We want to be the thing that makes purchasing pleasurable again.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pleasurable, and more likely to happen: while shopping cart abandonment continues to be an issue for all online retailers, Scalapay claims that its existence has increased conversions by 11%, and gives consumers the confidence to spend more, typically 48% more per shopper.</p>
<p>The growth of buy-now, pay-later services has been one of big hallmarks of the pandemic-era e-commerce market. Although the option to pay for items in installments had been around for years before Covid-19 &#8212; indeed, layaway and other delayed payment services were big even before e-commerce was a thing &#8212; usage of BNPL saw a new boost of attention on the back of way more people using online channels to shop, and &#8212; given the uncertainties of the economy &#8212; way more of them needing some financial help ultimately to make purchases.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That was complemented too by a new and more sophisticated approach: the leading BNPL providers are bringing together a much more ambitious big-data play, leveraging wider risk analysis and a much more creative and complete picture of a person and his/her finances in order to better understand what to expect out of any transaction. The algorithms and how they direct the course of transactions have become as important as the accessibility of the services themselves.</p>
<p>All of this has led to a huge rush of big BNPL companies getting even bigger. Klarna, which has long been seen as the most valuable startup in Europe (in terms of paper valuation) raised money at a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/fintech-giant-klarna-raises-639m-at-a-45-6b-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">valuation of nearly $46 billion in June</a>. Affirm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/wall-street-hugs-affirm-as-it-starts-life-as-a-public-company/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">went public at the start of the year</a> and is currently valued at aorund $23 billion. PayPal re-upped its own ambitions in the market with an Asian kicker just this week: it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/paypal-acquires-japans-paidy-for-2-7b-to-crack-the-buy-now-pay-later-market-in-asia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquired Paidy in Japan for nearly $3 billion</a>. And of course Square has waded into the space in a big way with its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/01/square-to-buy-buy-now-pay-later-giant-afterpay-in-29b-deal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$29 billion acquisition of Afterpay</a> in June.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s before you consider the many smaller BNPL companies that have raised and are raising money. They include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/uks-zilch-raises-80m-at-a-500m-valuation-for-its-direct-to-consumer-buy-now-pay-later-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zilch</a>, which is now valued at over $500 million; and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/affirm-spinout-resolve-raises-60m-for-its-b2b-buy-now-pay-later-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Resolve</a>, a spinout from Affirm, which has raised $60 million.</p>
<p>In that context, Scalapay&#8217;s $700 million valuation seems modest &#8212; maybe even a little like a bargain? You may not be surprised that this latest fundraising happened on the heels of the startup actually getting approached to be acquired, not by one but by two different companies, which were interested in the technology, but also the fact that Scalapay had made significant headway into specific markets &#8212; geographically, in Europe; and also in terms of product categories, specifically fashion &#8212; where they are keen to grow.</p>
<p>Mancini declined to say which companies except to note they were among the biggest of the lot. (Just my inference, but maybe the acquisition pace of some of the bigger players gives a clue as to whom it might have been?) In any case, Scalapay said no, but the chatter got other things moving, and that is how Tiger Global came into the picture.</p>
<p>Big investor pockets could prove to be a key part of how any of these companies fare going forward: relationship building and expanding your own pool of talent will be key for growing, both areas where having the right contacts and the right resources to meet new demands will come in handy.</p>
<p>&#8220;Scalapay has quickly become an important player in European payments and the BNPL sector,” said Alex Cook, Partner, Tiger Global, in a statement. “We are impressed by their product development pipeline and strong focus on merchant success. We are excited to support Scalapay in the next phase of its growth.&#8221;</p>
<p>Interestingly the company said it plans to stay very focused on improving the process of BNPL rather than diversify into other areas like fintech (areas where Affirm and Klarna are doing a lot); or the wider area of payments (an obvious move for Afterpay and Square).</p>
<p>“While the likes of Klarna and Afterpay have launched deposit accounts and moved further into the banking space, Scalapay’s exciting roadmap is laser focused on helping merchants with new customer experiences that increase conversion. They’re leveraging BNPL in an entirely new way,” added Francesco Filia, CEO of Fasanara Capital.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/scalapay-raises-155m-at-a-700m-valuation-as-buy-now-pay-later-services-continue-to-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teatis, low-sugar superfood powders developer for diabetics, closes seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/teatis-low-sugar-superfood-powders-developer-for-diabetics-closes-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/teatis-low-sugar-superfood-powders-developer-for-diabetics-closes-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plant-based food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telehealth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A serial entrepreneur Hiroshi Takatoh recognized the need for convenient and nutritious food for critically ill consumers after losing his late wife to cancer. Takatoh founded Teatis, a plant-based sugar blocking superfood powder for diabetic consumers, in 2017 in stealth mode and went fully operational in April 2021 by teaming up with a group of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A serial entrepreneur <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tak-hiroshi-takatoh/?originalSubdomain=jp">Hiroshi Takatoh</a> recognized the need for convenient and nutritious food for critically ill consumers after losing his late wife to cancer.</p>
<p>Takatoh founded <a href="https://teatismeal.com/">Teatis</a>, a plant-based sugar blocking superfood powder for diabetic consumers, in 2017 in stealth mode and went fully operational in April 2021 by teaming up with a group of doctors and registered nutritionists.</p>
<p>Teatis announced today it has raised $700,000 seed funding to advance its growth in the US market.  The seed money brings Teatis’ total funding to over $1million.</p>
<p>The seed round was led by <a href="https://www.genesiaventures.com/en/top-en/">Genesia Ventures</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryonations/">Ryo Ishizuka</a>, former CEO and co-founder of Japanese e-commerce company Mercari and <a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/person/takuya-noguchi-47e9">Takuya Noguchi</a>, CEO and founder of Japan’s skincare brand BULK HOMME. Seven other angel investors also participated in the seed funding.</p>
<p>Teatis will use the seed money for production and marketing in the US, where 122 million diabetics and pre-diabetics continue to work for prevention and treatment against diabetes, CEO and co-founder of Teatis Hiroshi Takatoh told TechCrunch. The company is now focusing on the US market where its production is located while its next funding, a Series A, is set for next year, Takatoh added.</p>
<p>“Most of our consumers, about 88%, are diabetics, and our recipe is built to help diabetics manage their blood sugar. A staggering number of Americans suffer from diabetes, and there is significant demand for diabetic-friendly foods that are nutritious, convenient and functional,” Takatoh said.</p>
<p>Teatis develops a supplement for all consumers interested in low-sugar foods, as well as pre-diabetics, Takatoh said. Teatis’ plant-based powders does not contain chemicals or sweeteners but include a special Japanese ingredient such as brown seaweed extract (Arame) that is proven to suppress the absorption of sugar from the intestinal tract and reduce blood sugar levels. The low-sugar powder can be made into teas, lattes or added to smoothies.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nyrrGpdXDs"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/oviva-grabs-80m-for-app-delivered-healthy-diet-programs/">Oviva grabs $80M for app-delivered healthy eating programs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Oviva grabs $80M for app-delivered healthy eating programs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/oviva-grabs-80m-for-app-delivered-healthy-diet-programs/embed/#?secret=nyrrGpdXDs" data-secret="nyrrGpdXDs" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The US meal placement market size for diabetes is estimated at $5 billion while the US consumer packaged foods market for diabetes is approximately $300 billion, Takatoh said.</p>
<p>“We combine food science and technology to solve problems for diabetics through food products and telehealth,” Takatoh said.</p>
<p>With its plan on building out a comprehensive one-stop shop for diabetic health, Teatis will launch a Registered Dietitian platform, <em>Teatis RD on Demand</em>, this month, to offer a full-service such as food products, telehealth, and recipes, for those battling diabetes.</p>
<p><em>Teatis RD on Demand</em> will provide private, 1-on-1 sessions with registered dietitians. It will start at $29 per 30 minutes, which is a reduced cost, versus traditional offline appointments that cost $150 per 30 minutes, and Teledoc, which costs $90 per 30 minutes, according to Takatoh.</p>
<p>&#8220;Many existing players in space are old companies that don&#8217;t have digital competency and data-driven production methods. Mr. Takatoh is a proven serial entrepreneur with the qualities and boldness to take over the market&#8230;I&#8217;m excited to see how Teatis&#8217; great ideas and products will help many people who are suffering from diabetes and other chronic diseases in the future,&#8221; Genesia Ventures Manager Shunsuke Sagara said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kAaT0X06Vx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/oviva/">Oviva scores $21M Series B to bring its digital diabetes treatment to more of Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Oviva scores $21M Series B to bring its digital diabetes treatment to more of Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/oviva/embed/#?secret=kAaT0X06Vx" data-secret="kAaT0X06Vx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="igWb5hJcuP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/plant-based-cereal-startup-offlimits-pours-2-3m-into-new-products/">Plant-based cereal startup OffLimits pours $2.3M into new products</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Plant-based cereal startup OffLimits pours $2.3M into new products&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/plant-based-cereal-startup-offlimits-pours-2-3m-into-new-products/embed/#?secret=igWb5hJcuP" data-secret="igWb5hJcuP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/teatis-low-sugar-superfood-powders-developer-for-diabetics-closes-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199250</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CookUnity whips up nationwide expansion following $47M round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/cookunity-whips-up-nationwide-expansion-following-47m-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/cookunity-whips-up-nationwide-expansion-following-47m-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 12:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chefs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CookUnity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[delivery services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Endeavor Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fuel Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaingels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IDCV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mateo Marietti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rebecca Liu-Doyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Restaurants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CookUnity combines the ready-to-eat meal category with a chef-focused business model that provides restaurant-quality meals at home.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chef-prepared, small-batch meal delivery startup <a href="https://www.cookunity.com/">CookUnity</a> is undergoing a major expansion after closing a $47 million Series B round.</p>
<p>Insight Partners led the round and was joined by Endeavor Capital and current investors IDCV, Fuel Ventures and Gaingels. The latest funding comes eight months after New York-based CookUnity closed a <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/cookunity-secures-15-5-million-in-series-a-funding-301207553.html">$15.5 million Series A round</a> led by Fuel Venture Capital. The company has now raised a total of $70 million since its inception in 2018.</p>
<p>Mateo Marietti, founder and CEO of CookUnity, had the idea for the subscription-based company five years ago. Marietti, who is from Argentina, was working in food tech and saw that modern delivery services were only able to offer limited food options and pricing, and was a trade-off between convenience and variety.</p>
<p>He went looking for a similar experience to apps like Spotify, where the music selection was limitless, and created CookUnity to connect creators of food with the people who would be eating it.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AL3MSTGSi3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/woodspoons-food-delivery-service-cooks-up-support-for-home-chefs-with-14m-round/">WoodSpoon’s food delivery service cooks up support for home chefs with $14M round</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;WoodSpoon’s food delivery service cooks up support for home chefs with $14M round&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/woodspoons-food-delivery-service-cooks-up-support-for-home-chefs-with-14m-round/embed/#?secret=AL3MSTGSi3" data-secret="AL3MSTGSi3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>CookUnity combines the ready-to-eat meal category with a chef-focused business model that provides restaurant-quality meals at home. The rotating menu features hundreds of dishes, starting at $10.49 per meal, with an option of a subscription plan for four, six, eight, 12 or 16 meals per week. Meals heat up in minutes and also include both fast-cooking instructions, like in a microwave, or how the chef might prepare it at home, like with an additional squeeze of lemon or other toppings.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199793" style="width: 463px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199793" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2199793 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?w=453" alt="" width="453" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg 4480w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?resize=768,1152 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?resize=1024,1536 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?resize=1365,2048 1365w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/onken_20210708_CookUnity_MateoMrietti_127.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 453px) 100vw, 453px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199793" class="wp-caption-text">CookUnity founder Mateo Marietti. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> CookUnity</p></div></p>
<p>Chefs are also given tools and resources to create a digital-first business, and Marietti told TechCrunch that top-selling chefs bring in upwards of $1 million a year.</p>
<p>“We are building the infrastructure, working with farmers, providing the ingredients and the tech layer for both the consumer app and the chef app,” he added. “We don’t employ any talent or cook the food, but we give chefs the tools to start recruiting cooks, gather information on new recipes, organize their team and expand into new markets while also seeing their sales for the day or week.”</p>
<p>The company’s platform is already working with notable chefs like Jean-Georges Vongerichten, Marc Forgione and Esther Choi, and the Series B funding will enable it to add more chefs, including local rising stars and established restaurateurs, enabling them to sell beyond the typical on-demand food delivery zone, Marietti said.</p>
<p>Starting with the flagship kitchen in Brooklyn, CookUnity initially expanded to San Francisco, Dallas-Fort Worth, Boston and Washington, D.C. Following the Series A, the company opened kitchens in Los Angeles, Austin and Chicago. The new funding will now enable the company to accelerate its nationwide expansion with new kitchens in Atlanta and Miami by the end of the year. When all of the new kitchens are online, Marietti estimates that CookUnity will be able to serve 88% of the U.S. population.</p>
<p>In the last 12 months, CookUnity saw over 550% growth and to date has over 50 chefs on its roster, with plans to increase to 150 across all of its kitchens by mid-2022.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As part of the investment, Rebecca Liu-Doyle, principal at Insight Partners, is joining the CookUnity board of directors. Insight’s model is to track companies for a long time before investing; in CookUnity’s case, Liu-Doyle was watching them for more than two years. She said the timing was right for Insight to invest.</p>
<p>In addition to product-market fit, strong chef retention and liking the company’s focus on the food market, which is a “massive total addressable market,” she said, CookUnity was on its way to building a big business with subscription-based revenue as it took on the complexities of the back-end business for chefs.</p>
<p>The value proposition is unique for both of the stakeholders — on the chef side there is a creator economy tailwind, which is taking the friction out of scaling a business while also enabling chefs to build a business with a larger footprint than they just selling food around their restaurants. On the consumer side, Liu-Doyle said CookUnity is providing affordable and convenient food without having to compromise on taste and quality.</p>
<p>“Very few companies can offer that: it is democratization on both fronts,” she added. “In order to execute on the vision, you need a specific team, which Mateo has, and show incremental improvement to the experience. It doesn&#8217;t just happen overnight. You have to be patient and deliberate in the way you improve the experience.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eOdgnQPlQ7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/delivery-hero-ceo-shares-what-hes-learned-about-managing-logistics-during-a-pandemic/">Delivery Hero CEO shares what he&#8217;s learned about managing logistics during a pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Delivery Hero CEO shares what he&#8217;s learned about managing logistics during a pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/16/delivery-hero-ceo-shares-what-hes-learned-about-managing-logistics-during-a-pandemic/embed/#?secret=eOdgnQPlQ7" data-secret="eOdgnQPlQ7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/cookunity-whips-up-nationwide-expansion-following-47m-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199745</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fin names former Twilio exec Evan Cummack as CEO, raises $20M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/fin-names-former-twilio-exec-evan-cummack-as-ceo-raises-20m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/fin-names-former-twilio-exec-evan-cummack-as-ceo-raises-20m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Kortina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arielle Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business process management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Round Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groupware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kleiner Perkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Lessin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fin's software captures employee workflow data from across applications and turns it into productivity insights to improve the way enterprise teams work and remain engaged.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Work insights platform <a href="http://www.fin.com/">Fin</a> raised $20 million in Series A funding and brought in Evan Cummack, a former Twilio executive, as its new chief executive officer.</p>
<p>The San Francisco-based company captures employee workflow data from across applications and turns it into productivity insights to improve the way enterprise teams work and remain engaged.</p>
<p>Fin was founded in 2015 by Andrew Kortina, co-founder of Venmo, and Facebook’s former VP of product and Slow Ventures partner Sam Lessin. Initially, the company was doing voice assistant technology — think Alexa but powered by humans and machine learning — and then workplace analytics software. You can read more about Fin’s origins at the link below.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8NIi3GgY4h"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/02/sam-lessin-and-andrew-kortina-on-their-voice-assistants-workplace-pivot/">Sam Lessin and Andrew Kortina on their voice assistant’s workplace pivot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sam Lessin and Andrew Kortina on their voice assistant’s workplace pivot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/02/sam-lessin-and-andrew-kortina-on-their-voice-assistants-workplace-pivot/embed/#?secret=8NIi3GgY4h" data-secret="8NIi3GgY4h" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In 2020, the company pivoted again to the company it is today. The new round was led by Coatue, with participation from First Round Capital, Accel and Kleiner Perkins. The original team was talented, but small, so the new funding will build out sales, marketing and engineering teams, Cummack said.</p>
<p>“At that point, the right thing was to raise money, so at the end of last year, the company raised a $20 million Series A, and it was also decided to find a leadership team that knows how to build an enterprise,” Cummack told TechCrunch. “The company had completely pivoted and removed ‘Analytics’ from our name because it was not encompassing what we do.”</p>
<p>Fin’s software measures productivity and provides insights on ways managers can optimize processes, coach their employees and see how teams are actually using technology to get their work done. At the same time, employees are able to manage their workflow and highlight areas where there may be bottlenecks. All combined, it leads to better operations and customer experiences, Cummack said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2199830" style="width: 2978px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199830" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2199830 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png" alt="" width="2968" height="1434" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png 2968w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png?resize=150,72 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png?resize=300,145 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png?resize=768,371 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png?resize=680,329 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png?resize=1536,742 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png?resize=2048,989 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/06-Fin.com-Uncover-how-work-is-really-done.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2968px) 100vw, 2968px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199830" class="wp-caption-text">Graphic showing how work is really done. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fin</p></div></p>
<p>Fin’s view is that as more automation occurs, the company is looking at a “renaissance of human work.” There will be more jobs and more types of jobs, but people will be able to do them more effectively and the work will be more fulfilling, he added.</p>
<p>Particularly with the use of technology, he notes that in the era before cloud computing, there was a small number of software vendors. Now with the average tech company using over 130 SaaS apps, it allows for a lot of entrepreneurs and adoption of best-in-breed apps so that a viable company can start with a handful of people and leverage those apps to gain big customers.</p>
<p>“It’s different for enterprise customers, though, to understand that investment and what they are spending their money on as they use tools to get their jobs done,” Cummack added. “There is massive pressure to improve the customer experience and move quickly. Now with many people working from home, Fin enables you to look at all 130 apps as if they are one and how they are being used.”</p>
<p>As a result, Fin’s customers are seeing metrics like 16% increase in team utilization and engagement, a 25% decrease in support ticket handle time and a 71% increase in policy compliance. Meanwhile, the company itself is doubling and tripling its customers and revenue each year.</p>
<p>Now with leadership and people in place, Cummack said the company is positioned to scale, though it already had a huge head start in terms of a meaningful business.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QGHZjeeXHv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/productivity-startup-time-is-ltd-raises-5-6m-to-be-the-google-analytics-for-company-time/">Productivity startup Time is Ltd. raises $5.6M to be the &#8216;Google Analytics for company time&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Productivity startup Time is Ltd. raises $5.6M to be the &#8216;Google Analytics for company time&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/10/productivity-startup-time-is-ltd-raises-5-6m-to-be-the-google-analytics-for-company-time/embed/#?secret=QGHZjeeXHv" data-secret="QGHZjeeXHv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Arielle Zuckerberg, partner at Coatue, said via email that she was part of a previous firm that invested in Fin’s seed round to build a virtual assistant. She was also a customer of Fin Assistant until it was discontinued.</p>
<p>When she heard the company was pivoting to enterprise, she “was excited because I thought it was a natural outgrowth of the previous business, had a lot of potential and I was already familiar with management and thought highly of them.”</p>
<p>She believed the “brains” of the company always revolved around understanding and measuring what assistants were doing to complete a task as a way to create opportunities for improvement or automation. The pivot to agent-facing tools made sense to Zuckerberg, but it wasn’t until the global pandemic that it clicked.</p>
<p>&#8220;Service teams were forced to go remote overnight, and companies had little to no visibility into what people were doing working from home,&#8221; she added. “In this remote environment, we thought that Fin&#8217;s product was incredibly well-suited to address the challenges of managing a growing remote support team, and that over time, their unique data set of how people use various apps and tools to complete tasks can help business leaders improve the future of work for their team members. We believe that contact center agents going remote was inevitable even before COVID, but COVID was a huge accelerant and created a compelling ‘why now’ moment for Fin’s solution.”</p>
<p>Going forward, Coatue sees Fin as “a process mining company that is focused on service teams.” By initially focusing on customer support and contact center use case — a business large enough to support a scaled, standalone business — rather than joining competitors in going after Fortune 500 companies where implementation cycles are long and there is slow time-to-value, Zuckerberg said Fin is better able to “address the unique challenges of managing a growing remote support team with a near-immediate time-to-value.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZYeV9ntDUB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/5-emerging-use-cases-for-productivity-infrastructure-in-2021/">5 emerging use cases for productivity infrastructure in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 emerging use cases for productivity infrastructure in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/22/5-emerging-use-cases-for-productivity-infrastructure-in-2021/embed/#?secret=ZYeV9ntDUB" data-secret="ZYeV9ntDUB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/fin-names-former-twilio-exec-evan-cummack-as-ceo-raises-20m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199822</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nuula raises $120M to build out a financial services &#8216;superapp&#8217; aimed at SMBs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/nuula-raises-120m-to-build-out-a-financial-services-superapp-aimed-at-smbs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/nuula-raises-120m-to-build-out-a-financial-services-superapp-aimed-at-smbs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 11:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atom bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edison Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honeywell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kabbage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuula]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PayPal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Canadian startup called Nuula that is aiming to build a superapp to provide a range of financial services to small and medium businesses has closed $120 million of funding, money that it will use to fuel the launch of its app and first product, a line of credit for its users. The money is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A Canadian startup called <a href="https://nuula.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nuula</a> that is aiming to build a superapp to provide a range of financial services to small and medium businesses has closed $120 million of funding, money that it will use to fuel the launch of its app and first product, a line of credit for its users.</p>
<p>The money is coming in the form of $20 million in equity from Edison Partners, and a $100 million credit facility from funds managed by the Credit Group of Ares Management Corporation.</p>
<p>The Nuula app has been in a limited beta since June of this year. The plan is to open it up to general availability soon, while also gradually bringing in more services, some built directly by Nuula itself and but many others following an embedded finance strategy: business banking, for example, will be a service provided by a third party and integrated closely into the Nuula app to be launched early in 2022; and alongside that, the startup will also be making liberal use of APIs to bring in other white-label services such as B2B and customer-focused payment services, starting first in the U.S. and then expanding to Canada and the U.K. before further countries across Europe.</p>
<p>Current products include cash flow forecasting, personal and business credit score monitoring, and customer sentiment tracking; and monitoring of other critical metrics including financial, payments and eCommerce data are all on the roadmap.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re building tools to work in a complementary fashion in the app,&#8221; CEO Mark Ruddock said in an interview. &#8220;Today, businesses can project if they are likely to run out of money, and monitor their credit scores. We keep an eye on customers and what they are saying in real time. We think it&#8217;s necessary to surface for SMBs the metrics that they might have needed to get from multiple apps, all in one place.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p4">Nuula was originally a side-project at BFS, a company that focused on small business lending, where the company started to look at the idea of how to better leverage data to build out a wider set of services addressing the same segment of the market. BFS grew to be a <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20190122005515/en/BFS-Capital-Achieves-2-Billion-in-Financing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">substantial business in its own right</a> (and it had raised its own money to that end, to the tune of<a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/54065-89/company/profile#investors" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> $184 million</a> from Edison and Honeywell).  Over time, it became apparent to management that the data aspect, and this concept of a super app, would be key to how to grow the business, and so it <a href="https://debanked.com/2021/04/bfs-capital-is-now-nuula/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pivoted and rebranded earlier this year</a>, launching the beta of the app after that.</p>
<p>Nuula&#8217;s ambitions fall within a bigger trend in the market. Small and medium enterprises have shaped up to be a huge business opportunity in the world of fintech in the last several years. Long ignored in favor of building solutions either for the giant consumer market, or the lucrative large enterprise sector, SMBs have proven that they want and are willing to invest in better and newer technology to run their businesses, and that&#8217;s leading to a rush of startups and bigger tech companies bringing services to the market to cater to that.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Super apps are also a big area of interest in the world of fintech, although up to now a lot of what we&#8217;ve heard about in that area has been aimed at consumers &#8212; just the kind of innovation rut that Nuula is trying to get moving.</p>
<p class="p4">&#8220;Despite the growth in services addressing the SMB sector, overall it still lacks innovation compared to consumer or enterprise services,&#8221; Ruddock said. &#8220;We thought there was some opportunity to bring new thinking to the space. We see this as the app that SMBs will want to use everyday, because we&#8217;ll provide useful tools, insights and capital to power their businesses.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p4">Nuula&#8217;s priority to build the data services that connect all of this together is very much in keeping with how a lot of neobanks are also developing services and investing in what they see as their unique selling point. The theory goes like this: banking services are, at the end of the day, the same everywhere you go, and therefore commoditized, and so the more unique value-added for companies will come from innovating with more interesting algorithms and other data-based insights and analytics to give more power to their users to make the best use of what they have at their disposal.</p>
<p>It will not be alone in addressing that market. Others building fintech for SMBs include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/22/uks-selina-finance-raises-42m-for-its-smb-loans-platform-based-on-home-equity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Selina</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/uks-anna-raises-21m-for-its-smb-focused-business-account-and-tax-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ANNA</a>, Amex&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/17/amex-acquires-softbank-backed-kabbage-after-tough-2020-for-the-smb-lender/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kabbage</a> (an early mover in using big data to help loan money to SMBs and build other financial services for them), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/novo-a-neobank-for-smbs-banks-41m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Novo</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/07/uks-atom-bank-raises-another-206m-led-by-bbva-for-millennial-and-smb-financial-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atom Bank</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/12/hoping-to-be-latams-top-digital-bank-for-smbs-xepelin-launches-a-lending-and-revenue-management-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xepelin</a>, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/liberis-the-embedded-finance-provider-for-smes-raises-additional-70m-in-equity-and-debt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Liberis</a>, biggies like Stripe, Square and PayPal, and many others.</p>
<p class="p4">The credit product that Nuula has built so far is a taster of how it hopes to be a useful tool for SMBs, not just another place to get money or manage it. It&#8217;s not a direct loaning service, but rather something that is closely linked to monitoring a customers&#8217; incomings and outgoings and only prompts a credit line (which directly links into the users&#8217; account, wherever it is) when it appears that it might be needed.</p>
<p class="p2">“Innovations in financial technology have largely democratized who can become the next big player in small business finance,” added Gary Golding, General Partner, Edison Partners. “By combining critical financial performance tools and insights into a single interface, Nuula represents a new class of financial services technology for small business, and we are excited by the potential of the firm.”</p>
<p>“We are excited to be working with Nuula as they build a unique financial services resource for small businesses and entrepreneurs,” said Jeffrey Kramer, Partner and Head of ABS in the Alternative Credit strategy of the Ares Credit Group, in a statement. “The evolution of financial technology continues to open opportunities for innovation and the emergence of new industry participants. We look forward to seeing Nuula’s experienced team of technologists, data scientists and financial service veterans bring a new generation of small business financial services solutions to market.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/nuula-raises-120m-to-build-out-a-financial-services-superapp-aimed-at-smbs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200013</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>With an Apple Store designer as a co-founder, Juno raises $20M to build apartments more sustainably</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/juno-raises-20m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/juno-raises-20m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comcast Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Juno]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[khosla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proptech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate Technology Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Juno, a proptech startup which aims to build more sustainable and affordable apartment buildings, has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round. Comcast Ventures, Khosla Ventures and Real Estate Technology (RET) Ventures co-led the financing, which brings the company’s total raised to $32 million since its 2019 inception. JLL Spark, Vertex Ventures, Anim, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://juno.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a proptech startup which aims to build more sustainable and affordable apartment buildings, has raised $20 million in a Series A funding round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Comcast Ventures, Khosla Ventures and Real Estate Technology (RET) Ventures co-led the financing, which brings the company’s total raised to $32 million since its 2019 inception. JLL Spark, Vertex Ventures, Anim, K50, Foundamental and Green D Alumni Ventures also participated in the Series A investment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno co-founder and CEO Jonathan Scherr said the San Francisco-based startup plans to build all electric properties by </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">assembling “the first OEM ecosystem for ground-up development.” (For the unacquainted, OEM stands for “original equipment manufacturer.&#8221;)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re&#8230;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">treating housing development like product development, a process we call ‘productization,’ ” he told TechCrunch. “By creating buildings that are worthy of being repeated, tools and systems can be created to enable continuous improvement and increase efficiency. If buildings are considered or designed in a one-off context, then the learnings from one project to the next will fail to exist.”</span></p>
<p>Note that Juno&#8217;s productization could be considered similar to the more commonly used term prefabrication in some aspects. While prefab construction company Katerra <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/softbank-backed-construction-giant-katerra-said-to-be-shutting-down-after-raising-billions/">crashed and burned</a>, a number of other companies in the space continue to raise money and grow, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/abodu-raises-20m-to-build-prefabricated-backyard-homes/">Abodu</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/khosla-backs-construction-tech-startup-mighty-buildings-plans-to-create-3d-printed-homes/">Mighty Buildings,</a> which is also backed by Khosla but is more focused accessory dwelling units and single-family homes. There is also North Carolina-based <a href="https://prescientco.com/">Prescient</a>, which is also  constructing multifamily housing and hotels through prefabrication.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199953" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199953" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2199953 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Exterior-2.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199953" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rendering of Austin project; Engraff Studio / Juno</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno&#8217;s theory is that via &#8220;productization,&#8221; it can create the tools, systems and processes that can lead to things like reduced design timelines, increased precision in estimation and scheduling and a “significantly accelerated” construction process. All this, Scherr said, can result in more affordable housing options for people all over the United States. Also, Juno claims that its design process, for example, is 60% faster than in traditional real estate development.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like other players in the space, Juno of course touts an approach that it says is far more sustainable than traditional construction methods.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Today, construction refuse is literally 2x that of all municipal refuse combined in the U.S.,” Scherr told TechCrunch. “The Juno system creates efficiency in the design, supply chain, and construction of buildings that reduce waste and energy usage.” Features include low-carbon, all timber construction, more exposed wood (which Juno says is anti-microbial) and entirely gasless buildings, for example.</span></p>
<p>Thanks to its focus on all-electric buildings in cities that have established roadmaps to clean energy generation, the Juno residential system is trending toward a net zero target for embodied carbon in its multifamily residential units, Scherr said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scherr founded Juno with BJ Siegel, who was a designer of the original Apple Store, and Chester Chipperfield, who currently serves as an advisor to the company. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chipperfield previously served as global creative director at Tesla, head of special projects at Apple and head of digital at Burberry. Scherr has worked as a venture investor and advisor to a number of companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As the concept architect for Apple’s retail program going back as far as 1999, BJ [Siegel] had thought about how to create an identity for the built environment that deserved to be repeated,” Scherr said. “By doing so, he and his colleagues at Apple began to think about Apple retail more like Apple’s products: grounded in a decentralized supply chain.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199963" style="width: 328px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199963" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2199963 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?w=200" alt="" width="318" height="478" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg 1363w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=100,150 100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=200,300 200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=768,1154 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=453,680 453w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=1022,1536 1022w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/founders-2.jpg?resize=33,50 33w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199963" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> From left to right: Chester Chipperfield, co-founder and advisor Jonathan Scherr, co-founder and CEO BJ Siegel, co-founder and Head of Design / Juno</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno was created with a similar model in mind: with the goal of designing &#8220;better&#8221; housing that could be replicated so that the company is able “to build out a supply chain and lay the groundwork for learning systems in ways that have never been possible before,” said Scherr, whose father was a real estate developer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno is starting out by building what it describes as the first national network of mass timber apartment buildings at scale with all-electric buildings in cities across the United States. And it’s partnering with </span><a href="https://swinerton.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Swinerton</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><a href="http://www.ennead.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Ennead Architects</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to put its model into practice. The startup has also broken ground on its first project &#8212; an apartment building in East Austin &#8212; and currently has more than 400 units in development. The East Austin building is slated to open in 2022. Juno also has sites planned for Seattle and Denver.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, the company plans to use its new capital to continue to build out its product, break ground on its first cohort of projects and engage with more developers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Juno&#8217;s investors are naturally bullish on what the company is doing, and plans to do.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evan Moore, partner at Khosla Ventures, said he does not generally invest in real estate development companies or builders or architects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But when a strong team is working on a dramatically different product in an important industry, I&#8217;ll get behind it,” he wrote via email.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, Moore added, apartment development has been a finance-driven industry, rather than product-driven, despite the fact that apartments are consumer products and derive their value from their use. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So there&#8217;s a tremendous opportunity to design buildings with the customer experience at the forefront,” he said. “What if Apple built apartment buildings? To me, that means working backwards from the experience you want to create, designing the components, supply chain and systems to support it, and working within cost as a constraint. That&#8217;s an ambitious idea, and an experiment worth undertaking.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sheena Jindal, principal at Comcast Ventures, notes that America’s housing stock is increasingly aged and in short supply &#8212; making it more difficult for people to buy houses. Her firm, she said, believes that everyone deserves access to an affordable home.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When we first met the Juno team, we were struck by their first principles approach to building,” she wrote via email. “Juno fundamentally understood what was broken in multifamily housing production and tackled it head on by focusing earlier in the value chain with its design and OEM sourcing strategy. Juno partners with existing players in the value chain, rather than displacing them.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p1tOMCYvQA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/">Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss proptech&#8217;s biggest opportunities</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fifth Wall&#8217;s Brendan Wallace and Hippo&#8217;s Assaf Wand discuss proptech&#8217;s biggest opportunities&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/26/fifth-walls-brendan-wallace-and-hippos-assaf-wand-discuss-proptechs-biggest-opportunities/embed/#?secret=p1tOMCYvQA" data-secret="p1tOMCYvQA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/juno-raises-20m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199947</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital therapeutics startup Neuroglee raises $10M to help people with neurodegenerative conditions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/digital-therapeutics-startup-neuroglee-raises-10m-to-help-people-with-neurodegenerative-conditions/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/digital-therapeutics-startup-neuroglee-raises-10m-to-help-people-with-neurodegenerative-conditions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alzheimer's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital therapeutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neurodegenerative disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuroglee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuroglee Therapeutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Neuroglee Therapeutics, a startup developing digital therapeutics for people with neurodegenerative diseases, has raised a $10 million Series A led by Openspace Ventures and EDBI. The funding will be used to launch virtual neurology clinics and to support Neuroglee’s move to Boston. Other participants included Ramen Singh, the former chief executive officer of Mundipharma; Biofourmis [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://neuroglee.com/">Neuroglee Therapeutics</a>, a startup developing digital therapeutics for people with neurodegenerative diseases, has raised a $10 million Series A led by Openspace Ventures and EDBI. The funding will be used to launch virtual neurology clinics and to support Neuroglee’s move to Boston. Other participants included Ramen Singh, the former chief executive officer of Mundipharma; Biofourmis co-founders Kuldeep Singh Rajput and Wendou Liu; and Eisai Co., the Japanese pharmaceutical that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/">led Neuroglee’s last round last year</a>.</p>
<p>In an email, founder and chief executive officer Aniket Singh Rajput told TechCrunch that the company is moving to Boston because the city “is one of the largest digital health hubs in the world. As a company devoted to developing our first line of solutions for treating mild cognitive impairment related to difficult-to-treat neurodegenerative conditions such as Alzheimer’s disease, we believe Boston will offer us the strategic support in order to do so.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="m7gOzSRZPH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/">Neuroglee gets $2.3 million to develop digital therapeutics for neurodegenerative diseases</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Neuroglee gets $2.3 million to develop digital therapeutics for neurodegenerative diseases&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/02/neuroglee-gets-2-3-million-to-develop-digital-therapeutics-for-neurodegenerative-diseases/embed/#?secret=m7gOzSRZPH" data-secret="m7gOzSRZPH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Neuroglee and the Mayo Clinic are currently working together on a new platform called Neuroglee Connect. Based on the Mayo Clinic’s 10-day in-person program HABIT (Health Action to Benefit Independence and Thinking) for people with mild cognitive impairment from possible neurodegenerative conditions, Neuroglee’s technology will enable HABIT to scale, making it available to patients and caregivers in their homes. Neuroglee Connect users will also have access to health navigators who are available 24 hours and clinical care teams for assessments and interventions.</p>
<p>Neuroglee&#8217;s product pipeline also includes digital therapeutics for Parkinson’s disease and strokes.</p>
<p>Since Neuroglee’s previous funding announcement in December 2020, Rajput said it has hit milestones like the successful product development of NG-001, its prescription digital therapy software for Alzheimer’s, and began work on its proof-of-concept study to earn NG-001 a Breakthrough Designation from the Federal Drug Administration.</p>
<p>Neuroglee’s adaptive learning tech uses machine learning and biomarkers related to cognitive function, mood and behavior to automatically personalize therapy plans for each patient, who access the software through a smartphone or tablet.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“For example, adjustments will be made to the number and type of tasks and games that are offered, based on the speed of the patient’s finger movements, time to complete games or tasks, and their facial expression identified through the device camera,” said Rajput. “The solution also incorporates reminiscence therapy, which uses images from the patient’s past to evoke positive memories and emotions, which have been shown to improve cognitive functioning.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OIJdvOtEXz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/softbank-vision-fund-2-leads-100-million-series-c-in-digital-therapeutics-company-biofourmis/">SoftBank Vision Fund 2 leads $100 million Series C in digital therapeutics company Biofourmis</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SoftBank Vision Fund 2 leads $100 million Series C in digital therapeutics company Biofourmis&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/02/softbank-vision-fund-2-leads-100-million-series-c-in-digital-therapeutics-company-biofourmis/embed/#?secret=OIJdvOtEXz" data-secret="OIJdvOtEXz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BrnMDt9asv"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/">Venture investing in elder tech</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture investing in elder tech&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/03/venture-investing-in-eldertech/embed/#?secret=BrnMDt9asv" data-secret="BrnMDt9asv" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/digital-therapeutics-startup-neuroglee-raises-10m-to-help-people-with-neurodegenerative-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200003</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft confirms investment in India&#8217;s Oyo in a multi-year strategic deal to co-develop travel and hospitality products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/microsoft-confirms-investment-in-indias-oyo-in-a-multi-year-strategic-deal-to-co-develop-travel-and-hospitality-products/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/microsoft-confirms-investment-in-indias-oyo-in-a-multi-year-strategic-deal-to-co-develop-travel-and-hospitality-products/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 08:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oyo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft has entered a “multi-year strategic alliance” with Oyo to work with the Indian startup to co-develop &#8220;next-generation&#8221; travel and hospitality products and tech. Thursday’s announcement confirms a late July TechCrunch report. TechCrunch had reported that Microsoft was in talks to invest in Oyo and was exploring ways to provide its technologies to the Indian [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Microsoft has entered a “multi-year strategic alliance” with Oyo to work with the Indian startup to co-develop &#8220;next-generation&#8221; travel and hospitality products and tech.</p>
<p>Thursday’s announcement confirms <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/microsoft-in-talks-to-back-india-oyo/">a late July TechCrunch report</a>. TechCrunch had reported that Microsoft was in talks to invest in Oyo and was exploring ways to provide its technologies to the Indian startup, which is one of the most valuable in the South Asian market.</p>
<p>In a press statement, Microsoft confirmed that it has also made a strategic equity investment in Oyo, but didn’t disclose the amount. A regulatory filing showed last month that the Windows-maker had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/microsoft-backs-indias-oyo-at-9-6-billion-valuation/">invested $5 million in the Indian startup</a>. The investment valued Oyo at $9.6 billion.</p>
<p>Oyo will switch to Microsoft Azure for its cloud-based needs and co-develop solutions with the American giant to “benefit patrons who operate small and medium hotel and home storefronts,” the firms said. &#8220;As part of this alliance, OYO will develop Smart Room experiences for travelers on the OYO platform, such as premium and customized in-room experiences for its guests. Using Microsoft’s Azure IoT, the experience will include self-check-in supported by a digital register of arrivals and departures and self-Know Your Customer (KYC) along with IoT-managed smart locks and virtual assistance,&#8221; the firms said.</p>
<p>“Combining the power of Azure with the tech and product stack developed by OYO, we are looking forward to accelerating innovation in travel and hospitality,” said Anant Maheshwari, President of Microsoft India, in a statement. “It is inspiring to see how the Microsoft cloud is empowering digital natives like OYO to accelerate industry transformation and innovations, turning the challenges of a post-pandemic era into opportunities for the future.”</p>
<p>Oyo has emerged as one of the largest hotel chains in the world, with presence in India, Southeast Asia, Europe and the U.S. But <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/02/technology/oyo-softbank-india.html">some of its missteps</a> in its pursuit of aggressive expansion — “toxic culture,” lapse in governance and relationship with many hotel owners — have scarred its growth.</p>
<p>Just as the startup was pledging to improve its relationship with hotel owners, the pandemic arrived. In response, Oyo slowed its growth and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/04/softbank-backed-indian-startup-oyo-to-cut-5000-jobs-globally/">laid off thousands of employees globally</a> earlier this year as nations across the world enforced lockdowns.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The pandemic hit the seven-year-old startup like a “cyclone,” CEO Ritesh Agarwal told Bloomberg TV in July. “We built something for so many years and it took just 30 days for it drop by over 60%,” he said, adding that the firm had not made any decision on exploring the public markets.</p>
<p>Airbnb-backed Oyo had between $780 million to $800 million in its bank, Agarwal said at a virtual conference recently, and had pared its “monthly burn” across all businesses to $4 million to $5 million. (The startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/01/despite-everything-oyo-still-has-1-billion-in-cash/">had about $1 billion in the bank</a> in December 2020.)</p>
<p>In July — after Agarwal’s remarks at the aforementioned conference — Oyo said it had raised $660 million in debt. That debt was used to pay off the previous debt, according to a person familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>As for Microsoft, Oyo is the latest of several strategic investments it has made in the country. The firm has backed a handful of startups in the South Asian market, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/google-leads-145-million-investment-in-indias-glance/">news aggregator and short-video platform DailyHunt,</a> e-commerce giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/04/10/flipkart-1-4-billion/">Flipkart</a>, and logistics <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/21/indian-logistics-saas-startup-fareye-bags-13-million/">SaaS firm FarEye</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/microsoft-confirms-investment-in-indias-oyo-in-a-multi-year-strategic-deal-to-co-develop-travel-and-hospitality-products/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200000</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two UK tech figures plan to row the Atlantic for charity supporting minority entrepreneurs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/two-uk-tech-figures-plan-to-row-the-atlantic-for-charity-supporting-minority-entrepreneurs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/two-uk-tech-figures-plan-to-row-the-atlantic-for-charity-supporting-minority-entrepreneurs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 07:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two UK tech figures are to row across the Atlantic Ocean to raise money for a charity that funds social entrepreneurs from minority backgrounds. Guy Rigby, founder and now Chair of the Entrepreneurial Services Group at Smith &#38; Williamson, and entrepreneur, investor David Murray will raise money for UnLtd which has supported over 15,000 social [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Two UK tech figures are to row across the Atlantic Ocean to raise money for a charity that funds social entrepreneurs from minority backgrounds.</p>
<p>Guy Rigby, founder and now Chair of the Entrepreneurial Services Group at Smith &amp; Williamson, and entrepreneur, investor David Murray will raise money for <a href="https://www.unltd.org.uk/impact2020">UnLtd</a> which has supported over 15,000 social entrepreneurs in the UK.</p>
<p>The pair have so far secured around £350,000 for UnLtd, with support from the UK’s Tech Nation, Founders Forum, and London Tech Week. You can donate to their fund-raising efforts on the &#8216;<a href="https://theentrepreneurship.co.uk/">The Entrepreneur Ship&#8217; here.</a>, will also be part of the <a href="https://theentrepreneurship.co.uk/sponsorship/">Talisker Whisky Atlantic Challenge</a>. Other tech orgs are invited to sponsor their efforts.</p>
<p>UnLtd has previously backed startup firms including <a href="https://patchworkhub.org/">Patchwork Hub</a> which built an accessible employment platform run by disabled people, as well as <a href="https://www.edukit.org.uk/">EduKit</a>, which developed an app to help school staff understand and address the mental health needs of their students.</p>
<p>Over the last year, UnLtd supported 662 social entrepreneurs, 42% of whom identified as being from a Black, Asian, or minority ethnic background and/or having a disability.</p>
<p>Rigby and Murray will row the 3,000 miles in December 2021 from the Canaries to Antigua, which they hope to reach in February 2022, rowing individually, 2 hours on, 2 hours off, around the clock for the duration of the crossing.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/09/two-uk-tech-figures-plan-to-row-the-atlantic-for-charity-supporting-minority-entrepreneurs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199542</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s WeRide unveils Robovan, its first electric, autonomous cargo van</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/weride-jiangling-motors-and-zto-express-unveil-robovan-an-autonomous-cargo-van/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/weride-jiangling-motors-and-zto-express-unveil-robovan-an-autonomous-cargo-van/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 06:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese autonomous driving company WeRide has unveiled its first cargo van, the vessel upon which it will self-drive into the world of urban logistics. WeRide will work with Chinese automobile manufacturer Jiangling Motors (JMC) and Chinese express delivery company ZTO Express to commercialize its first self-driving van at scale. The deal was signed on Wednesday [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Chinese autonomous driving company WeRide has unveiled its first cargo van, the vessel upon which it will self-drive into the world of urban logistics. WeRide will work with Chinese automobile manufacturer Jiangling Motors (JMC) and Chinese express delivery company ZTO Express to commercialize its first self-driving van at scale.</p>
<p>The deal was signed on Wednesday by Tony Han, founder and CEO of WeRide, Wenhui Jin, executive vice president of JMC, and Renqun Jin, vice president of ZTO, during WeRide&#8217;s latest online press conference dubbed &#8220;The Next.&#8221; As part of the agreement, WeRide and JMC will jointly design purpose-built models of the Robovan for mass production on JMC&#8217;s assembly lines, and ZTO will put the Robovans to good use in their urban logistics service, according to a statement released by the company. A WeRide spokesperson told TechCrunch that the Robovans will be based on JMC&#8217;s battery electric vehicle model with a fully-redundant vehicle platform, combined with WeRide&#8217;s full-stack software and hardware autonomous driving (AD) solutions.</p>
<p>WeRide has been raking in cash over the past year on its route to commercialization, with ove<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/weride-310-million-series-c/">r $600 million</a> raised from Series B and C rounds in the span of five months and a current $3.3 billion valuation. In June, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/20/chinas-weride-makes-first-acquisition-an-autonomous-trucking-firm.html">the company acquired MoonX.AI</a>, a Guangzhou-based autonomous trucking company, although it hasn&#8217;t yet committed to developing a commercial product in that space yet. Either way, having <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/weride-310-million-series-c/">ride-hailing</a>, autonomous <a href="https://www.weride.ai/en/mini-robobus-en/">busing</a>, urban logistics and even just a hint of self-driving trucks in the pipeline means WeRide&#8217;s moves to diversify its autonomous portfolio are edging it ahead of the competition.</p>
<p>Chinese search engine Baidu&#8217;s self-driving unit mainly focuses on robotaxi and, as of <a href="https://www.barrons.com/articles/baidu-gets-green-light-for-commercial-self-driving-bus-service-in-china-51618390800">April this year</a>, buses. Alongside its robotaxis, Pony.AI has at least p<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-pony-ai/toyota-backed-pony-ai-to-offer-autonomous-delivery-service-in-california-idUSKBN21Y3GK">iloted last-mile logistics</a> and just recently got the <a href="https://autonews.gasgoo.com/icv/70018226.html">go-ahead to test its trucks out in China</a>, but so far no buses. Waymo Via knocks both <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/18/waymo-via-is-scaling-up-autonomous-trucking-operations-in-texas-arizona-california/">last-mile and trucking off the list</a>, and its autonomous taxis make for a very long feather in the company&#8217;s cap, but Waymo hasn&#8217;t yet released any news about self-driving buses. GM-backed Cruise seems to be sticking with small vehicles and all they can provide, which includes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/cruise-secures-5b-credit-line-to-buy-electric-autonomous-cruise-origin-vehicles-from-gm/">rideshare</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21557603/cruise-walmart-autonomous-vehicles-delivery-arizona">delivery</a>.</p>
<p>WeRide says its van already has Level 4 autonomous capabilities, which the <a href="https://www.sae.org/news/press-room/2018/12/sae-international-releases-updated-visual-chart-for-its-%E2%80%9Clevels-of-driving-automation%E2%80%9D-standard-for-self-driving-vehicles">Society of Automotive Engineers</a> defines as a car that takes the wheel and doesn&#8217;t require human interaction in most cases, although a human still has the option to manually override. Level 4 vehicles can only operate in limited areas, which is why they have most recently catered to ridesharing, but delivery vehicles could conceivably operate within a geofence, as well.</p>
<p>Because WeRide already has two years of experience testing out its Robotaxi service with the public, the company says it&#8217;s confident that the Robovan will be able to handle itself in a variety of different traffic scenarios, from innercity to tunnels to highways, across ZTO&#8217;s network, which covers over 99% of China&#8217;s cities and counties, according to ZTO.</p>
<p>A WeRide spokesperson said the Robovan has already been built and has been quietly tested in China for some time now. It&#8217;s still too early in the process to provide a detailed timeline on when WeRide and JMC will begin mass production, but the spokesperson said the next step for WeRide will be to pick one to three locations to conduct pilot testing to verify the vehicles and the system&#8217;s stability.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Right after that, we aim for being true driverless in a few areas and build up our know-how of operating Robovans in urban logistics application,&#8221; the spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Considering both Robovan and Robotaxi are operating in urban cities, Robovan shares similar regulatory support as Robotaxi. Regulation in China is progressing step by step to catch up with the development of self-driving technology. You will see the application of true driverless Robovan in three to five years.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/weride-jiangling-motors-and-zto-express-unveil-robovan-an-autonomous-cargo-van/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Printify bags $45M, led by Index, to ride the custom printing boom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/printify-bags-45m-led-by-index-as-it-rides-the-custom-printing-boom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/printify-bags-45m-led-by-index-as-it-rides-the-custom-printing-boom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 05:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merchant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[print on demand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[printful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Printify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TransferWise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virgin group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zazzle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2198603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The creator economy loves merch which is great news for on-demand custom printing startups such as Latvia-based Printify &#8212; today it&#8217;s announcing a $45 million Series A round, led by Index Ventures, off the back of rising demand for its services. The mission: To keep growing its global marketplace of print shops to meet rising [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The creator economy loves merch which is great news for on-demand custom printing startups such as Latvia-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/09/printify-raises-3m-to-expand-its-marketplace-for-custom-printing/">Printify</a> &#8212; today it&#8217;s announcing a $45 million Series A round, led by Index Ventures, off the back of rising demand for its services.</p>
<p>The mission: To keep growing its global marketplace of print shops to meet rising demand for custom wares, shipped.</p>
<p>Also participating in the funding round: H&amp;M Group, Virgin Group, plus the founders of Transferwise, Vinted, Squarespace, RedHat, and entertainment industry investors including Will Smith’s Dreamers VC and <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">at least one other person who Printify has asked us not to name for </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">unspecified legal reasons.</span></p>
<p>TechCrunch understands Printify’s post-money valuation is just over $300M.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Ecommerce and creator-focused platforms like Patreon and Shopify &#8212; which cater to micro-brand creating individual sellers (be they designers, content creators, ecommerce entrepreneurs or other highly online hustlers) &#8212; are helping to fire up demand for custom products like t-shirts, mugs, stickers etc, expanding the market for on-demand printing and shipping.</span></p>
<p>Printify says it&#8217;s now connecting some two million merchants with <span class="il">print</span> providers all over the world &#8212; and shipping a million units per month.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also grown to employ close to 500 people &#8212; doubling its headcount over the past year, now with a plan to add a further 200 positions by the end of the year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Our main audiences are creators, entrepreneurs; most of our merchants are people who want to build a side-business and earn money in addition to their main income, however, we also see a high growth of creators and entrepreneurs who use Printify as a service that helps building their core business,&#8221; the startup tells TechCrunch.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s one of a number of custom printing startups that have positioned themselves to step in to tackle the printing and shipping piece at scale, often building up businesses over several years from a far smaller base. (Others in the space include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/07/16/printful/">Printful</a>, <a href="https://www.gelato.com">Gelato</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2012/09/07/zazzle-instant-iphone/">Zazzle</a>.)</p>
<p>The 2015-founder Printify has slightly fewer years in the business than some of its rivals but it argues that&#8217;s allowed it to be more focused on serving the micro-brand building merchants who are now sparking such a boom in demand custom wares.</p>
<p>&#8220;Printify gives the ability for everyone to earn additional income,&#8221; it says when asked about the competitive mix &#8212; touting a focus on product selection, quality and price as its special sauce, in addition to its marketplace&#8217;s global footprint, meaning it can print and ship products to meet demand from merchants all over the world.</p>
<p>&#8220;Those are the key aspects our merchants are looking for,&#8221; it adds. &#8220;Printify provides the largest selection of on-demand printed products for creators and merchants to sell online. Furthermore, Printify provides lowest prices, while ensuring reliable high quality standards.&#8221;</p>
<p>The most popular products being sold by merchants using its marketplace are &#8220;the classics&#8221; &#8212; aka T-shirts, hoodies, stickers, mugs, posters and hats.</p>
<p>&#8220;We also see a fast-growing market for baby and children&#8217;s products, sportswear, pet products and drinkware,&#8221; it adds. &#8220;Most merchants choose Printify because of our wide selection and geographical flexibility &#8212; we have 370+ products in our catalog and adding several each week, printed in 100+ locations all over the world.&#8221;</p>
<p>Commenting on the Series A funding in a statement, Dino Becirovic, principal at Index Ventures, said: &#8220;Printify is the leading marketplace for on-demand manufacturing, offering the largest selection of products and print providers. They have removed all the barriers to product creation and enabled over 2 million creators to launch successful merchandise businesses at the push of a button. Over time, as more manufacturers come online and more methods become available, Printify will allow any creator to bring their wildest product ideas to reality.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>This report was updated to remove the name of an investor after Printify told us the person in question had requested not to be mentioned in the funding announcement &#8220;due to legal reasons&#8221;</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yheqHGOzeH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/09/printify-raises-3m-to-expand-its-marketplace-for-custom-printing/">Printify raises $3M to expand its marketplace for custom printing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Printify raises $3M to expand its marketplace for custom printing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/09/printify-raises-3m-to-expand-its-marketplace-for-custom-printing/embed/#?secret=yheqHGOzeH" data-secret="yheqHGOzeH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AjRMmc9XAY"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/facebook-creator-bonuses/">Facebook will lure creators with $1 billion in payments</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook will lure creators with $1 billion in payments&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/facebook-creator-bonuses/embed/#?secret=AjRMmc9XAY" data-secret="AjRMmc9XAY" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/printify-bags-45m-led-by-index-as-it-rides-the-custom-printing-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2198603</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The newest Roomba gets smarter as it vacuums</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-newest-roomba-gets-smarter-as-it-vacuums/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-newest-roomba-gets-smarter-as-it-vacuums/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 04:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iRobot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roomba]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Roomba is easily among the most ubiquitous robots in the world &#8212; but it has never been one of the smartest. On the whole, that’s not a major issue. The top-selling vacuum is good at what it does: cleaning floors. But a roboticist’s work is never done; iRobot has turned the vast majority of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Roomba is easily among the most ubiquitous robots in the world &#8212; but it has never been one of the smartest. On the whole, that’s not a major issue. The top-selling vacuum is good at what it does: cleaning floors. But a roboticist’s work is never done; iRobot has turned the vast majority of its attention and resources on the line for good reason, and the company has spent virtually every generation improving the robot’s ability to perform its very specific task.</p>
<p>This time out, that means using on-board sensors to remember areas of the home and layout, along with areas that need a little extra cleaning time.</p>
<p>“We’ve turned on continuous learning, so that if you’ve changed things in your home, Roomba will figure it out,” CEO Colin Angle tells TechCrunch. “If you open a door that you’ve never opened before, the Roomba will go explore it. If you moved a couch, it will understand that the home is a bit different than it used to be, and that’s okay. The information that we’re gathering grows in richness.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199714" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199714" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2199714" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_Dirt-Disposal-Bag.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199714" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> iRobot</p></div></p>
<p>The other big piece of that puzzle is identifying and avoiding specific objects. The company says it has worked on identifying hundreds of potential objects, but is starting with two specific problem areas: cords and poop. Both are big potential problem areas for a robotic vacuum system, albeit for dramatically different reasons. In either case, you don’t want to have to get down on your hands and knees and deal with the fallout.</p>
<p>In the case of the former, iRobot made an acronym &#8212; and a guarantee. With Pet Owner Official Promise (P.O.O.P.), the company says it will replace any j7+ that runs over animal dookie. (Fine print: Offer valid for 1 year from purchase and covers replacement product only. Available in limited jurisdictions, additional terms and conditions apply.)</p>
<p>“You can Google this and see some not so pleasant examples of robots running over poop,” says iRobot’s director of Product Management, Hooman Shahidi. “We’ve solved this problem with consumers. If we see animal poop, we avoid it and inform the consumers that we saw it.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2199711" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199711" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2199711" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Roomba-j7_j7_Object-Detection_Pet-Waste.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199711" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> iRobot</p></div></p>
<p>Angle adds, “The glorious career of roboticists may not have been fully realized when we were sending people home and creating hundreds of models of poo. Sending people around to photograph and create synthetic models of poo. I don’t know how many tens of thousands of images of all different shapes and sizes of synthetic images were required, but this is not demo code, clearly. We can’t do pee. It has to have some 3D aspects to it, but it is something we believe you can count on for the robot to identify and avoid.&#8221;</p>
<p>The third piece is scheduling, with the system adapting to a user’s activities. That could mean cleaning while you’re away (using your phone as a trigger for proximity) or making sure it avoids rooms you’re in. If the robot has to traverse the house, it will drive quietly and not start up until it actually begins its job. The system also now offers a clean-time estimate to let the user know how long the job will take.</p>
<p>The j7 is available now in the U.S. and Canada for $649. The j7+, which includes a more compact cleaning base, will run $849. They’re also available in Europe and will be rolling out to additional markets next year. Genius 3.0, meanwhile, will be available as an OTA update for the rest of the company’s connected robots.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-newest-roomba-gets-smarter-as-it-vacuums/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199708</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia&#8217;s Pat Grady says it isn&#8217;t clear startups &#8220;should be accelerating&#8221; right now &#8212; here&#8217;s why</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sequoias-pat-grady-a-fog-has-descended-and-it-isnt-clear-startups-should-be-accelerating-right-now/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sequoias-pat-grady-a-fog-has-descended-and-it-isnt-clear-startups-should-be-accelerating-right-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[late-stage venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pat Grady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier today, we joined friend and former colleague Jon Fortt of CNBC in interviewing partner Pat Grady of Sequoia Capital, and it proved a wide-ranging conversation. You can check out the video below, but we thought there were some highlights worth pulling out for some of you, including as it pertains to the current market, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier today, we joined friend and former colleague Jon Fortt of CNBC in interviewing partner Pat Grady of Sequoia Capital, and it proved a wide-ranging conversation. You can check out the video below, but we thought there were some highlights worth pulling out for some of you, including as it pertains to the current market, which has never felt frothier.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s more than anecdotal. According to a recent <a href="https://www.wsgr.com/a/web/26202/EntrepreneursReport-Q1-2020.pdf">Wilson Sonsini report</a>, during the first quarter of this year, the median pre-money valuation for Series C and later financings hit a record $675 million &#8212; more than double the full year 2020 median of $315 million. Meanwhile, senior liquidation preferences in so-called up rounds dropped from appearing in 35% of related deals in 2017 to 20% in the first quarter &#8212; a trend that suggests that investors are removing terms in order to win deals. In some cases, founders are feeling so empowered that they are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/bessemer-replaces-board-member-at-hinge-health-following-competitive-tensions/">calling out investor behavior</a> that makes them uncomfortable, which is something you didn&#8217;t see until more recently.</p>
<p>But Grady said not all is what it seems to those of us on the sidelines. Indeed, he said that while Sequoia&#8217;s advice to founders as recently as March of this year was to hit the gas, things have changed more recently. Specifically, he said, &#8220;In the last couple of months, a rollout of the vaccines has kind of kind of tapered, so I would say that fog has descended onto the road [and] it&#8217;s not so clear the company should be accelerating anymore.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>On how COVID has impacted Sequoia&#8217;s outlook compared with the financial crisis of 2008, when Sequoia famously published its now-famous &#8220;<a href="https://www.sequoiacap.com/article/rip-good-times">RIP: Good Times</a>&#8221; memo:</strong></p>
<p>PG: If you go back to that RIP memo, I&#8217;d been at Sequoia for a year or so. It was the first major disruption that I had seen &#8212;  it was the first major disruption that a lot of our founders had seen. So the question we were getting was, &#8216;What does this mean for us?&#8217; It was the same sort of thing that happened in March of 2020 that caused us to put out the &#8216;<a href="https://medium.com/sequoia-capital/coronavirus-the-black-swan-of-2020-7c72bdeb9753">Black Swan</a>&#8216; memo [when] what we said was, &#8216;Hey, you need to brake when you&#8217;re going into the curve, so slow down [and] make sure you kind of have your bearings.&#8217;</p>
<p>In March of this year what we said was, &#8216;Okay, now that we&#8217;re coming out of the curve, go and accelerate.&#8217; Unfortunately, in the last couple of months, a rollout of the vaccines has kind of kind of tapered and so I would say that fog has descended onto the road [and] it&#8217;s not so clear the company should be accelerating anymore. We&#8217;re probably in the midst of more indecision now than we were a few months ago or even a year ago . . .we&#8217;re kind of stuck in the middle. And so what we&#8217;ve been telling companies today is focus on the basics.</p>
<p><strong>On the signals that suggest a slight slowdown to Sequoia, despite the current funding environment:</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We don&#8217;t pay that much attention to the fundraising numbers, but we do pay attention to employees and we do pay attention to customers, and if you look across not just our portfolio but also public companies in the market at large, attrition has spiked dramatically. There are a lot of people who said, &#8216;Hey, I hunkered down, I worked hard, I put in my time, but now that the world is starting to open up a little bit again, I&#8217;m going to take some time off. I&#8217;m going to travel on the see family. I&#8217;m going to find a new job. I&#8217;m going to start a company.&#8217; And so attrition numbers are actually spiking across the board.</p>
<p>If we look at the customer side of things &#8211;and this is not a number that you can get out of public companies because of the way they report [but it&#8217;s a number] you can see in private companies &#8212; a lot of companies added less revenue in the second quarter than they added in the first. So we actually have seen a little bit of a pullback on the customer side of things [and] that hasn&#8217;t necessarily shown up in the fundraising numbers.</p>
<p><strong>On whether that pullback is good, bad, or neutral for founders and investors:</strong></p>
<p>The good news is the whole reason startups exist is to solve important problems in the world, and never have we had a broader array of important problems to be solved than we do right now, because both consumer behavior and the way that businesses operate has changed so dramatically in the last 12 or 18 months. So if what I just said sounds like bad news, we actually think that on balance, it&#8217;s great news, because we see these jobs opening up in the world that founders are rushing to fill. I think that&#8217;s probably why the fundraising numbers are what they are, because everybody sees all those opportunities and they&#8217;re eager to jump in.</p>
<p><strong>On what happens when some of these many new opportunities invariably start to converge &#8212; given the current pace of startup funding &#8212;  and portfolio companies begin to collide, as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/09/sequoia-is-giving-away-21-million-to-a-payments-startup-it-funded-as-it-walks-away-from-deal/">happened to Sequoia</a> in March of last year:</strong></p>
<p>We have always had a policy that we do not invest in direct competitors. What defines a direct competitor? Two companies who are going after the same customers in the same market at the same moment in time. Now, if we have a company here in the U.S. going out to the US market, and our partners in India or China or Southeast Asia have a company in their market that does something similar for their market, that&#8217;s okay, and maybe someday, down the road, they all end up targeting the same sort of customers. But as long as they&#8217;re distinct markets at time zero and they don&#8217;t look like they&#8217;re converging, that&#8217;s okay.</p>
<p>When we&#8217;ve ended up in companies that had conflicts, either we&#8217;ve done the right thing as in the situation you referenced, or when two companies have kind of converged over time, we&#8217;ve set up information barriers and done our best to act in good faith.</p>
<p>There are two products in this market. There&#8217;s a product that is faster and cheaper money. And then there&#8217;s a product that is unfair advantage. The unfair advantage could be nothing more than that Sequoia doesn&#8217;t invest in a lot of companies. We don&#8217;t invest in a new company every day. We might partner with 15 to 20 new founders in any given year, and there&#8217;s some information value in the fact that Sequoia has gotten into business with a company. So if your unfair advantage is nothing more than the fact that Sequoia chose you, so to speak, that&#8217;s still a pretty good advantage when it comes to landing customers [and] landing employees. If your product is money, feel free to give it to competitive companies, because they&#8217;re going to get money from somewhere anyway.</p>
<p><em>[Editor&#8217;s note: We also talked about whether companies can forever stay distributed, Tiger Global, and why one of Sequoia&#8217;s biggest portfolio companies, the payments giant Stripe, isn&#8217;t a public company yet. You can find that in the video below.]</em></p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ssn1tMlTdEA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sequoias-pat-grady-a-fog-has-descended-and-it-isnt-clear-startups-should-be-accelerating-right-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199885</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab&#8217;s order backlog tops $141M as the company inks five-launch deal with Kinéis</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/rocket-labs-order-backlog-tops-141m-as-the-company-inks-five-launch-deal-with-kineis/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/rocket-labs-order-backlog-tops-141m-as-the-company-inks-five-launch-deal-with-kineis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 22:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neutron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter beck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satellites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was a busy first half of the year for U.S.-New Zealand company Rocket Lab, which posted earnings for the first six months of 2021 on Wednesday – the first such reporting since the company went public last month. Rocket Lab reported revenues for the six-month period of $29.5 million. Its order backlog also grew [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It was a busy first half of the year for U.S.-New Zealand company Rocket Lab, which posted earnings for the first six months of 2021 on Wednesday – the first such reporting since the company went public last month.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab reported revenues for the six-month period of $29.5 million. Its order backlog also grew to $141.4 million as of June 30, up 136% from $59.9 million compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>While the general trend seems to be positive, executives emphasized the continued impact of COVID-19 restrictions in New Zealand, the site of one of the company’s key launch facilities. CFO Adam Spice said the third quarter has already been impacted by the pandemic, after New Zealand introduced strict lockdown restrictions in response to an 855-person outbreak of the Delta variant. Those restrictions resulted in “no further launch activity planned” for the quarter, Spice said, and will likely result in a $10-15 million impact on revenues for the year.</p>
<p>Despite these setbacks, executives said they anticipated a yearly revenue of $50-54 million. GAAP operating expenses, meanwhile, hit $29.3 million for the six-month period, up from $11.9 million for the first half of last year. The majority of that increase was from R&amp;D spending, including the development of an automated flight termination system and the Neutron launch vehicle, Spice added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E9fMN78VUz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/peter-beck-on-rocket-labs-public-listing-debut-space-spacs-and-the-neutron-rocket/">Peter Beck on Rocket Lab&#8217;s public listing debut, space SPACs and the Neutron rocket</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Peter Beck on Rocket Lab&#8217;s public listing debut, space SPACs and the Neutron rocket&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/peter-beck-on-rocket-labs-public-listing-debut-space-spacs-and-the-neutron-rocket/embed/#?secret=E9fMN78VUz" data-secret="E9fMN78VUz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Rocket Lab, which started as a launch company, has significantly branched out since its founding in 2006. The company now fashions itself as an end-to-end space company, providing launch services, as well as the design, manufacturing and operation of spacecraft.</p>
<p>It is this latter business area that Rocket Lab has aggressively grown over the past eighteen months; some recent milestones include an agreement to develop three of Rocket Lab&#8217;s Photon spacecraft for space manufacturing company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/space-manufacturing-startup-varda-inks-deal-with-rocket-lab-for-three-spacecraft/">Varda Space Industries</a> and plans to send two <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/rocket-labs-mars-mission-gets-green-light-from-nasa/">Photons to Mars</a> on an upcoming space mission. The growth of its space systems division reflects these developments; for the six-month period, space systems made up a $5.4 million share of revenue, up from just $300,000 in the same quarter last year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rocket Lab also said it would start manufacturing satellite components at scale by the end of this year, starting with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/rocket-lab-boosts-its-space-systems-divison-in-quest-to-become-an-end-to-end-space-company/">reaction wheels</a>, a critical attitude and stability control system. Rocket Lab will be opening a new facility that will be capable of producing up to 2,000 reaction wheels annually, a massive increase in volumes compared to what’s ever been available to the space industry before.</p>
<p>“Satellite components typically have been produced in small numbers which has really limited the speed and scale of constellation development,” CEO Peter Beck said during an investor call Wednesday. “The [reaction wheel production] line has been built to solve that, enabling production at scale to meet the growing needs of customers in the industry at large.”</p>
<p>Rocket Lab’s space systems division was given a huge boost by the acquisition of major satellite hardware manufacturer Sinclair Interplanetary last year, and it likely won’t be the company’s last purchase. Rocket Lab has around a half dozen deals it’s actively investigating, Spice told investors Wednesday. “The Sinclair acquisition has really emboldened us to lean forward and look at opportunities.”</p>
<p>“What&#8217;s interesting about this market right now is it does really feel like it&#8217;s ripe for consolidation,” he said. “Not consolidation in the sense of large companies necessarily getting together but the fact [that] the invest-ability of space is a relatively new phenomenon,” he said.</p>
<p>Company executives stayed largely mum on the Neutron rocket, with Beck simply noting that it “continues to develop really well” and that the company will provide a more detailed development in the coming months.</p>
<p>“Neutron is a vehicle that is not an increment on Electron,” he said. “It is something that really sets a new standard within the space industry.”</p>
<p>Rocket Lab also announced today that it has inked a multi-launch contract with Kinéis, a French connectivity provider for Internet of Things devices, to deploy its satellite constellation across five Electron missions. Kinéis’ investors include the French space agency Centre National d’Études Spatiales and French space company Collecte Localisation Satellites.</p>
<p>The constellation will consist of 25 satellites in total, adding to the over 100 satellites Rocket Lab has launched on its Electron rocket to date. The launches are scheduled for the second quarter 2023.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Five Electron launches, 25 satellites, 1 entire constellation: we’ve signed a deal with <a href="https://twitter.com/KineisIoT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KineisIoT</a> to deliver their internet-of-things constellation to space on Electron. <a href="https://t.co/8UtjGQS0gm">pic.twitter.com/8UtjGQS0gm</a></p>
<p>— Rocket Lab (@RocketLab) <a href="https://twitter.com/RocketLab/status/1435697181785149441?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>This is just the latest multi-launch deal Rocket Lab has inked in recent months, including a contract with satellite analytics company BlackSky for five launches.</p>
<p>Rocket Lab has continued to rise, closing Wednesday at $15.09. That represents a nearly 50% increase since the company’s public debut at the end of August.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/rocket-labs-order-backlog-tops-141m-as-the-company-inks-five-launch-deal-with-kineis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199816</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 4 things needed to reach Biden&#8217;s ambitious 2050 solar goal</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-4-things-needed-to-reach-bidens-ambitious-2050-solar-goal/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-4-things-needed-to-reach-bidens-ambitious-2050-solar-goal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 22:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar energy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A report on the future of solar energy from the Department of Energy paints a sunny picture, if you will, of the next three decades, at the end of which nearly half the country&#8217;s energy will be provided by the sun. But for that to happen, big pushes need to happen along four major lines: [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-releases-solar-futures-study-providing-blueprint-zero-carbon-grid">A report on the future of solar energy from the Department of Energy</a> paints a sunny picture, if you will, of the next three decades, at the end of which nearly half the country&#8217;s energy will be provided by the sun. But for that to happen, big pushes need to happen along four major lines: better photovoltaics, more energy storage, lower soft costs, and putting about a million people to work.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what the report says needs to happen in each of these sectors in order to meet the ambitious goals it sets out.</p>
<h3>Better photovoltaics</h3>
<p>The solar cells themselves will need to continue to improve in both cost and efficiency in order to achieve the kind of installation volumes hoped for by the DOE. For reference, 2020 saw 15 gigawatts worth of solar installed, the most ever — but we&#8217;re going to need to double that installation rate by 2025, then double it again by 2030.</p>
<p>If photovoltaics don&#8217;t improve in efficiency, that means these already ambitious numbers need to go even higher to account for that. And if they stay at today&#8217;s prices, the costs will be too high to achieve those volumes as well.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199837" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199837" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2199837 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png" alt="" width="1024" height="555" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png 1429w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=300,163 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=768,417 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=680,369 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/PV-efficiencies.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2199837" class="wp-caption-text">Photovoltaics have come a long way, but they also have a long way to go.</p></div></p>
<p>Fortunately efficiency is going up and cost is going down already. But it&#8217;s not like that just happens naturally. Companies and researchers across the globe have spent millions on new manufacturing processes, new materials, and other improvements, incremental individually but which add up over time. This basic research and advancement of the science and methods around solar <em>must</em> continue at or beyond the pace that they have over the last two decades.</p>
<p>The DOE suggests that research along the lines of making more exotic PVs cheaper, or stacking cells to minimize bandgap-related losses could be crucial. Flexible and tile- or shingle-like substrates or semi-transparent installations that pass light through to crops or building interiors may also figure. Altogether the plan calls for a reduction of the overall cost to drop by almost half from $1.30/watt today on average to $0.70 by 2030 and more after that.</p>
<p>Solar concentrators get their own heading in the report, and many companies are looking into these to replace industrial processes. These will not likely be used to support the grid at large but will nevertheless replace many fossil fuel based processes.</p>
<h3>More energy storage</h3>
<p>An unavoidable consequence of getting your energy from the sun is that at night you must rely on stored energy in some form or another, originally nuclear or coal but increasingly a form of storage that collects excess power collected during the daytime. With more of peak usage being covered by renewables, cities can safely transition away from carbon-based energy sources.</p>
<p>While we often think of energy storage in terms of batteries, and certainly they will be present, but the amount of energy that must be stored rules out something like lithium-ion batteries as the primary storage mechanism. Instead, the excess energy can be put towards powering energy-hungry renewable fuel production, like hydrogen fuel cells. This fuel can then be used to generate power when solar can&#8217;t meet demand.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199844" style="width: 891px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199844" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2199844" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png" alt="" width="881" height="503" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png 881w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=300,171 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=768,438 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=680,388 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/load-chart.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 881px) 100vw, 881px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2199844" class="wp-caption-text">The diagram shows how demand would normally go (purple) then how it would go with solar (orange) and how energy storage could mitigate that load (solid colors).</p></div></p>
<p>That&#8217;s just the &#8220;off the top of the head&#8221; answer. As the report states: &#8220;Thermal, chemical, and mechanical storage technologies are under various stages of development, including pumped thermal storage, liquid air energy storage, novel gravity-based technologies, and geological hydrogen storage.&#8221;</p>
<p>No doubt there will be a variety of new and old technologies working to provide the various levels of energy redundancy and storage duration needs of the country. These will go a long way towards making solar and other renewable energy sources capable of being relied on for a greater proportion of demand.</p>
<h3>Lower soft costs</h3>
<p>If we&#8217;re going to double and redouble the rate of solar cell deployment, the costs have to come down not just for the cells themselves, but the whole end-to-end process: assessment, accounting, labor, and of course the profit due to the companies that will be doing the actual work.</p>
<p>Lowering non-hardware costs is already the goal of many startups, like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/">Aurora Solar</a>, which clearly saw the writing on the wall and started making it as easy as possible to plan, visualize, and sell solar installations entirely online.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="N4DQbUzFzr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/">Aurora Solar aims to power the growing solar industry with a $250M round C</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Aurora Solar aims to power the growing solar industry with a $250M round C&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/24/aurora-solar-aims-to-power-the-growing-solar-industry-with-a-250m-round-c/embed/#?secret=N4DQbUzFzr" data-secret="N4DQbUzFzr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Right now the all-in cost of a solar roof might be twice the cost of the hardware or more. There are several contributors to this, from financing to regulations to markets, and each has its own intricacies beyond the scope of this article. Suffice it to say that if you can shave one percent off the cost of a solar installation by streamlining the time or cost involved in any of these areas, there will be more than enough volume to turn that one point into a major sum. It will take the combined efforts of many organizational and commercial minds to make this happen, just as it takes the efforts of many scientific ones to improve PVs.</p>
<h3>A million jobs</h3>
<p>Last but certainly not least, someone has to <em>actually do</em> all this work. That means a whole lot of labor — several times the quarter million people currently estimated to be attached to the solar industry in the country today.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_1954598" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1954598" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-1954598" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg" alt="Workers install solar panels on the roofs of homes under construction in California." width="1024" height="694" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg 5000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=150,102 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=768,520 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=680,461 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=1536,1041 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=2048,1388 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/GettyImages-957099668.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1954598" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;photographer=MediaNews+GroupInland+Valley+Daily+Bulletin+via+Getty+Images" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Will Lester/Inland Valley Daily Bulletin <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Jobs in this sector will run the gamut, from skilled workers with construction experience to energy professionals who&#8217;ve managed grids to public-private partnership wizards who connect commerce to the government&#8217;s inevitable top-down incentives. The additional half a million to a million jobs will almost certainly comprise many brand new companies and sub-industries, but the general breakdown so far has been about 65 percent installation and project development, 25 percent sales and manufacturing, and the rest in miscellaneous roles.</p>
<p>It is worth noting, however, that energy concerns currently clinging with white knuckles to aging oil and coal infrastructure will need to do right by the tens of thousands they still employ, and the renewable energy sector is a perfect transition space. &#8220;Throughout the transition, certain fossil fuel companies may come under increasing financial distress,&#8221; the report reads, which is something of an understatement. The authors strongly suggest funding transition programs that cover training, relocation, and guarantees of existing financial benefits like pensions.</p>
<p>The report points out that the solar industry is overwhelmingly white and male, like a few others we could name, so it is probably worth putting in work on that front if the million hires are to be at all equitable.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/solar/solar-futures-study">You can browse the full study here.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/the-4-things-needed-to-reach-bidens-ambitious-2050-solar-goal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199772</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Google rolls out new Workspace features for all users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/daily-crunch-59/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/daily-crunch-59/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greg Kumparak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 22:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hi friends!</p>
<p>Welcome to the Daily Crunch for Wednesday, September 8, 2021. <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> is still out, so I&#8217;ll be steering this ship for a few more days while (I hope) he stares at trees, or the ocean, or really anything but words on a computer screen. Alex, if you&#8217;re reading this, please put your phone in airplane mode and do something cool. &#8212; <a href="https://twitter.com/grg">Greg</a></p>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/wright-tests-its-2-megawatt-electric-engines-for-passenger-planes/">Wright tests its electric engine for passenger planes:</a></strong> Electric planes face challenges that electric cars don&#8217;t, like … you know, needing to get off the ground. Current battery tech is just too heavy for existing engines to get up in the air efficiently. Devin Coldewey has a profile on Wright, a startup looking to tackle this by making an electric engine that produces more thrust from less energy. They&#8217;re currently testing it at sea level, with plans to get it up to flying heights sometime next year.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/howard-university-cancels-classes-after-ransomware-attack/">Howard University cancels classes after ransomware attack:</a></strong> &#8220;Sorry class, lessons are canceled for the day because we got hacked.&#8221; It&#8217;s the oh-so-2021 version of a snow day. Snow Crash Day?</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/sec-wants-to-regulate-coinbases-crypto-yield-product-coinbase-disagrees/">SEC threatens to sue Coinbase:</a></strong> Looks like there&#8217;s a bit of a battle potentially brewing between Coinbase and the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. Coinbase wants to launch a service that would let users loan out crypto assets to a lending pool and gain interest (noting that others already have launched similar services). Coinbase gave the SEC a heads-up … which, according to Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong, led to the SEC threatening to sue Coinbase if it moved forward.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/indian-fintech-slice-launches-27-credit-limit-cards-to-tap-200-million-users/">The credit card with a $27 limit:</a></strong> &#8220;The relatively young credit-rating system in India covers only a tiny fraction of the nation’s population,&#8221; writes Manish Singh. As a result, an equally tiny fraction of the population has access to credit cards. Slice, a startup out of Bangalore, is looking to help young people in the region start to slowly build their credit by introducing a card with a cap of 2,000 Indian rupees — or about $27.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/tiktok-and-snap-alums-launch-mayk-it-a-social-music-creation-app-with-4m-in-seed-funding/"><strong>A social network for making music:</strong></a> TikTok remixed the concept of the remix, allowing users to take another user&#8217;s video and remold it into their own thing. Mayk.it, a new social app founded by TikTok/Snap alums, wants to bring the focus back to music. One user makes a beat, others add vocals and everyone crosses their fingers for a hit. The app launched this week, simultaneously announcing it had raised $4 million in seed funding.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/paypal-acquires-japans-paidy-for-2-7b-to-crack-the-buy-now-pay-later-market-in-asia/">PayPal buys Paidy:</a></strong> $2.7 billion! That&#8217;s how much PayPal is dropping on Paidy, a popular buy now, pay later service from Japan. Kate Park writes that this move should help PayPal dive right into deferred payments in the country — which, as she points out, is the third largest e-commerce market in the world.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Debt versus equity: When do non-traditional funding strategies make sense?</h2>
<p>Many potential founders are well versed in startup economics — and many are completely green.</p>
<p>When it comes to raising funds, understanding the relative benefits (and limitations) of debt and equity financing is required knowledge, however.</p>
<p>Founders who are less willing to dilute their control may be willing to use debt financing to fund their capital expenditures, &#8220;but it doesn&#8217;t make sense for everyone,&#8221; says six-time entrepreneur David Friend.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QASQt316We"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/debt-versus-equity-when-do-non-traditional-funding-strategies-make-sense/">Debt versus equity: When do non-traditional funding strategies make sense?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Debt versus equity: When do non-traditional funding strategies make sense?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/debt-versus-equity-when-do-non-traditional-funding-strategies-make-sense/embed/#?secret=QASQt316We" data-secret="QASQt316We" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/microsoft-launches-a-personalized-news-service-microsoft-start/">Microsoft launches a personalized news service:</a></strong> Microsoft is taking a swing at the Apple News/Flipboard concept with Microsoft Start, a site/app that aggregates content from your favorite news sources. You can thumbs up/down things to tune the algorithm over time, because what the world needs is more robots telling us what to read. I miss Google Reader.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/google-workspace-opens-up-spaces-for-all-users/"><strong>Google opens Spaces for all:</strong></a> Last year Google rebranded its built-for-work toolset from G Suite to Google Workspace. Around the same time, it started testing new features that makes the myriad Workspace tools (Gmail, Docs, Meet, etc.) work more cohesively, retuning them with the sudden work-from-home spike in mind. As of today, those features are rolling out to everyone.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/twitter-full-width-image-tweets-test/">Twitter is testing big ol&#8217; full-width photos and videos:</a></strong> &#8220;While the result looks like a win to us, any change to Twitter’s design is likely to inspire a vocal subset of users to hate-tweet about it for a day or so before forgetting the changes altogether,&#8221; Taylor Hatmaker so perfectly sums up.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers. We’ve received great recommendations for growth marketers in the startup industry since we launched our survey.</p>
<p>We’re excited to read more responses as they come in! <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Our editorial coverage about growth marketing includes articles from the TechCrunch team, guest columns, and posts like “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/use-cohort-analysis-to-drive-smarter-startup-growth/">Use cohort analysis to drive smarter startup growth</a>” by <a href="https://twitter.com/metrickmind">Jonathan Metrick</a> on Extra Crunch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dZSc1bA1Cu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/use-cohort-analysis-to-drive-smarter-startup-growth/">Use cohort analysis to drive smarter startup growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Use cohort analysis to drive smarter startup growth&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/use-cohort-analysis-to-drive-smarter-startup-growth/embed/#?secret=dZSc1bA1Cu" data-secret="dZSc1bA1Cu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/daily-crunch-59/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199693</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tape It launches an AI-powered music recording app for iPhone</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/tape-it-launches-an-a-i-powered-music-recording-app-for-iphone/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/tape-it-launches-an-a-i-powered-music-recording-app-for-iphone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a.i.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accenture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sonalytic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soundcloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soundtrap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stockholm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tape It]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Apple officially discontinued Music Memos, an iPhone app that allowed musicians to quickly record audio and develop new song ideas. Now, a new startup called Tape It is stepping in to fill the void with an app that improves audio recordings by offering a variety of features, including higher-quality sound, automatic instrument [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, Apple <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/03/02/apple-music-memos-voice-memos-integration/">officially discontinued</a> Music Memos, an iPhone app that allowed musicians to quickly record audio and develop new song ideas. Now, a new startup called <a href="https://tape.it/">Tape It</a> is stepping in to fill the void with an app that improves audio recordings by offering a variety of features, including higher-quality sound, automatic instrument detection, support for markers, notes and images, and more.</p>
<p>The idea for Tape It comes from two friends and musicians, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tcwalther/">Thomas Walther</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jan-n-2559b2116/">Jan Nash</a>.</p>
<p>Walther had previously spent three and a half years at Spotify, following its 2017 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/07/spotify-acquires-audio-detection-startup-sonalytic/">acquisition of the audio detection startup Sonalytic</a>, which he had co-founded. Nash, meanwhile, is a classically trained opera singer, who also plays bass and is an engineer.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re joined by designer and musician <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christiancrusius/">Christian Crusius</a>, previously of the design consultancy Fjord, which was <a href="https://newsroom.accenture.com/industries/communications/accenture-completes-acquisition-of-fjord-expanding-digital-and-marketing-capabilities.htm">acquired</a> by Accenture.</p>
<p>The founders, who had played in a band together for many years, were inspired to build Tape It because it was something they wanted for themselves, Walther says. After ending his stint at Spotify working in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/17/spotify-acquires-online-music-studio-soundtrap/">their new Soundtrap division</a> (an online music startup Spotify also bought in 2017), he knew he wanted to work on a project that was more focused on the music-making side of things. But while Soundtrap worked for some, it wasn&#8217;t what either Walther or his friends had needed. Instead, they wanted a simple tool that would allow them to record their music with their phone &#8212; something that musicians often do today using Apple&#8217;s Voice Memos app and, briefly, Music Memos &#8212; until its demise.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199782" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199782" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2199782" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-3.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199782" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tape It</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Regardless of whether you&#8217;re an amateur or even like a touring professional&#8230;you will record your ideas with your phone, just because that&#8217;s what you have with you,&#8221; Walther explains. &#8220;It&#8217;s the exact same thing with cameras &#8212; the best camera is the one you have with you. And the best audio recording tool is the one you have with you.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>That is, when you want to record, the easiest thing to do is not to get out your laptop and connect a bunch of cables to it, then load up your studio software &#8212; it&#8217;s to hit the record button on your iPhone.</p>
<p>The Tape It app allows you to do just that, but adds other features that make it more competitive with its built-in competition, Voice Memos.</p>
<p>When you record using Tape It, the app leverages AI to automatically detect the instrument, then annotate the recording with a visual indication to make those recordings easier to find by looking for the colorful icon. Musicians can also add their own markers to the files right when they record them, then add notes and photos to remind themselves of other details. This can be useful when reviewing the recordings later on, Walther says.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199783" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199783" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2199783" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="510" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Photo-2.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199783" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tape It</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;If I have a nice guitar sound, I can just take a picture of the settings on my amplifier, and I have them. This is something musicians do all the time,&#8221; he notes. &#8220;It&#8217;s the easiest way to re-create that sound.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another novel, but simple, change in Tape It is it that breaks longer recordings into multiple lines, similar to a paragraph of text. The team calls this the &#8220;Time Paragraph,&#8221; and believes it will make listening to longer sessions easier than the default &#8212; which is typically a single, horizontally scrollable recording.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199785" style="width: 333px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199785" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2199785" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?w=323" alt="" width="323" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png 1580w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=71,150 71w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=142,300 142w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=768,1618 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=323,680 323w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=729,1536 729w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=972,2048 972w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Tape.png?resize=24,50 24w" sizes="(max-width: 323px) 100vw, 323px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199785" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Tape It</p></div></p>
<p>The app has also been designed so it&#8217;s easier to go back to the right part of recordings, thanks to its smart waveforms, in addition to the optional markers and photos. And you can mark recordings as favorites so you can quickly pull up a list of your best ideas and sounds. The app offers full media center integration as well, so you can play back your music whenever you have time.</p>
<p>However, the standout feature is Tape It&#8217;s support for &#8220;Stereo HD&#8221; quality. Here, the app takes advantage of the two microphones on devices like the iPhone XS, XR, and other newer models, then improves the sound using AI technology and other noise reduction techniques, which it&#8217;s developed in-house. This feature is part of its $20 per year premium subscription.</p>
<p>Over time, Tape It intends to broaden its use of AI and other IP to improve the sound quality further. It also plans to introduce collaborative features and support for importing and exporting recordings into professional studio software. This could eventually place Tape It into the same market that SoundCloud had initially chased before it shifted its focus to becoming more of a consumer-facing service.</p>
<p>But first, Tape It wants to nail the single-user workflow before adding on more sharing features.</p>
<p>&#8220;We decided that it&#8217;s so important to make sure it&#8217;s useful, even just for you. The stuff that you can collaborate on &#8212; if you don&#8217;t like using it yourself, you&#8217;re not going to use it,&#8221; Walther says.</p>
<p>Tape It&#8217;s team of three is based in Stockholm and Berlin and is currently bootstrapping.</p>
<p>The app itself is a free download on <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/tape-it-songwriting/id1576341885">iOS</a> and will later support desktop users on Mac and Windows. An Android version is not planned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/tape-it-launches-an-a-i-powered-music-recording-app-for-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI-driven voice assistant PolyAI raises $14M round led by Khosla Ventures</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/ai-driven-voice-assistant-polyai-raises-14m-round-led-by-khosla-ventures/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/ai-driven-voice-assistant-polyai-raises-14m-round-led-by-khosla-ventures/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cambridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instant Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interactions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passion Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Point72 Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PolyAI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Replicant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sands Capital Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starling bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of cambridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[user interfaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viasat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vinod Khosla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice assistant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199776</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Conversational AI” startup PolyAI, based out of London, has raised $14 million in a funding round led by Silicon Valley&#8217;s Khosla Ventures, with participation from existing investors (Point72 Ventures, Amadeus Capital, Sands Capital Ventures, Passion Capital and Entrepreneur First). This follows their $12 million Series A, and will provide resources for further U.S. expansion beyond [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">“Conversational AI” startup <a href="https://poly-ai.com/">PolyAI</a>, based out of London, has raised $14 million in a funding round led by Silicon Valley&#8217;s Khosla Ventures, with participation from existing investors (Point72 Ventures, Amadeus Capital, Sands Capital Ventures, Passion Capital and Entrepreneur First). This <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/08/polyai/">follows</a> their $12 million Series A, and will provide resources for further U.S. expansion beyond its existing U.S. team. The startup has now raised $28 million to date.</p>
<p>PolyAI builds and deploys voice assistants for automating customer services, which, claims the startup, sound like real humans. This helps companies get an infinite and cheaper supply of their best human voice operators, which reduces customer waiting times, and increases customer satisfaction and retention, says the company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EVQBuQ8Vyf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/31/how-artificial-intelligence-will-be-used-in-2021/">How artificial intelligence will be used in 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How artificial intelligence will be used in 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/31/how-artificial-intelligence-will-be-used-in-2021/embed/#?secret=EVQBuQ8Vyf" data-secret="EVQBuQ8Vyf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Co-founder Dr Nikola Mrkšić said: “The technical term for our technology is ‘multi-turn conversational AI’, but all the caller has to do is talk to it, like they would to a human. Compared to existing call centers, our assistants can boost customer satisfaction (CSAT) scores by up to 40% and reduce handling times by up to five minutes.”</p>
<p>“We build these systems very quickly (relative to the competition) — we get experiences like these up and running in 2-4 weeks thanks to our transformer-based language understanding models and the underlying dialog management platform,” he added.</p>
<p>In a statement, Vinod Khosla said: “PolyAI is one of the first AI companies using the newest generation of large pre-trained deep learning models (akin to BERT and GPT-3) in a real-world enterprise product. This means they can deploy automated AI agents in as little as two weeks, where incumbent providers of voice assistants would take up to six months to deploy an older version of this technology.”</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tZTO_-nWRHM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>A spinout from the University of Cambridge, PolyAI says it is effectively &#8220;pushing at an open door&#8221; as the pandemic has led to staffing shortages in call centers, driving more companies to deploy smart voice assistants, which appear not to have been replaced chatbots at all, as consumers generally prefer to speak than type.</p>
<p>“We were expecting the system to handle 40% of calls, but at launch it handled 80%, and within two weeks it was up to 87%,” said Brian Jeppesen of Landry’s Golden Nugget Hotels &amp; Casinos. “Callers think the AI agent is human”, Jeppesen continued, “which is great because the voice assistant never has a bad day, and is on 24/7. I wish I could hire more agents like that!”</p>
<p>Competitors include Nuance (recently acquired by Microsoft), Isoft, Interactions, SmartAction and Replicant. But PolyAI says its voice assistant can be turned live more quickly, in more languages, and charges on a per-minute basis.</p>
<p>Founded by Nikola Mrkšić (CEO), Tsung-Hsien Wen (CTO) and Pei-Hao Su (Engineering Director), the three met while doing PhDs with Professor Steve Young, a leader in spoken dialog systems who pioneered many technologies that underpin voice assistants like Siri, Google Assistant and Alexa.</p>
<p>Recent PolyAI clients include Landry’s Entertainment, Greene King, Starling Bank and Viasat.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/ai-driven-voice-assistant-polyai-raises-14m-round-led-by-khosla-ventures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199776</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reid Hoffman&#8217;s latest book gives us 10 ways to rethink entrepreneurship</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/reid-hoffmans-masters-of-scale-book/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/reid-hoffmans-masters-of-scale-book/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 21:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reid Hoffman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you’re in the mood for a pep talk, who better to turn to than a well-networked, optimistic mentor who is naturally in your corner? That friendly shoulder is the role that &#8220;Masters of Scale&#8221; wants to play. Inspired by LinkedIn co-founder and Greylock partner Reid Hoffman’s hit podcast, the new book, co-authored by Hoffman [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When you’re in the mood for a pep talk, who better to turn to than a well-networked, optimistic mentor who is naturally in your corner? That friendly shoulder is the role that &#8220;Masters of Scale&#8221; wants to play.</p>
<p>Inspired by LinkedIn co-founder and Greylock partner Reid Hoffman’s hit podcast, the new book, co-authored by Hoffman along with podcast executive producers June Cohen and Deron Triff, came out this week. Riddled with anecdotes and actionable takeaways, the book’s strength is wholly related to the sheer diversity of entrepreneurs that are represented in the text. Beyond sticking to tech leaders, the book draws lessons from Spanx founder Sara Blakely, Starbucks founder Howard Schultz and Union Square Hospitality Group CEO Daniel Meyer. Like any good mentor, the book is realistic. Mentors know you aren’t Bumble’s Whitney Wolfe Herd or Airbnb’s Brian Chesky yet, but can extract universally applicable lessons from those leaders so that you can relate to them.</p>
<p>While press wasn’t a main character in the book, &#8220;Master of Scale&#8221; has already changed my perspective on how I interview founders. Lessons from Tristan Walker made me want to ask more questions about founders, and their most controversial beliefs, rather than how they plan to spend their new round of funding. A note from Andrés Ruzo made me realize that a startup that makes too much sense might be a comfortable read, but it might not be a moonshot that disrupts the world; in other words, pursue the startups that have too much seemingly foolish ambition &#8212; because they may be where the best strides, and stories, are made. Finally, it confirmed my belief that the best litmus test for a founder is if they are willing to talk about the hardships ahead of them in an honest, humble way.</p>
<p>Through every feel-good story, I waited for the pandemic to be addressed. The pandemic’s impact on startup advice was largely isolated to a single chapter about the art of the pivot. Instead of interspersing advice on how to deal with the pandemic’s impact on venture capital, funding and markets more broadly, the book limited its references to the cataclysmic event. This choice keeps the advice smartly evergreen. That said, I felt like the book’s choice to not talk much about the ugly within startupland creates an imbalance of sorts. It would have benefitted from talking directly about divisive dynamics, ranging from how WeWork’s Adam Neumann impacted the way we talk about visionary founders, Brian Armstrong’s Coinbase memo and what it means for startup culture, or even the role of the tech press today. One could argue that the book never claims to be journalistic, and instead wanted to play the role of a cheerleading mentor, not a cynical one.</p>
<p>Writing a book based on a hit podcast isn’t necessarily a walk in the park. Audio is an entirely different medium from written text, and it takes a certain finesse to translate into text the charisma and humility of vocal banter. Hoffman and the authors thus certainly shine brighter in some stories than others, leaning heavily on a repeated, yet effective storytelling arc throughout the text: introduce problem, present aha moment, offer solutions and share universal lessons.</p>
<p>I read the book over a weekend; I recommend the same move for any aspiring entrepreneur, techie or startup journalist looking to pick up a copy. Reid and the coauthors will do a fantastic job connecting the dots of over 70 entrepreneurs for you, but the real magic will come from what happens when you pause in between the stories &#8212; either to Google a founder you resonate with, to change up your interview style or to finally start working on the idea you one day may just blitzscale.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2199607" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png" alt="" width="1000" height="844" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=150,127 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=300,253 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=768,648 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=680,574 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MastersofScale_3D_bookshot_facing.png?resize=50,42 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/reid-hoffmans-masters-of-scale-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199605</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech is transforming the world&#8217;s oldest asset class: Farmland</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/fintech-is-transforming-the-worlds-oldest-asset-class-farmland/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/fintech-is-transforming-the-worlds-oldest-asset-class-farmland/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 19:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Food Climate and Sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food supply]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenhouse gas emissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2199480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While farmland is among the oldest investment classes around, the average investor hasn’t had access to farmland the way that billionaires and institutional investors have. That's changing.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Artem Milinchuk</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/artem_milinchuk">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Artem Milinchuk is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://farmtogether.com/">FarmTogether</a>, a fintech platform channeling funding into natural assets, starting with U.S. farmland.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Farmland as an asset class has proven itself to be a stable investment decade after decade. <a href="https://farmland.illinois.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Correlation-Farmland-Utility-Center-2021.xlsm">Farmland’s negative correlation</a> with the Dow Jones Industrial Average sits at an eye-popping -43% for a three-year hold period, making it an excellent hedge against market volatility.</p>
<p>The asset has also been a steady <a href="https://www.nass.usda.gov/Publications/Trends_in_U.S._Agriculture/Land_Values/index.php">appreciator since 1987</a>, when institutional investors began incorporating farmland into their portfolios. Equally, investments into sustainably managed farmland have the potential to transform agriculture from one of the largest sources of greenhouse gas emissions to one of the largest carbon sinks.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			While farmland investments can provide passive income and a hedge during just about any economic condition, direct investments into the asset have been largely inaccessible to date.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>However, while farmland is among the oldest investment classes around, the average investor hasn’t had access to farmland the way that billionaires and institutional investors have.</p>
<p>Revolutions in fintech and a host of startups are changing this.</p>
<h2>Why farmland?</h2>
<p>COVID-19 affected the world in ways we couldn’t have predicted, and the markets were no exception. The <a href="https://voxeu.org/article/stock-market-and-economy-insights-covid-19-crisis">S&amp;P 500 plummeted in mid-March</a> and shed 34% of its pre-COVID peak value. But unlike past crises, the index rebounded just a month later.</p>
<p>This doesn’t mean that financial markets have fully recovered, however. We’ve seen <a href="https://www.morganstanley.com/articles/how-to-handle-volatility">plenty of volatility</a> since, both in the form of rallies and losses. This has caused many investors to move some of their portfolio out of equities.</p>
<p>This is where farmland entered the discussion.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2199597" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2199597" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2199597" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?w=680" alt="Farmland price per acre compared to the S&amp;P &amp; DJIA EOY close price" width="2000" height="1081" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png 5418w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=768,415 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=680,367 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=1536,830 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=2048,1107 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/chart2.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2199597" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://farmtogether.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FarmTogether <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<h2>A historically stable asset class</h2>
<p>Wild stock market fluctuations existed well before COVID-19. The <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/goldilocks-keynes-and-fluctuations-in-the-stock-market">latest era of volatility</a> began in 2018 and continued even as the economy grew prior to the pandemic. Given the unpredictability of the equities market, investors need to counterbalance what’s in store for stocks and funds.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/08/fintech-is-transforming-the-worlds-oldest-asset-class-farmland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2199480</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
