<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 16:57:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>A Bluetooth bug in a popular at-home COVID-19 test could falsify results</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ellume-bug-covid-results/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ellume-bug-covid-results/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 16:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluetooth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[f-secure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wireless]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A security researcher found a Bluetooth vulnerability in a popular at-home COVID-19 test allowing him to modify its results. F-Secure researcher Ken Gannon identified the since-fixed flaw in the Ellume COVID-19 Home Test, a self-administered antigen test that individuals can use to check to see if they have been infected with the virus. Rather than [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A security researcher found a Bluetooth vulnerability in a popular at-home COVID-19 test allowing him to modify its results.</p>
<p>F-Secure researcher Ken Gannon identified the since-fixed flaw in the Ellume COVID-19 Home Test, a self-administered antigen test that individuals can use to check to see if they have been infected with the virus. Rather than submitting a sample to a testing facility, the sample is tested using a Bluetooth analyzer, which then reports the result to the user and health authorities via Ellume’s mobile app.</p>
<p>Gannon found, however, that the built-in Bluetooth analyzer could be tricked to allow a user to falsify a certifiable result before the Ellume app processes the data.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250293" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>To carry out the hack, Gannon used a rooted Android device to analyze the data the test was sending to the app. He then identified two types of Bluetooth traffic that were most likely in charge of telling the mobile app if the user was COVID positive or negative, before writing two scripts that were able to successfully change a negative result into a positive one.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2250314" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2250314" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2250314 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/test-picture-1.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="292" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/test-picture-1.jpg 600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/test-picture-1.jpg?resize=150,73 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/test-picture-1.jpg?resize=300,146 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/test-picture-1.jpg?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2250314" class="wp-caption-text">The faked results from the Ellume at-home COVID-19 test. (Image: F-Secure)</p></div></p>
<p>Gannon says that when he received an email with his results from Ellume, it incorrectly showed he had tested positive. To complete the proof-of-concept, F-Secure also successfully obtained a certified copy of the faked COVID-19 test results from Azova, a telehealth provider that Ellume partners with for certifying at-home COVID-19 tests for travel or going into work.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://labs.f-secure.com/blog/faking-a-positive-covid-test">Gannon’s writeup</a> only includes changing negative results to positive ones, he says that the process &#8220;works both ways.” He also said that, before it was patched, “someone with the proper motivation and technical skills could’ve used these flaws to ensure they, or someone they’re working with, gets a negative result every time they’re tested.” In theory, a fake certification could be submitted to meet U.S. re-entry requirements.</p>
<p>In response to F-Secure’s findings, Ellume says it has updated its system to detect and prevent the transmission of falsified results.</p>
<p>“We will also deliver a verification portal to allow authorities – including health departments, employers, schools, event organizers and others – to verify the authenticity of the Ellume COVID-19 Home Test,” said Alan Fox, Ellume&#8217;s head of Information Systems. “Ellume is confident in the reliability of our ECHT test result, and we would like to thank F-Secure for bringing this issue to our attention and for the work they do every day to protect consumers, businesses and organizations around the globe.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9IiH48QgZC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/docket-vaccine-records-covid-security/">A security bug in health app Docket exposed COVID-19 vaccine records</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A security bug in health app Docket exposed COVID-19 vaccine records&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/27/docket-vaccine-records-covid-security/embed/#?secret=9IiH48QgZC" data-secret="9IiH48QgZC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ellume-bug-covid-results/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250293</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patreon CPO says the company will double in size in 2022</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/patreon-cpo-interview-double-in-size-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/patreon-cpo-interview-double-in-size-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 16:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack conte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jason citron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musicians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patreon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tik tok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Creator monetization startups are cropping up left and right as the tech world embraces the fast-growing creator economy. But Patreon, founded in 2013, has been around since before words like &#8220;influencer&#8221; were in our vocabulary — back when &#8220;Tik Tok&#8221; was a Kesha song, rather than the social platform that everyone is trying to emulate. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Creator monetization startups are cropping up <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/02/playground-launches-in-beta-to-help-creators-cultivate-community/">left</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/29/cobalt-launches-from-beta-with-a-2-8m-seed-to-help-creators-launch-products/">and</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/18/fourthwall-raises-17m-for-its-all-in-one-creator-commerce-platform/">right</a> as the tech world embraces the <a href="https://signalfire.com/blog/creator-economy/#:~:text=More%20than%2050%20million%20people,%25)%20when%20they%20grow%20up.">fast-growing</a> creator economy. But Patreon, founded in 2013, has been around since before words like &#8220;influencer&#8221; were in our vocabulary — back when &#8220;Tik Tok&#8221; was a Kesha song, rather than the social platform that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/twitter-is-the-latest-platform-to-test-a-tiktok-copycat-feature/">everyone</a> is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/24/spotify-tests-a-tiktok-like-vertical-video-feed-in-its-app/">trying</a> to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/03/netflix-launches-fast-laughs-a-tiktok-like-feed-of-funny-videos/">emulate</a>.</p>
<p>After <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/patreon-triples-valuation-to-4-billion/">tripling its valuation</a> to $4 billion earlier this year, Patreon is at a crossroads. Will it continue to be the company to beat when it comes to building for creators? At the same time, can Patreon stay ahead of its competition while making creators feel that the product is looking out for their best interests?</p>
<p>&#8220;We are not going to be one of those companies that defined the first eight years, but not the next eight years [of the creator economy],&#8221; Patreon Chief Product Officer Julian Gutman told TechCrunch.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2249936" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Speaking with TechCrunch about the platform&#8217;s plans for 2022, Gutman said that Patreon hopes to stay ahead of the curve by aggressively hiring, especially in product and engineering. Gutman himself only <a href="https://blog.patreon.com/product-leader-at-instagram-joins-patreon">joined Patreon</a> in January, bouncing over from Instagram, where he was Head of Product for Instagram&#8217;s home feed experience. In August, Patreon also hired Senior VP of Engineering <a href="https://blog.patreon.com/patreon-welcomes-former-googler-utkarsh-srivastava-as-senior-vp-of-engineering">Utkarsh Srivastava</a>, who formerly led teams at Google and Twitter.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve hired 60 folks across product, engineering and design in the last quarter, and kind of expect that pace of hiring to continue into the next year,&#8221; Gutman said. &#8220;We have folks joining from Instagram, Uber and Square, and all these companies that I would say are like the first generation of the creator economy.&#8221;</p>
<p>Patreon isn&#8217;t a new company, but Gutman thinks that since its mission from the get-go has been to help creative people make money, it&#8217;s better prepared to lead in this supposed &#8220;second generation&#8221; than social media platforms like his former employer Instagram. Regardless, social platforms are <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/14/snap-paid-250-million-to-creators-on-its-tiktok-clone-this-year/">investing heavily</a> in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/instagram-bonuses-reels-tiktok/">direct-to-creator payments</a>. But Patreon&#8217;s model enables sustainable, monthly creator payouts, as opposed to one-time <a href="https://about.instagram.com/features/reels/reels-surprise?gk_enable=about_ig_reels_contest_launch_holdout">surprise bonuses</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JwirUE3hNz"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/patreon-business/">The business of Patreon</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The business of Patreon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/patreon-business/embed/#?secret=JwirUE3hNz" data-secret="JwirUE3hNz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Patreon has 400 employees now, but Gutman said the company hopes to end next year with closer to 1000 employees. Within product, engineering and design specifically, Patreon hopes to scale from 150 employees (including 60 recent hires) to 400 in 2022.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think it&#8217;s a reflection of what we want to build, and the pace and the quality at which we want to build it,&#8221; Gutman said. &#8220;We&#8217;re really excited for potential creators right now, and we want to just be giving them as many tools as possible as quickly as possible to help them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Patreon has already teased some of the <a href="https://next.patreon.com/">projects it&#8217;s working on</a> for 2022, including a native video platform (so exclusive video content can live on-platform, not in an unlisted YouTube link), an improved posting experience with more formatting options, different ways of organizing content on a Patreon page, more data and analytics, a cleaner app design, simpler playback experiences for multimedia and more. The platform is even planning to revamp its <a href="https://blog.patreon.com/thoughts-on-improving-patron-billing">billing system</a>, which Patreon says has been &#8220;a source of confusion and frustration&#8221; for many of its creators.</p>
<p>But another big question for Patreon is whether it will bring crypto technology to the platform. Earlier this fall, Gutman, along with founder and CEO Jack Conte, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/29/patreon-confirms-its-exploring-crypto-as-a-way-for-creators-to-make-money/">confirmed</a> that Patreon is exploring crypto as a way for creators to make money. Patreon floated the idea of crypto creator coins in its fall Creator Policy Engagement Program update, but at a subsequent livestream, creators expressed concerns about how Patreon dabbling in crypto could impact their relationships with their patrons.</p>
<p>The actions that Patreon takes as a company impact the livelihoods of the creators making a living on their platform. Some creators on that livestream worried that if Patreon launched creator coins, their crypto-averse patrons might unsubscribe, even if they themselves weren&#8217;t using those tools.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are some really interesting fundamental pieces of [crypto] technology that are actually quite aligned with our mission and what everyone&#8217;s wanted for the creator economy for a long time — rights ownership, independence, owning your content, owning your business, owning your audience, decentralization, all these themes,&#8221; Gutman told TechCrunch. &#8220;But I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re ready to jump on any particular application or bandwagon.&#8221;</p>
<p>Patreon does not have a dedicated team working on crypto, though there are some people in the company who are passionate about crypto and formed what Gutman called &#8220;an internal pod in their spare time.&#8221; He said that early next year, Patreon might consider building a small team of a few people dedicated to investigating how the company could possibly leverage crypto to support creators.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not, &#8216;hey, let&#8217;s go build an NFT platform right now,&#8217; but you know, a couple of folks that are focused on this full time,&#8221; Gutman said. &#8220;And by the way, they might conclude, &#8216;Hey, you know what, there&#8217;s nothing for us to build here right now,&#8217; which is a totally fine, reasonable conclusion.&#8221;</p>
<p>Patreon isn&#8217;t taking the question of whether or not to dip its toes into crypto lightly. The choice could divide its community and force creators to act as spokespeople for the company&#8217;s decisions, which can alienate individual creators&#8217; patrons.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aDocDdgI3g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/discord-nfts-crypto-jason-citron/">Discord pushes pause on exploring crypto and NFTs amidst user backlash</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Discord pushes pause on exploring crypto and NFTs amidst user backlash&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/discord-nfts-crypto-jason-citron/embed/#?secret=aDocDdgI3g" data-secret="aDocDdgI3g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Earlier this month, Kickstarter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/kickstarter-plans-to-move-its-crowdfunding-platform-to-the-blockchain/">announced</a> it would move its crowdfunding platform to the blockchain, sparking <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/18/web3-kickstarter-and-discord-face-backlash-over-moves-into-crypto.html">backlash</a> from users, especially those who have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/21/the-debate-about-cryptocurrency-and-energy-consumption/">environmental concerns</a> about some blockchain technology. Meanwhile, in November, Discord CEO Jason Citron <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/09/discord-nfts-metamask-crypto/">tweeted</a> an image of the crypto wallet MetaMask integrated into the chat platform&#8217;s interface. But even crypto-savvy users worried that linking crypto wallets with Discord accounts could make it easier to carry out fraud and scams on the platform. After some users urged each other to cancel their paid Discord Nitro subscriptions in protest of the company&#8217;s perceived movements toward crypto, Citron put out a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/10/discord-nfts-crypto-jason-citron/">statement</a> saying that Discord doesn&#8217;t have plans to pursue the technology at this time.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think one other important thing for us is over the next few years, we want to provide a toolset that creators can piece together differently,&#8221; Gutman said. &#8220;So we might have a crypto part of the toolset if we think there&#8217;s something there that creators might choose to use.&#8221;</p>
<p>But more immediately, Gutman emphasized that community will be a focus for Patreon in 2022.</p>
<p>&#8220;When people think creators, they think content. But so much of what creators do is community today,&#8221; Gutman said. &#8220;They really are these community leaders. They help communities come together around a shared topic of interest or a shared passion, and I think it&#8217;s a really undervalued part of what creators offer the world, particularly in this day and age.&#8221;</p>
<p>Right now, a popular perk for creators to offer their fans is access to private, patron-only Discord servers. Gutman said that Patreon wants to create on-platform products for building community in addition to its suite of integrations with platforms like Discord.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are creator-first, so if creators want to use an integration and they prefer an integration, we&#8217;re really excited by that,&#8221; Gutman said. &#8220;It&#8217;s not so much an on-platform versus off-platform type of battle, but we are really excited to look at building more first-party community tools, and one of the things we&#8217;re excited about is where content meets community.&#8221;</p>
<p>Changes at a company like Patreon can be anxiety-inducing for creators who rely on the platform for their livelihood. In the new year, Patreon plans to conduct a creator census to maintain a direct line of communication with the people who stand to be most affected by big shifts in the company&#8217;s product plans.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed--video">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EkvyRj1aNX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/kickstarter-plans-to-move-its-crowdfunding-platform-to-the-blockchain/">Kickstarter plans to move its crowdfunding platform to the blockchain</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Kickstarter plans to move its crowdfunding platform to the blockchain&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/08/kickstarter-plans-to-move-its-crowdfunding-platform-to-the-blockchain/embed/#?secret=EkvyRj1aNX" data-secret="EkvyRj1aNX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vpZEBNHaEL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/discord-premium-memberships/">Discord is working on premium memberships, a new monetization option for creators</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Discord is working on premium memberships, a new monetization option for creators&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/07/discord-premium-memberships/embed/#?secret=vpZEBNHaEL" data-secret="vpZEBNHaEL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p8aEUknurW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/pinterest-invests-in-creator-tools-with-acquisition-of-video-creation-and-editing-app-vochi/">Pinterest invests in creator tools with acquisition of video creation and editing app Vochi</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pinterest invests in creator tools with acquisition of video creation and editing app Vochi&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/06/pinterest-invests-in-creator-tools-with-acquisition-of-video-creation-and-editing-app-vochi/embed/#?secret=p8aEUknurW" data-secret="p8aEUknurW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/patreon-cpo-interview-double-in-size-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The eVTOL take-off: Four trends that shaped 2021</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/top-evtol-trends-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/top-evtol-trends-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eVTOL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flying cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joby Aviation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2244974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Billions of dollars, dozens of deals, and one legal battle: the year in eVTOL was an unforgettable one, with developers picking up the pace even as the larger aviation sector was busy slowly recovering from the fallout from the COVID-19 pandemic. Below, we catch up with leading analysts and investors to identify the top trends [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Billions of dollars, dozens of deals, and one legal battle: the year in eVTOL was an unforgettable one, with developers picking up the pace even as the larger aviation sector was busy slowly recovering from the fallout from the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p>Below, we catch up with leading analysts and investors to identify the top trends that shaped eVTOL this year &#8212; and will likely continue to reverberate in the years to come.</p>
<h2>Did someone say SPAC?</h2>
<p>Archer Aviation. Joby Aviation. Lilium. Vertical Aerospace. What do these companies have in common, besides the fact that they’re each developing eVTOL aircraft? They all announced or completed mergers with blank-check firms this year, in an absolutely mind-blowing injection of capital into this once nascent – even far-fetched – technology.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2244974" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>If 2021 should be remembered for anything in the world of eVTOL, it’s principally the massive amount of money that has gone into the sector. Three SPAC deals alone – that of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/joby-aviation-makes-its-public-trading-debut-on-the-nyse/">Joby</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/archer-lands-1-1b-order-from-united-airlines-and-a-spac-deal/">Archer</a>, and German developer Lilium – raised over $2.5 billion combined in gross proceeds, with Joby’s proceeds constituting nearly half that figure at $1.1 billion. eVTOL aircraft are not the only mobility technology to have flocked to SPACs as a financial vehicle to take them to public markets, but the sheer number of deals is certainly one of the stand-out trends of this year.</p>
<p>“What&#8217;s different with the eVTOL industry today and where they were, let&#8217;s say a year ago, is access to capital,” Kristine Liwag, senior aerospace and defense analyst at Morgan Stanley, explained.</p>
<p>This outsized influx of cash means these companies now have a meaningful amount of capital to take them through the long and thorough process of certifying their aircraft with the Federal Aviation Administration, a necessary prerequisite to launching commercial operations. Whether it will be enough is another matter and dependent on each company&#8217;s progress and cost efficiency.</p>
<p>The high cost of commercializing the technology likely drove the SPAC trend. Aviation is a capital-intensive business, and many believe that it could cost as much as $1 billion to take an eVTOL from design through manufacturing and certification.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Definitely the standout for me was the fact that a number of leading startups have found a way to get a budget that is capable of getting an aircraft towards full certification,” David Wyatt, technology analyst at IDTechEx, said. “It feels like a big step has been jumped there in terms of the likelihood of getting more of these test aircraft into the air, from a prototype phase into something that is much more of a concrete eVTOL functional aircraft.”</p>
<p>Even beyond SPACs, there has been plenty of venture funding into eVTOL companies. 2021 also saw massive funding rounds, include Beta Technologies’ <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/beta-technologies-adds-368-million-in-series-a-funding-for-its-electric-aviation-ecosystem/">$368 million Series A</a> and Xpeng-backed HT Aero’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/xpeng-backed-urban-air-mobility-company-ht-aero-raises-500m/">$500 million Series A</a>.</p>
<p>“2021 has been the year where we&#8217;re not asking anymore the question of, can it be certified?” Sergio Cecutta, founder and partner at SMG Consulting, said. “Now the question we&#8217;re asking is, when will it be certified? We&#8217;re beyond, ‘Will these things ever fly? Are they certifiable?’ Yes, they are. Now we need to roll up our sleeves and do it.”</p>
<h2>Movement on the ground</h2>
<p>Air taxi developers aren’t just focused on their aircraft. In order to make the market for electric aviation a reality, they’ll need a whole lot more: ground infrastructure, like vertiports or specialized areas in airports, plus charging points capable of getting enough juice to their vehicles.</p>
<p>There’s still a <em>lot </em>of work to be done in this area – see part two for more details – but 2021 saw eVTOL operators make notable strides towards at least starting to establish infrastructure required for commercial operations by mid-decade. This includes a partnership between Lilium and ABB E-mobility to supply charging infrastructure for the Lilium Jet; separate partnerships between Joby and Archer with parking garage owner REEF Technology; and a partnership between Vertical and Heathrow Airport to explore how eVTOL could fit into the airport’s operations.</p>
<p>Archer, Joby and Volocopter are also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/how-los-angeles-is-preparing-for-the-air-taxi-takeoff/">collaborating with Urban Movement Labs</a> in Los Angeles to explore how the city can integrate urban air mobility into existing infrastructure and transportation networks.</p>
<p>“I know that airports are starting to really heavily think about this,” JetBlue Technology Ventures President Amy Burr said. “Anybody who&#8217;s doing any infrastructure project at an airport is thinking about whether or not they need to put in a vertiport.”</p>
<h2>(Contingent) orders</h2>
<p>Finally, in 2021 we saw an increase of orders for eVTOL aircraft – starting, of course, with news from United that it had placed a $1 billion order with Archer Aviation. That was followed by a cascade of orders for aircraft from Embraer-backed air taxi developer Eve Urban Air Mobility, an order from UPS for Beta Technologies, and conditional preorders topping 1,350 aircraft from Vertical Aerospace.</p>
<p>It’s important to be clear that none of these orders are firm, which makes sense because the commercial product doesn’t exist yet. Orders are contingent upon completion of development, certification and likely other performance milestones.</p>
<p>Yet, even if it should be a tempered signal for any individual company, it’s still a promising sign for the industry, Wyatt said.</p>
<p>“I think it&#8217;s promising in that obviously there is a market for these aircrafts […] It certainly gives the confidence that if these aircraft are given their flight certification, are able to fly, then there will be considerable interest from the market for these aircraft.”</p>
<h2>Auto gets involved</h2>
<p>The final notable trend of 2021 is the increased activity from legacy automakers. While startups might&#8217;ve grabbed the most headlines, these older and more established companies have also started to notice the promise of electric aviation. (Notably, established aerospace companies, like Boeing and Airbus, have maintained a more established interest in eVTOL &#8212; Boeing through its joint venture with Kitty Hawk, Wisk Aero; and Airbus with its CityAirbus NextGen eVTOL concept.)</p>
<p>Amongst automakers, Hyundai is one such example. While the company unveiled an eVTOL concept design at CES in 2020, this year it officially spun out its urban air mobility business, calling it Supernal. Honda also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/30/honda-motor-co-announces-plans-for-evtol-avatar-robots-and-space-technologies/">confirmed plans to develop</a> a hybrid eVTOL &#8212; notable because the company said it would be one piece of a &#8220;mobility ecosystem&#8221; that includes connected apps and Honda vehicles. Then, of course, there&#8217;s Chinese automaker Xpeng Motors, which announced at the end of October that it&#8217;s urban air mobility subsidiary HT Aero had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/xpeng-backed-urban-air-mobility-company-ht-aero-raises-500m/">raised $500 million</a> to deliver on an eVTOL car concept.</p>
<p>These efforts are worth paying attention to, because these major automakers have both the capital, as the manufacturing infrastructure  to make moves on eVTOL project. That&#8217;s no assurance of success, of course, and these larger companies may not face the same pressures (and motivations) as a startup, but it&#8217;s definitely something to keep watch of looking to the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/top-evtol-trends-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2244974</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘Borderless’ crypto networks wrestle with state sanction compliance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/borderless-crypto-networks-wrestle-with-state-sanction-compliance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/borderless-crypto-networks-wrestle-with-state-sanction-compliance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Riggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 15:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ConsenSys Academy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crypto companies may be choosing to avoid marginalized communities rather than devising strategic ways to include them.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The United States’ <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-imposes-sanctions-people-iran-syria-uganda-citing-rights-abuses-2021-12-07/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">financial sanctions</a> against countries like Iran create a messy regulatory environment where cryptocurrency startups have to pick their battles carefully. So far, the battles these companies aren&#8217;t picking are having real effects on users and can sometimes directly contradict the company’s alleged decentralization philosophy.</p>
<p>“Something will come down on someone. We just don’t know where or when these regulations will be tested,” said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/florio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Larry Florio</a>, general counsel at <a href="https://a16z.com/2021/08/31/investing-in-syndicate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Syndicate</a>, a company focused on enabling “decentralized autonomous organizations” (DAOs) for tech-savvy collectives.</p>
<p>For a previous example, the crypto custody startup BitGo was <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/126/20201230_bitgo.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">penalized in 2020</a> by the Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) for failing “to implement controls designed to prevent” interacting with users from sanctioned jurisdictions. Basically, BitGo is almost like a crypto bank; it helps store clients’ assets in secure vaults. And the legal penalty came when some of those clients may have received cryptocurrency from individuals in sanctioned jurisdictions. OFAC showed this is not allowed under U.S. sanctions. Along those same lines, the crypto exchange <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2018/11/15/binance-warns-iranian-traders-to-withdraw-crypto-amid-sanctions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Binance</a> has been known to routinely deactivate accounts owned by Iranians and Cubans.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248864" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>That’s supposedly why the ConsenSys Academy, one of the industry’s leading Ethereum-centric educational organizations, <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2021/11/24/consensys-suddenly-bars-iranian-students-from-ethereum-coding-class/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">banned roughly 50 Iranian students</a> from its online platform in November 2021, claiming a “recent review of our records shows that you indicated that you are located in a country that we are prohibited from providing goods or services to under U.S. law.”</p>
<p>This compliance review raises questions since the program was free, with no transactions involved, and Coogan Brennan, head of developer relations at ConsenSys Academy, gave an interview to <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/consensys-grants-help-iranian-women-130000273.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CoinDesk in February 2021</a> about these Iranian students and the challenges they faced. Former program participant Salman Sadeghi told TechCrunch that “Iranians are treated like second-class citizens in web3.”</p>
<p>“They knew that we were from Iran from the very beginning,” Sadeghi said. “I think sanctions harm innocent people as you see, not the government. It’s not fair…<a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2021/01/28/inside-irans-onslaught-on-bitcoin-mining/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ethereum mining</a> is still popular in Iran. But it’s <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2020/02/27/iranian-general-advocates-crypto-use-for-skirting-sanctions-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the government</a>, mostly, that mines cryptocurrency.”</p>
<p>Yet another thwarted student, who goes by @Alireza__28, said that he had already quit his job in Tehran to study at the academy and that getting kicked out of the program without a completion certificate, after months of participation, ruined his career plans.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“It was really humiliating,” he said. “There are many remote blockchain job opportunities that pay with crypto. It doesn&#8217;t matter where you are living. Another hope that I had was getting a job offer with a visa sponsorship [to leave Iran]. And the other big hope I had was to make a decentralized app from here, myself.”</p>
<p>It’s also unclear if the sanctions actually apply to this educational program at all. The <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/quicktakes/2014/06/04/coursera-restores-access-iranian-students" target="_blank" rel="noopener">educational platform Coursera </a>does allow Iranian students with direct permission from the U.S. government. According to Michael Mosier, the <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2021/05/27/fincens-new-head-says-controversial-trump-era-crypto-proposal-is-still-pending/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">former acting director</a> of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN), the Biden administration is trying to thaw relations with Iran. As such, OFAC might have granted ConsenSys permission to serve this population. For an example from a different sanctioned country, last year OFAC <a href="https://twitter.com/M_Mosier_/status/1447341598392606726?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">approved</a> a humanitarian<a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/us-government-enlists-usdc-global-193616264.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> stablecoin distribution campaign</a> in <a href="https://www.circle.com/blog/circle-partners-with-bolivarian-republic-of-venezuela-and-airtm-to-deliver-aid-to-venezuelans-using-usdc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Venezuela</a>.</p>
<p>“The big takeaway from the ConsenSys stuff is that it’s worth talking to experienced lawyers in the OFAC space,” Mosier said. “I find it hard to believe that ConsenSys can’t do this. There’s a lot of times when people self-select out of something rather than deal with the risk.”</p>
<p>On the other hand, Florio countered that it is hard to fault companies taking a conservative approach to such sanctions.</p>
<p>“Sometimes even just trying to seek a waiver could raise your profile and attract more regulatory scrutiny,” Florio said. “A lot of the way that the industry works these days is don’t ask, don’t tell.”</p>
<p>There may still be hope for Iranian Ethereum fans. ConsenSys global PR lead Elo Gimenez told TechCrunch his company is “fully dedicated to our mission of building the digital economy of tomorrow, which includes exploring ways that we can lawfully share and educate around the world, including in jurisdictions where international engagement can be challenging.”</p>
<p>In the meantime, it’s still commonplace for Iranians to use centralized NFT platforms and tools provided by Ethereum co-founder Joe Lubin’s portfolio companies like <a href="https://decrypt.co/66541/ethereum-gitcoin-raises-11-million-spins-out-consensys" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gitcoin</a> or MetaMask, usually in combination with a VPN service to mask their location. The crowdfunding platform Gitcoin, for example, is a crowdfunding platform that hosted a <a href="https://gitcoin.co/grants/2215/solidity-development-course-by-women-in-blockchain" target="_blank" rel="noopener">campaign</a> for Persian-speaking students that was active from March until <a href="https://twitter.com/annbrody7/status/1468737168294256644?s=21" target="_blank" rel="noopener">December</a> 2021.<em> </em></p>
<p>Gitcoin COO Kyle Weiss told TechCrunch that, as of December 8, 2021, his fundraising platform is now “marking this grant as inactive out of an abundance of caution to ensure compliance with U.S. law.”</p>
<p>However, Mary Beth Buchanan, the former general counsel for the cryptocurrency exchange Kraken who previously worked for the Department of Justice, where she contributed to the Sentencing Guidelines for Business Organizations, told TechCrunch she doesn’t agree that companies like Gitcoin and ConsenSys Academy need to automatically ban users from sanctioned countries.</p>
<p>“It’s quite possible the activity they wanted to engage in might even be exempt from sanctions. It may be that the company didn’t ask the right questions,” Buchanan said. “Lots of activities are completely exempt from the sanctions regime and others can be granted a general license. You can also apply to OFAC on a case-by-case basis to ask if what you’re doing is okay.… there are phone numbers so that even average people can call OFAC and talk through whether an activity is exempt from sanctions.”</p>
<p>In short, crypto companies may be choosing to avoid marginalized communities rather than devising strategic ways to include them. Buchanan said, especially in cases that involve art or education, it’s far less expensive to be compliant than most business owners might expect. In the meantime, some people from Iran, <a href="https://twitter.com/sobradob/status/1466112990261002241" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cuba</a> and other sanctioned countries feel the crypto industry operates with a de facto caste system. Needing to hide one&#8217;s identity in order to participate in online communities is not the same thing as the community being borderless or inclusive.</p>
<p>“Yes, we can develop our own user interfaces and web3 websites,” said Aysha Amin, one of the women involved with the shuttered Gitcoin campaign, describing the esoteric concept that people refer to as web3 or “the metaverse” when describing Ethereum projects and altcoin competitors like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/14/solana-a-blockchain-platform-followed-by-top-crypto-investors-says-its-a-lot-faster-than-ethereum/">Solana</a>. “This kind of isolation does not seem good.”</p>
<p>Beyond Gitcoin, Amin said she’s currently participating in an <a href="https://twitter.com/0xrajeev/status/1416793642182737920" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ethereum Foundation-supported</a> educational program, called Secureum, while also working for a Tehran-based tech company. Like many Iranians cited in this piece, she is a MetaMask user who intends to continue working in the space despite discriminatory bans on any specific platform.</p>
<p>“We started this [Farsi-language group for blockchain enthusiasts] group after finishing [another] ConsenSys blockchain developer bootcamp,” Amin said. “As long as I have my own private key, I’m not worried. MetaMask saves my info locally.”</p>
<p>For a little background, the Iranian group she’s a part of includes members that met in Japan at the <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2019/10/10/devcon-shows-ethereums-world-computer-is-a-movement-not-a-product/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevCon</a> Ethereum conference in 2019. Amin joined this subgroup of five Iranian women in 2021. Their U.S.-based partner in the Gitcoin campaign, Thessy Mehrain, described the Gitcoin campaign:</p>
<blockquote><p>I have worked with Consensys Academy on diversity initiatives. As part of that, I was offered scholarships for minority communities, which I in turn extended to <a href="https://coiniran.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CoinIran</a>, an Amsterdam-based organization that has the goal to educate about web3. I met them [CoinIran bloggers] at the Ethereum conference in Osaka. In 2020, a group of female developers took part in the Solidity bootcamp… a <a href="https://www.meetup.com/WomeninBlockchainCommunity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Women in Blockchain</a> chapter was formed in Tehran, the same as we have globally in NYC, Boston, Brisbane, Lagos and elsewhere… They are run locally, entirely independently to educate about the tech and its opportunities.</p></blockquote>
<p>All things considered, it appears these initiatives are more focused on education than strictly on financial transactions.</p>
<p>“Education helps an individual make informed decisions for themselves and also contribute to the progress of the society and nation,” Mehrain said. “These women are members of the global society and should be empowered by education to meaningfully contribute.”</p>
<p>And it also appears that the recent Gitcoin ban is an outlier among the global initiatives funded by Ethereum co-founders like Vitalik Buterin, founder of the Ethereum Foundation, and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffkauflin/2018/12/05/cryptopia-in-crisis-billionaire-joe-lubins-ethereum-experiment-is-a-mess-how-long-will-he-prop-it-up/?sh=7c51977c2f0a" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lubin</a>, the leading <a href="https://decrypt.co/66541/ethereum-gitcoin-raises-11-million-spins-out-consensys" target="_blank" rel="noopener">investor</a> behind ConsenSys. This is partially because, as Florio pointed out, it’s impossible to discriminate across the entire metaverse.</p>
<p>“I don’t see sovereign nations giving up their foreign policy arsenal… yet it&#8217;s unenforceable to say that Iranians can’t participate in anything without applying some type of firewall to the entire country of Iran. I don’t even think the technology exists to do something like that type of internet blockade,” Florio said. “Imposing sanction laws is going to be difficult and require creative interpretations&#8230;I don’t know how the enforcement will come there or if they’ll take into account there are no known methods of fully complying in this context.”</p>
<p>For now, some crypto companies prefer to ban Iranians and other people from sanctioned jurisdictions, rather than seek a compliant legal strategy for including them.</p>
<p>“We don’t have full access all the time. It’s easy to exclude or ban us in web3,” Amin said. “Here in Iran, people who work with blockchain technology, miners, traders, developers, always worry about their access to web3. And we definitely feel this ‘second class citizens’ treatment.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/borderless-crypto-networks-wrestle-with-state-sanction-compliance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ubiquitous platform brings all the influencers to the yard</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ubiquitous-platform-seed-investment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ubiquitous-platform-seed-investment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 15:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Influencer Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ubiquitous]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2248056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With traction metrics that would make any startup CFO foam at the mouth, TikTok influencer marketing platform Ubiquitous is making a big splash in the chaotic market of influencer marketing. It&#8217;s one of the fastest-growing segments of advertising and marketing, but one that brings some unique challenges; working with influencers directly is labor-intensive, but results [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">With traction metrics that would make any startup CFO foam at the mouth, TikTok influencer marketing platform <a href="https://www.ubiquitousinfluence.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ubiquitous</a> is making a big splash in the chaotic market of influencer marketing. It&#8217;s one of the fastest-growing segments of advertising and marketing, but one that brings some unique challenges; working with influencers directly is labor-intensive, but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/early-stage-brands-should-also-unlock-the-power-of-influencers/">results don&#8217;t lie</a>, and many brands are finding it&#8217;s worth the hassle.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve seen a bunch of activity in this space recently, including a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/01/productwind-raises-1-67m-to-connect-your-brand-with-hundreds-of-influencers/">$2 million ProductWind</a> round, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/15/kenyas-aifluence-closes-1m-for-its-ai-powered-influencer-marketing-platform/">Alfluence&#8217;s $1 million</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/18/cross-selling-startup-carro-secures-20m-to-connect-brands-with-each-other-influencers/">Carro&#8217;s $20 million</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/influencer-marketing/">many more</a>. The reason Ubiquitous&#8217; platform caught my eye is that it raised a $5 million round led by <a href="https://uncorkcapital.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Uncork</a> in its largest seed investment to date (with additional funding from <a href="https://100thieves.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">100 Thieves</a> and <a href="https://www.startingline.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Starting Line VC</a>), and the company has seen some stunning growth. The company launched just six months ago, has already booked $6 million of sales and is claiming astonishing conversion rates across the board, with 250 brands already using the platform, and corraling more than 1,000 influencers onto its platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was head of growth and then VP of Marketing for a company called <a href="https://www.getbellhops.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bellhop</a>. In that role, I came across this opportunity because I tried to put a test budget into TikTok influencers. We tried to find an agency or a platform or anything that specializes in this. We were looking at it for a week, but we concluded there wasn&#8217;t one. Like even when we&#8217;re talking to the <a href="https://www.viralnation.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Viral Nations</a> of the world, and all our traditional providers. They&#8217;re not taking this seriously. They&#8217;re not really investing in the space to be able to get us the data that we need,&#8221; Alex Elsea, co-founder at Ubiquitous, said as he outlined the history of the company. &#8220;That was final straw for me as a marketing leader. I&#8217;ve never had a good experience with an influencer marketing provider. And so we set out to create the company that was missing in the market.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2248056" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Running influencer campaigns in-house is tremendously work intensive; if you want to put $100,000 into a test campaign, you&#8217;re looking at 20-40 creators on the various platforms. That means you&#8217;re trying to find contact details for 100, negotiate with 50-60, sign agreements with 30 or so. Managing briefs, signing off on creative, handling negotiations and payments and contracts &#8212; it becomes an administrative nightmare very fast, and you&#8217;re often working with a number of creators who don&#8217;t have a slick process set up for how to handle this. In other words; you&#8217;re hiring amateurs for contract work, which is hard at the best of times.</p>
<p>&#8220;The moment it all clicked was in a meeting with myself and my marketing leadership team. I found myself wondering, &#8216;how is anyone doing this? How is anyone able to actually execute at this scale?&#8217; At the same time, the quotes and the rates that we got back from the TikTok influencers was astounding. They were a fourth of what we were paying on Instagram, and the engagement rates were four to six times higher. It was the best data I had ever seen &#8212; but it was so much work to make it happen that it just didn&#8217;t scale,&#8221; explains Elsea. &#8220;And so there was this meeting, we looked at each other, we were like, are we missing something? Or is this the best opportunity we&#8217;ve ever seen?&#8221;</p>
<p>Long story short, Elsea and his founding team had stumbled into a huge opportunity in a brand new market &#8212; influencer marketing has been happening for a while, but rarely at scale, and TikTok had a different approach than Instagram, which meant that the dynamics of running influencer campaigns suddenly started to make a lot more sense.</p>
<p>&#8220;And every brand is going through the same thing &#8212; so there is a huge need, and you need some tech to automate it, because otherwise, you need a massive team in order to deploy that budget on an influencer-by-influencer basis, using phone calls, text messages and emails. Our platform helps with that,&#8221; explains Elsea.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company is essentially a marketplace with an agency component: Ubiquitous helps marketing managers put together an influencer strategy, select the best influencers to work with, and then execute the whole campaign, end-to-end. The business model is clever, too, getting two bites of the apple for every transaction. The company charges its advertisers a platform fee, but it also charges a percentage of the money it pays out to its influencers. The company&#8217;s founders declined to specify exactly what its cut is on either side of the transaction.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve been doing it for about a year, with about a year and a half of testing. We officially launched April 1st, and we found product-market fit on the brand side and on the creator side. Since our launch, we went from zero to a $5 million revenue run rate, and in less than five months, it just took off,&#8221; explains Elsea. &#8220;To date, in reality, what VCs have been willing to fund has moved this industry the wrong way. It&#8217;s pushed it towards a SaaS model where you&#8217;re taking the humans out of the equation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ubiquitous decided that if campaigns are five-, six- and seven-figure sums, it wasn&#8217;t enough to sell the brands a SaaS package, give them a log-in and say &#8220;good luck, folks,&#8221; and instead built up a fully functional platform to take care of all aspects of the influencer marketing campaigns.</p>
<p>With the funds raised, the company has ambitious plans. The company admits that what it has built so far is a bit basic, but claims it is head and shoulders above what the competition is offering. To get further ahead, the company is scaling out an engineering and product team and is adding a number of tools that serve the creators.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have a deep passion for taking care of these creators. The whole industry is kind of designed to take advantage of the influencers. We want to fix that. We&#8217;ve been able to build a creator network of this size this quickly by building a brand that actually puts them first and takes care of them,&#8221; explains Elsea. &#8220;Instead of only bringing them deals, the creator-facing app is going to be the hub of their entire careers. We are talking about rolling out creator-facing insurance, accounting services and much more.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ubiquitous-platform-seed-investment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2248056</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Create target customer personas to develop successful growth strategies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/create-target-customer-personas-to-develop-successful-growth-strategies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/create-target-customer-personas-to-develop-successful-growth-strategies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 15:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[targeted advertising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To create successful growth strategies, relevant marketing campaigns and products that deliver real value to your customers, you must first understand your customers.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Jamie Viggiano</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jimbovig">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Jamie Viggiano is the chief marketing officer at <a href="https://www.fuelcapital.com">Fuel Capital</a>, an early-stage venture capital firm investing in consumer, SaaS and infrastructure businesses.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/20/start-building-your-brand-book-with-a-visioning-workshop/">Start building your brand book with a visioning workshop</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/5-questions-startups-should-consider-before-making-their-first-marketing-hire/">5 questions startups should consider before making their first marketing hire</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">To create successful growth strategies, relevant marketing campaigns and products that deliver real value to your customers, you must first <em>understand</em> your customers. Doing that requires studying them, talking to them and building target personas to help you make them real to your team. Developing your customer profile is an integral piece of positioning your brand and an indispensable section of your brand book.</p>
<p>Many founders broaden their total addressable market (TAM) to make the numbers on fundraising decks seem more exciting, but effective customer targeting requires you to surgically narrow to a specific customer profile — right down to a name, an age and even a face. Once you’ve identified your customer, it’s critically important to articulate the demographic <em>and</em> ethnographic elements that define them. Demographic information (such as location, gender, marital status) isn’t nearly enough, and to understand the customer, you must also understand relevant ethnographic elements like their lifestyles and motivations.</p>
<p>Here’s how:</p>
<p>Pull a list of your most dedicated users for each metric that matters to your company, such as highest LTV, most frequent user, highest number of purchases or even highest referring customer. Your goal is to generate a list of customers, and the exact number may vary depending on the stage of your company. For a seed company, I’d recommend pulling a list of 15-25 customers. If you’re pre-launch and don’t have customers just yet, you can build a list of your desired users using external data from third-party apps and Google.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			By clearly articulating the preferences, pain points and motivations of your ideal customers, you’ll be able to approach messaging in an informed and strategic manner. 					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Create a spreadsheet that includes at a minimum the following parameters:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unique customer ID</li>
<li>Location</li>
<li>Gender</li>
<li>Age</li>
<li>Career/profession</li>
<li>Referral source</li>
<li>Marital status</li>
<li>Education</li>
<li>Purchasing behavior (defining first purchase, second purchase, third purchase, etc.) and/or engagement behavior (first, interaction, second interaction and so on.)</li>
<li>LTV</li>
</ul>
<p>Since the above parameters include both internal and external data, you’ll have to use third-party tools or even do some cyber-sleuthing (you’ll be surprised how much you can learn with a Google search). Leverage your own database for usage behavior and customer journey, but put in the elbow grease necessary to understand more about each customer.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/create-target-customer-personas-to-develop-successful-growth-strategies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246690</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin is religion; web3 is greed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/bitcoin-is-religion-web3-is-greed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/bitcoin-is-religion-web3-is-greed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 15:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@jack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What matters here is that Jack Dorsey, a well-known proponent of the original cryptocurrency bitcoin, isn't big on web3 projects.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It&#8217;s my last day of work for the year, so we&#8217;re going to have some fun. Obviously, we&#8217;re talking crypto this morning.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jack">Jack Dorsey</a>, former Twitter CEO and present CEO of Block, the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/01/square-is-changing-its-name-to-block/">company formerly known as Square</a>, stirred the crypto pot recently, making explicit his preferences in the larger blockchain landscape by taking swipes at decentralized internet projects that don&#8217;t fall under Bitcoin&#8217;s aegis.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>To avoid being accused of misinterpreting Jack, here are his key statements, starting with <a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1473139010197508098">the genesis tweet</a> of the conversation:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2250255" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.09-AM.png?w=549" alt="" width="549" height="278" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.09-AM.png 549w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.09-AM.png?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.09-AM.png?resize=300,152 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.09-AM.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 549px) 100vw, 549px" /></p>
<p>Which <a href="https://twitter.com/mdudas/status/1473140692255969281">went down like a party foul with well-known web3 stans</a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2250256" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.33-AM.png?w=594" alt="" width="594" height="299" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.33-AM.png 594w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.33-AM.png?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.33-AM.png?resize=300,151 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.30.33-AM.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 594px) 100vw, 594px" /></p>
<p>And a few hours after Jack&#8217;s tweet, <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1473165434518224896">Elon Musk joined in the fun</a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2250258" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.32.15-AM.png?w=550" alt="" width="550" height="252" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.32.15-AM.png 550w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.32.15-AM.png?resize=150,69 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.32.15-AM.png?resize=300,137 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screen-Shot-2021-12-21-at-8.32.15-AM.png?resize=50,23 50w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /></p>
<p>There are several different things being said here, and a few of the tweets could use a bit of explaining if you don&#8217;t live on Twitter. The Exchange has your back:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>On who &#8220;owns&#8221; web3:</strong> Jack argues that regular users aren&#8217;t owners of web3 projects. Instead, the CEO claims that venture capitalists and, in turn, their investors are. Even more, Jack doesn&#8217;t expect this dynamic to change; instead, he anticipates that centralized capital pools backing a plethora of crypto projects will maintain quite a lot of control thanks to venture incentives.</li>
<li><strong>On being critical of web3: </strong>After being criticized for &#8220;stifling&#8221; web3 work, Jack dismissed the complaint and said that &#8220;critiques&#8221; can help folks choose to work on more fulfilling projects.</li>
<li><strong>On who will own web3:</strong> Elon Musk jumped into the fun to ask where web3 is, as he is struggling to find it. Jack then subtweets a16z, the venture capital firm, as the nexus point for web3 project funding, and therefore control.</li>
</ul>
<p>What matters in the above is that Jack, a well-known proponent of the original cryptocurrency, Bitcoin, isn&#8217;t big on web3 projects.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s notable that these two characters popped up to argue against the flood of greed that&#8217;s cropped up in the decentralized economy over the last few years, with every traditional pile of money wanting to get in on putative web3 returns.</p>
<h2>Who owns what?</h2>
<p>The core of Jack&#8217;s complaint is that leading web3 corporations are owned by venture capitalists, and therefore will have to live with venture incentives.</p>
<p>&#8220;Venture incentives,&#8221; of course, is a polite way of saying <em>running a company in such a manner that venture capitalists and their backers make lots of money. </em></p>
<p>The complaint is pretty true. Venture capitalists invested <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/venture-funds-poured-over-6-5-billion-into-crypto-in-q3-2021/">more than $6 billion</a> into crypto projects in Q3 2021 alone. That should give you an idea of the scale of the crypto world being purchased by traditional, private-market investors at the moment. More simply, pension funds own a lot of the crypto economy.</p>
<p>Jack&#8217;s diss about venture capitalists and web3 didn&#8217;t stop there. Not only did Jack say that web3 projects have a weakness in their core thanks to the economic bargains their progenitors have made with external capital, but also that they are <em>centralized. </em></p>
<p>Aside from calling someone a &#8220;nocoiner&#8221; who is going to, alternatively, &#8220;stay poor&#8221; or &#8220;ngmi,&#8221; saying that a crypto project is centralized is perhaps the rudest possible comment.</p>
<p>Is Jack wrong? No, he is not.</p>
<p>It is true that venture players are flooding the zone in web3 with cash and assistance because they think it will make them money. This leads to quite a lot of centralization. For example, I find it blisteringly funny that a16z is an investor in both Coinbase and OpenSea. And that Coinbase intends to get in on the NFT game. You know, the thing that OpenSea currently rules.</p>
<p>Even more, projects like <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/solana-generates-1-billion-in-returns-for-early-backers">Solana sold a bunch of their tokens for a song to venture investors</a>, effectively handing out upside that is forever frozen in already swollen accounts. Centralization? Of ownership <em>and</em> returns, in that case.</p>
<p>Centralization is antithetical to the original, somewhat punk Bitcoin ethos. Web3 advocates, as far as I can tell it, are perfectly content with using external funds to power their new token-based projects as a way to accelerate the future they see coming. Fiat as crutch, I suppose.</p>
<p>But Bitcoin didn&#8217;t need to raise three venture rounds in a year to grow. It just nailed an idea that <em>still </em>resonates. Something to think about.</p>
<p>Now we get to a very large <em>yeah, but</em>.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin is religion; web3 is greed</h2>
<p>While it&#8217;s nice to agree with someone on a crypto viewpoint, I don&#8217;t agree with Jack on everything.</p>
<p>For example, I don&#8217;t agree that Bitcoin is not centralized. It is to a degree that I don&#8217;t think that many people really grok. A new study found this week that &#8220;approximately 0.01% of Bitcoin holders control 27% of the 19 million Bitcoin that are now in circulation,&#8221; <a href="https://www.baystreet.ca/cryptonews/148/Bitcoin-Ownership-Increasingly-Concentrated-In-a-Few-Hands-Study">per Baystreet</a>.</p>
<p>This is why, when I consider the two warring religious camps in the crypto world &#8212; the Bitcoin maximalists who think that the original crypto project is a decentralized Jesus and the web3 &#8220;gm&#8221; crew &#8212; it&#8217;s clear that they are rather different.</p>
<p>Bitcoin maxis are <em>religious</em> in their belief that the OG crypto nailed it, and successive projects are bunk. And web3 is <em>greed</em>, a way to financialize everything online in a manner that allows traditional investors to own toll booths and tax collectors throughout the decentralized landscape.</p>
<p>So while I am more than content to nod along to Jack stirring the web3 pot, I don&#8217;t agree with his general philosophy. Still, Jack managed to point out that a bunch of naked wannabe emperors are, in fact, <em>au naturel</em>. And that&#8217;s a good way to kick off the day.</p>
<p>Merry Christmas.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/bitcoin-is-religion-web3-is-greed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250254</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ampla raises $40M Series A for its business of providing credit to commerce brands</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ampla-raises-40m-series-a-to-provide-commerce-brands-with-lines-of-credit-for-working-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ampla-raises-40m-series-a-to-provide-commerce-brands-with-lines-of-credit-for-working-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 15:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forerunner ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VMG Partners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ampla Technologies, a startup which provides financing to small-to-medium sized consumer-facing businesses, announced today it has raised $40 million in a Series A round of funding co-led by VMG Partners and Forerunner Ventures. Existing backer Core Innovation Capital also put money in the round. In conjunction with the equity investment, Ampla has also secured $250 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.getampla.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ampla Technologies</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a startup which provides financing to small-to-medium sized consumer-facing businesses, announced today it has raised $40 million in a Series A round of funding co-led by VMG Partners and Forerunner Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Existing backer Core Innovation Capital also put money in the round. In conjunction with the equity investment, Ampla has also secured $250 million in a debt facility so that it can begin financing brands. The capital infusions bring the New York-based startup’s total funding to $50 million in equity and $330 million in debt financing since its 2019 inception.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While there are a number of startups out there funding SMBs and e-commerce businesses, Ampla claims that its differentiator is that it provides businesses with a line of credit that includes “omnichannel” revenue streams in underwriting. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company&#8217;s goal is to give founders access to more capital at lower cost, according to Ampla CEO and founder Anthony Santomo. </span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250198" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ampla’s flagship product, for example, aims to provide (even pre-revenue) businesses with working capital so they can do things like purchase inventory and spend on marketing. Ampla currently works with SMBs in the consumer brand industry across both e-commerce and retail channels. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Its “proprietary” data-driven underwriting tool takes into consideration the two channels, and provides “fully transparent” interest rates with no hidden fees and larger credit limits, according to Santomo. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">By the full omnichannel view, we mean that we are able to look at not only e-commerce revenue streams but also retail revenue streams to capture the entire commerce view,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike raising venture money, the working capital is non-dilutive. Indeed, a number of startups providing alternative financing have emerged in recent years, including </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/clearbanc-unicorn-clearco/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clearco </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/settle-raises-15m-from-kleiner-perkins-to-give-e-commerce-companies-more-working-capital/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Settle</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, among others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ampla goes a step further, Santomo added, by providing adjacent financial tools designed “to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">help emerging companies grow more efficiently.”</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup has over 200 customers including Partake Foods, Bev, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Good Planet Foods and Serenity Kids. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nearly 30% of Ampla’s customer base so far is made up of businesses founded by people of color and over 40% by females, its execs claim.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the company declined to reveal hard revenue figures, it did say that its monthly transaction volume has grown over 300% in the last 12 months. Its headcount has quadrupled to 40 during that same timeframe</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ampla plans to use its new capital to, naturally, do more hiring </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">across product, technology, sales and operations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Growing our team will allow us to launch new products and iterate on existing products faster,” Santomo told TechCrunch. “All products are driven by customer feedback and demand.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The COVID-19 pandemic created a shift in e-commerce adoption. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the pandemic hit, “Ampla quickly realized that large increases in e-commerce sales were coming across the majority of its customer base,” Santomo said. “These large increases in e-commerce sales created a universal demand for a commercial-grade working capital solution.&#8221;</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ffjVFoG0rq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/03/why-and-when-startups-should-look-to-diverse-sources-of-capital/">Why and when startups should look to diverse sources of capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why and when startups should look to diverse sources of capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/03/why-and-when-startups-should-look-to-diverse-sources-of-capital/embed/#?secret=ffjVFoG0rq" data-secret="ffjVFoG0rq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jason Bornstein, principal at Forerunner Ventures, led acquisition and demand planning at Bonobos (</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> an e-commerce-driven apparel subsidiary of Walmart) in its early days that ended up raising over $100 million in funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the time, he recalls, “it was never easier to build a brand online, but it was challenging to build a business online.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But over the last decade, a playbook for how to launch a digital brand has developed. The enablement layer of products and services has matured, and there’s now a vibrant ecosystem of digital brands,” he wrote via email. “When it comes to financing, however, the choices aren’t at all clear-cut. While select brands may continue to take equity and venture debt through the VC ecosystem, most brands do not have access to appropriate capital to scale. Brands deserve a financial platform that appreciates and understands their business model, capital needs, and ambitions.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Forerunner became known in the market as an early supporter of digital brands, Bornstein points out that the firm has “always” believed that stores and wholesale will continue to play a meaningful role in a brand’s sales strategy and presence in the market. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Ampla shares this belief and uniquely considers omnichannel revenue when underwriting a business,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brooke Kiley, partner at VMG Catalyst, noted that VMG has a long history of investing in consumer products and has seen firsthand that there’s a lack of viable working capital options for emerging brands. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;The existing alternatives leave entrepreneurs confused and frustrated. With Ampla, what you see is what you get,” she wrote via email. “There are no hidden fees or intentionally confusing structure. Your business is evaluated as a whole – not just one individual revenue channel – and provided with flexible terms that are designed with the customer in mind.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/ampla-raises-40m-series-a-to-provide-commerce-brands-with-lines-of-credit-for-working-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250198</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airtable acqui-hires Walrus.ai&#8217;s founding team</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/airtable-acqui-hires-walrus-ais-founding-team/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/airtable-acqui-hires-walrus-ais-founding-team/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acquihire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airtable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software testing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walrus.ai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Airtable today announced that it quietly acquired Walrus.ai, a no-code software testing platform, earlier this year. &#8216;Acquired&#8217; may be overstating things a bit, though. Best I can tell, Walrus.ai&#8217;s homepage became unavailable a few months ago and Airtable tells me it has no plans to use any of the service&#8217;s technology. &#8216;Acquihire&#8217; may be a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.airtable.com/">Airtable</a> today announced that it quietly acquired <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/4-million-richer-walrus-ai-has-a-pitch-for-companies-looking-for-qa-testing-tools/">Walrus.ai</a>, a no-code software testing platform, earlier this year.</p>
<p>&#8216;Acquired&#8217; may be overstating things a bit, though. Best I can tell, Walrus.ai&#8217;s homepage became unavailable a few months ago and Airtable tells me it has no plans to use any of the service&#8217;s technology. &#8216;Acquihire&#8217; may be a better description, but neither Airtable&#8217;s Chief Product Officer Peter Deng and Walrus co-founder Scott White was quite ready to use this term.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think, at the end of the day, you want to work on things that align with the vision and the arc of what you&#8217;re trying to accomplish,&#8221; White told me.&#8221; Airtable is the natural evolution or the opportunity to fulfill the vision of what you set out to accomplish on a grander scale. And so I think of it as an evolution of what we&#8217;re working on, to be able to take that to the next level. I think it was an awesome opportunity.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2249697" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>White and his co-founders Jake Marsh and Akshay Nathan will join the company, with White becoming the product lead for solutions at Airtable, Nathan an engineering manager in the company&#8217;s enterprise organization and Marsh joining as a software engineer. Only the co-founders are joining the company. Walrus.ai had previously raised $4 million is seed funding from investors like Homebrew, Felicis Ventures and Leadout Capital.</p>
<p>The two companies argue that their overall vision was very much aligned. While the Walrus team, aimed to make building end-to-end software tests easier by helping users write their tests in plain English, Airtable wants to turn all of its users into app developers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qHPebLCk3n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/4-million-richer-walrus-ai-has-a-pitch-for-companies-looking-for-qa-testing-tools/">$4 million richer, Walrus.ai has a pitch for companies looking for QA-testing tools</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;$4 million richer, Walrus.ai has a pitch for companies looking for QA-testing tools&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/27/4-million-richer-walrus-ai-has-a-pitch-for-companies-looking-for-qa-testing-tools/embed/#?secret=qHPebLCk3n" data-secret="qHPebLCk3n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;Democratizing software creation &#8212; really kind of making it easy to build software, it all started there,&#8221; said Deng when I asked him how this deal came about. &#8220;I got introduced to Scott and the Walrus team and it was very immediately apparent that we share the same vision. The vision of Walrus was to make building high-quality software easy for developers. But, you know, when we started talking, I was like: &#8216;well, let&#8217;s just make building software easier for everyone. Right? And how about that?&#8217; I think there was just immediate click on the DNA of the co-founders and things that they were doing and things that we were doing, and we just started talking and it just felt more and more natural to just work together.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At Airtable, Deng and White argued, the Walrus team would be able to expand on its original vision and that their skills would transfer to building a different kind of product. As White noted, Airtable aims to make it easy for its users to do very complex things and make that process easy and seamless. And at the same time, with enterprise being Airtable&#8217;s fastest-growing segment, its service is also now being used to manage very complex workflows.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think about our work on those two dimensions: about how to make the floor very low for a net new creator to come onto the platform and start building &#8212; and then making sure that our core capabilities and infrastructure will allow us to scale to these massive enterprise engagements,&#8221; White said about the work he is doing at Airtable now. Neither White nor Deng would say what exactly the Walrus team is working on now, beyond Deng saying that they are &#8220;working on big things together&#8221; that involves a number of initiatives to solve &#8220;end-user problems in a very elegant way.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="3TXzGKau7y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/17/the-end-of-the-acqui-hire/">The End Of The Acqui-Hire?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The End Of The Acqui-Hire?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/05/17/the-end-of-the-acqui-hire/embed/#?secret=3TXzGKau7y" data-secret="3TXzGKau7y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/airtable-acqui-hires-walrus-ais-founding-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OnlyFans founder Tim Stokely steps down, appoints spokesperson as CEO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/onlyfans-founder-tim-stokely-steps-down-appoints-spokesperson-as-ceo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/onlyfans-founder-tim-stokely-steps-down-appoints-spokesperson-as-ceo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 14:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[onlyfans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Bull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world wide web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250266</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OnlyFans founder and CEO Tim Stokely is stepping down, Bloomberg reports. His successor is Ami Gan, the company&#8217;s former head of communications and marketing. This move comes after a tenuous year for OnlyFans, in which the company said it would ban the sex workers that thrive on the platform, a decision that it suspended a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">OnlyFans founder and CEO Tim Stokely is stepping down, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-21/onlyfans-ceo-tim-stokely-steps-down-giving-role-to-spokesperson-ami-gan">Bloomberg reports</a>. His successor is Ami Gan, the company&#8217;s former head of communications and marketing. This move comes after a tenuous year for OnlyFans, in which the company said it would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/onlyfans-bans-explicit-content/">ban</a> the sex workers that thrive on the platform, a decision that it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/onlyfans-suspends-decision-to-ban-explicit-content/">suspended</a> a week later.</p>
<p>If it seems strange to appoint a spokesperson as CEO of a company, you&#8217;re not off-base. But, per <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-21/onlyfans-ceo-tim-stokely-steps-down-giving-role-to-spokesperson-ami-gan">reports</a>, this was Stokely&#8217;s own decision. Stokely will remain with the company as an advisor.</p>
<p class="paywall">“We’ve worked side-by-side sharing our passion about the creator economy,” Gan, the new CEO, said. “Our priority is to continue being committed to being the safest social media platform in the world.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250266" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Gan also said that she will invest in OFTV, the company&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/onlyfans-promotes-its-sfw-app-as-it-seeks-funding-at-a-1b-valuation/">safe-for-work streaming app</a>, and will build new tools for creators. While Stokely&#8217;s own business background is in online pornography, Gan has worked for brands like Red Bull, Quest Nutrition and a cannabis cafe.</p>
<p>TechCrunch asked OnlyFans if this change in leadership will impact sex workers on the platform and is awaiting comment.</p>
<p>OnlyFans thrives thanks to its NSFW creators, and in August, the company was <a href="https://www.axios.com/onlyfans-investors-struggle-9cc92523-6607-40ad-9893-4175e7966b52.html">on track</a> to do $2.5 billion in sales this year, up from $1.2 billion last year (OnlyFans takes 20% of creator earnings). But then, the company dropped a bombshell that would jeopardize the livelihoods of the sex workers who made the app a billion-dollar enterprise: OnlyFans was going to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/onlyfans-bans-explicit-content/">ban</a> NSFW content. After swift backlash, OnlyFans <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/onlyfans-suspends-decision-to-ban-explicit-content/">suspended</a> this decision, saying that it resolved issues with banking providers.</p>
<p>Still, sex workers remain concerned about being deplatformed &#8212; after all, OnlyFans said it was &#8220;suspending&#8221; the ban, rather than reversing it.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>When platforms like OnlyFans threaten to ban sex workers, it can mean the loss of their livelihood, but it can also push them toward more dangerous, offline working conditions.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Congress introduced the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/3165/text">Safe Sex Workers Study Act</a> in 2019 to examine the affects of legislation like the<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/11/trump-signs-controversial-anti-sex-trafficking-bill/"> Fight Online Sex Trafficking Act</a> (FOSTA), which make online sex work more difficult. This study found that “community organizations [had] reported increased homelessness of sex workers” after losing the “economic stability provided by access to online platforms.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The possibility of changes at OnlyFans is also scary for sex workers <a href="https://openlettertopatreon.com/">who know how hard it is</a> to be shuffled from platform to platform. Even Patreon </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/vbqwwj/patreon-suspension-of-adult-content-creators">deplatformed sex workers</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> in 2018 &#8212; the company said that it </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/9kqye3/patreon-porn-adult-content-guidelines-open-letter">never allowed porn</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, but for years, these guidelines weren&#8217;t stringently enforced, so sex workers were able to use the platform to make a living.</span></p>
<p>Patreon at least provides creators with access to subscribers&#8217; emails, so they can still contact their fanbase even without the intermediary of the platform. But OnlyFans is more like Instagram or Twitter &#8212; even if someone follows you, you have no way of communicating with them outside the platform. How could you create a new business on a different platform if you have no way to contact your clients?</p>
<p>OnlyFans hasn&#8217;t indicated that this change in leadership will jeopardize sex workers &#8212; but this is a massive change to a platform that has already toyed with the trust of its NSFW creators.</p>
<p><em>This story is developing&#8230;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/onlyfans-founder-tim-stokely-steps-down-appoints-spokesperson-as-ceo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250266</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Pfeffel&#8221; artist satirizes Boris Johnson with parody NFTs, sending 52% of proceeds to charity</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/pfeffel-artist-satirises-boris-johnson-with-parody-nfts-sending-52-of-proceeds-to-charity/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/pfeffel-artist-satirises-boris-johnson-with-parody-nfts-sending-52-of-proceeds-to-charity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 14:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boris Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[databases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distributed computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[G7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Years Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenSea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As crazy as the NFT market has become, there’s been an increasing range of other things to do with NFTs other than pimp images of apes and punks &#8211; even if they have become enormously valuable. We’ve seen the auction of apartments as NFTs, for instance. And now we’re seeing charities starting to benefit from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As crazy as the NFT market has become, there’s been an increasing range of other things to do with NFTs other than pimp images of apes and punks &#8211; even if they have become enormously valuable.</p>
<p>We’ve seen the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/25/blockchain-startup-propy-plans-first-ever-auction-of-a-real-apartment-as-a-collectible-nft/">auction of apartments as NFTs</a>, for instance.</p>
<p>And now we’re seeing charities starting to benefit from the frenzy, raising funds in a transparent way, while engaging new audiences.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250252" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Even Binance has launched <a href="https://www.nftforgood.org/#/home">“NFT for Good”</a>, an open platform founded by the Binance Charity foundation, enabling people to convert their art and creativity into an auction targeting social and humanitarian issues.</p>
<p>Part of the reason it’s taking off is that NFTs <a href="https://nftevening.com/nft-charity-donations-are-on-the-rise-here-are-our-favourites/">gamify the process of fundraising</a>.</p>
<p>At the same time, Crypto art is entering the realism of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dada">Dadaism</a> and Satire. Remember the Ethereum token called FUCK, which raised $30,000 in the first half-hour of a July 2017 ICO? Now we have the world’s richest <a href="https://superrare.com/artwork-v2/the-million-dollar-line-20607">line as an NFT</a>, (literally a drawn line in red ink) currently priced at 260.774 Ether or $1.04M.</p>
<p>The worlds of NFT art and satire now collide in a new project, which has just gone live on the NFT platform OpenSea, dubbed “<a href="https://opensea.io/collection/nft-the-boris-drop">Non Fungible Tories &#8211; The Boris Drop</a>”.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This consists of a set of 8-bit parody portraits of UK Prime Minister Boris Johnson, where <em>52%</em> of proceeds (matching the infamous <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/politics/eu_referendum/results">Brexit vote majority figure</a>) will be going to a UK charity to help the homeless.</p>
<p>In the NFT series, the artist &#8211; who bills themselves as “Pfeffel, a punk artist” (their identity has been verified by TechCrunch as a UK-based tech founder) &#8211; satirizes some of Johnson’s most famous quotes</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Bozo.gif" alt="" width="600" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2250257" /></p>
<p>In their tribute to “a clown, an oaf, a wager of culture war, and a pound-shop Churchill”, Pfeffel has creates a series of NFTs based on Johnson’s quotes such as “<a href="https://opensea.io/assets/0x495f947276749ce646f68ac8c248420045cb7b5e/56877347506589068823172852319637238320636213562928988291262062303833967558657">Watermelon smile</a>”, “<a href="https://opensea.io/assets/0x495f947276749ce646f68ac8c248420045cb7b5e/56877347506589068823172852319637238320636213562928988291262062306032990814209">Letterbox</a>” and the moment he <a href="https://opensea.io/assets/0x495f947276749ce646f68ac8c248420045cb7b5e/56877347506589068823172852319637238320636213562928988291262062313729572208641">hid in a fridge</a> instead of answering a journalists&#8217; questions.</p>
<p>The NFTs also satirize the very Johnson latest controversy &#8211; throwing a party at No.10, <a href="https://opensea.io/assets/0x495f947276749ce646f68ac8c248420045cb7b5e/56877347506589068823172852319637238320636213562928988291262062328023223369729">featuring cheese and wine</a>, while the UK was in full pandemic lockdown. The “8-bit images of a 2-bit politician” will all be first editions.</p>
<p>Pfeffel has pledged that the charity <a href="https://www.crisis.org.uk/crisis-at-christmas/">Crisis at Christmas</a>, which helps the homeless on UK streets during the festive season, will benefit from the NTF auction.</p>
<p>Admittedly, there’s plenty of Johnson material for any NFT artist to lampoon.</p>
<p>Johnson has increasingly gained a reputation as a &#8216;care and conscience-free&#8217; politician, infamously coining the lines “fuck business” and “let the bodies pile up” in regards to the COVID-19 pandemic. He’s also slashed the UK’s aid budget, presided over the highest COVID death rate in Europe, and the deepest economic slump in the G7.</p>
<p>Pfeffel told TechCrunch: “One way to rebuke the devil is to laugh at him. My art laughs at Johnson. These NFTs will hopefully help to, in some way, alleviate the suffering of those on the streets who have been forgotten by a government that seems happy to party while the bodies pile up.”</p>
<p>The auction will go live on Tuesday at Noon and will end on New Year’s Eve at Noon. </p>
<p>You can follow the auction updates <a href="https://twitter.com/pfeffelart">on twitter here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/pfeffel-artist-satirises-boris-johnson-with-parody-nfts-sending-52-of-proceeds-to-charity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250252</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calibrate Ventures raises $97M for second fund targeting AI, automation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/calibrate-ventures-raises-97m-for-second-fund-targeting-ai-automation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/calibrate-ventures-raises-97m-for-second-fund-targeting-ai-automation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Built Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Calibrate Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farmwise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Schoettler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Dunlap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soft Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyson Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With capital flowing freely lately, managing partners Jason Schoettler and Kevin Dunlap shared some insights on what it takes to win deals these days. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.calibratevc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Calibrate Ventures</a>, a four-year-old early-stage venture capital firm backing startups leveraging artificial intelligence and automation, debuted its second fund, a $97 million vehicle that is about 25% higher than its previous fund.</p>
<p>With Calibrate Fund II, the firm has $175 million in assets under management, co-founder and managing partner Jason Schoettler told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The firm raised $80 million for its first fund in 2018. Since then, the firm invested in 17 companies, most notably Built Robotics, Embodied, FarmWise, Soft Robotics, Talage and TruckLabs. Together, those companies raised a collective $425 million.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2249988" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>A few investments have already been made from Calibrate Fund II, but they are unannounced at this time, Schoettler said.</p>
<p>With capital flowing freely lately, Schoettler, who previously worked at Shea Ventures, where he met co-founder and managing partner Kevin Dunlap, shared some insights on what it takes to win deals these days.</p>
<p>“We think domain expertise and experience go a long way to winning deals,” Schoettler said. “For example, having a network and infrastructure to help get introductions to customers or build out the board and strategic financing.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Dunlap, a mechanical engineer who previously worked for companies like Ring and Solar City, believes that companies like Ring or portfolio company Soft Robotics would not exist 10 years ago and make economic sense. It is all possible now that sensors are cheaper and computing power has increased, he added.</p>
<p>“We have large strategics investing in our companies alongside us, and sometimes after us, which is good,” Dunlap said. “It means we understand the sales cycle and revenue model to generate large returns. We lead with the ability we have to help them sell on the customer and technology side. Our founders also can lean on each other because they are doing similar things, but in different verticals.”</p>
<p>They also say this is lining the firm up to be aggressive as it sees interesting activity around AI and automation. In particular, Schoettler noted that with COVID last year, activity has gone from “zero to warp speed over the past 12 months,” and the firm has been focused on building out an infrastructure around the team and this new fund is its successful fundraising to set it up.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OOkpcXoiZ9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/soft-robotics-raises-another-10m-citing-pandemic-related-demand/">Soft Robotics raises another $10M, citing pandemic-related demand</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Soft Robotics raises another $10M, citing pandemic-related demand&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/soft-robotics-raises-another-10m-citing-pandemic-related-demand/embed/#?secret=OOkpcXoiZ9" data-secret="OOkpcXoiZ9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>As such, Schoettler and Dunlap grew their team in 2021 to meet that demand, adding three new venture partners, including Aimée Leifer, Paolo Pirjanian and Daniel Murray, hired Carrie Zawistowski as vice president of portfolio finance and brought on a firm to manage public relations and marketing for its portfolio companies.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the firm invests across a wide range of industries like education, healthcare, logistics, law, financial services, manufacturing and transportation.</p>
<p>Having mainly focused efforts around computer vision, AI, machine learning and to some extent, robotics, Schoettler and Dunlap say they are often pulled into areas where there are labor balance issues, like agriculture and construction, where labor is hard to find because people are not going into these positions.</p>
<p>Dunlap estimates that some $500 billion will be spent in the next several years on AI and AI implementation. He called out chicken producer Tyson, which announced in November that it would be <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/tyson-foods-plans-spend-over-13-bln-automation-projects-2021-12-09/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">investing $1.3 billion in automating its meat plants</a> over the next three years. Tyson Ventures is also an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/soft-robotics-raises-another-10m-citing-pandemic-related-demand/">investor in portfolio company Soft Robotics</a>.</p>
<p>“We expect real adoption for machine learning and advanced robotics in five to 10 years,” Dunlap added. “Automation is great for anything dirty, dull and dangerous, where it is hard to find people who are excited about taking those opportunities.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xOQP5Y13Bj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/venture-capital-is-going-to-need-a-record-breaking-run-of-ipos-to-clear-its-own-decks/">Venture capital is going to need a record-breaking run of IPOs to clear its own decks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Venture capital is going to need a record-breaking run of IPOs to clear its own decks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/venture-capital-is-going-to-need-a-record-breaking-run-of-ipos-to-clear-its-own-decks/embed/#?secret=xOQP5Y13Bj" data-secret="xOQP5Y13Bj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/calibrate-ventures-raises-97m-for-second-fund-targeting-ai-automation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249988</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Demand Curve: How Ahrefs&#8217; homepage educates prospects to purchase</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/demand-curve-how-ahrefs-homepage-educates-prospects-to-purchase/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/demand-curve-how-ahrefs-homepage-educates-prospects-to-purchase/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 13:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verified Experts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ahrefs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Growth Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This post tears down the homepage of Ahrefs, covering the key sections of a landing page so that you can apply their conversion tactics and copywriting strategies to your startup's homepage.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Joey Noble</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jynble">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joeynoble">Joey Noble</a> is community manager at <a href="https://demandcurve.com/">Demand Curve</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/demand-curve-how-customer-ios-homepage-converts-readers-into-customers/">Demand Curve: How Customer.io&#8217;s homepage converts readers into customers</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/11/demand-curve-how-zapier-acquires-customers-via-its-homepage/">Demand Curve: How Zapier acquires customers via its homepage</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">If you want your homepage to convert, it&#8217;s crucial to ensure that there is minimal confusion and friction for the user.</p>
<p>Conversion can be thought of as a formula: Conversion = Desire &#8211; Labor &#8211; Confusion. Keep this formula in mind when building your website. Your goal is to increase desire while decreasing labor (friction) and confusion. People have short attention spans, so if your homepage is confusing, they&#8217;re going to leave.</p>
<p>This post is going to tear down the homepage of Ahrefs, an all-in-one search engine optimization platform that allows marketers to perform competitive analysis, audit their site&#8217;s search traffic and find keywords that will allow them to rank better on search engines.</p>
<p>This teardown covers all the key sections of a landing page so that you can apply their conversion tactics and copywriting strategies to your startup&#8217;s homepage.</p>
<h2>Capture attention with an objection handler</h2>
<p>The first section of your website that a visitor will see is your above-the-fold (ATF) section. This section is important, because this is your chance to make a good first impression on visitors when they visit your website. If your ATF section is confusing or uninteresting, you risk the visitors leaving and reading nothing else.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>Ahrefs&#8217; ATF section has four pieces that we&#8217;ll dive into individually: the header, call to action, social proof and a subhead.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246578" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246578" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246578" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1.png" alt="Ahrefs' above the fold section has four pieces: header, call-to-action, social proof and a sub-header." width="1024" height="651" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1.png 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1.png?resize=150,95 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1.png?resize=300,191 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1.png?resize=768,489 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1.png?resize=680,433 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/1.png?resize=50,32 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246578" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve<strong><br /></strong></p></div></p>
<h2>A header that tackles the most common objection</h2>
<p>Your header must hook readers with your most compelling feature framed as a bold claim. When you handle your target audience&#8217;s biggest objection, it can serve as the bold claim that gets visitors to continue reading.</p>
<p>Ahrefs uses a common header template: Get [benefit] without [problem]. In this case, it&#8217;s flipped: With [product] you won&#8217;t have [problem] in order to get [benefit].</p>
<p>Ahrefs knows a lot of businesses need SEO but don&#8217;t have the time or resources to build expertise. So, Ahrefs tells their visitors you don&#8217;t have to be an SEO professional to use its product.</p>
<p>The underlying benefit here is that users will get more search traffic and rank higher on the web while not needing SEO expertise to do so.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2246582" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2246582" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2246582" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/2.png" alt="Ahrefs tells their visitors you don't have to be an SEO pro to use their product." width="1024" height="792" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/2.png 1218w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/2.png?resize=150,116 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/2.png?resize=300,232 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/2.png?resize=768,594 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/2.png?resize=680,526 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/2.png?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2246582" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h2>Make your call to action stand out</h2>
<p>Calls to action (CTAs) are the only way to move visitors down the relationship funnel. It&#8217;s nearly impossible to get someone to sign up without encouraging them to do so. Visitors instinctively don&#8217;t want to sign up.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/demand-curve-how-ahrefs-homepage-educates-prospects-to-purchase/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246493</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto mayors on the rise</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/crypto-mayors-on-the-rise/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/crypto-mayors-on-the-rise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 13:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decentralized Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital currencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[francis suarez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tampa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One mayor is certainly notable, and two mayors a pattern. But with more than three mayors on board the bitcoin bandwagon, it’s clearly a trend.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Brooks Rainwater</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/BrooksRainwater">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Brooks Rainwater is the director of the <a href="http://www.nlc.org/find-city-solutions/city-solutions-and-applied-research">Center for City Solutions and Applied Research at the National League of Cities</a>.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/28/autonomous-vehicles-make-congestion-pricing-even-more-critical/">Autonomous vehicles make congestion pricing even more critical</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/17/cities-that-didnt-win-hq2-shouldnt-be-counted-out/">Cities that didn’t win HQ2 shouldn’t be counted out</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Bitcoin and broader cryptocurrency prices have skyrocketed in 2021. Stories abound of pandemic-era crypto millionaires that have struck it rich in the sector.</p>
<p>The cryptocurrency narrative is a private sector one by design. Bitcoin and other crypto projects began with the intent to create an immutable digital currency that is decentralized and could not be affected by government monetary policy.</p>
<p>That said, in recent years — as the marketplace crested $2 trillion in value — the public sector has increasingly taken a closer look, with nascent regulations emerging in some countries, outright bans in others and even wholesale adoption in a few.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2249352" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The viewpoints of national governments — which print their own fiat currency — compared to some local governments can vary tremendously. Increasingly, there are a group of cities that see cryptocurrency as an opportunity to leverage the technology, financial and economic development potential of this new industry.</p>
<p>Certainly, bitcoin, blockchain and non-fungible tokens (NFTs) are not terms one often hears around City Hall. But increasingly, they are in cities like Miami, Tampa, New York and Jackson, Tennessee, as the mayors of these cities laid down a marker for entering the cryptocurrency realm. As an example of their intention, mayors from all four cities recently agreed to take one or more of their paychecks in bitcoin.</p>
<p>As many stories on city innovation do, it starts with one local official leading on the topic and laying down a challenge to his fellow mayors. In this case, Miami Mayor Francis Suarez <a href="https://twitter.com/FrancisSuarez/status/1455562833006059528" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tweeted out</a> that he would take his next paycheck in bitcoin. Incoming New York City Mayor Eric Adams sought to one-up him, saying he would take <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/04/new-york-mayor-elect-eric-adams-to-take-first-3-paychecks-in-bitcoin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">multiple paychecks</a> in bitcoin.</p>
<p>“Education is the best way to dispel the fear and misunderstanding surrounding crypto, and I believe that’s the root of what Mayor Adams and I are doing,&#8221; Suarez said. &#8220;If people see us dive in headfirst, perhaps it’ll give them the confidence to dip their toes in the water.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>One mayor is certainly notable, and two mayors a pattern. But with more than three mayors on board the bitcoin bandwagon, it’s clearly a trend.</p>
<p>Mayor Scott Conger of Jackson, Tennessee — one of the youngest mayors the city of about 70,000 people has elected — joined the friendly challenge and said he would take a paycheck in bitcoin, too. Conger and Suarez went back and forth <a href="https://twitter.com/MayorConger/status/1456411229220708356" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Twitter</a> about this — and Conger has been innovating in the crypto space in his small city.</p>
<p>Not to be outdone, another Florida mayor jumped into the mix as well. Mayor Jane Castor of Tampa made the announcement that she would take a paycheck in bitcoin at a cryptocurrency conference in her city only a few days later. With Tampa recently crowned a <a href="https://www.fox13news.com/news/tampa-tops-forbes-list-of-emerging-tech-cities" target="_blank" rel="noopener">top emerging tech city</a> and hosting 25% of tech jobs in the state, the alignment with this emerging field squares up.</p>
<p>Conger noted that what Suarez is doing doesn’t need to just be a big-city phenomenon &#8212; it can work in communities of all sizes. Seeing the interesting things happening on technology and cryptocurrency in larger cities, he thought about how that could translate in a place like Jackson — and like any good mayor, clearly had his eye toward the economic development potential for his city.</p>
<p>“It doesn’t have to be in just Miami or a large city,” he said. “Jackson has the opportunity to do that. I mean, we were the first city in the state of Tennessee to have gig fiber internet to the home. Why can’t we be the first to adopt newer technology as it comes along?”</p>
<p>Jackson has <a href="https://www.jacksonsun.com/story/news/local/2015/06/27/jackson-one-seven-tennessee-recognized-gig-city/29413037/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">super-fast internet service</a><span style="text-decoration: underline;">,</span> which allows it to compete broadly for companies in the tech sector. As a result, its mayor sees cryptocurrency and decentralized finance (DeFi) companies as a natural outgrowth for the community.</p>
<p>“The space is wide open,” Conger noted. As the retail industry shrinks and the amount of physical space existing businesses use is reduced, the mayor sees an opportunity. “As DeFi, crypto and tech companies start popping up, they are going to need a place to go.”</p>
<p>Driving home the advantage he sees in his smaller community, Conger added, “Why go to a city with millions of people when you can come to a city with 70,000 people?”</p>
<p>This focus on economic development is one shared by all four of these mayors, as well as other local leaders dipping their toe in the waters of cryptocurrency, as they think about the future of jobs in their cities. In Miami, this feels core to the mayor’s effort within the cryptocurrency space.</p>
<p>“Miami is built on a common theme, the people who come here are sick and tired of being left behind — or worse — being persecuted by their governments, and they come here in search of a better life and in return, they make our city better,&#8221; Suarez said. &#8220;The Miami Movement is about bringing high-quality, high-paying jobs to our city — I want to prepare Miami for the future and to create the next generation of leaders right here at home.&#8221;</p>
<p>This focus on talent attraction and talent retention is big in Miami and in so many other cities throughout the country. Whether in tech or finance — and in this case, crypto as a blend of both — Miami is seeking to grow these sectors.</p>
<p>“The Miami Movement is a result of a perfect storm of conditions that resulted in people flocking to Miami, but the push for a growing finance and tech sector has been decades in the making,” Suarez said. “It wasn’t as ‘spur of the moment’ as many people think it was. Attracting innovation and growth to our city is a tremendous benefit to every single Miamian.”</p>
<p>We can only imagine what a place like New York City may be able to do within the cryptocurrency sector due to its long-standing supremacy in finance and the increasing strength of its tech sector. Likewise, Tampa has been on the rise for many years now, and with its rising ability to attract tech talent and economic potential, we may see some interesting differentiation start to present itself as the cryptocurrency sector matures.</p>
<p>Which will be the first city to truly make a strong play in the metaverse or perhaps even mint a municipal NFT? With this kind of leadership happening at ground level, we will know soon enough as mayors embrace the growth of this digital industry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/crypto-mayors-on-the-rise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newly minted unicorn Tackle plans to use $100 million Series C to accelerate the future of software sales</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/newly-minted-unicorn-tackle-plans-to-use-100-million-series-c-to-accelerate-the-future-of-software-sales/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/newly-minted-unicorn-tackle-plans-to-use-100-million-series-c-to-accelerate-the-future-of-software-sales/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Heim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 13:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a16z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS Marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bottom up sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud marketplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coatue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GCP Marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low code development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martin casado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red hat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tackle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tackle.io]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tackle.io, a startup that helps software companies sell through cloud marketplaces such as AWS's, raised a $100 million Series C funding round co-led by Coatue and a16z at a $1.25 billion valuation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://tackle.io">Tackle.io</a>, an Idaho-based startup that helps software companies sell through cloud marketplaces such as AWS&#8217;s, announced today it has raised a $100 million Series C funding round. Co-led by<a href="https://www.coatue.com/"> Coatue</a> and <a href="https://a16z.com/">Andreessen Horowitz</a>, the round also saw participation from <a href="https://www.bvp.com/">Bessemer Venture Partners</a>.</p>
<p>Bringing Tackle&#8217;s total funding to $148 million, the Series C turned Tackle into a unicorn with a $1.25 billion valuation. A document sent to the press describes this figure as &#8220;a significant uplift&#8221; from its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/tackle-nabs-35m-series-b-to-help-companies-navigate-cloud-marketplaces/">$35 million Series B</a>, whose valuation wasn&#8217;t disclosed when it took place a mere nine months ago.</p>
<p>Tackle says it plans to use its new funding to accelerate the execution of its product roadmap, scale its go-to-market (GTM) teams, expand its global reach, and continue to innovate. That&#8217;s quite a list; with $100 million it may be possible.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250234" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>But since the list sounds a bit vague to us, let&#8217;s dive deeper into what Tackle is tackling.</p>
<p>As often, the company started with entrepreneurs scratching their own itch, my colleague Ron Miller reported last March. Tackle&#8217;s co-founder and CTO &#8220;Dillon Woods says that at previous jobs, he found that it took several months with a couple of engineers dedicated to the task to get a product onto the AWS marketplace, and he noticed that it was a similar set of tasks each time.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tackle solved that by coming up with a solution for independent software vendors (ISVs) to list onto major cloud marketplaces: those of Amazon&#8217;s AWS, Microsoft&#8217;s Azure, Google Cloud Platform, and IBM-owned Red Hat.</p>
<p>You might not have realized it yet, but &#8220;cloud marketplaces aren’t just one more channel for selling software – it’s becoming <em>the</em> channel,&#8221; a16z&#8217;s Martin Casado <a href="https://a16z.com/2021/03/09/investing-in-tackle/">wrote</a> last March. The investor joined Tackle&#8217;s board when his firm led the startup&#8217;s Series B round, and sees it as a category leader. &#8220;Tackle is the leading player for enabling companies to sell software through the cloud,&#8221; he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>At the time, Casado referred to Tackle having more than 200 customers. That number has now grown to 350, according to the company. This includes companies such as AppDynamics, Auth0, CrowdStrike, Dell, Gitlab, HashiCorp, Looker, McAfee, NewRelic, Okta, PagerDuty, Talend, and VMware, it says.</p>
<p>The clients range from startups &#8212; most of them &#8212; to corporations, but they have one thing in common: They make software. So why would they use a &#8216;zero engineering&#8217; solution to build and maintain marketplace integrations? <a href="https://tackle.io/blog/tackle-series-b-funding/">According</a> to Tackle, it&#8217;s because &#8220;software companies shouldn’t have to build software in order to sell software&#8221; – their human resources are better used elsewhere.</p>
<p>Says Tackle customer Robson Grieve, CMO at low-code platform OutSystems: &#8220;The Tackle Platform makes leveraging Marketplaces a business decision versus a distraction to product and engineering teams.&#8221;</p>
<p>This business decision – selling via cloud marketplaces – is increasingly common.</p>
<p>In its <a href="https://www.bvp.com/atlas/state-of-the-cloud-2021#Cloud-Marketplaces">State of the Cloud 2021 report</a>, Bessemer highlighted the adoption of cloud marketplaces as one of the top 3 best practices for companies to implement for GTM in the New Normal. The VC firm has backed Tackle since its seed round, and led its <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tackleio-secures-a-7-25m-series-a-funding-led-by-bessemer-venture-partners-301074096.html">$7.25 million Series A round</a> in 2020, with partner Michael Droesch joining the startup&#8217;s board at that time.</p>
<p>Fellow VC firm Battery Ventures, which to our knowledge hasn&#8217;t invested in Tackle, also backs up that view. In its <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/Battery_Ventures/state-of-the-opencloud-2020-238800487">State of the Open Cloud 2020 report</a>, it had listed &#8220;leverag[ing]&#8221; new cloud marketplaces to discover and reach customers as an operational best practice.</p>
<p>In its own <a href="https://tackle.io/resources/reports/state-of-cloud-marketplaces/">State of the Cloud Marketplaces Report</a>, Tackle heard from 67% of survey respondents that they planned to invest more in Marketplaces as a go-to-market avenue in 2022. The report also predicts that Cloud Marketplaces will exceed $10 billion in throughput by the end of 2023, and $50 billion by the end of 2025.</p>
<p>There are several drivers behind the rise of cloud marketplaces, but the gist is that B2B sales increasingly look like B2C sales – which is why investors are betting on Tackle. &#8220;We believe Tackle is well-positioned to help all sellers accelerate their shift toward Cloud Marketplaces and digital selling,&#8221; said Coatue general partner David Schneider, who will join Tackle’s board as an observer following the round.</p>
<p>Of course, we&#8217;d like to know more about Tackle&#8217;s revenue, but it is only saying that it doubled its ARR in 2021. &#8220;This has been a tremendous year for Tackle,&#8221; said CEO John Jahnke, as the company now &#8220;expects to see explosive growth&#8221; in 2022.</p>
<p>One thing that will grow for sure is its team: It increased from 56 to 160 employees this year, and the startup is planning to double its headcount in 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/newly-minted-unicorn-tackle-plans-to-use-100-million-series-c-to-accelerate-the-future-of-software-sales/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Runwise saves money and the planet by educating dumb buildings</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/runwise-raises-money-to-save-money/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/runwise-raises-money-to-save-money/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 13:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[initialized capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[notation capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Runwise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[susa ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2246532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the U.S., around 13% of greenhouse gases are spewed out of commercial and residential buildings. You&#8217;d be forgiven for scratching your head and asking why. If you tour a typical New York building, you&#8217;ll often find that the tech that runs deep in the underbellies of the brick-clad behemoths looks like the 1960s and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the U.S., <a href="https://www.epa.gov/ghgemissions/sources-greenhouse-gas-emissions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">around 13% of greenhouse gases</a> are spewed out of commercial and residential buildings. You&#8217;d be forgiven for scratching your head and asking why. If you tour a typical New York building, you&#8217;ll often find that the tech that runs deep in the underbellies of the brick-clad behemoths looks like the 1960s and smells even worse. <a href="https://www.runwise.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Runwise</a> is already in 4,000-ish buildings, and today announced it raised $11 million to put its tech into many thousand more. The company has a winning win/win combination of saving landlords money while giving planet earth a break in the process.</p>
<p>Runwise&#8217;s selling point is taking ancient tech that often operates on on/off switches or timers rather than sensors, and sprinkling enough technology on top to ensure that buildings aren&#8217;t heating more than they need to. The company has developed wireless sensors that operate on batteries with a 10-year battery life, and a controller computer that takes charge over the building&#8217;s boilers and heating. It claims that the average time to recuperate the cost of the install (in the form of reduced heating bills) is around nine months.</p>
<p>&#8220;Five or six years ago nobody gave a shit about the environment, and we&#8217;d be like, &#8216;but it&#8217;ll have a huge impact!&#8217;. They&#8217;d ask us about the bottom line, and suddenly we&#8217;d have a conversation going,&#8221; Lee Hoffman, COO and co-founder of Runwise explains. &#8220;Our vision long term is if you run buildings better you can change the carbon profile and affordability of pretty much every city out there. That&#8217;s really our goal; there are 12 million buildings in the United States. We&#8217;re in 4,000 today, there&#8217;s really no reason we shouldn&#8217;t be in all of them.&#8221;</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2246532" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The company has been bootstrapping for a decade, with some impressive results: its tech is already available in buildings owned by some of the largest real estate operators in the country, including Related, Blackstone, Lefrak, Equity Residential, Douglas Elliman and Fairstead. Runwise claims more than 300,000 people live and work in the 4,000 or so buildings it operates. It <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">decided it&#8217;s time to kick the company into a phase of hyper growth. It raised $11 million from </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://initialized.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Initialized Capital</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://susaventures.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Susa Ventures</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> and </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://notation.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Notation Capital</a>,<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> with participation from </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://nextview.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NextView Ventures</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> and several angels.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Most buildings in New York &#8212; and pretty much the entire country and the world &#8212; run on controls that were designed in the 1960s and 70s, made by a handful of companies. If you go into a brand-new Bank of America high-rise glass tower, it has a control box that has a fancy digital display, and it&#8217;s literally inside the same control from 1960s or 70s,&#8221; Hoffman explains, and gets a little animated in his incredulity. &#8220;It runs what&#8217;s called an outdoor reset, which is basically a static Excel table. If it&#8217;s heating this many minutes, turn on the heat. If this is the temperature outside, do this. It has no idea what&#8217;s going on inside the building. It&#8217;s all hardcoded. It&#8217;s completely bonkers. And this is controlling millions of dollars of energy spend in almost every building!&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/runwise-raises-money-to-save-money/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2246532</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Next-day package delivery startup Veho valued at $1B following $125M Series A</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/next-day-package-delivery-veho-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/next-day-package-delivery-veho-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bling Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Construct Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[distribution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fontinalis partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industry Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Itamar Zur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kyle Doherty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Last mile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Origin Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[package delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[packaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rachel Holt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retailers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart GoLocal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Veho's technology matches package delivery demand with qualified driver partners and lets customers know the actual time of delivery and even communicates when the driver is headed their way.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://shipveho.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Veho</a>, a startup applying technology to next-day package delivery, aims to solve the last mile of delivery — how packages get from fulfillment centers to the customer’s door. It also wants to do it with a unique flair: providing transparency into deliveries that starts with the option of when, where and how customers want their packages delivered and then real-time communication throughout the whole process.</p>
<p>Since raising its seed round in the summer of 2020, New York-based Veho has grown 40 times in revenue, while also increasing its employee count from 15 to 400, Veho co-founder and CEO Itamar Zur told TechCrunch.</p>
<p>It is already working in 14 U.S. markets, but plans to grow to 50 markets by the end of 2022. To do that, and invest in technology development, growing the team and introducing and scaling its doorstep returns program, the company announced $125 million in Series A funding that valued the company at $1 billion.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2249998" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>General Catalyst led the round and was joined by Construct Capital, led by Rachel Holt, Bling Capital, Industry Ventures, Fontinalis Partners and Origin Ventures. The latest funding round gives Veho a total of $130 million raised to date, Zur said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="D09le0JrZf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/walmart-announces-golocal-a-last-mile-delivery-service-for-other-retailers/">Walmart announces GoLocal, a last-mile delivery service for other retailers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Walmart announces GoLocal, a last-mile delivery service for other retailers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/walmart-announces-golocal-a-last-mile-delivery-service-for-other-retailers/embed/#?secret=D09le0JrZf" data-secret="D09le0JrZf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>You might be asking yourself why in the world a young company would take on so much capital up front like that, but Zur responded that Veho is “a substantial platform, not a small operation at this point, and we want to maintain fast growth.”</p>
<p>“We have an opportunity in the midst of the biggest e-commerce revolution, and after growing fast through the pandemic, that is not going away,” he added. “Customer experience is changing in front of our eyes, and other than speed and communication, what brands want to provide is visibility and data. We think it is the perfect time to take in more capital to continue to grow at a phenomenal rate.”</p>
<p>Sure, Amazon has a bear hug on about 50% of the last-mile market, and there is no debate that they are doing well here. Zur doesn’t deny it either, but he does see an opportunity to offer the same kind of delivery service for the 50% of e-commerce businesses that want to offer something faster than seven to 10 business days.</p>
<p>Veho&#8217;s technology matches package delivery demand with qualified driver partners and can then let customers know the actual time of day when they will receive their package and even when the driver is headed their way. It is also making it possible to reschedule a delivery in real time, change an address or provide personal delivery instructions.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2250030" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2250030" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2250030" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg" alt="Veho" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg 4000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Veho-Team-October-2021.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2250030" class="wp-caption-text">The Veho team. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Veho</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The idea for the company stems from Zur’s own experience. While in business school, he bought a subscription for meal delivery, but his first package never arrived. Zur recalls trying to get in touch with the delivery company, and after waiting for 40 minutes, the call was disconnected. As a result, he canceled the subscription, which is not unlike what other consumers do as they become more intolerant of receiving packages late or not at all.</p>
<p>“In an increasingly competitive e-commerce space, there are tons of companies looking for similarly fast delivery as Amazon, but lack the scale to do it,” Zur said. “Veho levels the playing field for these brands. The biggest missed opportunities are connecting the dots between the pre-packaged experience and delivery to help brands build more loyalty and for people to stay with them longer, to buy more and buy more frequently.”</p>
<p>Veho is not alone in trying to solve the last-mile problem, and is among companies around the world also raising capital for their approaches. For example, in the past six months, we saw <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/15/e-bike-subscription-service-zoomo-raises-60m-series-b-to-disrupt-last-mile-delivery/">Zoomo</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/last-mile-logistics-platform-cargamos-raises-11m-seed-round-to-expand-same-day-delivery/">Cargamos</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/last-mile-robotic-delivery-firm-coco-raises-36m/">Coco</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/22/deliverr-inventory-customers/">Deliverr</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/bringg-nabs-100m-at-a-1b-valuation-for-a-last-mile-delivery-platform-for-retailers/">Bringg</a> announce new rounds. Walmart also introduced its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/walmart-announces-golocal-a-last-mile-delivery-service-for-other-retailers/">Walmart GoLocal program</a> in the summer for other retailers to tap into the retail giant’s delivery network.</p>
<p>Zur doesn’t see Veho competing against the likes of Deliverr or some of those others, but does see the company competing with the national shipping companies. He believes their technology was designed for “an older world” that didn’t include e-commerce, and that is what separates Veho from them — that it was built “entirely around the needs of e-commerce customers” with a vision of how that sector will grow over the next decade.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EzuILyGbfH"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/last-mile-logistics-platform-cargamos-raises-11m-seed-round-to-expand-same-day-delivery/">Last-mile logistics platform Cargamos raises $11M seed round to expand same-day delivery</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Last-mile logistics platform Cargamos raises $11M seed round to expand same-day delivery&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/22/last-mile-logistics-platform-cargamos-raises-11m-seed-round-to-expand-same-day-delivery/embed/#?secret=EzuILyGbfH" data-secret="EzuILyGbfH" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/at-9-29-cagr-last-mile-delivery-market-size-is-expected-to-reach-usd-200-42-bn-in-2027--says-brandessence-market-research-301387705.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">global last-mile delivery market</a> was valued at around $108 billion in 2020 and is set to grow by <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/now/last-mile-delivery-market-grow-143000535.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$146.96 billion in the next four years</a>, with North America contributing to 39% of that growth, according to technology and research company Technavio.</p>
<p>With purchases shifting to e-commerce, the logistics and parcel delivery sectors are racing to keep up with demands. They’ve also been met with major setbacks in the past few years. From the aptly dubbed “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/10/16/technology/holiday-shipageddon.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shipaggedon</a>” during the holiday season in 2020, to manufacturing and shipping delays for everything from <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/30/developers-and-designers-can-help-businesses-manage-the-semiconductor-shortage/">semiconductors</a> to <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2021/11/5/22764088/supply-chain-shipping-delays-logistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener">getting a ship into the port</a>.</p>
<p>Veho wants to make the delivery experience so awesome that it facilitates trust between the consumer and e-commerce company so that consumers return to order again. Zur notes this is already happening, citing that its customers, which range from selling apparel and accessories to food and packaged goods, saw a 20% increase in customer repurchase, 40% increase in customer lifetime value and an eight-point increase in net promoter score compared to customers who received their box from a traditional shipping company.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Kyle Doherty, managing director at General Catalyst, said there is room for more companies going after an <a href="https://www.the-future-of-commerce.com/2021/08/03/post-pandemic-e-commerce/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$800 billion e-commerce market</a>, of which <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/272391/us-retail-e-commerce-sales-forecast/#:~:text=The%20eCommerce%20market%20encompasses%20the,such%20as%20smartphones%20and%20tablets." target="_blank" rel="noopener">half stems from the U.S</a>., and that is forecasted overall to grow around $100 billion each year.</p>
<p>Like Zur, Doherty had his own frustrations receiving packages at his home in San Francisco, which he said is notorious for <a href="https://www.kron4.com/news/bay-area/san-francisco-2nd-worst-u-s-city-for-package-theft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">having problems with package thefts</a>.</p>
<p>“You feel helpless and that you’ve lost control of the situation,” he added. “We have had a front-row seat to the dramatic acceleration in the use of e-commerce and a stressed supply chain. We had a belief that computer technology would enable logistics providers to provide a better experience. When I was introduced to Ita, I got it instantly. He also has empathy for merchants and consumers about the consumer experience, and that stood out on many fronts.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GbxmUqehDq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/last-mile-delivery-in-latin-america-is-ready-to-take-off/">Last-mile delivery in Latin America is ready to take off</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Last-mile delivery in Latin America is ready to take off&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/22/last-mile-delivery-in-latin-america-is-ready-to-take-off/embed/#?secret=GbxmUqehDq" data-secret="GbxmUqehDq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/next-day-package-delivery-veho-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249998</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech startup LiveFlow raises $3.5M Seed  to automate financial data flows</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/fintech-startup-liveflow-raises-3-5m-seed-to-automate-financial-data-flows/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/fintech-startup-liveflow-raises-3-5m-seed-to-automate-financial-data-flows/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bradley Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[managing partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mattias Ljungman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moonfire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moonfire Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oliver jung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real time data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SeedCamp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fintech startup LiveFlow has raised a $3.5M Seed round which was led by Moonfire Ventures with backing from Y Combinator, Seedcamp and WndrCo.  Also participating was Victor Jacobsson, co-founder of Klarna; Bradley Horowitz, former VP Product at Google; Oliver Jung, former VP International Expansion at AirBnB, Phillip Chambers, Peakon founder &#38; CEO, and others. LiveFlow [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Fintech startup <a href="https://www.liveflow.io/">LiveFlow</a> has raised a $3.5M Seed round which was led by Moonfire Ventures with backing from Y Combinator, Seedcamp and WndrCo.  Also participating was Victor Jacobsson, co-founder of Klarna; Bradley Horowitz, former VP Product at Google; Oliver Jung, former VP International Expansion at AirBnB, Phillip Chambers, Peakon founder &amp; CEO, and others.</p>
<p>LiveFlow allows companies to sync real-time data from their accounting services, banks, and payment platforms into their custom reports, thereby automating workflows, consolidating company accounts, and allowing more company-wide collaboration.</p>
<p>Founded almost a year ago by CEO Lasse Kalkar and COO Anita Koimur (ex-Revolut), and CTO Evan O’Brien (ex-Web Summit), LiveFlow has most of its customers in the US, such as accounting firms like Ascent CFO, CFO Minded and TinyCFO &#8211; as well as a handful of startups from Y Combinator.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250106" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Lasse Kalkar, co-founder and CEO, LiveFlow said: “In my previous companies, I felt the frustration of manually pulling together financial reports. That&#8217;s where the idea for LiveFlow came from.”</p>
<p>Mattias Ljungman, founder and managing partner at Moonfire Ventures said: “LiveFlow provides a critical service by automating and streamlining the reporting process, giving businesses the visibility and real-time information they need to better manage their business.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/fintech-startup-liveflow-raises-3-5m-seed-to-automate-financial-data-flows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250106</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Woola raises €2.5M Seed led by Future Ventures to replace bubble wrap with wool</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/woola-raises-e2-5m-seed-led-by-future-ventures-to-replace-bubble-wrap-with-wool/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/woola-raises-e2-5m-seed-led-by-future-ventures-to-replace-bubble-wrap-with-wool/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 09:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blue bottle coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bubble wrap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estonia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[packaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pipedrive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steve jurvetson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veriff]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2250179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some 55 billion parcels are shipped in bubble wrap every year. Plastic bubble wrap is reliant on fossil fuels and 98% of plastic packaging is single-use. You can imagine the adverse environmental impact of all this plastic. The founders of Woola were running an online e-commerce store and saw the packaging problem first-hand. The lack [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Some 55 billion parcels are shipped in bubble wrap every year. Plastic bubble wrap is reliant on fossil fuels and 98% of plastic packaging is single-use. You can imagine the adverse environmental impact of all this plastic.</p>
<p>The founders of <a href="http://woola.io">Woola</a> were running an online e-commerce store and saw the packaging problem first-hand. The lack of options in sustainable and scalable protective packaging led to them re-discovering wool — an unused resource that is elastic and regulates temperatures and humidity.</p>
<p>The result was their startup, which uses leftover sheep wool to replace bubble wrap. These wool-based packages can be reused, repurposed, or returned by the end-user, with the ultimate goal of making the solution ‘closed-loop’ so nothing goes to waste.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2250179" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Woola opened a production facility in Estonia and launched its first product in December 2020. Wool envelopes were the first products to hit the market. It’s now expanding to the UK, France and Germany. The next product rolling out in January 2022 is targeted at beverage companies.</p>
<p>They’ve now a raised €2.5M Seed round led by Future Ventures. Future is joined by co-investors Kaarel Kotkas (CEO at Veriff), Janer Gorohhov (Co-founder at Veriff), Kristina Lilleõis (VP of People at Veriff), Zem Joaquin (founder of Near Future Summit), Bryan Meehan (executive chair of Blue Bottle Coffee). Woola’s previous investors include the co-founders of Pipedrive, Bolt and the angel fund Lemonade Stand.</p>
<p>“Bubble wrap has been dominating the packaging industry for ages – but its decline is inevitable,” said Woola’s CEO and co-founder Anna-Liisa Palatu. “The industry is broken for two reasons: fossil fuel reliance and single-use mindset. We need to get rid of both to make packaging more sustainable.” She is joined by co-founders Jevgeni Sirai and Katrin Kabun.</p>
<p>Steve Jurvetson from Future Ventures commented: “While e-commerce is booming, single-use plastic packaging is out of control. Woola can replace it all with beautiful envelopes made from scrap wool that would otherwise be burned or buried. The world needs sustainable alternatives to the petrochemical economy for a healthier future.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Sheep wool is an unused resource – more than 200,000 tonnes of wool is thrown away in Europe yearly. Woola says this is enough to fulfill 120% of the global bubble wrap demand.</p>
<p>The startup will compete with whitelabel plastic bubble wrap and alternatives like Ranpak and S-Packaging.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/woola-raises-e2-5m-seed-led-by-future-ventures-to-replace-bubble-wrap-with-wool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2250179</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Africa&#8217;s Planet42 gets $30M for its car subscription service, Mexico expansion</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/south-africas-planet42-gets-30m-for-its-car-subscription-service-mexico-expansion/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/south-africas-planet42-gets-30m-for-its-car-subscription-service-mexico-expansion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 08:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autochek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car subscription]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markus Villig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Naspers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planet42]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture debt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2249946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Planet42, a South Africa-based car subscription company that buys used cars from dealerships and rents to customers via a subscription model, has raised $30 million in equity and debt. The investment &#8212; which co-founder and CEO Eerik Oja called a bridge round &#8212; is a prequel to a larger Series A round next year. It [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https://planet42.com/za/&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiIyM3x1vP0AhVKx4UKHdfdBWUQFnoECAUQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw3MVfxIL6pZDb9Lyzcd7i8V">Planet42</a>, a South Africa-based car subscription company that buys used cars from dealerships and rents to customers via a subscription model, has raised $30 million in equity and debt.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The investment &#8212; which co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https://za.linkedin.com/in/eerik&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjV-56z1_P0AhVF14UKHXxhDg8Qjjh6BAgDEAE&amp;usg=AOvVaw2BvAbzxJKTZ_UKLgOTiCX1">Eerik Oja</a> called a bridge round &#8212; is a prequel to a larger Series A round next year. It comprises</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> $6 million equity and $24 million in debt financing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company raised $2.4 million in a seed round in June 2020 and followed it with $10 million in debt from emerging markets-focused <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/12/emerging-markets-lender-lendable-seeks-100m-to-fund-fintech-companies/amp/&amp;ved=2ahUKEwi47a7L1_P0AhUkxIUKHWjwC3sQFnoECBgQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw3MmURVyrRSRpMST5nAYFVz">venture debt fund Lendable</a> in December. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fund doubled its participation in this recently raised debt round at $20 million, while other investors completed the rest</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2249946" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Naspers, through its early-stage investment vehicle, <a href="https://www.naspers.com/foundry">Naspers Foundry</a>, led the equity round with $3.4 million. Existing investors include Change Ventures, the lead investor from Planet42’s seed round, as well as Startup Wise Guys, Martin and Markus Villig of Bolt, and Ragnar Sass of Pipedrive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Planet42, though based in South Africa, has Estonian roots due to the founders’ heritage: Oja and CFO <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https://ee.linkedin.com/in/marten-orgna&amp;ved=2ahUKEwixy86k2PP0AhVBzRoKHc3aCrcQjjh6BAgIEAE&amp;usg=AOvVaw1u7QGEe_NBaeXmQ_gVyHT_">Marten Orgna</a> founded the company in 2017</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. In an interview, Oja mentioned that they created the car subscription model to cater to private individuals ignored by South African banks when they need vehicle financing</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our car subscription [model] is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">socially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> inclusive. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For us, the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">differentiating factor is our customers would not have a car without us,” Oja said, adding that because the company is buying second-hand cars, the unit cost is lower compared to a subscription model that purchases new cars.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It can be challenging to get a personal car in most emerging markets, especially if one’s income isn’t stable. And without a good credit history, lenders tend to ignore people with bad credit or give them unfavorable interest rates for vehicle financing.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Planet42 is one of the few upstarts focused on the African market tackling this inequality via a car subscription offering</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The company claims to use proprietary scoring algorithms superior to traditional credit scores in assessing risk in underbanked customer segments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has over 700 dealerships. And with its algorithms, customers can find out what budget suits them and choose new or pre-owned cars from Planet42’s dealerships network.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After that, Planet42 buys the car and rents it out to the customer on a subscription basis. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Planet42 claims that of all the customers served so far, 89% would have had no other means of gaining access to a personal vehicle</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’ve gotten so good with our scoring that we can now enable the customers who couldn’t get bank financing to get a brand new car</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We have figured out a way how to do it </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">sustainably</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that we can put entry-level brand new cars in the hands of the same target market and customers who are </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">unfairly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ignored by banks,” the chief executive said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Four years later and $50 million in equity and debt raised later, Planet42 has listed more than 7,000 cars to customers in South Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This number was 3,000 when Oja spoke with TechCrunch in March, and he noted that the company grew 25% month on month in 2021</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2250128" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2250128" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2250128" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Planet42-founders-Marten-Orgna-and-Eerik-Oja-1024x684-1.jpg?w=680" alt="Planet42" width="680" height="454" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Planet42-founders-Marten-Orgna-and-Eerik-Oja-1024x684-1.jpg 1024w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Planet42-founders-Marten-Orgna-and-Eerik-Oja-1024x684-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Planet42-founders-Marten-Orgna-and-Eerik-Oja-1024x684-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Planet42-founders-Marten-Orgna-and-Eerik-Oja-1024x684-1.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Planet42-founders-Marten-Orgna-and-Eerik-Oja-1024x684-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Planet42-founders-Marten-Orgna-and-Eerik-Oja-1024x684-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2250128" class="wp-caption-text">Planet42 founders (Marten Orgna and Eerik Oja)</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/tlcom-and-4dx-drive-13-1m-seed-round-to-scale-autocheks-platform-across-africa/amp/&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjN8N7b2PP0AhUNz4UKHZCcCRMQFnoECAQQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw1GUNVVCPpT_9_7zz3tc7iv">Autochek</a> and <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;rct=j&amp;url=https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/09/moove-raises-23m-to-create-flexible-options-for-drivers-to-own-cars-in-africa/amp/&amp;ved=2ahUKEwi1_PT62PP0AhWQyIUKHULNBBUQFnoECAkQAQ&amp;usg=AOvVaw0nri-j9EGOffq93YtdSCj4">Moove</a> are other companies offering similar services in parts of sub-Saharan Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. While Moove focuses on financing ride-hailing cars, Planet42 and Autochek services </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are targeted</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> at private individuals. Planet42 has a cohesive network of automobile industry stakeholders on its platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both Moove and Autochek have made inroads into other African countries after </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">initially</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> launching from Nigeria. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">But for Planet42, the next attractive market lies off the continent. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">just</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> not doing it right now, but we’re not ruling it out for the future,” Oja answered on whether Planet42 would expand into other parts of Africa</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the main reason is market size. South Africa has like 25% of all the passenger cars on the African continent; that means that whatever market we go next in Africa will </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">necessarily</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> be smaller than South Africa. In South Africa, 1.1 million second-hand cars get sold and bought every year. In Mexico, that number is 7 million. So the Mexican market is six times larger than South Africa. So we want to go for the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> big markets.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company said it has bought its first cars for clients in Mexico. Similar challenges stemming from transport inequality abound in the country, where 63% of the population deal with only cash.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But Mexico is one of the few countries Planet42 plans to expand to in the foreseeable future, said Oja, who also said that the company has set up an office and employed two staff.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He said the company hopes to have bought over 1 million cars for its customers across its present and future markets by 2025. Planet42 said it has also made strides in becoming a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/why-south-africa-based-car-subscription-company-planet42-is-going-carbon-neutral/amp/">carbon-neutral company</a> via a wind farm project in Northern Cape, South Africa. The car subscription company financed the farm for months with money from carbon offset credits.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KtLMPP8ILm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/why-south-africa-based-car-subscription-company-planet42-is-going-carbon-neutral/">Why South Africa-based car subscription company Planet42 is going carbon neutral</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why South Africa-based car subscription company Planet42 is going carbon neutral&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/why-south-africa-based-car-subscription-company-planet42-is-going-carbon-neutral/embed/#?secret=KtLMPP8ILm" data-secret="KtLMPP8ILm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/21/south-africas-planet42-gets-30m-for-its-car-subscription-service-mexico-expansion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249946</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
