<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 15:05:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>MoviePass co-founder&#8217;s PreShow Interactive raises $3M to expand into gaming</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/preshow-interactive/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/preshow-interactive/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 15:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PreShow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stacy spikes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PreShow Interactive is giving gamers a new way to earn in-game currency in exchange for watching ads — a concept that&#8217;s become familiar in mobile games but hasn&#8217;t really made much headway on PCs or consoles. The startup is led by MoviePass&#8217; founding CEO Stacy Spikes. When I spoke to Spikes about PreShow two years [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.preshow.co">PreShow Interactive</a> is giving gamers a new way to earn in-game currency in exchange for watching ads — a concept that&#8217;s <a href="https://www.adjust.com/blog/understanding-rewarded-video-ads/">become familiar in mobile games</a> but hasn&#8217;t really made much headway on PCs or consoles.</p>
<p>The startup is led by MoviePass&#8217; founding CEO Stacy Spikes. When <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/21/preshow-kickstarter/">I spoke to Spikes about PreShow two years ago</a>, he was beta testing an app that provided users with free movie tickets in exchange for watching ads. But obviously, theatrical moviegoing has taken a big hit in the past year.</p>
<p>Spikes told me yesterday that he&#8217;d always hoped to bring the PreShow concept to four categories — theatrical movies, gaming, subscription streaming and video on demand — but the pandemic forced the startup to shift focus more quickly than expected and explore what a gaming experience might look like.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The current plans is to launch a new PreShow Interactive app this summer, where viewers can connect their in-game accounts and identify how much virtual currency they want to earn. Then they watch a package of ads and PreShow will automatically transfer the currency to their account — in other words, it&#8217;s buying the currency for them.</p>
<p>Users will have to download a separate app to watch the ads and get the benefits, but Spikes said this is actually better than trying to integrate advertising or branded content into the game itself, which can be a slow process for the developer and the advertiser, while also being distracting for the players. And this means PreShow Interactive should able to support 20,000 games at launch, across PCs, consoles and virtual reality.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145696" style="width: 346px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145696" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2145696" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.jpg?w=336" alt="PreShow Interactive" width="336" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.jpg 701w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.jpg?resize=74,150 74w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.jpg?resize=148,300 148w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.jpg?resize=336,680 336w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.jpg?resize=25,50 25w" sizes="(max-width: 336px) 100vw, 336px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2145696" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PreShow Interactive</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We just didn’t see the purpose of spending the time on integrations when it&#8217;s not really necessary,&#8221; he added. &#8220;Our deal is only with the consumer for their time. We&#8217;re saying, &#8216;This is your time. It has value.'&#8221;</p>
<p>One of the key elements to Preshow&#8217;s approach is technology that can detect when the viewer is actually looking at their phone screen — the ads will stop playing if you turn away. Critics have described this as <a href="https://gizmodo.com/moviepass-co-founders-new-startup-must-be-stopped-1833464132">&#8220;creepy surveillance tech,&#8221;</a> but Spikes claimed that early PreShow users have embraced the approach. He also argued that it&#8217;s more transparent than the data collection and targeting currently driving online advertising.</p>
<p>&#8220;We used to think data was the new oil, but now our feeling is that permission and engagement and attention is the new oil,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>In addition to revealing its new strategy, PreShow is announcing that it has raised $3 million in seed funding led by Harlem Capital, with participation Canaan Partners, Wavemaker Ventures, Front Row Fund, ROC Fund, BK Fulton and Monroe Harris.</p>
<p>And to be clear, Spikes said PreShow isn&#8217;t abandoning theatrical movies. He said that the PreShow app will eventually offer both movie and gaming deals &#8220;under one roof,&#8221; but brands aren&#8217;t currently eager to advertise to moviegoers.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re ready to go when the marketplace is ready to go,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed--video">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="lXn2FUfqia"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/21/preshow-kickstarter/">MoviePass co-founder&#8217;s new startup PreShow gives you free movie tickets for watching ads</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;MoviePass co-founder&#8217;s new startup PreShow gives you free movie tickets for watching ads&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/21/preshow-kickstarter/embed/#?secret=lXn2FUfqia" data-secret="lXn2FUfqia" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/preshow-interactive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145669</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Head, tail, knees and trees (knees and trees)</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/robotics-roundup-9/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/robotics-roundup-9/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plus one robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some fun ones this week, so let’s get all of those pesky business transactions out of the way first, shall we? I mean, not that tens of millions of dollars changing hands for future robotics technology is boring, he said, tugging at his collar for comedic effect. Big raise this week for Plus One Robotics. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Some fun ones this week, so let’s get all of those pesky business transactions out of the way first, shall we? I mean, not that tens of millions of dollars changing hands for future robotics technology is boring, he said, tugging at his collar for comedic effect.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2144464" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144464" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2144464" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/PlusOne-1083-1440x720-1.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="512" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/PlusOne-1083-1440x720-1.jpeg 1440w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/PlusOne-1083-1440x720-1.jpeg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/PlusOne-1083-1440x720-1.jpeg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/PlusOne-1083-1440x720-1.jpeg?resize=768,384 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/PlusOne-1083-1440x720-1.jpeg?resize=680,340 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/PlusOne-1083-1440x720-1.jpeg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2144464" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Plus One Robotics</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Big raise this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/robotic-vision-startup-plus-one-raises-33m/">for Plus One Robotics.</a> The San Antonio-based company raised a healthy $33 million Series B, bringing its total funding above $40 million. The company mostly traffics in the warehouse and logistics space &#8212; obviously a category with a lot of excitement around it after last year’s massive shut down. As many companies have told me, most clients are simply looking for a way to help their footing in the competition against Amazon.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In addition to its massive headcount and seemingly bottomless resources, the e-commerce giant has deployed a huge army of robots in its warehouse. Plus One, for its part, doesn’t make the robots, but rather the vision software that works with them. The company’s product is designed to work across a broad range of robotic arms and grippers, allowing workers to control up to 50 systems at once.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2144666" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144666" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2144666" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg?resize=2048,1153 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/ascend-benefits-3.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2144666" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Roam Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>We’ve talked about exoskeletons quite a bit on these pages, but <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/roam-robotics-introduces-a-smart-knee-brace/">Roam offers</a> an interesting alternative to a number of bigger, bulkier and harder products on the market. The company’s latest device I liken to a standard knee brace, with AI and robotic capabilities that assist with movement. Specifically it helps with things like walking up stairs and standing up from a seated position.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2142990" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/groot-walk-dance.gif" alt="" width="650" height="364" /></p>
<p>And here we have a tiny tree man. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/disney-imagineerings-project-kiwi-is-free-walking-robot-that-will-make-you-believe-in-groot/">Project Kiwi</a> is kind of like Pinocchio if he really leaned into the whole wooden thing in the process of becoming a real boy. Obviously Disney’s going for the (sometimes) littlest Guardian of the Galaxy, Groot, for its latest extremely impressive animatronic.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fTnYVgaIA3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/disney-imagineerings-project-kiwi-is-free-walking-robot-that-will-make-you-believe-in-groot/">Disney Imagineering’s Project Kiwi is a free-walking robot that will make you believe in Groot</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Disney Imagineering’s Project Kiwi is a free-walking robot that will make you believe in Groot&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/disney-imagineerings-project-kiwi-is-free-walking-robot-that-will-make-you-believe-in-groot/embed/#?secret=fTnYVgaIA3" data-secret="fTnYVgaIA3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Matthew was extremely impressed seeing the beautiful little tree guy in action and, living vicariously through some YouTube videos, I definitely have to confirm.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ARiknLTOZs?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>A fun <a href="https://www.cit.cmu.edu/news-events/news/2021/04/16-robotic-tail.html">bit of research out of Carnegie Mellon</a> this week. The latest bit of biomimicry is a bit surprising. Obviously Cheetah has been a big inspiration for a number of quadrupedal robots (MIT in particular has a whole lot going in the Cheetah department). Specifically, though, the CMU researchers are looking at the big cat’s tail. Per CMU:</p>
<blockquote><p>The cheetah’s lightweight furry tail is known as an aerodynamic drag tail; that is, it acts sort of like a parachute. Most robotic tails have high inertia, but the cheetah manages to retain low inertia. Inertia is a physical quality that describes an object’s resistance to changes in motion — high tail inertia means the tail can apply high forces. Aerodynamic tails instead use a different principle — aerodynamic drag — to achieve high forces without a large inertia.</p></blockquote>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AVDSO3sskx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/enhanced-computer-vision-sensors-raise-manufacturing-stakes-for-robots-as-a-service/">Enhanced computer vision, sensors raise manufacturing stakes for robots as a service</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enhanced computer vision, sensors raise manufacturing stakes for robots as a service&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/08/enhanced-computer-vision-sensors-raise-manufacturing-stakes-for-robots-as-a-service/embed/#?secret=AVDSO3sskx" data-secret="AVDSO3sskx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/robotics-roundup-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145385</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ReleaseHub nabs $2.7M seed to give developers on-demand environments</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/releasehub-nabs-2-7m-seed-to-give-developers-on-demand-environments/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/releasehub-nabs-2-7m-seed-to-give-developers-on-demand-environments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 14:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ReleaseHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every developer relies on environments like testing, staging and production as they build software, but building them can be a time-consuming operation. ReleaseHub, an early stage startup that was part of the Y Combinator Winter 2020 cohort, wants to change that by providing a service to make environments available on demand. Today, the company announced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Every developer relies on environments like testing, staging and production as they build software, but building them can be a time-consuming operation. <a href="http://ReleaseHub.com">ReleaseHub</a>, an early stage startup that was part of the Y Combinator Winter 2020 cohort, wants to change that by providing a service to make environments available on demand.</p>
<p>Today, the company announced a $2.7 million seed, and also announced that service is generally available while they were at it. Sequoia led the round with participation from Y Combinator, Rogue VC, Liquid Capital and unnamed angel investors.</p>
<p>Company co-founder and CEO Tommy McClung says that every developer in the world has to use environments in their development workflow, but it remains for the most part a manual process.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;All of those environments are incredibly difficult to build. So the problem we&#8217;re solving is the ability to create those on demand. Instead of having to have a DevOps team that is responsible for managing, creating and maintaining them, the software does that and you can instantaneously create them,&#8221; McClung told me.</p>
<p>The service is integrated into GitHub and BitBucket, so you can build the environments on the fly as you need them based on templates for the various type. &#8220;The real value that we&#8217;re bringing to the table here is that we&#8217;re bringing that together in an almost virtualized way so that you can reproduce these environments on demand,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>McClung who has been working in technology for over 20 years says this is a problem he&#8217;s seen over and over again at the various companies he&#8217;s worked at over the years. After running engineering at TrueCar, his most recent company, he decided to build a startup to solve the problem once and for all.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Qnd2i1hAqA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/featurepeek-moves-beyond-y-combinator-with-1-8m-seed/">FeaturePeek moves beyond Y Combinator with $1.8M seed</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;FeaturePeek moves beyond Y Combinator with $1.8M seed&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/05/13/featurepeek-moves-beyond-y-combinator-with-1-8m-seed/embed/#?secret=Qnd2i1hAqA" data-secret="Qnd2i1hAqA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>He notes that this is the second time he&#8217;s been a YC company and while the size and scope of the operation has changed since he last participated in 2009, the process remains much the same. For starters, there were 20 companies involved back then and over 200 this time around, but he says by breaking it down into smaller groups, it helped create the same feel.</p>
<p>The company launched at the beginning of last year, and spent last year building the product and working with design partners and beta customers ahead of today&#8217;s release. The plan is to offer a subscription service where companies pay by the number of environments they create.</p>
<p>ReleaseHub currently has 10 employees including the three founders with plans to add more, especially engineers to help continue building out the solution and adding more layers of functionality. As he does this, McClung says bringing in a diverse group of employees is a priority for the founding team.</p>
<p>&#8220;I mean I&#8217;ve been building companies for a long time and it has to be embedded into the DNA of the company at the very earliest stages, so making sure that you have diverse talent [from the start],&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He says the plan is to stay 100% remote even after offices open again. &#8220;We were forced into being remote and actually we made it work really well for us. You know in a lot of ways it&#8217;s advantageous for work-life balance,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SGgbw79n0w"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/4-enterprise-developer-trends-that-will-shape-2021/">4 enterprise developer trends that will shape 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 enterprise developer trends that will shape 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/06/22/4-enterprise-developer-trends-that-will-shape-2021/embed/#?secret=SGgbw79n0w" data-secret="SGgbw79n0w" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/releasehub-nabs-2-7m-seed-to-give-developers-on-demand-environments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145671</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smartphone shipments jumped 27% globally in Q1</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/smartphone-shipments-jumped-27-globally-in-q1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/smartphone-shipments-jumped-27-globally-in-q1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 14:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canalys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More good news from a smartphone market currently rebounding from the far reaching impacts of the pandemic. New numbers from Canalys put global shipments for Q1 2021 at 27% above where they were the same time last year. The industry was hit early and hit hard by Covid-19. The first quarter saw company running into [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">More good news from a smartphone market currently rebounding from the far reaching impacts of the pandemic. New numbers from Canalys put global shipments for Q1 2021 at 27% above where they were the same time last year.</p>
<p>The industry was hit early and hit hard by Covid-19. The first quarter saw company running into serious supply chain issues as the pandemic first hit China and parts of Asia where most manufacturing occurs. Following that, demand began to slow, as fewer people were interested in buying mobile devices, coupled with broader economic and job impacts.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145631" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145631" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2145631" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-29.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-29.jpg 1250w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-29.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-29.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-29.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-29.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/unnamed-29.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2145631" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Canalys</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Samsung continued to lead the way globally, with 76.5 million, up from 59.6 million, representing a 28% jump, year-over-year. In all, the company controls around 22% of global shipments (same as a year prior).</p>
<p>In second place, Apple represented the biggest jump of the quarter, with a 41% increase from 37.1 million to 52.4 million. That no doubt owes substantially to the big upgrades that arrived toward to the end of last year. Huawei’s struggles, meanwhile, have knocked the company out of the top five.</p>
<p>“Xiaomi is in pole position to be the new Huawei,” said Canalys’ Ben Stanton said in a release. “Its competitors offer superior channel margin, but Xiaomi’s sheer volume actually gives distributors a better opportunity to make money than rival brands. But the race is not over. Oppo and Vivo are hot on its heels, and are positioning in the mid-range in many regions to box Xiaomi in at the low end.”</p>
<p>The study also notes that LG’s exit from the category should mix things up a bit, as well, particularly in the Americas region, which accounted for 80% of the company’s sales last year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="E6AoElegjL"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/apple-record-china-2021/">Apple sales bounce back in China as Huawei loses smartphone crown</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple sales bounce back in China as Huawei loses smartphone crown&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/28/apple-record-china-2021/embed/#?secret=E6AoElegjL" data-secret="E6AoElegjL" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/smartphone-shipments-jumped-27-globally-in-q1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145630</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blue Origin will start selling tickets for New Shepard space tourism flights on May 5</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/blue-origin-will-start-selling-tickets-for-new-shepard-space-tourism-flights-on-may-5/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/blue-origin-will-start-selling-tickets-for-new-shepard-space-tourism-flights-on-may-5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Origin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space tourism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Origin seems very close to flying paying customers on its New Shepard sub-orbital rocket, having conducted a dress rehearsal of astronaut loading and unloading on its latest mission. Today, it also revealed that it will be selling the first ticket (tickets?) on board its inaugural commercial flight starting next week, on Wednesday, May 5. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Blue Origin seems very close to flying paying customers on its New Shepard sub-orbital rocket, having conducted a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/blue-origin-launches-and-lands-new-shepard-rocket-in-key-prep-flight-for-human-passengers/">dress rehearsal of astronaut loading and unloading</a> on its latest mission. Today, it also revealed that it will be selling the first ticket (tickets?) on board its inaugural commercial flight starting next week, on Wednesday, May 5.</p>
<p>The &#8216;when, and how much&#8217; are the two burning questions that remain around the Jeff Bezos-backed space company&#8217;s first commercial passenger flights. Blue Origin has been in the process of testing, developing and flight-certifying its spacecraft for human use for the past few years, and in its most recent missions the focus has squarely been on what are essentially finishing touches, like the aforementioned dress rehearsal, and a test of cabin comfort, communication and control features on a flight before that earlier this year.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QAg3A3QY1b"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/blue-origin-launches-and-lands-new-shepard-rocket-in-key-prep-flight-for-human-passengers/">Blue Origin launches and lands New Shepard rocket in key prep flight for human passengers</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Blue Origin launches and lands New Shepard rocket in key prep flight for human passengers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/blue-origin-launches-and-lands-new-shepard-rocket-in-key-prep-flight-for-human-passengers/embed/#?secret=QAg3A3QY1b" data-secret="QAg3A3QY1b" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>We&#8217;ve tried asking Blue Origin CEO Bob Smith about the cost of flights a number of times before, but he declined to provide specifics, beyond <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/02/blue-origins-passengers-will-pay-hundreds-of-thousands-of-dollars-for-a-ticket-on-new-shepard/">saying that it&#8217;ll be in the &#8220;hundreds of thousands&#8221; of dollars range</a>. That&#8217;s not a surprising ticket price given the ride, which includes a trip to space in the reusable New Shepard capsule stage that allows passengers to spend multiple minutes totally weightless in zero gravity, with ample window real estate to take in the space-based perspective of Earth.</p>
<p>Blue Origin isn&#8217;t share much more right now about what we&#8217;ll see next week when it starts selling its first passenger capacity, but did say we can expect more details come Wednesday, so stay tuned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/blue-origin-will-start-selling-tickets-for-new-shepard-space-tourism-flights-on-may-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145621</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Erase All Kittens raises $1M Seed round for Mario-style game which teaches girls to code</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/erase-all-kittens-raises-1m-seed-round-for-mario-style-game-which-teaches-girls-to-code/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/erase-all-kittens-raises-1m-seed-round-for-mario-style-game-which-teaches-girls-to-code/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code Kingdoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[codecombat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cofounder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science technology engineering and mathematics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shazam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swift Playgrounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Erase All Kittens (EAK) is an EdTech startup that created a ‘Mario-style’ web-based game designed for kids aged 8-12. However, the game has a twist: it places an emphasis on inspiring girls to code (since let’s face it, most coding tools are created by men). After reaching 160,000 players in over 100 countries, it’s now [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://eraseallkittens.com/">Erase All Kittens</a> (EAK) is an EdTech startup that created a ‘Mario-style’ web-based game designed for kids aged 8-12. However, the game has a twist: it places an emphasis on inspiring girls to code (since let’s face it, most coding tools are created by men). After reaching 160,000 players in over 100 countries, it’s now raised a $1M Seed funding led by <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/twinkl-ltd/">Twinkl Educational Publishing</a>, with participation from first investor Christian Reyntjens of the <a href="https://ablacksquare.com/">A Black Square</a> family office, alongside angel investors, including one of the founders of Shazam.</p>
<p>While the existing EAK game is free, a new game launched in July will be paid for, further boosting the product’s business model.</p>
<p>EAK says its research shows that some 55% of its players are girls, and 95% want to learn more about coding after playing its game. EAK is currently being used in over 3,000 schools, mostly in the UK and US, and its traction increased by 500% during the lockdowns associated with the pandemic.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/ePTL0QtKObM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;start=30&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>It’s Erase All Kittens’ contention that coding education tools for children have been largely built by men and so naturally appeal more to boys. With most teaching repetitive coding, in a very rigid, instructional way, it tends to appeal more to boys than girls, says EAK.</p>
<p>The female-founded team has a platform for changing the perception that kids, especially girls, have of coding. After R&amp;D of two years, it came up with a game designed to teach kids and girls as young as 8 skills such as HTML, CSS, and Javascript through highly gamified, story-driven gameplay. Kids get to chat with characters on their journey, for example, a serial entrepreneur unicorn mermaid called Tarquin Glitterquiff.</p>
<p>“Players edit the code that governs the game environment, building and fixing levels as they play in order to save kittens in a fantasy internet universe,” said  Dee Saigal, cofounder, CEO and creative director. Saigal is joined by co-founder Leonie Van Der Linde; CTO Rex Van Der Spuy; Senior Games Developer Jeremy Keen; and 2D Games Artist Mikhail Malkin.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145642" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145642" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Erase-All-Kittens-game.jpg" alt="Erase All Kittens game" width="1024" height="692" class="size-full wp-image-2145642" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Erase-All-Kittens-game.jpg 1039w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Erase-All-Kittens-game.jpg?resize=150,101 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Erase-All-Kittens-game.jpg?resize=300,203 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Erase-All-Kittens-game.jpg?resize=768,519 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Erase-All-Kittens-game.jpg?resize=680,459 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Erase-All-Kittens-game.jpg?resize=50,34 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2145642" class="wp-caption-text">Erase All Kittens game</p></div></p>
<p>The existing game teaches HTML skills and how to create URLs, and the new game (released in July this year) will teach HTML, CSS, and Javascript skills &#8211; bridging the huge gap between kids learning the concepts and being able to create on the web like developers.</p>
<p>Said Saigal: “We&#8217;re designing a coding game that girls genuinely love &#8211; one that places a huge emphasis on creativity. Girls can see instant results as they code, there are different ways to progress through the game, and learning is seamlessly blended with storytelling.”</p>
<p>Saigal said: “When I was younger I wanted to be a games designer. I loved coming up with ideas for games but coding had always seemed like an impossible task. We weren’t taught coding at school, and I couldn’t see anyone who looked like me making games, so I didn&#8217;t think it was something I could do.”</p>
<p>“Whilst researching our target audience, we found that one of the biggest obstacles for girls still begins with gender stereotypes from an early age. By the time girls reach school, this snowballs into a lack of confidence in STEM skills and lower expectations from teachers, which in turn can lead to lower performance—a gap that only widens as girls get older.”</p>
<p>EAK’s competitors include Code Kingdoms, Swift Playgrounds and CodeCombat. But Saigal says these games tend to appeal far more to boys than to girls.</p>
<p>The new game (see below) will be sold to schools and parents, globally. EAK will also be carrying out a one-for-one scheme, where for every school account purchased, one will be donated to underserved schools via partnerships with tech companies, educational organizations, and NGOs.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/O4xsnMvGBnY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>Jonathan Seaton, Co-founder and CEO at Twinkl and Director of TwinklHive, said: “We’re really excited to partner with Erase All Kittens, as a digital company Twinkl recognizes the importance of preparing children to succeed in the digital age and we believe through this partnership we can really make a difference.”</p>
<p>“The team is particularly excited about helping further Erase All Kitten’s mission to empower girls and give them the same opportunities to learn to code and build their own digital creations. Ensuring that all children have equal access to opportunities to learn is at the heart of Twinkl’s vision and a key motivation in the development of this partnership for both organizations.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2145627" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145627" loading="lazy" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/GirlPlaying4.png" alt="Erase All Kittens" width="600" height="400" class="size-full wp-image-2145627" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/GirlPlaying4.png 600w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/GirlPlaying4.png?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/GirlPlaying4.png?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/GirlPlaying4.png?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2145627" class="wp-caption-text">Erase All Kittens</p></div></p>
<p>Erase All Kittens says it is addressing the global skills gap, where the gender gap is increasingly widening. According to PWC, just 24% of the tech workforce is female and women make up just 12% of all engineers, while only 3% of female students in the UK list tech as their first career choice.</p>
<p>Research by <a href="http://www.childwise.co.uk/">Childwise</a> found that 90% of girls give up on coding after first trying it, and if they lose interest in STEM subject by the age of 11, they never recover from that. This is a huge and growing problem for the tech industry and for investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/erase-all-kittens-raises-1m-seed-round-for-mario-style-game-which-teaches-girls-to-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145623</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lime launches 100 e-mopeds in New York City as Mayor de Blasio reveals plan to fully re-open by July 1</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/lime-launches-100-e-mopeds-in-new-york-city-as-mayor-de-blasio-reveals-plan-to-fully-re-open-by-july-1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/lime-launches-100-e-mopeds-in-new-york-city-as-mayor-de-blasio-reveals-plan-to-fully-re-open-by-july-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric mopeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Weeks after Lime became one of the first companies to win the bid to operate e-scooters in New York City, the micromobility giant is bringing e-mopeds to the city&#8217;s streets. This will be the first company to host multiple modes of micromobility sharing in NYC. On Friday, Lime will release 100 electric mopeds onto the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Weeks after Lime became <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/bird-lime-and-veoride-selected-for-nyc-e-scooter-pilot/">one of the first companies to win the bid to operate e-scooters in New York City</a>, the micromobility giant is bringing e-mopeds to the city&#8217;s streets. This will be the first company to host multiple modes of micromobility sharing in NYC.</p>
<p>On Friday, Lime will release 100 electric mopeds onto the streets of Brooklyn, with planned expansions in Queens and lower Manhattan in the coming weeks. NYC is often choked and heated by smog from car pollution, but if it wants to achieve <a href="https://onenyc.cityofnewyork.us/initiatives/achieve-carbon-neutrality-and-100-percent-clean-electricity/">carbon neutrality by 2050</a>, it&#8217;ll have to get comfortable with seeing more electric micromobility crop up.</p>
<p>Lime will be directly competing with the only other existing dockless e-moped operator in the city, Revel, which just announced the launch of an all-EV rideshare service. Lime&#8217;s initial geographic zones of operation will more or less match Revel&#8217;s map, which includes much of north Brooklyn, from Williamsburg, to Greenpoint and Brooklyn Heights, but which will also extend southeast to the Flatlands, according to a Lime spokesperson.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Earlier this month, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/27/lime-adds-shared-electric-mopeds-to-the-mix/">Lime also launched e-mopeds in Washington D.C. and Paris</a>. With each launch, Lime has stressed its commitment to rider and road user safety with features like AI-enabled helmet detection and license verification and a liveness test, which asks the rider to make various facial expressions into the camera when signing up in order to prove they&#8217;re a real person, rather than using a static photo of someone else. A spokesperson said Lime can also use the liveness test to match the rider to their driver&#8217;s license to ensure it&#8217;s the same person.</p>
<p>Lime also requires a mandatory rider education curriculum designed in consultation with the Motorcycle Safety Foundation, and its service is covered by <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/a/automobile-liability-insurance.asp#:~:text=Liability%20car%20insurance%20is%20the,property%20while%20operating%20a%20vehicle.&amp;text=The%20two%20components%20of%20liability,liability%20and%20property%20damage%20liability.">motor vehicle liability insurance</a>, which provides financial protection if a rider were to harm someone else or their property while driving, but not for the rider or rider&#8217;s property.</p>
<p>Competitor Revel learned the hard way to include such safety features. Last summer, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/27/electric-moped-startup-revel-returns-to-new-york-with-helmet-selfie-other-in-app-safety-features/">the company took its mopeds off the roads for a few weeks</a> following several deaths and reports that riders weren&#8217;t wearing helmets, in order to come up with a safety plan that would assuage the city&#8217;s fears. Now Revel requires that users take a helmet selfie and requires all riders to take a 21-question safety training quiz and watch an instructional video before hopping on a moped for the first time. The app also has a community reporting tool that anyone can use to report bad behavior to Revel.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The steps Lime and Revel are taking to ensure rider safety are not dictated by the NYC Department of Transportation. Whereas the DOT engaged in a lengthy process to approve e-scooters to operate in the city, mopeds are not regulated by the city.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;We made an effort to work collaboratively with DOT, keep them informed of our plans, answer their questions and address any concerns,&#8221; a Lime spokesperson told TechCrunch.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Lime will also offer its Lime Aid program to give discounted rates to Pell Grant recipients, job seekers and recipients of subsidy programs, as well as free rides to frontline workers, teachers, non-profit employees, artists and hospitality workers — those who have been most affected by the pandemic.</p>
<p>As more New Yorkers get vaccinated and the city starts to open up (with a freshly-revealed plan to fully re-open the city by July 1) , Lime wants to entrench itself as a leading micromobility vessel, and they couldn&#8217;t ask for a better time than a post-pandemic summer.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“The pandemic has pushed New Yorkers to look for new ways to get around that are safe, sustainable and car-free,” said Lime CEO Wayne Ting in a statement. &#8220;Now, as New York emerges from a difficult year, we are eager to support an economic comeback driven not by cars, but by sustainable options that reduce congestion and allow for open-air, socially-distanced travel.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/lime-launches-100-e-mopeds-in-new-york-city-as-mayor-de-blasio-reveals-plan-to-fully-re-open-by-july-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145452</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The gig is up on 21st-century exploitation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/the-gig-is-up-on-21st-century-exploitation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/the-gig-is-up-on-21st-century-exploitation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig workers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s app-based or “gig” economy is frequently dressed up in talk about “modern innovation” and the “21st century of work.” This facade is a wolf in sheep’s clothing. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Rebecca Dixon</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/rebeccadnelp">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.nelp.org/expert/rebecca-dixon/">Rebecca Dixon</a> is the executive director of the <a href="https://www.nelp.org/">National Employment Law Project</a>. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Today’s app-based or “gig” economy is frequently dressed up in talk about “modern innovation” and the “21st century of work.” This facade is a wolf in sheep’s clothing.</p>
<p>Precarious, contingent work is nothing new — we’ve always had jobs that are low-paying, insecure and dismissed as “<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2021/04/theres-no-such-thing-as-a-low-skill-worker/618674/">unskilled</a>.” Due to systemic racism and a historically exploitative economy, workers of color have always been, and continue to be, heavily concentrated in the most exploitative industries.</p>
<p>The only difference is that today, companies like Uber, DoorDash and Instacart claim they don’t have to play by the rules because they use digital apps to manage their workforce. Even as many of these tech giants remain unprofitable, they have been allowed for far too long to shirk responsibility for providing safe and just working conditions where workers can thrive on and off the job.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Even as many of these tech giants remain unprofitable, they have been allowed for far too long to shirk responsibility for providing safe and just working conditions where workers can thrive on and off the job.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Workers’ rights in the so-called gig economy are often positioned as a modern problem. But when we think about the problems faced by gig and app-based workers, who are predominantly people of color, we must learn from the past in order to move forward to a just economy.</p>
<p>The federal government has long failed to address widespread worker exploitation. Since the passage of the National Labor Relations Act, jobs like agricultural and domestic work, which were largely performed by workers of color, were carved out of labor rights and protections. The “independent contractors” of today, who are largely workers of color, fall into this same category of workers who have been excluded from labor laws. Combined, Black and Latinx workers make up less than 29% of the nation’s total workforce, but they comprise almost 42% of workers for app-based companies.</p>
<p>Gig companies argue that the drivers, delivery people, independent contractors and other workers who build their businesses, take direction from them and whose pay they set are millions of tiny businesses that do not need baseline benefits and protections. They do this in order to shield themselves from taking responsibility for their frontline workforce. Corporations then avoid paying basic costs like a minimum wage, healthcare, paid sick leave, compensation coverage and a litany of other essential benefits for their employees. For many workers, these conditions only serve to proliferate inequality nationwide and ultimately uphold a deeply flawed economy built upon worker exploitation and suffering.</p>
<p>App-based companies are the face of a larger, sinister trend. Over the last four decades, federal policies have greatly eroded the bargaining power of workers and concentrated more power in the hands of corporations and those who already have substantial wealth and power. This has perpetuated and worsened the racial wage and wealth gaps and contributed to the ever-increasing degradation of working conditions for too many.</p>
<p>It’s clear that, in order to build an economy that works for all people, “gig” and app-based companies cannot be allowed to exploit their workers under the guise of “innovation.” These companies claim their workers want to remain independent contractors, but what workers want is good pay, job security, flexibility and full rights under federal laws. This is a reasonable and just demand &#8212; and necessary to close generational gender and racial wealth gaps.</p>
<p>App-based companies are pouring significant resources into promoting government policies that prop up their worker exploitation model. Uber, Lyft, DoorDash Instacart and other app-based companies are loudly peddling misinformation in state legislatures, city councils and federal offices. Elected leaders at all levels need to recognize these policies for what they are — corporate efforts to rewrite the laws to benefit them — and reject the corporate interests behind the policies that carve out workers from universal protections.</p>
<p>Congress must also reject exclusions that lock people of color out of basic employment protections and pass legislation to extend protections to <em>all workers</em>, including app-based workers. The <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/842">PRO Act</a> is a great first step, which extends bargaining protections to workers who have been wrongly classified as “independent contractors” by their employers.</p>
<p>Across the country, app-based workers have organized to protect their health and safety and demand that their rights as workers be recognized and protected. Elected leaders cannot keep falling for corporate propaganda claiming a “21st-century” model. Work in the 21st century is still work; work that is organized on an app is still work.</p>
<p>We call on Congress to recognize the labor rights and protections of all workers and act boldly to ensure that app-based companies cannot block workers from equal rights in the name of “flexibility” and “innovation.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GiRvHn1f6X"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/">An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/embed/#?secret=GiRvHn1f6X" data-secret="GiRvHn1f6X" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/the-gig-is-up-on-21st-century-exploitation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wasabi scores $112M Series C on $700M valuation to take on cloud storage hyperscalers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/wasabi-scores-112m-series-c-on-700m-valuation-to-take-on-cloud-storage-hyperscalers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/wasabi-scores-112m-series-c-on-700m-valuation-to-take-on-cloud-storage-hyperscalers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boston startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidelity Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wasabi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking on Amazon S3 in the cloud storage game would seem to be a fool-hearty proposition, but Wasabi has found a way to build storage cheaply and pass the savings onto customers. Today the Boston-based startup announced a $112 million Series C investment on a $700 million valuation. Fidelity Management &#38; Research Company led the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Taking on Amazon S3 in the cloud storage game would seem to be a fool-hearty proposition, but <a href="http://wasabi.com">Wasabi</a> has found a way to build storage cheaply and pass the savings onto customers. Today the Boston-based startup announced a $112 million Series C investment on a $700 million valuation.</p>
<p>Fidelity Management &amp; Research Company led the round with participation from previous investors. It reports that it has now raised $219 million in equity so far, along with additional debt financing, but it takes a lot of money to build a storage business.</p>
<p>CEO David Friend says that business is booming and he needed the money to keep it going. &#8220;The business has just been exploding. We achieved a roughly $700 million valuation on this round, so  you can imagine that business is doing well. We&#8217;ve tripled in each of the last three years and we&#8217;re ahead of plan for this year,&#8221; Friend told me.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He says that demand continues to grow and he&#8217;s been getting requests internationally. That was one of the primary reasons he went looking for more capital. What&#8217;s more, data sovereignty laws require that certain types of sensitive data like financial and healthcare be stored in-country, so the company needs to build more capacity where it&#8217;s needed.</p>
<p>He says they have nailed down the process of building storage, typically inside co-location facilities, and during the pandemic they actually became more efficient as they hired a firm to put together the hardware for them onsite. They also put channel partners like managed service providers (MSPs) and value added resellers (VARs) to work by incentivizing them to sell Wasabi to their customers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WJHjhC3BjQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/with-a-50b-run-rate-in-reach-can-anyone-stop-aws/">With a $50B run rate in reach, can anyone stop AWS?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;With a $50B run rate in reach, can anyone stop AWS?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/22/with-a-50b-run-rate-in-reach-can-anyone-stop-aws/embed/#?secret=WJHjhC3BjQ" data-secret="WJHjhC3BjQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Wasabi storage starts at $5.99 per terabyte per month. That&#8217;s a heck of a lot cheaper <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/pricing/">than Amazon S3</a>, which starts at 0.23 per gigabyte for the first 50 terabytes or $23.00 a terabyte, considerably more than Wasabi&#8217;s offering.</p>
<p>But Friend admits that Wasabi still faces headwinds as a startup. No matter how cheap it is, companies want to be sure it&#8217;s going to be there for the long haul and a round this size from an investor with the pedigree of Fidelity will give the company more credibility with large enterprise buyers without the same demands of venture capital firms.</p>
<p>&#8220;Fidelity to me was the ideal investor. [&#8230;] They don&#8217;t want a board seat. They don&#8217;t want to come in and tell us how to run the company. They are obviously looking toward an IPO or something like that, and they are just interested in being an investor in this business because cloud storage is a virtually unlimited market opportunity,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>He sees his company as the typical kind of market irritant. He says that his company has run away from competitors in his part of the market and the hyperscalers are out there not paying attention because his business remains a fraction of theirs for the time being. While an IPO is far off, he took on an institutional investor this early because he believes it&#8217;s possible eventually.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think this is a big enough market we&#8217;re in, and we were lucky to get in at just the right time with the right kind of technology. There&#8217;s no doubt in my mind that Wasabi could grow to be a fairly substantial public company doing cloud infrastructure. I think we have a nice niche cut out for ourselves, and I don&#8217;t see any reason why we can&#8217;t continue to grow,&#8221; he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1Mv2kwaDpN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/12/wasabi-just-landed-68-million-to-upend-cloud-storage/">Wasabi just landed $68 million to upend cloud storage</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Wasabi just landed $68 million to upend cloud storage&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/12/wasabi-just-landed-68-million-to-upend-cloud-storage/embed/#?secret=1Mv2kwaDpN" data-secret="1Mv2kwaDpN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/wasabi-scores-112m-series-c-on-700m-valuation-to-take-on-cloud-storage-hyperscalers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145592</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vectra AI picks up $130M at a $1.2B valuation for its network approach to threat detection and response</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/vectra-ai-picks-up-130m-at-a-1-2b-valuation-for-its-network-approach-to-threat-detection-and-response/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/vectra-ai-picks-up-130m-at-a-1-2b-valuation-for-its-network-approach-to-threat-detection-and-response/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vectra ai]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cybersecurity nightmares like the SolarWinds hack highlight how malicious hackers continue to exploit vulnerabilities in software and apps to do their dirty work. Today a startup that&#8217;s built a platform to help organizations protect themselves from this by running threat detection and response at the network level is announcing a big round of funding to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Cybersecurity nightmares like the SolarWinds hack highlight how malicious hackers continue to exploit vulnerabilities in software and apps to do their dirty work. Today a startup that&#8217;s built a platform to help organizations protect themselves from this by running threat detection and response at the network level is announcing a big round of funding to continue its growth.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vectra.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vectra AI</a>, which provides a cloud-based service that uses artificial intelligence technology to monitor both on-premise and cloud-based networks for intrusions, has closed a round of $130 million at a post-money valuation of $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>The challenge that Vectra is looking to address is that applications &#8212; and the people who use them &#8212; will continue to be weak links in a company&#8217;s security set-up, not least because malicious hackers are continually finding new ways to piece together small movements within them to build, lay and finally use their traps. While there will continue to be an interesting, and mostly effective, game of cat-and-mouse around those applications, a service that works at the network layer is essential as an alternative line of defense, one that can find those traps before they are used.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Think about where the cloud is. We are in the wild west,&#8221; Hitesh Sheth, Vectra&#8217;s CEO, said in an interview. &#8220;The attack surface is so broad and attacks happen at such a rapid rate that the security concerns have never been higher at the enterprise. That is driving a lot of what we are doing.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sheth said that the funding will be used in two areas. First, to continue expanding its technology to meet the demands of an ever-growing threat landscape &#8212; it also has a team of researchers who work across the business to detect new activity and build algorithms to respond to it. And second, for acquisitions to bring in new technology and potentially more customers.</p>
<p>(Indeed, there has been a proliferation of AI-based cybersecurity startups in recent years, in areas like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/cado-security-locks-in-10m-for-its-cloud-native-digital-forensics-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">digital forensics</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/appomni-raises-40m-for-tools-to-secure-enterprise-saas-apps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">application security</a> and specific sectors like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/actzero-emerges-from-stealth-with-40m-for-a-suite-of-cybersecurity-solutions-aimed-at-smbs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SMBs</a>, all of which complement the platform that Vectra has built, so you could imagine a number of interesting targets.)</p>
<p>The funding is being led by funds managed by Blackstone Growth, with unnamed existing investors participating (past backers include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/21/vectra-raises-36m-for-its-ai-based-approach-to-cybersecurity-intrusion-detection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Accel, Khosla</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/10/vectra-lands-100m-series-e-investment-for-ai-driven-network-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TCV</a>, among other financial and strategic investors). Vectra today largely <a href="https://www.vectra.ai/resource-type/case-studies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">focuses on enterprises</a>, highly demanding ones with lots at stake to lose. Blackstone was initially a customer of Vectra&#8217;s, using the company&#8217;s flagship Cognito platform, Viral Patel &#8212; the senior MD who led the investment for the firm &#8212; pointed out to me.</p>
<p>The company has built some specific products that have been very prescient in anticipating vulnerabilities in specific applications and services. While it said that sales of its Cognito platform grew 100% last year, C<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ognito Detect for Microsoft Office 365 (a separate product) sales grew over 700%. Coincidentally, Microsoft&#8217;s cloud apps have faced a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/microsoft-says-china-backed-hackers-are-exploiting-exchange-zero-days/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wave of malicious threats</a>. Sheth said that implementing Cognito (or indeed other network security protection) &#8220;could have prevented the SolarWinds hack&#8221; for those using it.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Through our experience as a client of Vectra, we’ve been highly impressed by their world-class technology and exceptional team,&#8221;  John Stecher, CTO at Blackstone, said in a statement. &#8220;They have exactly the types of tools that technology leaders need to separate the signal from the noise in defending their organizations from increasingly sophisticated cyber threats. We’re excited to back Vectra and Hitesh as a strategic partner in the years ahead supporting their continued growth.”</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Sheth said that endpoint security will not be a focus for the moment because &#8220;in cloud there is so much open territory&#8221;. Instead it partners with the likes of CrowdStrike, SentinelOne, Carbon Black and others.</p>
<p>In terms of what is emerging as a stronger entry point, social media is increasingly coming to the fore, he said. &#8220;Social media tends to be an effective vector to get in and will remain to be for some time,&#8221; he said, with people impersonating others and suggesting conversations over encrypted services like WhatsApp. &#8220;The moment you move to encryption and exchange any documents, it&#8217;s game over.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/vectra-ai-picks-up-130m-at-a-1-2b-valuation-for-its-network-approach-to-threat-detection-and-response/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145590</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gr4vy launches Cloud payment orchestration, pulls in $11.1M Series A led by Nyca Partners</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/gr4vy-launches-cloud-payment-orchestration-pulls-in-11-1m-series-a-led-by-nyca-partners/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/gr4vy-launches-cloud-payment-orchestration-pulls-in-11-1m-series-a-led-by-nyca-partners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gr4vy, (pronounced ‘gravy’) is a cloud-native payments company with a “payment orchestration platform (POP)” that merges a Cloud platform with payments infrastructure. It’s also announcing a Series A funding round of $11.1M, led by Nyca Partners (a VC with a bench of partners who are ex-Visa ), with participation from Activant Capital (a fintech investor), [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://Gr4vy.com/">Gr4vy</a>, (pronounced ‘gravy’) is a cloud-native payments company with a “payment orchestration platform (POP)” that merges a Cloud platform with payments infrastructure. It’s also announcing a Series A funding round of $11.1M, led by Nyca Partners (a VC with a bench of partners who are ex-Visa ), with participation from Activant Capital (a fintech investor), Global Founders Capital, and Firestartr bringing its total funding to $12.2M.</p>
<p>So what is Gr4vy tackling here?</p>
<p>Over a video call, John Lunn, founder and CEO of Gr4vy outlined how it works.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He told me that having worked in the payments space since the mid 1990s (Lunn is a veteran of PayPal) he saw the same problem over and over again: every retailer in the world is building the same piece of software.</p>
<p>He said retailers often start with one payment processor, grow and expand, but basically end up building what is now known as an &#8216;orchestration&#8217; platform. Essentially it&#8217;s like an internal router to route your payments wherever they need to go in the world. But the problem is that it all gradually becomes much and more complex to maintain.</p>
<p>He said: “I looked at the problem. I realized we need to create a piece of software that the retailer can run that will mean that payments get out of the way and it can all can be managed and orchestrated the way the retailer wants to do it&#8230; I thought there are two ways to do this: you can either get an endpoint SAAS to connect to this. But the more I thought about it, the more I felt like that&#8217;s actually not the solution here. We needed to give you something that allows you to do it yourself and fits into your infrastructure. So what we built with Gravy is essentially a cloud, where we spin you up an instance of Gravy on the cloud, wherever, whatever cloud you need it to be on, whether it’s, Google, Amazon, Microsoft, or even in your own data center. That essentially gives you a platform to manage and control how your payments flow, both on the front end and the back end.”</p>
<p>Thus Gr4vy is quite a new idea: it combines Cloud and payment orchestration together on the one platform.</p>
<p>Gr4vy wil compete to some extent with <a href="http://Spreedly.com">Spreedly</a> and <a href="https://modopayments.com/">modo</a>. However, Gr4vy claims to be the only payments provider that will spin up a cloud instance for a customer.</p>
<p>It says, this gives a lot of flexibility for managing a payments stack as a company scales and removes a lot of the risks caused by a single point of failure or shared infrastructure. It also means it can be deployed across geographies, putting ‘Edges’ closer to customers. This, says Gr4vy, means fewer abandoned shopping carts, lost payments, and stronger compliance with local regulations. The platform also offers centralized reporting, monitoring, and management.</p>
<p>Lunn added: “We are the only payment orchestration platform built natively in the cloud&#8230; Retailers can expand and control their payment stack from anywhere. Gr4vy is also payment service provider agnostic. Retailers can mix and match providers, payment methods and route their transactions without being locked into a single ecosystem.”</p>
<p>So, Gr4vy, acts as a conduit between retailers’ shopping carts and payment providers. By offering instances &#8211; says the startup &#8211; it can give retailers individualized infrastructure in the cloud.</p>
<p>The launch of Gr4vy comes at a key time for online retailers as the world moves from part online shopping to almost 100% due to the pandemic.</p>
<p>GR4vy says its benefits include flexibility, customized workflows, a PCI1 Certified Gr4vy vault, a universal API, an easy modern checkout, no-code admin and centralized Transaction Reports.</p>
<p>Hans Morris, managing partner of Nyca Partners said in a statement: “Very few people in the world have as much experience and insight in international payments as John and his team. And their vision of what is needed for merchants is spot-on: a cloud-native tool to let businesses orchestrate and optimize their payments using their intuitive interfaces (no engineering!), robust security, and simple, seamless implementation. Much easier than managing today’s menu of complex, multiple payment platforms.”</p>
<p>“As investors focused on the future of commerce infrastructure, we’re eager to continue working with John and the Gr4vy team as they simplify payments orchestration for merchants and marketplaces of all sizes,” added Steve Sarracino, founder and partner at Activant Capital.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/gr4vy-launches-cloud-payment-orchestration-pulls-in-11-1m-series-a-led-by-nyca-partners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145580</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google announces career and digital training initiative for formerly incarcerated individuals</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/google-formerly-incarcerated/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/google-formerly-incarcerated/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google today announced the launch of Grow with Google Career Readiness for Reentry. The initiative &#8212; created in partnership with nonprofits The Last Mile, Center for Employment Opportunities (CEO), Defy Ventures, Fortune Society and The Ladies of Hope Ministries &#8212; is designed to offer job readiness and digital skill training for formerly incarcerated individuals. As [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google today announced the launch of <a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/grow-with-google/readiness-for-reentry/">Grow with Google Career Readiness for Reentry</a>. The initiative &#8212; created in partnership with nonprofits The Last Mile, Center for Employment Opportunities (CEO), Defy Ventures, Fortune Society and The Ladies of Hope Ministries &#8212; is designed to offer job readiness and digital skill training for formerly incarcerated individuals.</p>
<p>As the company notes in a blog post today, returning citizens have an <a href="https://www.prisonpolicy.org/reports/outofwork.html">unemployment rate 5x higher</a> than the national average &#8212; and returning citizens who are Black experience this at an even higher rate, due to discriminatory practices. In all, some 600,000 Americans attempt to make the transition from incarceration to employment every year.</p>
<p>Beginning this year, the initiative is set to train 10,000 people with a combination project-based and video learning curriculum. The learnings revolve around five points, per Google,</p>
<blockquote>
<ol>
<li>Getting Started with the Basics</li>
<li>Job Search</li>
<li>Job <span class="il">Readiness</span>,</li>
<li>Online Safety</li>
<li>“Next Step” Job <span class="il">Readiness</span> Skills</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
<p>“Lack of access to digital skills training and job coaching puts formerly incarcerated individuals at a severe disadvantage when trying to reenter the workforce and increase their economic potential,” said YouTube’s Global Head of Human Rights Malika Saada Saar in a statement tied to the news. “We are thrilled to work alongside program partners who have demonstrated true expertise and leadership in supporting successful reentry through digital skills training to men and women, mothers and fathers, impacted by incarceration.”</p>
<p>The company notes that the program is part of a broader initiative that has found it investing $40 million in criminal justice reform nonprofits, as well as $60 million for computer science learning.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cdk9xBsUrG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/reimagine-pathways-for-returned-citizens-at-techcrunch-sessions-justice/">Reimagining the path forward for the formerly incarcerated at TechCrunch Sessions: Justice</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Reimagining the path forward for the formerly incarcerated at TechCrunch Sessions: Justice&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/reimagine-pathways-for-returned-citizens-at-techcrunch-sessions-justice/embed/#?secret=cdk9xBsUrG" data-secret="cdk9xBsUrG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/google-formerly-incarcerated/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145404</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hacking my way into analytics: A creative’s journey to design with data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/hacking-my-way-into-analytics-a-creatives-journey-to-design-with-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/hacking-my-way-into-analytics-a-creatives-journey-to-design-with-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 12:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[database]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There's a growing need for basic data literacy in the tech industry, and it’s only getting more taxing by the year, so it's essential to equip your whole team with the right exploratory medium.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Sydney Anh Mai</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sydneyanhmai/">Sydney Anh Mai</a> is an award-winning product designer at Kickstarter. <a href="http://sydbydesign.com/">Her work</a> has appeared on The Verge, Design Weekly and Core 77. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Growing up, did you ever wonder how many chairs you’d have to stack to reach the sky?</p>
<p>No? I guess that’s just me then.</p>
<p>As a child, I always asked a lot of “how many/much” questions. Some were legitimate (&#8220;How much is 1 USD in VND?&#8221;); some were absurd (&#8220;How tall is the sky and can it be measured in chairs?&#8221;). So far, I’ve managed to maintain my obnoxious statistical probing habit without making any mortal enemies in my 20s. As it turns out, that habit comes with its perks when working in product.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Growing up, did you ever wonder how many chairs you’d have to stack to reach the sky?					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>My first job as a product designer was at a small but energetic fintech startup whose engineers also dabbled in pulling data. I constantly bothered them with questions like, “How many exports did we have from that last feature launched?” and “How many admins created at least one rule on this page?” I was curious about quantitative analysis but did not know where to start.</p>
<p>I knew I wasn’t the only one. Even then, there was a growing need for basic data literacy in the tech industry, and it’s only getting more taxing by the year. Words like “data-driven,” “data-informed” and “data-powered” increasingly litter every tech organization’s product briefs. But where does this data come from? Who has access to it? How might I start digging into it myself? How might I leverage this data in my day-to-day design once I get my hands on it?</p>
<h2>Data discovery for all: What’s in the way?</h2>
<p>“Curiosity is our compass” is one of Kickstarter’s guiding principles. Powered by a desire for knowledge and information, curiosity is the enemy of many larger, older and more structured organizations — whether they admit it or not — because it hinders the production flow. Curiosity makes you pause and take time to explore and validate the “ask.” Asking as many what’s, how’s, why’s, who’s and how many’s as possible is important to help you learn if the work is worth your time.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/hacking-my-way-into-analytics-a-creatives-journey-to-design-with-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145086</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MagicBell raises $1.9M to build a plug-and-play notification platform for product teams</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/magicbell-raises-1-9m-to-build-a-plug-and-play-notification-platform-for-product-teams/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/magicbell-raises-1-9m-to-build-a-plug-and-play-notification-platform-for-product-teams/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 12:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cherry Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christian reber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seed funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YC W21]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the key ingredients in effective product development is receiving timely and relevant notifications about customer use, engagement, potential issues and more. Engineers, developers and product managers rely on that flow of information between themselves and their users, but it&#8217;s typically delivered either via legacy email tools, or through notification systems built into product [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">One of the key ingredients in effective product development is receiving timely and relevant notifications about customer use, engagement, potential issues and more. Engineers, developers and product managers rely on that flow of information between themselves and their users, but it&#8217;s typically delivered either via legacy email tools, or through notification systems built into product management dashboards that devs have to hand-code themselves. <a href="https://magicbell.com">MagicBell</a>, a startup that just went through Y Combinator&#8217;s most recent Winter cohort, has raised a $1.9 million seed round to deliver a rich notification platform for product teams that&#8217;s easy to integrate and use.</p>
<p>The round was led by Cherry Ventures, and includes participation by a number of angel investors including Algolia co-founder Nicolas Dessaigne, Twitter Director of Product Management Marie Outtier, and Wunderlist and Pitch co-founder Christian Reber. This list itself is a great endorsement of the need for what MagicBell&#8217;s building, since it&#8217;s a storied collection of veteran experts who have ample experience actually building some of the world&#8217;s most engaging software products.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sophia [Bendz], Partner at Cherry Ventures], of course, worked at Spotify,&#8221; explained MagicBell CEO and co-founder Hana Mohan in an interview. &#8220;She has built a consumer product, and she has invested in a lot of startups [&#8230;] we followed YC&#8217;s advice in this batch, which was to definitely leave some room in the round for strategic angels.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2145573" style="width: 516px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2145573" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2145573" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png?w=506" alt="MagicBell's Notification inbox" width="506" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png 1088w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png?resize=112,150 112w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png?resize=223,300 223w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png?resize=768,1032 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png?resize=506,680 506w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/magicbell-inbox.png?resize=37,50 37w" sizes="(max-width: 506px) 100vw, 506px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2145573" class="wp-caption-text">An example of MagicBell&#8217;s Notification inbox.</p></div></p>
<p>That deep product experience on the cap table should serve MagicBell well as it seeks to grow the team, which currently consists of Mohan and co-founder Josue Montano. She and Montano previously worked on customer support ticketing system startup SupportBee, but found they were spending a lot of their time and effort on just building a notifications system for the platform. The greater opportunity, they realized, was in making that process plug-and-play, and scalable, since it&#8217;s something that can be intensely cost- and effort-intensive in setting up a new product, even though it&#8217;s also not anyone&#8217;s primary focus when building their software.</p>
<p>Basically everyone today is familiar and comfortable with a robust notification system — we use them constantly on our Android and iOS devices. But those notification systems are challenging to make successful, despite essentially being a commodity feature at this point. MagicBell offers a notification inbox that&#8217;s embeddable into existing software via React, Javascript and REST (with additional frameworks in the pipeline), which provides real-time notification delivery, syncing of delivery and read status, individual user preference settings, and delivery across web, email and mobile clients.</p>
<p>Long term, the plan is to build MagicBell into a full-featured notification platform that offers a highly-customizable means of keeping your product team and customers informed and in sync. Accordingly, the startup&#8217;s first priority with this initial funding is to hire engineers to help it build, says Mohan, and it&#8217;s also being driven by the product roadmaps of some of its initial customers — which coincidentally, includes a number of its investors.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the cool things for us was definitely that three or four of our customers ended up investing,&#8221; Mohan said, noting that <a href="https://pitch.com">Reber&#8217;s startup Pitch</a> was actually a customer before he decided to invest. &#8220;The other great thing about [Pitch] is that they have a pretty extensive roadmap themselves of launching a mobile offering, both on iOS and Android. So they&#8217;re really pushing the product forward, which is great for us.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mohan is also one of the inaugural guests on our <a href="http://pod.link/found">new podcast Found</a>, and you can <a href="http://apple.co/found">subscribe now</a> to get our episode with her when it becomes available on Friday. She goes into a lot more detail about YC, and the process of identifying the need for MagicBell in the market, plus plenty more, so be sure to tune in.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/magicbell-raises-1-9m-to-build-a-plug-and-play-notification-platform-for-product-teams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145565</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RapidDeploy raises $29M for a cloud-based dispatch platform aimed at 911 centers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/rapiddeploy-raises-29m-for-a-cloud-based-dispatch-platform-aimed-at-911-centers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/rapiddeploy-raises-29m-for-a-cloud-based-dispatch-platform-aimed-at-911-centers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 12:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[911]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ambulance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbyne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emergency services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[police]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapiddeploy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rapidsos]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last year of pandemic living has been real-world, and sometimes harrowing, proof of how important it can be to have efficient and well-equipped emergency response services in place. They can help people remotely if need be, and when they cannot, they make sure that in-person help can be dispatched quickly in medical and other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The last year of pandemic living has been real-world, and sometimes harrowing, proof of how important it can be to have efficient and well-equipped emergency response services in place. They can help people remotely if need be, and when they cannot, they make sure that in-person help can be dispatched quickly in medical and other situations. Today, a company that&#8217;s building cloud-based tools to help with this process is announcing a round of funding as it continues to grow.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rapiddeploy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RapidDeploy</a>, which provides computer-aided dispatch technology as a cloud-based service for 911 centers, has closed a round of $29 million, a Series B round of funding that will be used both to grow its business, and to continue expanding the SaaS tools that it provides to its customers. In the startup&#8217;s point of view, the cloud is essential to running emergency response in the most efficient manner.</p>
<p class="p1">&#8220;911 response would have been called out on a walkie talkie in the early days,&#8221; said Steve Raucher, the co-founder and CEO of RapidDeploy, in an interview. &#8220;Now the cloud has become the nexus of signals.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Washington, DC-based RapidDeploy provides data and analytics to 911 centers &#8212; the critical link between people calling for help and connecting those calls with the nearest medical, police or fire assistance &#8212; and today it has about 700 customers using its RadiusPlus, Eclipse Analytics and Nimbus CAD products.</p>
<p>That works out to about 10% of all 911 centers in the US (7,000 in total), and covering 35% of the population (there are more centers in cities and other dense areas). Its footprint includes state coverage in Arizona, California, and Kansas. It also has operations in South Africa, where it was originally founded.</p>
<p>The funding is coming from an interesting mix of financial and strategic investors. Led by Morpheus Ventures, the round also had participation from GreatPoint Ventures, Ericsson Ventures, Samsung Next Ventures, Tao Capital Partners, Tau Ventures, among others. It looks like the company had raised about $30 million before this latest round, according to <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/265357-09/company/profile#board-members" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PitchBook data</a>. Valuation is not being disclosed.</p>
<p>Ericsson and Samsung, as major players in the communication industry, have a big stake in seeing through what will be the next generation of communications technology and how it is used for critical services. (And indeed, one of the big leaders in legacy and current 911 communications is Motorola, a would-be competitor of both.) AT&amp;T is also a strategic go-to-market (distribution and sales) partner of RapidDeploy&#8217;s, and it also has integrations with Apple, Google, Microsoft, and OnStar to feed data into its system.</p>
<p>The business of emergency response technology is a fragmented market. Raucher describes them as &#8220;mom-and-pop&#8221; businesses, with some 80% of them occupying four seats or less (a testament to the fact that a lot of the US is actually significantly less urban than its outsized cities might have you think it is), and in many cases a lot of these are operating on legacy equipment.</p>
<p>However, in the US in the last several years &#8212; buffered by innovations like the Jedi project and <a href="https://firstnet.gov/network" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FirstNet</a>, a next-generation public safety network &#8212; things have been shifting. RapidDeploy&#8217;s technology sits alongside (and in some areas competes with) companies like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/14/carbyne-raises-25m-for-a-next-generation-platform-to-improve-emergency-911-responses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Carbyne</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/rapidsos-raises-85m-for-its-emergency-response-data-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RapidSOS</a>, which have been tapping into the innovations of cell phone technology both to help pinpoint people and improve how to help them.</p>
<p>RapidDeploy&#8217;s tech is based around its RadiusPlus mapping platform, which uses d<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ata from smart phones, vehicles, home security systems and other connected devices and channels it to its data stream, which can help a center determine not just location but potentially other aspects of the condition of the caller. Its Eclipse Analytics services, meanwhile, are meant to act as a kind of assistant to those centers to help triage situations and provide insights into how to respond. The Nimbus CAD then helps figure out who to call out and routing for response. </span></p>
<p>Longer term, the plan will be to leverage cloud architecture to bring in new data sources and ways of communicating between callers, centers and emergency care providers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s about being more of a triage service rather than a message switch,&#8221; Raucher said. &#8220;As we see it, the platform will evolve with customers&#8217; needs. Tactical mapping ultimately is not big enough to cover this. We&#8217;re thinking about unified communications.&#8221; Indeed, that is the direction that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/20/technology/you-dont-need-flying-cars-to-save-lives.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">many of these services seem to be going</a>, which can only be a good thing for us consumers.</p>
<p>“The future of emergency services is in data, which creates a faster, more responsive 9-1-1 center,” said Mark Dyne, Founding Partner at Morpheus Ventures, in a statement. “We believe that the platform RapidDeploy has built provides the necessary breadth of capabilities that make the dream of Next-Gen 9-1-1 service a reality for rural and metropolitan communities across the nation and are excited to be investing in this future with Steve and his team.” Dyne has joined the RapidDeploy board with this round.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/rapiddeploy-raises-29m-for-a-cloud-based-dispatch-platform-aimed-at-911-centers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145574</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Returnal&#8217; is a frantic, familiar pleasure — but spurns mainstream appeal to its peril</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/returnal-review-a-familiar-frantic-pleasure-but-a-risky-next-gen-debut/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/returnal-review-a-familiar-frantic-pleasure-but-a-risky-next-gen-debut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Devin Coldewey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 12:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PS5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2143183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Returnal, released today for the PlayStation 5, is an action adventure that has you exploring an alien world that reconfigures itself whenever you die, bringing you back for another shot at escaping. It&#8217;s exciting, frustrating, and beautiful, though it isn&#8217;t particularly original. But while it is arguably the first game to be released that was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>Returnal</em>, released today for the PlayStation 5, is an action adventure that has you exploring an alien world that reconfigures itself whenever you die, bringing you back for another shot at escaping. It&#8217;s exciting, frustrating, and beautiful, though it isn&#8217;t particularly original. But while it is arguably the first game to be released that was designed and built for next generation consoles, it&#8217;s not the mainstream hit many gamers are waiting for.</p>
<p>First I should probably justify my &#8220;arguably.&#8221; The PS5 debuted with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/demons-souls-the-first-truly-next-gen-game-is-a-lopsided-but-impressive-showcase/">the impressive remake of <em>Demon&#8217;s Souls</em>,</a> and while I enjoyed that greatly, it was only next-gen in its presentation; many dated aspects faithfully carried over from the original mean it can&#8217;t really be considered a fully next generation title. The pack-in <em>Astro&#8217;s Playroom</em> is a delight but doesn&#8217;t compare with full-scale games. <em>Destruction All-Stars</em> was something of a damp squib. And excellent games like <em>Spider-Man: Miles Morales</em> and <em>Assassin&#8217;s Creed: Valhalla</em> span the generations, playing best but by no means exclusively on PS5.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="n7pOq0JUhO"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/demons-souls-the-first-truly-next-gen-game-is-a-lopsided-but-impressive-showcase/">Demon&#8217;s Souls: The first truly next-gen game is a lopsided but impressive showcase</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demon&#8217;s Souls: The first truly next-gen game is a lopsided but impressive showcase&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/13/demons-souls-the-first-truly-next-gen-game-is-a-lopsided-but-impressive-showcase/embed/#?secret=n7pOq0JUhO" data-secret="n7pOq0JUhO" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>So <em>Returnal</em> really is, in a non-trivial way, the first <em>really</em> &#8220;next-gen&#8221; PS5 game — and it carries the &#8220;next-gen&#8221; PS5 price tag of $70, more in many regions. Can it justify this premium? In some ways yes, but like <em>Demon&#8217;s Souls</em> this is a difficult game that involves a potentially off-putting amount of repetition and failure for mainstream audiences.</p>
<p>The game starts with your character, a sci-fi space explorer working for a mysterious company called Astra (there are clear nods to Weyland-Yutani from <em>Alien</em>), crashing on a forbidden planet and finding herself — literally — stuck in a sort of time loop. (You&#8217;ll see what I mean by literally.)</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2144036" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144036" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2144036" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-4.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2144036" class="wp-caption-text">The developers have obviously seen Prometheus.</p></div></p>
<p>Without getting into the specifics of the plot, which is slowly revealed through found recordings, exploration of ancient ruins, and decoding alien symbols, Selene is seemingly trapped on the planet until she can figure out what&#8217;s going on, and whenever she dies the world shifts around to provide new challenges and opportunities.</p>
<p>Each loop or &#8220;cycle&#8221; involves the player starting from the crash site and progressing through the world, different but familiar every time. You encounter enemies, collect power-ups like new weapons or artifacts that affect your abilities, and occasionally an item that will permanently augment your suit or open new paths to take.</p>
<p>To call any individual aspect of the game original would be inaccurate — it takes with a free hand from its august predecessors in both gameplay and presentation. Without spoiling too much I&#8217;d say its progression and design share the most with indie breakout hit <em>Dead Cells</em>, with a dose of <em>Risk of Rain 2,</em> and a setting <del>lifted wholesale from</del> elaborating on <em>Alien</em> and <em>Prometheus</em>. That said, the story and backstory owe more to <em>Solaris</em>. It wears its influences on its sleeve to be sure, but they come together as something cohesive, not a sloppy pastiche.</p>
<h2>Run, gun, rinse, repeat</h2>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2144034" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-2.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><em>Returnal</em> starts out almost frustratingly simple, but this is soon remedied as new abilities and layers of complexity are added to the mix; expect the &#8220;tutorial&#8221; to be meted out over a few hours as things are discovered organically.</p>
<p>You make your way through what amounts to arena after arena, sometimes large and multi-layered, sometimes confined, and fight whatever appears. Combat is frantic and high risk — monsters don&#8217;t telegraph ponderous swipes at you but rather spew dozens or hundreds of bullets in your direction, making you rely on smart anticipatory movement and the cluttered landscape to stay alive. As you defeat them you accrue increasingly powerful boons that only last until you get hit, at which point they all disappear, adding a layer of urgency to every encounter: you could gain a crucial edge for the next miniboss — or lose what you&#8217;ve built up over minutes of careful play. You can&#8217;t take any enemy lightly — those that don&#8217;t kill you will make you weaker.</p>
<p>The player moves forward by exploring and eventually defeating an area boss, encounters that are more than a little taxing and generally take a few tries. Then it&#8217;s on to a new, different &#8220;biome&#8221; to do it all again with a different color scheme (and new enemies, hazards and so on).</p>
<p>The look and feel of <em>Returnal</em> is what you might call &#8220;early next-gen.&#8221; It&#8217;s detailed, interesting looking and realistic in a sci-fi way, and it uses lighting and color well to create both a sense of place and gameplay objectives. It&#8217;s better in some ways than what you&#8217;d expect from a PS4 or Xbox One game but ultimately the advances here seem to be more on the side of &#8220;fewer limitations&#8221; rather than &#8220;new capabilities.&#8221; Load times are practically non-existent — a second or two at most — and in places where sightlines are farther than a room or two, the scale of what&#8217;s being drawn is impressive. The framerate is a steady 60, making combat fluid no matter how crowded and chaotic it gets.</p>
<p>As for the claim of a &#8220;living world&#8221; that&#8217;s truly different every time, you can pretty much ignore that. You&#8217;ll encounter the same rooms and structures repeatedly, maybe with different enemies or items, but don&#8217;t expect a wildly different experience every loop. Just enough that the repetition isn&#8217;t too repetitious.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2144037" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144037" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2144037" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-5.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2144037" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Sony/Housemarque</p></div></p>
<p>Sound is solid and I&#8217;d definitely recommend headphones. Your number one issue is going to be getting blasted in the back and positional audio will help a lot with that, as each enemy has characteristic noises for its actions.</p>
<p>The PS5 controller&#8217;s advanced haptics are put to good use with two-stage virtual triggers and a lot of contextual vibrations. I do wish there was a way to control these with a bit more granularity, as the constant patter of rain in the first area was numbing my hands, but the other haptic cues were useful and quickly became second nature.</p>
<p>Games in the &#8220;roguelite&#8221; (i.e. you start from scratch every life like a roguelike, but occasionally gain permanent upgrades) genre can fall flat if your progression, either within a loop or over many of them, involves little more than &#8220;+4% pistol damage&#8221; or a few more hit points. Fortunately <em>Returnal</em> is well aware of this and its weapons, artifacts, perks and so on often confer interesting bonuses or risk/reward mechanics. And you only have one weapon at a time, meaning the choice between, say, an assault rifle with special ability A and a shotgun with special ability B is a complex and risky one.</p>
<p>Eventually you&#8217;ll be able to skip past certain areas, but you may not want to, preferring to scour side paths for resources so you&#8217;re not going into the next boss room naked and afraid. In general the game manages to keep a lot of interesting tensions going on with the player that make every decision consequential, not to say agonizing.</p>
<h2>Next-gen price tag</h2>
<p>Is <em>Returnal</em> worth its premium $70 asking price? For some people, yes. But this isn&#8217;t the kind of mainstream blockbuster that would ordinarily justify the increased cost.</p>
<p>So far I&#8217;ve played about 20 hours, done 30-odd runs, and based on what I know I&#8217;m about halfway through the game. Most of my progress was made on what I think of &#8220;prestige&#8221; runs, the handful where everything goes right and I get much further than before, making them tense and exciting. (Many ended within five minutes due to poor momentum or rage quits.) The game promises replay value past the credits, though, so a guess of 40 hours of content is more of a floor than a ceiling.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2144033" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2144033" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2144033" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="576" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg 2500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/returnal-ps5-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2144033" class="wp-caption-text">One of several trips to your house, inexplicably replicated on the alien planet&#8230;</p></div></p>
<p>The difficulty may present a barrier to many players. A dialogue at the start of the game warns you that the game is meant to be challenging and that death is part of the journey. Great, but that doesn&#8217;t make it any less frustrating when you get ambushed by a dozen enemies, wiping out half an hour of of progress in an instant. While generally the game falls into the &#8220;tough but fair&#8221; category, there are spikes here and there that feel gratuitous, and loops where you feel unlucky or underpowered and have to fight the urge to reset.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t mind personally — compared to the <em>Dark Souls</em> series it&#8217;s a cakewalk. I almost beat the first boss on my first encounter; good luck doing that with Ornstein and Smough or Father Gascoigne! But like those games it takes a certain type of player to <em>want to</em> power through the early hours and access the huge amount of value essentially locked behind repeated failure. Similar to how many <em>Demon&#8217;s Souls</em> players never progress past that game&#8217;s punishing first area, players not ready for the acrobatics and perseverance necessary to traverse the unforgiving bullet hell of <em>Returnal</em> may never escape its gloomy, restrictive first biome for the bright, open second one or glimpse its intriguing backstory. (I&#8217;ve included some tips below to help people get through the first hours.)</p>
<p>Compared with the steady progression and traditional storytelling of something like <em>AC: Valhalla</em> or <em>Miles Morales</em> this may put off less masochistic gamers or prompt more than a few controller-throwing, refund-requesting moments. After all, paying $70 for a game that slaps you in the face while you try to access the latter $50 worth of it can be justifiably frustrating.</p>
<p>With all that said, it is nice to see a AAA next-generation game that isn&#8217;t a sequel or franchise, and seeing the &#8220;roguelite&#8221; formula embraced seriously beyond the indie world. <em>Returnal</em> may not be for everyone, but for the subset of gamers who have embraced this genre for years, it&#8217;s an easy one to recommend.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Tips for playing:</strong></p>
<p>If you do decide to dive in, here are a handful of non-spoilery &#8220;wish I&#8217;d known that&#8221; tips to get you on the right track.</p>
<ul>
<li>There are lots of hidden rooms and items, so check your mini-map frequently for things you&#8217;ve missed in the chaos and peek in every nook and cranny.</li>
<li>When you&#8217;re undamaged, healing pickups contribute towards adding crucial max health — one more reason to not get hit.</li>
<li>New abilities create new opportunities in old areas — there&#8217;s a reason so much of the first biome is inaccessible at first.</li>
<li>You can get to those treasures behind bars. Look around carefully (and shoot everything).</li>
<li>&#8220;Malignant&#8221; treasure is usually more trouble than it&#8217;s worth and the debuffs can sink a run. Only do if desperate or you have a cure handy. (Parasites on the other hand can be very useful.)</li>
<li>There&#8217;s always a healing item for sale at the biome&#8217;s &#8220;shop,&#8221; so there&#8217;s no excuse for going into a boss room without one. (And self-healing artifacts will save your life five times over.)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/returnal-review-a-familiar-frantic-pleasure-but-a-risky-next-gen-debut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2143183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zynga and Rollic acquire the hyper-casual game studio behind High Heels</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/rollic-zynga-uncosoft/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/rollic-zynga-uncosoft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rollic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zynga]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, Zynga bought hyper-casual game maker Rollic. Today, Rollic is a Zynga subsidiary, and it&#8217;s announcing the acquisition of another game studio called Uncosoft. Like Rollic, Uncosoft develops hyper-casual games and is based in Turkey (Istanbul in Rollic&#8217;s case, Izmir in Uncosoft&#8217;s). In fact, Rollic has already published a couple of Uncosoft games, most [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Last year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/zynga-completes-rollic-acquistion/">Zynga bought hyper-casual game maker Rollic</a>. Today, <a href="https://rollicgames.com">Rollic</a> is a Zynga subsidiary, and it&#8217;s announcing the acquisition of another game studio called <a href="https://www.uncosoft.com">Uncosoft</a>.</p>
<p>Like Rollic, Uncosoft develops hyper-casual games and is based in Turkey (Istanbul in Rollic&#8217;s case, Izmir in Uncosoft&#8217;s). In fact, Rollic has already published a couple of Uncosoft games, most notably High Heels, in which the player navigates an obstacle course in increasingly ridiculous high heels — the company said High Heels (or, if you insist, High Heels!) has been downloaded more than 60 million times since it launched in January, and it&#8217;s even been praised for bringing <a href="https://www.inputmag.com/gaming/high-heels-app-game-queer-joy">&#8220;queer joy to the top of the App Store charts.&#8221;</a></p>
<p>Rollic co-founder and CEO Burak Vardal told me that when you&#8217;re in the hyper-casual gaming business, you&#8217;re &#8220;always looking for product-oriented teams.&#8221; And it sounds like Vardal is impressed by what he&#8217;s seen of the Uncosoft team, making him confident that it can successfully build &#8220;new titles like High Heels.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Producing a game together as development studio and publisher, you already start working like a merged company,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You argue about game design all day, you share strategies [&#8230;] and you — not on purpose — start learning about how that company operates, how are the founders, how is the art team.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KeQZWjGjEB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/zynga-completes-rollic-acquistion/">Zynga completes its acquisition of hyper-casual game maker Rollic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zynga completes its acquisition of hyper-casual game maker Rollic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/zynga-completes-rollic-acquistion/embed/#?secret=KeQZWjGjEB" data-secret="KeQZWjGjEB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Meanwhile, Uncosoft CEO Edip Enes Çakır said in a statement that there has been &#8220;unprecedented harmony&#8221; between the two teams as they&#8217;ve worked together in recent years, and that &#8220;our culture and vision of making global games will be augmented with the expertise of Rollic and Zynga.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rollic was actually <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/02/zynga-completes-rollic-acquistion/">Zynga&#8217;s fourth acquisition in Istanbul</a>, so it&#8217;s clear that the city and country are becoming a bit of a hub. Vardal said Rollic does have partners outside of Turkey, but he suggested that the country has been particularly successful with hyper-casual games because of <a href="https://www.dailysabah.com/education/2018/09/18/number-of-students-in-turkey-surpasses-population-of-143-countries">its huge student population</a>.</p>
<p>Vardal also suggested that High Heels points to a path that other hyper-casual games might follow to success: <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/8/22272980/high-heels-tiktok-ios-app-store-free-game">namely, TikTok</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;The animations of the game and the character mechanic are what we call TikTok-able,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It had a huge impact in Gen Z and huge organic reach in TikTok [&#8230;] The new generation wants content that feeds that ecosystem.&#8221;</p>
<p>The financial terms of the acquisition were not disclosed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="x6gOcVk1Sp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/zynga-q4-earnings/">Zynga CEO says he&#8217;s on the lookout for more acquisitions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Zynga CEO says he&#8217;s on the lookout for more acquisitions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/10/zynga-q4-earnings/embed/#?secret=x6gOcVk1Sp" data-secret="x6gOcVk1Sp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/rollic-zynga-uncosoft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145376</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX launches 60 more Starlink satellites</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international space station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starlink]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX has launched another batch of Starlink satellites, adding 60 more to the constellation on orbit. This is the 24th Starlink launch in total, and means SpaceX has now sent up over 1,500 Starlink spacecraft, with around 1,438 of those still in operation. This is the first Starlink launch since April 7 — which, surprisingly, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX has launched another batch of Starlink satellites, adding 60 more to the constellation on orbit. This is the 24th Starlink launch in total, and means SpaceX has now sent up over 1,500 Starlink spacecraft, with around 1,438 of those still in operation. This is the first Starlink launch since April 7 — which, surprisingly, is the biggest gap between these launches in quite a while.</p>
<p>This year, SpaceX&#8217;s overall launch calendar has been dominated by Starlink launches, as the company seeks to expand the availability, quality and coverage of its low Earth orbit broadband internet network. SpaceX also opened up availability of Starlink service this year, and now seems to be mostly supply-constrained on the consumer receiver terminal side, rather than necessarily on network capacity or regional ability.</p>
<p>Regarding that few week gap in the Starlink launch pace, it&#8217;s not like SpaceX was slacking in the meantime; the launcher sent up its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/spacex-successfully-launches-astronauts-with-a-re-used-dragon-spacecraft-for-the-first-time/">second crew of astronauts destined for the International Space Station in a flight just last week</a>. Plus, it has two three additional Starlink launches tentatively scheduled to happen in May.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5k8WXB4zs4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/spacex-successfully-launches-astronauts-with-a-re-used-dragon-spacecraft-for-the-first-time/">SpaceX successfully launches astronauts with a re-used Dragon spacecraft for the first time</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;SpaceX successfully launches astronauts with a re-used Dragon spacecraft for the first time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/spacex-successfully-launches-astronauts-with-a-re-used-dragon-spacecraft-for-the-first-time/embed/#?secret=5k8WXB4zs4" data-secret="5k8WXB4zs4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This latest launch took off from Cape Canaveral in Florida at 11:44 PM EDT (8:44 PM PDT) on Wednesday, and it used a flight-proven Falcon 9 first stage booster, which was used on six prior missions, including four Starlink launches.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/spacex-launches-60-more-starlink-satellites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145579</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vivid Money raises $73 million to build a European financial super app</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/vivid-money-raises-73-million-to-build-a-european-financial-super-app/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/vivid-money-raises-73-million-to-build-a-european-financial-super-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 11:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenger bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neobank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vivid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vivid Money]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[German startup Vivid Money has raised a new $73 million Series B funding round (€60 million) led by Greenoaks with existing investor Ribbit Capital also participating. Following today’s funding round, Vivid Money has reached a valuation of $436 million (€360 million). Vivid Money could be considered as a Revolut competitor designed specifically for the Eurozone. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">German startup <a href="https://vivid.money">Vivid Money</a> has raised a new $73 million Series B funding round (€60 million) led by Greenoaks with existing investor Ribbit Capital also participating. Following today’s funding round, Vivid Money has reached a valuation of $436 million (€360 million).</p>
<p>Vivid Money could be considered as a Revolut competitor designed specifically for the Eurozone. Built on top of <a href="https://www.solarisbank.com/en/">Solarisbank</a> for the banking infrastructure, the company lets you send, receive, spend, invest and save money in different ways.</p>
<p>When you create an account, you get a German IBAN that starts with DE as well as a metal card. There are no card details on the card itself —&nbsp;everything is available in the app instead. Like other fintech startups, Vivid Money lets you control your card from the app —&nbsp;you can lock it and unlock it, add it to Google Pay and Apple Pay, etc.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>After that, you can top up your account and hold dozens of different currencies. When you pay with your card abroad, the startup applies a small mark-up on the current exchange rate — you should get a better exchange rate than what you usually get with a regular bank.</p>
<p>In addition to this fairly standard feature set, Vivid Money offers stock trading with fractional shares. You can invest in stocks and ETFs and there’s no commission. Similarly, you can buy, hold and share cryptocurrencies from the app. The startup has partnered with CM Equity AG for those features.</p>
<p>The company also has a <a href="https://vivid.money/en-de/cashback/">cashback program</a> and a premium subscription for €9.90 per month. Paid users get higher limits on free cash withdrawals, the ability to create a virtual card, support for additional currencies and better cashback rewards.</p>
<p>Finally, users can create sub-accounts called pockets. You can move money around from one pocket to another and add other users to your pockets. Each pocket has its own IBAN, which means that you can pay for certain bills with a separate pocket. You can also associate your card with a specific pocket for upcoming purchases.</p>
<p>Vivid Money has managed to add a ton of features in no time. It now has a ton of money on its bank account. Now let’s see if it can attract a significant user base to compete with other, well-established European fintech players.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/vivid-money-raises-73-million-to-build-a-european-financial-super-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145569</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here are all the startups pitching today at Venture Day Minsk</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/here-are-all-the-startups-pitching-today-at-venture-day-minsk/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/here-are-all-the-startups-pitching-today-at-venture-day-minsk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 10:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2145563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Venture Day Minsk (organised by tech startup hub Imaguru) is run annually, but because of the pandemic and the political situation in Belarus it has gone virtual. Even Imaguru itself has had to switch to online-only operations after Lukashenko&#8217;s thugs shut down its physical space. If you want to support them, check out their startups, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://venturedayminsk.com/">Venture Day Minsk</a> (organised by tech startup hub <a href="https://imaguru.by/">Imaguru</a>) is run annually, but because of the pandemic and the political situation in Belarus it has gone virtual. Even Imaguru itself has had to switch to online-only operations after Lukashenko&#8217;s thugs <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/belarusian-regimes-thugs-shut-down-imaguru-the-countrys-key-startup-hub/">shut down its physical space</a>. If you want to support them, check out their startups, and maybe <a href="https://imaguru.myshopify.com/">grab a T-shirt</a>.</p>
<p>There are are always interesting startups to watch out of Belarus, a country which has produced startups like Splitmetrics, MSQRD, PingFin, DEIP and TrackDuck well as PandaDoc.</p>
<p>A run-down of who is pitching in below.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You can tune in to the live stream <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yWRS4diaIeE">here</a>. Investors can network with the startups <a href="https://venturedayminsk2021.dealroomevents.com/pub/d/signup?redirectUrl=%2F">here</a>. And you can join the startup pitches on Clubhouse <a href="https://www.joinclubhouse.com/event/M5Ka74wv">here</a>. On twitter the hashtag <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23vdminsk&amp;src=typed_query&amp;f=live">is here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Startups pitching:</strong></p>
<p>1 &#8211; <a href="https://www.teenup.app/index.html">TeenUP: </a>learning video platform teens-2-teens to unlock the teenagers’ potential and personality @TeenUP12</p>
<p>2 &#8211; <a href="https://dignity.tech/">Dignity</a>: app for Business &amp; Personal needs to talk, organize, sell, pay &amp; manage without middlemen, make your Digital life private and secure your Assets #dignity</p>
<p>3 &#8211; <a href="https://voxmate.com/">Voxmate</a>: an intuitive, gesture-based, Android app for people who are blind or visually impaired. It makes news, books, games and instant messaging accessible in a completely new way @voxmateapp</p>
<p>4 &#8211; <a href="https://labmap.me/">LabMap App</a>: app to explain laboratory tests in 24 hours in a clear language and monitor the state of health and the dynamics of biological indicators.</p>
<p>5 &#8211; Pigpughttps://pigpug.co/: AI neurofeedback brain training system for kids with ADHD and ASD @PigPugHealth</p>
<p>6 &#8211; <a href="https://cutt.ly/vbowJTu">SOVA App</a>: mobile app for overwhelmed, exhausted or anxious people to get stress relief fast and sleep well by night rituals  #sovaapp</p>
<p>7 &#8211; <a href="https://en.itgen.io/">Itgen</a>: an online edu platform for 1-1 live tutoring for kids from 8 to 16 years old @itgenik</p>
<p>8 &#8211; <a href="https://filmustage.com/">Filmustage</a>: app which highlights breakdown elements in movie/game screenplays in seconds, changing the process from breakdown creation to breakdown discussion @filmustage</p>
<p>9 &#8211; <a href="https://djinnsensor.com/">DjinnSensor</a>: IoT &amp; cloud solution to manage indoor environment #djinnsensor</p>
<p>10 &#8211; <a href="https://skinive.com/">Skinive</a>: a Skincare AI-Assistant, based on the DL &amp; CV technologies &amp; medical experience which enables you to check your skin spots within 30 seconds. @skinive1</p>
<p>11 &#8211; <a href="https://www.farba.me/">FARBA</a>: a professional apps design and prototyping tool  #farbaapp</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/29/here-are-all-the-startups-pitching-today-at-venture-day-minsk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2145563</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
