<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:53:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>EU fines BMW, VW $1B for running emissions cartel since the 90s</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/eu-fines-bmw-vw-1b-for-running-emissions-cartel-since-the-90s/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/eu-fines-bmw-vw-1b-for-running-emissions-cartel-since-the-90s/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daimler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Porsche]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volkswagen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As environmental issues really came of age in the 1990s, certain German automakers were meeting in secret groups to make sure their cars would continue to industriously contribute to greenhouse gas emissions. According to the European Union, Volkswagen, Audi, Porsche, BMW and Mercedes-Benz parent company Daimler have been illegally colluding to restrict competition in emission [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As environmental issues really came of age in the 1990s, certain German automakers were meeting in secret groups to make sure their cars would continue to industriously contribute to greenhouse gas emissions. According to the European Union, Volkswagen, Audi, Porsche, BMW and Mercedes-Benz parent company Daimler have been illegally colluding to restrict competition in emission cleaning for new diesel passenger cars, essentially slowing the deployment of cleaner emissions tech. On Thursday, <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_21_3581">the EU issued fines of $1 billion</a> (€875 million) to Volkswagen and BMW for their involvement in the emissions cartel.</p>
<p>“The five car manufacturers Daimler, BMW, Volkswagen, Audi and Porsche possessed the technology to reduce harmful emissions beyond what was legally required under EU emission standards,&#8221; said executive VP of the EU Commission Margrethe Vestager in a statement. &#8220;But they avoided to compete on using this technology&#8217;s full potential to clean better than what is required by law. So today&#8217;s decision is about how legitimate technical cooperation went wrong. And we do not tolerate it when companies collude. It is illegal under EU Antitrust rules. Competition and innovation on managing car pollution are essential for Europe to meet our ambitious Green Deal objectives. And this decision shows that we will not hesitate to take action against all forms of cartel conduct putting in jeopardy this goal.”</p>
<p>All parties acknowledged their involvement and agreed to settle. Volkswagen, which owns Audi and Porsche, will have to pay around $595 million, and BMW will pay $442 million. Daimler would have had to pay around $861 million, but the company is evading fines by being the whistleblower. So we guess Daimler just gets off scot-free?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/bmw-remained-profitable-2020-strong-half-76385265">BMW made a net profit of $4.62 billion last year</a>, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-22/volkswagen-posts-12-2-billion-profit-in-resilient-pandemic-year">and VW made about $12.2 billion</a> and nearly $23 billion in 2019, so this fine sort of feels like a slap on the wrist. And let us remember, this is not the first time VW has gotten into an emissions scandal.</p>
<p>In 2015, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency issued a notice of violation of the Clean Air Act to VW for intentionally adding software into its diesel engines to make it look like it was following emissions controls, when in reality its cars were actually producing far more than the legal amount.</p>
<p>In its action against the companies, the EU specifically homed in on the agreement reached by the companies on the sizes of tanks used for AdBlue, a solution that mixes with diesel car exhaust to neutralize harmful pollutants. The companies agreed not to compete on making cars cleaner even though they had the tech to do so.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.spiegel.de/wirtschaft/soziales/volkswagen-audi-porsche-bmw-und-daimler-unter-kartellverdacht-a-1159052.html">Der Spiegel first broke the news about the cartel in 2017</a>, and the companies set to work greenwashing. In the same year, all of the involved parties, as well as Ford Motor Company,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/11/03/bmw-daimler-ford-and-volkswagen-team-up-on-high-power-charging-network/"> joined forces to create a high-power charging network for EVs called Ionity</a>. The plan was to build and operate around 400 charging stations across Europe by 2020, but it looks like <a href="https://insideevs.com/news/454268/ionity-300-fast-charging-stations-europe/">Ionity only managed to install 300 across Europe</a>, and it even significantly increased the price of a charge by <a href="https://electrek.co/2020/01/17/ionity-increases-electric-vehicle-charging-prices-500-percent-january-31/">500% last year</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, VW&#8217;s heavy-truck business, the Traton Group, Daimler Truck and Volvo group joined up to invest nearly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/05/volvo-daimler-traton-invest-593-million-to-build-electric-truck-charging-network/">$593 million in a network of public charging stations</a> for electric heavy-duty long-haul trucks and buses around Europe.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZyvN8h9ztA"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/whats-fueling-hydrogen-tech/">What&#8217;s fueling hydrogen tech?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What&#8217;s fueling hydrogen tech?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/whats-fueling-hydrogen-tech/embed/#?secret=ZyvN8h9ztA" data-secret="ZyvN8h9ztA" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/eu-fines-bmw-vw-1b-for-running-emissions-cartel-since-the-90s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175371</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halo will launch a remotely operated car service powered by 5G in Las Vegas</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/halo-will-launch-a-remotely-operated-car-service-powered-by-5g-in-las-vegas/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/halo-will-launch-a-remotely-operated-car-service-powered-by-5g-in-las-vegas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 22:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5g]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Las Vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5G technology has generated a lot of hype for its potential to power driverless cars using a remote operator, but for the past few years that’s all it’s been — hype. Las Vegas-based startup Halo and telecom giant T-Mobile are teaming up to change that, with a driverless electric car service in Las Vegas powered [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">5G technology has generated a lot of hype for its potential to power driverless cars using a remote operator, but for the past few years that’s all it’s been — hype. Las Vegas-based startup Halo and telecom giant T-Mobile are teaming up to change that, with a driverless electric car service in Las Vegas powered on 5G to launch later this year.</p>
<p>The service, which will start with five vehicles, will work by connecting users to Halo’s pilot fleet of vehicles via an app. After a user has ordered a vehicle, a remote operator will drive it to the waiting customer. Once the car is delivered, the user can get behind the steering wheel and operate the vehicle as normal for the duration of their trip. When the trip is complete, the remote operator takes back over and drives it to the next waiting customer.</p>
<p><a href="https://halo.car/">Halo</a> departs significantly from companies like Waymo or Cruise, which are developing a full self-driving technology stack that aims to completely remove the human — remote or in-car — from the equation. Instead, Halo vehicles will be equipped with nine cameras, radars and ultrasonics as backup (no lidar), and it will connect to remote operators via T-Mobile’s Ultra Capacity midband 5G network.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Halo CEO Anand Nandakumar told TechCrunch that the service can also run on extended range low-band 5G network and on LTE as needed.</p>
<p>Halo said in a press release that its cars will be equipped with an algorithm that “learns in the background while humans control the vehicle, building a unique feedback loop to achieve Level 3 capabilities over time,” suggesting that the company has its sights set on autonomy in the long term. (“Level 3” refers to the Society of Automotive Engineers’ five levels of autonomous driving. L3 indicates features that allow the driver to be out of the loop under very limited conditions.)</p>
<p>“Full autonomy is a massive challenge from both a technical and social-trust perspective that won’t be solved for years to come,” Nandakumar said in the release. “But Halo has been designed to address these challenges by building automation over time starting with a solution that consumers will feel comfortable using today.”</p>
<p>The startup also said its vehicles will be equipped with an advanced safe stop mechanism, which will immediately bring cars to a full stop if a potential safety hazard is detected.</p>
<p>Last year, Halo joined the 5G Open Innovation Lab T-Mobile co-founded, giving the startup access to the telecom’s engineers and midspectrum network. Nandakumar declined to specify if T-Mobile is one of the company’s investors.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L4KDZLUOQu"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/for-successful-ai-projects-celebrate-your-graveyard-and-be-prepared-to-fail-fast/">For successful AI projects, celebrate your graveyard and be prepared to fail fast</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;For successful AI projects, celebrate your graveyard and be prepared to fail fast&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/for-successful-ai-projects-celebrate-your-graveyard-and-be-prepared-to-fail-fast/embed/#?secret=L4KDZLUOQu" data-secret="L4KDZLUOQu" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/halo-will-launch-a-remotely-operated-car-service-powered-by-5g-in-las-vegas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175351</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Indian food delivery startup Zomato will seek post-IPO valuation up to $8.6B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/daily-crunch-28/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/daily-crunch-28/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 22:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for July 8, 2021. Forget about Hot ___ Summer. It’s Hot <em>IPO</em> Summer in technology land, and today’s news underscores just how inviting the global exit market is proving to be.</p>
<p>But before we get into the TechCrunch Top 3, the good news from the site is that our latest super-deep company teardown, or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/ec1/">EC-1</a>, is live. This time, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/">we looked at NS1</a>, a company that we wrote is building “a strategic node at the core of the modern web delivery tech stack.” The whole series is fire. &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fJ5q7S8iIt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/">The NS1 EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NS1 EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/embed/#?secret=fJ5q7S8iIt" data-secret="fJ5q7S8iIt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">3</span></h2>
<p>When we said it was IPO season, we weren’t kidding. Here’s the day’s biggest exit news, which has a theme, as you’ll see:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/instacart-hires-facebook-executive-as-new-ceo-ahead-of-expected-ipo/">Instacart hires new CEO as it preps to go public:</a></strong><strong> </strong>Big news from the world of grocery delivery today as longtime Instacart CEO and co-founder Apoorva Mehta promoted himself to chairman of the company’s board. Facebook exec Fidji Simo is taking the helm. Back during my first stint at TechCrunch, Mehta would send me Facebook messages when his company added new Bay Area markets. How times change!</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/zomato-ipo/">India’s Zomato sets IPO price range:</a> </strong>The day’s <em>other</em> big news from the world of delivery comes from India’s Zomato, which will price its IPO “shares in the range of 72 Indian rupees (96 cents) to 76 ($1) and is targeting an upper limit valuation of $8.56 billion,” TechCrunch reports.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/circle-is-a-good-example-of-why-spacs-can-be-useful/"><strong>Crypto-powered Circle is going public via a SPAC:</strong></a><strong> </strong>If you are a crypto-minded person, you’ve heard of Circle. If you aren’t, it’s the company that bought SeedInvest and is helping build stablecoin USDC. It’s going public via a SPAC at a multibillion-dollar valuation. Call it riding the Coinbase wave.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>Flipping the script and going back to the earlier stages of startup life, here’s a rundown of news from startup land:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/powerz-raises-8-3-million-for-its-video-game-focused-on-education/"><strong>PowerZ raises $8.3M to fuse gaming and education:</strong></a> The French startup is both a gaming company<em> and </em>edtech startup. The startup thinks that “educational games will become mainstream really quickly,” TechCrunch reports. This makes sense: I have learned more about the Middle Ages from Crusader Kings III than any book I’ve read.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/rootly-nabs-3-2m-seed-to-build-sre-incident-management-solution-inside-slack/">Rootly raises $3.2M to bring SRE tooling into Slack:</a> </strong>Look, we all live inside of Slack or Teams, so why not bring more functionality into the services? Rootly wants to bring “an incident-response solution inside” of the work platform that Salesforce is buying. The round and company are neat, as is the fact that startups are building atop Slack itself.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/homebrew-leads-z1s-effort-to-bring-digital-banking-to-latin-americas-teens/"><strong>Z1 wants to bring fintech to LatAm zoomers:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Homebrew is putting early-stage money to work in Latin America in hopes that Z1 can mimic what Nubank has managed in the region, namely <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/08/fintech-all-star-nubank-raises-a-750m-mega-round/">build a fintech titan and raise a zillion dollars</a>. Per TechCrunch, Z1 was a recent Y Combinator grad, which means that Homebrew acquired around 0.8 bips worth of equity in the $2.5 million the transaction. We kid.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/popshop-live-raises-around-20m-at-a-100m-valuation-for-its-livestream-shopping-platform-for-hipsters/"><strong>Popshop Live raises $20M for modern QVC:</strong></a> Now worth around $100 million, Popshop Live has built a “standalone business that taps into the millennial taste for shopping from smaller and more edgy brands and individuals as much as bigger retailers.” With new capital and retailer momentum, it’s a startup to watch.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/smile-identity-raises-7m-to-build-kyc-and-identity-verification-tools-for-africa/"><strong>Smile Identity raises $7M Series A to verify identities:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Focused on the African market, Smile Identity has put together a lettered round for KYC and ID services on the continent. TechCrunch reports that Costanoa Ventures co-led the deal with CRE Venture Capital.</li>
</ul>
<p>To close out, Natasha <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_/status/1413195928651980800">scooped</a> that “Peter Boyce II has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/peter-boyce-stellation-capital/">left General Catalyst to start his own firm</a>, a little over a year after the venture capital firm promoted him to partner.” It’s a busy week for new venture funds, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/acrylic-debut-crypto-fund/">Acrylic</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/06/renegade-partners-rolls-out-its-much-anticipated-debut-fund-with-100-million/">Renegade</a> also making news.</p>
<h2>The NS1 EC-1</h2>
<p>For the latest entry in our series of long-form articles that explore the inner workings of notable startups, we looked at NS1, an internet infrastructure company best known for its software-defined domain name services (DNS).</p>
<p><strong>Part 1: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/">Origin story:</a></strong> How three engineers decided to rebuild the internet&#8217;s core addressing system.</p>
<p><strong>Part 2: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-product/">Product development and roadmap:</a></strong> Experimentation, open-source efforts and expanding beyond DNS.</p>
<p><strong>Part 3: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-competition/">Competitive landscape:</a></strong> A look at the broader internet infrastructure market.</p>
<p><strong>Part 4: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-customers/">Customer development:</a></strong> How their top competitor&#8217;s stumble became &#8220;the gift that kept on giving.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about how NS1 transformed &#8220;a slumbering and dreary yet reliable aspect of the internet&#8221; into &#8220;a strategic moat and an enterprise win&#8221; in just eight years, read on.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fJ5q7S8iIt"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/">The NS1 EC-1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The NS1 EC-1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/embed/#?secret=fJ5q7S8iIt" data-secret="fJ5q7S8iIt" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> <em>You can sign up here</em></a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>A few notes from Big Tech before we wrap our news coverage. Enjoy:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/dropbox-is-reimagining-the-workplace-with-dropbox-studios/"><strong>Dropbox reinvents work(places):</strong></a> No, not in the product sense, but in terms of how it is approaching offices as COVID slowly wanes. The result? Something that looks more like a fancy, private coffee spot than an office. I demand that all companies mimic this immediately.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/beyond-meat-launches-plant-based-chicken-tenders-at-us-restaurants/"><strong>Tendies from $BYND:</strong></a> Yep, Beyond Meat has launched plant-based “chicken” tenders at some 400 U.S. restaurants. The company, long a public firm and thus befitting of our Big Tech moniker, has had a tumultuous life since it went public. Its shares have traded as high as $239 since it debuted. Today, the company is still worth a healthy $140 per share, far above its original $25 IPO price.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>TechCrunch wants to help startups find the right expert for their needs. To do this, we’re building a shortlist of the top growth marketers. We’ve received great recommendations for growth marketers in the startup industry since we launched our survey.</p>
<p>We’re excited to read more responses as they come in! <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">Fill out the survey here.</a></p>
<p>Our editorial coverage about growth marketing includes articles from the TechCrunch team, guest columns and posts like “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/">Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</a>” by <a href="https://twitter.com/njcostelloe">Nick Costelloe</a> on Extra Crunch. If you’re interested in writing a column, learn more <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/04/domain-experts-wanted-submit-your-guest-articles-to-extra-crunch/?tpcc=ECTW2020">here</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ejM0Xh6FN5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/">Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/embed/#?secret=ejM0Xh6FN5" data-secret="ejM0Xh6FN5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/daily-crunch-28/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Demand Curve: How to double conversions on your startup&#8217;s homepage</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/demand-curve-how-to-double-conversions-on-your-startups-homepage/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/demand-curve-how-to-double-conversions-on-your-startups-homepage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 20:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Want to convert twice as many visitors into customers? Follow these copywriting tactics.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Nick Costelloe</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/njcostelloe">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Nick writes actionable growth marketing insights as head of content at<a href="http://demandcurve.com/"> Demand Curve</a>. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/">Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Between our work at<a href="http://demandcurve.com/"> Demand Curve</a> and our agency,<a href="http://bellcurve.com/"> Bell Curve</a>, we&#8217;ve rewritten over 1,000 websites for startups across most industries.</p>
<p>Want to convert twice as many visitors into customers? Follow these copywriting tactics.</p>
<h2>Everything &#8220;above the fold&#8221; must have a purpose</h2>
<p>The section of your homepage that&#8217;s immediately visible to a visitor before they start scrolling is called &#8220;above the fold.” (Think of a print newspaper: Everything above the literal fold in the paper is the most important information.) When a visitor sees the content above the fold, they decide to either keep scrolling or exit your site.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In seconds, they&#8217;re trying to figure out what you do and whether you’re a fit for them.</p>
<p>The most common mistake we see startups make? Their “above the fold” is either uninteresting or confusing. This often happens when marketers attempt to squeeze too much content above the fold.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The most common mistake we see startups make? Their “above the fold” is either uninteresting or confusing.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The truth is, most of the information on your website is irrelevant to new visitors. So the area above the fold should be used to explain how you can help new visitors solve a specific problem.</p>
<p>For example, you might see a homepage that promotes the newest technical blog post that the company published. But that&#8217;s not useful to a visitor who doesn&#8217;t yet understand what you do.</p>
<p>To further confuse the visitor, many companies add an extensive navigation bar to the top of their site. In theory, this allows your visitors to easily access any part of your website. In practice, it leads to decision fatigue and low conversion rates.</p>
<p>Unless the content directly helps answer what you do and whether you&#8217;re a good fit for that visitor, it should be removed.</p>
<p>There are three things you can do to improve the conversion rate of your homepage:</p>
<ol>
<li>Craft a sharp header.</li>
<li>Use a complementary subheader.</li>
<li>Design with intention.</li>
</ol>
<p>Let&#8217;s get into the tactics of these three areas of improvement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Write headers that speak to an individual (not a crowd)</h2>
<p>Your header is the largest piece of text on your website. In under 10 words (about the longest we&#8217;d recommend), your header needs to accomplish three things:</p>
<h3>1. Identify how customers get value from your product.</h3>
<p>This is your most important value proposition. If you can&#8217;t explain how someone gets value from your product in fewer than 10 words, it&#8217;ll be a challenge to keep visitors&#8217; attention for much longer.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s how we uncover your key value proposition:</p>
<ul>
<li>What bad alternative do people resort to when they lack your product?</li>
<li>How is your product better than the bad alternative?</li>
<li>Now turn the last step into an action statement — that&#8217;s your value proposition.</li>
</ul>
<p>Take Airbnb:</p>
<ul>
<li>The bad alternative is being stuck in a sterile hotel without experiencing any real culture.</li>
<li>Airbnb&#8217;s product is better than the bad alternative because it allows you to stay in a local’s home.</li>
<li>So if we turn the second question into an action statement, we&#8217;d get a value proposition like: Experience new cities like a local.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are some more examples from top startups:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175032" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175032" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2175032 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="823" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png 1702w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png?resize=150,121 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png?resize=300,241 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png?resize=768,617 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png?resize=680,547 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png?resize=1536,1235 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-1.png?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175032" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h3>2. Include an enticing hook that keeps visitors reading.</h3>
<p>Telling your visitors what you do is a good start, but now we need to get them excited about your product.</p>
<p>A huge missed opportunity we see a lot of startups make with their website copy? It&#8217;s not action oriented. In a world where customers can shop 24/7, there&#8217;s very little urgency for your visitors to take action now.</p>
<p>Adding a hook will increase the likelihood that a visitor buys from you on their first visit.</p>
<p>There are two ways we like to write hooks:</p>
<ul>
<li>Offer a bold claim: something highly specific that triggers the thought, &#8220;Wow, I didn&#8217;t know that was possible.”</li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2175034" style="width: 625px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175034" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175034" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-2.png" alt="" width="615" height="346" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-2.png 615w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-2.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-2.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-2.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175034" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<ul>
<li>Or address common objections: questions or pushback that your visitor is likely already thinking about. Addressing objections right away might seem counterintuitive, but bringing attention to your weaknesses will actually make your visitor trust your brand more. With no direct sales team, your copy is going to need to work hard to answer as many questions as possible.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are some value propositions of top startups that incorporate their biggest objections upfront.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175035" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175035" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2175035 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png" alt="" width="1024" height="765" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png 1694w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png?resize=150,112 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png?resize=300,224 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png?resize=768,574 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png?resize=680,508 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png?resize=1536,1148 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-3.png?resize=50,37 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175035" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h3>3. Speak directly to your ideal customer persona</h3>
<p>To truly make the message in your header grab the attention of your visitor, rewrite your value proposition to speak directly to your customer personas.</p>
<p>To do so, list your top two to three customer personas. Rewrite your headers to address the part of your product they value most. Use their own language, not industry jargon. The best way to learn what your customers love about your product is through one-on-one customer interviews or reading customer success tickets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="4ckLIedx1Y"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/">Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Demand Curve: 10 lies you’ve been told about marketing&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/10-lies-youve-been-told-about-marketing/embed/#?secret=4ckLIedx1Y" data-secret="4ckLIedx1Y" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Now you&#8217;ve got headers that speak directly to your ideal customer persona. You can either A/B test which header leads to a higher conversion rate or create custom landing pages using each header to drive traffic from different sources to specific pages.</p>
<p>For example, if you include a link to your website in a guest blog post, send that audience to the page with the most relevant header.</p>
<p>Here are some examples of writing multiple value propositions for the same startup:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175036" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175036" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175036" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png" alt="" width="1024" height="721" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png 1704w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png?resize=768,541 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png?resize=680,479 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png?resize=1536,1082 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-4.png?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175036" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h2>Use a subheader to explain how your header can be possible</h2>
<p>We suggest spending about 50% of your time working on writing the header and 25% of your time on the subheader. Why? Because if your header isn&#8217;t interesting, your visitors won&#8217;t even bother reading the subheader.</p>
<p>Your subheader should be used to expand on two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>How does your product work <em>exactly</em>?</li>
<li>Which of your features make our header&#8217;s bold claim believable?</li>
</ol>
<p>You can use your top two to three features to explain how your header is achieved.</p>
<p>For example, let&#8217;s say Airbnb&#8217;s header is: Experience your getaway vacation like a local. No minimum stays.</p>
<p>To make this statement believable, we need to explain how it&#8217;s possible to vacation like a local and how &#8220;no minimum stays&#8221; is possible.</p>
<p>A subheader could read something like: An online rental marketplace with thousands of short-term rentals in your area.</p>
<p>Do not use industry jargon or technical terms in your subheader or header. Use words that a fifth-grade reader would understand. Use short sentences. Lengthy paragraphs will kill the momentum of your reader.</p>
<p>Here are a few more examples of using the subheader to explain the header:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175037" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175037" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175037" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png" alt="" width="1024" height="586" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png 1696w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png?resize=300,172 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png?resize=768,439 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png?resize=680,389 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png?resize=1536,878 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-5.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175037" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
<h2>Make your homepage feel familiar and function as expected</h2>
<p>The last aspect to consider when creating a high-converting homepage is the design. We see a lot of high-tech startups try to use their website to show off their creativity.</p>
<p>From our experience, your website is not the place to try to be original.</p>
<p>A website&#8217;s design should rarely be unique. It&#8217;s your <em>product</em> that should be unique. Your website is just a familiar medium for communicating your product&#8217;s uniqueness.</p>
<h3>Functionality</h3>
<p>Using familiar buttons and navigation that other websites have popularized will save your visitor the hassle of having to learn how your website works. For example, we&#8217;ve come to expect there to be a &#8220;home&#8221; button in the top left of the page. Attempting to place the same button in the bottom right for the sake of uniqueness will lead to confusion and possibly a lost customer. Stick with what works.</p>
<h3>Images</h3>
<p>Consider these goals when adding images to your homepage:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove uncertainty by showing your product in action. GIFs or looping videos are a terrific way of demonstrating how it works without taking up any additional space.
<p><div id="attachment_2175038" style="width: 862px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175038" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175038" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-6.gif" alt="" width="852" height="752" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175038" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://judy.co/">Judy</a></p></div></li>
<li>If you sell physical goods, use images to show off various use cases and close-ups of the material and texture. This will help your visitor assess the quality of the product and further validate that the product is right for them.</li>
</ul>
<p><div id="attachment_2175040" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175040" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175040" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png" alt="" width="1024" height="542" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png?resize=150,79 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png?resize=768,406 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png?resize=680,360 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png?resize=1536,813 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-7.png?resize=50,26 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175040" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.allbirds.com/">Allbirds</a></p></div></p>
<h3>Call-to-action buttons</h3>
<p>Your call-to-action buttons (CTA) are where you&#8217;ll convert a visitor of your webpage into an active shopper. Therefore, your CTAs should be a continuation of the magic that you teased in your header copy.</p>
<p>Make the CTA button copy action focused and tell your visitor what will happen once they click it.</p>
<p>Here are some examples of CTA buttons that feel natural because they continue the narrative that began with the header copy:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175041" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175041" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175041" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png" alt="" width="1024" height="411" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png 1684w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png?resize=150,60 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png?resize=300,120 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png?resize=768,308 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png?resize=680,273 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png?resize=1536,617 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/DC-8.png?resize=50,20 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175041" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Demand Curve</p></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/demand-curve-how-to-double-conversions-on-your-startups-homepage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175030</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can advertising scale in VR?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 20:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Augmented Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Marketing Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtual reality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bottom line: VR usage needs more scale before ad revenue makes a dent.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Michael Boland</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/arinsider">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mike Boland is chief analyst of <a href="https://artillry.co/intelligence/">ARtillery Intelligence</a>, an AR/VR research firm.	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/15/your-in-car-attention-is-medias-next-battleground/">Your in-car attention is media&#8217;s next battleground</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/25/mobile-and-enterprise-are-the-keys-to-vrar-scale/">Mobile and enterprise are the keys to VR/AR scale</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">One of VR&#8217;s prospective revenue streams is ad placement. The thought is that its levels of immersion can engender high engagement with various flavors of display ads. Think billboards in a virtual streetscape or sporting venue. Art imitates life, and all that.</p>
<p>This topic reemerged recently in the wake of Facebook&#8217;s<a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/blaston-in-game-vr-facebook-advertising-reverse-course/"> experimental ads</a> in Blaston VR. As TechCrunch&#8217;s Lucas Matney<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebooks-entry-into-vr-advertising-isnt-going-too-well/"> observed</a>, it didn&#8217;t go too well. The move triggered a resounding backlash, followed by the game publisher, Resolution Games,<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/facebooks-entry-into-vr-advertising-isnt-going-too-well/"> backing out</a> of the trial.</p>
<p>This chain of events underscored Facebook&#8217;s headwinds in VR ad monetization, which stem from its broader ad issues. In fairness, this was an experimental move to test the VR advertising waters … which Facebook accomplished, though it didn’t get the result it wanted.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			VR advertising is a bit of a double-edged sword. It could take several years for VR usage to reach requisite levels for meaningful ad monetization.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Regardless, we&#8217;ve taken this opportunity to revisit our<a href="https://artillry.co/artillry-intelligence/vr-global-revenue-forecast-2019-2024/"> ongoing analysis</a> and market sizing of VR advertising in general. The short version: There are pros and cons on both qualitative and quantitative levels.</p>
<h2>The pros of VR advertising</h2>
<p>VR advertising&#8217;s opportunity goes back to factors noted above: potentially high ad engagement given inherent levels of immersion. On that measure, VR<a href="https://www.marketingdive.com/news/study-vr-ads-aid-same-day-recall-for-70-of-users/507755/"> exceeds</a> all other media, which can mean higher-quality impressions, brand recall and other common display-ad metrics.</p>
<p>Historical evidence also suggests that VR could follow a path toward ad monetization. VR shows similar patterns to media that were increasingly ad supported as they matured. These include video, social media, mobile apps and games (just ask Unity).</p>
<p>To put some numbers behind that, <a href="https://arinsider.co/2020/03/06/xr-talks-will-vr-follow-mobiles-monetization-path/">75%</a> of apps in the Apple App Store&#8217;s first year were paid apps &#8212; similar to VR today. That figure declined to 15% in 2014 and hovers around 10% today. Over time, developers learned they could reach scale through free downloads.</p>
<p>Prevalent revenue models today include in-app purchases &#8212; especially in mobile gaming &#8212; and advertising. The question is whether VR will follow a similar path as developers learn that they can reach scale faster through free apps that employ &#8220;back-end monetization&#8221; like ad support.</p>
<p>This trend also follows audience dynamics: Early adopters are more likely to pay for content and experiences. But as a given technology or media matures, its transition to mainstream audiences requires different business models with less upfront commitment and friction.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today, there are only about 18% of applications in VR stores such as Steam and Oculus that are free,&#8221;<a href="https://arinsider.co/2020/03/06/xr-talks-will-vr-follow-mobiles-monetization-path/"> Admix CEO Samuel Huber said</a>. &#8220;This is fine for now because we are still very early in the market and most of these users are early adopters. They are willing to pay for content, just like they were willing to pay for prototype unproven hardware and generally, they have higher purchasing power than the average person.”</p>
<h2>Drawbacks of VR advertising</h2>
<p>Considering the above advantages, VR advertising is a bit of a double-edged sword (or beat saber). Those advantages are counterbalanced by a few practical disadvantages in the medium&#8217;s early stage. Much of this comes down to the requirement for scale.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/can-advertising-scale-in-vr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: TV Clubhouse</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/gillmor-gang-tv-clubhouse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/gillmor-gang-tv-clubhouse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 18:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Leary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denis Pombriant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank radice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Teare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Markman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gillmor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Gang spends a lot of time these days on the streaming wars, so it seems appropriate that Congress wants to get into it. With Netflix’s success at overturning the structure of Hollywood’s broadcast television production and advertising processes, consumers are taking advantage of a Golden Age of choices. Senator Elizabeth Warren is resuscitating her [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MxaOdI1qcUw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>The Gang spends a lot of time these days on the streaming wars, so it seems appropriate that Congress wants to get into it. With Netflix’s success at overturning the structure of Hollywood’s broadcast television production and advertising processes, consumers are taking advantage of a Golden Age of choices. Senator Elizabeth Warren is resuscitating her plan to tax the billionaire class as a way to fund the progressive part of the infrastructure bill through the Democrat-only reconciliation process. As bait, she is using Amazon’s MGM acquisition as the carrot, suggesting the deal would be anti-competitive and dilutive of consumer choice. Coming as streaming passes broadcast as a percentage of the entire television market, it’s not clear just what consumers are going to lose with a smorgasbord of captivating programming choices.</p>
<p>The streaming heavyweights are in the throes of a transition from building audience to locking in paying customers. Netflix has jumped way out in front with an enormous audience fueling an equally gigantic investment in original programming. Apple TV+ has blinked earliest, moving their free trial of a year with a new Apple device purchase to 3 months, barely long enough to get halfway through the second season of their hit The Morning Show. Similar Disney+ deals with Verizon Wireless unlimited broadband upgrades are starting to time out as Disney tries to survive the pandemic’s impact on theme park revenue and steep costs of moving newly acquired properties from theaters to streaming, And then there are the rest of the old studio and network players, trying to build enough scale to compete with the leaders. Comcast consumed NBC and Universal Studios, CBS and Viacom merged to knit together broadcast, cable networks, and Paramount studios, now renamed Paramount +. And reality TV giant Discovery absorbed the remnants of WarnerMedia’s scripted studio and cable operation as AT&amp;T backed away from content to pay for investment in 5G.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Ironically, ad-supported networks may turn out to be where the real action is. Although streaming subscribers are running up against a budget cap as they opt out of cable bundles, their antipathy for advertising is finessed by some midtier networks like Hulu and Paramount + mixing some ads with subscriptions at a reduced monthly charge. Comcast is already managing that transition with HBO Max, bundling the new streaming network with basic cable packages that include the HBO premium service. Combining HBO’s pre-pandemic windowed, or delayed from theatrical release feature films with original series programming is one thing: adding a monthly new feature simultaneously with theatrical release for all of 2021 has proven a powerful way of attracting new HBO Max subscribers in the battle for streaming. While the strategy will moderate in 2022 as theaters reopen, movie-goers are learning to appreciate the marriage of smaller titles with the convenience of subscription television.</p>
<p>Although big budget films like F9 are enjoying considerable success theatrically, smaller films like Parasite and other streaming releases are winning Oscars and other awards. Films have been eligible for Oscars and Golden Globes without the requirement of theatrical runs during the pandemic, and will continue for at least one more year. The HBO Max theater/digital gambit angered producers and talent with its bold move made easier during 2020’s lockdown, but WarnerMedia CEO Jason Kilar was apparently the loser in AT&amp;T’s Discovery/WarnerMedia deal as Discovery’s CEO David Zaslav was picked to run the combined company. But audiences may find more affinity with popcorn at home than the distributors expect as vaccinations take root. Kilar may have bootstrapped a look at what success will mean in the New Normal similar to what companies are saving in travel and facilities costs as we incorporate the strengths of work/play-from-anywhere and the mobile transformation.</p>
<p>The ad streamers bring more to the party than just subscriber discounts. While Netflix has made hay with binge viewing (dumping an entire season of shows at one time) ad streamers are using a hybrid of binge production and broadcast-style staged release as a way of updating the feel of appointment television with Peak TV dynamics. Using the weekly series model a la This Is Us and Gray’s Anatomy, shows like Paramount +‘s The Good Fight are released on a weekly basis with the release night staggered across the key nights of the week. Instead of browsing the TV Guide, you get a notification that the new episode has “dropped.” In effect, the linear tv schedule so beloved by advertisers and marketers is creating a new prime time schedule across the variety of streaming networks. With constant mergers and realignment of studios, cable assets, and streaming models, we already don’t have a clue what network is screening our new shows let alone what the network is called this week, so mobile messaging becomes the point of sale for sharing digital experiences. With cable giants like Comcast deriving more and more broadband customers as cable cutting persists, and set top boxes like AppleTV and Roku smart tvs capturing more scale and competing for a combination of ad-supported and original programming, the built in microphone on their remotes leapfrogs the vanished TV guides with audio commands that require only the name of the show or even the name of the favorite star.</p>
<p>The creator economy is experiencing a surge of services across the social networks. Newsletters, conversational audio sites, and new notification services from Apple are promoting media to support these AI-driven user rankings of the new Hollywood streaming winners. Apple’s notification summary screens in iOS 15 effectively present a way to organize a personalized digest of show notifications, freeing you from interrupting work to track the weekly dropping of favorite shows. It won’t be long before Twitter and other newsletter tools let you broadcast those alerts to special groups you define for watercooler-like conversations about the latest spoilers. Clubhouse and other social audio rooms will invite media analysts, showrunners, and stars to interact with these newly empowered fans, and some of the more proficient will graduate to subscription newsletter recaps and transcribed interviews. Advertisers will sponsor these streams, expanding the impact of the intersection of subscription and ad-supported hybrid services.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><strong><em>from the <a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang/issues/gillmor-gang-newsletter-revue-10-677620"> Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center">__________________</p>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Frank Radice, Michael Markman, Keith Teare, Denis Pombriant, Brent Leary and Steve Gillmor. Recorded live Friday, June 18, 2021.</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p>@fradice, @mickeleh, @denispombriant, @kteare, @brentleary, @stevegillmor, @gillmorgang</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.getrevue.co/profile/gillmorgang">Subscribe to the new Gillmor Gang Newsletter</a></strong> and join the backchannel <a href="https://t.me/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> on Telegram.</p>
<p><a href="http://facebook.com/gillmorgang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gillmor Gang on Facebook</a> … and here’s our sister show <a href="http://facebook.com/g3show" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">G3 on Facebook</a>.<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2012361" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg 1920w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/F06D2685-6169-42C0-AE3B-D2545A1B3534.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/gillmor-gang-tv-clubhouse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175287</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evernote quietly disappeared from an anti-surveillance lobbying group&#8217;s website</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/evernote-surveillance-lobbying/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/evernote-surveillance-lobbying/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 18:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edward Snowden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evernote]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass surveillance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Security Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transparency report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA FREEDOM Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington D.C.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2013, eight tech companies were accused of funneling their users&#8217; data to the U.S. National Security Agency under the so-called PRISM program, according to highly classified government documents leaked by NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden. Six months later, the tech companies formed a coalition under the name Reform Government Surveillance, which as the name would [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In 2013, eight tech companies were accused of funneling their users&#8217; data to the U.S. National Security Agency under the so-called PRISM program, according to highly classified government documents leaked by NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden. Six months later, the tech companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/12/08/tech-companies-outline-more-nsa-reform-demands/">formed a coalition</a> under the name Reform Government Surveillance, which as the name would suggest was to lobby lawmakers for reforms to government surveillance laws.</p>
<p>The idea was simple enough: to call on lawmakers to limit surveillance to targeted threats rather than conduct a dragnet collection of Americans&#8217; private data, provide greater oversight and allow companies to be more transparent about the kinds of secret orders for user data that they receive.</p>
<p>Apple, Facebook, Google, LinkedIn, Microsoft, Twitter, Yahoo and AOL (to later become Verizon Media, which owns TechCrunch — <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/private-equity-firm-apollo-agrees-to-buy-verizon-media-assets-for-5-billion/">for now</a>) were the founding members of <a href="https://www.reformgovernmentsurveillance.com/">Reform Government Surveillance</a>, or RGS, and over the years added Amazon, Dropbox, Evernote, Snap and Zoom as members.</p>
<p>But then sometime in June 2019, Evernote quietly disappeared from the RGS website without warning. What&#8217;s even more strange is that nobody noticed for two years, not even Evernote.</p>
<p>&#8220;We hadn&#8217;t realized our logo had been removed from the Reform Government Surveillance website,&#8221; said an Evernote spokesperson, when reached for comment by TechCrunch. &#8220;We are still members.&#8221;</p>
<p>Evernote <a href="https://www.reformgovernmentsurveillance.com/evernote-joins-the-reform-government-surveillance/">joined the coalition</a> in October 2014, a year and a half after PRISM first came to public light, even though the company was never named in the leaked Snowden documents. Still, Evernote was a powerful ally to have onboard, and showed RGS that its support for reforming government surveillance laws was gaining traction outside of the companies named in the leaked NSA files. Evernote cites its membership of RGS in its <a href="https://evernote.com/privacy/transparency-report">most recent transparency report</a> and that it supports efforts to &#8220;reform practices and laws regulating government surveillance of individuals and access to their information&#8221; — which makes its disappearance from the RGS website all the more bizarre.</p>
<p>TechCrunch also asked the other companies in the RGS coalition if they knew why Evernote was removed and all either didn&#8217;t respond, wouldn&#8217;t comment or had no idea. A spokesperson for one of the RGS companies said they weren&#8217;t all that surprised since companies &#8220;drop in and out of trade associations.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175238" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175238" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2175238 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="789" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg 2212w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg?resize=150,116 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg?resize=300,231 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg?resize=768,592 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg?resize=680,524 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg?resize=1536,1183 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg?resize=2048,1578 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rgs-members.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175238" class="wp-caption-text">The website of the Reform Government Surveillance coalition, which features Amazon, Apple, Dropbox, Facebook, Google, Microsoft, Snap, Twitter, Verizon Media and Zoom, but not Evernote, which is also a member. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p>
<p>While that may be true — companies often sign on to lobbying efforts that ultimately help their businesses; government surveillance is one of those rare thorny issues that got some of the biggest names in Silicon Valley rallying behind the cause. After all, few tech companies have openly and actively advocated for an increase in government surveillance of their users, since it&#8217;s the users themselves who are asking for more privacy baked into the services they use.</p>
<p>In the end, the reason for Evernote&#8217;s removal seems remarkably benign.</p>
<p>&#8220;Evernote has been a longtime member — but they were less active over the last couple of years, so we removed them from the website,&#8221; said an email from Monument Advocacy, a Washington, D.C. lobbying firm that represents RGS. &#8220;Your inquiry has helped to prompt new conversations between our organizations and we&#8217;re looking forward to working together more in the future.&#8221;</p>
<p>Monument has been involved with RGS since near the beginning after it was hired by the RGS coalition of companies to lobby for changes to surveillance laws in Congress. Monument has spent $2.2 million in lobbying to date since it began work with RGS in 2014, <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/federal-lobbying/clients/issues?cycle=2018&amp;id=F193676">according to OpenSecrets</a>, specifically on lobbying lawmakers to push for changes to bills under congressional consideration, such as changes to the Patriot Act and the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act, or FISA, albeit with mixed success. RGS <a href="https://www.reformgovernmentsurveillance.com/statement-of-reform-government-surveillance-on/">supported</a> the USA Freedom Act, a bill designed to curtail some of the NSA&#8217;s collection under the Patriot Act, but was unsuccessful in <a href="https://www.reformgovernmentsurveillance.com/statement-on-the-fisa-amendments-reauthorization/">its opposition</a> to the reauthorization of Section 702 of FISA, the powers that allow the NSA to collect intelligence on foreigners living outside the United States, which was reauthorized <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/16/senate-fisa-section-702-cloture-vote-wyden-paul/">for six years</a> in 2018.</p>
<p>RGS has been largely quiet for the past year — issuing just <a href="https://www.reformgovernmentsurveillance.com/importance-of-transatlantic-data-flows/">one statement</a> on the importance of transatlantic data flows, the most recent <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/european-parliament-amps-up-pressure-on-eu-us-data-flows-and-gdpr-enforcement/">hot-button issue</a> to concern tech companies, fearing that anything other than the legal status quo could see vast swaths of their users in Europe cut off from their services.</p>
<p>&#8220;RGS companies are committed to protecting the privacy of those who use our services, and to safeguard personal data,&#8221; said the statement, which included the logos of Amazon, Apple, Dropbox, Facebook, Google, Microsoft, Snap, Twitter, Verizon Media and Zoom, but not Evernote.</p>
<p>In a coalition that&#8217;s only as strong as its members, the decision to remove Evernote from the website while it&#8217;s still a member hardly sends a resounding message of collective corporate unity — which these days isn&#8217;t something Big Tech can find much of.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="uFBTMAIue9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/microsoft-gag-orders/">Microsoft says a third of its government data requests have secrecy orders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Microsoft says a third of its government data requests have secrecy orders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/microsoft-gag-orders/embed/#?secret=uFBTMAIue9" data-secret="uFBTMAIue9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/evernote-surveillance-lobbying/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175187</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peter Boyce II has left General Catalyst to start his own $40M fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/peter-boyce-stellation-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/peter-boyce-stellation-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 17:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter boyce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Peter Boyce II has left General Catalyst to start his own firm, a little over a year after the venture capital firm promoted him to partner. His new firm is called Stellation Capital, and filings indicate that he is looking to raise up to $40 million for the debut investment vehicle. Sources say that most, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://twitter.com/badboyboyce">Peter Boyce II</a> has left General Catalyst to start his own firm, a little over a year after the venture capital firm<a href="https://pitchbook.com/newsletter/general-catalyst-names-three-partners"> promoted him to partner</a>. His new firm is called Stellation Capital, and filings indicate that he is looking to raise up to $40 million for the debut investment vehicle. Sources say that most, if perhaps not all, of that total has been closed <a href="https://sec.report/Document/0001858819-21-000001/">since the initial SEC filing in April.</a></p>
<p>Boyce declined to comment for this story. It’s been a quiet transition for the investor; his LinkedIn and Twitter have not been updated to indicate his new job title, but his personal website indicates the new gig. For an investor to leave a prominent venture capital firm after an eight-year tenure to raise dozens of millions of his own — and somehow do so quietly and <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=stellation%20capital&amp;src=typed_query">with minimal coverage</a> — might be a result of the funding frenzy and consequential numbness to yet another filing.</p>
<p>Boyce joined GC in 2013 and led investments in Ro, Macro, towerIQ and Atom. He’s also supported portfolio companies such as Giphy, Jet.com and Circle. Beyond GC, Boyce has experience co-founding and running Rough Draft Ventures, a program that helps incubate startups founded by students and recent graduates, as well as promote entrepreneurship on campuses.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vpNaqcBzKn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/general-catalysts-katherine-boyle-and-peter-boyce-are-looking-for-obsessive-founders/">General Catalyst&#8217;s Katherine Boyle and Peter Boyce are looking for &#8216;obsessive&#8217; founders</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;General Catalyst&#8217;s Katherine Boyle and Peter Boyce are looking for &#8216;obsessive&#8217; founders&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/11/general-catalysts-katherine-boyle-and-peter-boyce-are-looking-for-obsessive-founders/embed/#?secret=vpNaqcBzKn" data-secret="vpNaqcBzKn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Stellation Capital will leverage his work and name into early-stage investments. The name of the firm, per its website, is derived from the Latin root of stella, which means star. The name also describes “the process of extending a polygon in new dimensions to form a new shape … just like we’re extending the potential of a founder into new possibilities.”</p>
<p>It’s unclear what the firm’s check size and cadence will be, but it did say it wants to back successful companies at “their earliest stages” on the website.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/peter-boyce-stellation-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instacart hires Facebook executive as new CEO ahead of expected IPO</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/instacart-hires-facebook-executive-as-new-ceo-ahead-of-expected-ipo/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/instacart-hires-facebook-executive-as-new-ceo-ahead-of-expected-ipo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 17:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apoorva Mehta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fidji Simo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instacart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instacart has appointed Facebook executive Fidji Simo as its new CEO, just seven months after she joined the grocery delivery company’s board of directors. Simo, formerly the vice president and head of the Facebook app, will replace Instacart founder and current CEO Apoorva Mehta on August 2. Mehta will transition to executive chairman of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instacart has appointed Facebook executive <a href="https://twitter.com/fidjissimo">Fidji Simo</a> as its new CEO, just seven months after she joined the grocery delivery company’s board of directors. Simo, formerly the vice president and head of the Facebook app, will replace Instacart founder and current CEO Apoorva Mehta on August 2. Mehta will transition to executive chairman of the board, <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/instacart-appoints-board-member-fidji-simo-to-chief-executive-officer-and-announces-founder-and-current-ceo-apoorva-mehta-will-serve-as-executive-chairman-of-the-board-301327620.html">per a statement from Instacart.</a></p>
<p>Instacart declined on behalf of Simo for request to provide further comment.</p>
<p>Women of color chief executives at the forefront of billion-dollar businesses are still an unfortunately rare occurrence. Simo is the co-founder of Women in Product, a nonprofit organization that works to empower women in product management, as well as advance and advocate for women’s careers in tech. The transition marks that Facebook has lost one of its few female leaders, and Instacart has a new energy as it plans to increase its head count by 50% in 2021.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CX6Qnm8qD8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/instacart-raises-265m-at-a-39b-valuation/">Instacart raises $265M at a $39B valuation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instacart raises $265M at a $39B valuation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/instacart-raises-265m-at-a-39b-valuation/embed/#?secret=CX6Qnm8qD8" data-secret="CX6Qnm8qD8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The departure of Mehta from his role so close to an expected IPO is as notable as it is rare. Mehta founded Instacart 10 years ago, incubating it through <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/instacart">Y Combinator’s 2012 summer batch</a> to its most <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/02/instacart-raises-265m-at-a-39b-valuation/">recent valuation of $39 billion. </a></p>
<p>The pandemic spotlighted Instacart’s purpose, as millions of people around the world faced quarantines and limited in-person interactions, including trips to the grocery store. The increased consumer spending on for-delivery services led Instacart to hire hundreds of thousands of workers, as well as launch same-day delivery on a variety of products beyond avocados — including electronics, sports equipment and prescription medicine</p>
<p>The growth hasn’t come without controversy. Instacart joined Uber, Lyft, DoorDash and Postmates <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon"> as major backers for Proposition 22</a>, a measure that would classify gig workers as independent contractors, limiting the types of benefits that they could receive. Prop 22 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/03/prop-22-results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">eventually passed</a>, which could be seen as beneficial to Instacart executives and detrimental to the shoppers who make the deliveries. The event happened after years of protests, class-action lawsuits over wages and tipping debacles in which Instacart was scrutinized for unfair policies toward its shoppers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Xk90IDbuua"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/">An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;An even bigger battle for gig worker rights is on the horizon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/13/an-even-bigger-battle-for-gig-worker-rights-is-on-the-horizon/embed/#?secret=Xk90IDbuua" data-secret="Xk90IDbuua" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Simo obviously has experience working at controversial companies, thanks to her decade at Facebook. Facebook&#8217;s Chief Operating Officer Sheryl Sandberg replied to Simo&#8217;s announcement in a comment on the platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;Fidji — I&#8217;m immensely grateful for the impact you&#8217;ve had on Facebook over the last 10 years,&#8221; Sandberg wrote. &#8220;You&#8217;ve worn so many hats leading the Facebook App — all while advocating for gender equality in the tech community. I&#8217;m so proud to see where you&#8217;re headed. Cheering you on!&#8221;</p>
<p>Instacart describes Simo as a &#8220;core driver of Facebook&#8217;s mobile monetization strategy&#8221; and the leader behind the architecture of Facebook&#8217;s advertising business. The executive helped scale Facebook as it grew from 1,000 to 100,000 employees, and through its transition to the public markets — experience that may mesh well with Instacart&#8217;s ambitions to eventually go public.</p>
<p>Her rise to chief executive comes as the pandemic winds down and parts of the world begin to reopen, which will likely signal a new chapter about how Instacart conducts business and faces new challenges on how the business stays relevant.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/instacart-hires-facebook-executive-as-new-ceo-ahead-of-expected-ipo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175212</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Achieving digital transformation through RPA and process mining</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/achieving-digital-transformation-through-rpa-and-process-mining/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/achieving-digital-transformation-through-rpa-and-process-mining/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 17:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business process management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud Elements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot process automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uipath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For your transformation journey to be successful, you need to develop a deep understanding of your goals, people and the process.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Alp Uguray</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/alp_uguray">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alparhanuguray/">Alp Uguray</a> is an award-winning technologist, adviser and investor with 2x <a href="https://www.uipath.com/community/rpa-community-blog/introducing-uipath-2020-most-valuable-professionals">UiPath</a> (MVP) Most Valuable Professional Award and is a globally recognized expert on intelligent automation, AI (artificial intelligence), RPA, <a href="https://www.sykes.com/digital/learn-with-us/ebooks/process-mining-bible/">process mining</a> and enterprise digital transformation. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Understanding what you will change is most important to achieve a long-lasting and successful robotic process automation transformation. There are three pillars that will be most impacted by the change: people, process and digital workers (also referred to as robots). The interaction of these three pillars executes workflows and tasks, and if integrated cohesively, determines the success of an enterprisewide digital transformation.</p>
<p>Robots are not coming to replace us, they are coming to take over the repetitive, mundane and monotonous tasks that we’ve never been fond of. They are here to transform the work we do by allowing us to focus on innovation and impactful work. RPA ties decisions and actions together. It is the skeletal structure of a digital process that carries information from point A to point B. However, the decision-making capability to understand and decide what comes next will be fueled by RPA’s integration with AI.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			From a strategic standpoint, success measures for automating, optimizing and redesigning work should not be solely centered around metrics like decreasing fully loaded costs or FTE reduction, but should put the people at the center.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>We are seeing software vendors adopt vertical technology capabilities and offer a wide range of capabilities to address the three pillars mentioned above. These include powerhouses like UiPath, which recently went public, Microsoft’s Softomotive acquisition, and Celonis, which recently became a unicorn with a $1 billion Series D round. RPA firms call it &#8220;intelligent automation,&#8221; whereas Celonis targets the execution management system. Both are aiming to be a one-stop shop for all things related to process.</p>
<p>We have seen investments in various product categories for each stage in the intelligent automation journey. Process and task mining for process discovery, centralized business process repositories for CoEs, executives to manage the pipeline and measure cost versus benefit, and artificial intelligence solutions for intelligent document processing.</p>
<p>For your transformation journey to be successful, you need to develop a deep understanding of your goals, people and the process.</p>
<h2>Define goals and measurements of success</h2>
<p>From a strategic standpoint, success measures for automating, optimizing and redesigning work should not be solely centered around metrics like decreasing fully loaded costs or FTE reduction, but should put the people at the center. To measure improved customer and employee experiences, give special attention to metrics like decreases in throughput time or rework rate, identify vendors that deliver late, and find missed invoice payments or determine loan requests from individuals that are more likely to be paid back late. These provide more targeted success measures for specific business units.</p>
<p>The returns realized with an automation program are not limited to metrics like time or cost savings. The overall performance of an automation program can be more thoroughly measured with the sum of successes of the improved CX/EX metrics in different business units. For each business process you will be redesigning, optimizing or automating, set a definitive problem statement and try to find the right solution to solve it. Do not try to fit predetermined solutions into the problems. Start with the problem and goal first.</p>
<h2>Understand the people first</h2>
<p>To accomplish enterprise digital transformation via RPA, executives should put people at the heart of their program. Understanding the skill sets and talents of the workforce within the company can yield better knowledge of how well each employee can contribute to the automation economy within the organization. A workforce that is continuously retrained and upskilled learns how to automate and flexibly complete tasks together with robots and is better equipped to achieve transformation at scale.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/achieving-digital-transformation-through-rpa-and-process-mining/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174506</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dodge challenges: Can the automaker bring muscle into the electric future?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/dodge-challenges-can-the-automaker-bring-muscle-into-the-future/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/dodge-challenges-can-the-automaker-bring-muscle-into-the-future/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Burns]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 16:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dodge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EVs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stellantis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The term muscle car has always been a euphemism for concessions. Want the most power for the money? Forget about a sports car from Porsche or Lotus. Buy a muscle car and just take corners a bit slower. Today Dodge announced it&#8217;s making an electric muscle car and it will be available in 2024. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The term muscle car has always been a euphemism for concessions. Want the most power for the money? Forget about a sports car from Porsche or Lotus. Buy a muscle car and just take corners a bit slower. Today <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/">Dodge announced it&#8217;s making an electric muscle car</a> and it will be available in 2024. The first question that comes to mind: Well, if it&#8217;s a muscle car, what&#8217;s missing?</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a difference between a muscle car and a sports car, and Dodge is uniquely suited to know the differences. The brand has long been associated with horsepower and going fast in a straight line. The Dodge Viper. The Dodge Challenger. Even the Dodge Durango, a lumbering SUV, is available with a tricked-out V8 capable of putting out 710 hp — more power than most Porsches, though no one is about to pit a Durango against a 911 on the track.</p>
<p>Part of the draw of electric vehicles revolves around their mechanical simplicity. That was the original sales pitch for the muscle car, too. But, instead of offering a sports car with a tuned chassis and remarkable aerodynamics, which adds significant development cost, American car companies just stuffed larger engines in everyday family cars. Bam. Muscle cars, baby.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Let&#8217;s assume Dodge uses the muscle car mold and makes a low-cost, high-power, straight-line electric racer — think Dodge Challenger rather than Toyota Supra. This mold has several distinct characteristics.</p>
<p>One, burnouts. Muscle cars are known for their burnouts, which themselves are a byproduct of an overabundance of power, lack of chassis refinement and utter disregard for your tires&#8217; tread. Dodge teased this capability in its announcement tweet, showing a vehicle smoking all four tires. Dodge knows its audience.</p>
<p>Muscle car owners expect to be able to tune, tweak and modify their vehicles at home. That&#8217;s one of the main appeals to this type of vehicle. Straight from the factory, muscle cars are capable, but the buyer understands the automaker omitted certain parts to keep the sticker price as low as possible. Want better traction? Swap out the tires. Want better cornering? Add stiffer sway bars. An electric muscle car must be modifiable — something that&#8217;s increasingly rare as performance is more often optimized through software tweaks than mechanical upgrades.</p>
<p>Tesla has long been criticized for its aversion to vehicle modifications and at-home repairs. This is an opportunity for Dodge and others. A large swath of car buyers expect to be able to wrench on their vehicles, and I&#8217;ll wager this demographic is critical to Dodge&#8217;s future growth.</p>
<p>These unique characteristics of muscle cars are what make the segment so appealing for Dodge. The auto brand struggles to keep up with the market with a stable of stale vehicles, and the muscle car&#8217;s low-cost formula could allow for cheaper development costs.</p>
<p>And keeping development costs low is what Dodge needs right now.</p>
<p>Dodge is owned by Stellantis, a new automobile conglomerate formed when FCA, Dodge&#8217;s old owner, merged with the Dutch automaker PSA Group. It gets more confusing when Dodge&#8217;s previous owner is mentioned. Once always mentioned along with the giants of GM and Ford, Chrysler previously owned Dodge but is now just another brand in the Stellantis family. Together, Dodge and Chrysler offer only six vehicles, and none have seen significant updates in years.</p>
<p>An electric muscle car could revitalize the brand in the same way the Bronco is revitalizing Ford.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="H2HxutJtS1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/from-electric-charging-to-supply-chain-management-inmotion-ventures-preps-jaguar-for-a-sustainable-future/">From electric charging to supply chain management, InMotion Ventures preps Jaguar for a sustainable future</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;From electric charging to supply chain management, InMotion Ventures preps Jaguar for a sustainable future&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/from-electric-charging-to-supply-chain-management-inmotion-ventures-preps-jaguar-for-a-sustainable-future/embed/#?secret=H2HxutJtS1" data-secret="H2HxutJtS1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Look at Ford. The 2021 Bronco is a hit because it lines up nicely with consumer&#8217;s expectations of a Bronco. People hardly remember the engine and chassis issues that were long associated with the Bronco. Instead, people remember a durable off-roader (and slow car chases), so Ford made a durable off-roader loaded with modern conveniences.</p>
<p>Dodge should do the same with its upcoming electric muscle car. But, of course, calling a vehicle a muscle car sets certain expectations that Dodge would be wise to deliver.</p>
<p>Likewise, Ford is also selling a four-door electric Mustang, and its heavily rumored Chevrolet is preparing a similar electric SUV Corvette. While most people love the electric Mustang (I don&#8217;t), they also concede the Mustang naming muddles the branding.</p>
<p>What is it going to be called? Automakers are increasingly turning to their back catalog for new branding. GM revived the Hummer for its first electric truck, and Ford brought back the Bronco and F-150 Lightning. Dodge has a lot of history with muscle cars. There&#8217;s the legendary Charger Daytona (perfect if the upcoming car is built on the current Charger or Challenger), the low-cost Coronet and its upgraded sibling Coronet Super Bee, the Dodge Stealth or Dodge Polara — though maybe Polara is too close to the EV maker Polestar. Or Dodge could turn to names used by Plymouth, another brand previously owned by Chrysler. So there&#8217;s the Plymouth Roadrunner, Duster, Fury and Barracuda, too.</p>
<p>Last question: How will Dodge make the car sound like a muscle car? Hopefully, they won&#8217;t. I&#8217;m here for feeling performance rather than hearing it — and I drive a big F-150 with a custom exhaust.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EEdUVl9I7X"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/">Auto giant Stellantis to invest €30B in electrification through 2025</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Auto giant Stellantis to invest €30B in electrification through 2025&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/embed/#?secret=EEdUVl9I7X" data-secret="EEdUVl9I7X" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<hr />
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/StellantisEVDay2021?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#StellantisEVDay2021</a> | Timothy Kuniskis: &quot;<a href="https://twitter.com/Dodge?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Dodge</a> will not sell electric cars, it will sell American eMuscle&quot; <a href="https://t.co/adpUdnY5hy">https://t.co/adpUdnY5hy</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Stellantis (@Stellantis) <a href="https://twitter.com/Stellantis/status/1413119088440786947?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/dodge-challenges-can-the-automaker-bring-muscle-into-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175147</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Auto giant Stellantis to invest €30B in electrification through 2025</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 16:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battery Electric Vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiat Chrysler Automobiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plug ins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stellantis]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stellantis, the global automaker born out of a merger between Fiat Chrysler Automobiles and French automaker Groupe PSA, will invest €30 billion ($35.5 billion) in electric vehicles and new software over the next four years as part of a major push to transition away from internal combustion engines. The world’s fourth-largest automaker joins rivals such [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Stellantis, the global automaker born out of a merger between Fiat Chrysler Automobiles and French automaker Groupe PSA, will invest €30 billion ($35.5 billion) in electric vehicles and new software over the next four years as part of a major push to transition away from internal combustion engines.</p>
<p>The world’s fourth-largest automaker joins rivals such as General Motors and Volkswagen in earmarking billions toward EV investments through the first part of the decade. Among the company’s plans are manufacturing an electric Dodge muscle car and an electric Ram pickup truck, both by 2024. Stellantis also said it would offer an electric or plug-in model in every vehicle segment under its Jeep brand by 2025.</p>
<p>The ultimate aim, CEO Carlos Tavares said during the company’s inaugural EV Day event on Thursday, is to hit sales targets for low-emission vehicles (including plug-ins) of 70% in Europe and 40% in the U.S. by 2030.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Stellantis has been slower to electrify than some of its rivals, perhaps due in part to its lineup’s best-sellers skewing toward performance and heavy-duty models. The company designs and manufactures cars across over a dozen brands, including Jeep, Chrysler, Ram Trucks and Dodge. Its major brands in Europe include Peugeot, Vauxhall, Citroen and Fiat.</p>
<p>In order to deliver on its electrification strategy, Stellantis executives said that the company will also manufacture 130 gigawatt hours of battery capacity by 2025 and around 260 gigawatt hours across five factories in North America and Europe by 2030. The company will use two battery chemistries by 2024, with the goal of developing solid-state battery technology by 2026.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175179" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175179" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175179" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png" alt="" width="1024" height="587" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png 2374w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png?resize=300,172 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png?resize=768,441 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png?resize=680,390 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png?resize=1536,881 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png?resize=2048,1175 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-11.19.02.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175179" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="http://www.stellantis.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stellantis <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>The car giant is also developing a portfolio of four dedicated electric vehicle platforms: Small, for city driving; Medium, for premium vehicles; Large, for performance and muscle models; and Frame, for trucks and heavy-duty vehicles. The platforms will have a range of up to 300 miles for Small and 500 miles for Large and Frame. The aim is to decrease battery costs by 40% by 2024, Stellantis CFO Richard Palmer said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yItLzuo1SQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/">Rimac Automobili founder Mate Rimac shares lessons from bootstrapping an EV company</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rimac Automobili founder Mate Rimac shares lessons from bootstrapping an EV company&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/rimac-automobili-founder-mate-rimac-shares-lessons-from-bootstrapping-an-ev-company/embed/#?secret=yItLzuo1SQ" data-secret="yItLzuo1SQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="RYUrmFQ0Vg"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/waymo-and-fiat-chrysler-expand-partnership-to-develop-self-driving-ram-vans/">Waymo and Fiat Chrysler&#8217;s next big project is to develop self-driving Ram vans</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Waymo and Fiat Chrysler&#8217;s next big project is to develop self-driving Ram vans&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/21/waymo-and-fiat-chrysler-expand-partnership-to-develop-self-driving-ram-vans/embed/#?secret=RYUrmFQ0Vg" data-secret="RYUrmFQ0Vg" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/auto-giant-stellantis-to-invest-e30b-in-electrification-through-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175156</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Accellion data breach continues to get messier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/the-accellion-data-breach-continues-to-get-messier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/the-accellion-data-breach-continues-to-get-messier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 16:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accellion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arkansas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colorado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kroger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morgan stanley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qualys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singtel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Synopsys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of California]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Morgan Stanley has joined the growing list of Accellion hack victims — more than six months after attackers first breached the vendor’s 20-year-old file-sharing product.  The investment banking firm — which is no stranger to data breaches — confirmed in a letter this week that attackers stole personal information belonging to its customers by hacking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Morgan Stanley has joined the growing list of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/accellion/">Accellion</a> hack victims — more than six months after attackers first breached the vendor’s 20-year-old file-sharing product.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The investment banking firm — <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/morgan-stanley-fined-1-million-for-client-data-breach-1465415374">which is no stranger to data breaches</a> — confirmed in a letter this week that attackers stole personal information belonging to its customers by hacking into the Accellion FTA server of its third-party vendor, Guidehouse.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>In a letter sent to those affected, first reported by <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/morgan-stanley-reports-data-breach-after-vendor-accellion-hack/">Bleeping Computer</a>, Morgan Stanley admitted that threat actors stole an unknown number of documents containing customers&#8217; addresses and Social Security numbers.</p>
<p>The documents were encrypted, but the letter said that the hackers also obtained the decryption key, though Morgan Stanley said the files did not contain passwords that could be used to access customers&#8217; financial accounts.</p>
<p>“The protection of client data is of the utmost importance and is something we take very seriously,” a Morgan Stanley spokesperson told TechCrunch. “We are in close contact with Guidehouse and are taking steps to mitigate potential risks to clients.”</p>
<p>Just days before news of the Morgan Stanley data breach came to light, an <a href="https://www.arhealthwellness.com/about-us.html">Arkansas-based healthcare provider</a> confirmed it had also suffered a data breach as a result of the Accellion attack. Just weeks before that, so did UC Berkeley. While data breaches tend to grow past initially reported figures, the fact that organizations are still coming out as Accellion victims more than six months later shows that the business software provider still hasn’t managed to get a handle on it.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The cyberattack was first uncovered on December 23, and Accellion initially claimed the FTA vulnerability was patched within 72 hours before it was later forced to explain that new vulnerabilities <a href="https://www.accellion.com/company/press-releases/accellion-provides-update-to-recent-fta-security-incident/">were discovered</a>. Accellion’s next (and final) update came in March, when the company claimed that all known FTA vulnerabilities — which authorities say were exploited by the FIN11 and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/ukrainian-police-arrest-multiple-clop-ransomware-gang-suspects/">Clop ransomware gang</a> — have been remediated.</p>
<p>But incident responders said Accellion’s response to the incident wasn’t as smooth as the company let on, claiming the company was slow to raise the alarm in regard to the potential danger to FTA customers.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of New Zealand, for example, raised concerns about the timeliness of alerts it received from Accellion. In a <a href="https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/news/2021/05/reserve-bank-taking-action-to-respond-to-data-breach-reports">statement</a>, the bank said it was reliant on Accellion to alert it to any vulnerabilities in the system — but never received any warnings in December or January.</p>
<p>&#8220;In this instance, their notifications to us did not leave their system and hence did not reach the Reserve Bank in advance of the breach. We received no advance warning,&#8221; said RBNZ governor Adrian Orr.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2524PRPWY8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/">To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;To guard against data loss and misuse, the cybersecurity conversation must evolve&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/to-guard-against-data-loss-and-misuse-the-cybersecurity-conversation-must-evolve/embed/#?secret=2524PRPWY8" data-secret="2524PRPWY8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>This, according to a discovery made by KPMG International, was due to the fact that the email tool used by Accellion failed to work: &#8220;Software updates to address the issue were released by the vendor in December 2020 soon after it discovered the vulnerability. The email tool used by the vendor, however, failed to send the email notifications and consequently the Bank was not notified until 6 January 2021,&#8221; the KPMG&#8217;s <a href="https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/-/media/ReserveBank/Files/data-breach/kpmg-incident-assessment.pdf">assessment</a> said.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>&#8220;We have not sighted evidence that the vendor informed the Bank that the System vulnerability was being actively exploited at other customers. This information, if provided in a timely manner is highly likely to have significantly influenced key decisions that were being made by the Bank at the time.&#8221;</p>
<p>In March, back when it was <a href="https://www.accellion.com/company/security-updates/mandiant-issues-final-report-regarding-accellion-fta-attack/">releasing updates</a> about the ongoing breach, Accellion was keen to emphasize that it was planning to retire the 20-year-old FTA product in April and that it had been working for three years to transition clients onto its new platform, Kiteworks. A press release from the company in May says 75% of Accellion customers have <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/en/news-release/2021/05/18/2231538/0/en/Accellion-FTA-Customers-Migrate-to-Kiteworks-to-Protect-Their-Most-Sensitive-Data.html">already migrated</a> to Kiteworks, a figure that also highlights the fact that 25% are still clinging to its now-retired FTA product.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>This, along with Accellion now taking a more hands-off approach to the incident, means that the list of victims could keep growing. It’s currently unclear how many the attack has claimed so far, though recent tallies put the list at around 300. This list includes Qualys, Bombardier, Shell, Singtel, the University of Colorado, the University of California, Transport for New South Wales, Office of the Washington State Auditor, grocery giant Kroger and law firm Jones Day.</p>
<p>&#8220;When a patch is issued for software that has been actively exploited, simply patching the software and moving on isn’t the best path,&#8221; Tim Mackey, principal security strategist at the Synopsys Cybersecurity Research Center, told TechCrunch. &#8220;Since the goal of patch management is protecting systems from compromise, patch management strategies should include reviews for indications of previous compromise.&#8221;</p>
<p>Accellion declined to comment.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="8Ld0RQrCQp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/ukrainian-police-arrest-multiple-clop-ransomware-gang-suspects/">Ukrainian police arrest multiple Clop ransomware gang suspects</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ukrainian police arrest multiple Clop ransomware gang suspects&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/16/ukrainian-police-arrest-multiple-clop-ransomware-gang-suspects/embed/#?secret=8Ld0RQrCQp" data-secret="8Ld0RQrCQp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/the-accellion-data-breach-continues-to-get-messier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175085</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PowerZ raises $8.3 million for its video game focused on education</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/powerz-raises-8-3-million-for-its-video-game-focused-on-education/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/powerz-raises-8-3-million-for-its-video-game-focused-on-education/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 16:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PowerZ]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup PowerZ has raised another $8.3 million (€7 million at today’s exchange rate) including $1.2 million (€1 million) in debt — the rest is a traditional equity round. The company is both an edtech startup and a video game studio with an ambitious goal — it wants to build a game that is as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://powerz.tech">PowerZ</a> has raised another $8.3 million (€7 million at today’s exchange rate) including $1.2 million (€1 million) in debt — the rest is a traditional equity round. The company is both an edtech startup and a video game studio with an ambitious goal — it wants to build a game that is as engaging as Minecraft or Fortnite, but with a focus on education.</p>
<p>In February, PowerZ launched the first version of its game on computers. It doesn’t have a lot of content, but the company wanted to start iterating as quickly as possible. Aimed at kids who are six years old and over, PowerZ teleports the player into a fantasy world with cute dragons and magic spells.</p>
<p>“The idea is really to build a sort of Harry Potter,” co-founder and CEO Emmanuel Freund told me. “You have this world that is super nice and very interesting. Like with Hogwarts, you want to come back regularly, and the story will progress over a very long time.”</p>
<p>15,000 children tried out the first chapter. On average, they spent four hours in the game. I asked whether Freund was satisfied with those metrics. He told me he thought his company’s vision was “completely validated.”</p>
<p>Bpifrance Digital Venture, RAISE Ventures and Bayard are investing in today’s round. Existing investors Educapital, Hachette Livres, Pierre Kosciusko-Morizet and Michaël Benabou are also investing once again.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175174" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175174" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2175174" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png" alt="" width="1024" height="614" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png?resize=768,461 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png?resize=680,408 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png?resize=1536,922 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/devices-background.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175174" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> PowerZ</p></div></p>
<p>Now, it’s time to add content, expand to other platforms and launch new languages. When it comes to content, the company wants to partner with other game studios. They’re going to create new islands and design games that make you learn new stuff. Zero Games, Opal Games and ArkRep are the first third-party studios to contribute to PowerZ.</p>
<p>When those new chapters are available, kids will be able to practice mental calculation, geometry, vocabulary, foreign languages, sign language, but also astronomy, photography, architecture, sculpture, cooking, wildlife, yoga, etc.</p>
<p>“Basically we want to position ourselves as a publisher,” Freund said. “The only thing we want to keep in-house is the main storyline.”</p>
<p>As for new platforms, PowerZ is launching its game on the iPad this week. The company realized that launching on computers was a mistake. Adults are already using computers or don’t want to leave your kid on the computer. That’s why PowerZ is starting with the iPad and the iPhone will follow suite. In 2022, the company expects to release its game on the Nintendo Switch and potentially other game consoles.</p>
<p>While the game is only available in French for now, the startup is also thinking about launching an English version soon.</p>
<p>“The game is completely free right now. We have an idea to monetize it. We&#8217;ll copy every other games with in-app purchases for visual items,” Freund said.</p>
<p>When you look further down the roadmap, PowerZ has some radically ambitious goals. Freund believes that educational games will become mainstream really quickly. Many companies don’t want to develop this kind of stuff because screens are bad for kids.</p>
<p>“If we just say that screens are bad, we’ll end up with an Amazon product to learn math. I feel a sense of urgency to develop an educational platform for screens that can scale,” Freund told me.</p>
<p>PowerZ wants to reach hundreds of thousands of children as quickly as possible. And just like Fortnite or Minecraft, the company believes its game can act as a platform for other stuff that can evolve over time.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="L73RaIDvrC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/powerz-is-a-video-game-focused-on-education-founded-by-shadow-founder/">PowerZ is a video game focused on education founded by Shadow founder</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;PowerZ is a video game focused on education founded by Shadow founder&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/16/powerz-is-a-video-game-focused-on-education-founded-by-shadow-founder/embed/#?secret=L73RaIDvrC" data-secret="L73RaIDvrC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/powerz-raises-8-3-million-for-its-video-game-focused-on-education/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175161</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robotic funding doesn’t grow on trees</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/robotics-roundup-19/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/robotics-roundup-19/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fetch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zebra Technologies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I mentioned at the close of last week’s roundup, the biggest issue in writing this roundup on Wednesday is that sometimes news breaks on Thursday morning. Again, I’m asking the robotics community to try not make any big headlines on Thursdays. That would really help a guy out. Last week, news broke that Zebra [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As I mentioned at the close of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/robotics-roundup-18/">last week’s roundup</a>, the biggest issue in writing this roundup on Wednesday is that sometimes news breaks on Thursday morning. Again, I’m asking the robotics community to try not make any big headlines on Thursdays. That would really help a guy out.</p>
<p>Last week, news broke that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/01/zebra-technologies-is-acquiring-warehouse-robotics-company-fetch/">Zebra Technologies had purchased Fetch</a>. I’ve written about the latter several times over the past couple years, and spoken to founder Melonee Wise a number of times, as well. Ultimately, it’s not much of a surprise Fetch went the acquisition route. If I were a better man, however, I would have leaned heavily toward an acquisition by some mega-retailer like Walmart or Target.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2172692" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2172692" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2172692" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fetch-robotics-melonee-wise.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="682" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fetch-robotics-melonee-wise.jpeg 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fetch-robotics-melonee-wise.jpeg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fetch-robotics-melonee-wise.jpeg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fetch-robotics-melonee-wise.jpeg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fetch-robotics-melonee-wise.jpeg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fetch-robotics-melonee-wise.jpeg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2172692" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TechCrunch</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Everyone is looking for a competitive advantage against Amazon, including those big names. And, of course, they’ve got the deep pockets to purchase a head start. Ultimately, I think a deal like this is better for the industry, at large, given how Amazon’s acquisitions tend to go. The company loves to buy up startups and keep all of that cool technology to itself. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/02/fetch-robotics-ceo-on-the-companys-acquisition-and-the-future-of-warehouse-robots/">I spoke to Wise about the deal</a>, late last week. Some excerpts:</p>
<blockquote><p>As we were fundraising for our Series D, this opportunity came out of that. I think when you look at it, over the last couple of years, we’ve had a good relationship with them. With the pandemic, there’s been a huge draw for more and more automation technology. Before the pandemic, there were already labor shortages for warehouse and logistics, and the pandemic only exacerbated it. One of the other great things about us joining Zebra is they have a strong go-to-market engine, and they can amplify our sales capability. They’re already in all of the customers we want to be working with. It helps us reach a much broader, wider and deeper audience.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>I think it’s complicated. When I started the company, I never really planned on anything. I just wanted to go build something. I mean that in the most sincere way. I wanted to go build something and not fail. And the question is, what does not failing look like? I think the facts are that in the last 20-something years, almost no robotics company has IPO’ed. Now we’re starting to see SPACS, but there hasn’t been a robotics company that’s IPO’ed through the traditional route.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>In terms of vision of how we’re thinking about it, Zebra is very excited to kind of make Fetch the centerpiece of this whole new offering that they’re building out. It’s a high strategic priority for them.</p></blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_1802082" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1802082" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-1802082" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg 2400w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Abundant-Robotics-at-TG-Global-03-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1802082" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Abundant</p></div></p>
<p>On the whole, this week marked a pretty substantial slow down in terms of funding announcements. We did get one big bummer news item, as Abundant Robotics is shutting down. <a href="https://www.goodfruit.com/abundant-robotics-closes-shop/">Good Fruit Grower</a> got the following statement from CEO Dan Steere,</p>
<blockquote><p>After a series of promising commercial trials with prototype apple harvesters, the company was unable to raise enough investment funding to continue development and launch a production system.</p></blockquote>
<p>We’ve reached out for further comment, but the company’s understandably not champing at the bit to discuss where things went wrong. It’s easier, of course, to celebrate the successes than it is to dissect the failures, the latter happens much more often than we can to admit in this field. Often they arrive early in the process and don’t really warrant a lot of ink.</p>
<p>Abundant’s different. From the outside, the Bay Area company appeared to be on the right track toward becoming a dominant name in robotic fruit harvesting. The company had raised a total of $12 million, including Series A in 2017. Granted, that’s not an insignificant amount of time to go between raises and bringing robotics to production is extraordinarily difficult.</p>
<p>What’s more surprising is that the company couldn’t drum up enough interest to get it across the finish line during the pandemic, when, anecdotally, interest in robotics and automation seems to be heating up. Certainly that applies to farming, which has experienced series labor shortages over the past year. More insight into that soon, I hope.</p>
<div class="embed-vimeo embed breakout embed--video" style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/566792422" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p>Sarcos, meanwhile, keeps finding its way into the news cycle. This week, it’s the launch of the<a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210707005077/en/Sarcos-Robotics-Successfully-Implements-Next-Generation-Teleoperation-Capabilities-of-Guardian%C2%AE-XT%E2%84%A2-Robotic-System"> teleoperated Guardian XT</a>. The company’s exoskeletons get all the love (thanks in no small part to some high profile partnerships), but company also produces non-body mounted robotics. Per the company,</p>
<p>The SenSuit controller enables the Guardian XT robot to mimic the operator’s movements in real-time. It is an inertial measurement unit (IMU)-based motion tracker that communicates with the robot and leverages Sarcos’ proprietary force feedback technologies. The company also plans to integrate a VR- or AR-based HMD to provide remote visual and situational awareness to the operator. The Guardian XT robot is equipped with 3-degrees of freedom end effectors that enable dexterous control of trade tools and materials, including hand-held power tools, welding and cutting equipment, inspection and test equipment, parts and components, hazardous materials, and retail inventory goods, amongst others.</p>
<p>The system is capable of lifting and moving up to 200 pounds and will hit the market by the end of next year.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2174784" style="width: 970px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2174784" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2174784" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/img-slide-5.jpeg" alt="" width="960" height="538" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/img-slide-5.jpeg 960w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/img-slide-5.jpeg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/img-slide-5.jpeg?resize=300,168 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/img-slide-5.jpeg?resize=768,430 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/img-slide-5.jpeg?resize=680,381 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/img-slide-5.jpeg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2174784" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fusion</p></div></p>
<p>Meanwhile, robotic surgery company <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/07/06/2258470/0/en/Integrity-Implants-and-Fusion-Robotics-Merge-to-Form-Accelus.html">Fusion Robotics announced</a> this week announced plans to merge with Adaptive Geometry, another tech company specializing in spinal surgery technology. The two companies will combine to create the perfectly nondescript Accelus (frankly, Fusion is a pretty good name for two combined companies, but maybe that&#8217;s just me).</p>
<p>“Accelus will create opportunities for wide-scale adoption of robotics in spine surgery—both in hospitals and ambulatory surgery centers (ASCs)—by addressing previous constraints related to cost and efficiency,” Accelus Chris Walsh said in a release. “Both Fusion Robotics and Integrity Implants have built enabling technology platforms that create a force multiplier for spinal care. Our products and culture create accessibility to fit each patient’s anatomy, each surgeon’s preferred approach, and each healthcare facility’s space and budget limitations, embodying our core principle of access without compromise.”</p>
<p>That’s a lot of business talk this week, so here’s a fun video of Boston Dynamics doing fun Boston Dynamics stuff, presumably to welcome their new Hyundai overlords:</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7atZfX85nd4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/robotics-roundup-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174779</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Circle is a good example of why SPACs can be useful</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/circle-is-a-good-example-of-why-spacs-can-be-useful/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/circle-is-a-good-example-of-why-spacs-can-be-useful/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Circle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seedinvest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special-purpose acquisition company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stablecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Circle is the sort of business that is correct for a SPAC-led debut. It could not go public in a traditional manner in its current state of maturity.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the wake of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/coinbases-direct-listing-alters-the-landscape-for-fintech-and-crypto-startups/">Coinbase&#8217;s direct listing earlier this year</a>, other crypto companies may be looking to go public sooner than later. That appears to be the case with Circle, a Boston-based technology company that provides API-delivered financial services and a stablecoin.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Circle will not direct list or pursue a traditional IPO. Instead, the company is <a href="https://www.circle.com/hubfs/investors/Press-Release-Circle-Concord-July2021.pdf">combining</a> with Concord Acquisition Corp., a SPAC, or blank-check company. The transaction values the crypto shop at an enterprise value of $4.5 billion and an equity value of around $5.4 billion.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995212 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-gry.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>The offering marks an interesting moment for the crypto market. Unlike Coinbase, which operates a trading platform and generates fees in a manner that is widely understood by public-market investors, Circle&#8217;s offerings are a bit more exotic.</p>
<p>Circle&#8217;s <a href="https://www.circle.com/hubfs/investors/Circle-Investor-Presentation-July2021.pdf">SPAC presentation</a> details a company whose core business deals with a stablecoin &#8212; a crypto asset pegged to an external currency, in this case, the U.S. dollar &#8212; and a set of APIs that provide crypto-powered financial services to other companies. It <a href="https://www.seedinvest.com/blog/seedinvest/seedinvest-officially-closes-its-sale-to-circle">also owns SeedInvest</a>, an equity crowdfunding platform, though Circle appears to generate the bulk of its anticipated revenues from its other businesses.</p>
<p>For more on the deal itself, TechCrunch&#8217;s Romain Dillet has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/cryptocurrency-company-circle-to-go-public-in-spac-deal/">a piece focused on the transaction</a>. Here, we&#8217;ll dig into the company&#8217;s investor presentation, talk about its business model, and riff on its historical and anticipated results and valuation multiples.</p>
<p>In short, we get to have a little fun. Let&#8217;s begin.</p>
<h2>How Circle&#8217;s business works</h2>
<p>As noted above, Circle has three main business operations. Here&#8217;s how it describes them in its deck:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2175000" style="width: 732px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2175000" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2175000 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-8.20.21-AM.png" alt="" width="722" height="234" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-8.20.21-AM.png 722w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-8.20.21-AM.png?resize=150,49 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-8.20.21-AM.png?resize=300,97 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-8.20.21-AM.png?resize=680,220 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-08-at-8.20.21-AM.png?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 722px) 100vw, 722px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2175000" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Circle investor presentation</p></div></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s consider each one, starting with USDC.</p>
<p>Stablecoins have become popular in recent quarters. Because they are pegged to an external currency, they operate as an interesting form of cash inside the crypto world. If you want to have on-chain buying power, but don&#8217;t want to have all your value stored in more volatile, and tax-inducing, cryptos that you might have to sell to buy anything else, stablecoins can operate as a more stable sort of liquid currency. They can combine the stability of the U.S. dollar, say, and the crypto world&#8217;s interesting financial web.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/circle-is-a-good-example-of-why-spacs-can-be-useful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rootly nabs $3.2M seed to build SRE incident management solution inside Slack</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/rootly-nabs-3-2m-seed-to-build-sre-incident-management-solution-inside-slack/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/rootly-nabs-3-2m-seed-to-build-sre-incident-management-solution-inside-slack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[incident management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[incident response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rootly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XYZ Venture Capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175089</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As companies look for ways to respond to incidents in their complex microservices-driven software stacks, SREs — site reliability engineers — are left to deal with the issues involved in making everything work and keeping the application up and running. Rootly, a new early-stage startup wants to help by building an incident-response solution inside of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">As companies look for ways to respond to incidents in their complex microservices-driven software stacks, SREs — site reliability engineers — are left to deal with the issues involved in making everything work and keeping the application up and running. <a href="https://rootly.io/">Rootly</a>, a new early-stage startup wants to help by building an incident-response solution inside of Slack.</p>
<p>Today the company emerged from stealth with a $3.2 million seed investment. XYZ Venture Capital led the round with participation from 8VC, Y Combinator and several individual tech executives.</p>
<p>Rootly co-founder and CEO Quentin Rousseau says that he cut his SRE teeth working at Instacart. When he joined in 2015, the company was processing hundreds of orders a day, and when he left in 2018 it was processing thousands. It was his job to make sure the app was up and running for shoppers, consumers and stores even as it scaled.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>He said that while he was at Instacart, he learned to see patterns in the way people responded to an issue and he had begun working on a side project after he left looking to bring the incident response process under control inside of Slack. He connected with co-founder JJ Tang, who had started at Instacart after Rousseau left in 2018, and the two of them decided to start Rootly to help solve these unique problems that SREs face around incident response.</p>
<p>&#8220;Basically we want people to manage and resolve incidents directly in Slack. We don&#8217;t want to add another layer of complexity on top of that. We feel like there are already so many tools out there and when things are chaotic and things are on fire, you really want to focus quickly on the resolution part of it. So we&#8217;re really trying to be focused on the Slack experience,&#8221; Rousseau explained.</p>
<p>The Rootly solution helps SREs connect quickly to their various tools inside Slack, whether that&#8217;s Jira or Zendesk or DataDog or PagerDuty, and it compiles an incident report in the background based on the conversation that&#8217;s happening inside of Slack around resolving the incident. That will help when the team meets for an incident post-mortem after the issue is resolved.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6RSaZIp3b2"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/4-women-in-engineering-discuss-harassment-isolation-and-perseverence/">4 women in engineering discuss harassment, isolation and perseverence</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4 women in engineering discuss harassment, isolation and perseverence&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/07/4-women-in-engineering-discuss-harassment-isolation-and-perseverence/embed/#?secret=6RSaZIp3b2" data-secret="6RSaZIp3b2" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The company is small at the moment with fewer than 10 employees, but it plans to hire some engineers and sales people over the next year as they put this capital to work.</p>
<p>Tang says that they have built diversity as a core component of the company culture, and it helps that they are working with investor Ross Fubini, managing partner at lead investor XYZ Venture Capital. &#8220;That&#8217;s also one of the reasons why we picked Ross as our lead investor. [His firm] has probably one of the deepest focuses around [diversity], not only as a fund, but also how they influence their portfolio companies,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Fubini says there are two main focuses in building diverse companies including building a system to look for diverse pools of talent, and then building an environment to help people from underrepresented groups feel welcome once they are hired.<br />
&#8220;One of our early conversations we had with Rootly was how do we both bring a diverse group in and benefit from a diverse set of people, and what&#8217;s going to both attract them, and when they come in make them feel like this is a place that they belong,&#8221; Fubini explained.</p>
<p>The company is fully remote right now with Rousseau in San Francisco and Tang in Toronto, and the plan is to remain remote whenever offices can fully reopen. It&#8217;s worth noting that Rousseau and Tang are members of the current Y Combinator batch.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6GdwX1kdR3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/">How you react when your systems fail may define your business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How you react when your systems fail may define your business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/31/how-you-react-when-your-systems-fail-may-define-your-business/embed/#?secret=6GdwX1kdR3" data-secret="6GdwX1kdR3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/rootly-nabs-3-2m-seed-to-build-sre-incident-management-solution-inside-slack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175089</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The NS1 EC-1</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NS1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are excruciatingly high stakes for software today. Trillions of dollars of market cap, billions of consumers, hundreds of billions of revenue, and limitless hours of usage are dependent on software working in real time, all the time, without downtime. As the sophistication of software delivery has increased, every layer of the tech stack has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">There are excruciatingly high stakes for software today. Trillions of dollars of market cap, billions of consumers, hundreds of billions of revenue, and limitless hours of usage are dependent on software working in real time, all the time, without downtime.</p>
<p>As the sophistication of software delivery has increased, every layer of the tech stack has been rewritten — an accelerated evolution has led to a bevy of multibillion-dollar, up-and-coming unicorns and multiple massive public market debuts.</p>
<p>However, today we’re talking about one of the most integral pillars holding up the internet. The Domain Name System, otherwise known as DNS, is the key addressing system that connects browsers, users, devices and servers together. Type in “www.techcrunch.com” in your browser, and DNS finds the address linked to that name and tells routers and switches across the world which server to connect to and how to send data back to you.</p>
<p>Unlike physical postal addresses, innovation around DNS addressing has flourished in recent years. Traffic management, performance scaling, and cost shaping have turned DNS from a basic directory into a vital layer for guaranteeing the reliability of all software in use on the internet today while protecting the bottom line.</p>
<p>Few companies have parlayed internet infrastructure experience into a world-class engineering company quite like <b>NS1</b>. The New York City-based startup has raised more than $100 million as it builds a strategic node at the core of the modern web delivery tech stack. Customers are flocking: 760 at latest count (up from 600 a year ago), with year-over-year bookings growth well into the triple digits.</p>
<p>How did the company take a slumbering and dreary yet reliable aspect of the internet and turn it into a strategic moat and an enterprise win? And what lessons can we learn about the future of the enterprise infrastructure layer from one of its leading lights? That’s what we’re here to find out.</p>
<p>The lead writer of this EC-1 is <b>Sean Michael Kerner</b>. Kerner has been covering the IT and enterprise infrastructure market for more than a decade as a tech journalist (or, <a href="https://twitter.com/TechJournalist">@TechJournalist</a> as he is known on Twitter). Perhaps most importantly, he’s also partially fluent in Klingon, which has no bearing on this EC-1, but is one of those cool facts we wanted to include anyway. The lead editor for this package was <b>Danny Crichton</b>, the assistant editor was <b>Ram Iyer</b>, the copy editor was <b>Richard Dal Porto</b>, and illustrations were drawn by <b>Nigel Sussman</b>.</p>
<p><i>NS1 had no say in the content of this analysis and did not get advance access to it. Kerner has no financial ties to NS1 or other conflicts of interest to disclose.</i></p>
<p>The NS1 EC-1 comprises four main articles numbering 10,300 words and a reading time of 41 minutes. Here’s what we’ll be (DNS) addressing:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Part 1: Origin story</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/">1 napkin and 22 lines of code, or how NS1 rewrote the rules of internet infrastructure</a>” (2,700 words/11 minutes) — Sets the context for NS1’s business and provides a brief explanation of why DNS (the technology at the core of the NS1 service) matters.</li>
<li><b>Part 2: Product development and roadmap</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-product/">WTF is NS1? It’s DNS, DDI, and maybe other TLAs</a>” (2,700 words/11 minutes) — Analyzes NS1&#8217;s products, vision and open-source efforts through NS1 Labs.</li>
<li><b>Part 3: Competitive landscape</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-competition/">The fight for the future of DNS is white hot</a>” (2,300 words/9 minutes) — Evaluates how NS1 competes in a space littered with well-funded Big Tech companies and well-established mature companies.</li>
<li><b>Part 4: Customer development</b> “<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-customers/">Outages, pandemics and the reengineering of traffic on the internet</a>” (2,600 words/10 minutes) — Explores how companies like Roblox and Pinterest have had to reshape their networking infrastructure in light of massive growth and increasing demands for resilience from users.</li>
</ul>
<p>We’re always iterating on the EC-1 format. If you have questions, comments or ideas, please send an email to TechCrunch Managing Editor Danny Crichton at <a href="mailto:danny@techcrunch.com">danny@techcrunch.com</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EKk9qZmPLI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/">1 napkin and 22 lines of code, or how NS1 rewrote the rules of internet infrastructure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;1 napkin and 22 lines of code, or how NS1 rewrote the rules of internet infrastructure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/embed/#?secret=EKk9qZmPLI" data-secret="EKk9qZmPLI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174018</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>1 napkin and 22 lines of code, or how NS1 rewrote the rules of internet infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NS1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kris Beevers, John Sullivan and Alex Vayl wanted to rebuild the core addressing system of the internet and transform it from a cost center into a critical tool for software reliability and cost savings.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">It’s the most important primary layer in the modern tech stack for internet software, and its most intriguing evolution was written on a napkin in a New York City bar and translated to just shy of two dozen lines of Python code.</p>
<p>Such is the nature of tech innovation today, and such was the birth of NS1. Kris Beevers, along with Jonathan Sullivan and Alex Vayl, wanted to rebuild the core addressing system of the internet — the Domain Name System, or DNS — and transform it from a cost center into a critical tool for software reliability and cost savings. It was a smart idea back in 2012 and gained much steam a few years later when a fortuitous outage at a competitor left hundreds of websites stranded.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			It’s the most important primary layer in the modern tech stack for internet software, and its most intriguing evolution was written on a napkin in a New York City bar and translated to just shy of two dozen lines of Python code.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>NS1 may make the networks of the internet more reliable. But the story of the company is also built on the back of a durable social network of engineers who met at a little-known NYC startup named Voxel. That startup would go on to become, unintentionally, an incubator for several massive enterprise companies and exits.</p>
<p>Chance encounters, bold engineering and lucky breaks: It’s the quintessential startup tale, and it’s changing the face of software delivery.</p>
<h2>“You learn a lot because you&#8217;re doing way more than you rightfully should.&#8221;</h2>
<p>NS1’s story begins back at the turn of the millennium, when Beevers was an undergrad at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI) in upstate New York and found himself employed at a small file-sharing startup called Aimster with some friends from RPI. Aimster was his first taste of life at an internet startup in the heady days of the dot-com boom and bust, and also where he met an enterprising young engineer by the name of Raj Dutt, who would become a key relationship over the next two decades.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174019</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WTF is NS1? It’s DNS, DDI, and maybe other TLAs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danny Crichton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ec-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NS1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2174020</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NS1 looks at DNS differently from the competition: It doesn’t consider it as just a conduit to connect traffic; instead, DNS is treated as a routing system that can direct traffic very effectively.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">&#8220;We are not a DNS company, despite the name, and despite everything we&#8217;re talking about,&#8221; NS1 founder and CEO Kris Beevers says.</p>
<p>That might sound counter-intuitive, given that the company’s flagship product offering is literally called Managed DNS. The issue and the challenge NS1 actually solves today goes much deeper, and by positioning itself as being about more than DNS, the company helps to differentiate itself against what is, by any measure, a very commoditized technology.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Across its product portfolio, NS1 leverages data and injects software-defined intelligence, automation and real-time decisioning policy to steer and optimize traffic at the DNS layer.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>NS1 looks at DNS differently from the competition: It doesn’t consider it as just a conduit to connect traffic; instead, DNS is treated as a routing system that can direct traffic very effectively.</p>
<p>Across its product portfolio, NS1 leverages data and injects software-defined intelligence, automation and real-time decisioning policy to steer and optimize traffic at the DNS layer, Beevers says. It does all this by a core technology known as the filter chain, and it is foundational to NS1’s current success.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-origin/">In the first part of this EC-1</a>, I spoke about how Beevers wrote 22 lines of code to sketch out that filter chain technology, bringing NS1 to life. I will now look at how the company has expanded beyond DNS into what’s known as DDI, a key technology stack for managing internal networks within companies. We’ll also talk about NS1’s open-source efforts, and why experimentation remains a bedrock principle of the company’s engineering culture.</p>
<h2>Managing external traffic: DNS and active traffic management</h2>
<p>&#8220;Something that I will say very often to our team and to our customers in the market is, we&#8217;re not here to make DNS better; we&#8217;re not here to make DDI better, which is another realm that we play in now,&#8221; Beevers said. &#8220;We&#8217;re here to turn those technologies into leverage to solve much bigger problems that equate to connecting applications with an audience more effectively, at better scale, driving better performance and experiences with security and reliability.&#8221;</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/ns1-ec1-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2174020</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
