<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 18:50:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Diversity data isn&#8217;t very transparent: What&#8217;s the problem?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/diversity-data-isnt-very-transparent-whats-the-problem/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/diversity-data-isnt-very-transparent-whats-the-problem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 18:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity and inclusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2221892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A problem emerges when reviewing diversity data: While the reports often describe incremental gains or losses in diversity numbers, they often fail to analyze data that can help make tangible change.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Fran Benjamin</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/franbenjamin">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Fran Benjamin is managing partner at <a href="https://www.goodworks.consulting/">Good Works Consulting</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Monique Cadle</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Monique Cadle is founding partner at <a href="https://www.goodworks.consulting/">Good Works Consulting</a> and VP of people at <a href="https://delfidiagnostics.com/">Delfi Diagnostics</a>. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">In the tech industry, diversity is a hot topic. We’ve seen companies such as Facebook and Google commit to diversity, equity and inclusion initiatives in hopes of improving their company culture. But <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/12/six-years-into-diversity-reports-big-tech-has-made-little-progress.html">analysis shows</a> that there has been no appreciable change in diversity for these allegedly DEI-driven companies over the past 10 years despite these efforts.</p>
<p>In the 2010s, many tech companies made their annual diversity reports public to demonstrate transparency. Still, a problem emerges when reviewing the data: While the reports often describe incremental gains or losses in diversity numbers, they often fail to analyze data that can help the company make tangible change.</p>
<h2>Using data to dig deeper into systems that impact diversity</h2>
<p>The data in these reports provide us with a statement of the outcomes. We can see if the company has had growth or decline in the measured areas of diversity &#8212; typically demographic representation. What we can&#8217;t see is why these outcomes are happening and at what point in the system we&#8217;re missing the mark.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2221892" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Therefore, these reports miss out on the powerful accountability effects of measuring improved processes and systems.</p>
<p>To illustrate an example, we&#8217;ll look at a company&#8217;s marketing data.</p>
<p>When a large corporation is trying to optimize its marketing funnel, it can see data at every level of the marketing process. For example, they can estimate the number of impressions they receive from external marketing efforts, quantify the number of conversions from ads to their website and calculate how many website visitors convert to customers. This information is used regularly to optimize performance and increase sales &#8212; and it&#8217;s prioritized because leaders know that revenue generation is essential for the company to succeed.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Leaders can accomplish this quality of analysis at the hiring level by recording and analyzing data at every level of the recruiting system. Data sets would include demographic information for every point of interaction, including but not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>The number of impressions received for a job ad.</li>
<li>Candidates identified through sourcing channels.</li>
<li>Candidates being presented for interviews.</li>
<li>Interviewer assessment results.</li>
<li>Job offers and job offers accepted.</li>
</ul>
<p>Leaders could then ensure demographic representation at each level of the process is at least equivalent to the demographics of the available talent pool. The company would then need to prioritize using this data to make changes to the system regularly (not annually) to improve the results.</p>
<p>Recruiting is only one example, and there are other areas of business that can benefit from more informative diversity data.</p>
<h2>Making information actionable</h2>
<p>As a leader, you have a choice to make your data actionable by publishing information that can result in accountability and greater equity and inclusion.</p>
<p>Consider sharing each of the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pay transparency and pay equity by demographic.</li>
<li>Engagement and inclusion data by demographic.</li>
<li>Rates of promotion by demographic.</li>
<li>Rates of retention by demographic.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, your general counsel’s skin may crawl at these recommendations. However, organizations innovating on talent, culture and equity are willing to wander into these territories of transparency and accountability.</p>
<p>Moreover, we have seen organizations that are willing to stand on their integrity wholeheartedly by publishing these data make significant progress toward building cultures of belonging that center on diversity.</p>
<h2>Data transparency doesn&#8217;t equal data <em>accountability</em></h2>
<p>We often believe that if we can measure something, we can change it; however, measurement alone does not drive change. Therefore, it’s crucial to measure the right data elements while holding stakeholders accountable for measurable change.</p>
<p>Let’s consider how this is done in sales.</p>
<p>Sales teams measure individual performance based on their contribution to achieving revenue targets. They are <em>required </em>to get results or risk losing their job because failure can cause harm to the business.</p>
<p>If we did the same for DEI, we&#8217;d see leaders held accountable for getting tangible results quarterly or annually as part of their performance appraisal goals. But, unfortunately, putting out a report stating what occurred won’t inspire leaders to do more to change the processes that impact outcomes meaningfully.</p>
<h2>Benchmarking against already low numbers won&#8217;t move the needle</h2>
<p>Diversity reporting often benchmarks annual data against the company&#8217;s previous metrics, the industry as a whole, companies of a similar size or an entire geography (i.e., the U.S.). This form of measuring progress makes incremental progress seem like a bigger achievement than it is. Leaders can point to this data and say they are meeting industry standards, but if the industry’s rate of progress is negligible, it simply removes accountability for achieving better results. Organizations have not been getting diversity right for decades, why benchmark to those underperforming?</p>
<p>Let’s say this simply: Benchmarking to poor performance is a poor practice.</p>
<p>If you do a benchmark, at least seek to make a real improvement by benchmarking against companies performing in the top quartile when it comes to diversity representation. But, again, this sets the bar higher and challenges leaders to be more strategic.</p>
<p>More importantly, companies should benchmark against the available talent pool (by using <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat11.htm">Bureau of Labor Statistics</a> data in the U.S., or by <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/">graduation rates by demographic and field of study</a><span style="text-decoration: underline;">)</span> to determine underrepresentation within your geography, industry and job field.</p>
<p>For example, the rate of graduation among women computer science majors is dramatically higher than the representation of women in junior-level software engineering roles in most companies.</p>
<p>And yet, even BLS data can be flawed because it relies on several assumptions about who is eligible for employment and excludes whole swaths of truly employable people. So, you may also combine these benchmarks with <em>local </em>population data as yet another data set to show how effective you’ve been.</p>
<p>If tech companies publish data that not only describes what is currently happening in the organization but also gives context to how systemic bias impacts diverse talent who cannot access their organizations, these reports might motivate behavioral change and be more valuable for readers from other industries aspiring to improve their own organizational outcomes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/diversity-data-isnt-very-transparent-whats-the-problem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2221892</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intelligent Implants raises $8.7M to help you grow a spine</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/intelligent-implants-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/intelligent-implants-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haje Jan Kamps]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 18:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EIC Accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intelligent Implants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sosv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2221172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spinal surgery is not for the faint of heart at the best of times, but Intelligent Implants raised €7.5 million ($8.7 million) to make spinal surgery less of a pain in the backside. The company&#8217;s smart implants&#8217; first application is in spinal fusion surgery &#8212; where two or more vertebrae are permanently connected to improve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Spinal surgery is not for the faint of heart at the best of times, but <a href="http://intelligentimplants.ie">Intelligent Implants</a> raised €7.5 million ($8.7 million) to make spinal surgery less of a pain in the backside. The company&#8217;s smart implants&#8217; first application is in spinal fusion surgery &#8212; where two or more vertebrae are permanently connected to improve stability, correct a deformity or reduce pain. Globally, more than a million of these surgeries are performed, but they are typically seen as a last resort because of the risk of complications or continued pain after the operation.</p>
<p>Intelligent Implants uses wireless implantable electronics to stimulate, steer and monitor bone growth. The company points out that the current state-of-the-art post-operation management is potentially long-term dependence on physical therapy and/or painkillers. Intelligent Implants is wading into the market to add a more tech-forward solution to the mix.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s smart, active implants aren&#8217;t the first devices in this category. You&#8217;ll be familiar with pacemakers and cochlear implants, which have been available since the 1950s and 1970s, respectively. Intelligent Implants’s innovation is in creating a solution that doesn&#8217;t require wires or batteries. The product is placed between vertebrae with the same standard surgical procedure as current non-active implants.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2221172" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>The implant is then powered externally through induction, much like how your phone might use a wireless charging pad. This creates an electric field that stimulates and guides bone growth.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t wish this surgery on anyone, but if you have to do it, we have to make sure that the outcomes are as good as they can be,&#8221; said John Zellmer, CEO of Intelligent Implants.</p>
<p>The electrodes that are used for stimulation can also be used as sensors. The device consists of a standard orthopedic implant, with some additional magic thrown in. The magic, in this case, is a number of electrodes that can be used for neuromodulation to aid bone growth, along with some antennas and electronics to control it all. After fusion surgery, the patients wear a spinal corset to keep everything in place where it is meant to be &#8212; and that&#8217;s a convenient place to keep the power and control units for the device.</p>
<p>Zellmer explains that Intelligent Implants get the sensor side of the equation almost as a side effect of the bone-growth stimulation. He explains that the device can do impedance measurements. Bone doesn&#8217;t conduct very well, so when the graft material is gradually replaced by bone in the body, the electrical signature changes, and in the process you can measure the bone growth.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2221214" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2221214" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2221214" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Intelligent-Implant-co-founders-Erik-Zellmer-John-Zellmer-and-Martin-Larsson.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="388" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Intelligent-Implant-co-founders-Erik-Zellmer-John-Zellmer-and-Martin-Larsson.png 1001w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Intelligent-Implant-co-founders-Erik-Zellmer-John-Zellmer-and-Martin-Larsson.png?resize=150,86 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Intelligent-Implant-co-founders-Erik-Zellmer-John-Zellmer-and-Martin-Larsson.png?resize=300,171 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Intelligent-Implant-co-founders-Erik-Zellmer-John-Zellmer-and-Martin-Larsson.png?resize=768,438 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Intelligent-Implant-co-founders-Erik-Zellmer-John-Zellmer-and-Martin-Larsson.png?resize=680,388 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Intelligent-Implant-co-founders-Erik-Zellmer-John-Zellmer-and-Martin-Larsson.png?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2221214" class="wp-caption-text">Intelligent Implants co-founders Erik Zellmer, John Zellmer and Martin Larsson. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Intelligent Implants</p></div></p>
<p>The company&#8217;s product &#8212; called SmartFuse &#8212; just received a <a href="https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/how-study-and-market-your-device/breakthrough-devices-program">Breakthrough Device designation</a> from the FDA, which, among other things, means that the government agency believes that &#8220;the device provides for more effective treatment or diagnosis of life-threatening or irreversibly debilitating human disease or conditions.&#8221; The company explains that, in order to be part of the program, it completed large-animal trials on sheep, which showed three times more bone growth and cut the time to fusion down by 50%.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is pretty uncommon to get a Breakthrough Device Designation based on pre-clinical data,&#8221; said Zellmer, who points out that most BDDs are based on human trials. &#8220;We definitely did a big dance around the office when we got the news.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company has so far been using sheep for its trials to date &#8212; sheep or goats being the most commonly used animals for orthopedic trials. The company is aiming to do its first human clinical trials in 2023.</p>
<p>“After a family member suffered from poor outcomes we decided to tackle this hard problem. We knew our solution would only work if our team had strong domain knowledge, long-term commitment and if we could fit our technology into the current practices (standard-of-care) of surgeons,&#8221; said Zellmer. &#8220;We are now more than halfway in bringing our product SmartFuse to market, and the FDA’s decision is a confirmation that our approach was sound.”</p>
<p>The company was part of the SOSV <a href="https://hax.co/">HAX</a> tech program, before graduating and announcing it is closing its seed round today. It raised €4.5 million ($5.2 million) from EU’s <a href="https://eic.ec.europa.eu/eic-funding-opportunities/eic-accelerator_en">EIC Accelerator</a>, with participation from <a href="https://sosv.com/">SOSV</a>, and an additional €3 million ($3.5 million) from a group of Swedish angel investors.</p>
<p>&#8220;We met the SOSV partner Bill Liao back in 2015, and he has been supporting us ever since. That&#8217;s a long time for a venture firm, and they have done a really amazing job, both in terms of helping us from an operational perspective, but also supporting us in every round since then,&#8221; says Zellmer. &#8220;I think that is spectacular: We are doing something really hard here. This is a Class 3 device, an active implantable device with a stimulation system. What we are doing is totally new, and bringing that into the orthopedics field shows vision and guts.&#8221;</p>
<p>“Creating implantable technology is about as hard as it gets, and Intelligent Implants have been tremendously steady in its progress. We are proud to keep supporting them on this journey to help millions of patients and serve a market poised to reach $9B in a few years”, says Bill Liao, general partner at SOSV.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/intelligent-implants-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2221172</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Lunchclub landed a preemptive term sheet from Lightspeed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/how-lunchclub-landed-a-preemptive-term-sheet-from-lightspeed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/how-lunchclub-landed-a-preemptive-term-sheet-from-lightspeed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neesha A. Tambe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 18:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra Crunch Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LunchClub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Live]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In less than seven days, Lunchclub co-founder Vlad Novakovski had a sizable term sheet in hand from Lightspeed Ventures, despite his startup not looking to raise at the time. How did that happen?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In less than seven days, Lunchclub co-founder Vlad Novakovski had a sizable term sheet in hand from Lightspeed Ventures, despite his startup not looking to raise at the time. How did that happen? A sticky product experience with the customer feedback and growth to back it up made the startup an investment opportunity Lightspeed’s Nicole Quinn just couldn’t pass up.</p>
<p>A week ago, Novakovski and Quinn joined us on TechCrunch Live to give a breakdown of Lunchclub’s Series A deck and the details on how they connected toward the beginning of the pandemic. Lunchclub is an AI-driven networking tool virtually connecting professionals across multiple industries and levels.</p>
<p>TechCrunch Live, formerly known as Extra Crunch Live, takes place every Wednesday at noon PDT/3 p.m. EDT. Each week, audiences get to hear the backstory, best practices and should-haves from founders and the investors who led their round. In the second half, founders in the audience get to live-pitch directly to the guests.</p>
<p>Take a look at some key learnings from our chat with Vlad and Nicole below, and check out the full recording of the episode with the live pitch-off.</p>
<h2>A well placed intro goes a long way</h2>
<p>The impact of your early-stage investors can go a long way. Nicole Quinn discovered Lunchclub through one of the company’s initial investors in the early months of the pandemic in 2020.</p>
<p>“I received an email from an angel investor in Lunchclub, Greg Arrese, saying, ‘Lunchclub just started doing fireside chats,” Nicole recalled. “These fireside chats have really found product-market fit. I mean, we just launched them and they&#8217;ve got thousands of people joining them.’”</p>
<p>Initially connecting with Vlad to participate in a fireside chat and learn more about the company on Wednesday, conversations quickly evolved resulting in a term sheet on Monday, less than a week after meeting.</p>
<p>Introductions to investors from other founders are often touted as the best way to get in front of a VC. In Vlad’s case, it was the investor who made a difference.</p>
<p>“I think as a founder … that speaks to [the] kind of value having a strong … angel investor network when you do your seed or your pre-seed,” Vlad added.</p>
<h2>Consumer feedback is everything</h2>
<p>Founders diligently build products to solve a problem but the true test is with the customers themselves. Novakovski’s Series A deck had customer feedback in the form of social media screenshots but had limited data and case studies — a change he wished he had made before.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/how-lunchclub-landed-a-preemptive-term-sheet-from-lightspeed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222127</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram rolls out new tools for creators to collaborate and partner with brands</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/instagram-rolls-out-new-tools-for-creators-to-collaborate-and-partner-with-brands/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/instagram-rolls-out-new-tools-for-creators-to-collaborate-and-partner-with-brands/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram is testing new tools for creators to earn commissions and form partnerships with brands on its platform. The Facebook-owned company is expanding its existing native affiliate tool, which launched in June and allows creators to discover products, share them with followers and earn commissions for sales driven by their posts. With this latest launch, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram is <a href="https://business.instagram.com/blog/creators-brands-collaborate-content/">testing new tools</a> for creators to earn commissions and form partnerships with brands on its platform. The Facebook-owned company is expanding its existing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/instagram-adds-affiliate-and-shop-features-for-creators/">native affiliate tool</a>, which launched in June and allows creators to discover products, share them with followers and earn commissions for sales driven by their posts.</p>
<p>With this latest launch, creators can now add a digital storefront to showcase products or collections that are already part of their affiliate partnerships within the &#8220;view shop&#8221; button on their profile and earn a commission on sales. Instagram says this new feature is currently only available to creators who are part of its native affiliate program.</p>
<p>Instagram is also testing new branded content partnership features to help creators get discovered by brands. Creators now have the ability to add to their preferred &#8216;brands list&#8217; brands they’re interested in partnering with, which will give them priority when companies are searching for new creators to work with.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222547" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Additionally, Instagram is rolling out a new folder within DMs exclusively for partnership messages. The new folder aims to ensure that creators don’t miss opportunities from brands whose messages may have otherwise been buried in a creator’s inbox. Partnership messages will skip the requests folder and get priority placement so that brands and creators are able to find and manage their content partnerships.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2222550" style="width: 946px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2222550" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2222550" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png" alt="" width="936" height="930" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png 936w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=300,298 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=768,763 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=680,676 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/instagram-brands-creators-feature.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 936px) 100vw, 936px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2222550" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Instagram</p></div></p>
<p>Brands now also have the option to use data and unique filters to discover suitable creators for their campaigns. They can then also organize shortlists to manage multiple campaigns and creators. Businesses can now also create branded content Reels ads. Further, Instagram has rolled out new account permissions that allow creators to enable brands to create content ads from any of the creator’s posts, stories and Reels.</p>
<p>“These brand-creator partnership tools are a big part of our ongoing commitment to help creators make a living on Instagram — whether they’re partnering with brands, earning money from advertising, getting support from their audience or earning bonuses directly from Instagram,” the company said in a <a href="https://business.instagram.com/blog/creators-brands-collaborate-content/">blog post.</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Instagram notes that it will continue to test and refine these features and make them available for more brands and creators in the future.</p>
<p>It’s worth noting that Instagram is among several digital platforms working to make it easier for brands and creators to work together. For instance, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/tiktoks-new-creator-marketplace-api-lets-influencer-marketing-companies-tap-into-first-party-data/">TikTok</a> has a Creator Marketplace that helps marketers discover top TikTok personalities for their brand campaigns. Similarly, <a href="https://newsroom.pinterest.com/en/post/introducing-new-ways-for-creators-to-earn-money-and-partner-with-brands-on-pinterest">Pinterest</a> has rolled out features to help creators partner with brands on its platform.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="o27RwEmUGX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/30/instagram-launches-a-creators-account-to-encourage-more-creation/">Instagram launches a &#8216;creators&#8217; account to encourage more&#8230; creation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram launches a &#8216;creators&#8217; account to encourage more&#8230; creation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/30/instagram-launches-a-creators-account-to-encourage-more-creation/embed/#?secret=o27RwEmUGX" data-secret="o27RwEmUGX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="853v1XwQQQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/instagram-launches-a-new-section-for-shopping-product-drops/">Instagram launches a new section for shopping product drops</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Instagram launches a new section for shopping product drops&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/instagram-launches-a-new-section-for-shopping-product-drops/embed/#?secret=853v1XwQQQ" data-secret="853v1XwQQQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/instagram-rolls-out-new-tools-for-creators-to-collaborate-and-partner-with-brands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222547</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voyager, Nanoracks and Lockheed&#8217;s &#8216;Starlab&#8217; is the latest sign that the low Earth orbit economy is coming</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 17:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nanoracks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voyager Space Holdings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The era of private space stations is officially here as Nanoracks, Voyager Space and Lockheed Martin announce plans to launch a commercial station in 2027, but it’s just the next logical step for developing the new space economy, the companies say. “One of our key theses for the industry is that the last 10 years [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The era of private space stations is officially here as Nanoracks, Voyager Space and Lockheed Martin <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/nanoracks-lockheed-martin-and-voyager-space-plan-to-launch-crewed-commercial-space-station-by-2027/">announce plans to launch a commercial station in 2027</a>, but it’s just the next logical step for developing the new space economy, the companies say.</p>
<p>“One of our key theses for the industry is that the last 10 years have been defined by building access to space, the next 10 years will be about destinations,” Voyager CEO Dylan Taylor said.</p>
<p>The new space station, dubbed “Starlab” in homage to the third-ever U.S. space station, Skylab, will be composed of an inflatable habitat module, a docking node and a robotic arm. The companies anticipate robust demand from both the public sector and private industry, though Nanoracks CEO Jeffrey Manber emphasized, “the core of Starlab is science.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222562" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>While Starlab could eventually also host tourists, he added that it’s not a tourism-first project. “Space tourism is what captures the headlines, but to have a sustainable business model, you really do need to move beyond that,” he said.</p>
<p>The trio of companies have submitted Starlab to NASA as a bid under the agency’s Commercial Low Earth Orbit Destinations project, which will allocate up to $400 million in contracts to private companies developing space stations. Any such project will likely require intensive public investment, but Taylor said the funding is just as important as a sign to the world that NASA is interested in maintaining a presence in low Earth orbit, particularly in light of the impending deorbiting of the International Space Station.</p>
<p>Manber echoed his sentiments. “We do not want a space station gap,” he said. “Everybody in the industry, in the community, understands that we cannot have a period where the United States lacks a space station, or space stations, in low Earth orbit.”</p>
<p>Overall, however, private financing will be key, and this is where Voyager comes in. The company, which acquired majority control over Nanoracks this year, will be overseeing financing and allocating capital for the project.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“Realistically, there is not enough funding from Congress,” Manber said. “Those days have gone. This is a commercial project.”</p>
<p>Many things remain unclear regarding the future of the LEO economy, especially how companies and public agencies plan to balance standardization across design with keeping competitive. Taylor suggested a consortium approach could be one way to create standards for a handful of key technologies. Investment from NASA could also help drive commonality across habitation systems, Lisa Callahan, Lockheed Martin’s VP of commercial civil space, said in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>“NASA as a customer has unleashed this extraordinary revolution in space transportation,” Manber said. “Building on the success that NASA had with cargo, building on the success of commercial crew, one can anticipate that with the markets interested in space, we&#8217;re going to see the same thing with smaller private space stations.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222562</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum: The great handshake</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/ethereum-the-great-handshake/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/ethereum-the-great-handshake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 17:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peer to peer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart contract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web 3.0]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ethereum and the emergence of Web 3.0 paint a shifting picture -- an internet not just private, but open and transparent by default.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Ashley Tolbert</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ashleytolb">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="www.twitter.com/ashleytolb">Ashley Tolbert</a> is an information security researcher and engineer. 	</div>
	
	</div>

<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Tarah Wheeler</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/tarah">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://twitter.com/tarah">Tarah Wheeler</a> is an information security researcher and <a href="https://www.belfercenter.org/person/tarah-wheeler">Belfer Center Cyber Project Fellow at Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Ethereum is the world’s most popular digital contract compiler, maintained by many but owned by none. Perhaps one of the most interesting factors behind its popularization is the future it paints &#8212; one that transforms our current internet standards for ownership, value creation and, most importantly, privacy.</p>
<h2>A transformed future?</h2>
<p>Not only can apps be written on top of Ethereum, but it allows any digital thing &#8212; a picture, a music file, a video, your mom’s favorite pumpkin pie recipe &#8212; to be uniquely owned, traded and stored for value, among many other possibilities that are created daily.</p>
<p>While many have predicted the future of the internet to be layered in bundles and levels of protection, it turns out that, <a href="https://www.washington.edu/accesscomputing/world-wide-access-accessible-web-design#:~:text=Accessibility%20Guidelines&amp;text=As%20Tim%20Berners%2DLee%2C%20Director,disability%20is%20an%20essential%20aspect.&amp;text=Building%20web%20content%20that%20is,challenge%20for%20web%20development%20teams.">paraphrasing</a> Tim Berners-Lee, making the underlying technologies accessible to everyone supercharges its adoption and usefulness.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222126" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Ethereum and the emergence of Web 3.0 paint a shifting picture &#8212; an internet not just private, but open and transparent by default.</p>
<h2>A brief history</h2>
<p>In 2013, Vitalik Buterin <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitalik_Buterin">conceived</a> the idea of Ethereum, which would be developed and deployed two years later. The platform was built to allow anyone in the world with access to the internet to write permanent applications (known as decentralized apps or dApps) upon it, which anyone else can interact with but cannot change &#8212; basically open source software with integrity to the nth degree. The bread and butter of these apps are called smart contracts &#8212; a digital contract or intermediary.</p>
<p>Translated, that means financial and legal services no longer require a middleman. Ethereum basically substitutes an escrow agent, a notary, a bank teller who checks your ID, or a mortgage originator for an instant, digital transaction.</p>
<p>This invaluable function makes Ethereum one of the most recognized cryptocurrencies and blockchains in existence, with many contenders trailing. Bitcoin prices recently hit an <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/price/bitcoin">all-time high</a>, and the hype surrounding Ethereum remains in full swing.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2020/01/06/what-is-web-3-0/">Web 3.0</a>, an associated concept, is an imagined future internet that uses these peer-to-peer blockchains to allow users to interact with data, value stores, entities, etc., all without a middleman.</p>
<h2>Ethereum today</h2>
<p>As Ethereum becomes an underlying infrastructure for legal cases, financial deals, binding agreements and more, understanding its weaknesses and strengths will become a fundamental trait of property ownership and transfer.</p>
<p>Updating Stephen Hawking’s <a href="https://twitter.com/codeorg/status/357514287658434560">words</a> on how “basic computer programming is an essential skill to learn,” understanding the fundamentals of smart contracts such as those on Ethereum will become a basic legal and financial skill.</p>
<p>Today, the most booming applications on Ethereum are NFTs &#8212; non-fungible tokens. While NFTs are relatively new, they’re catching on with consumers, artists and investors not only as a store of value but as an assertion of digital, unique ownership.</p>
<p>NFTs allow anything digital (any file) to be owned and traded on the internet because it can’t be manipulated, changed or copied – it’s non-fungible. Any social media hubbub surrounding Apes, Kittys or Punks are all in relation to the burgeoning fan-favorite phenomenon of luxury digital art.</p>
<p>We predict that one use case for this technology will be in interplanetary mining, as companies based on Earth will need to buy and sell mineral rights in asteroids that few if any of their human employees have ever actually visited or seen themselves.</p>
<p>Other predictions for use cases are mortgage lending, property purchasing, event ticketing, music festivals, file storage and gaming &#8212; <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22725083/axie-infinity-sky-mavis-blockchain-economy-game-pokemon">Axie Infinity</a>, for example, is a testament to how players can make a decent living in an NFT-based gaming world.</p>
<p>The possibilities are endless and are being thought up by the curious and energized community more and more every day.</p>
<h2>Challenges and Ethereum of tomorrow</h2>
<p>As regulation catches up to the power of this underlying technology, many wonder if we’ll see attempts to control it. Much like the years-long debate in the <a href="https://www.law.com/sites/almstaff/2017/11/14/riana-pfefferkorn-the-looming-battle-in-the-crypto-wars/?slreturn=20210921141037">Crypto Wars</a>, which entailed requests to compromise or break encryption, changes to the assertions of Ethereum’s immutability could compromise its main valuable characteristic: its permanent integrity.</p>
<p>There may be a potential conflict between Ethereum’s immutability and its widespread adoption. It might mean that financial regulators will attempt to take some form of ownership or control over its deployment. We would be curious as to how those potential future regulators would answer the question: How can a widely connected sphere of nodes be cautiously governed while not compromising its true value &#8212; decentralization itself?</p>
<p>Other challenges and limitations the technology is likely to face are performance sustainability &#8212; fees to build on top of Ethereum called gas fees have <a href="https://www.businessinsider.in/cryptocurrency/news/ethereums-scaling-issues-strike-again-as-time-magazines-nfts-sell-for-30-times-their-price/articleshow/86490791.cms">gone up</a> in recent years and the platform is known to be slowing in processing time. Ethereum 2.0 is anticipated to smooth inefficiencies, but how do we continue to maintain speed in a blockchain optimized for storing and computing each and every transaction?</p>
<p>Security also remains a challenge, with known Ethereum vulnerabilities existing though not widely exploited. Poly Network reported a hack this year that resulted from a <a href="https://time.com/nextadvisor/investing/cryptocurrency/poly-network-hack/">&#8220;vulnerability between contract calls.” </a></p>
<p>Smart contracts are intricate and complex functions to write, so they require in-depth auditing before being deployed to a network. Ethereum security is also built on passwordless, asymmetric cryptography. It’s entirely possible that quantum computing will eventually disrupt our asymmetric cryptography standards.</p>
<p>We’re interested in how Ethereum and blockchains can be sustained, and we’re HODLing all the way through. Into the metaverse and beyond ….</p>
<p><em>The views expressed here are those of Ashley Tolbert and Tarah Wheeler and not the views of their affiliations.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/ethereum-the-great-handshake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222126</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk says Starship should be ready for first orbital launch next month, &#8216;pending regulatory approval&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/elon-musk-says-starship-should-be-ready-for-first-orbital-launch-next-month-pending-regulatory-approval/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/elon-musk-says-starship-should-be-ready-for-first-orbital-launch-next-month-pending-regulatory-approval/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Darrell Etherington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 16:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SpaceX&#8217;s Starship rocket is still in development in southeast Texas, with major progress being made on key elements like the launch tower construction, and installation of the vacuum-rated Raptor engines that will power the vehicle once it reaches space. Elon Musk says that it could be ready to make its first orbital flight attempt next [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">SpaceX&#8217;s Starship rocket is still in development in southeast Texas, with major progress being made on key elements like the launch tower construction, and installation of the vacuum-rated Raptor engines that will power the vehicle once it reaches space. Elon Musk says that it could be ready to make its first orbital flight attempt next month — provided it gets the regulatory sign-offs it needs.</p>
<p>SpaceX will require approvals from the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to make the attempt, as it has for all of its prior test flights of Starship from its development location outside of Brownsville, Texas. The FAA basically requires that SpaceX demonstrate it has taken all necessary safety precautions to ensure that there&#8217;s minimal risk in case of anything going wrong during the launch attempts.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">If all goes well, Starship will be ready for its first orbital launch attempt next month, pending regulatory approval</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222531" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1451581465645494279?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>At this stage of development, that&#8217;s not even a highly unlikely outcome: SpaceX has already seen a number of its Starship prototypes explode (or experience &#8220;rapid, unscheduled disassembly,&#8221; as it&#8217;s often known in the industry) during the development program. Starship testing has also had its successes, however, including completing high-altitude flight tests that are still within Earth&#8217;s atmosphere, and bringing the spacecraft back down for a controlled landing.</p>
<p>The next major milestone for SpaceX is flying a fully stacked version of its Starship and Super Heavy booster combo beyond Earth&#8217;s atmosphere and to outer space. As told by Musk, the company is technically ready for that step, but that regulatory approval could take a lot longer than a month to materialize, if the FAA&#8217;s recent call for public comments on granting a launch license are any indication.</p>
<p>During town hall meetings this past week, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738106/spacex-boca-chica-starship-launch-site-faa-town-hall-environmental-assessment">supporters and detractors both got very vocal and raised a number of issues</a> that the FAA will have to review and address along with SpaceX before proceeding to the next step. The FAA could forestall resolving some of these by issuing a temporary license for the purpose of a test and revisiting ongoing launch permissions, however.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/elon-musk-says-starship-should-be-ready-for-first-orbital-launch-next-month-pending-regulatory-approval/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222531</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revue now lets you subscribe to newsletters directly on your Twitter timeline</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/revue-now-lets-you-subscribe-to-newsletters-directly-on-your-twitter-timeline/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/revue-now-lets-you-subscribe-to-newsletters-directly-on-your-twitter-timeline/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 16:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscribe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscribers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[timeline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Starting today, Revue writers have another tool to turn their Twitter followers into newsletter subscribers. Now, when you tweet out your newsletter, readers will see a subscribe button embedded in the tweet. Revue is making it very difficult to not use Revue. https://t.co/UaFS1lhrNM &#8212; Austin Rief ☕️ (@austin_rief) October 22, 2021 When you share individual [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Starting today, Revue writers have another tool to turn their Twitter followers into newsletter subscribers. Now, when you tweet out your newsletter, readers will see a subscribe button embedded in the tweet.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Revue is making it very difficult to not use Revue. <a href="https://t.co/UaFS1lhrNM">https://t.co/UaFS1lhrNM</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Austin Rief <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2615.png" alt="☕" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@austin_rief) <a href="https://twitter.com/austin_rief/status/1451572064159207425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222503" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>When you share individual issues of your newsletter, they&#8217;ll look the same as if you shared an article from any other website &#8212; only once someone clicks the article, when they return to their timeline, they&#8217;ll see the subscribe button.</p>
<p>In August, Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/19/twitter-is-testing-a-feature-that-puts-users-revue-newsletters-on-their-profiles/">tested a feature</a> that allowed Revue newsletter writers to highlight their newsletter right on their profile. By September, the feature <a href="https://twitter.com/revue/status/1435641482254368772">became available</a> to all Revue writers. But previously, subscribing to a newsletter via Twitter &#8212; whether on someone&#8217;s profile, or now, via a tweet &#8212; required verifying your email. But now, if you already have an email address linked to your Twitter account, you can subscribe with one click without confirming via email.</p>
<p>This feature is currently available on the web, but will roll out to iOS and Android soon, Revue said in a <a href="https://twitter.com/revue/status/1451564116007657472">tweet</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Absolutely weighing the pros and cons of moving my entire subscriber list and newsletter to Revue thanks to this update&#8230; <a href="https://t.co/vbAkWtgKC4">https://t.co/vbAkWtgKC4</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; Alexa Heinrich (she/her) (@HashtagHeyAlexa) <a href="https://twitter.com/HashtagHeyAlexa/status/1451570989595234306?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 22, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Twitter <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/twitter-acquires-revue/">acquired Revue</a> in January, helping the platform compete in the fast-growing newsletter space. Revue takes a <a href="http://help.getrevue.co/en/articles/4754361-how-pricing-works-on-revue">5% cut of creators’ earnings</a>, plus a standard 2.9%, plus $0.30 processing fee. So, if someone subscribes to your Revue newsletter for $5, you’ll take home $4.30. Comparatively, Substack takes 10% of writers’ revenue, plus processing fees.</p>
<p>Twitter has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/01/twitters-acquisition-strategy-eat-the-public-conversation/">remained busy</a> with acquisitions this year, announcing its acquisition of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/twitter-acquires-group-chat-app-sphere/">Sphere</a>, a group chat app, this week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/revue-now-lets-you-subscribe-to-newsletters-directly-on-your-twitter-timeline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;ll be discussing why it&#8217;s automation&#8217;s moment at TC Sessions: SaaS on Oct. 27th</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/well-be-discussing-why-its-automations-moment-at-tc-sessions-saas-on-oct-27th/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/well-be-discussing-why-its-automations-moment-at-tc-sessions-saas-on-oct-27th/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CapitalG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel Dines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Wright]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laela Sturdy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ServiceNow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Sessions: SaaS 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uipath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2221300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year automation hit center stage when robotic process automation (RPA) vendor UiPath went public after raising $2 billion in private investment. Investors who had been a part of that were richly rewarded when it closed above its private valuation. At the same time, established companies like ServiceNow, Microsoft, IBM and others were seeing the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This year <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/">automation hit center stage</a> when robotic process automation (RPA) vendor <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/a-cooling-trend-in-public-markets-makes-uipaths-down-round-ipo-a-win-for-the-company/">UiPath went public</a> after raising $2 billion in private investment. Investors who had been a part of that were richly rewarded when it closed <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/as-uipath-closes-above-its-final-private-valuation-cfo-ashim-gupta-discusses-his-companys-path-to-market/">above its private valuation</a>. At the same time, established companies like ServiceNow, Microsoft, IBM and others were seeing the value in building automation into their product sets.</p>
<p>We are fortunate to have three people who have been smack dab in the middle of this trend on a panel called &#8220;Automation&#8217;s Moment Is Now&#8221; at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=automationpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=automationpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TC Sessions: SaaS</a> happening on October 27th. Those panelists include UiPath CEO Daniel Dines; Laela Sturdy, general partner at CapitalG and Dave Wright, chief innovation officer at ServiceNow.</p>
<p>Dines&#8217; company, which went public in April, concentrates mostly on RPA, and is the market leader according to Gartner, but automation has many dimensions beyond RPA, including no-code/low-code tools and workflow automation. As we wrote on in an article <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/no-code-workflow-and-rpa-line-up-for-their-automation-moment/">on the hot automation market</a> earlier this year:</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2221300" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<blockquote><p>What we have here is a frothy mix of startups and large companies racing to provide a comprehensive spectrum of workflow automation tools to empower companies to spin up workflows quickly and move work involving both human and machine labor through an organization.</p></blockquote>
<p>RPA helps companies automate a series of mundane legacy tasks, which can include human intervention or not. Think of pulling information from an insurance claim, adding it to a spreadsheet and emailing a human administrator with the needed information &#8212; and doing all of this without a human touching it.</p>
<p>ServiceNow got into RPA in March when it bought <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/23/servicenow-takes-rpa-plunge-by-acquiring-india-based-startup-intellibot/">Indian startup Intellibot</a>. It also has several tools for low-code and workflow automation, and with the Intellibot purchase, other acquisitions and organic development, has built automation across its entire platform.</p>
<p>Sturdy was an investor in UiPath and serves on its board. Other investments include Stripe, Cloudflare and Credit Karma, which Intuit <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/intuit-credit-karma/">bought last year for $7.1 billion</a>. She was also the captain of the women&#8217;s basketball team while attending Harvard, and participated in the 1998 NCAA basketball tournament, <a href="https://www.thecrimson.com/article/2002/3/14/a-look-back-to-1998-harvard/">helping defeat No. 1 Stanford</a> in a huge upset.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We&#8217;re going to discuss why automation is coming to the fore now, the role of the pandemic in its rising popularity and whether it&#8217;s a jobs killer or if it&#8217;s actually making life easier for employees.</p>
<p>We hope you&#8217;ll join us at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-sessions-saas-2021/?utm_medium=&amp;utm_campaign=saas2021&amp;utm_content=automationpost&amp;utm_source=tc&amp;promo=automationpost&amp;display=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Sessions: SaaS on October 27th</a>. We&#8217;ll also be talking to Monte Carlo CEO Barr Moses, Microsoft executive Jared Spataro and investor Casey Aylward.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-45444285401be6baab1af8d28ccb4105"
			width="99%"
			height="1000"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/45444285401be6baab1af8d28ccb4105"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="bizzabo"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-45444285401be6baab1af8d28ccb4105')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-45444285401be6baab1af8d28ccb4105'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/well-be-discussing-why-its-automations-moment-at-tc-sessions-saas-on-oct-27th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2221300</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook&#8217;s next chapter just might make sense</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/facebooks-next-chapter-just-might-make-sense/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/facebooks-next-chapter-just-might-make-sense/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 15:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I could never really figure out why Facebook spent heavily on VR, but the move may have actually been pretty brilliant from a strategic perspective.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Shares of Snap are off just over 20% this morning, a huge cut to the valuation of the social networking company.</p>
<p>In one sense, the post-earnings drop is an indictment of the company&#8217;s business. On the other, Snap&#8217;s stock has merely retreated to midyear levels and remains far above the historical price range it found itself mired in during its more unprofitable days.</p>
<p>But Snap&#8217;s <a href="https://s25.q4cdn.com/442043304/files/doc_financials/2021/q3/Q3-2021-Press-Release.pdf">earnings report</a> and its ensuing selloff have not held their impact to just the company&#8217;s own value. Other social companies have also taken hits: Facebook shares are off nearly 5% this morning, while Twitter is off around 3%. It&#8217;s an arse day for social media companies that are public &#8212; and for their private-market brethren, even if we can&#8217;t see their prices change as granularly.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Let&#8217;s answer the <em>why</em> before we get into what the situation may mean for social companies more generally. We&#8217;ll focus on Facebook at that point, considering its metaverse and impending name change.</p>
<h2>Why Snap is down: Supply chains and Apple&#8217;s power</h2>
<p>Snap posted $1.07 billion in revenue in its most recent quarter, lower than market expectations of $1.10 billion, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/21/snap-earnings-q3-2021.html">per CNBC reporting</a>. That revenue result was up 57% year over year, and Snap narrowed its net loss to just under $72 million in the quarter, down from just under $200 million in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>Even better, Snap posted massively improved cash flow results in the period when compared to its year-ago results. Growth? Check. Improving profitability? Check. Ability to self-fund? Check. And yet its stock fell sharply. Why? Guidance.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Snap said that it expects revenues for Q4 2021 &#8220;to be between $1.165 million and $1.205 million.&#8221; The market, in contrast, expected the company to generate $1.36 billion in the current quarter. The <em>lowest</em> analyst estimate for Q4 2021 Snap revenue <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/SNAP/analysis?p=SNAP">that Yahoo Finance has on file</a> was $1.20 billion. The company may miss even that guess.</p>
<p>Companies that are valued more on growth than GAAP profitability tend to swing sharply when growth slows. And Snap is forecasting an almighty revenue growth deceleration. That explains the selloff. But what explains the company&#8217;s slowing revenue growth?</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/facebooks-next-chapter-just-might-make-sense/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222463</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Meet rolls out new audio and video locks for hosts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/google-meet-rolls-out-new-audio-and-video-locks-for-hosts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/google-meet-rolls-out-new-audio-and-video-locks-for-hosts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 15:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google meet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Teams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videoconferencing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google Meet is getting new audio and video locks to let hosts turn off the microphones and cameras of other participants. The new feature essentially lets you mute a user and prevent them from unmuting themselves until you unlock them. Earlier this year, Google rolled out the ability for hosts to mute everyone all at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google Meet is getting new <a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2021/10/google-meet-meeting-hosts-now-have-more.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GoogleAppsUpdates+%28Google+Workspace+Updates+Blog%29">audio and video locks</a> to let hosts turn off the microphones and cameras of other participants. The new feature essentially lets you mute a user and prevent them from unmuting themselves until you unlock them.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Google rolled out the ability for hosts to mute everyone all at once in a group call. This latest feature takes the move a step further by preventing participants from unmuting themselves at any point during the call.</p>
<p>Once a host enables either an audio or video lock in the main meeting, it will also be applied to breakout rooms. However, any changes made to a lock setting within a breakout room will not affect the settings of other breakout rooms or the main meeting.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222490" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Google says audio and video locks give hosts more control over their meetings by letting them decide when they want to allow different levels of participation from users. It also gives them the ability to address disruptive meeting participants.</p>
<p>It’s worth noting that participants using versions of the Android and iOS apps that do not support the new feature will be removed from the meeting if the host turns on the audio or video lock. If users try to join a meeting that currently has the locks enabled, they will be prompted to update their app in order to be allowed into the meeting. However, if the host turns off the locks, the participants will be able to rejoin the meeting.</p>
<p>The new audio and visual lock features are starting to roll out today to all Google Workspace customers, along with G Suite Basic and Business customers.</p>
<p>Google has been rolling out numerous features for Meet over the past few months, as it continues to compete with Zoom and Microsoft Teams amid the work-from-home era brought on by the pandemic. For instance, the company launched a new feature last month that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/20/google-meet-will-automatically-adjust-webcam-brightness-in-your-browser/">automatically adjusts</a> your webcam brightness. Additionally, Google rolled out a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/google-meet-gets-a-refreshed-ui-multi-pinning-autozoom-and-more/">refreshed UI</a> and several features for Meet in April. The videoconferencing platform has also partnered with other services, such as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/otter-ai-expands-automatic-transcription-assistant-to-microsoft-teams-google-meet-and-cisco-webex/">Otter.ai</a>, with the goal of retaining and attracting more users.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/google-meet-rolls-out-new-audio-and-video-locks-for-hosts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222490</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Trump SPAC is doing stonk things, which is hilarious</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/the-trump-spac-is-doing-stonk-things-which-is-hilarious/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/the-trump-spac-is-doing-stonk-things-which-is-hilarious/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 14:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donald trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamestop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TMTG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[None of this makes sense. Even by the standards of 2021 and the SPAC era, this is all very stupid.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When news broke that former U.S. President Donald Trump had <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/trump-launches-his-own-social-media-platform-truth-social/">conceived of a media and technology company</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/inside-the-trump-spac-deal-taking-on-twitter-disney-cnn-and-every-major-tech-company/">intended to take it public via a blank-check company</a>, you would have been forgiven if you immediately began to wonder how quickly you could short the stock.</p>
<p>Pick a reason: Right-leaning social networks have largely flopped; the company appeared to be severely underfunded given the scope of its goals and the wealth of its rivals; the fact that there was no product available to use, let alone historical revenue to model forward. There are other reasons for skepticism, but those are my favorite.</p>
<p>And yet! Shares of the SPAC in question, Digital World Acquisition Corp, shot higher on the news. And it is repeating the feat this morning:</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222456" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2222460" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-9.30.40-AM.png?w=362" alt="" width="362" height="127" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-9.30.40-AM.png 362w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-9.30.40-AM.png?resize=150,53 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-9.30.40-AM.png?resize=300,105 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-22-at-9.30.40-AM.png?resize=50,18 50w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" /></p>
<p>Recall that DWAC is the Class A share ticker symbol of Digital World Acquisition Corp, while DWACU is the same equity, but with half a warrant attached. The latter shares are up less, which is a bit odd.</p>
<p>Regardless, DWAC now sports a market cap of around $4.7 billion, per Yahoo Finance. That means that Digital World &#8212; aka Trump Media and Technology Group (TMTG) &#8212; is something akin to the newest unicorn to come out of the land of media and tech. Sure, it&#8217;s a public price, but because the company that will merge with Digital World is so nascent as to be risible: <em>Fuck it</em>, let&#8217;s call it a startup.</p>
<p>None of this makes sense. Even by the standards of 2021 and the SPAC era, this is all very stupid.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The only thing that TMTG has that makes it anything other than hot air attached to tissue-thin market statistics &#8212; we&#8217;d like to thank the company&#8217;s presentation for reminding us that podcasts are rising in popularity, a truly mind-bending insight &#8212; is Trump&#8217;s name. Recall that TMTG intends on using SPAC money to fund its operations, not Trump cash; it doesn&#8217;t even really have the financial backing of the man whose name is atop its business. You know, the supposed billionaire.</p>
<p>Perhaps the fact that the company is so silly should have tipped us off to it becoming a memestock, or stonk. Why? Because only the wackiest companies seem to make the cut. Physical retail is falling amid rising digital delivery of gaming goods? Let&#8217;s send GameStop to the moon. No one is renting cars? Let&#8217;s pile into Hertz stock. That sort of thing.</p>
<p>So, almost, <em>of course</em> DWAC is going vertical. Why <em>not?! </em>This stock shooting higher is at once utterly hilarious and a grim indictment of efficient market theory. Nothing makes a stonk better as a meme than it making little to no sense as a business. Thus, TMTG is up a kajillion percent, which makes sense precisely in how little sense it makes.</p>
<p>Normally I&#8217;d just go to bed at this point, but it turns out I have a lot of work to do so, we&#8217;ll leave this here for now. Good luck to everyone trading today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/the-trump-spac-is-doing-stonk-things-which-is-hilarious/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222456</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working to understand Rent the Runway&#8217;s IPO valuation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/working-to-understand-rent-the-runways-ipo-valuation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/working-to-understand-rent-the-runways-ipo-valuation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 14:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Levie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rent the Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stitch fix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeWork]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If we make critical remarks about Rent the Runway's business, we're not mocking the market demand it is working to meet. We're noting that it is perhaps undercharging, which makes some numbers wonky.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">When you file to go public, you want folks to like the numbers. You do not want people to mock the numbers.</p>
<p>The most extreme version of this obvious truism was WeWork&#8217;s <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/wework-files-its-s-1-we-dive-into-the-numbers-and-pose-some-questions/">first run at the public markets</a>. It filed, everyone found its <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/wework-may-reduce-its-valuation-ahead-of-ipo-by-tens-of-billions/">results to be ridiculous</a>, and the IPO eventually got yanked. A more modest &#8212; yet still negative &#8212; reaction can be found in Box&#8217;s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/03/24/box-files-for-250m-ipo-on-full-year-revenue-of-124m-net-loss-of-168m/">first attempt at going public</a>.</p>
<p>Both companies eventually did debut, with Box managing to do so via normal methods, while WeWork had to wait for a SPAC to chariot it to the public markets. And no, I am not trying to draw any sort of business similarity between Box (software company run by a sane person) and WeWork (non-software business run by a person slightly less trustworthy than Aaron Levie).</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money. </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on TechCrunch+</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>A more recent example from the <em>folks not liking the numbers much</em> category is Rent the Runway&#8217;s IPO filing. The company &#8212; a good business idea that has engendered a large user base over time &#8212; is not entirely gorgeous from a business perspective.</p>
<p>In case you don&#8217;t want to read through Rent the Runway&#8217;s <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001468327/000119312521301156/d194411ds1a.htm">IPO filing</a> or <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/05/what-rent-the-runways-ipo-filing-says-about-the-business-of-loaner-garments/">our notes on its numbers</a>, the gist is that it appears that the depreciation costs relating to clothing that Rent the Runway rents to customers are sufficiently steep as to make the company&#8217;s overall business profile unsteady.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220369 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-orng-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>To combat that look, Rent the Runway provided adjusted profitability metrics that excluded inventory depreciation. <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">It wasn&#8217;t a very popular move. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">More simply, it appears that Rent the Runway is just undercharging for its product when we consider the full set of costs associated with providing its service and running its business.</span></p>
<p>Regardless of our concerns, however, the company&#8217;s first IPO price range values the company north of $1 billion, so its IPO will be a unicorn debut. As such, we have to take it seriously. This morning, let&#8217;s quickly calculate its IPO valuation range, its resulting multiples and compare the company to a related entity to get a grip on what the market is telling us about the fashion rental unicorn.</p>
<h2>Pricing Rent the Runway</h2>
<p>First, a bit of an apology. As an unfashionable slacker, I have too long dismissed investments in appearance. Mostly, this was my being both a boor <em>and</em> a bore, but it was also intellectually lazy.</p>
<p>In reality, humans love to express themselves through dress, both physical (clothing, makeup, etc.) and virtual (character skins, NFTs, etc.). And they will spend to look good.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d hazard that the impulse to look good physically and in digital realms are pretty related, if not the same thing. So, the beating heart of the League of Legends business model (in-game cosmetics) and Rent the Runway&#8217;s (renting fashionable attire) should get similar levels of care.</p>
<p>All that&#8217;s to say: If we make some critical remarks about certain elements of Rent the Runway&#8217;s business results, we&#8217;re not mocking what it wants to do or the market demand it is working to meet. Instead, we&#8217;re noting that Rent is perhaps undercharging for its products, which makes some numbers a bit wonky.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/working-to-understand-rent-the-runways-ipo-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222442</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another month, another billion dollars in value appreciation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/another-month-another-billion-dollars-in-value-appreciation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/another-month-another-billion-dollars-in-value-appreciation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superplastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, and welcome to Equity, TechCrunch&#8217;s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. And have a good time. This week Mary Ann and Natasha and Alex (along with our amazing production team Grace, Chris, and Kell) took on a bevy of topics from around the world of startups and technology more [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/eb0eff22-7390-4537-86cf-d1cc5a0f42bc?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello, and welcome to Equity, TechCrunch&#8217;s venture capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. And have a good time.</p>
<p>This week Mary Ann and Natasha and Alex (along with our amazing production team Grace, Chris, and Kell) took on a bevy of topics from around the world of startups and technology more broadly.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222245" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<ul>
<li>We naturally kicked off with news that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/facebook-reportedly-plans-to-change-its-name-to-focus-on-the-metaverse/">Facebook intends to rebrand itself.</a> Which we don&#8217;t think will do much to detract from its various crises. But the news <em>does</em> underscore that Facebook is, in fact, serious about writing its next chapter.</li>
<li>From there it was time to talk funding rounds. This week we picked <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/vertical-oceans-aims-to-grow-sustainable-shrimp-in-huge-aqua-towers-inside-cities/">Vertical Oceans and its fishy plans</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/superplastic-guggimon-janky-virtual-celebrities-series-a/">Superplastic and its stable of rude digital critters</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/modern-age-is-on-a-mission-to-put-people-in-the-drivers-seat-of-their-aging-journey/">Modern Age and its plan to help us all age a bit more gracefully.</a></li>
<li>Vibe Capital, founded by Teachable&#8217;s Ankur Nagpal, is a<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/20/vibe-capital-is-a-new-venture-firm-built-for-scrappy-international-founders/"> $60 million fund for international, scrappy founders.</a> We spoke about the founder to investor pipeline, and why everyone wants each other&#8217;s jobs.</li>
<li>And then Alex ran us through some data from the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/china-venture-capital-q3-2021/">Chinese venture capital market</a>, information that was far more positive than we anticipated. Given, you know, the country&#8217;s regulatory crackdown on technology companies.</li>
<li>We closed with a number of major fintech rounds, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/18/with-customers-like-coinbase-and-shopify-remote-hiring-startup-deel-raises-425m-at-a-5-5b-valuation/">new capital for Deel</a> and a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/21/brex-raises-300m-at-a-12-3b-valuation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">funding scoop on Brex</a>, which is now officially a decacorn. Notably, Deel and Brex both raised mega-rounds just six months after raising mega-rounds.</li>
<li>While we&#8217;re in a bubble, it&#8217;s easy to get lost in the same narrative: everything is booming! This week&#8217;s episode was a good reminder of how diverse, and nuanced, this ever-lasting startup summer truly is.</li>
</ul>
<div class="article-content"><em>Equity drops every Monday, Wednesday and Friday morning at 7:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity">Overcast</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ">Spotify</a> and all the casts.</em></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/another-month-another-billion-dollars-in-value-appreciation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222245</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hiring is just the first step when building an early-stage comms team</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/hiring-is-just-the-first-step-when-building-an-early-stage-comms-team/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/hiring-is-just-the-first-step-when-building-an-early-stage-comms-team/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reporter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2221645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An awesome strategic comms pro should be your first marketing investment. Without clear, concise and compelling messaging, your business loses the majority of its impact.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Yousuf Khan</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/yakhan">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yousufakhan">Yousuf Khan</a> is a partner at <a href="https://ridge.vc/">Ridge Ventures</a>. Prior to joining Ridge, he was the first CIO of Automation Anywhere, CIO and vice president of Customer Success at cloud-based AI platform Moveworks, as well as CIO of Pure Storage, Qualys and Hult International Business School. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/">3 keys to pricing early-stage SaaS products</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/develop-a-buyers-guide-to-educate-your-startups-sales-team-and-customers/">Develop a buyer’s guide to educate your startup&#8217;s sales team and customers</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">An awesome strategic comms pro should be your first marketing investment.</p>
<p>Without clear, concise and compelling messaging, your business loses the majority of its impact. Forget press and analysts — you will struggle to land customers or investors if your value proposition isn’t positioned correctly. Even if it’s too early to add someone full time, seek outside help from someone with a level of seniority that matches your own.</p>
<p>The processes of early messaging/positioning and early product design should not be treated as entirely separate. Allowing these messaging sessions to expose shortcomings or uncover new potential will help ensure all your future marketing efforts are rooted in truth and accuracy.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			If you’ve put together a strong comms team, they have a strategy and a plan. You can help them execute that plan incrementally, but you can undo its progress in the blink of an eye.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>When it is time to add a full-time comms person to your team, look for a strategic partner rather than a manager. Hire someone who understands your business, not just theirs. Even though they’re not a spokesperson, they’ll often be the first representative from your company with whom reporters, analysts and influencers will interact.</p>
<p>They should be able to discuss your product and industry as well as anyone on your sales team. If that sounds like a tall order, it is — yet another reason to properly invest in the role.</p>
<h2>Media relations is a small piece of the puzzle</h2>
<p>Too many people treat communications and PR as if they&#8217;re interchangeable when the latter is actually just a fractional percentage of the former. Traditional media relations is simply much less important than it was a decade ago.</p>
<p>The number of employed business journalists in the world dwindles every day, while the number of publications that accept paid and contributed content grows. The reporter you simply &#8220;have&#8221; to meet today might well be running PR for one of your competitors tomorrow.</p>
<p>Those left are stretched thin. They don’t even have the bandwidth to cover everything they need to. The days of a sure-fire business press story or guaranteed trade coverage around a product launch are long gone.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we&#8217;ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>All tech companies think they’re doing something unique and incredible, and many are. But no matter what you’re doing, there’s always someone out there who can bump you from the news cycle.</p>
<p>Figure out a way to measure the output of your communications program beyond the number of articles placed; those mentions are meaningless if they’re not aligned with your message. Relationships and creativity are the key to a strong media presence in today’s landscape. For the same reason they don’t have time to cover everything, reporters have to rely on a network of people they trust to tell them what’s important.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/hiring-is-just-the-first-step-when-building-an-early-stage-comms-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2221645</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>a16z, Base Partners cook up $15M in funding for Colombia cloud kitchen concept Foodology</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/a16z-base-partners-cook-up-15m-in-funding-for-colombia-cloud-kitchen-concept-foodology/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/a16z-base-partners-cook-up-15m-in-funding-for-colombia-cloud-kitchen-concept-foodology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Base Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniela Izquierdo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food and drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food delivery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harvard Business School]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaguar Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Juan Guillermo Azuero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kayyak Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Foodology collects data on user preferences and cross-references that with nearby food options in a geographical area to manage the end-to-end creation of original dishes with delivery.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Foodology has been whipping up its restaurant brands in cloud and virtual kitchens in Colombia and Mexico since 2019, and with a new infusion of capital, hopes to scale that across Latin America.</p>
<p>The Bogotá-based company closed on $15 million in Series A funding in a round led by Andreessen Horowitz and Base Partners. Existing investors Kayyak Ventures and Jaguar Ventures (now Wollef) joined in as did a group of angel investors, including Instacart president Nilam Ganenthiran, Kavak CEO Carlos Garcia, Ualá CEO Pierpaolo Barbieri, former Burger King Chairman Dick Boyce and Merama CEO Sujay Tyle. Including the new funding, Foodology has raised more than $20 million.</p>
<p>The company was founded by CEO Daniela Izquierdo and Juan Guillermo Azuero, who met in a restaurant industry course at Harvard Business School. Izquierdo told TechCrunch that she is a big fan of cooking and wanted to mix that passion with a business.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222282" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>“It is a risky industry — people go broke, restaurants are closing down and it is capital-intensive to set it up, even a small shop,” she added. “We wanted to bring in technology and data to be more efficient and be prepared for a virtual world, which behind it is food delivery. Many restaurants did not change at all to serve the delivery customer.”</p>
<p>Azuero added that on the customer side, food delivery is “usually just an OK experience, not a great experience” and often the food packaging is not the best. Foodology is working to change that, and they say they have built a model that enables it to rapidly scale original and third-party restaurant brands across Latin American markets within weeks and deliver meals in a way that will delight customers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Here’s how it works: Foodology collects data on user preferences and cross-references that with nearby food options in a geographical area to manage the end-to-end creation of original dishes with delivery.</p>
<p>The company typically has seven to 10 brands being made in one kitchen and performs R&amp;D on the best-sold dishes in order to create menus with its full team of chefs, Izquierdo said.</p>
<p>Foodology currently operates 20 kitchens in six cities across Colombia and 10 in Mexico and has 60 corporate employees and over 300 in its kitchens. In Colombia, it is taking 100,000 orders per month and just passed a milestone of 1 million orders total. Izquierdo aims to open another six kitchens, as well as use the new funding to enter the Brazilian and Peruvian markets next year.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1114000/foodservice-sales-growth-latin-america/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Latin America’s food service industry</a> was forecasted to generate $264 billion in 2020. To keep up, in addition to expanding the number of kitchens, the company will use the new funding on product development as it grows 50% month in revenue, a pace the founders see continuing as it opens more locations in Mexico and enters the new markets. Their goal is to support 500 kitchens in the future, Azuero said.</p>
<p>“There are tons of people looking to have virtual restaurants and brands, but very few have a model at scale in the region,” Izquierdo said. “We are by far the biggest player doing it in LatAm.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KmuBdlNGpQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/vcs-say-there-are-more-startup-opportunities-to-chase-in-latin-america/">VCs say there are more startup opportunities to chase in Latin America</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;VCs say there are more startup opportunities to chase in Latin America&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/vcs-say-there-are-more-startup-opportunities-to-chase-in-latin-america/embed/#?secret=KmuBdlNGpQ" data-secret="KmuBdlNGpQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/a16z-base-partners-cook-up-15m-in-funding-for-colombia-cloud-kitchen-concept-foodology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Klarna jets into travel with Inspirock acquisition</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/klarna-travel-inspirock-acquisition/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/klarna-travel-inspirock-acquisition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anoop Goyal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Sandstrom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspirock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MakeMyTrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merchandising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palo alto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prakash Sikchi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel bookings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Though it might seem strange for a company like Klarna to get into travel, CMO David Sandstrom says travel is a pain point Klarna wants to solve for its consumers. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.klarna.com/us/aus47/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Klarna</a>, the global retail bank, payments and shopping service, can now add “travel agent” to that list.</p>
<p>The company announced Friday that it acquired Inspirock, an online trip planner using artificial intelligence and local expertise to enable Klarna’s 90 million users to quickly and easily explore a destination’s offerings and create personalized itineraries. Financial terms of the deal were not disclosed.</p>
<p>Inspirock, based in East Palo Alto, was founded in 2012 by CEO Anoop Goyal and Prakash Sikchi. Over 25 million travelers use Inspirock annually to plan trips based on their interests or seek out new places to visit.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222323" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2222438" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2222438" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2222438 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg?w=300" alt="David Sandstrom, Klarna" width="300" height="275" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg 2047w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg?resize=150,138 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg?resize=300,275 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg?resize=768,704 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg?resize=680,624 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg?resize=1536,1408 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/David-Sandstrom.jpg?resize=50,46 50w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2222438" class="wp-caption-text">David Sandstrom, CMO of Klarna</p></div></p>
<p>It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/06/24/inspirock/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">raised $3 million in venture capital</a> funding in 2015, led by existing investor MakeMyTrip, one of India’s largest travel booking sites. David Sandstrom, Klarna’s chief marketing officer, told TechCrunch the entire Inspirock team is joining Klarna.</p>
<p>“Our goal at Inspirock has been to make planning a trip fast, fun and easy,” said Goyal in a written statement. “Together we can deliver on Klarna’s ambitions of providing a smooth shopping experience to the travel space in an innovative way. Klarna and Inspirock together can bring great inspiration, tools and shopping experiences, making planning the trip as fun as the actual trip itself.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Aq1KGLUaU1"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/really-this-market-isnt-good-enough/">Really, this market isn&#8217;t good enough?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Really, this market isn&#8217;t good enough?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/21/really-this-market-isnt-good-enough/embed/#?secret=Aq1KGLUaU1" data-secret="Aq1KGLUaU1" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>It’s been a busy year for Klarna, which is valued at $45.6 billion: This is the company’s fifth acquisition this year and follows three acquisitions over the summer of Apprl, Stocard and HERO, as well as Toplooks.ai earlier this year.</p>
<p>The acquisitions strategy so far was to enable creation of content at scale, Sandstrom said. He is bullish about ways to move into inspiration, curation and social shopping, which are key to what Klarna is doing. Sandstrom believes that e-commerce has shifted from an experience that was lonely and transactional into one that adds emotion.</p>
<p>“The next generation of e-commerce for me is going to be the social aspect, where we connect with peers and are able to do a deeper dive into reviews and interact with key opinion leaders,” he added. “We have put massive investments into content creation and curation, which will be an enabler for our entire customer base to create content.”</p>
<p>Though it might seem strange for a company like Klarna to get into the travel business, Sandstrom says the acquisition of Inspirock is his company&#8217;s way of solving another pain point for its consumers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In this case, after booking flight and hotel reservations, helping plan what the consumer will actually do on that vacation. And, providing them a way to purchase event and attraction tickets using Klarna’s buy now, pay later service. Integrating Inspirock also provides an opportunity to connect Klarna’s 250,000 retail partners to travelers that may visit their respective areas.</p>
<p>Some 66% of global travel bookings are already made online, and that figure is expected to grow to 72% by 2025 as the <a href="https://www.reportlinker.com/p06064498/Online-Travel-Agent-Global-Market-Report-COVID-19-Growth-And-Change-To.html?utm_source=GNW">global online travel agent market</a> itself is poised to reach $833.5 billion by that year.</p>
<p>Klarna’s own research shows that an average of 21% of people around the world put travel at the top of their list for categories in which they plan to splurge on in 2021.</p>
<p>“Forty-two percent of people say they are frustrated planning their trips,” Sandstrom said. “There are already kick-ass sites for booking airlines and hotels, and we aren’t going into that. What we are doing is connecting local retailers and merchants with that trip planning experience so that consumers can have an easier time planning what they want to do during the visit and actually experience a city.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="XA9IluJq43"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/">Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Livestream e-commerce: Why companies and brands need to tune in&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/livestream-e-commerce-why-companies-and-brands-need-to-tune-in/embed/#?secret=XA9IluJq43" data-secret="XA9IluJq43" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/klarna-travel-inspirock-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222323</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Citcon raises $30M to make paying with mobile wallets &#8216;as easy as paying with a credit card&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/citcon-raises-30m-to-make-paying-with-mobile-wallets-as-easy-as-paying-with-a-credit-card/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/citcon-raises-30m-to-make-paying-with-mobile-wallets-as-easy-as-paying-with-a-credit-card/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citcon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cota Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile wallets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Citcon, a mobile wallet payment provider, has closed on $30 million in funding in a Series C round co-led by Norwest Venture Partners and Cota Capital.  Sierra Ventures and Sonae IM also joined the financing, which brings San Jose-based Citcon’s total raised since its 2015 inception to nearly $50 million. Citcon’s mission is straightforward: to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.citcon.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Citcon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a mobile wallet payment provider, has closed on $30 million in funding in a Series C round co-led by Norwest Venture Partners and Cota Capital. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sierra Ventures and Sonae IM also joined the financing, which brings San Jose-based Citcon’s total raised since its 2015 inception to nearly $50 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Citcon’s mission is straightforward: to allow merchants to accept payments by mobile wallet and alternative currencies “with the same ease as they process traditional credit card payments today,” according to CEO and founder Chuck Huang.</span></p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222309" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before starting Citcon, Huang spent four years as a lead systems architect at Visa, where he led the s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ystem architecture design and development for several products, including its mobile payment gateway and card-based rewards redemption platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Citcon was built on the premise that mobile payments provide a “more user-friendly, secure and safer” contactless shopping and payment experience for both consumers and merchants. And that was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">before</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the COVID-19 pandemic accelerated the surge in contactless payments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clearly, Citcon is doing something right. As 2021 draws to a close, Citcon’s annualized payment volume is about $1 billion, representing over 300% year-over-year growth. Revenue, too, has grown by the same percentage, according to Huang.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup’s payment technology is integrated </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">with POS and e-commerce systems such as Toshiba, Oracle, Cegid, Shopify and SAP. And it’s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">deployed at more than 30,000 merchants’ sites and locations, including L&#8217;Oréal, Tumi, Texas Instruments, Macy’s and Panda Express.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Citcon offers something that Apple Pay and Google Pay don’t, according to Huang. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Ours is software-based and so unlike with Apple Pay or Google Pay, you don&#8217;t need a bank or credit card attached to the wallets,” he explained. “We have a unified API for both mobile and alternative payment methods (APMs).”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Traditional payment infrastructure was not designed to accept mobile wallets so merchants had to deal with a lot of implementation, Huang said. Since Citcon does a single API integration for a merchant, it allows that merchant to accept over 100 mobile wallets around the world.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2222355 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/qr-code-payment-cap.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/qr-code-payment-cap.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/qr-code-payment-cap.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/qr-code-payment-cap.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/qr-code-payment-cap.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/qr-code-payment-cap.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/qr-code-payment-cap.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The trend of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">software-based wallets for payments has accelerated globally over the last couple of years, according to Huang. And Citcon is poised to capitalize on that trend.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“China is an almost cashless society and its residents use this kind of wallet extensively, but it is gaining momentum all over,” Huang told TechCrunch. For example, in the U.S. the startup is working with PayPal/Venmo to enable this software wallet for its users. It has also partnered with Klarna to create a “buy now, pay later” wallet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, Citcon plans to use its new capital to add to its current headcount of 100, and expand globally. It already has offices in the U.S., Canada, Europe and Asia. It’s eyeing “rapid” overseas expansion with a particular focus on Latin America and the Asia-Pacific market.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Norwest Venture Partners’ partner Priti Youssef Choksi said her firm was first drawn to Citcon’s leadership team.</span> Sh<span style="font-weight: 400;">e described Huang and president and COO Wei Jang as “thought leaders” in the world of payments. The pair, she noted, are both natives of China and can bring an international view into how mobile wallets can evolve within the U.S.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is important because there are several key themes converging around mobile payments both in the U.S. and abroad,” she wrote via email. For one, mobile wallets have eclipsed credit cards to become the most widely used form of payment globally, with active mobile wallets expected to grow from 2.8 billion in 2020 to 4.8 billion in 2025.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In the U.S., they’re quickly gaining share given new wallets (such as crypto, buy now, pay later platforms and neobank wallets) are increasingly popular among younger consumers, and as the pandemic has pushed consumers/merchants towards contactless payments,” Choksi added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She is also impressed by the company’s ability to have navigated compliance challenges surrounding each wallet and country in which it operates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is particularly important given the regulatory scrutiny on payment flows in the U.S. and around the world,” Choksi said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cota Capital partner Ben Malka said his firm has been closely following trends in alternative tender-type usage, both globally and in the U.S.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“While we believe we are still in the early innings, there is a tremendous market opportunity to enable different payment types,” he said. “We were impressed with Chuck and his team. They have deep experience in the payment industry and the right acumen to build a global payments company.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/citcon-raises-30m-to-make-paying-with-mobile-wallets-as-easy-as-paying-with-a-credit-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222309</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jaguar Ventures roars into its next phase with name change, new fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/jaguar-ventures-roars-into-its-next-phase-with-name-change-new-fund/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/jaguar-ventures-roars-into-its-next-phase-with-name-change-new-fund/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 13:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cristóbal Perdomo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Pérez-Grovas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaguar Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kavak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Konfio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nubank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peixe-Urbano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wollef]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The new fund will enable Wollef to finally write the larger checks they weren't able to with their previous funds.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://jaguarvc.com/">Jaguar Ventures</a>, a Mexican fund investing in early-stage startups, is now Wollef and is launching its third fund with a target of raising $100 million before the first quarter of 2022.</p>
<p>The firm got started back in 2013 when Eric Pérez-Grovas, who launched the Mercado Libre Mexico operations, joined with Cristóbal Perdomo, a serial founder of companies like Groupalia, which was sold to the Brazilian Peixe Urbano.</p>
<p>Since then, the company has invested in 31 companies, including unicorns Kavak, Konfío, Loft and Nubank. Its first fund raised $9.3 million in 2014, followed by a second fund of $22 million. Though 10 of the companies are in Mexico, another 19 are foreign companies that see Mexico as a key market, Pérez-Grovas told TechCrunch.</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222239" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>Initially, the pair chose “jaguar” for its name because it was distinctive at the time, was an animal present in the Americas, where the firm invested and was an aggressive animal which spoke to the way they liked to invest. Unfortunately, several other entities emerged with “jaguar” in their name, and it caused some confusion, Pérez-Grovas added.</p>
<p>“We wanted to choose another name that was unique, and Cristóbal pointed out that we chose the wrong animal,” he said. “He said we should have chosen the wolf instead because though it is a hunter, it travels in a pack and the ‘alpha’ can be female or male. Wollef fits better and aligns with our vision of working as a team with the entrepreneur.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Pérez-Grovas and Perdomo say the Latin American startup ecosystem is booming, noting data from the Latin American Venture Capital Association that showed venture capital in the first half of 2021 <a href="https://lavca.org/industry-data/2021-latin-american-startup-directory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hit $6 billion dollars,</a> up from the $4.8 billion that was invested in 2020.</p>
<p>This boom became beneficial to Wollef, which has had an easier time attracting limited partners into its latest fund. Perdomo explained that when they were raising in 2013, maybe 10 people out of 100 family offices and businesses in Mexico they called would take a meeting. That grew to half taking a meeting in 2019 for the second fund, but still only 10% of LPs got in. Now, the firm is on the receiving end of the calls, especially organizations from the U.S. that want to get involved in Latin America.</p>
<p>The new fund will be similar to the previous ones that have been agnostic to the sector, though much of Wollef&#8217;s portfolio comprises fintech, marketplaces and e-commerce companies, they said.</p>
<p>The firm is looking to invest in another 20 to 25 new companies, and Pérez-Grovas and Perdomo say they are eager to be able to write the larger checks this time around than with their previous funds. They expect to put in first checks between $500,000 and $1 million.</p>
<p>One of the unique aspects between them and other firms is that Wollef does not share information on companies with anyone. Pérez-Grovas explained that other firms in the country don’t see investments as financial returns, but instead as a way of gathering information.</p>
<p>“They may not have been successful, so they are using firms now for information,” he added. “We are helping startups for financial returns. That is also what we love about U.S. investors, they are looking for that, too.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xALwuyyRmG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/how-vcs-can-get-the-most-out-of-co-investing-alongside-lps/">How VCs can get the most out of co-investing alongside LPs</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How VCs can get the most out of co-investing alongside LPs&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/how-vcs-can-get-the-most-out-of-co-investing-alongside-lps/embed/#?secret=xALwuyyRmG" data-secret="xALwuyyRmG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/jaguar-ventures-roars-into-its-next-phase-with-name-change-new-fund/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222239</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Audit Sight takes on new capital to eliminate all of the back and forth between auditors, companies</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/audit-sight-takes-on-new-capital-to-eliminate-all-of-the-back-and-forth-between-auditors-companies/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/audit-sight-takes-on-new-capital-to-eliminate-all-of-the-back-and-forth-between-auditors-companies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accounting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alumni Ventures Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audit Sight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auditing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guidewire Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyde Park Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ira Weiss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan Womack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pricewaterhousecoopers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PWC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T.C. Whittaker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2222049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company intends to build out several SaaS applications and is poised to roll out its first two modules for revenue and accounts receivables by the end of the year.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Financial statement audits are an essential part of doing business, but often are complex and can require documentation gathering, most times requiring email correspondence back and forth between the auditor and the company for files and information to complete the task.</p>
<p>T.C. Whittaker, co-founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.auditsight.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Audit Sight</a>, says companies can spend millions of dollars per year on these audits, but the customer experience is lacking. He recalls doing audit work from a windowless room, punching numbers into a spreadsheet while he was working for PwC.</p>
<p>“It was really painful,” he told TechCrunch. “They have to show all of the details, and out of that, the auditor will make some selections and there is a crazy back-and-forth with the client who is also trying to do their day job. Even back then, I was thinking there had to be a better way to do this.”</p><div id="tc-target-mid-article-2222049" class="tc-target-mid-article ad-unit--size-auto"></div>
<p>He ended up building a company inside of PwC with co-founder Jonathan Womack around cloud systems for audit work and ultimately they left PwC last year to start another company, this time Atlanta-based Audit Sight, that eliminates all of the back and forth by using APIs to access client records and can also look at 100% of the transactions instead of a sample.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2222053" style="width: 1447px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2222053" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2222053 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audit-Sight-screenshot.png" alt="Audit Sight" width="1437" height="896" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audit-Sight-screenshot.png 1437w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audit-Sight-screenshot.png?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audit-Sight-screenshot.png?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audit-Sight-screenshot.png?resize=768,479 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audit-Sight-screenshot.png?resize=680,424 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Audit-Sight-screenshot.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1437px) 100vw, 1437px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2222053" class="wp-caption-text">Audit Sight dashboard. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Audit Sight</p></div></p>
<p>To continue developing its software, the company announced Friday $2.5 million in seed funding, led by Hyde Park Venture Partners, with participation from Alumni Ventures Group and individual investors, including Johnson Cook, CEO of Greenlight; Aaron Rankin, co-founder of Sprout Social; and John Seybold and Ken Branson, co-founders of Guidewire Software.</p>
<p>Whittaker notes that the audit services industry is projected to be a $43 billion market in the United States this year, so the new funding will enable the company to jump on additional hiring to meet that demand. It has already added Eric Kingery as chief technology officer and Attila Domokos as executive vice president of engineering.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company intends to build out several SaaS applications and is poised to roll out its first two modules for revenue and accounts receivables by the end of the year. Audit Sight has customers piloting the software currently.</p>
<p>“Our next steps are to get this thing into the hands of paying customers,” Whittaker added. “Audits are a good thing and provide a lot of trust for how companies are doing. It’s also how banks determine if they want to lend money. We are at the forefront of providing transparency into this world.”</p>
<p>As part of the investment, Ira Weiss, partner at Hyde Park Venture Partners, has joined the Audit Sight board. Weiss knew the company’s team while they were still at PwC and also knew this pain point intimately when he was briefly an auditor himself.</p>
<p>His firm invests in companies that are going after large markets to solve problems that couldn’t have been solved before. In this case, due to accounting systems not yet having largely moved to the cloud.</p>
<p>One of the things that attracted Weiss to the investment was Whittaker’s and Womack’s backgrounds and previous expertise in working with accounting and software.</p>
<p>“I see a world where you can have audits done quickly and painlessly,” he added. “You can contact your audit firm and in less than a week, the firm can do some semblance of an audit. Even 30 or 40 years from now it could be instantaneous.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GUQxhJ3kmw"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/18/what-you-should-know-about-prepping-your-startup-for-the-public-markets/">What you should know about prepping your startup for the public markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;What you should know about prepping your startup for the public markets&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/18/what-you-should-know-about-prepping-your-startup-for-the-public-markets/embed/#?secret=GUQxhJ3kmw" data-secret="GUQxhJ3kmw" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/audit-sight-takes-on-new-capital-to-eliminate-all-of-the-back-and-forth-between-auditors-companies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2222049</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
