<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 09:02:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Helsinki&#8217;s Maki.vc poised to close fund at €100M, key focus will be sustainability, deeptech</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/helsinkis-maki-vc-poised-to-close-fund-at-e100m-key-focus-will-be-sustainability-deeptech/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/helsinkis-maki-vc-poised-to-close-fund-at-e100m-key-focus-will-be-sustainability-deeptech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 08:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Helsinki-based VC Maki.vc is poised to reach the final close of its second fund at €100 million, with the aim to invest in seed-stage startups across Europe. The first investments from the new fund include UK-based Baseimmune (antigen discovery and vaccine design), Volare (Foodtech), and PixieRay (adaptive eyeglasses). Maki.vc’s initial ticket sizes range from €250,000 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Helsinki-based VC <a href="http://Maki.vc">Maki.vc</a> is poised to reach the final close of its second fund at €100 million, with the aim to invest in seed-stage startups across Europe.</p>
<p>The first investments from the new fund include UK-based Baseimmune (antigen discovery and vaccine design), Volare (Foodtech), and PixieRay (adaptive eyeglasses).</p>
<p>Maki.vc’s initial ticket sizes range from €250,000 to €3 million. The VC’s first €80M fund invested in sustainable textile fiber producer Spinnova, quantum computing team IQM, and Oatly’s partner for carbon labeling, CarbonCloud.</p>
<p>In a statement, Maki.vc’s Founding Partner Ilkka Kivimäki said: “Within the deep tech and brand-driven focus, we have no industry or geographical restrictions, but instead we look for relentless founders. Common to the most advanced technologies and most captivating brands is their ability to approach the world’s greatest challenges in unconventional ways.”</p>
<p>In an interview with TechCrunch Kivimäki added: “We have 77 investments already in the new fund. So up and running and hitting the ground running.”</p>
<p>Is there a change in strategy?</p>
<p>“Actually, very little,” he said. “We were already talking about the sustainability aspect. I think that that is going to many more new materials, new processes, including all of the food tech stuff. And we are definitely not shying away from hardware and complex things. We were initial investors in IQM which is the quantum computer. We were the only venture investor in a company called Spinnova which is making yarn from wood fibers.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The new fund is backed by 70+ LPs comprising of exited entrepreneurs and corporate executives, including Wise co-founder Taavet Hinrikus and Teleport co-founder Sten Tamkivi, Supercell co-founder &amp; CEO Ilkka Paananen, Wolt co-founders Oskari Petas and Mika Matikainen, Small Giant Games chair of the board Timo<br />
Soininen, chair of the board at Ensto Marjo Miettinen and Seriously CEO &amp; co-founder Petri Järvilehto.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/helsinkis-maki-vc-poised-to-close-fund-at-e100m-key-focus-will-be-sustainability-deeptech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202029</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean antitrust regulator fines Google $177M for abusing market dominance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/south-korean-antitrust-regulator-fines-google-177m-for-abusing-market-dominance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/south-korean-antitrust-regulator-fines-google-177m-for-abusing-market-dominance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Park]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 08:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Korea Fair Trade Commission (KFTC) said on Tuesday it fined Google $177 million for abusing its market dominance in the Android operating system (OS) market. The U.S. tech company has restricted market competition by prohibiting local smartphone makers like Samsung Electronics and LG Electronics from customizing their Android OS, through Google’s anti-fragmentation agreements (AFA), [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Korea Fair Trade Commission (KFTC) <a href="http://www.ftc.go.kr/www/selectReportUserView.do?key=10&amp;rpttype=1&amp;report_data_no=9254">said</a> on Tuesday it fined Google $177 million for abusing its market dominance in the Android operating system (OS) market.</p>
<p>The U.S. tech company has restricted market competition by prohibiting local smartphone makers like Samsung Electronics and LG Electronics from customizing their Android OS, through Google’s anti-fragmentation agreements (AFA), according to the antitrust regulator statement.</p>
<p>Under the AFA, smartphone developers are not allowed to install or develop “Android forks”, modified versions of Android.</p>
<p>The KFTC banned Google LLC, Google Asia Pacific and Google Korea from imposing local smartphone developers to sign the AFA and make changes on details about the existing version. The new measure in South Korea will be applied to not only mobiles devices but also other Android-powered smart devices including watches and TVs.</p>
<p><a href="https://source.android.com/compatibility/overview">Android&#8217;s compatibility program</a> has spurred innovation among Korean mobile operator owners and software developers and that has led to a better user experience for Korean consumers, Google said in its statement. “The KFTC’s decision released today ignores these benefits, and will undermine the advantages enjoyed by consumers. Google intends to appeal the KFTC’s decision,” a spokesperson at Google said.</p>
<p>The commission has been investigating Google over the anti-competition practice in OS market since July 2016, a spokesperson at KFTC said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qTJF675rHx"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/google-hit-with-123m-antitrust-fine-in-italy-over-android-auto/">Google hit with $123M antitrust fine in Italy over Android Auto</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google hit with $123M antitrust fine in Italy over Android Auto&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/13/google-hit-with-123m-antitrust-fine-in-italy-over-android-auto/embed/#?secret=qTJF675rHx" data-secret="qTJF675rHx" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Google’s global mobile OS market share excluding China has been increased to 97.7% in 2019 from 38% in 2010, as per KFTC’s announcement.</p>
<p>Google’s AFA has also limited to launch tech companies’ new devices like smart watches and TVs using the operating system (OS) including Samsung’s smart watch in 2013, LG Electronics’ LTE smart speaker in 2018 as well as Amazon’s smart TV in 2018.</p>
<p>South Korea’s watchdog is probing into three other cases including the Play Store app market, billing system and the advertisement market.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, South Korea’s “anti-Google law”, <a href="https://www.kcc.go.kr/user.do?mode=view&amp;page=A05030000&amp;dc=K05030000&amp;boardId=1113&amp;cp=1&amp;boardSeq=51891">takes effect on 14 September, based on Korea Communications Commission’s press release.</a></p>
<p>In late August, South Korea <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/south-korea-passes-anti-google-law-bill-to-curb-google-apple-in-app-payment-commission/">passed a bill</a> to curb global tech companies including Google and Apple from imposing their own proprietary in-app payment service and commissions on app developers.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HEAcNLvGxN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/">Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google faces a major multi-state antitrust lawsuit over Google Play fees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/07/google-state-lawsuit-android-attorneys-general/embed/#?secret=HEAcNLvGxN" data-secret="HEAcNLvGxN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vT0Lr1wi3K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/apple-and-google-pressed-in-antitrust-hearing-on-whether-app-stores-share-data-with-product-development-teams/">Apple and Google pressed in antitrust hearing on whether app stores share data with product development teams</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple and Google pressed in antitrust hearing on whether app stores share data with product development teams&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/apple-and-google-pressed-in-antitrust-hearing-on-whether-app-stores-share-data-with-product-development-teams/embed/#?secret=vT0Lr1wi3K" data-secret="vT0Lr1wi3K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/south-korean-antitrust-regulator-fines-google-177m-for-abusing-market-dominance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PassFort, a RegTech SaaS for KYC and AML, nets $16.2M</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/passfort-a-regtech-saas-for-kyc-and-aml-nets-16-2m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/passfort-a-regtech-saas-for-kyc-and-aml-nets-16-2m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 08:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[know your customer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[level equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money laundering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulatory compliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulatory technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worldremit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[London-based PassFort, a SaaS provider that helps business meet compliance requirements such as KYC (Know Your Customer) and AML (Anti-Money Laundering) reporting, has closed a $16.2 million Series A led by US growth equity fund, Level Equity. The 2015-founded startup&#8216;s existing investors OpenOcean, Episode 1 and Entrepreneur First also participated in the round. The Series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">London-based <a href="https://www.passfort.com">PassFort</a>, a SaaS provider that helps business meet compliance requirements such as KYC (Know Your Customer) and AML (Anti-Money Laundering) reporting, has closed a $16.2 million Series A led by US growth equity fund, Level Equity.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/09/09/ef4/">2015-founded startup</a>&#8216;s existing investors OpenOcean, Episode 1 and Entrepreneur First also participated in the round. The Series A is a mix of equity and debt, with $4.89M worth of venture debt being provided by Shard Credit Partners.</p>
<p>PassFort tells TechCrunch it now has 54 customers in total, saying the majority are in the digital payments space. It&#8217;s also selling its SaaS to customers in foreign exchange, banking and (ofc) crypto. It also touts some &#8220;major&#8221; customer wins preceding this raise &#8212; name-checking the likes of Curve and WorldRemit.</p>
<p>The new funding will be put towards stepping up its growth globally &#8212; with PassFort noting it&#8217;s hired a new C-suite for its growth team to lead the planned global push.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also hiring more staff in business development and marketing, and plans to significantly bump spending across marketing, sales and customer support roles as it gears up to scale up.</p>
<p>&#8220;On the product side we are developing the solution to meet the demands of the changing digital economy and the threats it faces,&#8221; says CEO and co-founder Donald Gillies. &#8220;This means investing heavily into our new compliance policy cloud, system-to-system integrations with market-leading CRM and transaction monitoring systems as well as building a data team capable of deriving valuable real-time insights across our customer network.&#8221;</p>
<p>PassFort says its revenues grew ~2.5x over the past 12 months.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Gillies credits COVID-19 with really hitting the digital &#8220;accelerator&#8221; and driving adoption for compliance tools, as fintechs and regulated businesses look to streamline their approach to customer on-boarding and risk monitoring.</p>
<p>Alongside this accelerated digital transformation, he also points to a rise in cyber crime and increasingly sophisticated financial crime driving demand for compliance tools, and a &#8220;huge&#8221; rise in the number of regulations announced since COVID-19, noting: &#8220;Estimates from those who track regulatory changes stated that by August 2020, more than 1,330 COVID-19 related regulatory announcements had been made globally by regulators.&#8221;</p>
<p>As well as serving up an &#8220;always-on picture of risk&#8221;, as PassFort&#8217;s marketing puts it, the platform offers a single place to access and manage customer profiles, while also centralizing records for audit purposes.</p>
<p>PassFort&#8217;s SaaS also tracks efficiency &#8212; supporting customers to see where holdups in the onboarding process might be, to help with customer experience as well as the wider support it offers to compliance teams.</p>
<p>The startup says its integration model is such that it can &#8220;ingest datasets from any provider and interoperate with any system&#8221;, so &#8212; for example &#8212; it has pre-built connectors to more than 25 data providers at this stage.</p>
<p>It also offers a single API to integrate with a customer&#8217;s existing back-office system.</p>
<p>Another feature of the SaaS it flags is a focus on &#8220;low to no-code&#8221; &#8212; to increase accessibility and help customers with high complexity in their compliance needs (such as multiple customer types, multiple product lines and multi-jurisdictions. This includes a smart policy builder with a &#8216;drag and drop&#8217; interface to help customers configure complex workflows.</p>
<p>On the competitive side, PassFort names Dublin-based <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/12/fenergo-raises-80m-at-an-800m-valuation-for-compliance-and-other-fintech-services-aimed-at-banks/">Fenergo</a> as its closest competitor but says it&#8217;s targeting a broader market &#8212; likening its own product to &#8216;Salesforce for compliance teams&#8217; and saying its goal is to get the SaaS into the hands of &#8220;every financial crime and compliance team in the world&#8221;.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Charles Chen, partner at Level Equity &#8212; who&#8217;s now joining PassFort’s board of directors &#8212; added: “Over the last few years, financial institutions and organisations have experienced exponential growth in business volumes and data, which has only increased the complexity in staying compliant with ever-evolving regulatory laws. In parallel, we’ve experienced an unprecedented rise in sophisticated financial crime activity as channels into financial systems have been digitized.</p>
<p>&#8220;This has underscored the importance of compliance matters such as AML/KYC, yet companies often have to weigh the trade-offs between speed, compliance and automation. PassFort has solved this challenge by providing a next-generation RegTech software solution that enables customers to offer a seamless customer onboarding experience, maintain best-in-class monitoring capabilities, and balance automation vs. human touch via its intelligent orchestration engine. We are thrilled to partner with the industry thought leader in this space and look forward to supporting the company’s future growth initiatives.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/passfort-a-regtech-saas-for-kyc-and-aml-nets-16-2m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201365</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch Apple unveil the new iPhone live right here</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-iphone-13-mini-pro-max-keynote-live-stream-livestream/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-iphone-13-mini-pro-max-keynote-live-stream-livestream/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 07:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple fall event 2021]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone 13]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple is set to announce new iPhone models today. The company is holding a (virtual) keynote at 10 AM PT (1 PM in New York, 6 PM in London, 7 PM in Paris). And you’ll be able to watch the event right here as the company is streaming it live. Rumor has it that there [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple is set to announce new iPhone models today. The company is holding a (virtual) keynote at <strong>10 AM PT (1 PM in New York, 6 PM in London, 7 PM in Paris)</strong>. And you’ll be able to watch the event right here as the company is streaming it live.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EvGOlAkLSLw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/what-we-expect-from-next-weeks-apple-event/">Rumor has it</a> that there will be a new generation of iPhone models. Reports suggest that the company is going to call it the iPhone 13 and that there will be four different models just like last year. Today, you can expect to learn more about the iPhone 13, iPhone 13 Mini, iPhone 13 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro Max.</p>
<p>When it comes to new features, it’s safe to say that there will be big camera upgrades. This year, the company seems to be focused on video improvements in particular. The iPhone 13 should also come with a better display and a faster chip.</p>
<p>But that’s not all. Apple is likely to use this opportunity to announce a new Apple Watch model. There will be bigger design changes with the Apple Watch Series 7 with sharp edges.</p>
<p>There could be more product announcements as Apple has been working on the AirPods 3. They will replace or complement the entry-level AirPods 2 in the audio lineup. The AirPods Pro and AirPods Max will remain unchanged for now.</p>
<p>Finally, there’s a small chance that we get to hear more about new Macs with custom designed Apple chips as well as new iPad models…</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>You can watch the live stream directly on this page, as Apple is streaming its conference on YouTube.</p>
<p>If you have an Apple TV, you can open the TV app and look for the &#8216;Apple Special Event&#8217; section. It lets you stream today’s event and rewatch old ones.</p>
<p>And if you don’t have an Apple TV and don’t want to use YouTube, the company also lets you live stream the event from the <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-events/livestream/">Apple Events section</a> on its website. This video feed now works in all major browsers — Safari, Mozilla Firefox, Microsoft Edge and Google Chrome.</p>
<p>We’ll be covering the event and you can <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021">follow our liveblog</a> for live commentary.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/apple-fall-event-2021"><img alt="Read more about Apple's Fall 2021 Event on TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/apple-fall-event-2021-banner.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/14/apple-iphone-13-mini-pro-max-keynote-live-stream-livestream/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201607</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India and Singapore to link their payments systems to enable &#8216;instant and low-cost&#8217; cross-border transactions</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/india-and-singapore-to-link-their-digital-payments-upi-paynow-systems/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/india-and-singapore-to-link-their-digital-payments-upi-paynow-systems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 06:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2202004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[India and Singapore are working to link their digital payments systems to enable “instant, low-cost fund transfers,” in a major push to disrupt the cross-border transactions between the two nations that amounts to over $1 billion each year. The project to link India’s Unified Payments Interface (UPI) and Singapore’s PayNow is targeted for operationalization by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">India and Singapore are working to link their digital payments systems to enable “instant, low-cost fund transfers,” in a major push to disrupt the cross-border transactions between the two nations that amounts to over $1 billion each year.</p>
<p>The project to link India’s Unified Payments Interface (UPI) and Singapore’s PayNow is targeted for operationalization by July 2022, both nation&#8217;s central banks said on Tuesday. Users on either of the systems will be able to make transactions to one another without having to sign up to the second platform, the banks added.</p>
<p>&#8220;When implemented, fund transfers can be made from India to Singapore using mobile phone numbers, and from Singapore to India using UPI virtual payment addresses (VPA). The experience of making a PayNow transfer to a UPI VPA will be similar to that of a domestic transfer to a PayNow VPA,&#8221; said Monetary Authority of Singapore in a <a href="https://www.mas.gov.sg/news/media-releases/2021/singapores-paynow-and-indias-upi-to-link-in-2022">press statement</a>.</p>
<p>UPI, a five-year-old payments infrastructure developed by a coalition of retail banks, has become the most popular ways users in India transfer money to one another and to businesses.</p>
<p>The railroads, adopted by scores of local and global firms including Google and Facebook, is now processing over 3 billion transactions each month. Like UPI, Singapore&#8217;s PayNow also brings interoperability between banks and payments apps, allowing user from one payment app to make transaction to those on other apps.</p>
<p>Nearly 250 million people across the world send over $500 billion in cross-border remittances annually, a report by Citi said earlier this year. But the space is ripe for disruption. “The fees are extremely high. It is embarrassing that we have not solved this issue so far,” Citi analysts wrote. Global average cost for sending money is around 6.5%. The RBI and the MAS didn&#8217;t reveal the cross-border fees that they would charge their users.</p>
<p>India&#8217;s central bank <a href="https://www.rbi.org.in/Scripts/BS_PressReleaseDisplay.aspx?prid=52223">described</a> the project as a &#8220;significant milestone in the development of infrastructure for cross-border payments&#8221; between India and Singapore, and said the linkage &#8220;closely aligns with the G20’s financial inclusion priorities of driving faster, cheaper and more transparent cross-border payments.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The linkage builds upon the earlier efforts of NPCI International Private Limited (NIPL) and Network for Electronic Transfers (NETS) to foster cross-border interoperability of payments using cards and QR codes, between India and Singapore and will further anchor trade, travel and remittance flows between the two countries.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/india-and-singapore-to-link-their-digital-payments-upi-paynow-systems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2202004</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Political economist Neil Malholtra on why some in Silicon Valley turned on Gavin Newsom</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/political-economist-neil-malholtra-on-why-some-in-silicon-valley-turned-on-gavin-newsom/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/political-economist-neil-malholtra-on-why-some-in-silicon-valley-turned-on-gavin-newsom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 06:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whether or not Democratic California Governor Gavin Newsom survives Tuesday&#8217;s recall election may depend to some degree on a small but vocal group of Silicon Valley power players who&#8217;ve thrown their weight behind the effort to oust him, including some who previously supported mostly Democratic politicians. To better understand what happened, we talked recently with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Whether or not Democratic California Governor Gavin Newsom survives Tuesday&#8217;s recall election may depend to some degree on a small but vocal group of Silicon Valley power players who&#8217;ve thrown their weight behind the effort to oust him, including some who previously supported mostly Democratic politicians.</p>
<p>To better understand what happened, we talked recently with political economist and Stanford business school professor Neil Malhotra about research he conducted in 2017 about the <a class="external-link" href="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/faculty-research/working-papers/predispositions-political-behavior-american-economic-elites-evidence" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-offer-url="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/faculty-research/working-papers/predispositions-political-behavior-american-economic-elites-evidence" data-event-click="{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/faculty-research/working-papers/predispositions-political-behavior-american-economic-elites-evidence&quot;}">political attitudes of the tech elite</a> &#8212; and why some seemed so quick to turn on Newsom this year. Our conversation has been edited lightly for length.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How did you get into this line of work?</strong></p>
<p>NM: It was motivated from a historical perspective. When you look at a lot of major changes in American politics and parties, a lot of them have been driven by major business interests and sources of wealth. A good example is the robber barons, including Leland Stanford at the turn of the century. And it looks like we&#8217;re going through a similar period right now.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Based on your research, how do attitudes of Silicon Valley folks differ from the California population, as well as the national population in general?</strong></p>
<p>NM: Just to be clear, I use Silicon Valley as a metaphor. A lot of these people are located in other areas of the country as well, like Boston, Austin, Research Triangle, Los Angeles, etc. But just generally, I think the attitudes of this group of technology elites is unique and something you don&#8217;t see in any other part of the population. I&#8217;ve called them liberal-terian. To distinguish them from libertarians, they tend to be very liberal on social issues and issues related to globalization, like immigration and free trade. And they support redistribution, so they have very high support for universal health care. But they&#8217;re very against government regulation. So this distinguishing between redistribution and regulation is what makes this population very unique, even among very rich people in the United States.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Meaning regulation around labor? Is this about limiting the number of skilled educated immigrants who can come to the U.S. or about gig workers or . . .?</strong></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>NM: They are very, very supportive of immigration, and also very, very supportive of gig workers, and against the ability to restrict the labor market in any way.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re also very, very anti union, which also distinguishes them from other people within the Democratic Party. I think the general belief system they have is to let the market operate and then afterward redistribute money through taxes and social programs, because they feel that this is what will grow the pie the biggest and still allow for equality, rather than putting a lot of restrictions in place <em>a priori</em>, which will shrink innovation, shrink the pie.</p>
<p><strong>TC: There are many in tech who talk about the redistribution of wealth but in practice shield their assets or their companies&#8217; assets. Any thoughts about how sincere they are about this, based on your research?</strong></p>
<p>NM: They are very supportive of high income taxes. But maybe that&#8217;s self-serving, given that a lot of their wealth comes from capital gains, and it&#8217;s very possible they would be less supportive of capital gains taxes, not because it takes away their wealth, but because they would feel that it stifles innovation.</p>
<p>One of the leading tech figures in Silicon Valley, Chamath Palihapitiya, has said that California&#8217;s high taxes was one of the reasons he was supporting the recall.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Do you find that in general, the supporters of the recall were citing taxation as an issue or are there other issues that were more front of mind?</strong></p>
<p>NM: The COVID restrictions [were also top of mind]. I think that there&#8217;s a sense that these tech entrepreneurs really identify with entrepreneurs, even if they&#8217;re not elite entrepreneurs, and that includes small business owners, restaurant owners, gym owners, small landlords. They feel like the government has been punishing these people over the course of the pandemic. Further, I think that in addition to being against unions, they&#8217;re generally against public sector unions like teachers unions. And so I think the restrictions on school openings also struck a chord with this population.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Newsom&#8217;s camp has raised quite a bit of money compared with his recall opponents. Do you think that the money raised in this recall effort is going to substantially impact turnout?</strong></p>
<p>NM: I think everything makes a difference on the margin. All that money does go to advertising get-out-the-vote efforts. But at the end of the day, if there&#8217;s a real movement, it can&#8217;t really overcome it. Hillary Clinton out-raised Trump tremendously, and I&#8217;m sure all that money did help. But the big question is going to be, who&#8217;s excited to turn out, who&#8217;s going to motivate, and they may need that $70 million to convince people who are not that excited about voting in this election to vote in it to save him.</p>
<p><strong>TC: A number of tech luminaries who have supported this recall. How does it benefit them if Newsom loses? It seems they&#8217;re betting on chaos in a way.</strong></p>
<p>NM: I think a good test case of this is [congressman] Ro Khanna. In his first campaign against Mike Honda [in 2014], he ran as a Silicon Valley technocrat and was supported by [Facebook COO Shery] Sandberg and all of these tech luminaries, and he lost that election. Then he shifted and became the Bernie Sanders guy and was, I think, the national co-chair of Bernie Sanders campaign, and now is this quasi &#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Squad_(United_States_Congress)">squad&#8221;</a> member that&#8217;s on the far left. I just think that&#8217;s really interesting. It&#8217;s almost like a microcosm of the Democratic Party first embracing the tech community, and then now being very against it. This recall could reshape those alliances again potentially,</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/political-economist-neil-malholtra-on-why-some-in-silicon-valley-turned-on-gavin-newsom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201984</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital freight marketplace BridgeLinx raises $10 million in Pakistan&#8217;s largest seed funding</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/digital-freight-marketplace-bridgelinx-raises-10-million-in-pakistans-largest-seed-funding/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/digital-freight-marketplace-bridgelinx-raises-10-million-in-pakistans-largest-seed-funding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 06:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bazaar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blackbuck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckley Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Convoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harry stebbings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[josh buckley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pakistan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BridgeLinx, a 9-month-old Lahore-headquartered startup that operates a digital freight marketplace, said on Tuesday it has raised $10 million in what is the largest seed financing round in Pakistan. Harry Stebbings’ 20 VC, Josh Buckley’s Buckley Ventures and Indus Valley Capital co-led the startup’s financing round, which Salman Gul, co-founder and chief executive of BridgeLinx, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">BridgeLinx, a 9-month-old Lahore-headquartered startup that operates a digital freight marketplace, said on Tuesday it has raised $10 million in what is the largest seed financing round in Pakistan.</p>
<p>Harry Stebbings’ 20 VC, Josh Buckley’s Buckley Ventures and Indus Valley Capital co-led the startup’s financing round, which Salman Gul, co-founder and chief executive of BridgeLinx, told TechCrunch completed within weeks.</p>
<p>This is 20 VC and Buckley Ventures’ second lead investment in Pakistan in recent weeks <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/17/pakistans-airlift-raises-85-million-for-its-quick-commerce-startup-eyes-international-expansion/">following an $85 million round in quick-commerce startup Airlift</a>. Indus Valley Capital, which recently also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/pakistans-b2b-marketplace-and-digital-ledger-platform-bazaar-raises-30-million/">backed business-to-business marketplace Bazaar</a>, has invested in all three of the recent high-profile investments in the South Asian country.</p>
<p>Wavemaker Partners, Quiet Capital, TrueSight Ventures, Soma Capital, Flexport, Magnus Rausing’s UNTITLED and founders of Convoy and Bazaar also participated in the round.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.bridgelinxpk.com">BridgeLinx</a> is building a digital freight marketplace. The platform connects shippers &#8212; such as manufacturing companies, cement factories, textile companies &#8212; with truckers and private fleets.</p>
<p>It also provides its tech solutions to ensure documents validation on both ends, timely pickups, port operations and safety of cargo, said Gul, who previously worked at consultancy firm KPMG in Canada.</p>
<p>BridgeLinx has already onboarded thousands of carriers and is moving thousands of freight-loads each week for many large customers, he said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>As is true in India, Pakistan’s trucking system has a big inefficiency problem that continues to drag the economy.</p>
<p>One of the biggest problems faced by truckers is that once they have made a delivery, they have no work left during the return journey. So a truck delivering something to Lahore from Islamabad is likely not carrying something on its way back to the nation&#8217;s capital. This decades-old inefficiency continues to cost every stakeholder.</p>
<p>Startups like BridgeLinx are attempting to find ways to make this system more efficient, said Gul, who added that he has closely studied how Convoy, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/21/indias-blackbuck-valued-at-1-billion-in-67-million-fundraise/">India’s BlackBuck</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/10/rivigo-india-seriese/">Rivigo</a> have expanded their businesses in the recent years.</p>
<p>BridgeLinx, like BlackBuck, currently operates on an asset-lite model &#8212; that is, it doesn&#8217;t own any vehicles. But Gul said there is benefit in replicating something from Rivigo, which owns its fleets. By having some trucks of its own, BridgeLinx will be able to ensure that vehicles on its platform are operating round the clock by having multiple drivers working in shifts.</p>
<p>“We will eventually have a hybrid of what BlackBuck and Rivigo offer,” he said.</p>
<p>The startup will deploy the fresh capital to expand to more verticals and broaden its tech offerings. It is also working on hiring more talent, he said.</p>
<p>“BridgeLinx has cracked the code for making end-to-end freight work in a hassle free manner and therefore signed up some of the top businesses in Pakistan,&#8221; said Aatif Awan, Managing Partner at Indus Valley Capital, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe this team is well on its way to bring unprecedented efficiencies to the country’s economy and are really excited to partner with them.”</p>
<hr />
<p>On a side note, it&#8217;s fascinating to see Stebbings and Buckley emerge as the earliest investors to back startups in Pakistan at a time when several high-profile venture funds in Asia &#8212; including Sequoia Capital India, Accel, and Lightspeed &#8212; are yet to make any move in the country. Arguably, it&#8217;s the best time to back startups in Pakistan. The internet penetration has grown considerably in the country in the past decade and scores of startups are beginning to build the railroads for commerce, logistics, and payments.</p>
<p>Prosus has backed one startup in Pakistan &#8212; ride-hailing firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/prosus-ventures-leads-13-million-investment-in-pakistan-ride-hailing-giant-bykea/">Bykea</a> &#8212; and it recently made its first investment Bangladesh &#8212; commerce startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/shopup-raises-22-5-million-to-digitize-millions-of-mom-and-pop-shops-in-bangladesh/">ShopUp</a>, which counts Sequoia as one of its earliest backers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/digital-freight-marketplace-bridgelinx-raises-10-million-in-pakistans-largest-seed-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201992</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese tech giant Baidu begins publicly testing Apollo Go robotaxis in Shanghai</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/chinese-tech-giant-baidu-begins-publicly-testing-apollo-go-robotaxis-in-shanghai/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/chinese-tech-giant-baidu-begins-publicly-testing-apollo-go-robotaxis-in-shanghai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 05:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autonomous driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baidu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotaxi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese search engine giant Baidu has begun publicly testing its Apollo Go robotaxi mobile platform in Shanghai, marking the company&#8217;s continued expansion of its footprint in China.  While Baidu says its robotaxis have achieved Level 4 capabilities, a human safety operator will be present during all rides, which are open to the public as of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chinese search engine giant Baidu has begun publicly testing its Apollo Go robotaxi mobile platform in Shanghai, marking the company&#8217;s continued expansion of its footprint in China. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Baidu says its robotaxis have achieved Level 4 capabilities, a human safety operator will be present during all rides, which are open to the public as of Sunday, in order to comply with local regulations. The</span><a href="https://www.sae.org/news/press-room/2018/12/sae-international-releases-updated-visual-chart-for-its-%E2%80%9Clevels-of-driving-automation%E2%80%9D-standard-for-self-driving-vehicles"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Society of Automotive Engineers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> defines an L4 autonomous car as one that doesn’t require human interaction in most cases and can only operate in limited areas. Companies like Waymo, Cruise, Motional, Pony.AI and Yandex are all using a similar combination of lidar, radar, cameras and GPS to build a vehicle brain that&#8217;s capable of L4 autonomy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shanghai&#8217;s fleet will be made up of Baidu&#8217;s electric Hongqi EVs, its fourth generation autonomous vehicles produced with FAW. The company did not disclose how many vehicles it has initially launched, but a Baidu spokesperson told TechCrunch that the goal is to make it to around 200 vehicles in Shanghai. In total, Baidu says it is either testing or publicly deploying about 500 AVs across 30 cities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Baidu does have a permit to test its driverless tech in California, it hasn&#8217;t yet deployed any service and is instead putting most of its resources towards scaling up in China. There’s a huge increase in demand for robotaxi services at home, says a company spokesperson, so Baidu is focusing on improving its technology, building lots of vehicles and ensuring a good user experience. Shanghai marks the fifth city where the Apollo Go robotaxi service is open to the public, including Changsha, Cangzhou, Beijing and Guangzhou. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just a few weeks ago, Baidu expanded its Apollo Go services in Beijing into the Tongzhou District, which is considered to be the eastern gateway into the city, adding 22 new stations over 31 miles. In April, the company launched 10 fully driverless robotaxis in the capital city’s Shougang Park, a 1.2 square mile area that has become the testing ground for China’s first commercialized robotaxi operations. No human safety operator sits behind the wheel of these cars, only a safety member in the passenger seat to provide riders with reassurance. Each ride costs 30 yuan ($4.60) and is open to passengers aged 18 to 60. Everywhere else, including Shanghai, rides are free because the service is still in its trial phase.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Riders in Shanghai can use the Apollo Go app to call a robotaxi from 9:30am to 11pm and be picked up or dropped off at one of 150 stations across the Jianding District, which is home to Shanghai University, the Shanghai International Circuit and many tourist attractions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shanghai is also the location of Baidu’s Apollo Park, an autonomous vehicle facility for operation, testing and R&amp;D. The 10,000 square meter space will house the 200 AVs Baidu hopes to bring to the city, which would make it the site of the largest self-driving fleet in East China. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Baidu’s long game is to deploy 3,000 AVs in the next two to three years across 30 cities in China. Considering the company has been investing in R&amp;D for AV tech since 2013 and has been running the Apollo project since 2017, Baidu is poised to do just that. In June, </span><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/baidu-and-baic-groups-arcfox-brand-collaborate-to-launch-apollo-moon-robotaxis-plan-mass-production-at-affordable-costs-301314427.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Baidu and BAIC Group unveiled plans for the Apollo Moon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is set to be mass-produced with a per unit manufacturing price of 480,000 yuan, or about $75,000, which is actually pretty cheap, all things considered. Baidu says it will produce 1,000 of these vehicles over the next couple of years, as well as different models yet to be announced, in order to supply its growing fleet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Infrastructure is a big part of Baidu’s goals to expand Apollo Go. A spokesperson from Baidu said the company is also investing in building 5G-powered, V2X infrastructure in hundreds of intersections throughout major Chinese cities. Baidu is already installing sensors like cameras and lidar, coupled with edge compute systems that can transfer road information to autonomous systems, in order to reduce traffic congestion. In the long term, smart infrastructure will help AVs perform more robustly and serve to offset some of the huge costs associated with onboard sensors and computing power, according to the company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Baidu says its robotaxis currently still rely on onboard capabilities to achieve L4 autonomy, the company sees V2X as the future of large scale deployment. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/chinese-tech-giant-baidu-begins-publicly-testing-apollo-go-robotaxis-in-shanghai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201922</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Equity crew riffs on the Intuit-Mailchimp news</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/the-equity-crew-riffs-on-the-intuit-mailchimp-news/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/the-equity-crew-riffs-on-the-intuit-mailchimp-news/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 22:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. We are back! From this morning, I suppose. But the news cycle doesn&#8217;t wait for our publishing schedule, so the Equity crew got together to yammer all about the Intuit-Mailchimp acquisition. A $12 billion deal composed of stock and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/ed7be868-446d-42d3-a7b7-33f5a2642c7e?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture-capital-focused podcast where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>We are back! From this morning, I suppose. But the news cycle doesn&#8217;t wait for our publishing schedule, so the Equity crew got together to yammer all about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/">the Intuit-Mailchimp acquisition</a>.</p>
<p>A $12 billion deal composed of stock and cash, it&#8217;s a big one. And as Mailchimp has both a history of bootsrapping <em>and</em> a founding story in a non-Silicon Valley city we had lots to chat about.</p>
<p>As a general reminder, if you do listen to the show, <a href="https://twitter.com/equitypod">hit us up on Twitter</a> as we are doing more and more of these Spaces. They are good and relaxed fun, so don&#8217;t take them too seriously. We like to have fun.</p>
<p>Alright, Equity is back on Wednesday with our regularly scheduled programming. Chat then!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PDT, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PDT, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/the-equity-crew-riffs-on-the-intuit-mailchimp-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Apple urges users to update all devices after hacktivists reveal zero-day flaw</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/daily-crunch-61/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/daily-crunch-61/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 22:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Hello and welcome back to Daily Crunch for September 13, 2021. This is <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and I am back! A big thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/grg">Greg</a> for taking over last week while I was on staycation. It is lovely to be back with you all.</p>
<p>Before we dive into the news, a reminder <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">that Disrupt is <em>next week</em></a>. So, make sure you have a ticket and get hype. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/only-one-week-until-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-opens-a-world-of-opportunity/">More here</a>. It’s going to be a heck of a show.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OGkLQsA9Rj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TechCrunch Disrupt 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/embed/#?secret=OGkLQsA9Rj" data-secret="OGkLQsA9Rj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3+</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/epic-games-appeals-last-weeks-ruling-in-antitrust-battle-with-apple/">The Apple-Epic war far from over:</a> </strong>While the internet digests the recent, controversial ruling between Apple and gaming giant Epic, the latter party is not letting the decision sit. Epic is appealing. What’s at stake is the monetization of mobile applications for years to come. Given how much money is in the mix, it’s not a huge surprise that the legal wrangling is taking time.</li>
<li><strong>Welcome back to IPO season: </strong>Toast, a software-and-hardware startup that is the, well, toast of Boston, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/toast-looks-toward-18b-valuation-in-upcoming-ipo/">targeting a huge valuation gain</a> in its IPO. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/what-to-make-of-freshworks-first-ipo-price-range/">So is Freshworks</a>. We’re tracking both companies and will have more notes as they get closer to trading. Expect many, many more offerings in the coming weeks.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/chinese-crackdown-on-tech-giants-threatens-its-cloud-market-growth/"><strong>China’s regulatory crackdown could harm its cloud market:</strong></a> That’s the recent summary of a report that TechCrunch covered, discussing the larger Chinese software market. News also broke earlier today that the Chinese government may break up Ant, the Alibaba financial affiliate, and that the country wants to reduce the number of EV companies its market currently supports.</li>
<li><strong>BREAKING NEWS TODAY: Apple has released a patch to a zero-day flaw</strong> “that affects every iPhone, iPad, Mac and Apple Watch,” <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/">TechCrunch reports</a>. Update your devices, folks.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Dg3ovsXGMi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/">Apple patches a NSO zero-day flaw affecting all devices</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Apple patches a NSO zero-day flaw affecting all devices&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/embed/#?secret=Dg3ovsXGMi" data-secret="Dg3ovsXGMi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/grubmarket-gobbles-up-120m-at-a-1b-pre-money-valuation-to-take-on-the-grocery-supply-chain/"><strong>GrubMarket lands $120M to connect food growers, consumers:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Sure, you’ve ordered food delivery. That’s one plank of the food game. But for distributors, wholesalers and supermarkets, there are far greater needs to be served than just what you and I can consume for dinner. That’s the market that GrubMarket plays in, and it just raised a huge bloc of cash to keep its growth rates up.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/bitsight-raises-250m-from-moodys-and-acquires-cyber-risk-startup-visiblerisk/"><strong>BitSight raises from Moody’s, buys VisibleRisk:</strong></a> BitSight, a startup that “assesses the likelihood that an organization will be breached,” per TechCrunch, has purchased an Israeli cyber-risk-assessment startup VisibleRisk for an undisclosed price. The Moody’s round put $250 million into BitSight, funds that we presume it used to snag VisibleRisk. What’s the connection? Moody’s wants to use cyber risks in its credit ratings, we reckon.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/spoton-raises-300m-at-a-3-15b-valuation-acquires-appetize/"><strong>SpotOn also raises, buys smaller company:</strong></a> Unicorn SpotOn, which provides financial software and technology to small businesses, has raised a $300 million round that values the company at $3.15 billion. It’s also buying Appetize, “a digital and mobile commerce payments platform for enterprises such as sports and entertainment venues, theme parks and zoos.” The round is notable not only for its size, but also because SpotOn raised at a $1.875 billion valuation in May and a $625 million valuation last year.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/jumpcloud-raises-159m-on-2-56b-valuation-for-cloud-directory-tool/"><strong>JumpCloud raises $159M:</strong></a> JumpCloud sells cloud directory services and a host of other cloud-based identity services. It’s now worth $2.56 billion, a tidy sum. Sapphire Ventures’ Jai Das led the round. He’s a nice dude in my experience. The company grew its customer base by around 40% since last November. I asked the story’s author Ron Miller <em style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">why</em><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> JumpCloud was cool enough for him to cover. He said that the company’s effort to “provide a range of identity services, such as single sign-on and multifactor authentication&#8221; is important.</span></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/rezilion-raises-30m-help-security-operations-teams-with-tools-to-automate-some-of-their-work/"><strong>I suppose it’s time to learn what DevSevOps is:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Every technology wants its own neologism. DevOps. Adtech. Finservices. Hell, even Databricks’ Lakehouse. Add DevSecOps to your personal lexicon. Per our own Ingrid Lunden, DevSecOps is “the area of IT that addresses the needs of security teams and the technical work that they need to do in their jobs.” Startup Rezilion just raised $30 million for its efforts to serve that particular market.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/egyptian-startup-capiter-raises-33m-to-expand-b2b-e-commerce-platform-across-mena/"><strong>Everyone loves an e-commerce platform play:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Shopify is big. BigCommerce is growing nicely. And investors want to put capital into the next, similar effort. Enter Egyptian startup Capiter, which just snagged a $33 million round to “help manufacturers and sellers distribute products and [ … ] access them on a single platform” in Africa.</li>
<li>To close out our startup coverage, <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/gm-invests-in-radar-software-startup-oculii-as-demand-for-automated-driving-features-rise/">GM just invested into radar software startup Oculi.</a></strong> The move fits neatly into the trend of self-driving cars getting better and better over time, even if they are not yet <em>there</em>, if you will.</li>
</ul>
<h2>3 keys to pricing early-stage SaaS products</h2>
<p>Every founder who launches an enterprise software startup has to figure out the &#8220;right&#8221; pricing model for their products.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a consequential decision: Per-seat licenses are easy to manage, but what if customers prefer a concurrent licensing model?</p>
<p>&#8220;Early pricing discussions should center around the buyer’s perspective and the value the product creates for them,&#8221; says Ridge Ventures partner Yousuf Khan, who previously worked as a CIO.</p>
<p>&#8220;Of course,&#8221; he notes, &#8220;self-evaluation is hard, especially when you’re asking someone else to pay you for something you’ve created.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wZfLFEw0Y9"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/">3 keys to pricing early-stage SaaS products</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 keys to pricing early-stage SaaS products&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/embed/#?secret=wZfLFEw0Y9" data-secret="wZfLFEw0Y9" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Kicking off our short big technology section today, let’s pick back up with the automotive theme from GM’s news we discussed above. Ford also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/ford-hires-new-chief-digital-information-officer-as-it-seeks-to-expand-into-software-and-services/">made headlines today</a> by hiring Mike Amend to be its chief of digital and information. That it is not surprising that Ford would make such a hire is good indication of where the automotive market is heading.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/instagram-is-building-a-favorites-feature-so-you-dont-miss-important-posts/"><strong>Instagram thinks you follow too many people:</strong></a> That’s my read of the social service’s effort to build a product in its service that will allow users to favorite accounts and thus not miss their updates. Algorithmic timeline problems, I suppose.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/dutch-court-finds-uber-drivers-are-employees/"><strong>Dutch judge makes Uber sad:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Sure, that’s a slightly subjective summary, but news that a Dutch judge has ruled that Uber drivers are actually employees is antithetical to the ride-hailing company’s position. So it can’t be happy. And what’s the opposite of happy?</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="1024" height="643" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Are you all caught up on last week’s coverage of growth marketing? If not, read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/data-remains-a-vital-part-of-the-marketing-world/">here</a>.</p>
<p>TechCrunch wants you to recommend growth marketers who have expertise in SEO, social, content writing and more! If you’re a growth marketer, pass this <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a> along to your clients; we’d like to hear about why they loved working with you.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="AOa6dXFxki"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/data-remains-a-vital-part-of-the-marketing-world/">Data remains a vital part of the marketing world</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Data remains a vital part of the marketing world&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/10/data-remains-a-vital-part-of-the-marketing-world/embed/#?secret=AOa6dXFxki" data-secret="AOa6dXFxki" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2100312" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2100312" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2100312" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg" alt="A composite image of immigration law attorney Sophie Alcorn in front of a background with a TechCrunch logo." width="1024" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg 1800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=150,99 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=300,198 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=768,506 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=680,448 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=1536,1013 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sophie-Alcorn-TechCrunch1-3.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2100312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Joanna Buniak / <a href="https://www.alcorn.law/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sophie Alcorn <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a></p></div></p>
<p>Join Danny Crichton on <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1yoKMAoovojKQ?s=20">Twitter Spaces</a> tomorrow, Tuesday, September 14, at 2 p.m. PDT/5 p.m. EDT as he discusses whether remote work will make H-1B visas redundant with <a href="https://twitter.com/Sophie_Alcorn">Sophie Alcorn</a>, a lawyer at Alcorn Immigration Law and guest columnist for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/sophie-alcorn/">“Dear Sophie”</a> on Extra Crunch.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/daily-crunch-61/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201781</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon releases a Kindle software redesign to make navigation easier</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/kindle-releases-a-software-redesign-to-make-navigation-easier/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/kindle-releases-a-software-redesign-to-make-navigation-easier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 22:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-readers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yeah, yeah, you don&#8217;t need to charge a real book or update a book&#8217;s software. But now, our trusty Kindles remind us that they&#8217;re actually Wi-Fi connected, electronic devices capable of change as Amazon unveils a rare, significant design upgrade for the first time in years. To simplify navigation, the new look adds a two-tab bar to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Yeah, yeah, you don&#8217;t need to charge a <em>real </em>book or update a book&#8217;s software. But now, our trusty Kindles remind us that they&#8217;re actually Wi-Fi connected, electronic devices capable of change as Amazon unveils a rare, significant design upgrade for the first time in years.</p>
<p>To simplify navigation, the new look adds a two-tab bar to the bottom of the home screen, letting users easily toggle between the &#8220;home&#8221; and &#8220;library&#8221; screens. To access frequently used features, Kindle introduced an arrow on the top of the screen. When tapped, it reveals buttons to access airplane mode, Bluetooth, dark mode, sync or the rest of the settings menu. There&#8217;s also a brightness slider.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2201849" style="width: 2230px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2201849" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2201849 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png" alt="Amazon releases a Kindle software redesign to make navigation easier" width="2220" height="734" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png 2220w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png?resize=150,50 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png?resize=300,99 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png?resize=768,254 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png?resize=680,225 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png?resize=1536,508 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png?resize=2048,677 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-13-at-5.16.09-PM.png?resize=50,17 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2220px) 100vw, 2220px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2201849" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Amazon notified customers about the update on Friday and says it will roll out in the coming weeks, but many users with eligible devices &#8212; Kindle (8th Gen and above), Kindle Paperwhite (7th Gen and above) and Kindle Oasis &#8212; have already downloaded the upgrade. If you&#8217;re not sure what kind of Kindle you have, you can check <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=GK33S847NN4V6Y83">here</a>, but if your Kindle is from 2015 or later, you&#8217;re probably eligible. If your Kindle is connected to Wi-Fi, the update will install automatically, but you can manually download it <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=GKMQC26VQQMM8XSW">here</a>.</span></p>
<p>The company says it will continue to improve the home and library screens later this year &#8212; users will be able to swipe left on the home page to see recently read books from their library. Then, the library screen will introduce new filter and sort menus, a new collection view and an interactive scroll bar.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2201866 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Pack-2-UPDATED_Jaeger-Decanter-Group-1000x1000._CB642431930_-e1631585977996.jpg" alt="Amazon releases a Kindle software redesign to make navigation easier" width="1000" height="650" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Pack-2-UPDATED_Jaeger-Decanter-Group-1000x1000._CB642431930_-e1631585977996.jpg 1000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Pack-2-UPDATED_Jaeger-Decanter-Group-1000x1000._CB642431930_-e1631585977996.jpg?resize=150,98 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Pack-2-UPDATED_Jaeger-Decanter-Group-1000x1000._CB642431930_-e1631585977996.jpg?resize=300,195 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Pack-2-UPDATED_Jaeger-Decanter-Group-1000x1000._CB642431930_-e1631585977996.jpg?resize=768,499 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Pack-2-UPDATED_Jaeger-Decanter-Group-1000x1000._CB642431930_-e1631585977996.jpg?resize=680,442 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Pack-2-UPDATED_Jaeger-Decanter-Group-1000x1000._CB642431930_-e1631585977996.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></p>
<p>This is the biggest design update that Kindle has released since <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/09/a-quick-tour-of-amazons-new-ui-for-kindle-e-readers/">around 2016</a> &#8212; but if you noticed that the user interface felt outdated while you wrapped up your <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/28/climate-change-summer-2021-book-reviews/">summer reading</a>, now you know that Amazon noticed too.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/kindle-releases-a-software-redesign-to-make-navigation-easier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201780</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Use creative automation software to amp up your brand&#8217;s lower-funnel assets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/use-creative-automation-software-to-amp-up-your-brands-lower-funnel-assets/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/use-creative-automation-software-to-amp-up-your-brands-lower-funnel-assets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Saunders]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 21:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Ecommerce and D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2200484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In addition to driving a clear lift in revenue, automating digital marketing assets means cost and time savings, too. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Miha Mikek</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/mihamikek1">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<p>
Miha Mikek is the CEO and co-founder of creative automation company <a href="https://celtra.com/">Celtra</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">With the holiday season around the corner, growth marketers are gearing up for their busiest time of the year. E-commerce brands are now leaning heavily on social sales and digital advertising, but should also expect an omnichannel shopper &#8212; <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/celtras-2021-holiday-marketing-survey-reveals-shopper-desire-for-omnichannel-ad-personalization-301365523.html">62% of shoppers</a> plan to purchase both online and in-store this holiday season, according to Celtra.</p>
<p>The marketplace is crowded. Digital marketing requires high volumes of on-brand creative assets, and it is tough to produce them fast enough without compromising on brand equity or storytelling. While marketing channels have exploded in volume, most creative production workflows are the same as they were 50 years ago.</p>
<p>But marketing is a monster that feeds on creative assets, requiring more and more each quarter.</p>
<p>The reality is, any paid impression is also a brand impression and a chance to differentiate in the market. In fact, paid impressions are often the only chance you get to influence some shoppers. That&#8217;s why creative &#8212; your brand, your design and your message &#8212; matters. In growth marketing, traffic, subscriptions, direct-to-consumer channels, testing and, ultimately, revenue all rely on creative to succeed.</p>
<p>Yet, lower-funnel assets are rarely brilliant in branding or even remotely interesting. Teams are limited in meeting global demands across more channels than ever, and the creative they produce is suffering. Brands don’t have the luxury of spending time on design craft and storytelling at scale. Conversely, most creative automation solutions that can assist with efficiency aren’t currently equipped to scale high-quality creative that prioritizes branding and design excellence.</p>
<p>Enterprises are suffering from a creative gap where their content and asset needs are growing fast while team resources and budgets are stagnant or even declining.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there isn’t a magic AI bullet to solve the challenge. You can’t just buy creative technology in the hopes that it alone will bridge the gap. You need to rethink workflows and team collaboration. If you’re serious about elevating your growth marketing creative, you need to invest in tools that are built for scale and brand governance at once.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/use-creative-automation-software-to-amp-up-your-brands-lower-funnel-assets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2200484</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intuit confirms $12B deal to buy Mailchimp</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 20:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon Intuit confirmed persistent rumors that it was in the process of buying Mailchimp, detailing a $12 billion transaction that will bring the well-known email infra company to its corporate remit. Intuit is not a well-known player in the email marketing space. The company is instead best known for its TurboTax software (and associated [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">This afternoon Intuit <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210913005806/en/Intuit-to-Acquire-Mailchimp">confirmed</a> persistent rumors that it was in the process of buying Mailchimp, detailing a $12 billion transaction that will bring the well-known email infra company to its corporate remit.</p>
<p>Intuit is not a well-known player in the email marketing space. The company is instead best known for its TurboTax software (and associated lobbying of the U.S. government to ensure its rent-seeking can continue), its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/24/intuit-credit-karma/">recent purchase of Credit Karma</a> and its more <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2009/09/14/the-value-of-techcrunch50-mint-acquired-by-intuit-for-170m-two-years-after-winning-tc40/#:~:text=Today%2C%20exactly%20two%20years%20after%20launching%20at%20TechCrunch40%2C,as%20the%20maker%20of%20Quicken%2C%20QuickBooks%2C%20and%20TurboTax.">dated acquisition of Mint</a>.</p>
<p>The Mailchimp transaction will comprised both cash and stock.</p>
<p>The question rattling around your brain at the moment is the correct thing to ask: <em>Why is Intuit spending 10% of its market capitalization to buy an email marketing company?<strong> </strong></em></p>
<p>Per a release, Intuit thinks that the deal &#8220;advances&#8221; its &#8220;powering prosperity around the world, and its strategy to become an AI-driven expert platform.&#8221; Normally at this juncture I&#8217;d convert the company&#8217;s corporate-speak to something in English, but I&#8217;m struggling.</p>
<p>The company had more to say in that its Mailchimp buy would allow it to &#8220;accelerate two of [Intuit&#8217;s] previously shared strategic Big Bets: to become the center of small business growth; and to disrupt the small business midmarket.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is a bit more grokkable. Intuit&#8217;s QuickBooks service is a well-known product in the SMB space. Presumably Intuit reckons that it can sell more services to its existing small business customers. It still feels like a bit of a stretch, but we presume that the eggheads have come to the conclusion that ensuing corporate synergies will more than compensate for the sticker shock that the deal includes.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Shares of Intuit are up a slim 0.15% in after-hours trading, implying something of a shrug from Wall Street concerning the transaction; given how well leaked the deal was on its way to consummation, the combination may have already been priced into Intuit&#8217;s share price.</p>
<p>For Atlanta, where Mailchimp is headquartered, the deal is a win. Mailchimp is a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/13/mailchimps-ben-chestnut-on-bootstrapping-a-startup-to-700m-in-revenue/">famously bootstrapped company</a>, so if you were looking for confirmation that you can build decacorns outside of Silicon Valley and without venture capital help, here&#8217;s evidence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/intuit-confirms-12b-deal-to-buy-mailchimp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201803</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitch sues two users for harassing streamers with hate raids</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/twitch-hate-raids-lawsuits/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/twitch-hate-raids-lawsuits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online harassment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitch filed a lawsuit late last week against two people on its own platform for running automated hate and harassment campaigns. The harassment, often targeted at Black and LGBTQ streamers, manifests in a unique Twitch phenomenon as a &#8220;hate raid.&#8221; On Twitch, creators regularly point viewers toward another friendly account after their stream concludes to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitch filed a lawsuit late last week against two people on its own platform for running automated hate and harassment campaigns.</p>
<p>The harassment, often targeted at Black and LGBTQ streamers, manifests in a unique Twitch phenomenon as a &#8220;hate raid.&#8221; On Twitch, creators regularly point viewers toward another friendly account after their stream concludes to boost their audiences, a practice known as a &#8220;raid.&#8221; Hate raids invert that formula, sending swarms of bots to harass streamers who have inadequate tools at their disposal to block the influx of abuse.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pbSHQiakmM"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/">Streamers are boycotting Twitch today to protest the platform&#8217;s lack of action on &#8216;hate raids&#8217;</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Streamers are boycotting Twitch today to protest the platform&#8217;s lack of action on &#8216;hate raids&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/embed/#?secret=pbSHQiakmM" data-secret="pbSHQiakmM" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The hate raids leverage Twitch&#8217;s new tagging system, which many transgender users had requested to make it easier to build community and to discover content that resonates. In May, Twitch added more than 350 new tags to help viewers sort streams by &#8220;gender, sexual orientation, race, nationality, ability, mental health, and more.&#8221; Accounts spreading abuse now use those tags to target racist, sexist, transphobic and homophobic harassment toward streamers, another unfortunate misuse of a tool explicitly designed to give creators a boost.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We’ve seen a lot of conversation about botting, hate raids, and other forms of harassment targeting marginalized creators. You’re asking us to do better, and we know we need to do more to address these issues. That includes an open and ongoing dialogue about creator safety.</p>
<p>&mdash; Twitch (@Twitch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1425550620887375876?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>In the suit, Twitch described hate raiders as &#8220;highly motivated&#8221; malicious individuals who improvise new ways to circumvent the platform&#8217;s terms of service. Twitch named two users, &#8220;CruzzControl&#8221; and &#8220;CreatineOverdose,&#8221; in the suit but the company was unable to obtain their legal names. The users are based in the Netherlands and Austria, respectively, and their activity began in August of this year. Twitch alleges that CruzzControl alone has been linked to 3,000 bot accounts involved in hate raids.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>While it&#8217;s possible that Twitch won&#8217;t be able to identify the real identities of individuals behind the recent harassment campaigns, the lawsuit could act as a deterrent for other accounts directing waves of abuse on the streaming platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;While we have identified and banned thousands of accounts over the past weeks, these actors continue to work hard on creative ways to circumvent our improvements, and show no intention of stopping,&#8221; the lawsuit reads. &#8220;We hope this Complaint will shed light on the identity of the individuals behind these attacks and the tools that they exploit, dissuade them from taking similar behaviors to other services, and help put an end to these vile attacks against members of our community.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This Complaint is by no means the only action we’ve taken to address targeted attacks, nor will it be the last,&#8221; a Twitch spokesperson told TechCrunch. &#8220;Our teams have been working around the clock to update our proactive detection systems, address new behaviors as they emerge, and finalize new proactive, channel-level safety tools that we’ve been developing for months.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prior to Twitch&#8217;s legal action, some Twitch creators <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/">organized #ADayOffTwitch</a> to protest the company&#8217;s failure to offer solutions for users targeted by hate raids. People participating in the protest demanded that Twitch take decisive actions toward protecting streamers from hate raids, including letting creators deny incoming raids and screen out chat participants with newly made accounts. They also drew attention to Twitch policies that allow unlimited accounts to be linked to a single email address, a loophole that makes it easy to create and deploy armies of bot accounts.</p>
<p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/525072029/content?start_page=1&view_mode&access_key=key-xpRLiCP4IDAiS4C4TwrW"  data-auto-height="true" scrolling="no" id="scribd_525072029" width="100%" height="500" frameborder="0"></iframe>
		<div style="font-size:10px;text-align:center;width:100%"><a href="https://www.scribd.com/doc/525072029" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">View this document on Scribd</a></div></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tBXfrJVyRm"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/twitch-off-platform-harassment-policy/">Twitch expands its rules against hate and abuse to include behavior off the platform</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitch expands its rules against hate and abuse to include behavior off the platform&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/twitch-off-platform-harassment-policy/embed/#?secret=tBXfrJVyRm" data-secret="tBXfrJVyRm" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="72YfJNW2DX"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/twitch-updates-its-hateful-content-and-harassment-policy-after-company-called-out-for-its-ownabuses/">Twitch updates its hateful content and harassment policy after company called out for its own abuses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitch updates its hateful content and harassment policy after company called out for its own abuses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/twitch-updates-its-hateful-content-and-harassment-policy-after-company-called-out-for-its-ownabuses/embed/#?secret=72YfJNW2DX" data-secret="72YfJNW2DX" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/twitch-hate-raids-lawsuits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201731</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple patches an NSO zero-day flaw affecting all devices</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 19:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citizen Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSO Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pegasus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spyware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple has released security updates for a zero-day vulnerability that affects every iPhone, iPad, Mac and Apple Watch. Citizen Lab, which discovered the vulnerability and was credited with the find, urges users to immediately update their devices. The technology giant said iOS 14.8 for iPhones and iPads, as well as new updates for Apple Watch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Apple has released security updates for a zero-day vulnerability that affects every iPhone, iPad, Mac and Apple Watch. Citizen Lab, which discovered the vulnerability and was credited with the find, urges users to immediately update their devices.</p>
<p>The technology giant said iOS 14.8 for iPhones and iPads, as well as new updates for Apple Watch and macOS, will fix at least one vulnerability that it said &#8220;may have been actively exploited.&#8221;</p>
<p>Citizen Lab said it has now discovered new artifacts of the ForcedEntry vulnerability, details it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/">first revealed</a> in August as part of an investigation into the use of a zero-day vulnerability that was used to silently hack into iPhones belonging to at least one Bahraini activist.</p>
<p>Last month, Citizen Lab said the zero-day flaw — named as such since it gives companies zero days to roll out a fix — took advantage of a flaw in Apple’s iMessage, which was exploited to push the Pegasus spyware, developed by Israeli firm NSO Group, to the activist’s phone.</p>
<p>Pegasus gives its government customers near-complete access to a target’s device, including their personal data, photos, messages and location.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--callout block--right" >
		<h4 class="block--callout__title">Read more on TechCrunch</h4>
		
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/">A new NSO zero-click attack evades Apple’s iPhone security protections</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/20/citizen-lab-iphone-nso-group/">Dozens of journalists’ iPhones hacked with NSO ‘zero-click’ spyware</a></li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/nso-fleming-data-location/">NSO used real people’s location data to pitch its contact-tracing tech</a></li>
</ul>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The breach was significant because the flaws exploited the latest iPhone software at the time, both iOS 14.4 and later iOS 14.6, which Apple released in May. But also the exploit broke through new iPhone defenses that Apple had baked into iOS 14, dubbed BlastDoor, which were supposed to prevent silent attacks by filtering potentially malicious code. Citizen Lab calls this particular exploit ForcedEntry for its ability to skirt Apple&#8217;s BlastDoor protections.</p>
<p>In its <a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/09/forcedentry-nso-group-imessage-zero-click-exploit-captured-in-the-wild/">latest findings</a>, Citizen Lab said it found evidence of the ForcedEntry exploit on the iPhone of a Saudi activist, running at the time the latest version of iOS. The researchers said the exploit takes advantage of a weakness in how Apple devices render images on the display.</p>
<p>Citizen Lab now says that the same ForcedEntry exploit works on all Apple devices running, until today, the latest software.</p>
<p>Citizen Lab said it reported its findings to Apple on September 7. Apple pushed out the updates for the vulnerability, known officially as <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201222">CVE-2021-30860</a>. Citizen Lab said it attributes the ForcedEntry exploit to NSO Group with high confidence, citing evidence it has seen that it has not previously published.</p>
<p>John Scott-Railton, a researcher at Citizen Lab, told TechCrunch that messaging apps, like iMessage, are increasingly a target of nation states hacking operations and this latest find underlines the challenges in securing them.</p>
<p>In a brief statement, Apple&#8217;s head of security engineering and architecture Ivan Krstić confirmed the fix.</p>
<p>&#8220;After identifying the vulnerability used by this exploit for iMessage, Apple rapidly developed and deployed a fix in iOS 14.8 to protect our users. We’d like to commend Citizen Lab for successfully completing the very difficult work of obtaining a sample of this exploit so we could develop this fix quickly. Attacks like the ones described are highly sophisticated, cost millions of dollars to develop, often have a short shelf life, and are used to target specific individuals. While that means they are not a threat to the overwhelming majority of our users, we continue to work tirelessly to defend all our customers, and we are constantly adding new protections for their devices and data,&#8221; said Krstić.</p>
<p>NSO Group declined to answer our specific questions.</p>
<p><em>Updated with comment from Apple.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NO6ayjQwng"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/toolkit-nso-pegasus-iphone-android/">This tool tells you if NSO&#8217;s Pegasus spyware targeted your phone</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;This tool tells you if NSO&#8217;s Pegasus spyware targeted your phone&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/19/toolkit-nso-pegasus-iphone-android/embed/#?secret=NO6ayjQwng" data-secret="NO6ayjQwng" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/apple-zero-day-nso-pegasus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201737</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram is building a &#8216;Favorites&#8217; feature so you don&#8217;t miss important posts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/instagram-is-building-a-favorites-feature-so-you-dont-miss-important-posts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/instagram-is-building-a-favorites-feature-so-you-dont-miss-important-posts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[like button]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news feed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Instagram confirmed it&#8217;s developing a new feature called &#8220;Favorites,&#8221; which would allow users to select certain accounts whose posts they would like to see higher in their feed. A similar feature already exists on Facebook where it gives users a bit more control over the News Feed algorithm. On Facebook, users can select up to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Instagram confirmed it&#8217;s developing a new feature called &#8220;Favorites,&#8221; which would allow users to select certain accounts whose posts they would like to see higher in their feed. A similar feature already exists on Facebook where it gives users a bit more control over the News Feed algorithm. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/1634545223376778">On Facebook</a>, users can select up to 30 friends or Facebook Pages whose posts get shown higher in the News Feed. It&#8217;s unclear what limit an Instagram Favorites feature would have, however.</p>
<p>The Instagram Favorites feature was recently spotted in development by reverse engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/">Alessandro Paluzzi</a>, who found a new pushpin icon for Favorites in the Instagram Settings menu, and other details about how the feature may work.</p>
<p>According to screenshots Paluzzi <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1435919581277609989">posted</a> on Twitter, users will be able to search across the Instagram accounts they are currently following to create a list of Favorites. This list can be edited at any time, and Instagram notes that users would not be notified when they&#8217;re added to someone&#8217;s Favorites.</p>
<p>This is a similar level of privacy as offered by Instagram&#8217;s several-years-old &#8220;Close Friends&#8221; feature, which instead focuses on allowing users to create a separate list of followers so they can share their more private and personal Instagram Stories with a select group of their own choosing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Instagram?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Instagram</a> is working on &quot;Favorites&quot; <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2139.png" alt="ℹ" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Posts from your favorites are shown higher in feed. <a href="https://t.co/NfBd8v4IHR">pic.twitter.com/NfBd8v4IHR</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alessandro Paluzzi (@alex193a) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1435919581277609989?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2021</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Paluzzi tells us he was able to add contacts to the Favorites list, but didn&#8217;t yet notice any changes to the Instagram feed after doing so. That implies the feature is still being built and a launch is not imminent.</p>
<p>&#8220;This feature is an internal prototype that’s still in development, and not testing externally,&#8221; an Instagram spokesperson told TechCrunch. They declined to share any other specifics about the feature.</p>
<p>A Favorites feature could play into Instagram&#8217;s larger plans to better establish itself as a home for creator content. In other leaks, Paluzzi had also found the company was building out &#8220;Fan Subscriptions,&#8221; which would allow users to pay for elevated access to creator content &#8212; like exclusive live videos or Stories, for example. Paid subscribers may also be given a special badge that would highlight their name when they commented, DM&#8217;ed or viewed the creator&#8217;s Stories.</p>
<p>Given that users who were paying for content would not want to miss a moment, it would make sense to give them tools to designate those creators as &#8220;Favorites&#8221; whose posts were also more highly ranked in their Feed.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Let&#39;s see another step of the Creators&#39; onboarding screen of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Instagram?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Instagram</a>&#39;s Fan Subscriptions feature <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/eBxIp6BtXw">pic.twitter.com/eBxIp6BtXw</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Alessandro Paluzzi (@alex193a) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1437372672791531528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>A Favorites feature could also be useful to those who had taken a break from Instagram and would rather see the important photos and videos they missed from favorite accounts upon their return, rather than just the most recent or interesting updates from across all of the accounts they follow.</p>
<p>And while not likely the main goal, the new feature could help to address users&#8217; complaints about the algorithmic feed in general.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ru1ft3h7uo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/15/understanding-instagrams-founding-story-and-more-from-sxsw/">Understanding Instagram&#8217;s founding story and more from SXSW</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Instagram&#8217;s founding story and more from SXSW&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/15/understanding-instagrams-founding-story-and-more-from-sxsw/embed/#?secret=ru1ft3h7uo" data-secret="ru1ft3h7uo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Today, there are still a number of people who want to be able to see Instagram posts in chronological order, preferring to not have posts re-ordered by an algorithm they can&#8217;t control. Favorites wouldn&#8217;t give in to this demand (though Instagram has <a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/instagram-is-testing-a-way-to-display-posts-in-chronological-order">tested</a> a chronological feed in the past). But it would at least give users the ability to ensure they weren&#8217;t missing the posts from those whose updates they wanted to see the most.</p>
<p>Though Instagram did say it&#8217;s working on the development of Favorites, it doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean such a feature will launch to the public. Companies of Instagram&#8217;s size often prototype new ideas, but only some of those tests make it to a general release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/instagram-is-building-a-favorites-feature-so-you-dont-miss-important-posts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201703</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford hires new chief digital information officer as it seeks to expand into software and services</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/ford-hires-new-chief-digital-information-officer-as-it-seeks-to-expand-into-software-and-services/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/ford-hires-new-chief-digital-information-officer-as-it-seeks-to-expand-into-software-and-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 18:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Motor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ford Motor has hired Mike Amend as its chief digital and information officer as the automaker seeks to expand into software, subscriptions and in-vehicle connectivity. Amend, who was president of Lowe’s Online for three years, will focus on Ford’s “use of data, software and technology” — all areas central to Ford’s new Ford+ strategy, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Ford Motor has hired Mike Amend as its chief digital and information officer as the automaker seeks to expand into software, subscriptions and in-vehicle connectivity. Amend, who was president of Lowe’s Online for three years, will focus on Ford’s “use of data, software and technology” — all areas central to Ford’s new Ford+ strategy, the OEM said.</p>
<p>The hire is just the latest sign that Ford is serious about beefing up its digital offerings for customers, as the company seeks to pivot toward high-tech segments. The company calls this plan “Ford+,” which it unveiled earlier this year. Central to this plan is electric vehicles, which Ford wants to comprise around half of its global sales by 2030, as well as expanding into new sources of revenue via subscriptions and digital services.</p>
<p>To that end, Amend will oversee a number of teams, including Ford’s technology and software platform function and its global data insight and analytics section.</p>
<p>Amend isn’t Ford’s only recent hire of note. The automaker also recently poached Doug Field — the tech executive who was leading Apple’s special projects team, and who also led the development of the Model 3 at Tesla — as chief advanced technology and embedded systems officer. The two will work closely, along with chief of product Hau Thai-Tang, Ford said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yf2tdk3x5e"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/ford-hires-apple-executive-who-led-its-secret-car-project/">Ford hires Apple executive who led its secret car project</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ford hires Apple executive who led its secret car project&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/07/ford-hires-apple-executive-who-led-its-secret-car-project/embed/#?secret=yf2tdk3x5e" data-secret="yf2tdk3x5e" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Amend’s career includes growing the online businesses of major retailers, including Lowe’s, The Home Depot and JCPenney. Ford’s interim chief information officer, Sakis Kitsopanidis, will continue to serve as director of integrated enterprise resource planning.</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/ford-hires-new-chief-digital-information-officer-as-it-seeks-to-expand-into-software-and-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201686</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 keys to pricing early-stage SaaS products</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 18:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SaaS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pricing journey is long and, despite what some founders might think, jumping headfirst into customer acquisition isn’t the first stop. Step one is making sure you have a fully fledged product.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Yousuf Khan</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/yakhan">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yousufakhan">Yousuf Khan</a> is a partner at <a href="https://ridge.vc/">Ridge Ventures</a>. Prior to joining Ridge, he was the first CIO of Automation Anywhere, CIO and vice president of Customer Success at cloud-based AI platform Moveworks, as well as CIO of Pure Storage, Qualys and Hult International Business School. 	</div>
	
		<div class="contributor-byline__more-articles">
		<span class="more-articles-title">More posts by this contributor</span>
		<ul class="more-articles-list">
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/develop-a-buyers-guide-to-educate-your-startups-sales-team-and-customers/">Develop a buyer’s guide to educate your startup&#8217;s sales team and customers</a></li>
						<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/customer-advisory-boards-are-a-gold-mine-for-startup-brand-champions/">Customer advisory boards are a gold mine for startup brand champions</a></li>
					</ul>
	</div>
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">I’ve met hundreds of founders over the years, and most, particularly early-stage founders, share one common go-to-market gripe: Pricing.</p>
<p>For enterprise software, traditional pricing methods like per-seat models are often easier to figure out for products that are hyperspecific, especially those used by people in essentially the same way, such as Zoom or Slack. However, it&#8217;s a different ballgame for startups that offer services or products that are more complex.</p>
<p>Most startups struggle with a per-seat model because their products, unlike Zoom and Slack, are used in a litany of ways. Salesforce, for example, employs regular seat licenses and admin licenses — customers can opt for lower pricing for solutions that have low-usage parts — while other products are priced based on negotiation as part of annual renewals.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			You may have a strong champion in a CIO you’re selling to or a very friendly person handling procurement, but it won’t matter if the pricing can’t be easily explained and understood. Complicated or unclear pricing adds more friction.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Early pricing discussions should center around the buyer’s perspective and the value the product creates for them. It&#8217;s important for founders to think about the output and the outcome, and a number they can reasonably defend to customers moving forward. Of course, self-evaluation is hard, especially when you’re asking someone else to pay you for something you’ve created.</p>
<p>This process will take time, so here are three tips to smoothen the ride.</p>
<h2>Pricing is a journey</h2>
<p>Pricing is not a fixed exercise. The enterprise software business involves a lot of intangible aspects, and a software product’s perceived value, quality, and user experience can be highly variable.</p>
<p>The pricing journey is long and, despite what some founders might think, jumping headfirst into customer acquisition isn’t the first stop. Instead, step one is making sure you have a fully fledged product.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a late-seed or Series A company, you’re focused on landing those first 10-20 customers and racking up some wins to showcase in your investor and board deck. But when you grow your organization to the point where the CEO isn’t the only person selling, you’ll want to have your go-to-market position figured out.</p>
<p>Many startups fall into the trap of thinking: &#8220;We need to figure out what pricing looks like, so let&#8217;s ask 50 hypothetical customers how much they would pay for a solution like ours.&#8221; I don&#8217;t agree with this approach, because the product hasn&#8217;t been finalized yet. You haven&#8217;t figured out product-market fit or product messaging and you want to spend a lot of time and energy on pricing? Sure, revenue is important, but you should focus on finding the path to accruing revenue versus finding a strict pricing model.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/3-keys-to-pricing-early-stage-saas-products/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201429</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join Team TechCrunch at these speed networking sessions at Disrupt</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/join-team-techcrunch-for-a-series-of-speed-networking-meet-greets-the-day-before-tc-disrupt-2021-begins/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/join-team-techcrunch-for-a-series-of-speed-networking-meet-greets-the-day-before-tc-disrupt-2021-begins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexandra Ames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 17:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2021]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2198670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grab a red Sharpie, circle September 20 on your calendar (ooh, how old-school) and get ready to jumpstart your TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 networking experience. Sure, Disrupt’s “official” run is September 21-23, but why wait to meet other movers and shakers in your specific tech category? We’re hosting a series of speed networking sessions to get [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Grab a red Sharpie, circle September 20 on your calendar (ooh, how old-school) and get ready to jumpstart your <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> networking experience. Sure, Disrupt’s “official” run is September 21-23, but why wait to meet other movers and shakers in your specific tech category?</p>
<p>We’re hosting a series of speed networking sessions to get your Disrupt kicked off on Monday, September 20. These events will take place in CrunchMatch, our AI-powered platform that helps you find and connect with attendees on your must-meet list.</p>
<p><strong>Pro Tip 1:</strong> If you purchased a pass, you received an email with instructions on how to access CrunchMatch. Yeah, you did.</p>
<p><strong>Pro Tip 2:</strong> You still have time to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/tickets/">buy your Disrupt 2021 pass</a> for less than $100. Look through <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/#0affacde-e0ed-4a3c-abc4-988cb1c0eb3e">the Disrupt agenda</a> and see all the programming, events and opportunity waiting for you.</p>
<p>We love free swag, and we’re pretty sure you do, too. So, we’ll randomly select<strong> one participant from each networking session to receive a TC swag bag</strong>. W00t!</p>
<p>Here are the meet and greets happening at Disrupt &#8212; choose your category and kickstart your connections.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Peer-to-Peer: Investors</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Connect with your community of startup investors to share connections, insights and expertise.</span></li>
<li><strong>Peer-to-Peer: Early-Stage Founders</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Meet the founders also launching at Disrupt to share insights and grow your support network.</span></li>
<li><strong>The Full Stack:</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Meet the data analysts, engineers, hackers, data scientists and software developers that power your tech.</span></li>
<li><strong>BIPOC &amp; Women of Disrupt</strong> <strong>(and their allies): <span style="font-weight: 400;">We invite all women and BIPOC (and all allies) attending Disrupt to join us for this roundup to inspire one another and grow your network.</span></strong></li>
<li><strong>B2B 2 Connect: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Are you working on products that make it easier for businesses to thrive? Meet and share ideas and others with the SaaS and Enterprise community.</span></strong></li>
<li><strong>DNA/Tech: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Meet the scientists who are using technology and engineering to produce advancements in health and biology. </span></strong></li>
<li><strong>Planet/Impact: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passionate about making an impact on our planet? Join this networking session focused on sustainability, green tech and clean tech projects.   </span></li>
<li><strong>Money Matters:</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Network with the power brokers changing the face of financial services, banking and crypto.</span></li>
<li><strong>Autonobot: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Discover the builders automating our lives with robotics and hardware alongside the scientists creating the artificial intelligence that powers it all.</span></strong></li>
<li><strong>The Station: <span style="font-weight: 400;">Share insights with people pushing the boundaries of mobility including drone technology, autonomous vehicles and transportation.</span></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021">TechCrunch Disrupt 2021</a> takes place on September 21-23, and these meet-and-greet sessions can help you hit the networking ground running. Make the most out of your TC Disrupt experience!</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><em>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at Disrupt 2021? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </em><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html"><em>filling out this form</em></a>.</p>
<p>	<iframe
			id="wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			width="99%"
			height="1300"
			src="https://tcprotectedembed.com/protected-iframe/82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47"
			scrolling="true"
			frameborder="0"
			class="wpcom-protected-iframe"
	>
	</iframe>
	<script type="text/javascript">
		( function() {
			var func = function() {
				var iframe = document.getElementById('wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47')
				if ( iframe ) {
					iframe.onload = function() {
						iframe.contentWindow.postMessage( {
							'msg_type': 'poll_size',
							'frame_id': 'wpcom-iframe-82e7089bb76c80e1d7d73433ec8b0f47'
						}, "https:\/\/tcprotectedembed.com" );
					}
				}

				// Autosize iframe
				var funcSizeResponse = function( e ) {

					var origin = document.createElement( 'a' );
					origin.href = e.origin;

					// Verify message origin
					if ( 'tcprotectedembed.com' !== origin.host )
						return;

					// Verify message is in a format we expect
					if ( 'object' !== typeof e.data || undefined === e.data.msg_type )
						return;

					switch ( e.data.msg_type ) {
						case 'poll_size:response':
							var iframe = document.getElementById( e.data._request.frame_id );

							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.width )
								iframe.width = '100%';
							if ( iframe && '' === iframe.height )
								iframe.height = parseInt( e.data.height );

							return;
						default:
							return;
					}
				}

				if ( 'function' === typeof window.addEventListener ) {
					window.addEventListener( 'message', funcSizeResponse, false );
				} else if ( 'function' === typeof window.attachEvent ) {
					window.attachEvent( 'onmessage', funcSizeResponse );
				}
			}
			if (document.readyState === 'complete') { func.apply(); /* compat for infinite scroll */ }
			else if ( document.addEventListener ) { document.addEventListener( 'DOMContentLoaded', func, false ); }
			else if ( document.attachEvent ) { document.attachEvent( 'onreadystatechange', func ); }
		} )();
	</script>
	</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/join-team-techcrunch-for-a-series-of-speed-networking-meet-greets-the-day-before-tc-disrupt-2021-begins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2198670</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Colossal sold investors on a quest to resurrect a woolly mammoth</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/how-colossal-sold-investors-on-a-quest-to-resurrect-a-woolly-mammoth/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/how-colossal-sold-investors-on-a-quest-to-resurrect-a-woolly-mammoth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Betuel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 17:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colossal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRISPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gene editing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mammoth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2201508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are a growing number of companies interested in CRISPR&#8217;s potential to upend medicine. It’s probably safe to say there’s only one company interested in using the gene-editing system to create a living, breathing woolly mammoth. Or, at least, something pretty close to it.  That’s the primary mission of a new company called Colossal. Co-founded [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a growing number of companies interested in CRISPR&#8217;s potential to upend medicine. It’s probably safe to say there’s only one company interested in using the gene-editing system to create a living, breathing woolly mammoth. Or, at least, something pretty close to it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s the primary mission of a new company called Colossal. Co-founded by maverick geneticist </span><a href="https://wyss.harvard.edu/team/core-faculty/george-church/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">George Church</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and entrepreneur Ben Lamm, the former CEO of Hypergiant, the company aims to bring one of those creatures back to life using CRISPR to edit the genomes of existing Asian elephants. In that sense the creature would be very similar to a woolly mammoth, but would be more like an elephant-mammoth hybrid. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a project that Church’s lab has been invested in for years. But now, Church and Lamm have managed to sell investors on the idea that bringing back a mammoth is more than a science-fiction project. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today Colossal announced its launch and a $15 million seed round led by </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/thomas-tull/?sh=69eeff657645"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thomas Tull</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, former CEO of Legendary Entertainment (the company responsible for the likes of Dune, Jurassic World and The Dark Knight). The round includes investments from Breyer Capital, Draper Associates, Animal Capital, At One Ventures, Jazz Ventures, Jeff Wilke, Bold Capital, Global Space Ventures, Climate Capital, Winklevoss Capital, Liquid2 Ventures, Capital Factory, Tony Robbins and First Light Capital.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;These two are a powerhouse team who have the ability to completely shift our understanding of modern genetics while developing innovative technologies that not only help bring back lost species, but advance the entire industry,” Robbins tells TechCrunch. “I am proud to be an investor in their journey.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lamm comes to Colossal as the founder of Hypergiant, a Texas-based AI company. He has also built and sold three other companies:</span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/07/conversable-chatbot-will-offer-allergy-info-along-with-a-side-of-wingstop-wings/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Conversable</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (acquired by LivePerson), </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2015/07/22/chaotic-moon-sells-to-accenture/?_ga=2.258284355.817522353.1631490695-1476558031.1622655185"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chaotic Moon Studios</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (acquired by Accenture) and Team Chaos (acquired by Zynga). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And big, provocative, projects are part of what Church is already famous for. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Church created the first direct genomic sequencing method in the 1980s, and went on to help initiate the Human genome project. Now, he leads synthetic biological efforts at the Wyss Institute, where he </span><a href="https://wyss.harvard.edu/team/core-faculty/george-church/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">has focused</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on synthesizing entire genes and genomes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> While CRISPR gene editing has only just entered human trials, and typically aims to edit a single disease-causing gene, Church’s projects often think far bigger &#8212; often along the lines of speeding along evolution. In 2015, Church and colleagues edited </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature.2015.18525"><span style="font-weight: 400;">62 genes in pig embryos</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (a record at the time) in an effort to create organs for human transplants. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company spun out of that endeavor, eGenesis, is behind on Church’s initial timeline (he predicted pig organs would be viable transplants by 2019), but the company is performing </span><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2019/06/12/239014/crispr-pig-organs-are-being-implanted-in-monkeys-to-see-if-theyre-safe-for-humans/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">preclinical experiments</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on monkeys.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Resurrecting a woolly mammoth has long been in Church’s crosshairs. </span><a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2121503-can-we-grow-woolly-mammoths-in-the-lab-george-church-hopes-so/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2017</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, his lab at Harvard University reported that they had managed to add 45 genes to the genome of an Asian elephant in an attempt to recreate the mammoth. Through a sponsored research agreement, this company will fully support the mammoth work at Church’s lab.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company’s pitch for bringing back the Mammoth, per the press release, is to combat the effects of climate change through ecosystem restoration. Lamm expands on that point: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our goal is not to just bring back the Mammoth, that’s a feat in itself,” he says. &#8220;It’s for the successful re-wilding of mammoths. If you take that toolkit, you have all the tools are your disposal to prevent extinction or to bring back critically endangered species.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">About 1 million plant and animal species are </span><a href="https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/biodiversity/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">threatened with extinction</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Colossal’s mammoth project, should it succeed, would suggest they have developed the capacity to both repopulate recently dead creatures, and even perform what Lamm calls &#8220;genetic rescue&#8221; to stop them from disappearing in the first place. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Genetic rescue is the process of increasing genetic diversity in an endangered population &#8212; this could be achieved through gene-editing, or in some cases, cloning new individuals to create a wider gene pool (provided the clone and the existing animals have different enough genes). There is already some evidence that this is possible. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In February 2021, a black-footed ferret named </span><a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/elizabeth-ann-first-cloned-black-footed-ferret-180977065/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Elizabeth Ann</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> became the first cloned endangered species native to North America. She was cloned from the DNA housed in frozen tissue samples collected in 1988. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2201592" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2201592" loading="lazy" class="breakout size-full wp-image-2201592" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="640" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg 3300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=2048,1280 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/GettyImages-1192609742.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2201592" class="wp-caption-text">Mammoth in the middle of mountains. This is a 3D render illustration. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Orla / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bringing back extinct species might help combat a consequence of climate change, but it doesn’t solve the root problem. As long as the human-based drivers of climate change remain in-tact, there’s not much hope for a newly reborn creature that was killed by climate change the first time; in fact, fluctuating climates were </span><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-21201-8"><span style="font-weight: 400;">one reason megafauna </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">died off in the first place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, there could be serious </span><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1617138120300844?via%3Dihub"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ecosystem ramifications</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from re-wilding long-dead species, like spreading novel disease, displacing existing species and altering the actual landscape (elephants are ecosystem engineers, after all). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If tackling biodiversity is part of Colossal’s core pitch, why go directly for the mammoth when there are species that might be saved right now? Lamm notes that the company may also try to edit the genomes of Asian elephants to make them more resilient; however, the mammoth project remains the company&#8217;s “north star.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The argument, from Lamm’s perspective, is that the mammoth project is a moonshot. Even if the company shoots for the moon and lands among the stars, they will have to develop proprietary technology for de-extinction that might then be licensed or sold to potential buyers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It’s very similar to the Apollo program &#8212; which was a literal moonshot. A bunch of technologies were created along the way. Things like GPS, the fundamentals of the internet and semiconductors. All those were highly monetizable,” he says.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In short, the mammoth project is more like an incubator for developing a host of intellectual property. That might include projects like artificial wombs or other applications of CRISPR, Lamm notes. These products will still face massive scientific hurdles &#8212; existing artificial womb projects </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">aren’t even near entering human trials</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; but those hurdles might be slightly more achievable than living, breathing beings. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not that Colossal doesn’t have plenty of interim plans while that research is being done. The company is also out to create an especially memorable brand along the way. Lamm says you could think of the brand as “Harvard meets MTV.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though there’s no company that Lamm says is a direct comparison to Colossal, he mentioned several large space brands and agencies, like Blue Origin, SpaceX and notably NASA in our conversation — “I think that NASA is the best brand the United States ever made,” he notes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If you look at SpaceX and Blue Origin and Virgin, my 91-year-old grandmother knew these guys went to space. ULA and other people have been launching rockets and putting satellites up there for decades &#8212; nobody cared. These companies did a great job of bringing the public in,” he says. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s all a bit reminiscent of Elon Musk’s plan for </span><a href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/full/10.1089/space.2017.29009.emu"><span style="font-weight: 400;">sending humans to Mars</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, although Starship (the vehicle that’s supposed to get us there) hasn’t moved beyond </span><a href="https://www.space.com/spacex-starship-orbital-test-flight-readiness-musk"><span style="font-weight: 400;">prototype test</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> flights. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The big ideas, says Lamm, draw in the public. The intellectual property developed along the way can pacify investors in the meantime. The perspective is inescapably sci-fi, but perhaps it’s supposed to be that way. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that’s not to say that the company isn’t absolutely dead-set on bringing a mammoth to life. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This capital, says Lamm, should be sufficient to help develop a viable mammoth embryo. They’re aiming to have the first set of calves born in the next four to six years. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/13/how-colossal-sold-investors-on-a-quest-to-resurrect-a-woolly-mammoth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2201508</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
