<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:33:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Tusk Ventures&#8217; Jordan Nof and Wheel&#8217;s Michelle Davey to talk fundraising tips on Extra Crunch Live</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/tusk-ventures-jordan-nof-and-wheels-michelle-davey-to-talk-fundraising-tips-on-extra-crunch-live/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/tusk-ventures-jordan-nof-and-wheels-michelle-davey-to-talk-fundraising-tips-on-extra-crunch-live/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extra crunch live announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jordan nof]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michelle davey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tusk Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wheel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2169734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Tusk Ventures portfolio is impressive, if not intimidating. It includes Lemonade, FanDuel, Coinbase, Latch, Bird and many, many more. We&#8217;re lucky to be joined by Tusk co-founder and general partner Jordan Nof for an upcoming episode of Extra Crunch Live, and even luckier that he&#8217;s bringing Wheel co-founder Michelle Davey along with him. Wheel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The Tusk Ventures portfolio is impressive, if not intimidating. It includes Lemonade, FanDuel, Coinbase, Latch, Bird and many, many more. We&#8217;re lucky to be joined by Tusk co-founder and general partner Jordan Nof for an upcoming episode of <a href="http://techcrunch.com/ecl">Extra Crunch Live</a>, and even luckier that he&#8217;s bringing Wheel co-founder Michelle Davey along with him.</p>
<p>Wheel is an infrastructure company focused on virtual care, and has raised more than $65 million in funding from Lightspeed, CRV and Tusk, of course.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live is all about helping founders build better venture-backed businesses. We do this by bringing together investors and the founders they invest in to chat about how they came together, what stood out to them about the other party, and how they work together today. <a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-tusk-venture-partners-and-wheel?ref=1c496e6adc7a">Register here for Extra Crunch Live: Tusk Venture Partners and Wheel!</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>We also chat about general principles for fundraising, board construction, packaging and pricing, and other tactical advice for founders.</p>
<p>Oh, and if that weren&#8217;t enough, Extra Crunch Live also features an audience pitch-off, where folks in attendance can come onto our virtual stage and pitch their products to our guests, who then give their live feedback.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re incredibly excited to be joined by two powerhouses such as Nof and Davey, and we sincerely hope you&#8217;ll join us to hear what they have to say.</p>
<p>Extra Crunch Live, which goes down every Wednesday at 3pm ET/noon PT, is accessible to anyone and everyone. But only Extra Crunch members can access the content on-demand. And, by the way, the Extra Crunch library is growing every single day. Not a member yet? Subscribe to Extra Crunch <a href="http://techcrunch.com/subscribe">here</a>!</p>
<p>The Tusk Ventures + Wheel episode of Extra Crunch Live goes down on Wednesday, July 14 at 3pm ET/noon PT.</p>
<p><a href="https://hopin.com/events/extra-crunch-live-tusk-venture-partners-and-wheel?ref=1c496e6adc7a">Register here!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/tusk-ventures-jordan-nof-and-wheels-michelle-davey-to-talk-fundraising-tips-on-extra-crunch-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2169734</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Simpplr raises $32M for its intranet platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/simpplr-raises-32m-for-its-intranet-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/simpplr-raises-32m-for-its-intranet-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forrester]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intranet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nutanix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[splunk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telecommuting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tola capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Simpplr, a modern platform for building intranet sites (or &#8217;employee communications and enablement platforms,&#8217; as the company calls it), today announced that it has raised a $32 million Series C round led by Tola Capital. Norwest Ventures, which led the company&#8217;s Series B round last year, as well as Salesforce Ventures and George Still Ventures [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.simpplr.com/">Simpplr</a>, a modern platform for building intranet sites (or &#8217;employee communications and enablement platforms,&#8217; as the company calls it), today announced that it has raised a $32 million Series C round led by Tola Capital. Norwest Ventures, which led the company&#8217;s Series B round last year, as well as Salesforce Ventures and George Still Ventures also participated. This brings Simpplr&#8217;s total funding to just over $61 million.</p>
<p>As Simpplr CEO and founder Dhiraj Sharma told me, the Series B round was meant to help the team accelerate product innovation and development. Unsurprisingly, the COVID-19 pandemic only increased demand for digital workplace solutions like Simpplr. As Sharma noted, the company&#8217;s thesis was always that the world was moving toward remote/hybrid work. The pandemic only accelerated this process and with that, the sense of urgency in its customer base to modernize their own platforms for communicating with their employees. To keep up with this growth, the company doubled its team since last August (though Sharma, just like many other startup founders I&#8217;ve recently talked to, also bemoaned that it’s becoming increasingly hard to find talent).</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/simpplr.gif"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2177267" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/simpplr.gif" alt="" width="800" height="450" /></a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company says that it added 100 enterprise customers over the course of the last year. Today, its customer base includes a number of early adopters like Splunk or Nutanix, which were always building toward a global workforce and always had a need for a product like Simpplr. But due to the pandemic, more traditional businesses like Fox, AAA insurance or Renewal by Andersen also needed to quickly find ways to support their newly remote workforces.</p>
<p>&#8220;When this pandemic happened, there were lots of traditional companies who didn&#8217;t think that they would be doing remote work as much in the near future as they had to,&#8221; Sharma said. &#8220;For them, things changed and then what they realized is that they did not have effective means of formal employee communication and also lacked the digital employee experience &#8212; and they realized that very quickly.&#8221;</p>
<p>Simpplr is obviously not the only intranet solution on the market, but Sharma argues that the service isn&#8217;t just recognized by analyst firms like Gartner and Forrester, but also highly reviewed by its customers, in large parts thanks to its focus on user experience. &#8220;UX is our number one strength and differentiator. We have been pushing the boundaries of intranet for last five years,&#8221; he said and cited features like the company&#8217;s <a href="https://www.simpplr.com/auto-governance-engine/">auto-governance engine</a>, which he likened to a &#8220;Roomba for your intranet.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177270" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/covid-intranet-1x-1.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177270" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2177270" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/covid-intranet-1x-1.png" alt="" width="720" height="391" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/covid-intranet-1x-1.png 720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/covid-intranet-1x-1.png?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/covid-intranet-1x-1.png?resize=300,163 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/covid-intranet-1x-1.png?resize=680,369 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/covid-intranet-1x-1.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2177270" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Simpplr</p></div></p>
<p>Analytics, too, is another area where Simpplr is trying to differentiate itself. &#8220;Our company&#8217;s mission is to help companies build a better workplace &#8212; and unless we can show the areas of improvement and provide insights like how to do something better, we just become a dumb tool,” he said. “For us, what is very important is not only that you are communicating but helping our customers to understand what&#8217;s working and what&#8217;s not working. What&#8217;s the impact of the communication and how are your employees feeling about it?&#8221;</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the company is working on building more AI into its tools &#8211; including its analytics &#8212; to help companies better communicate with their employees and understand the impact of those messages.</p>
<p>As for the new funding round, Sharma noted that he bootstrapped his previous two companies, which has made him take a somewhat conservative approach to fundraising. &#8220;When I used to hear that your investors or VCs expect growth at all costs, I just could never understand that,&#8221; he said. &#8220;So while building this company, even though this is a venture-funded company, I still wanted to make sure that I use the finances responsibly and I build a business in a sustainable manner. I wanted to make sure that if we raised a large investment, we have a proper use for that investment and that this investment will bring the right results.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tola Capital principal Eddie Kang will now join Simpplr&#8217;s board. &#8220;The future of work is hybrid and Simpplr is essential to a company&#8217;s ability to engage with employees,&#8221; he said. &#8220;As enterprise software investors, what excites us about Simpplr’s platform is that it allows leadership teams to streamline communications across channels and provides a turnkey platform that drives value to customers very quickly. Our partnership with Simpplr will accelerate its roadmap to meet the needs of global business leaders and communications teams.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/simpplr-raises-32m-for-its-intranet-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177241</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>M1 Finance raises $150M in SoftBank-led Series E, boosts valuation to $1.45B</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/m1-finance-raises-150m-in-softbank-led-series-e-boosts-valuation-to-1-45b/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/m1-finance-raises-150m-in-softbank-led-series-e-boosts-valuation-to-1-45b/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M1 Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SoftBank Vision Fund 2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just over four months after announcing a $75 million Series D, M1 Finance today is announcing a new $150 million Series E round of funding led by SoftBank’s Vision Fund 2. The financing, which also included participation from existing backers, propels the Chicago-based fintech to unicorn status with a valuation of $1.45 billion. It also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just over four months after announcing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/m1-finance-raises-another-rapid-fire-round-after-scaling-its-aum-to-more-than-3-5b/">a $75 million Series D</a>, </span><a href="https://www.m1finance.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">M1 Finance</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> today is announcing a new $150 million Series E round of funding led by SoftBank’s Vision Fund 2.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The financing, which also included participation from existing backers, propels the Chicago-based fintech to unicorn status with a valuation of $1.45 billion. It also marks M1’s fourth funding round in just over a 13-month time frame, and brings its total raised since its mid-2015 inception to over $300 million. Previous investors include Coatue Management, Left Lane Capital, Jump Capital and Clocktower Technology Ventures, among others.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the time of its Series D in March, M1 was “near unicorn status,” according to founder and CEO Brian Barnes.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sTnSbssozP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/m1-finance-raises-another-rapid-fire-round-after-scaling-its-aum-to-more-than-3-5b/">M1 Finance raises another rapid-fire round after scaling its AUM to more than $3.5B</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;M1 Finance raises another rapid-fire round after scaling its AUM to more than $3.5B&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/09/m1-finance-raises-another-rapid-fire-round-after-scaling-its-aum-to-more-than-3-5b/embed/#?secret=sTnSbssozP" data-secret="sTnSbssozP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup combines three different traditional fintech services into one (automated investing, borrowing and banking/spending) and has seen rapid growth over the past couple of years. At the time of its last raise in early March, for example, it had reached $3.5 billion in AUM (assets under management). Today, the company says it now has $4.5 billion in AUM, which is up more than fivefold compared to 18 months prior, according to Barnes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since July 1, 2020, the company has more than doubled its user base and tripled its AUM.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177210" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177210" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177210 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/M1_1200x630_2-1.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="382" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/M1_1200x630_2-1.jpg 1064w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/M1_1200x630_2-1.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/M1_1200x630_2-1.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/M1_1200x630_2-1.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/M1_1200x630_2-1.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/M1_1200x630_2-1.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177210" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> M1 Finance</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">M1 first launched to the public in late 2016 with the mission of building a platform that would help people manage and grow their money “with control and automation – for free.” (For more details on just how M1 makes its money, check out its blog <a href="https://www.m1finance.com/blog/how-m1-makes-money/">here</a>).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, the company says it has “hundreds of thousands” of customers that either invest, conduct digital checking or access portfolio lines of credit through its platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like many other companies, M1 saw a pandemic-driven boost in business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In particular, there seemed to be a surge of new interest in investing, particularly by millennials, according to Barnes. </span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177212" style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177212" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177212 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="390" height="260" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg 6016w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?resize=768,513 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?resize=680,454 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?resize=1536,1025 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?resize=2048,1367 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BrianBarnes-1.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 390px) 100vw, 390px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177212" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> M1 Finance founder &amp; CEO Brian Barnes</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Lockdown led many to decrease their spending, while an uncertain future increased the appetite to build wealth for the long-term through investing,” he told TechCrunch. “M1 experienced this firsthand. We quadrupled our assets under management since the start of the pandemic last March&#8230; and saw a 3x increase in signups in January 2021 compared to the month prior.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last December, M1 launched </span><a href="https://www.m1finance.com/blog/smart-transfers/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Smart Transfers,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> allowing its “Plus” clients to automate financial goals based on pre-set rules. In February of this year, it released </span><a href="https://www.m1finance.com/custodial/#:~:text=A%20custodial%20account%20is%20an,the%20assets%20in%20the%20account."><span style="font-weight: 400;">Custodial Accounts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, giving M1 Plus parents or guardians the ability to invest in portfolios for younger generations. In June, M1 launched </span><a href="https://www.m1finance.com/blog/send-check/#:~:text=This%20new%20feature%2C%20exclusively%20for,'t%20do%20it%20digitally)."><span style="font-weight: 400;">Send Check,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which allows M1 Plus clients to send physical checks from their M1 Spend Plus checking accounts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We always want to be the ones pushing for change, just as we have by moving away from the manual input of every trade or one-size-fits-all portfolios,” Barnes said. “Our plan is to continue to innovate across Invest, Borrow and Spend, finding ways to make complex processes seamless.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Munish Varma, managing partner at SoftBank Investment Advisers, says his firm believes M1 is “well-positioned to consolidate users’ financial lives on a one-stop super-app with its Invest, Spend and Borrow products.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company plans to use its fresh capital to build new products and features, further &#8220;innovate&#8221; its platform and do more hiring. M1 has grown its headcount from 40 at the start of 2020 to 250 employees today.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As my colleague Alex Wilhelm pointed out when covering M1’s Series D, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the company is not the only service in the savings, investing and spending spaces that has seen growth in the last year. Robinhood and Public </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/as-expected-stock-trading-service-public-raises-220m-at-unicorn-valuation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">have done well on</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/01/robinhoods-q4-2020-revenue-shows-a-return-to-growth/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">investing side of things</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and Chime has </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/how-robinhood-and-chime-raised-2b-in-the-last-year/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">scaled quickly</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the spending and saving markets.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cLvhMjRTqF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/how-robinhood-and-chime-raised-2b-in-the-last-year/">How Robinhood and Chime raised $2B+ in the last year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How Robinhood and Chime raised $2B+ in the last year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/23/how-robinhood-and-chime-raised-2b-in-the-last-year/embed/#?secret=cLvhMjRTqF" data-secret="cLvhMjRTqF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/m1-finance-raises-150m-in-softbank-led-series-e-boosts-valuation-to-1-45b/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177193</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your funding round isn&#8217;t special, but you might be</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/your-funding-round-isnt-special-but-you-might-be/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/your-funding-round-isnt-special-but-you-might-be/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding round]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. For this week’s deep dive, Alex and Natasha and Danny decided it was time to chat about funding rounds. Yep, everyone&#8217;s favorite topic, just in time for the return of our wonderful producer Chris. To help us navigate these particular waters, we had [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/96eff6a2-4a16-43ef-859d-384e772fb277?dark=false" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/equity/id1215439780">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p>For this week’s deep dive, <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny</a> decided it was time to chat about funding rounds. Yep, everyone&#8217;s favorite topic, just in time for the return of our wonderful producer <a href="https://twitter.com/CGates123">Chris.</a></p>
<p>To help us navigate these particular waters, we had our friend and friendly competitor <a href="https://twitter.com/alexrkonrad">Alex Konrad</a> on the show. Konrad is a senior editor over at Forbes, and part of the founding duo behind the <a href="https://www.forbes.com/newsletter/midastouch/">Midas Touch newsletter.</a> We like him &#8211; and his puppy!</p>
<p>With four of us around the Zoom table, here&#8217;s what we got into:</p>
<ul>
<li>An overview of the venture capital market in Q2. You can read <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/09/startups-have-never-had-it-so-good/">TechCrunch&#8217;s coverage of the global numbers here</a>, and our further exploration of the US market here. TechCrunch has more coming on the matter, so stay tuned.</li>
<li>While the show includes the staggering statistics on the current funding frenzy, we soon broadened the conversation to why it all matters.</li>
<li>Consider this a peek into the reporter&#8217;s notebook! We spoke about the supply and demand for covering funding rounds, the imbalance in who receives what money, and how an overall reader ad writer numbness to that $2 million pre-seed impacts the headlines.</li>
<li>Which landed us into our final section: how to stand out in the overall deluge of funding rounds. Here we all had a take, because all reporters find different things interesting. Here we answer questions about what metrics to pay attention to, how to be more than a number in your pitch, and the value of talking about topics other than your startup&#8217;s success.</li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks again to Alex K. for joining the show! Find him on Twitter,https://twitter.com/alexrkonrad and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexkonrad/">check out his work at Forbes.</a></p>
<p>Chat with everyone on Friday, a show that is already coming together to be a scorcher. A bit like the weather. Except in San Francisco. Natasha is cold!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 a.m. PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/your-funding-round-isnt-special-but-you-might-be/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176828</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acelerate raises $14.44M Series A to turn existing restaurants into cloud kitchens</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/acelerate-raises-14-44m-series-a-to-turn-existing-restaurants-into-cloud-kitchens/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/acelerate-raises-14-44m-series-a-to-turn-existing-restaurants-into-cloud-kitchens/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jordan Crook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acelerate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Acelerate, a software company looking to help restaurants make the most out of their infrastructure, is today announcing the close of a $14.44 million Series A financing led by Sequoia Capital. The startup was founded by George Jacobs, who grew up working in his family&#8217;s pizzeria. He attended USC with a plan to get a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://acelerate.io/">Acelerate</a>, a software company looking to help restaurants make the most out of their infrastructure, is today announcing the close of a $14.44 million Series A financing led by Sequoia Capital.</p>
<p>The startup was founded by George Jacobs, who grew up working in his family&#8217;s pizzeria. He attended USC with a plan to get a business degree and ultimately expand Georgee&#8217;s Pizza, but realized that there was an opportunity beyond his own family restaurant to help all kinds of restaurants in the wake of the tech boom.</p>
<p>After a couple of years at Doordash, he came up with the idea for Acelerate, a startup working to give restaurants a way to make the most of their infrastructure.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The first piece of the business is a simple software solution that allows restaurants to manage their entire digital footprint, from order management, pricing, menu updates and changes, to sales and marketing. The idea is that many restaurants are selling through their own brick-and-mortar location, of course, but also selling through a bevy of other platforms like Doordash, Uber Eats, or Seamless. On top of that, their restaurants are listed on Opentable, Yelp, and other marketing platforms.</p>
<p>It can be a lot to manage.</p>
<p>Acelerate&#8217;s SaaS product allows restaurants to manage all of these platforms from a single spot.</p>
<p>But where the company really differentiates from rival players is its licensing business. Acelerate has developed seven proprietary restaurant brands, all with their own menus. They license those brands, complete with the recipes, cooking instructions, and a training guide to restaurants who want to offer more through their online sales portals.</p>
<p>For example, an ice cream shop working with Acelerate may have a strong business in the summer, but struggle in the winter. That same ice cream shop may have a full working kitchen that rarely gets used save for what it takes to make ice cream and cones.</p>
<p>Acelerate allows that shop to license the rights to operate a burger shop or a BBQ joint out of that same space, teaching employees how to make a bacon cheeseburger or a rack of ribs, thus creating an additional revenue stream for that restaurant during leaner months for its traditional business.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2177394" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1142.jpeg?w=225" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1142.jpeg 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1142.jpeg?resize=113,150 113w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1142.jpeg?resize=225,300 225w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1142.jpeg?resize=510,680 510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/IMG_1142.jpeg?resize=38,50 38w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Moreover, Acelerate not only licenses its own brands, but works with existing restaurant brands to license out their menus to other restaurant partners.</p>
<p>Thus far, Acelerate has signed on three existing restaurants as brand licensing partners.</p>
<p>Big chains, like Applebees, only use the software piece of Acelerate, but smaller restaurants gravitate toward the licensing product as a way to expand their business, it said. As cloud kitchens trend upward, the startup has found a way to turn existing restaurants into cloud kitchens, as well.</p>
<p>The software side of the business operates as expected, on a monthly subscription model. On the licensing side, restaurants can license one of the brands offered through Acelerate, either homegrown or third-party. Acelerate collects a 40 percent fee from restaurant partners, which includes all third-party marketplace, order processing and delivery fees, as well as promotional spend. The startup also negotiates national food distribution deals to help restaurants get up and running with a new ingredient list.</p>
<p>Jacobs told TechCrunch that Acelerate is currently working with thousands of restaurants on the software side, and that hundreds of stores are licensing the Acelerate brands.</p>
<p>The startup&#8217;s new capital will be used towards further growth of the team and product. Right now, Acelerate has 11 full time employees, and about half of them are women or underrepresented minorities, according to Jacobs.</p>
<p>Jacobs explained that the unique opportunity for the company is that it&#8217;s not purely a software play that sits on top of an already complicated tech stack.</p>
<p>&#8220;The big opportunity lies in the combination of two great pieces of operating a restaurant, which is technology and operations,&#8221; said Jacobs. &#8220;To do that, we believe that proximity is power and we need to be as close to our customers as possible. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re really doubling down on building local teams and ensuring that we&#8217;re hands on with our operator and restaurant partners.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/acelerate-raises-14-44m-series-a-to-turn-existing-restaurants-into-cloud-kitchens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177385</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former Nutanix execs launch new startup with $50M seed round</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/former-nutanix-execs-launch-new-startup-with-50m-seed-round/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/former-nutanix-execs-launch-new-startup-with-50m-seed-round/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DevRev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dheeraj pandey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayfield fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nutanix]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today a new software company from two former Nutanix executives called DevRev emerged from stealth with a $50 million seed round from Mayfield Fund, Khosla Ventures and several industry luminaries. The company, which aims to bring the coding and revenue processes closer together, already has 75 employees working on the new software platform, which they [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today a new software company from two former Nutanix executives called <a href="https://devrev.ai/">DevRev</a> emerged from stealth with a $50 million seed round from Mayfield Fund, Khosla Ventures and several industry luminaries. The company, which aims to bring the coding and revenue processes closer together, already has 75 employees working on the new software platform, which they hope to have ready to launch later this year.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not every day you see a $50 million seed round, but perhaps the fact that former Nutanix co-founder and CEO Dheeraj Pandey and his former SVP of engineering Manoj Agarwal are involved, could help explain the investor enthusiasm for the new project.</p>
<p>Pandey says that he has seen a gap between developers and the revenue the applications they create are supposed to generate. The idea behind the new company is to break down the silos that exist between the front of the office and the back of the office and give developers a deeper understanding of the customers using their products, or at least that&#8217;s the theory.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;Dev and Rev are Yin and Yang to each other. In today&#8217;s world they are really far apart with tons of bureaucracy between these two parties. Our goal to bring dev and rev to get rid of the bureaucracy,&#8221; Pandey told me</p>
<p>The company intends to build an API to help developers pull this information from existing systems for companies already working with a CRM tool like Salesforce, while helping gather that customer information for younger companies who might lack a tool. Regardless, the idea is to bring that info where the developer can see it to help build better products.</p>
<p>The way it works in most companies is customer service or sales hears complaints or suggestions about the product, and tickets get generated, but putting these issues in front of the people building the software isn&#8217;t always easy or direct. DevRev hopes to change that.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="mymAPcYBHQ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/">Why Slack and Salesforce execs think they&#8217;re better together</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Why Slack and Salesforce execs think they&#8217;re better together&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/04/why-slack-and-salesforce-execs-think-theyre-better-together/embed/#?secret=mymAPcYBHQ" data-secret="mymAPcYBHQ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Navin Chaddha, managing director at Mayfield, whose firm is investing in DevRev, sees a need to bring these different parts of the company together in a more direct way. &#8220;The code that developers work on today is used by support as well as marketing and sales. By bringing the world of issues and tickets closer to the world of revenue and growth, DevRev’s unified platform bridges the gap between developer and customer and elevates the developer to a business leader,&#8221; Chaddha said.</p>
<p>With 75 employees working on the problem, DevRev is already a substantial startup. As experienced founders Pandey and Agarwal certainly understand the importance of building a diverse and inclusive company. Pandey sees the top of the employment funnel really being focused on engineering, design and business schools and the company is working to bring in a diverse group of young employees.</p>
<p>&#8220;[We are looking at ways] to search for talent and to promote talent, to make them into leaders. I think we have an empty canvas by the way, and we have this idea of COVID, and being able to do remote work has really grown the top of the funnel, the mouth of the funnel now can be anything and everything. [&#8230;] [Colleges and universities] are I would say the real source of all diversity at the end of the day. We have seen how engineering schools, design schools and business schools are actually getting so diverse,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The company is working to build the product now and reaching out to developer communities on Discord, GitHub and other places that developers gather online to get their input, while testing and improving the product in-house and with design partners.</p>
<p>Nutanix, the founders&#8217; previous company, launched in 2009 and raised over a $1 billion <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/nutanix-execs-discuss-how-they-built-their-2016-ipo-roadshow-deck/">before going public in 2016</a>. Pandey and Agarwal left Nutanix at the end of last year to launch the new company.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xold0KvWnS"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/nutanix-execs-discuss-how-they-built-their-2016-ipo-roadshow-deck/">Nutanix execs discuss how they built their 2016 IPO roadshow deck</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Nutanix execs discuss how they built their 2016 IPO roadshow deck&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/28/nutanix-execs-discuss-how-they-built-their-2016-ipo-roadshow-deck/embed/#?secret=xold0KvWnS" data-secret="xold0KvWnS" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/former-nutanix-execs-launch-new-startup-with-50m-seed-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177374</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>India bans Mastercard from adding new customers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/india-bans-mastercard-from-adding-new-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/india-bans-mastercard-from-adding-new-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reserve Bank of India has indefinitely barred Mastercard from issuing new debit, credit, or prepaid cards to customers in the South Asian market over noncompliance with local data storage rules. The South Asian market&#8217;s central bank said the new restrictions will go into effect on July 22. &#8220;Notwithstanding lapse of considerable time and adequate opportunities [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Reserve Bank of India has indefinitely barred Mastercard from issuing new debit, credit, or prepaid cards to customers in the South Asian market over noncompliance with local data storage rules.</p>
<p>The South Asian market&#8217;s central bank said the new restrictions will go into effect on July 22. &#8220;Notwithstanding lapse of considerable time and adequate opportunities being given, the entity has been found to be non-compliant with the directions on Storage of Payment System Data,&#8221; RBI said in a statement Wednesday.</p>
<p>The new order won&#8217;t impact existing customers of Mastercard, which is one of the top three card issuers in India, RBI said. &#8220;Mastercard shall advice all card issuing banks and non-banks to conform to these directions,&#8221; it said.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>This isn&#8217;t the first time India’s central bank has penalized any firm for noncompliance with local data-storage rules, which was unveiled in 2018 and mandated compliance within six months. The rules require payments firms to store all Indian transaction data within servers in the country.</p>
<p>In April, RBI <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/23/india-restricts-american-express-from-adding-new-customers-for-violating-data-storage-rules/">restricted American Express and Diners Club from adding new customers</a>, citing violation of the same rules.</p>
<p>Visa, Mastercard and several other firms, as well as the U.S. government, have previously requested New Delhi to reconsider its rules, which they have argued is designed to allow the regulator “unfettered supervisory access.”</p>
<p>Visa, Mastercard and American Express had also lobbied to either significantly change the rules or completely discard it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/india-bans-mastercard-from-adding-new-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177378</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-Plaid employees raise $30M for Stytch, an API-first passwordless authentication platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/ex-plaid-employees-raise-30m-for-stytch-an-api-first-passwordless-authentication-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/ex-plaid-employees-raise-30m-for-stytch-an-api-first-passwordless-authentication-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Access Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Password]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plaid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Secret Double Octopus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stytch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thrive Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venmo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Hockey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are far fewer annoying things than managing one’s passwords. There are a bunch of companies out there to help you attempt to do that. And there’s also a number of companies that want to go a step further and eliminate the password completely. One such company, Stytch, just raised $30 million in a Series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are far fewer annoying things than managing one’s passwords.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a bunch of companies out there to help you attempt to do that. And there’s also a number of companies that want to go a step further and eliminate the password completely.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One such company, </span><a href="https://stytch.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stytch</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, just raised $30 million in a Series A round of funding as it launches out of beta with its API-first passwordless authentication platform.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round caught our attention for a couple of reasons.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For one, this is the same startup that just months earlier announced it had raised </span><a href="https://stytch.com/blog/announcing-our-seed-round/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a $6.25 million seed round</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> led by Benchmark with participation from Index Ventures and a number of angels including Plaid co-founder William Hockey. That round was speculated to have valued the new company at a staggering $200 million (although that was never confirmed), and was actually raised last summer around the time of Stytch’s founding, but only announced this year. Other angels that have backed the company include Figma co-founder and CEO Dylan Field, Very Good Security co-founder Mahmoud Abdelkader, startup advisor Elad Gil and early Stripe employee and Cocoon co-founder Amber Feng.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also notable about this round is that Stytch was founded by two former Plaid employees, Reed McGinley-Stempel (CEO) and Julianna Lamb (CTO), who built user authentication features that “millions” use to connect their bank accounts to apps like Venmo, Coinbase and Robinhood. The company was founded on the premise that passwords are no longer secure, and make companies easy targets for hackers and expose them to account takeover risk.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NBjxBQ1Rpo"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/">Enterprise security attackers are one password away from your worst day</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enterprise security attackers are one password away from your worst day&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/embed/#?secret=NBjxBQ1Rpo" data-secret="NBjxBQ1Rpo" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lamb says that as she and McGinley-Stempel worked together at Plaid on user authentication, they realized how frustrating it is to build sign-up and login flows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In addition to it being complicated, it&#8217;s resource intensive and error-prone to build in house,” she told TechCrunch. “The other thing that really frustrated us was that the core building blocks that all companies use for authentication had really significant security and conversion issues. It struck us that the web has improved in so many ways over the past few decades, but authentication is still stuck in the 1990s.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thrive Capital led the Series A, which also included participation from Coatue Management and existing backers Benchmark and Index. The company declined to reveal its new valuation, although sources say only that it is “north of $200 million.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stytch claims that it simplifies the authentication process by giving developers and users the “tools and infrastructure to incorporate passwordless authentication methods into modern applications.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically, the team is creating “simple” APIs and SDKs (software development kits) that the founders say allow &#8220;any company to boost user onboarding and retention by removing passwords from their application, while improving security and saving significant engineering time in the process.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177130" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177130" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177130 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/StytchProductShot.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="426" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/StytchProductShot.jpg 1390w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/StytchProductShot.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/StytchProductShot.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/StytchProductShot.jpg?resize=768,481 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/StytchProductShot.jpg?resize=680,426 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/StytchProductShot.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177130" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Stytch</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In its first year of operation, Stytch released its product in beta to more than 350 developers who have added passwordless features such as email magic links, SMS and WhatsApp passcodes and one-click user invitations into their user onboarding and authentication login flows. As mentioned above, Stytch launched out of beta this week to make all of the features publicly available in conjunction with the funding announcement. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;What we found is that it makes more sense to be more flexible with developers,&#8221; Lamb told TechCrunch. &#8220;The thing that even surprised us about the API-first approach is that we now also have a handful of Fortune 500 companies using the product and the primary reasoning from their standpoint was one of the simplicity of getting set up on the platform. It took them an hour rather than the multiple months they sometimes spend with other providers. There is also the direct API piece where it&#8217;s just a much more flexible way to think about workflows in onboarding or login.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nearly</span><a href="https://services.google.com/fh/files/blogs/google_security_infographic.pdf"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">65%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of users reuse passwords across accounts, which can pose major security threats and breach liabilities, according to a study conducted by Google. Also, many people struggle with remembering passwords and the password reset process can be so frustrating that many users </span><a href="http://www.ponemon.org/local/upload/file/NokNokWP_FINAL_3.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">just give up on the account</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This can negatively impact businesses that rely on e-commerce sites, who lose customers over that frustration.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thrive’s Gaurav Ahuja, who is taking a seat on Stytch’s board with the funding round, believes that the startup’s product </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">is specifically designed for improving sign-up conversion and user retention, and its customizable front end tools help companies get started “quickly.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He said his firm talked to many developers who used it and saw “how impressed they were with the company’s best-in-class API docs and speed to go live.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the past several years we&#8217;ve seen that most authentication systems are both outdated and pose a security risk to users,” Ahuja told TechCrunch via email. “Stytch is addressing both of these issues head on.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new capital will be used to roll out more authentication options, including biometrics, WebAuthn, OAuth logins, QR codes and push notification login. The company also plans to launch additional user infrastructure features and to build out session management and advanced fraud detection solutions. Stytch also aims to hire 20 people by year’s end.</span></p>
<p>Stytch is not the only company out to kill the password. Boston-based Transmit Security in June raised a massive $543 million in Series A funding in what was believed to be the largest Series A investment in cybersecurity history and one of the highest valuations for a bootstrapped company. Microsoft has announced plans to make <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/windows-10/">Windows 10</a> password-free, and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/12/7-new-security-features-apple-quietly-announced-at-wwdc/">Apple recently previewed Passkeys in iCloud Keychain</a>, a method of passwordless authentication powered by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/04/10/fido-alliance-and-w3c-have-a-plan-to-kill-the-password/">WebAuth</a>.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NNZfJHROry"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/transmit-security-raises-543m-series-a-to-kill-off-the-password/">Transmit Security raises $543M Series A to kill off the password</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Transmit Security raises $543M Series A to kill off the password&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/transmit-security-raises-543m-series-a-to-kill-off-the-password/embed/#?secret=NNZfJHROry" data-secret="NNZfJHROry" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/ex-plaid-employees-raise-30m-for-stytch-an-api-first-passwordless-authentication-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177105</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unybrands brings in $300M to acquire more e-commerce businesses</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/unybrands-brings-in-300m-to-acquire-more-e-commerce-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/unybrands-brings-in-300m-to-acquire-more-e-commerce-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crayhill Capital Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ulrich Kratz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unybrands]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unybrands is the latest e-commerce aggregator to pick up a significant investment, this time closing $300 million in growth capital from Crayhill Capital Management.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://unybrands.com/">Unybrands</a> is the latest e-commerce aggregator to pick up a significant investment, this time closing $300 million in growth capital from Crayhill Capital Management.</p>
<p>The Miami-based company, which created a platform for e-commerce businesses looking to scale their operations on and off Amazon, was founded in 2020. It previously raised a <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/unybrands-closes-25m-seed-to-acquire-scale-online-brands/">$25 million seed round</a> in February.</p>
<p>Unybrands looks for brands across eight categories, including baby, garden and outdoor, sports and fitness and personal care, and provides capital and resources to grow those brands.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Since the February seed round, Unybrands said it closed on multiple acquisitions in both the United States and Europe, and along with more in the works, will put the company on track to beat its 2021 projections of completing 20 deals.</p>
<p>Ulrich Kratz, co-founder and CEO, told TechCrunch via email that the funding “gives us more firepower to execute and overachieve on our business goals.” It will also enable the company to accelerate acquisitions of Fulfillment By Amazon brands, invest in technology development and further build out its team. Unybrands has more than 25 full-time employees across the U.S., Europe and Asia and plans to more than double its headcount by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The company said it already began building out its technology platform to provide functionalities like finding new targets, automating supply chain management and optimizing e-commerce growth investments.</p>
<p>“Unybrands had an incredibly strong first half of the year,” Kratz said. “We’ve been able to accelerate our business plan across all fronts, including acquisitions, technology and team building. Crayhill has significant e-commerce experience in general and a dedicated strategy to finance players in the Amazon ecosystem, and they have been a great partner.”</p>
<p>Unybrands’ major cash infusion follows a strong e-commerce trend of buying and consolidating multiple smaller third-party merchants that sell their goods via Amazon’s marketplace. Leading the pack is <a href="http://thras.io/">Thrasio</a>, which raised <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/">nearly $2 billion</a> in both debt and equity over the past three years.</p>
<p>This capital raise is in good company: This week, <a href="https://www.elevatebrands.com/">Elevate Brands</a> brought in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elevate-brands-banks-250m-to-roll-up-third-party-merchants-selling-on-amazons-marketplace/">$250 million in funding</a>, while a new company, Foundry, debuted after <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210712005556/en/Foundry-Launches-To-Grow-Endur%5B%E2%80%A6%5Dnds-Raises-100-Million-of-Long-Term-Private-Equity-Capital">raising $100 million</a>. Others amassing large rounds recently include <a href="https://heyday.co/">Heyday</a>’s $70 million from General Catalyst and Berlin’s The Razor Group <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/berlins-razor-group-raises-400m-to-buy-and-scale-amazon-marketplace-merchants/">raise of $400 million</a>.</p>
<p>Kratz feels the real growth and penetration of e-commerce and direct-to-consumer is just starting to accelerate, which is creating an environment for several players to provide better ways to do business.</p>
<p>“And, the space has attracted a lot of capital, which is a big validation of the enormous upside,” he added.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="pg4OTpnDsK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/e-commerce-roll-ups-present-the-next-wave-of-disruption-in-consumer-packaged-goods/">E-commerce roll-ups are the next wave of disruption in consumer packaged goods</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;E-commerce roll-ups are the next wave of disruption in consumer packaged goods&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/e-commerce-roll-ups-present-the-next-wave-of-disruption-in-consumer-packaged-goods/embed/#?secret=pg4OTpnDsK" data-secret="pg4OTpnDsK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/unybrands-brings-in-300m-to-acquire-more-e-commerce-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177183</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Echo Dot designed by Diane von Furstenberg? Yeah, sure, why not</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/an-echo-dot-designed-by-diane-von-furstenberg-yeah-sure-why-not/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/an-echo-dot-designed-by-diane-von-furstenberg-yeah-sure-why-not/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIane von furstenberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Echo Dot]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Amazon launched Build It, a fun little program that lets customers preorder concept devices. Think about it like Indiegogo or Kickstarter, where the company will only actually make the product if enough people buy-in via preorder. Obviously Amazon has a significantly larger ability to absorb a misstep than your average first-time hardware [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Earlier this year, Amazon launched Build It, a fun little program that lets customers preorder concept devices. Think about it like Indiegogo or Kickstarter, where the company will only actually make the product if enough people buy-in via preorder. Obviously Amazon has a significantly larger ability to absorb a misstep than your average first-time hardware startup, but I digress.</p>
<p>This latest round isn’t particularly experimental as far as these things go. The company partnered with fashion mogul Diane von Furstenberg to create new coverings for its popular entry-level smart speaker. The Echo Dot x Diane von Furstenberg is being offered up in three varieties: Midnight Kiss, Ikat or Twigs. It&#8217;s not exactly thew new product entries <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/amazon-will-let-users-vote-on-new-alexa-with-pre-orders-including-a-cuckoo-clock/">we saw the first time out</a>, which included a sticky note printer, smart scale and Alexa cuckoo clock.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177197" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177197" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2177197" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="745" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg 2102w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg?resize=150,109 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg?resize=300,218 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg?resize=768,559 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg?resize=680,495 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg?resize=1536,1118 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1491 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Screen-Shot-2021-07-13-at-5.39.12-PM.jpg?resize=50,36 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177197" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Amazon</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Each runs $59 &#8212; the price of the Echo Dot with clock and $10 more than the standard Dot. The product looks to otherwise be the same as the latest gen Echo Dot. The company says it will be donating to Vital Voices, a charity chosen by the designer &#8212; though it wouldn’t specify how much when we asked.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PK7VIqkM8F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/amazon-echo-dot-with-clock-review-a-mostly-aesthetic-update/">Amazon Echo Dot with Clock review: A mostly aesthetic update</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon Echo Dot with Clock review: A mostly aesthetic update&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/amazon-echo-dot-with-clock-review-a-mostly-aesthetic-update/embed/#?secret=PK7VIqkM8F" data-secret="PK7VIqkM8F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Preorders open now and close August 13. If the designs don’t hit their goal, customers won’t be charged. Once they&#8217;re live, &#8220;a select number of successful prints may be available at full price after the campaign closes, while supplies last,&#8221; according to Amazon.</p>
<p>[gallery ids="2177362,2177364,2177365,2177366,2177367,2177368,2177369,2177370"]</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="wQNw0tzJN0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/amazon-will-let-users-vote-on-new-alexa-with-pre-orders-including-a-cuckoo-clock/">Amazon will let users vote on new Alexa devices with pre-orders, including a cuckoo clock</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon will let users vote on new Alexa devices with pre-orders, including a cuckoo clock&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/17/amazon-will-let-users-vote-on-new-alexa-with-pre-orders-including-a-cuckoo-clock/embed/#?secret=wQNw0tzJN0" data-secret="wQNw0tzJN0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rWWNKmMQNP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/amazons-newest-product-lets-companies-build-their-own-alexa-assistant/">Amazon&#8217;s newest product lets companies build their own Alexa assistant for cars, apps and video games</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Amazon&#8217;s newest product lets companies build their own Alexa assistant for cars, apps and video games&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/amazons-newest-product-lets-companies-build-their-own-alexa-assistant/embed/#?secret=rWWNKmMQNP" data-secret="rWWNKmMQNP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/an-echo-dot-designed-by-diane-von-furstenberg-yeah-sure-why-not/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177195</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Backed by $5M led by General Catalyst, Evvy launches a vaginal microbiome test to support women&#8217;s health research</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/backed-by-5m-led-by-general-catalyst-evvy-launches-a-vaginal-microbiome-test-to-support-womens-health-research/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/backed-by-5m-led-by-general-catalyst-evvy-launches-a-vaginal-microbiome-test-to-support-womens-health-research/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancestry.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bioinformatics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evvy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[femtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Catalyst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Juno Bio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microbiome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another US femtech startup has joined the race to build up data-sets to support research into and understanding of a range of health issues that can affect women. Evvy has today launched an at-home test kit for the vaginal microbiome. The user returns their swab to the startup for analysis &#8212; and gets detailed information [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Another US femtech startup has joined the race to build up data-sets to support research into and understanding of a range of health issues that can affect women.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.evvy.com">Evvy</a> has today launched an at-home test kit for the vaginal microbiome. The user returns their swab to the startup for analysis &#8212; and gets detailed information and analysis of the microbes (fungi and bacteria) that are present in their vagina and may be associated with a variety of health concerns.</p>
<p>Users of the test also get personalized suggestions for things they could try (such as diet and lifestyle changes) to improve the balance of microbes &#8212; potentially helping with related heath issues they may be suffering from, like yeast infections or BV.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Variances in the microbes present in an individual&#8217;s vaginal microbiome are thought to have broad implications for women’s health &#8212; playing a role in relatively minor infections (like thrush) but Evvy also flags research linking imbalances in the vaginal microbiome to more serious issues like infertility or pre-term birth, or even linkages to the progression of cervical cancer.</p>
<p>Decoding the vaginal microbiome is thus seen as an opportunity to support a broad range of women&#8217;s health goals.</p>
<p>&#8220;We give users back a full understanding of everything that&#8217;s present. So here are all of the bacteria and fungi and importantly what is the relative amount of each of those bacteria,&#8221; explains CEO and co-founder Priyanka Jain, noting that users also get their test data in a downloadable format so they can take the information to their healthcare provider if they wish.</p>
<p>&#8220;There are certain bacteria that play really important roles in the vagina, either positive or negative, and understanding if that&#8217;s 90% of your vagina vs 5% makes a big difference&#8230; For every single microbe that we show to a woman we also fully explain what that microbe is, what the scientific understanding of it is today, how it might contribute to symptoms, how it might be behaving with other microbes that exist in your vagina &#8212; as well as if research has shown that it&#8217;s related to any health outcomes that you might care about.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We also give every woman a full personalized plan &#8212; that includes ways to help reduce any type of disruptive bacteria, ways to promote their protective bacteria and ways to overall maintain their vaginal health based on their personal life experiences,&#8221; she adds.</p>
<p>As with many such femtech startups, Evvy is targeting the women&#8217;s health data gap. This refers to how women can have a relatively poor experience of traditional healthcare, perhaps especially when seeking help or support with conditions related to female biology, because of historic under-representation of women in medical research &#8212; which means female health conditions tend to be less well researched and understood vs conditions affecting biological men.</p>
<p>Even relatively common conditions which can affect the vagina &#8212; such as a simple yeast infection &#8212; can be frustratingly difficult to connect to individual triggers. And while over-the-counter treatments do work, some women report recurrent infections &#8212; and may benefit from a better understanding of why the infections may be occurring in the first place.</p>
<p>The problem of less research into women&#8217;s health issues does also mean that femtech startups can have a lot of ground to cover to live up to enticing pitches of &#8216;demystifying&#8217; the female body, as Evvy couches it. In its case, a key challenge is clearly analyzing the vaginal microbiome data it gets from users and turning it into useful recommendations for each person &#8212; without overpromising, given there may be relatively little research to back up possible links to wider health conditions.</p>
<p>Evvy says it tackles this challenge by signposting the level of research associated with each of the personalized suggestions it offers.</p>
<p>&#8220;I always say treat women like they&#8217;re smart,&#8221; says Jain. &#8220;What we actually do on each of our recommendations is we rate them. So they&#8217;re either rated as &#8216;novel&#8217;, &#8217;emerging&#8217; or &#8216;established&#8217;. And we show the women this is the research that exists on this type of treatment [and how relevant it might be to them personally &#8212; based on] if it was done on people that resemble you enough that you are actually interested in what the results are.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our goal is to highlight everything that&#8217;s out there. Because women are&#8230; looking for answers everywhere &#8212; and you see this kind of amazing crowdsourcing of knowledge, of people trying to figure out what might work for them &#8212; and our goal is to say, from a scientific perspective, this is everything that has been studied and we are actually just transparent about how well researched each of those things are.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jain says wider research-related goals include trying to identify biomarkers with suspected links to a swathe of serious female health issues &#8212; such as infertility, preterm birth, STI acquisition and cervical cancer progression.</p>
<p>Although it&#8217;s important to note that Evvy&#8217;s commercial offering comes with a disclaimer that it&#8217;s not providing medical advice &#8212; and is only selling a &#8220;wellness&#8221; test for now. This is because the service is not a regulated medical device. Hence Evvy specifies it&#8217;s only providing customers with &#8220;information&#8221; about their vaginal microbiome (although the co-founders told us they may consider applying for FDA clearance in the future).</p>
<p>The gap in knowledge around female health issues has led to a proliferation of &#8216;wellness&#8217; claims and products targeted at women &#8212; some of which are, unfortunately, peddling what amounts to &#8216;snake oil&#8217;; i.e. selling products that lack rigorous scientific research to underpin a fuzzy range of &#8216;holistic benefits&#8217; suggested by the associated marketing (crystal-healing yoni eggs, anyone?).</p>
<p>Being in the unregulated &#8216;wellness&#8217; category therefore has risks for any femtech startup. But Evvy also sees an opportunity to cut through some of the noise and dubious claims by arming women with robust data on what&#8217;s going on in their bodies and connecting them with genuine scientific expertise that can help them interpret it.</p>
<p>Education is a key goal for the startup, per CMO Laine Bruzek.</p>
<p>&#8220;How can we bring the scientific community, care providers and women together in the same place to get their questions answered quickly and with the best scientific information&#8230; Education is just such an important goal for us because there&#8217;s not a lot of great information that exists on the Internet,&#8221; she says.</p>
<p>&#8220;Not just about your vaginal microbiome &#8212; which is sort of a new and emerging space &#8212; but just vaginal health in general. There&#8217;s so much misinformation, there&#8217;s so much snake oil that people are selling. So we want to make sure that we have, not just a chance to bring the women together, but that we give them access to people who are pushing the bounds of vaginal health research so that they can get the best information when they need it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Evvy&#8217;s approach &#8212; which includes bringing in OBGYNs and experts in gynecology &amp; reproductive health as advisors (although the founders themselves have data science and product design backgrounds) &#8212; has attracted some top-tier investors: Today it&#8217;s announcing a $5 million seed round led by General Catalyst which will see the fund&#8217;s Margo Georgiadis (formerly the CEO of Ancestry.com) join the board.</p>
<p>Commenting in a statement, Georgiadis said: &#8220;Evvy is breaking boundaries to advance women’s health with more affordable and comprehensive testing starting with its vaginal microbiome metagenomics test. The team has bold plans to enable greater early detection, improved treatment, and enhanced therapeutics using new female-specific biomarkers.”</p>
<p>“There is a huge opportunity to build new datasets that will transform our understanding of these conditions in the female body, and I truly believe that Evvy&#8217;s unique platform combined with the development of new therapeutics will catalyze a new era in women&#8217;s health,&#8221; added Dr. Craig Cohen, professor of obstetrics, gynecology &amp; reproductive sciences at UCSF and advisor to Evvy in another supporting statement.</p>
<p>Evvy is not the first startup to sell a home testing kit for the vaginal microbiome, targeting women who may be suffering from conditions related to microbial imbalances, or &#8212; well &#8212; just women who want to learn more about their own bodies.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/juno-bio-launches-a-vaginal-microbiome-test-kit-targeting-the-womens-health-data-gap/">Juno Bio</a>, for example, launched an at-home test kit last year.</p>
<p>But Evvy is using a technique &#8212; called metagenomic sequencing &#8212; which the founders say is able to capture more data than other commercial tests, or the typical tests a woman is able to obtain via a doctor&#8217;s office (where scans may only look for a few specific pathogens). So the pitch is the approach provides a higher fidelity view of what&#8217;s going on inside a woman&#8217;s vagina.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of the work that we&#8217;ve done is specifically incorporating what&#8217;s called metagenomic sequencing into the analysis of the vaginal microbiome,&#8221; explains Jain. &#8220;When you go to the doctor&#8217;s office the type of test that they can run is what&#8217;s called a PCR test &#8212; essentially they take a sample and they look for a specific pathogen within that sample. So oftentimes when you go to the doctor you&#8217;ll get a PCR test that looks for one to three different individuals pathogens.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since then there have been a few iterations of improvements on that done by other companies. Some are not using what&#8217;s called 16-S sequencing &#8212; which is a form of amplicon sequencing &#8212; which is definitely a large step up from PCR but the downside is it&#8217;s only able to look at certain variable regions of the genome. And you actually have to pre-define what you&#8217;re looking for. So it&#8217;s much harder to do discovery and you&#8217;re not able to find all bacteria and fungi that are present. Because 16-S actually can&#8217;t detect fungi at all so you have to separately test for it &#8212; which means you can&#8217;t understand their relative relationships.</p>
<p>&#8220;So our test is really the first time anyone is using metagenomics at scale to better understand the vaginal microbiome; both for individual woman and the healthcare system as a whole&#8230; In the same way that 16-S was an improvement on PCR, metagenomics is just an improvement on 16-S; it allows us to understand everything that&#8217;s possibly present across all bacteria and fungi.&#8221;</p>
<p>Per Jain, the service is the only commercially available vaginal microbiome test that&#8217;s able to use metagenomics.</p>
<p>A key part of Evvy&#8217;s work as a startup is then the analysis of this higher dimension data it&#8217;s capturing &#8212; to map different microbes to potential health outcomes (based on its analysis of existing research) &#8212; and understand how to interpret individual findings and offer relevant and actionable information to each user.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of our work has been on the data analysis part,&#8221; confirms Jain. &#8220;So when you do metagenomics sequencing you get much, much higher fidelity data back &#8212; and we had to build out everything from, we co-developed an amazing bioinformatics pipeline that is able to analyze that type of data and understand which bacteria and fungi they are. And then actually mapped out for each of those bacteria and fungi how are they related to the vaginal microbiome? What type of symptoms might they cause, and also what type of health implications might they be related to.</p>
<p>&#8220;Lastly we&#8217;ve done a tonne of work with our science advisory board around putting together personalized recommendations that take into account &#8212; not only the microbial data that we get from the test &#8212; but also someone&#8217;s health history and their symptoms, and if what stage of menopause they&#8217;re in, or all of this other information so that we can actually make this information actionable for the women.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Once data from paying users starts to flow the idea is also to support a range of Evvy&#8217;s own research initiatives and partnerships (on the latter, specific details are being kept under wraps for now) &#8212; all aimed at furthering knowledge of women&#8217;s health and supporting what they hope will be more products in future.</span></p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s been so much research done showing that the vaginal microbiome is for example related to pre-term birth,&#8221; says Jain. &#8220;When you look at women who deliver early or pre-term, they tend to have very different vaginal microbiomes than women who don&#8217;t. But a lot of the sequencing that&#8217;s been done in that space has been using things like 16-S &#8212; and our goal is to bring a much higher level of fidelity. And so, more specifically, we can look at the strain level of bacteria &#8212; whereas 16-S and other forms of sequencing can only get you to the species level. And when we&#8217;re looking at something as complex as pre-term birth, cervical cancer progression and STI acquisition it&#8217;s not just what&#8217;s there &#8212; but it&#8217;s getting to the very, very high fidelity information of specifically what strains are there. So that we can actually start to discover what are the biomarkers that might be leading to differences between people who deliver pre-term and people who don&#8217;t.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The other value of metagenomic sequencing is it gives us functional profiling,&#8221; she adds. &#8220;Which helps us not only understand who&#8217;s there but also what they might be doing &#8212; and all of that information together is more likely able to help us better understand these complex conditions that research has shown is related but no-one&#8217;s been able to figure out exactly how.&#8221;</p>
<p>While the overarching goal is that data from users&#8217; vaginal swab samples will support research into a range of women&#8217;s health issues, Evvy&#8217;s users are also paying for a commercial service to get their individual analysis &#8212; so what can they expect?</p>
<p>The at-home swab test kit is being priced at $129 for one test kit &#8212; which delivers them with a personalized analysis after two weeks.</p>
<p>Evvy is also offering a membership rate for users who want to be able to carry out multiple tests &#8212; to be able to track changes to their vaginal microbiome &#8212; and for those users tests will cost $99 each (with the user able to take a test every three months).</p>
<p>As they launch the service across the US&#8217; 20 states, Evvy&#8217;s co-founders say they&#8217;re hoping &#8220;thousands&#8221; of women will sign up to quantify their vaginal microbiome and support the wider goal of backing research into female health.</p>
<p>&#8220;Why is it that looking at the bacteria in the vaginal microbiome is 94% accurate in predicting whether or not a cycle of IVF works?&#8221; asks Jain. &#8220;Why is it that women who give birth pre-term have a differing vaginal microbiome than people who don&#8217;t? Or the whole cervical cancer progression, STI acquisition, pelvic inflammatory disease.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s so many conditions that seem to be &#8212; either the vaginal microbiome is an interesting diagnostic opportunity [or] there&#8217;s even some very early research showing that women who have PCOS [polycystic ovary syndrome] or endometriosis have varying markers in their vaginal microbiome from women who don&#8217;t have those conditions &#8212; so everything from helping to detect disease to helping diagnose things, to helping predict risk for so many of these conditions that often we don&#8217;t catch for too long.</p>
<p>&#8220;Also thinking about treatment as well &#8212; something like IVF success or pre-term birth &#8212; if we&#8217;re able to identify risk earlier can we actually come up with interventions that are personalized to that individual person so that we&#8217;re able to avoid that negative outcome in the long term?&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nQfkF1qWNd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/juno-bio-launches-a-vaginal-microbiome-test-kit-targeting-the-womens-health-data-gap/">Juno Bio launches a vaginal microbiome test kit &#8212; targeting the women&#8217;s health data gap</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Juno Bio launches a vaginal microbiome test kit &#8212; targeting the women&#8217;s health data gap&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/30/juno-bio-launches-a-vaginal-microbiome-test-kit-targeting-the-womens-health-data-gap/embed/#?secret=nQfkF1qWNd" data-secret="nQfkF1qWNd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iMqydYphqq"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/28/femtech-poised-for-growth-beyond-fertility/">Femtech poised for growth beyond fertility</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Femtech poised for growth beyond fertility&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/28/femtech-poised-for-growth-beyond-fertility/embed/#?secret=iMqydYphqq" data-secret="iMqydYphqq" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MMP5V3IxHK"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/03/femtechs-billion-dollar-year/">Femtech&#8217;s billion-dollar year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Femtech&#8217;s billion-dollar year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/03/femtechs-billion-dollar-year/embed/#?secret=MMP5V3IxHK" data-secret="MMP5V3IxHK" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/backed-by-5m-led-by-general-catalyst-evvy-launches-a-vaginal-microbiome-test-to-support-womens-health-research/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176138</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Accounting firm Proper banks $9M Series A to automate property management</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/accounting-firm-proper-banks-9m-series-a-to-automate-property-management/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/accounting-firm-proper-banks-9m-series-a-to-automate-property-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Real Estate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bling Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klarna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MetaProp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QED Investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RealPage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Proper’s tech-enabled service is designed to execute those specific real estate accounting-related processes and apply automation to those that are repetitive.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://proper.ai/">Proper</a>, an automated accounting and bookkeeping service for property managers, announced Wednesday it raised $9 million in Series A funding in a round led by QED.</p>
<p>Existing investors MetaProp, Expa and Bling Capital also participated in the round, which gives the San Francisco-based proptech company a total amount raised of $13.8 million. The company brought in <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/startups-to-watch-stix-sanzo-workpatterns-jamm-ceresa-brio-systems-proper-tetra-insights/">$4.8 million of seed funding</a> last August.</p>
<p>CEO Mark Rojas, whose background is in product development, founded Proper in 2017 after spending a year-and-a-half learning the ropes in a property manager’s office. He was looking at the maintenance side of the business when he realized how much the accounting part of the business “was almost a dumpster fire.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“I knew the space was rife with problems to solve and how much accounting was a bigger part of the operations that needed to be executed each month and tied everything else together,” Rojas told TechCrunch. “Property managers don’t often come from an accounting background — usually they have a real estate license, so that lack of expertise can put them in a position where they can’t scale their portfolio, or if they try to, things break.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2177286" style="width: 4810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2177286" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2177286 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png" alt="" width="4800" height="2700" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png 4800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/CFP-MacBook-Burple-Background-Landscape-.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4800px) 100vw, 4800px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2177286" class="wp-caption-text">Proper dashboard</p></div></p>
<p>Proper’s tech-enabled service is designed to execute those specific real estate accounting-related processes and apply automation to those that are repetitive. The company said property managers with 1,000 doors can see 63% higher profit margins and spend 45% less time per year on accounting.</p>
<p>Rojas says accounting automation in real estate has been neglected with few startups stepping up to solve it like Proper is. He considers proptech still in its infancy with much of the innovation coming from home buying, selling and maintenance rather than accounting. It also doesn’t have a “champion company” yet leading the way.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IXHp4zfxqy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/">10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;10 proptech investors see better era for residential and retail after pandemic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/24/10-proptech-investors-see-better-era-for-residential-and-retail-after-pandemic/embed/#?secret=IXHp4zfxqy" data-secret="IXHp4zfxqy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Rather than sit and wait for a company like that to emerge, Proper pivoted to address accounting in early 2020 and saw “growth explode” over the past year. Rojas said he saw the opportunity to not only scale aggressively on the revenue side, but also build a lasting business that was sustainable.</p>
<p>“Real estate is the most valuable asset class, and what I am looking at is how big this industry could be,” he added. “That idea of there being no competitors enables us to be aggressive, be the go-to brand and scale with that high demand.”</p>
<p>Now armed with the Series A funding, the company intends to focus on operations, product development, build a new customer-facing platform and add to its headcount across business functions. Rojas said it went from zero to $2.3 million in annual recurring revenue in 2020 over 12 months. Proper also grew from 15 to 120 employees in 2021 and expects to end the year with about 200.</p>
<p>Proper paused its sales and marketing in order to scale, and Rojas is ready to hit the “play” button again. He is also happy to work with QED, which is in alignment with the company’s vision.</p>
<p>As part of the investment, QED Partner Matt Risley is joining Proper’s board of directors. Risley’s background is in fintech, and he was previously chief financial officer of e-commerce payment platform Klarna.</p>
<p>Risley told TechCrunch he initially met Rojas during Proper’s seed round and was tracking the company’s growth as its initial ideas came to fruition. He considers Proper among the success stories coming out of the real estate industry that also include RealPage, Yardi and AvidXchange.</p>
<p>He spent time with small business owners using Proper and said its product has a good market fit.</p>
<p>“What we see consistently is they are passionate about the core business of delivering value to clients and have a true expertise,” Risley said. “We also see the relief that Proper gives property owners and managers from doing bookkeeping. Anything that enables small businesses to spend more time on what they like about their businesses, they will seize upon it.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="7vMr7iOxB0"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/guest-series-d/">Property management startup Guesty raises $50M and acquires competitor Your Porter</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Property management startup Guesty raises $50M and acquires competitor Your Porter&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/guest-series-d/embed/#?secret=7vMr7iOxB0" data-secret="7vMr7iOxB0" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/accounting-firm-proper-banks-9m-series-a-to-automate-property-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardless raises $40M to help more brands launch custom credit cards</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/cardless-raises-40m/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/cardless-raises-40m/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Activant Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loyalty program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manchester united]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many consumers use their credit cards to rack up rewards to be used toward travel.  But what if you’re a sports fan, and using your credit card could lead to a virtual conversation with a player on your favorite team? Thanks to San Francisco-based Cardless, that opportunity may be less of a stretch than you [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many consumers use their credit cards to rack up rewards to be used toward travel. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what if you’re a sports fan, and using your credit card could lead to a virtual conversation with a player on your favorite team? Thanks to San Francisco-based </span><a href="https://www.cardless.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cardless</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, that opportunity may be less of a stretch than you think.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup, which is out to give brands and tech companies a way to launch custom co-branded credit cards, has raised $40 million in a Series B funding round led by Activant Capital. Other investors include the owners and management of the Phoenix Suns and Boston Celtics and existing backers such as Accomplice and Pear VC. The financing brings the two-year-old company’s total raised since its 2019 inception to $50 million. Accomplice and Greycroft co-led its $7 million Series A last June.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put simply, Cardless aims to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">help consumer brands launch credit cards “very quickly and easily” by h</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">andling the program creation, card underwriting, lending, issuance and customer service for brands. This quarter, the startup launched three digital programs &#8212; with the NBA’s Cleveland Cavaliers, British soccer team Manchester United and the Miami Marlins, a Major League Baseball team based in Florida.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company is out to modernize the whole concept of co-branded credit card programs. Of the 200 that exist in the U.S. today, only one is from a company that is less than two decades old, according to Cardless’ co-founder and president Michael Spelfogel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There are close to 200 brands with traditional cards but they are often old legacy businesses such as Costco and Sam’s,” he told TechCrunch. “We want to connect folks with brands they love most, and elevate fans’ relationships with those brands.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cardless’ customized rewards programs are catered to very specific demographics “that actually truly appreciate the value that that brand is providing,” Spelfogel added. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Our first programs helped fans get things like players’ autographs and experiences that money can’t buy,” he said.  The company plans to announce “several” more programs this year and says that it’s able to do so “in a matter of weeks” compared to traditional issuers, which can take months or more than a year to issue similar programs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those reward programs include digital apps and numberless, virtual cards.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2176845" style="width: 541px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2176845" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2176845 " src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cardless_founder_photo.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="531" height="354" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cardless_founder_photo.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cardless_founder_photo.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cardless_founder_photo.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cardless_founder_photo.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cardless_founder_photo.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Cardless_founder_photo.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 531px) 100vw, 531px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2176845" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Cardless; left to right: Michael Spelfogel, co-founder and president; Scott Kazmierowicz, co-founder and CEO.</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cardless is attempting to shake up a massive market. Consume</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">r credit cards yielded an estimated $150 billion in revenue for traditional banks in 2019, but startups only captured a small fraction of the value. Cardless aims to help brands and tech companies snag a larger piece of the huge market by working with a bank issuer to provide simple card issuance and bespoke digital credit programs for customers of those brands. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This funding round is the result, not the start, of the long-awaited transition to digital-focused card issuing,” said Scott Kazmierowicz, Cardless CEO, in a written statement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cardless is not restricted to working with sports brands.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re committed to supporting the super users of today’s influential brands across a variety of verticals,” said Spelfogel.  “Cardless puts the customer first by eliminating fees and providing responsible products with transparent rates.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andrew Steele of Activant was impressed with Cardless’ </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ability to power and execute &#8220;unique&#8221; credit card programs &#8220;for prestigious and innovative brands&#8221; just two years after launch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Most brands have been restricted from launching innovative credit card programs due to the limitations of incumbent providers,” he added. “It became clear that Cardless can transform and expand one of the largest markets in digital payments, and that we&#8217;re only in the early innings of what&#8217;s possible.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="hbYwrXCsje"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/privacy-com-rebrands-to-lithic-raises-43m-for-virtual-payment-cards/">Privacy.com rebrands to Lithic, raises $43M for virtual payment cards</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Privacy.com rebrands to Lithic, raises $43M for virtual payment cards&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/privacy-com-rebrands-to-lithic-raises-43m-for-virtual-payment-cards/embed/#?secret=hbYwrXCsje" data-secret="hbYwrXCsje" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/cardless-raises-40m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176835</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Castor, a clinical trial process company, raises $45M to create more human-centered research</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/castor-a-clinical-trial-process-company-raises-45m-to-create-more-human-centered-research/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/castor-a-clinical-trial-process-company-raises-45m-to-create-more-human-centered-research/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 11:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Castor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clinical trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Derk Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eight Roads Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F-prime Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inkef capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Treskow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science 37]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[two sigma ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world health organization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2176974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Castor is on a mission to make every clinical trial faster and patient-focused.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.castoredc.com/">Castor</a> is on a mission to make every clinical trial faster and patient-focused. The clinical trial software company announced Wednesday it raised $45 million in Series B funding to continue modernizing the process as the industry shifts to decentralized clinical trials.</p>
<p>Eight Roads Ventures and F-Prime Capital co-led the round and were joined by existing investors Two Sigma Ventures and Inkef Capital. The Series B brings Castor’s total funding to $65 million since it was founded in 2012.</p>
<p>Clinical trials are “stuck in a rut,” Derk Arts, M.D., co-founder and CEO of Castor told TechCrunch. Currently, they take a long time to set up and don’t involve continuous data monitoring.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>They also require patient participants to travel to a research site that could be hours away from their home. As a result, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26011295/">slow enrollment</a> accounts for nearly 40% of terminated trials, and an inconvenient process inhibits researchers from attracting a diverse group of patients, he said.</p>
<p>Castor, which is remote first, but has offices in New York and Amsterdam, is one of several companies bringing technology to a process that is largely still done on paper. Its software provides a self-service version enabling researchers to design studies and integrate in-person and remote patient data from any source in real time. Patients interested in joining trials can enroll and share their data via a mobile app.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MNPBa6IdpZ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/8-vcs-agree-behavioral-support-and-remote-visits-make-digital-health-a-strong-bet-for-2021/">8 VCs agree: Behavioral support and remote visits make digital health a strong bet for 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 VCs agree: Behavioral support and remote visits make digital health a strong bet for 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/8-vcs-agree-behavioral-support-and-remote-visits-make-digital-health-a-strong-bet-for-2021/embed/#?secret=MNPBa6IdpZ" data-secret="MNPBa6IdpZ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The global pandemic pushed innovation forward at an accelerated pace, and Castor responded in turn, making its software free for COVID-19 research.</p>
<p>It then saw an influx of users and new customers like the World Health Organization. WHO used Castor for its “Solidarity Trial,” which was identifying how existing medications might improve outcomes compared to standard of care alone. The study included over 10,000 patients across 553 sites in 30 countries, Arts said.</p>
<p>Michael Treskow, partner at Eight Roads Ventures, called Arts “a straight shooter” who knows the industry’s pain points and is bringing the clinical trials industry into the modern age.</p>
<p>“Technology is making a real impact,” Treskow added. “Castor is so driven to dramatically improve clinical trials, and with its work with WHO has a significant use case of how this is important. As we have seen with the rapid development of COVID vaccines, this is what the industry is able to do.”</p>
<p>The clinical trial market is valued at around $16 billion and is growing rapidly at 16% per year, Arts says. A market that big is also attracting companies that want to innovate it. He cites Science 37 and Medable, which recently pulled in a <a href="https://news.crunchbase.com/news/medable-secures-78m-series-c-extension/">$78 million extension</a> to its $91 million Series C.</p>
<p>The Series B enables Castor to have teams in place to respond to the fast-growing industry. Last year, the company nearly tripled in revenue growth and is on course to do the same in 2021. Castor has 150 employees currently and expects to hit 200 by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Arts, who has a background in software programming and in medicine, said the new funds will go toward continued product development, interoperability and collecting real-world evidence from decentralized trials. The company is focusing on the United States for now, but sees potential in moving into the Asia region later this year.</p>
<p>“Patients deserve to have an amazing service, and it is up to us to deliver on that,” he said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fn6TASB8YV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/">4G Clinical&#8217;s clinical trial management software attracts over $200M in new funding</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;4G Clinical&#8217;s clinical trial management software attracts over $200M in new funding&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/4g-clinicals-clinical-trial-management-software-attracts-over-200m-in-new-funding/embed/#?secret=fn6TASB8YV" data-secret="fn6TASB8YV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/castor-a-clinical-trial-process-company-raises-45m-to-create-more-human-centered-research/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2176974</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>YuLife nabs $70M at a $346M valuation for its gamified, wellness-oriented approach to life insurance</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/yulife-nabs-70m-at-a-346m-valuation-for-its-gamified-wellness-oriented-approach-to-life-insurance/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/yulife-nabs-70m-at-a-346m-valuation-for-its-gamified-wellness-oriented-approach-to-life-insurance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 11:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life insurance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Life insurance &#8212; financial protection you buy against your death &#8212; may not read like the liveliest of industries on paper. But a life insurance startup that believes it can turn that stigma around, by infusing the concept with gamification and a push towards wellness and health &#8212; and change the life insurance industry in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Life insurance &#8212; financial protection you buy against your death &#8212; may not read like the liveliest of industries on paper. But a life insurance startup that believes it can turn that stigma around, by infusing the concept with gamification and a push towards wellness and health &#8212; and change the life insurance industry in the process &#8212; is today announcing significant funding, a sign of the traction it&#8217;s getting for its big ideas.</p>
<p><a href="https://yulife.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YuLife</a>, a London startup that has built a new kind of life insurance concept &#8212; it incentivizes and rewards users to focus on their physical and mental health through a gamified interface &#8212; has raised $70 million in what is, to date, one of the largest Series B&#8217;s raised by an insurtech startup in Europe.</p>
<p>Led by Target Global, the round also included Eurazeo, Latitude and previous backers Creandum, Notion Capital, Anthemis, MMC Ventures, and OurCrowd. Sammy Rubin, YuLife&#8217;s CEO and founder, confirmed that the round values YuLife at $346 million (£250 million).</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company will be using the funding to continue expanding its business, build more products on its platform, and importantly continue to invest in the technology that it uses to run its service and determine how its policies should run.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our insurance is about helping people live healthier and longer lives,&#8221; Rubin said in an interview. &#8220;If we can help to reduce claims while incentivizing people to do that, it&#8217;s a win-win.&#8221; But it&#8217;s about more than that, he added. &#8220;We are building a new type of risk model where we are able to create new actuarial tables, which have not been updated in 200 years. Actually, I think smoker rates and how they&#8217;ve changed was the last update. So, most will just look at your age and whether you are a smoker and that’s it.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">YuLife is currently active only in the UK and is only sold directly to organizations, who in turn provide it to their employees. That business currently &#8212; which also includes income protection and critical illness cover &#8212; provides $15 billion of coverage and has seen 10x growth in the last year &#8212; a bumper one for life insurance policies, possibly for the worst reasons (hello, pandemic; goodbye, predicting what the future might look like). Customers include Capital One, Co-op, Curve, Havas Media, Severn Trent, and Sodexo.</span></p>
<p>That $15 billion is just a drop in the bucket in an industry that is currently <a href="https://www.swissre.com/institute/research/sigma-research/World-insurance-series.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">estimated</a> to be worth some $2.2 trillion.</p>
<p>The company got its start on the back of a persistent problem that Rubin experienced at his previous insurance startup PruProtect (which is now called Vitality Life).</p>
<p>&#8220;Usually insurance benefits just sit on shelf and never get used,&#8221; he said. YuLife set out to change that by making the policy &#8220;all about engagement.&#8221;</p>
<p>The app &#8212; built by veterans of the gaming industry &#8212; is designed around the concept of different environments, currently covering forest, ocean, desert and mountains, which YuLife collectively terms its &#8220;Yuniverse.&#8221; (This incidentally also became a template for the company&#8217;s HQ design in London.)</p>
<p>Within each of these environments, users are encouraged to walk, cycle, meditate and do other activities to get around their environments in a healthy way, while at the same time being able to compare their progress against other co-workers. There is a degree of personalization in everyone&#8217;s experience, in that one person leaning into one activity over another seems to produce different subsequent scenarios.</p>
<p>Along with this, users are offered discounts on third-party products to further engage with the game within YuLife, which could include a subscription to meditation app Calm, FitBit and Garmin devices, and more.</p>
<p>As users make their ways through their worlds, they get rewards, in the form of something called YuCoins. The YuCoins can in turn be used to redeem vouchers from the likes of Amazon and Asos to buy things&#8230; consumerism being another way to improve happiness for some of us.</p>
<p>All of this sums up as more than just a policy aimed at giving people peace of mind for their families should they depart this world.</p>
<p>&#8220;Long term, it&#8217;s not just about health, it’s about lifestyle,&#8221; Rubin said.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also about YuLife&#8217;s business: the various products that it offers are built around an affiliate model, so there is a business interest for the company around offering and seeing items purchased and redeemed. However, this is not essential to using the app as a policy holder.</p>
<p>The win-win theme runs strong, but so too does the fact that YuLife is taking a different approach altogether, in an industry where most of the &#8220;disruption&#8221; has up to now been more about how to buy life insurance, rather than reassessing what life insurance actually is. For others in the space doing just that, see <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/27/deadhappy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DeadHappy</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/07/bima-nabs-30m-more-for-micro-health-and-life-insurance-aimed-at-emerging-markets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BIMA</a>, and the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/30/the-jay-z-backed-life-insurance-startup-ethos-has-raised-35-million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jay-Z</a> backed <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-11/life-insurance-startup-ethos-valued-at-more-than-2-billion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ethos</a>. That being said, it&#8217;s also not the only one tackling &#8220;lifestyle&#8221; as part of life insurance: <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/sproutt-launches-uses-data-and-ai-to-finally-reward-life-insurance-customers-who-live-healthy-300973985.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sproutt</a> is another rethinking that area as well.</p>
<p>“YuLife is redefining life insurance, using the most innovative technologies to transform a largely traditional industry,” said Ben Kaminski, partner, Target Global, in a statement. “With health and wellbeing increasingly thrust into the limelight in the wake of Covid-19, YuLife is fundamentally changing insurance by incentivizing people to lead healthier lifestyles. YuLife is ideally positioned to build on its tenfold growth during the pandemic and lead the way in helping its clients respond to the challenges posed by an ever-changing working environment. We are very proud to partner with YuLife on its journey of becoming a global leader in life insurance.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/yulife-nabs-70m-at-a-346m-valuation-for-its-gamified-wellness-oriented-approach-to-life-insurance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177353</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Next Gen Foods to launch its plant-based chicken in the U.S. after raising a $20M seed extension from investors like GGV</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/next-gen-foods-to-launch-its-plant-based-chicken-in-the-u-s-after-raising-a-20m-seed-extension-from-investors-like-ggv/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/next-gen-foods-to-launch-its-plant-based-chicken-in-the-u-s-after-raising-a-20m-seed-extension-from-investors-like-ggv/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catherine Shu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 09:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat substitutes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plant-based meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TiNDLE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Singapore-based Next Gen Foods will bring its plant-based chicken alternative to the United States after raising a $20 million seed extension. Investors included GGV Capital, agriculture and food tech-focused Bits x Bites, food and beverage company Yeo Hiap Seng, entrepreneur and “Blitzscaling” author Chris Yeh and English footballer Dele Alli. Returning investors include Temasek, which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Singapore-based <a href="https://nextgenfoods.sg/">Next Gen Foods</a> will bring its plant-based chicken alternative to the United States after raising a $20 million seed extension. Investors included GGV Capital, agriculture and food tech-focused Bits x Bites, food and beverage company Yeo Hiap Seng, entrepreneur and “Blitzscaling” author Chris Yeh and English footballer Dele Alli.</p>
<p class="p1">Returning investors include Temasek, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/plant-based-food-startup-next-gen-lands-10m-seed-round-from-investors-including-temasek/">led Next Gen Foods’ original $10 million seed round</a>, announced in February, and K3 Ventures. The first $10 million was already the largest seed funding ever raised by a plant-based food tech company, based on data from Pitchbook, and now the round totals $30 million. Part of the funding will be used to fill 50 roles in the U.S. for its research and development, sales, supply chain and finance and marketing teams.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Next Gen also announced changes to its leadership team. Co-founder Timo Recker is moving from his chief executive officer position to chairman, while Andre Menezes, another founder, will take over the CEO spot. Former Temasek director Rohit Bhattacharya will join the startup as its chief financial officer.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9Nzy0ulPyz"><p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/plant-based-food-startup-next-gen-lands-10m-seed-round-from-investors-including-temasek/">Plant-based food startup Next Gen lands $10M seed round from investors including Temasek</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Plant-based food startup Next Gen lands $10M seed round from investors including Temasek&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/24/plant-based-food-startup-next-gen-lands-10m-seed-round-from-investors-including-temasek/embed/#?secret=9Nzy0ulPyz" data-secret="9Nzy0ulPyz" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p class="p1">Next Gen’s chicken alternative, called TiNDLE, launched in Asia through partnerships with restaurants and is now served in more than 70 locations in Singapore, Hong Kong and Macau. Over the next 12 months, Next Gen will take a similar approach as it enters the U.S., working with food services in cities to develop TiNDLE dishes for their menus. Eventually it will expand to other distribution channels, like retail, Menezes told TechCrunch.</p>
<p class="p1">To replicate chicken meat’s texture, Next Gen uses a proprietary blend of plant-based fats, including sunflower oils, and natural flavors. This allows TiNDLE products to replicate the aroma and browning of chicken when it cooks.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In the U.S., Next Gen faces rivalry from plant-based food companies like Beyond Meat, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/08/beyond-meat-launches-plant-based-chicken-tenders-at-us-restaurants/">launched its Chicken Tenders product</a> at about 400 restaurants earlier this week. Panda Express, a popular food chain, is also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/13/panda-express-is-piloting-beyond-meat-orange-chicken-in-select-locations/">piloting Beyond Meat orange chicken</a>.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">When asked about the competitive landscape, Menezes said, “We are really glad this sector is gaining traction and we do not see other plant-based companies as our competitors. The only competition we worry about are the companies bringing unsatisfactory products to consumers. Consumers may end up having the wrong impression that plant-based foods compromise in taste and experience even today.”<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">He added that TiNDLE is GMO and cholesterol-free, and Next Gen has an asset-light business model that will make it easier to scale into new markets.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Before launching Next Gen, Recker founded German-based LikeMeat, while Menezes worked at one of the world’s largest poultry exporters before serving as general manager of Singapore food distributor Country Foods.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In a statement, GGV managing partner Jenny Lee said, “The Next Gen team has one of the strongest founder-market fits in foodtech, having previously developed and successfully launched a plant-based meat product for the European market. The team’s focus on product quality, brand recall and distribution provides a strong foundation for the future growth of the company.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/next-gen-foods-to-launch-its-plant-based-chicken-in-the-u-s-after-raising-a-20m-seed-extension-from-investors-like-ggv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Railsbank raises $70M to build out its fintech-as-a-service platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/railsbank-raises-70m-to-build-out-its-fintech-as-a-service-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/railsbank-raises-70m-to-build-out-its-fintech-as-a-service-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 09:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banking-as-a-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fintech as a service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Railsbank]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Financial services-as-a-service &#8212; where entities like neobanks, retailers and others can create and sell their own financial products by way of a few lines of code and APIs &#8212; has been one of the bigger trends in the world of fintech in recent years, with embedded finance on its way to being a $7.2 trillion [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Financial services-as-a-service &#8212; where entities like neobanks, retailers and others can create and sell their own financial products by way of a few lines of code and APIs &#8212; has been one of the bigger trends in the world of fintech in recent years, with embedded finance on its way to being a $7.2 trillion market by 2030, according to <a href="https://medium.com/ideas-from-bain-capital-ventures/fintech-the-fourth-platform-part-two-78952feabd97" target="_blank" rel="noopener">forecast</a> from Bain Capital. Now, one of the companies building and providing those APIs is announcing some growth funding to expand.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.railsbank.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Railsbank</a>, which builds APIs for banking, payment cards and credit products for use by fintechs but also a wide range of other kinds of businesses, has raised $70 million in new equity funding, money that the London startup plans to use to continue growing internationally and to add more features to its product set.</p>
<p>“Our mission is to reinvent, unbundle and democratise access to the complex, opaque and byzantine 70-year-old credit card market, which is worth $4 trillion in the U.S. alone,&#8221; Nigel Verdon, CEO and co-founder of Railsbank, told TechCrunch in an interview <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/railsbank-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last year</a>. Verdon is a repeat entrepreneur, with one of his previous companies being Currency Cloud.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Railsbank not disclosing its valuation, but Verdon hints that it is in the high hundreds of millions and close to $1 billion.</p>
<p>&#8220;As a policy, we rarely talk about valuation as we prefer to talk about customers,&#8221; he told TechCrunch today. &#8220;Valuation is a very inward facing and self centered metric. Saying that, near unicorn would best describe us today.”<u></u><u></u></p>
<p>As a point of comparison <a href="https://my.pitchbook.com/profile/167998-06/company/profile#deal-history" target="_blank" rel="noopener">data from Pitchbook</a> noted that the company was valued at just under $200 million in its last round at the end of last year (we <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/12/railsbank-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported on it here</a>).</p>
<p>This latest round is being led by Anthos Capital, a previous backer of the company, with Central Capital, Cohen and Company, and Chris Adelsbach’s fund Outrun Ventures, as well as other unnamed previous backers also participating. Central Capital is a strategic investor: it&#8217;s the VC arm of the largest privately held bank in Indonesia, while Cohen and Company is the founder of Bancorp. Those backers speak to where Railsbank is targeting its services and who is interested in potentially working with it.</p>
<p>Banking-as-a-service, and other financial products-as-a-service, has become one of the most significant building blocks not just in the world of fintech, but in financial services overall. As with Twilio or Sinch in communications, or Stripe in payments, the idea here is that financial specialists have built out the complicated infrastructure and partnerships that underpin a product like a credit card, or a banking account.</p>
<p>This is then packaged up in a service that can be integrated into another one by way of an API, and the small amount of code needed to add it to another platform. In turn, that API can be used not just by another financial services company that is consumer- or business-facing, but by any kind of company that sees offering a financial product as part of a bigger customer service and loyalty play. That could mean a retailer offering its own-brand credit card, but also a &#8220;neobank&#8221; that is building a slick front end with great customer service and personalization, without needing to build the now-commoditized banking infrastructure underneath it to run it.</p>
<p>Railsbank is far from being the only company that has identified and built around this concept. Other big players include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/rapyd-raises-300m-on-a-2-5b-valuation-to-boost-its-fintech-as-a-service-api/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rapyd</a>, which raised a big round at a $2.5 billion valuation earlier this year; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/unit-raises-51m-in-accel-led-series-b-to-grow-its-banking-as-a-service-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit</a>, which also has been picking up funding and growing; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/fintechos-nabs-61-5m-for-a-low-code-approach-to-modernizing-legacy-banking-and-insurance-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FintechOS</a>, which really does what its name says; and the startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/10x-a-uk-fintech-raises-187m-to-build-new-services-for-old-banks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">10x</a> was even built for incumbent players to also have access to lighter fintech-as-a-service.</p>
<p>Railsbank believes its distinct from many of its would-be competitors in part because it has built a lot of its own infrastructure from the ground up (hence the &#8220;rails&#8221; in its name), &#8220;bypassing&#8221; legacy players, in contrast to others that are built as software that still ultimately runs on top of stacks (and inefficiencies) of those older providers. This also means that it is regulated as a financial institution.</p>
<p>Railsbank is also in the business of making some acquisitions in order to grow its business, for example <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/28/railsbank-wirecard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">acquiring the UK business of German fintech Wirecard</a> when it was crashing due to financial malpractices. And it doesn&#8217;t build everything from scratch: earlier this year it also <a href="https://plaid.com/blog/partnering-with-railsbank-to-power-the-next-generation-of-financial-needs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">partnered with Plaid</a> to embed some of its services within Railsbank&#8217;s.</p>
<p>Railsbank does not disclose a full list of customer names but has case studies on a number of smaller clients that speak to just how widely proliferated financial services are today. They include <a href="https://railsbank.medium.com/get-to-know-our-customer-gosolo-4b8439d9c753?source=user_profile---------4----------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GoSolo</a>, <a href="https://railsbank.medium.com/get-to-know-our-customer-kyshi-fc3ba3f2a4f3?source=user_profile---------6----------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kyshi</a>, and <a href="https://railsbank.medium.com/get-to-know-out-customer-simpledcard-5cb0d65c074c?source=user_profile---------8----------------------------" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SimpledCard</a>.</p>
<p>“The market has evolved so rapidly since we founded the world’s first BaaS business, the Bancorp,&#8221; noted Betsy Cohen, chairman of Fintech Masala and founder of Bancorp, in a statement. &#8220;As we move into the $7 trillion embedded finance market, it has been great watching Railsbank&#8217;s growth story. With this investment, it&#8217;s a privilege to continue to be part of the journey with a global leader like Railsbank.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/railsbank-raises-70m-to-build-out-its-fintech-as-a-service-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177325</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anyone is building a marketplace for advice, one 5-minute call at a time</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/anyone-is-building-a-marketplace-for-advice-one-5-minute-call-at-a-time/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/anyone-is-building-a-marketplace-for-advice-one-5-minute-call-at-a-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 09:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anyone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cavalry Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[closed social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supernode Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweden]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2175010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone, an audio app that&#8217;s building a &#8216;marketplace for advice&#8217; one five-minute phone call at a time, is launching new versions of its iOS and Android apps today* and beginning to large-scale onboarding after operating in a limited closed beta for the past six months. The app &#8212; which was founded around 18 months ago [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://anyo.ne">Anyone</a>, an audio app that&#8217;s building a &#8216;marketplace for advice&#8217; one five-minute phone call at a time, is launching new versions of its <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/anyone/id1492481733">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.anyonemobile&amp;gl=ES">Android</a> apps today* and beginning to large-scale onboarding after operating in a limited closed beta for the past six months.</p>
<p>The app &#8212; which was founded around 18 months ago (so pre-pandemic) &#8212; has a simple premise: Advice is best delivered verbally, concisely and one-to-one, in a time-limited format.</p>
<p>Video is distracting and a hassle to fit into busy people&#8217;s schedules. Text is time-consuming and prone to misunderstandings. But a simple phone call can &#8212; quickly and usefully &#8212; cut through, is the thinking here.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Hence the decision to hard-stop at a five-minute phone call. The app automatically terminates each call at the five minute mark &#8212; no ifs, no buts (and, well, hopefully fewer time-nibbling &#8216;ums&#8217; and &#8216;ahs&#8217; too).</p>
<p>To fund development of the marketplace, the team has raised around $4 million in total to date &#8212; mainly comprised of a $3.6M seed round led by Berlin-based Cavalry Ventures with participation from Supernode Global, Antler and a number of high-profile angel investors (contributing angels include Atomico&#8217;s Sarah Drinkwater and Sameer Singh<em>; </em>and ustwo&#8217;s Matt &#8216;Mills&#8217; Miller, among others).</p>
<p>Broadly speaking, online audio has shown its staying power through a sustained <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/apple-podcasts-subscriptions-go-live-worldwide/">podcast boom</a> and, more recently, a buzzy moment for social audio, via developments like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/clubhouse/">Clubhouse</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/11/twitter-spaces-to-launch-publicly-next-month-may-include-spaces-only-tweets/">Twitter Spaces</a> &#8212; which speak to a general sense of pandemic-struck &#8216;Zoom fatigue&#8217; as remote workers max out on video calls at work yet still crave meaningful connections with other people at a time when opportunities to mingle in person are still limited vs pre-COVID-19.</p>
<p>A lot of social audio can still be very noisy, though, and Anyone wants to be anything but. This is short-form, topic-specific audio.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0PzPTele5A"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/clubhouse/">Clubhouse closes an undisclosed $4B valuation Series C round, as tech giants&#8217; clones circle</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Clubhouse closes an undisclosed $4B valuation Series C round, as tech giants&#8217; clones circle&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/clubhouse/embed/#?secret=0PzPTele5A" data-secret="0PzPTele5A" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Why five minutes? It&#8217;s short enough for a busy person to <em>almost not have to think twice</em> about taking a cold call from someone they&#8217;ve probably never spoken to before &#8212; while being just about long enough that some useful advice can be distilled and imparted across those 300 seconds of one-to-one connection.</p>
<p>Naturally the short format does not allow for group/conference calls. It&#8217;s one-to-one only.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Anyone&#8217;s CEO also reckons this &#8220;intimate&#8221;, short-form audio</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> format could help drive diversity of advice by encouraging people whose voices may be underrepresented in traditional mentorship fora to feel more comfortable offering their time and knowledge to others. (He touts a current 50:50 user-split between men and women offering expertise through the app &#8212; and 25% people of color.)</span></p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not about taking long form meetings and compressing them &#8212; it&#8217;s about taking those conversations that would never have happened&#8230; and making them happen,&#8221; says CEO and co-founder David Orlic, pointing out that mainstream calendar apps have a default meeting slot that&#8217;s set to half an hour or an hour. So the wider thesis is that our current tools/infrastructure just aren&#8217;t set up to help people give and grab bitesized advice. (And, well, on the Internet anyone can claim to be an expert &#8212; but of course you can&#8217;t rely on the quality of the &#8216;advice&#8217; you find freely floating around online.)</p>
<p>&#8220;Our belief is that there are a lot of five minute problems that we could be solving &#8212; whereas there are a lot of 30 or 60 minute problems that have solutions designed for them already. So we&#8217;re kind of building this for those conversations that aren&#8217;t happening,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Orlic hints that the intention is also to leave Anyone&#8217;s callers a little hungry for more &#8212; to feed demand for more five-minute conversations and so fuel transactions across the marketplace.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you look at the demand side &#8212; the callers &#8212; there&#8217;s always multiple calls involved. So people will call a lot of people and ask them basically the same question or bounce ideas. And then they will aggregate those insights into something that&#8217;s much more valuable than one conversation,&#8221; he continues. &#8220;So it&#8217;s like building an advisory board for yourself.&#8221;</p>
<p>The idea for the platform came after Orlic and his co-founders realized they could trace key career decisions to a handful of short conversations &#8212; brief moments of advice that ended up profoundly influencing the trajectory of their working lives, to the point where they were still looking back on them years later.</p>
<p>&#8220;None of us in the founding team had any networks to speak of when we were growing up. And we had fairly little exposure to opportunity. Alfred is from a small village in the middle of nowhere in Sweden, I grew up in an immigrant family, and Sam is a working class bloke from Leeds. And looking back at our careers we could track them back to this handful of conversations &#8212; these haphazard moments when someone gave us a piece of critical advice,&#8221; he tells TechCrunch. &#8220;For them it was just another five minute chat but for us it turned out to be life-changing.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;For Alfred it was some quick advice on how he could land a job at Google which he managed to do and spent almost a decade there working as a growth guy on Google Chrome and other stuff; for Sam it was how to start a company; for me it was the suggestion that I as a creative should pursue an MBA &#8212; which I ended up doing. So we started thinking long and hard about the concept of advice, and we became obsessed with opening up these closed networks.&#8221;</p>
<p>The aim for Anyone&#8217;s marketplace is to make similarly pivotal moments accessible to all sorts of people &#8212; by giving the app&#8217;s users the chance to call any expertise provider on the network (provided they can afford the fee) and ask their question.</p>
<p>A slogan on its website poses the question &#8220;imagine if you could call anyone in the world&#8221; &#8212; which is certainly a poetic-sounding moonshot to be shooting for, although the size of the user-base remains far off that global vision at this early stage.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re building is really the phone book of the future,&#8221; says Orlic, slotting his elevator pitch into our ~30-minute phone conversation. &#8220;We&#8217;re building a place for unique, one-to-one, five minute experiences &#8212; which is something really different from most social audio plays.&#8221;</p>
<p>He points to a trend of other apps intentionally applying limits to change/define the user experience in behavior-shaping ways (like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/poparazzi-hypes-itself-to-the-top-of-the-app-store/">Poparazzi</a>, a self-styled &#8216;anti-Instagram&#8217; photo sharing app that doesn&#8217;t let you take selfies to make you take more pics of your friends and vice versa; or the dating app <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/28/thursday-snags-3-5m-for-a-dating-app-thats-live-once-a-week/">Thursday</a> which limits users to one active day of use per week to prevent endless swiping and nudge matches toward going on an actual in-person date).</p>
<p>The marketplace component of Anyone&#8217;s app is another intentional limit too, of course. Calls are not free by default.</p>
<p>Putting a price on Anyone&#8217;s one-to-one advice is one way to try to weed out unserious (or indeed abusive) users from those genuinely seeking others&#8217; expertise on specific topics.</p>
<p>But primarily it&#8217;s there to provide an incentivize for people who have expertise worth sharing to make themselves available to take cold-calls (even very short ones) from strangers/those outside their existing contact networks.</p>
<p>Pricing for a five-minute call is set by Anyone users. So the call fee can vary from nothing at all (if the user distributes a free voucher code) to as little as $5 or all the way up to $500 (!) which does sound pretty crazy expensive. But Orlic notes users can choose to donate their fee to a charity if they do not wish to financially benefit from the advice they&#8217;re dishing out (so there may be instances where a high fee includes a philanthropic component).</p>
<p>With such highly variable fees, the app will need to have a good safety mechanism to re-confirm a user really does want to be charged the specific fee. (And, god forbid, to avoid the risk of butt-dialling&#8230; <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f62c.png" alt="😬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />)</p>
<p>&#8220;If you want to connect with someone I think it&#8217;s reasonable to put a cost on the scarcest resource on the planet which is someone&#8217;s undivided attention,&#8221; Orlic argues, suggesting that plenty of mainstream tech confuses transient &#8216;access&#8217; with attention. &#8220;We can &#8216;access&#8217; people everywhere &#8212; we can listen to them, read them, follow them. But that&#8217;s not the same as attention&#8230; Someone&#8217;s undivided attention is a remarkable, remarkable thing. And the five-minute cap forces you to be very clear and to the point about what you want to chat about.&#8221;</p>
<p>With its intentionally attention-slicing infrastructure &#8212; which manages ephemeral contacts into precisely measured and billed units &#8212; &#8220;all of a sudden you have all of these conversations that wouldn&#8217;t have happened happening thanks to this manageable way of connecting with people&#8221;, is the claim.<span style="letter-spacing: -0.1px; font-size: 1rem;"> </span></p>
<p>Anyone users wanting to list themselves on the marketplace to sell one-to-one advice will need to create a profile that specifies their availability to take calls and some basic details (name, career details, location etc), as well as setting their five minute fee.</p>
<p>They also need to provide details of the &#8220;conversation topics&#8221; they&#8217;re comfortable giving advice on.</p>
<p>Co-founder Alfred Malmros&#8217; profile includes examples such as: &#8220;Make the leap. Quitting a dream job to make it on your own&#8221;; &#8220;Rising quickly in a large organisation &#8212; politics vs. talent&#8221;; and &#8220;It takes a fool to remain sane. Thriving as an employee&#8221; &#8212; so topic steerage looks intended to be not only specific but maybe also give a flavor of the individual&#8217;s personality to further help advice-seekers decide if they want to shell out for five minutes of that particular person&#8217;s time.</p>
<p>The risk of imposters or low quality advice is being managed by &#8220;vetting and verification&#8221; processing all advisors have to go through prior to being able to sell, per Orlic. &#8220;Beyond verification, we put a lot of work into making sure that everyone on Anyone understands what constitutes good advice, how to avoid projection and biases in conversations, etc,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>The platform also incorporates a rating system &#8212; again, in an attempt to keep quality up across the marketplace.</p>
<p>Anyone&#8217;s early users are a blend of creators, founders and investors, per Orlic &#8212; including a lot of first and second time founders, as you might expect, with the pandemic having limited in-person startup networking opportunities.</p>
<p>He also says they&#8217;ve attracted a lot of people mid career, looking for advice on how to quit their jobs and pivot into something totally new &#8212; again, likely fuelled by the pandemic reconfiguring many things around how we work (and, more broadly, how we may be thinking about work-life balance).</p>
<p>&#8220;When you&#8217;re doing that kind of big life decision you really want to connect with a lot of people and ask around,&#8221; he suggests on the interest from established professionals looking for advice on a career switch. &#8220;Also there&#8217;s a high willingness to pay, I&#8217;d argue, when you&#8217;re in that position.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Business is a huge thing as a marketplace for advice,&#8221; Orlic adds, noting that a record number of businesses started in the last year too. &#8220;Investors &#8212; by the way &#8212; love this for deal flow because they can speed date a lot of founders and then pick who they continue with.&#8221;</p>
<p>Parents are another community of early users he highlights &#8212; saying they&#8217;ve been both offering and soliciting advice during the early test phase. He says one of the best pieces of advice he&#8217;s personally gained through the network was a conversation about parenting, adding: &#8220;I&#8217;ve had some really profound conversations with other dads. People that know a lot more about parenting than I do &#8212; where I&#8217;ve gotten really actionable advice and support. So that has been a big thing for me personally.&#8221;</p>
<p>Orlic also says he&#8217;s excited about potential in the area of mental health &#8212; suggesting the short-form format could be helpful to get people to have conversations about therapy which, since they&#8217;re so bitesized and bounded, may be a non-intimidating introduction toward taking up more sustained support.</p>
<p>He also mentions that he&#8217;s excited about the potential for civic society to make use of the platform as a tool for driving public engagement and awareness around issues and campaigns.</p>
<p>Appropriately enough, Anyone&#8217;s team has been dogfooding by using the app to get advice to help build the startup. (Orlic admits he asked someone on the network how to get TechCrunch&#8217;s attention and was advised, by the unnamed investor, to pitch this reporter &#8212; so it sounds like he got some solid advice there ;)</p>
<p>The app has had around 1,000 test users during the closed beta period &#8212; with some 12,000 on the wait-list that Orlic says they&#8217;ll be onboarding over the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Network building &#8212; so growing the size of the user-base on both the expertise and demand sides &#8212; is clearly going to be a key challenge here. (And notably Orlic emphases the <a href="https://course.breadcrumb.vc">network effects expertise</a> of its angel backer, Singh.)</p>
<p>Anyone&#8217;s five-minute format may be bitesize enough to encourage users to spread the word of any good experiences they have on the platform to their (wider) social graphs on mainstream social networks. Although the calls themselves must surely remain private between the two interlocutors &#8212; so there are some hard limits on the app content being able to go viral.</p>
<p>(At the time of writing, a link to Anyone&#8217;s privacy policy wasn&#8217;t working so we asked for a confirm on the privacy of calls &#8212; and Orlic told us: &#8220;All calls on the new app are completely e2e encrypted, and there’s no way to listen in on an ongoing conversation. For user safety, calls are recorded, anonymised and stored in a secure environment for maximum 30 days. So in case a user reports a specific call in the app and wants a refund, or if an advisor flags up harassment or other serious issues, we can deal with that in a sustainable way.&#8221;)</p>
<p>At the same time it&#8217;s not hard to imagine a platform like Twitter (or, indeed, LinkedIn) seeing value in offering a similar one-to-one user call capability &#8212; and bolting it on as a feature on an established network where users have already built up extensive social graphs. So If Anyone&#8217;s idea really takes off the risk of cloning could get very real &#8212; which means it will have to balance network building/growth with attention to the quality of the community it&#8217;s building and innovating to keep its users happily stuck to its own (inevitably smaller) network.</p>
<p>Commenting on backing the app in a statement, Claude Ritter, managing partner at Cavalry Ventures, said: “What sets Anyone apart from other audio apps is the quality and connection of 1:1 advice. The team saw the potential of audio and the emergence of the creator economy long before the hype. We’re impressed by what they’ve accomplished to date and by their mission to build the phone book of the future.”</p>
<p>Around 9,000 five-minute calls have been made via Anyone&#8217;s platform so far, per Orlic &#8212; who says the goal they&#8217;re shooting for as they open up access now is to get to 100,000 calls within a year.</p>
<p>The business model for now is to take a straightforward 20% cut of the advice fee.</p>
<p>On the fee side there&#8217;s also potential for things to get bumpy if momentum builds around the concept &#8212; given that platform giants have been known to take a predatory approach to pricing when trying to close down creator-supporting upstart competition via their own fast-following clones. (See, for example, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/facebooks-newsletter-platform-bulletin-is-now-live/">Facebook&#8217;s recent dive into offering a newsletter platform</a> &#8212; for which it&#8217;s both paying writers upfront for contributions and, at least initially, not taking any cut of their subscriptions.)</p>
<p>It&#8217;s clear that Anyone will need to pay particular attention to the quality of the advice and community it&#8217;s building. It may even end up needing to hone in on serving particular niches and specialisms in order to leverage differentiation vs larger more generalist networks which have the advantage of larger user-bases should they decide to move in on the same &#8216;quick call&#8217; turf.</p>
<p>At the same time, there are signs that some of the buzz around social audio may be fading away to more of a hmm as the hype dies down and app users tire of all the noise. But again, that&#8217;s why Anyone keeping the audio side intentionally short looks smart.</p>
<p>&#8220;We feel that we are part of a movement that is rebuilding the Internet as we know it and building something that is more sustainable and healthy &#8212; and really creating value,&#8221; says Orlic, discussing the changing landscape around social apps. &#8220;Closed social is a topic that I&#8217;m really excited by. We&#8217;ve seen this for years, with Slack channels and WhatsApp groups. We&#8217;ve seen social closing off because of a tonne of different reasons &#8212; and with <a href="https://geneva.com">Geneva</a> and a lot of new really cool startups and platforms we&#8217;re seeing everything focus around communities. People building communities around specific verticals and then monetizing them in different ways. So we&#8217;re definitely a part of that wave.</p>
<p>&#8220;A lot of our most active users are people who have built audiences around specific topic and want more meaningful connections with those audiences &#8212; the Substack writers that use us as a way to both connect with their existing readers but also gaining new superfans, if you will, because when you&#8217;ve had a five minute chat with someone and then sign up to read their Substack, you will read everything they write after that kind of intro. So we&#8217;re definitely a part of that closed social. But as a business we are a marketplace &#8212; because again we&#8217;re obsessed with that idea of someone&#8217;s undivided attention being a very scarce resource and the fact that we&#8217;re seeing the &#8216;cameo-ification&#8217; of everything and everyone. And that is also here to stay.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Monetization &#8212; in one way &#8212; sounds like a really crass and cynical concept but at the end of the day we want people to build income streams around things they&#8217;re passionate and know a lot about. At the end of the day that is a wonderful, wonderful thing,&#8221; he adds. &#8220;A creator middle class is a very exciting concept because looking at all the big platforms, old social media, we know where the money is going &#8212; it&#8217;s going to the top 0.1% of influencers and creators. Whereas small and mid tier creators are not making money to sustain themselves off their passion. For that you have all of these cohort-based courses through Maven. And platforms like us &#8212; that enable people to connect directly with each other in a one-to-one setting.</p>
<p>&#8220;We think it&#8217;s very cool that we&#8217;re doing an opinionated, one-to-one, five-minutes, audio-only platform because that gives us a unique positioning. And this is what excites the team. Seeing these stories come out of it &#8212; and those stories would not come out of it if it was just another broadcasting or Clubhouse thing.&#8221;</p>
<p>There is of course no small irony that it&#8217;s exactly because of the proliferation of mobile connectivity and apps &#8212; which have driven increased utility by providing people with on-demand access to so much data (and people) &#8212; that the traditional &#8216;quick call&#8217; of old has been derailed, creating conditions where a startup feels there&#8217;s an opportunity to build a dedicated marketplace for scheduled quick phone calls. (Albeit, one that&#8217;s aiming to scale to a far wider network that the average person would have had in their phone book back in the 1980s, say.)</p>
<p>But as software and connectivity keeps eating the world, enforcing tech upgrades and reconfiguring learned behaviors, it&#8217;s clear that the resulting disruption can recreate the right conditions for new tools to come in and repackage some of the old convenience &#8212; which maybe got a bit lost in the noise.</p>
<p><em>*App Store review gods willing</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="30qQnr3OdJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/social-networking-app-for-women-peanut-adds-live-audio-rooms/">Social networking app for women, Peanut, adds live audio rooms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Social networking app for women, Peanut, adds live audio rooms&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/social-networking-app-for-women-peanut-adds-live-audio-rooms/embed/#?secret=30qQnr3OdJ" data-secret="30qQnr3OdJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="KQtLWlJW60"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-confirms-its-working-on-a-clubhouse-rival-too/">LinkedIn confirms it&#8217;s working on a Clubhouse rival, too</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;LinkedIn confirms it&#8217;s working on a Clubhouse rival, too&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/30/linkedin-confirms-its-working-on-a-clubhouse-rival-too/embed/#?secret=KQtLWlJW60" data-secret="KQtLWlJW60" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/anyone-is-building-a-marketplace-for-advice-one-5-minute-call-at-a-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2175010</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian storytelling platform Pratilipi raises $48 million led by gaming giant Krafton</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/indian-storytelling-platform-pratilipi-raises-48-million-led-by-gaming-giant-krafton/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/indian-storytelling-platform-pratilipi-raises-48-million-led-by-gaming-giant-krafton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manish Singh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 08:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Krafton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexus Venture Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pratilipi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pratilipi, an Indian startup that operates an online storytelling platform to enable writers to share their work in various formats, said on Wednesday it has raised $48 million in a new financing round led by Krafton. South Korean gaming giant Krafton led the Series D round for the seven-year-old Bangalore-based startup, bringing its to-date raise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Pratilipi, an Indian startup that operates an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/06/pratilipi-a-youtube-for-writers-storytelling-platform-in-india-raises-15-million/">online storytelling platform to enable writers to share their work</a> in various formats, said on Wednesday it has raised $48 million in a new financing round led by Krafton.</p>
<p>South Korean gaming giant Krafton led the Series D round for the seven-year-old Bangalore-based startup, bringing its to-date raise to $78.8 million.</p>
<p>Existing investor Omidyar Network India as well as scores of high-profile entrepreneurs including Pratilipi chief executive Ranjeet Pratap Singh as well as Unacademy’s Hemesh Singh and Gaurav Munjal, Locus’ Nishith Rastogi, Meesho’s Vidit Aatrey, Udhyam’s Mekin Maheshwari and NoBroker’s Amit Agarwal also participated in the round.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.pratilipi.com">Pratilipi</a> started its journey as an online reading and writing platform where writers shared their stories in several Indian languages. The idea at the time was to create a platform where quality literary work could be hosted and shared in Indian languages, something that only had sparse representation on the web, said Singh, who is a voracious reader of Indian literary work and worked at Vodafone before starting Pratilipi, in an interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The platform has ballooned to become a market leader in the years since. Over 370,000 writers on the platform today share their work in a dozen languages and more than 30 million readers browse Pratilipi each month to read stories.</p>
<p>These writers can choose to share their work with readers for free or charge a subscription fee. But increasingly there’s another avenue for them to monetize their work.</p>
<p>Pratilipi &#8212; which has expanded to book publishing, audio and comics in recent years &#8212; uses proprietary algorithms to identify stories that it believes could be turned into a book or a web series and buys the IP from the writers.</p>
<p>The startup, which late last year acquired local market leading podcast network (IVM Podcasts), has inked several partnerships with industry players including giant on-demand video streaming service MX Player, which carried Pratilipi’s show “<a href="https://www.mxplayer.in/show/watch-midnight-lily-series-online-dee4ace99985ecbbae176456ed973090">Midnight Lily</a>” earlier this year.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have been a part of Pratilipi’s growth story since the early stages,&#8221; said Pratik Poddar, Principal at Nexus Venture Partners, an early backer of Pratilipi, in a statement. &#8220;Over the years, we have witnessed the team’s deep product focus, an obsession to make creators successful, and keen understanding of monetizing content IP which is extensible across different formats.”</p>
<p>Pratilipi’s Singh said the startup will deploy the fresh funding to broaden its partnerships with industry players as well as invest in building in-house publishing stack. With Krafton, which recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/17/battlegrounds-mobile-pubg-returns-to-india/">launched the Battlegrounds Mobile India game</a> in the South Asian country, the startup aims to develop stories that can be incorporated into global gaming franchises.</p>
<p>The demand for original stories has surged in India in recent years and many streaming services and publishing giants are engaging with Pratilipi, he said. “We will continue to work with ecosystem partners and for formats where we already have in-house expertise we will expand on those,” he said.</p>
<p>Pratilipi also plans to use the fresh funds to expand outside of India. A fraction of its users today already live outside the country, said Singh. &#8220;We haven&#8217;t worked on the expansion so far, but now the plan is to actively reach out to creators and readers in other markets,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Wednesday&#8217;s announcement also illustrates Krafton&#8217;s <a href="https://in.ign.com/playerunknowns-battlegrounds-mobile/161501/news/krafton-india-investments-to-extend-beyond-gaming">growing push into the Indian market</a>, where in recent months it has held talks to acquire several gaming studios, according to a person familiar with the matter. In March, the firm <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/08/krafton-pubg-mobile-developer-invests-22-4-million-in-india-nodwin/">led a $22.4 million investment in Nodwin</a> and last month it co-led a $9 million round in Loco.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is exciting to see the growth of Indian local IPs in online literature, comics and audio platform in Pratilipi, which is already the largest player in India in multiple categories,&#8221; said Sean Hyunil Sohn, Head of Krafton&#8217;s India division, in a statement.</p>
<p>&#8220;With Pratilipi already having a multilingual platform for online literature, it is poised to become one of the strongest players in emerging markets in the future. Krafton believes in long term potential of local Indian IPs that can be successful not just in India but globally as well across formats including literature, comics and gaming and our investment in Pratilipi is another step in realising that vision.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/indian-storytelling-platform-pratilipi-raises-48-million-led-by-gaming-giant-krafton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177317</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wecasa raises $17.7 million for its home care and wellness marketplace</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/wecasa-raises-17-7-million-for-its-home-care-and-wellness-marketplace/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/wecasa-raises-17-7-million-for-its-home-care-and-wellness-marketplace/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Romain Dillet]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketplace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wecasa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2177052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[French startup Wecasa has raised a $17.7 million funding round (€15 million). Blisce is leading the funding round with existing investors Serena, ISAI and Frédéric Mazzella also participating. The company has been building a marketplace for home care and wellness. Over the past few years, Wecasa has kept adding new verticals. The startup originally specialized [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">French startup <a href="https://www.wecasa.fr">Wecasa</a> has raised a $17.7 million funding round (€15 million). Blisce is leading the funding round with existing investors Serena, ISAI and Frédéric Mazzella also participating. The company has been building a marketplace for home care and wellness.</p>
<p>Over the past few years, Wecasa has kept adding new verticals. The startup originally specialized in hairdressing at home. It then added massage, beauty treatments, housekeeping, babysitting and sports coaching.</p>
<p>While the company is mostly active in France, it expanded to London in April 2021. Up next, Wecasa expects to launch its service in a couple of new European markets as soon as next year.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>When it comes to metrics, Wecasa expects to generate $23.6 million (€20 million) in revenue this year. That would represent a three-fold increase compared to 2020 revenue. There are 150,000 Wecasa customers and 5,000 registered professionals on the platform.</p>
<p>Like many marketplaces, finding more partners will be key to supporting the company’s growth. Wecasa expects to add another 3,000 professionals by the end of 2021 for instance. There are currently 50 people working for the company and the startup is hiring another 30 employees this year.</p>
<p>This isn’t the only marketplace focused on home care and wellness in France. When it comes to housekeeping, Wecasa competes with Helpling, O2, Shiva and others. When it comes to babysitting, Wecasa competes with Yoojo, Yoopies and others. Some other marketplaces also focus on one-off jobs, such as fixing something that is broken — examples include Lulu dans ma rue and Stootie.</p>
<p>Wecasa has been slowly adding new categories, which is a smart move as it’s easier to make sure you’re working with competent professionals if you don’t have a thousand different verticals. There’s also a huge market opportunity as a lot of recommendations for a baby-sitter or a housekeeper still happen offline — there will be room for multiple marketplaces. And Wecasa now seems to be well positioned to build a strong brand and service across multiple markets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/14/wecasa-raises-17-7-million-for-its-home-care-and-wellness-marketplace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2177052</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
