<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 19:27:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>AI-driven audio cloning startup gives voice to Einstein chatbot</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/ai-driven-audio-cloning-startup-gives-voice-to-einstein-chatbot/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/ai-driven-audio-cloning-startup-gives-voice-to-einstein-chatbot/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 19:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alforithmic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer graphics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[synthesized media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UneeQ]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;ll need to prick up your ears up for this slice of deepfakery emerging from the wacky world of synthesized media: A digital version of Albert Einstein &#8212; with a synthesized voice that&#8217;s been (re)created using AI voice cloning technology drawing on audio recordings of the famous scientist&#8217;s actual voice. &#160; The startup behind the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">You&#8217;ll need to prick up your ears up for this slice of deepfakery emerging from the wacky world of synthesized media: A digital version of Albert Einstein &#8212; with a <a href="https://www.aflorithmic.ai/post/creating-einsteins-voice">synthesized voice</a> that&#8217;s been (re)created using AI voice cloning technology drawing on audio recordings of the famous scientist&#8217;s actual voice.</p>
<p><iframe class='youtube-player' width='640' height='360' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/RiWB2o-9qMs?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;start=1&#038;wmode=transparent' allowfullscreen='true' style='border:0;' sandbox='allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation'></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The startup behind the &#8216;uncanny valley&#8217; audio deepfake of Einstein is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/04/aflorithmic-nabs-1-3m-for-ai-driven-personalized-audio-as-a-service/">Aflorithmic</a> (whose seed round we covered back in February).</p>
<p>While the video engine powering the 3D character rending components of this &#8216;digital human&#8217; version of Einstein is the work of another synthesized media company &#8212; UneeQ &#8212; which is hosting the interactive chatbot version <a href="https://einstein.digitalhumans.com/?_ga=2.154407672.1137264718.1618594174-91366519.1618594174">on its website</a>.</p>
<p>Alforithmic says the &#8216;digital Einstein&#8217; is intended as a showcase for what will soon be possible with conversational social commerce. Which is a fancy way of saying deepfakes that make like historical figures will probably be trying to sell you pizza soon enough, as industry watchers have <a href="https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/european-union-regulating-ai-allowing-the-use-of-deepfakes/">presciently warned</a>.</p>
<p>The startup also says it sees educational potential in bringing famous, long deceased figures to interactive &#8216;life&#8217;.</p>
<p>Or, well, an artificial approximation of it &#8212; the &#8216;life&#8217; being purely virtual and Digital Einstein&#8217;s voice not being a pure tech-powered clone either; Alforithmic says it also worked with an actor to do voice modelling for the chatbot (because how else was it going to get Digital Einstein to be able to say words the real-deal would never even have dreamt of saying &#8212; like, er, &#8216;blockchain&#8217;?). So there&#8217;s a bit more than AI artifice going on here too.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is the next milestone in showcasing the technology to make conversational social commerce possible,&#8221; Alforithmic&#8217;s COO Matt Lehmann told us. &#8220;There are still more than one flaws to iron out as well as tech challenges to overcome but overall we think this is a good way to show where this is moving to.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.aflorithmic.ai/post/creating-einsteins-voice">blog post</a> discussing how it recreated Einstein&#8217;s voice the startup writes about progress it made on one challenging element associated with the chatbot version &#8212; saying it was able to shrink the response time between turning around input text from the computational knowledge engine to its API being able to render a voiced response, down from an initial 12 seconds to less than three (which it dubs &#8220;near-real-time&#8221;). But it&#8217;s still enough of a lag to ensure the bot can&#8217;t escape from being a bit tedious.</p>
<p>Laws that protect people&#8217;s data and/or image, meanwhile, present a legal and/or ethical challenge to creating such &#8216;digital clones&#8217; of living humans &#8212; at least not without asking (and most likely paying) first.</p>
<p>Of course historical figures aren&#8217;t around to ask awkward questions about the ethics of their likeness being appropriated for selling stuff (if only the cloning technology itself, at this nascent stage). Though licensing rights may still apply &#8212; and do in fact in the case of Einstein.</p>
<p>&#8220;His rights lie with the Hebrew University of Jerusalem who is a partner in this project,&#8221; says Lehmann, before &#8216;fessing up to the artist licence element of the Einstein &#8216;voice cloning&#8217; performance. &#8220;In fact, we actually didn&#8217;t clone Einstein&#8217;s voice as such but found inspiration in original recordings as well as in movies. The voice actor who helped us modelling his voice is a huge admirer himself and his performance captivated the character Einstein very well, we thought.&#8221;</p>
<p>Turns out the truth about high-tech &#8216;lies&#8217; is itself a bit of a layer cake. But with deepfakes it&#8217;s not the sophistication of the technology that matters so much as the impact the content has &#8212; and that&#8217;s always going to depend upon context. And however well (or badly) the faking is done, how people respond to what they see and hear can shift the whole narrative &#8212; from a positive story (creative/educational synthesized media) to something deeply negative (alarming, misleading deepfakes).</p>
<p>Concern about the potential for deepfakes to become a tool for disinformation is rising, too, as the tech gets more sophisticated &#8212; helping to drive moves toward regulating AI in Europe, where the two main entities responsible for &#8216;Digital Einstein&#8217; are based.</p>
<p>Earlier this week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/amp/">a leaked draft</a> of an incoming legislative proposal on pan-EU rules for &#8216;high risk&#8217; applications of artificial intelligence included some sections specifically targeted at deepfakes.</p>
<p>Under the plan, lawmakers look set to propose &#8220;harmonised transparency rules&#8221; for AI systems that are designed to interact with humans and those used to generate or manipulate image, audio or video content. So a future Digital Einstein chatbot (or sales pitch) is likely to need to unequivocally declare itself artificial before it starts faking it &#8212; to avoid the need for Internet users to have to apply a virtual <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Umc9ezAyJv0"><em>Voight-Kampff</em> <em>test</em></a>.</p>
<p>For now, though, the erudite-sounding interactive Digital Einstein chatbot still has enough of a lag to give the game away. Its makers are also clearly labelling their creation in the hopes of selling their vision of AI-driven social commerce to other businesses.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2q4ZCxYgHh"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/">EU plan for risk-based AI rules to set fines as high as 4% of global turnover, per leaked draft</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;EU plan for risk-based AI rules to set fines as high as 4% of global turnover, per leaked draft&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/eu-plan-for-risk-based-ai-rules-to-set-fines-as-high-as-4-of-global-turnover-per-leaked-draft/embed/#?secret=2q4ZCxYgHh" data-secret="2q4ZCxYgHh" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aSPsxW5f50"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/04/an-optimistic-view-of-deepfakes/">An optimistic view of deepfakes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;An optimistic view of deepfakes&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/04/an-optimistic-view-of-deepfakes/embed/#?secret=aSPsxW5f50" data-secret="aSPsxW5f50" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/ai-driven-audio-cloning-startup-gives-voice-to-einstein-chatbot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139807</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data scientists: Bring the narrative to the forefront</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/data-scientists-bring-the-narrative-to-the-forefront/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/data-scientists-bring-the-narrative-to-the-forefront/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 18:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Consumer Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter Wang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storytelling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Data alone doesn’t spur innovation — rather, it’s data-driven storytelling that helps uncover hidden trends, powers personalization, and streamlines processes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Peter Wang</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/pwang">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Peter Wang is CEO and co-founder of data science platform <a href="https://anacondacon.io/">Anaconda</a>. He’s also a co-creator of the PyData community and conferences, and a member of the board at the Center for Humane Technology.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">By 2025, 463 exabytes of data will be <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/04/how-much-data-is-generated-each-day-cf4bddf29f/">created</a> each day, according to some estimates. (For perspective, one <a href="https://searchstorage.techtarget.com/definition/exabyte">exabyte</a> of storage could hold 50,000 years of DVD-quality video.) It’s now easier than ever to translate physical and digital actions into data, and businesses of all types have raced to amass as much data as possible in order to gain a competitive edge.</p>
<p>However, in our collective infatuation with data (and obtaining more of it), what’s often overlooked is the role that storytelling plays in extracting real value from data.</p>
<p>The reality is that data by itself is insufficient to really influence human behavior. Whether the goal is to improve a business’ bottom line or <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-03-31/how-to-make-people-stay-home">convince</a> people to stay home amid a pandemic, it’s the narrative that compels action, rather than the numbers alone. As more data is collected and analyzed, communication and storytelling will become even more integral in the data science discipline because of their role in separating the signal from the noise.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Data alone doesn’t spur innovation — rather, it’s data-driven storytelling that helps uncover hidden trends, powers personalization, and streamlines processes.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Yet this can be an area where data scientists struggle. In Anaconda’s <a href="https://www.anaconda.com/state-of-data-science-2020">2020 State of Data Science survey</a> of more than 2,300 data scientists, nearly a quarter of respondents said that their data science or machine learning (ML) teams lacked communication skills. This may be one reason why roughly 40% of respondents said they were able to effectively demonstrate business impact &#8220;only sometimes&#8221; or &#8220;almost never.&#8221;</p>
<p>The best data practitioners must be as skilled in storytelling as they are in coding and deploying models — and yes, this extends beyond creating visualizations to accompany reports. Here are some recommendations for how data scientists can situate their results within larger contextual narratives.</p>
<h2>Make the abstract more tangible</h2>
<p>Ever-growing datasets help machine learning models better understand the scope of a problem space, but more data does not necessarily help with human comprehension. Even for the most left-brain of thinkers, it’s not in our <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/grasping-giant-numbers-is-far-from-second-nature-1490952621">nature</a> to understand large abstract numbers or things like marginal improvements in accuracy. This is why it’s important to include points of reference in your storytelling that make data tangible.</p>
<p>For example, throughout the pandemic, we’ve been bombarded with countless statistics around case counts, death rates, positivity rates, and more. While all of this data is important, tools like <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health-news/travel-plans-this-interactive-map-will-show-your-risk-for-covid-19">interactive maps</a> and conversations around <a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/coronavirus-r-number-uk">reproduction numbers</a> are more effective than massive data dumps in terms of providing context, conveying risk, and, consequently, helping change behaviors as needed. In working with numbers, data practitioners have a responsibility to provide the necessary structure so that the data can be understood by the intended audience.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/data-scientists-bring-the-narrative-to-the-forefront/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138510</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Squarespace files for a direct listing on the NYSE</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/squarespace-files-for-a-direct-listing-on-the-nyse/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/squarespace-files-for-a-direct-listing-on-the-nyse/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 18:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direct listing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squarespace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today Squarespace, a well-known software-and-hosting provider for SMB websites, released its S-1 filing. The company is pursuing a direct listing on the New York Stock Exchange, or NYSE. It will trade under the ticker symbol &#8220;SQSP.&#8221; The company&#8217;s financial results paint the picture of a rapidly growing company that has a history of profitability. Squarespace [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Today Squarespace, a well-known software-and-hosting provider for SMB websites, released <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1496963/000110465921051251/tm213918-6_s1.htm#tPARS">its S-1 filing</a>. The company is pursuing a direct listing on the New York Stock Exchange, or NYSE. It will trade under the ticker symbol &#8220;SQSP.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s financial results paint the picture of a rapidly growing company that has a history of profitability. Squarespace also has listed financial results that are inclusive of some share conversions, among other matters. Its pro forma results presume that &#8220;all shares of our convertible preferred stock had automatically converted&#8221; into different types of common stock. The pro forma results are also inclusive of a private placement, and its <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-31/squarespace-buys-restaurant-tech-startup-tock-for-400-million">recent acquisition of Tock</a>.</p>
<p>It will take some time to unspool that particular knot. For now we&#8217;ll stick to Squarespace&#8217;s historical results through 2020 without those accoutrements; if you intend to buy shares in the company, you&#8217;ll want to understand the more complicated math. For now let&#8217;s focus on Squarespace&#8217;s own metrics.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In 2019, Squarespace generated revenues of $484.8 million, leading to gross profit of $402.8 million, operating income of $61.3 million and net income of $58.2 million. In 2020 those numbers changed to revenues of $621.1 million, gross profit of $522.8 million, operating income of $40.2 million and net income of $30.6 million.</p>
<p>Squarespace&#8217;s revenue grew just over 28% in 2020, compared to 2019.</p>
<p>For reference, its pro forma results for 2020 include a modest revenue gain to $644.2 million, gross profit of $530.5 million, an operating loss of $246.4 million and a net loss of $267.7 million.</p>
<p>Squarespace has a history of cash generation, including operating cash flow of $102.3 million in 2019 and $150.0 million in 2020. The company&#8217;s cash flow data explains why Squarespace is not pursuing a traditional IPO. As Squarespace can self-fund, it does not need to sell shares in its public debut.</p>
<p>Turning to Squarespace-specific metrics, the company&#8217;s &#8220;unique subscriptions&#8221; rose from 2.984 million in 2019 to 3.656 million in 2020. Its annual recurring revenue (ARR) rose from $549.2 million to $705.5 million in 2020.</p>
<p>Squarespace&#8217;s ARR grew around 28.5% in 2020, a faster pace of expansion than its GAAP revenues.</p>
<p>Per the company&#8217;s SEC filing, the company &#8220;completed its estimate of the fair value of its Class A common stock for financial reporting purposes as a weighted-average $63.70 per share for shares granted prior to March 11, 2021.&#8221; That should help form a reference price measuring stick for now.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IBUoUDAT3X"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/08/in-pandemic-era-entrepreneurs-turn-to-spacs-crowdfunding-and-direct-listings/">In pandemic era, entrepreneurs turn to SPACs, crowdfunding and direct listings</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;In pandemic era, entrepreneurs turn to SPACs, crowdfunding and direct listings&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/08/in-pandemic-era-entrepreneurs-turn-to-spacs-crowdfunding-and-direct-listings/embed/#?secret=IBUoUDAT3X" data-secret="IBUoUDAT3X" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Finally, who owns the company? Major shareholders include the company&#8217;s founder and CEO Anthony Casalena, who owns just around 76% of the company&#8217;s Class B shares, or 49,086,410 total units. Accel has 15,514,196 Class A shares. General Atlantic has 22,361,073 Class A shares and 4,958,345 Class B shares, while Index Ventures has 19,460,619 of the Class A equity.</p>
<p>The majority of <em>voting</em> power rests with the company&#8217;s CEO, with 68.2% control. Public market investors will have to vet how much they like having zero say in the company&#8217;s future direction.</p>
<p>Regardless, this is going to be a fascinating debut. More shortly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/squarespace-files-for-a-direct-listing-on-the-nyse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139828</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla owners can now see how much solar or coal is powering their EVs</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/tesla-owners-can-now-see-how-much-solar-or-coal-is-powering-their-evs/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/tesla-owners-can-now-see-how-much-solar-or-coal-is-powering-their-evs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 18:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GreenTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Model 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Model S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TezLab]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tesla owners can now see exactly what kind of energy is powering their electric vehicles. TezLab, a free app that&#8217;s like a Fitbit for a Tesla vehicle, pushed out a new feature this week that shows the energy mix — breaking down the exact types and percentages of fossil fuels and renewable energy — coming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Tesla owners can now see exactly what kind of energy is powering their electric vehicles. TezLab, a free app that&#8217;s like a Fitbit for a Tesla vehicle, pushed out a new feature this week that shows the energy mix — breaking down the exact types and percentages of fossil fuels and renewable energy — coming from charging locations, including Superchargers and third-party networks throughout the United States.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re tracking the origin of data as it relates to energy, so we know if you&#8217;re in Tucson or Brooklyn (or any location) where the energy is coming from and what the mix of that energy looks like,&#8221; Ben Schippers, the CEO and co-founder of TezLab explained in a recent interview. &#8220;As a result, we can see how much carbon is being pushed out into the atmosphere based on your charge, whether you&#8217;re charging at home, or whether you&#8217;re charging at a Supercharger.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.electricitymap.org/map">ElectricityMap</a>, a project from Tomorrow, provided the energy data, which TezLab then folded into its consumer-facing app. Once downloaded, the app knows when and where a Tesla owner is plugging in. The energy mix feature builds off of an existing program on the app that gave owners more general information on how dirty or clean their charge is.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2139818" style="width: 325px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tezlab.gif"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2139818" loading="lazy" class="vertical wp-image-2139818 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tezlab.gif?w=315" alt="" width="315" height="680" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2139818" class="wp-caption-text">Image Credits: TezLab</p></div></p>
<p>Take Tesla&#8217;s Linq High Roller Supercharger in Las Vegas, a V3 Supercharger that is supposed to<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/18/teslas-new-v3-supercharger-can-charge-up-to-1500-electric-vehicles-a-day/"> support a peak rate of up to 250 kilowatts</a> and has been heralded for its use of Tesla solar panels and its Powerpack batteries to generate and store the power needed to operate the chargers.</p>
<p>According to TezLab&#8217;s data, 1.7% of the energy is from solar. The primary source of renewable energy is actually hydro at 65.6% — courtesy of the Hoover Dam. The remaining energy mix from the Supercharger is about 33% natural gas.</p>
<p>Tesla&#8217;s Supercharger in Hawthorne, California, which was one of the first to have solar panels, has an energy mix of 0.2% solar, 5.5% nuclear,13.3% natural gas, 27% coal and 49.9% wind.</p>
<p>The top 10 &#8220;cleanest&#8221; Superchargers — a list that includes Centralia, Leavenworth, Moses Lake and Seattle, Washington — achieved that goal thanks to hydroelectric power. Superchargers with the most solar energy are all located in the same power grid in California. Superchargers in Barstow, Oxnard, Cabazon, San Diego, Mojave, Inyokern, San Mateo, Seaside and Santa Ana, California all have 22.7% solar and 15% wind energy. The remaining mix at these locations is 0.2% battery storage, 2.9% biomass, 5.6% geothermal, 6.3% hydro, 6.6% nuclear and 40% natural gas.</p>
<p>TezLab was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/06/15/meet-tezlab-the-fitbit-for-tesla-vehicles/">born out of HappyFunCorp</a>, a software engineering shop that builds apps for mobile, web, wearables and Internet of Things devices for clients that include Amazon, Facebook and Twitter, as well as an array of startups. HFC’s engineers, including co-founders Schippers (who is now chairman of the company&#8217;s board) and William Schenk, were attracted to Tesla largely because of its software-driven approach. The group was particularly intrigued at the opportunity created by the openness of the Tesla API. The Tesla API is technically private. But the endpoints are accessible to outsiders. When reverse-engineered, it’s possible for a third-party app to communicate directly with the API.</p>
<p>TezLab launched in 2018 with some initial features that let owners track their efficiency, total trip miles and use it to control certain functions of the vehicle, such as locking and unlocking the doors and heating and air conditioning. More features have been added, mostly focused on building community, including one that allows Tesla owners to rate Supercharger stations.</p>
<p>All of that data is aggregated and anonymous. TezLab has said it won&#8217;t sell that data. It does post on its website insights gleaned from that data, such as a breakdown of model ownership, the average trip length and average time between plugging in.</p>
<p>As other electric vehicles come to market, TezLab is adding those to the app, including the Ford Mustang Mach-E.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WmRiLS1B2n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/">Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/embed/#?secret=WmRiLS1B2n" data-secret="WmRiLS1B2n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/tesla-owners-can-now-see-how-much-solar-or-coal-is-powering-their-evs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139779</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple Music streaming revenue detailed in letter to artists</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/apple-music-streaming-revenue-detailed-in-letter-to-artists/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/apple-music-streaming-revenue-detailed-in-letter-to-artists/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Streaming revenue has been a longtime concern for musicians, especially those scraping by in the wake of an industry-wide implosion of record labels. Of course, a year that has made touring an impossibility has only brought those issues into starker relief as the primary revenue source for many has completely dried up. Apple is hoping [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Streaming revenue has been a longtime concern for musicians, especially those scraping by in the wake of an industry-wide implosion of record labels. Of course, a year that has made touring an impossibility has only brought those issues into starker relief as the primary revenue source for many has completely dried up.</p>
<p>Apple is hoping to clarify some of the major questions around streaming revenue in a letter it sent to artists. The note, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-music-reveals-how-much-it-pays-when-you-stream-a-song-11618579800">reported by The Wall Street Journal</a>, outlines a revenue that amounts to around double what Spotify pays out.</p>
<p>“As the discussion about streaming royalties continues, we believe it is important to share our values,” the company notes. “We believe in paying every creator the same rate, that a play has a value, and that creators should never have to pay for featuring music in prime display space on its service.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The company’s comment is a clear shot at Spotify’s much more varied payment model. What that actually works out to at the end of the day, however, is a slightly more complicated question. Things start at around a penny-per-stream (though it can go down from there). That amount is paid out to rights holders &#8212; be they record labels or publishers. It’s another in a long line of issues that have led many musicians to question the efficacy of intermediaries in 2021.</p>
<p>Spotify CEO Daniel Ek fanned the flames in an interview last year, stating, “Some artists that used to do well in the past may not do well in this future landscape, where you can’t record music once every three to four years and think that’s going to be enough.”</p>
<p>At the end of the day, it’s a battle of pennies &#8212; or fractions thereof, for many artists. And it has become immensely difficult for mid-tier and truly independent artists to maintain a living as the world has shifted to a streaming model. Services like Bandcamp and Soundcloud have worked to make things more manageable for smaller artists, but the life of a modern musician remains a struggle &#8212; especially in the age of COVID-19.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="JUw4Q54wfi"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/25/music-made-2020-better-but-we-failed-to-make-2020-better-for-musicians/">Music made 2020 better, but we failed to make 2020 better for musicians</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Music made 2020 better, but we failed to make 2020 better for musicians&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/25/music-made-2020-better-but-we-failed-to-make-2020-better-for-musicians/embed/#?secret=JUw4Q54wfi" data-secret="JUw4Q54wfi" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="sUiz1h2Jrf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/generative-algorithms-are-redefining-the-intersection-of-software-and-music/">Generative algorithms are redefining the intersection of software and music</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Generative algorithms are redefining the intersection of software and music&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/07/15/generative-algorithms-are-redefining-the-intersection-of-software-and-music/embed/#?secret=sUiz1h2Jrf" data-secret="sUiz1h2Jrf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/apple-music-streaming-revenue-detailed-in-letter-to-artists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139809</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enterprise security attackers are one password away from your worst day</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 17:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credential stuffing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberwarfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FireEye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Security Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SolarWinds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[IT organizations must shift their enterprise security strategy to detect credential-based attacks before they become a problem.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Ralph Pisani</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/RalphRpisani">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Ralph Pisani is president at <a href="https://www.exabeam.com/">Exabeam</a> and has 20 years of experience in sales and channel and business development at organizations like Imperva and SecureComputing (acquired by McAfee).	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">If the definition of insanity is doing the same thing over and over and expecting a different outcome, then one might say the cybersecurity industry is insane.</p>
<p>Criminals continue to innovate with highly sophisticated attack methods, but many security organizations still use the same technological approaches they did 10 years ago. The world has changed, but cybersecurity hasn’t kept pace.</p>
<p>Distributed systems, with people and data everywhere, mean the perimeter has disappeared. And the hackers couldn’t be more excited. The same technology approaches, like correlation rules, manual processes and reviewing alerts in isolation, do little more than remedy symptoms while hardly addressing the underlying problem.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			The current risks aren’t just technology problems; they&#8217;re also problems of people and processes.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Credentials are supposed to be the front gates of the castle, but as the SOC is failing to change, it is failing to detect. The cybersecurity industry must rethink its strategy to analyze how credentials are used and stop breaches before they become bigger problems.</p>
<h2>It’s all about the credentials</h2>
<p>Compromised credentials have long been a primary attack vector, but the problem has only grown worse in the midpandemic world. The acceleration of remote work has increased the attack footprint as organizations struggle to secure their network while employees work from unsecured connections. In April 2020, the <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/cybersecurity/493198-fbi-sees-spike-in-cyber-crime-reports-during-coronavirus-pandemic">FBI said</a> that cybersecurity attacks reported to the organization grew by 400% compared to before the pandemic. Just imagine where that number is now in early 2021.</p>
<p>It only takes one compromised account for an attacker to enter the active directory and create their own credentials. In such an environment, all user accounts should be considered as potentially compromised.</p>
<p>Nearly all of the hundreds of breach reports I’ve read have involved compromised credentials. More than 80% of hacking breaches are now enabled by brute force or the use of lost or stolen credentials, according to the<a href="https://enterprise.verizon.com/resources/reports/2020-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf"> 2020 Data Breach Investigations Report</a>. The most effective and commonly-used strategy is credential stuffing attacks, where digital adversaries break in, exploit the environment, then move laterally to gain higher-level access.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/enterprise-security-attackers-are-one-password-away-from-your-worst-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137945</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BrandProject expands beyond the studio model with a new $43M fund</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/brandproject-capital/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/brandproject-capital/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 17:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brandproject]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BrandProject — a firm that&#8217;s backed successful direct-to-consumer commerce startups like Freshly (acquired by Nestlé), Persona (also acquired by Nestlé) and Chef&#8217;s Plate (acquired by Hello Fresh) — is announcing that it has raised $43 million for what it says is its first traditional venture fund. Founded by Andrew Black, who previously co-founded Virgin Mobile [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://brandproject.com/">BrandProject</a> — a firm that&#8217;s backed successful direct-to-consumer commerce startups like Freshly (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/nestle-acquires-freshly/">acquired by Nestlé</a>), Persona <a href="https://www.nestle.com/media/news/nestle-health-science-acquisition-persona">(also acquired by Nestlé</a>) and Chef&#8217;s Plate (<a href="https://www.foodbusinessnews.net/articles/12735-hellofresh-to-acquire-canadian-meal-kit-company">acquired by Hello Fresh</a>) — is announcing that it has raised $43 million for what it says is its first traditional venture fund.</p>
<p>Founded by Andrew Black, who previously co-founded Virgin Mobile Canada and served as president of LEGO Americas, BrandProject has been investing from a $12 million fund tied to BrandProject Studio, where the money is just a small part of what&#8217;s being offered — apparently six of the firm&#8217;s eight team members are entirely focused on supporting startups, often serving as de facto CTOs, CFOs and CMOs.</p>
<p>With the new BrandProject Capital fund, the firm will be able to make larger investments in (somewhat) more mature companies. Black estimated that the new fund will be writing checks of between $1 million and $3 million; the goal is for half of the deals to be new investments, while the other half consists of follow-on investments in startups from BrandProject Studio.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re going to be supporting the same type of businesses out of Studio or Capital, but with Studio, nothing&#8217;s too early for us — we&#8217;re all about team, team, team,&#8221; said partner Hayden Williams. &#8220;But if it&#8217;s a Capital deal, we&#8217;re going to look for some evidence that something is working, even if it&#8217;s a small scale.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="HmFtthbYg6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/">Inside the US’ epic first-quarter venture capital results</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Inside the US’ epic first-quarter venture capital results&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/embed/#?secret=HmFtthbYg6" data-secret="HmFtthbYg6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The focus will continue to be direct-to-consumer brands, and although the pandemic has led to tremendous e-commerce growth, Black said it hasn&#8217;t changed the BrandProject strategy.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2139825" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2139825" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2139825" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?w=680" alt="BrandProject Team" width="680" height="387" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png 4695w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?resize=150,85 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?resize=300,171 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?resize=768,437 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?resize=680,387 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?resize=1536,874 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?resize=2048,1165 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/BrandProject-Team.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2139825" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> BrandProject</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;We haven’t adjusted our investment focus at all because of COVID,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We’ve always invested behind categories, brands and segments that we just think the world needs.&#8221;</p>
<p>One of the limited partners who invested in the new fund is probably BrandProject&#8217;s biggest success story — Freshly co-founder and CEO Michael Wystrach, who <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/30/nestle-acquires-freshly/">sold his healthy meal startup to Nestlé for $1.5 billion</a>. Wystrach recalled <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/01/16/brandproject-consumer-startup-incubator/">reading about BrandProject in TechCrunch</a> and, after looking up the firm, sending unsolicited meals to partner Jay Bhatti in New York.</p>
<p>At that point, Freshly had only raised friends-and-family funding, and Wystrach admitted, &#8220;We would have taken a check from anyone.&#8221; But he said he was lucky that Bhatti liked the food and the firm decided to invest, with Black becoming an interim co-CEO, Bhatti serving as interim CTO and partner Andrew Bridge serving as interim CMO.</p>
<p>&#8220;What I loved about BrandProject is that they never came in and told us what kind of business we’re building,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;It was never a case where they said, &#8216;You need to do this.&#8217; It was our business, and they were team members in helping us build the business.&#8221;</p>
<p>To illustrate the idea behind the new fund, Wystrach compared the investment ecosystem to the U.S. schools: &#8220;Where Andrew and the team come in, they’re K through 8 or maybe K through 6, they&#8217;re very hands on &#8230; With the new fund, maybe they’re moving to middle school.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="EaMAANpLOG"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/01/16/brandproject-consumer-startup-incubator/">BrandProject Aims To Apply The Betaworks Model To Consumer Products And Goods</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;BrandProject Aims To Apply The Betaworks Model To Consumer Products And Goods&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2014/01/16/brandproject-consumer-startup-incubator/embed/#?secret=EaMAANpLOG" data-secret="EaMAANpLOG" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/brandproject-capital/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139793</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Soona raises $10.2M to make remote photo and video shoots easy</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/soona-series-a/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/soona-series-a/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Ha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 16:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Square Ventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Soona, a startup aiming to satisfy the growing content needs of the e-commerce ecosystem, is announcing that it has raised $10.2 million in Series A funding led by Union Square Ventures. When I wrote about Soona in 2019, the model focused on staging shoots that can deliver videos and photos in 24 hours or less. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://soona.co">Soona</a>, a startup aiming to satisfy the growing content needs of the e-commerce ecosystem, is announcing that it has raised $10.2 million in Series A funding led by Union Square Ventures.</p>
<p>When I <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/30/soona-seed-funding/">wrote about Soona in 2019</a>, the model focused on staging shoots that can deliver videos and photos in 24 hours or less. The startup still operates studios in Austin, Denver and Minneapolis, but co-founder and CEO Liz Giorgi told me that during the pandemic, Soona shifted to a fully virtual/remote model — customers ship their products to Soona, then watch the shoot remotely and offer immediate feedback, and only pay for the photos ($39 each) and video clips ($93 each) that they actually want.</p>
<p>In some cases, the studio isn&#8217;t even necessary — Giorgi said that 30% of Soona&#8217;s photographers and crew members are working from home.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Soona has now worked with more than 4,000 customers, including Lola Tampons, The Sill and Wild Earth, with revenue growing 400% last year. Giorgi said that even as larger in-person shoots become possible again, this approach still makes sense for many clients.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s nothing we sell online that does not require a visual, but not every single visual requires a massive full-day shoot,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2139790" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2139790" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2139790" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/book-a-photo-or-video-shoot.jpg?w=680" alt="Soona" width="680" height="617" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/book-a-photo-or-video-shoot.jpg 1080w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/book-a-photo-or-video-shoot.jpg?resize=150,136 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/book-a-photo-or-video-shoot.jpg?resize=300,272 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/book-a-photo-or-video-shoot.jpg?resize=768,697 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/book-a-photo-or-video-shoot.jpg?resize=680,617 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/book-a-photo-or-video-shoot.jpg?resize=50,45 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2139790" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Soona</p></div></p>
<p>Giorgi also suggested that Soona&#8217;s approach has unlocked a &#8220;new level of scalability,&#8221; adding, &#8220;Internally at Soona, we really believe in the remote-shoot experience. It&#8217;s not only more efficient, it&#8217;s a lot more fun not having to fly a brand manager from Miami and have them spend a full day at a warehouse in New York. That&#8217;s not only cost-prohibitive, it&#8217;s also a time-consuming and exhausting process for everyone.&#8221;</p>
<p>The new funding follows <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/30/soona-seed-funding/">a $1.2 million seed round</a>. Giorgi said the Series A will allow Soona to develop a subscription product with more collaboration tools and more data about what kinds of visual content is most effective.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BMvYBT9ic7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/series-a-how-to/">So you want to raise a Series A</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;So you want to raise a Series A&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/09/series-a-how-to/embed/#?secret=BMvYBT9ic7" data-secret="BMvYBT9ic7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;There’s an opportunity to own the visual ecosystem of e-commerce from beginning to end,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Giorgi also noted that Soona continues to employ its <a href="https://soona.co/candorclause/">&#8220;candor clause&#8221;</a> requiring investors to disclose whether they&#8217;ve ever faced complaints of sexual harassment or discrimination. In fact, the clause has been expanded to cover complaints around racism, ableism or anti-LGBTQ discrimination.</p>
<p>&#8220;In some ways it’s a gate that prevents bad actors from being involved [&#8230;] but it really drives a deeper connection with the investor and the founder,&#8221; Giorgi said. &#8220;We can have conversations about our values and how we see the world. We get to have a conversation about equality and justice at at time when we&#8217;re talking a lot about equity and the cap table.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BKB6pBn5id"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/30/soona-seed-funding/">Soona raises $1.2M for quick, affordable content creation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Soona raises $1.2M for quick, affordable content creation&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/05/30/soona-seed-funding/embed/#?secret=BKB6pBn5id" data-secret="BKB6pBn5id" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/soona-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139763</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nelo raises $3M to grow &#8216;buy now, pay later&#8217; in Mexico</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/nelo-raises-3m-to-grow-buy-now-pay-later-in-mexico/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/nelo-raises-3m-to-grow-buy-now-pay-later-in-mexico/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bnpl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homebrew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[latin america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexico city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nelo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satya patel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2138115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buy now, pay later is a way of paying for purchases via installment loans that generally have no interest. The concept has grown in popularity in recent years, especially in markets such as the United States, Europe and Australia. Numerous players abound, all fighting for market share &#8212; from Affirm to Klarna to Afterpay, among [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy now, pay later is a way of paying for purchases via installment loans that generally have no interest. The concept has grown in popularity in recent years, especially in markets such as the United States, Europe and Australia. Numerous players abound, all fighting for market share &#8212; from Affirm to Klarna to Afterpay, among others.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But notably, none of these bigger players have yet to penetrate another very large market &#8212; Latin America. Enter </span><a href="https://www.nelo.mx/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nelo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a startup founded by former Uber international growth team leads, which is building buy now, pay later in Mexico. The company is already live with more than 45 merchants and over 150,000 users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">San Francisco-based fintech-focused VC firm Homebrew led its recent seed round of $3 million, which also included participation from Susa Ventures, Crossbeam, Rogue Capital, Unpopular Ventures and others. With the latest capital infusion, Nelo has raised a total of $5.6 million since its 2019 inception.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nelo is not the only player in the Mexican market. A number of others, including Alchemy and Addi, have recently outlined plans for buy now, pay later offerings in the region. But where Nelo has an advantage, believes CEO Kyle Miller, is its established relationships with about 45 merchants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What I’m excited about is the relationship with the merchants,” Miller told TechCrunch. “If we find a large global one and increase conversion for them, that is our defensibility [against competitors]. What’s important here is signing on merchants, since they usually only have one offering in their checkout.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He and co-founder Stephen Hebson used to work for Uber’s international growth team, growing financial services products in India, Mexico, China and Brazil.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We got to see a cross market where countries were accelerating and where others weren’t,” Miller recalls. “For example, China was a leader in mobile payments and digital finance in India was completely transformed.”</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_2138139" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2138139" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2138139 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="453" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg 3000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Nelo-Founders.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2138139" class="wp-caption-text">Nelo co-founders Stephen Hebson and Kyle Miller; Image courtesy of Nelo</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But in markets like Mexico, the percentage of cash payments for trips was very high. And to Miller and Hebson, this spelled opportunity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nelo launched its first product in Mexico in January 2020, similar to a debit card offering from a neobank. In the middle of the year, the company launched credit installment loans.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It became immediately clear that it was going to be our most popular feature,” Miller said. “By the end of the year, it was the vast majority of our business and something that our users were telling their friends about. We were solving a real pain point.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indeed, cash remains the dominant method of payment in Mexico, with <a href="https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2020/12/10/mexicans-lack-access-to-credit">an estimated 86% of all payments</a> being in the form of cash. According to eMarketer, the region was the <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/latin-america-will-fastest-growing-retail-ecommerce-market-this-year">fastest-growing e-commerce market</a> in the world in 2020, with 37% year over year growth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Access to credit is something we take for granted in the U.S.,” Miller said. “By the end of the year, we realized this was the future of business, and we decided to focus just on credit.”</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="A6ekha83zc"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/stori-raises-32-5m-to-build-mexicos-credit-card-for-the-masses/">Stori raises $32.5M in a Lightspeed-led Series B to build Mexico’s credit card for the masses</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Stori raises $32.5M in a Lightspeed-led Series B to build Mexico’s credit card for the masses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/stori-raises-32-5m-to-build-mexicos-credit-card-for-the-masses/embed/#?secret=A6ekha83zc" data-secret="A6ekha83zc" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In March, Nelo launched its first product via an Android app and will be launching a web app soon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Customers can use its offering like a credit card, connecting directly with merchants such as Netflix and Spotify. Many users are paying for things like utility bills and cell phone bills, turning them from prepaid to postpay.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With its current product, the company has lent about $2 million, and is seeing growth of about 20% month over month.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re seeing massive demand for this new product in the way of organic signups,” Miller said, “for all the reasons Buy Now, Pay Later has been successful in markets like the U.S., Europe and Australia.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paying for installments is already common in Latin America, particularly in Brazil, so the concept is not foreign to residents in the region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We expected this is soon going to be a competitive market, so we’re hiring data scientists and engineers to continue improving our product, and grow,” Miller said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1JATIk91q6"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/latin-americas-digital-transformation-is-making-up-for-lost-time/">Latin America&#8217;s digital transformation is making up for lost time</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Latin America&#8217;s digital transformation is making up for lost time&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/01/latin-americas-digital-transformation-is-making-up-for-lost-time/embed/#?secret=1JATIk91q6" data-secret="1JATIk91q6" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nelo has about 14 employees with an engineering team in New York.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Homebrew Partner Satya Patel says he’s </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">excited about Nelo because he believes the startup “solves a serious problem related to the lack of credit for Mexican consumers.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Credit card penetration is less than 10% in Mexico and other forms of credit are effectively non-existent,” he wrote via email. “Nelo makes it possible for Mexicans to easily and inexpensively increase their purchasing power at the point of sale. And importantly, Nelo is delivering this solution online, supporting growing interest in e-commerce, and also offline, where consumers regularly shop today.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Patel adds that what Nelo is building is valuable because he is not aware of any reliable, comprehensive consumer credit rating data set in Mexico.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They are building underwriting models based on proprietary data and growing the merchant network at an incredible rate,” he said. “This buy now, pay later opportunity is untapped in Mexico but requires a very different approach than what has been successful in other markets.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Nelo team, according to Patel, understands the nuances of the market and “is executing at an exceptional pace.”</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/nelo-raises-3m-to-grow-buy-now-pay-later-in-mexico/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2138115</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reform the US low-income broadband program by rebuilding Lifeline</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/reform-the-us-low-income-broadband-program-by-rebuilding-lifeline/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/reform-the-us-low-income-broadband-program-by-rebuilding-lifeline/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Siebert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital divide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Communications Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet service providers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2137873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Lifeline program, a monthly subsidy designed to help low-income families afford telephone services, needs to be polished to ensure all Americans have access to broadband internet.
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Rick Boucher</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/rickboucherdc">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Rick Boucher was a Democratic member of the U.S. House for 28 years and chaired the House Energy and Commerce Committee's Subcommittee on Communications and the Internet. He is the honorary chairman of the <a href="https://internetinnovation.org/">Internet Innovation Alliance</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">“If you build it, they will come” is a mantra that’s been repeated for more than three decades to embolden action. The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3c_pJ_CLJQ">line</a> from “Field of Dreams” is a powerful saying, but I might add one word: “If you build it <strong>well</strong>, they will come.”</p>
<p>America’s <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/general/lifeline-program-low-income-consumers">Lifeline program</a>, a monthly subsidy designed to help low-income families afford critical communications services, was created with the best intentions. The original goal was to achieve universal telephone service, but it has fallen far short of achieving its potential as the Federal Communications Commission has attempted to convert it to a broadband-centric program.</p>
<p>The FCC’s Universal Service Administrative Company estimates that only <a href="https://www.usac.org/lifeline/learn/program-data/#:~:text=Lifeline%20Participation%20%20%20State%20%20%20January,%20%2024%25%20%2049%20more%20rows%20">26%</a> of the families that are eligible for Lifeline currently participate in the program. That means that nearly three out of four low-income consumers are missing out on a benefit for which they qualify. But that doesn’t mean the program should be abandoned, as the Biden administration’s newly released infrastructure plan suggests.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--left">
		<blockquote>
			Now is the right opportunity to complete the transformation of Lifeline to broadband and expand its utilization by increasing the benefit to a level commensurate with the broadband marketplace and making the benefit directly available to end users.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>Rather, now is the right opportunity to complete the transformation of Lifeline to broadband and expand its utilization by increasing the benefit to a level commensurate with the broadband marketplace and making the benefit directly available to end users. Instead, the White House <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/31/fact-sheet-the-american-jobs-plan/">fact sheet</a> on the plan recommends price controls for internet access services with a phaseout of subsidies for low-income subscribers. That is a flawed policy prescription.</p>
<p>If maintaining America’s global competitiveness, building broadband infrastructure in high-cost rural areas, and maintaining the nation’s rapid deployment of 5G wireless services are national goals, the government should not set prices for internet access.</p>
<p>Forcing artificially low prices in the quest for broadband affordability would leave internet service providers with insufficient revenues to continue to meet the nation’s communications infrastructure needs with robust innovation and investment.</p>
<p>Instead, targeted changes to the Lifeline program could dramatically increase its participation rate, helping to realize the goal of connecting Americans most in need with the phone and broadband services that in today’s world have become essential to employment, education, healthcare and access to government resources.</p>
<p>To start, Lifeline program participation should be made much easier. Today, individuals seeking the benefit must go through a process of self-enrollment. Implementing “coordinated enrollment&#8221; — through which individuals would automatically be enrolled in Lifeline when they qualify for certain other government assistance benefits, including SNAP (the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, formerly known as food stamps) and Medicaid — would help to address the severe program underutilization.</p>
<p>Because multiple government programs serve the same constituency, a single qualification process for enrollment in all applicable programs would generate government efficiencies and reach Americans who are missing out.</p>
<p>Speaking before the American Enterprise Institute back in 2014, former FCC Commissioner Mignon Clyburn <a href="https://docplayer.net/8728441-Lifeline-reform-means-more-than-just-another-broadband-cable-service.html">said</a>, “In most states, to enroll in federal benefit programs administered by state agencies, consumers already must gather their income-related documentation, and for some programs, go through a face-to-face interview. Allowing customers to enroll in Lifeline at the same time as they apply for other government benefits would provide a better experience for consumers and streamline our efforts.”</p>
<p>Second, the use of the Lifeline benefit can be made far simpler for consumers if the subsidy is provided directly to them via an electronic Lifeline benefit card account — like the SNAP program’s electronic benefit transfer (EBT) card. Not only would a Lifeline benefit card make participation in the program more convenient, but low-income</p>
<p>Americans would then be able to shop among the various providers and select the carrier and the precise service(s) that best suits their needs. The flexibility of greater consumer choice would be an encouragement for more program sign-ups.</p>
<p>And, the current Lifeline subsidy amount — $9.25 per month — isn’t enough to pay for a broadband subscription. For the subsidy to be truly meaningful, an increase in the monthly benefit is needed. Last December, Congress passed the temporary Emergency Broadband Benefit to provide low-income Americans up to a $50 per month discount ($75 per month on tribal lands) to offset the cost of broadband connectivity during the pandemic. After the emergency benefit runs out, a monthly benefit adequate to defray the cost of a broadband subscription will be needed.</p>
<p>In order to support more than a $9.25 monthly benefit, the funding source for the Lifeline program must also be reimagined. Currently, the program relies on the FCC’s Universal Service Fund, which is financed through a “tax” on traditional long-distance and international telephone services.</p>
<p>As greater use is made of the web for voice communications, coupled with less use of traditional telephones, the tax rate has increased to compensate for the shrinking revenues associated with landline phone services. A decade ago, the tax, known as the “contribution factor,” was <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/general/contribution-factor-quarterly-filings-universal-service-fund-usf-management-support">15.5%</a>, but it’s now more than double that at an unsustainable <a href="https://www.neca.org/docs/default-source/wwpdf/public/da21308.pdf">33.4%</a>. Without changes, the problem will only worsen.</p>
<p>It’s easy to see that the financing of a broadband benefit should no longer be tied to a dying technology. Instead, funding for the Lifeline program could come from a “tax” shared across the entire internet ecosystem, including the edge providers that depend on broadband to reach their customers, or from direct congressional appropriations for the Lifeline program.</p>
<p>These reforms are realistic and straightforward. Rather than burn the program down, it’s time to <strong>rebuild </strong>Lifeline to ensure that it fulfills its original intention and reaches America’s neediest.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="IQJXb6u29a"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/will-the-pandemic-spur-a-smart-rebirth-for-cities/">Will the pandemic spur a smart rebirth for cities?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Will the pandemic spur a smart rebirth for cities?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/29/will-the-pandemic-spur-a-smart-rebirth-for-cities/embed/#?secret=IQJXb6u29a" data-secret="IQJXb6u29a" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/reform-the-us-low-income-broadband-program-by-rebuilding-lifeline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2137873</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook&#8217;s decision-review body to take &#8216;weeks&#8217; longer over Trump ban call</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/facebooks-decision-review-body-to-take-weeks-longer-over-trump-ban-call/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/facebooks-decision-review-body-to-take-weeks-longer-over-trump-ban-call/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donald trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oversight board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[platform regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook&#8217;s self-styled and handpicked &#8220;Oversight Board&#8221; will make a decision on whether or not to overturn an indefinite suspension of the account of former president Donald Trump within &#8220;weeks&#8221;, it said in a brief update statement on the matter today. The high-profile case appears to have attracted major public interest, with the FOB tweeting that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook&#8217;s self-styled and handpicked &#8220;Oversight Board&#8221; will make a decision on whether or not to overturn an indefinite suspension of the account of former president Donald Trump within &#8220;weeks&#8221;, it said in a brief update statement on the matter today.</p>
<p>The high-profile case appears to have attracted major public interest, with the FOB tweeting that it&#8217;s received more than 9,000 responses so far to its earlier <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/facebook-trump-oversight-board-public-comment/">request for public feedback</a>.</p>
<p>It added that its commitment to &#8220;carefully reviewing all comments&#8221; after an earlier extension of the deadline for feedback is responsible for the extension of the case timeline.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The board&#8217;s statement adds that it will provide more information &#8220;soon&#8221;.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">(2/2): The Board’s commitment to carefully reviewing all comments has extended the case timeline, in line with the Board’s bylaws. We will share more information soon.</p>
<p>&mdash; Oversight Board (@OversightBoard) <a href="https://twitter.com/OversightBoard/status/1383058864074063874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 16, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Trump&#8217;s indefinite suspension from Facebook and Instagram was announced by Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/mark-zuckerberg-announces-trump-banned-from-facebook-and-instagram-for-at-least-the-next-two-weeks/">on January 7</a>, after the then-president of the U.S. incited his followers to riot at the nation’s Capitol &#8212; an insurrection that led to chaotic and violent scenes and a number of deaths as his supporters clashed with police.</p>
<p>However, Facebook quickly referred the decision to the FOB for review &#8212; opening up the possibility that the ban could be overturned in short order as Facebook has said it will be bound by the case review decisions issued by the board.</p>
<p>After the FOB accepted the case for review it initially said it would issue a decision within 90 days of January 21 &#8212; a deadline that would have fallen next Wednesday.</p>
<p>However, it now looks like the high-profile, high-stakes call on Trump&#8217;s social media fate could be pushed into next month.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a familiar development in Facebook-land. Delay has been a longtime feature of the tech giant&#8217;s crisis PR response in the face of a long history of scandals and bad publicity attached to how it operates its platform. So the tech giant is unlikely to be uncomfortable that the FOB is taking its time to make a call on Trump&#8217;s suspension.</p>
<p>After all, devising and configuring the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/21/meet-facebooks-latest-fake/">bespoke case review body</a> &#8212; as its proprietary parody of genuine civic oversight &#8212; is a process that has taken Facebook years already.</p>
<p>In related <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/facebook-instagram-users-can-now-ask-oversight-panel-to-review-decisions-not-to-remove-content/">FOB news this week</a>, Facebook announced that users can now request the board review its decisions <em>not</em> to remove content &#8212; expanding the board&#8217;s potential cases to include reviews of &#8220;keep ups&#8221; (not just content takedowns).</p>
<p><em>This report was updated with a correction: The FOB previously extended the deadline for case submissions; it has not done so again as we originally stated.</em></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rk2ymMRuIB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/facebook-trump-oversight-board-public-comment/">You can now give Facebook&#8217;s Oversight Board feedback on the decision to suspend Trump</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;You can now give Facebook&#8217;s Oversight Board feedback on the decision to suspend Trump&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/29/facebook-trump-oversight-board-public-comment/embed/#?secret=rk2ymMRuIB" data-secret="rk2ymMRuIB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="usgrrL6OuE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/facebook-instagram-users-can-now-ask-oversight-panel-to-review-decisions-not-to-remove-content/">Facebook, Instagram users can now ask &#8216;oversight&#8217; panel to review decisions not to remove content</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook, Instagram users can now ask &#8216;oversight&#8217; panel to review decisions not to remove content&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/facebook-instagram-users-can-now-ask-oversight-panel-to-review-decisions-not-to-remove-content/embed/#?secret=usgrrL6OuE" data-secret="usgrrL6OuE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6A5El7w2Cp"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/facebook-oversight-board-other-social-networks-beyond-facebook/">Facebook Oversight Board says other social networks &#8216;welcome to join&#8217; if project succeeds</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook Oversight Board says other social networks &#8216;welcome to join&#8217; if project succeeds&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/11/facebook-oversight-board-other-social-networks-beyond-facebook/embed/#?secret=6A5El7w2Cp" data-secret="6A5El7w2Cp" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/facebooks-decision-review-body-to-take-weeks-longer-over-trump-ban-call/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139705</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The IPO market is sending us mixed messages</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/the-ipo-market-is-sending-us-mixed-messages/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/the-ipo-market-is-sending-us-mixed-messages/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Cloud and Enterprise Infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you only stayed up to date with the Coinbase direct listing this week, you&#8217;re forgiven. It was, after all, one heck of a flotation. But underneath the cryptocurrency exchange&#8217;s public debut, other IPO news that matters did happen this week. And the news adds up to a somewhat muddled picture of the current IPO [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">If you only stayed up to date with the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/15/coinbases-direct-listing-alters-the-landscape-for-fintech-and-crypto-startups/">Coinbase direct listing this week</a>, you&#8217;re forgiven. It was, after all, one heck of a flotation.</p>
<p>But underneath the cryptocurrency exchange&#8217;s public debut, other IPO news that matters did happen this week. And the news adds up to a somewhat muddled picture of the current IPO market.</p>
<p>To cap off the week, let&#8217;s run through IPO news from UiPath, Coinbase, Grab, AppLovin and Zenvia. The aggregate dataset should help you form your own perspective about where today&#8217;s IPO markets really are in terms of warmth for the often unprofitable unicorns of the world.</p>
<p>Recall that we&#8217;re in the midst of a slightly more turbulent IPO window than we saw during the last quarter. After seemingly watching every company&#8217;s IPO <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/airbnbs-first-day-pop-caps-off-a-stellar-week-for-tech-ipos/">price above-range and then charge higher on opening day</a>, several companies <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/kaltura-puts-debut-on-hold-is-the-tech-ipo-window-closing/">pulled their offerings</a> as the second quarter started. It <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/31/as-compass-downsizes-its-ipo-signs-of-weakness-appear-for-high-growth-companies/">was a surprise</a>.</p>
<p>Since then we&#8217;ve <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/compass-ceo-hails-ipo-as-a-fundraising-event-amid-challenging-market/">seen Compass go public</a>, but not at quite the level of performance it might have anticipated, and, then, this week, much has happened.</p>
<p>What follows is a minidigest of IPO news from the week, tagged with our best read of just how bullish (or not) the happening really was:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/uipaths-first-ipo-pricing-could-be-a-warning-to-late-stage-investors/">UiPath&#8217;s first IPO price interval</a>:</strong> <span style="color: #ff0000;">Neutral to bearish<span style="color: #000000;">.</span></span> Though <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/what-we-all-missed-in-uipaths-latest-ipo-filing/">we anticipate that UiPath will set a higher IPO price interval</a> before it begins to trade, that its first swing at-bat was a valuation cut of around $9 billion did not set our hearts aflame. And we could be wrong about it getting valued more richly before starting to trade.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/the-ipo-market-is-sending-us-mixed-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139686</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM&#8217;s second $2.3B battery plant with LG Chem to open in late 2023</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/gms-second-2-3b-battery-plant-with-lg-chem-to-open-in-late-2023/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/gms-second-2-3b-battery-plant-with-lg-chem-to-open-in-late-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirsten Korosec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Automotive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric vehicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG Chem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GM and LG Chem announced Friday plans to build a second U.S. battery cell factory — a $2.3 billion facility in Spring Hill, Tennessee that will supply the automaker with the cells needed for the 30 electric vehicle models it plans to launch by mid decade. Construction on the plant, which is located next to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">GM and LG Chem announced Friday plans to build a second U.S. battery cell factory — a $2.3 billion facility in Spring Hill, Tennessee that will supply the automaker with the cells needed for the 30 electric vehicle models it plans to launch by mid decade.</p>
<p>Construction on the plant, which is located next to GM&#8217;s existing Spring Hill factory, will begin immediately, the company&#8217;s CEO and Chairman Mary Barra said in a press conference. The battery factory is expected to be completed by late 2023, and create 1,300 jobs.</p>
<p>Once fully operational, the joint venture&#8217;s two battery factories will have production capacity of more than 70 gigawatt hours, which LG Chem Energy Solutions CEO Jong Hyun Kim noted is two times bigger than the Tesla gigafactory in Nevada. Tesla’s factory in Sparks, Nevada, which is part of a partnership with Panasonic, has a 35 GW-hour capacity.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The foundation of GM&#8217;s shift to EVs is its Ultium platform, and the Ultium lithium-ion batteries, which will be built at the Spring Hill factory. These new batteries will use less of the rare earth material cobalt and feature a single common cell design that can be configured more efficiently for higher energy density and a smaller space than current GM batteries, Barra said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="f1snKyPiyI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/battery-resourcers-raises-20m-to-commercialize-its-recycling-plus-manufacturing-operations/">Battery Resourcers raises $20M to commercialize its recycling-plus-manufacturing operations</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Battery Resourcers raises $20M to commercialize its recycling-plus-manufacturing operations&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/battery-resourcers-raises-20m-to-commercialize-its-recycling-plus-manufacturing-operations/embed/#?secret=f1snKyPiyI" data-secret="f1snKyPiyI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;This versatility means we can put more battery power into a wider variety of vehicles, and at a better price for customers,&#8221; Barra said. &#8220;It&#8217;s truly a revolution in electric vehicle technology that will help democratize EV ownership for millions of customers, which will change lives and change the world.&#8221;</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">GM has used LG Chem as a lithium-ion and electronics supplier for at least a decade. The companies began working together in 2009. That relationship deepened as GM developed and then launched the Chevy Bolt EV. In 2019, GM and LG Chem formed a joint venture to mass produce battery cells as the automaker began to shift toward more electric vehicles. The two companies said at the time that they would <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/05/gm-lg-chem-to-invest-2-3-billion-to-in-ev-battery-joint-venture/">invest up to a total of $2.3 billion</a> into the new joint venture and establish a battery cell assembly plant on a greenfield manufacturing site in the Lordstown area of Northeast Ohio that will create more than 1,100 new jobs.</p>
<p id="speakable-summary">Steel construction began in July 2020 on the Ultium Cells LLC battery cell manufacturing facility in Lordstown, a nearly 3-million-square-foot factory that will mass produce Ultium battery cells and packs. The Lordstown factory will be able to produce 30 gigawatts hours of capacity annually.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="U7dCSOKuF5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/">Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Giving EV batteries a second life for sustainability and profit&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/giving-ev-batteries-a-second-life-for-sustainability-and-profit/embed/#?secret=U7dCSOKuF5" data-secret="U7dCSOKuF5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The batteries produced at the Lordstown factory, along with GM&#8217;s underlying electric architecture, will be used in a broad range of products across its Cadillac, Buick, Chevrolet and GMC brands, as well as the Cruise Origin autonomous shuttle that was revealed in January 2020. The Cadillac Lyriq EV flagship and an all-electric GMC Hummer, which will be revealed this fall and go into production in the fourth quarter of 2021, will use the Ultium battery system. GM plans to reveal the Lyriq at a virtual event August 6.</p>
<p>This modular architecture, called “Ultium,” (same as the battery) will be capable of 19 different battery and drive unit configurations, 400-volt and 800-volt packs with storage ranging from 50 kWh to 200 kWh, and front, rear and all-wheel drive configurations. At the heart of the new modular architecture will be the large-format pouch battery cells manufactured at this new factory.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/gms-second-2-3b-battery-plant-with-lg-chem-to-open-in-late-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139697</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What we all missed in UiPath&#8217;s latest IPO filing</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/what-we-all-missed-in-uipaths-latest-ipo-filing/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/what-we-all-missed-in-uipaths-latest-ipo-filing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uipath]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Robotic process automation platform UiPath filed its first S-1/A this week, setting an initial price range for its shares. The numbers were impressive, if slightly disappointing because what UiPath indicated in terms of its potential IPO value was a lower valuation than it earned during its final private fundraising. It&#8217;s hard to say that a company [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Robotic process automation platform UiPath <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/uipaths-first-ipo-pricing-could-be-a-warning-to-late-stage-investors/">filed its first S-1/A</a> this week, setting an initial price range for its shares. The numbers were impressive, if slightly disappointing because what UiPath indicated in terms of its potential IPO value was a lower valuation than it earned during its final private fundraising. It&#8217;s hard to say that a company looking to go public at a valuation north of $25 billion is a letdown, but compared to preceding levels of hype, the numbers were a bit of a shock.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>The Exchange explores startups, markets and money.  </em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Read it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange">every morning on Extra Crunch</a> or get <a href="https://techcrunch.com/newsletters">The Exchange newsletter</a> every Saturday.</em></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>Here at The Exchange, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/12/uipaths-first-ipo-pricing-could-be-a-warning-to-late-stage-investors/">we wondered</a> if the somewhat slack news regarding UiPath&#8217;s potential IPO valuation was a warning to late-stage investors; the number of unicorns being minted or repriced higher feels higher than ever, and late-stage money has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/inside-the-us-epic-first-quarter-venture-capital-results/">never been more active in the venture-backed startup world</a> than it has been recently.</p>
<p>If UiPath were about to eat about $10 billion in worth to go public, it wouldn&#8217;t be the best indicator of how some of those late-stage bets will perform.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/?tpcc=theexchange"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-1995213 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/exchange-banner-sq-orng.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>But in good news for UiPath shareholders, most everyone &#8212; ourselves included! &#8212; who discussed the company&#8217;s price range didn&#8217;t dig into the fact that the company first disclosed quarterly results to the <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001734722/000119312521112457/d98556ds1a.htm">same S-1/A filing</a> that included its IPO valuation interval. And those numbers are very interesting, so much so that The Exchange is now generally expecting UiPath to target a higher price interval before it debuts.</p>
<p>That should either limit or close its private/public valuation gap, and, we imagine, lower a few investors&#8217; blood pressure. Let&#8217;s look at the numbers.</p>
<h2>UiPath&#8217;s fascinating 2020</h2>
<p>The top-line numbers for UiPath&#8217;s 2020 are impressive. As <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/uipaths-ipo-filing-suggests-robotic-process-automation-is-booming/">we&#8217;ve discussed</a>, the company grew its revenues from $336.2 million in 2019 to $607.6 million in 2020, while boosting its gross profit margin by 7 percentage points to 89% last year. That&#8217;s great!</p>
<p>And it improved its net margins from -155% in 2019 to just -15% in 2020. The company&#8217;s rapid growth, improving revenue quality and extreme deficit reduction were among the reasons it was a bit surprising to see its estimated public-market value come in so far underneath its final private price.</p>
<p>But let&#8217;s dig into the company&#8217;s quarterly results &#8212; a big thanks to the reader who sent us in this direction &#8212; to get a clearer picture of UiPath. Here&#8217;s the data:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2139681" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2139681" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2139681 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-16-at-8.38.05-AM.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="334" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-16-at-8.38.05-AM.png 841w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-16-at-8.38.05-AM.png?resize=150,74 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-16-at-8.38.05-AM.png?resize=300,147 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-16-at-8.38.05-AM.png?resize=768,377 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-16-at-8.38.05-AM.png?resize=680,334 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Screen-Shot-2021-04-16-at-8.38.05-AM.png?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2139681" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> UiPath</p></div></p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/what-we-all-missed-in-uipaths-latest-ipo-filing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139678</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Level raises $27M from Khosla, Lightspeed &#8216;to rebuild insurance from the ground up&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/level-raises-27m-from-khosla-lightspeed-to-rebuild-insurance-from-the-ground-up/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/level-raises-27m-from-khosla-lightspeed-to-rebuild-insurance-from-the-ground-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employee benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Round Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khosla Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Level]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thistle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Level, a startup that aims to give companies a more flexible way to offer benefits to employees, has raised $27 million in a Series A funding round led by Khosla Ventures and Lightspeed Venture Partners. Operator Collective and leading angels also participated in the financing, along with previous backers First Round Capital and Homebrew. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="http://www.level.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Level</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a startup that aims to give companies a more flexible way to offer benefits to employees, has raised $27 million in a Series A funding round led by </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Khosla Ventures</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lightspeed Venture Partners</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Operator Collective</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and leading angels also participated in the financing, along with previous backers </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">First Round Capital </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Homebrew</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The round was reportedly raised at a “nine-figure” valuation, but the company did not provide more specifics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Founded in 2018, New York City-based Level says it’s “rebuilding insurance from the ground up” via flexible networks and real-time claims with the goal of helping employers and employees get the most out of their benefit dollars. </span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Employers can customize plans to do things like offer 100% coverage across treatments. The company also </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">touts the ability to process claims in four hours. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“That’s lightning fast when compared to 30- to 60-day claims often processed by traditional payers,” said Founder and CEO Paul Aaron, who was one of the first employees at Square, led the network team at Oscar Health and is an inventor of several patents in the payments space.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Level first launched</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">employer-sponsored dental</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">benefits in the summer of 2019 and started serving its first beta customers that fall. It also now offers vision plans. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company has more than 10,000 members from companies such as Intercom, Udemy, KeepTruckin and Thistle that have paid for care via its platform. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Insurance is confusing and often feels unfair. Networks restrict where you can go, billing takes weeks and you always seem to owe more than you expect,” Aaron said. “We believe paying with insurance should be as easy as any other purchase.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Level says it is taking a full-stack approach and building end-to-end tools, from automated underwriting to real-time benefit analytics. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It plans to launch </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a new insurance product aimed at “helping smaller businesses offer bigger benefits” that typically only enterprises have the ability to offer. The company also aims to help employers get money back for any unused benefits after paying a fixed amount each month. Ultimately, the goal is to be able to offer a full suite of products that will allow companies of all sizes &#8212; from two employees to 20,000 &#8212; provide better benefits for their teams. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Level claims that its self-insured dental and vision products let companies offer more coverage to their teams while often cutting nearly 20% from their benefits budget. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Employers already spend so much money on benefits, and neither they nor their teams get enough out of it,” said Jana Messerschmidt from Lightspeed Venture Partners, in a written statement. “Businesses of all sizes need to compete for talent with innovative benefits that help people get more from their paychecks. Level offers a far superior employee experience, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">you’re getting bang for your buck.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, Khosla&#8217;s Samir Kaul said he believes </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Level can do for insurance and benefits &#8220;what Square Cash did for person-to-person payments.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investor </span><a href="https://level.com/blog/first-round-offers-better-dental-coverage-while-saving"><span style="font-weight: 400;">First Round Capital claims to have saved 47%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by switching from fully insured to Level. And, </span><a href="https://level.com/blog/thistle-saved-41-on-dental-benefits-with-level"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thistle says it saw 41% in savings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by switching to Level. </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="9xrC9g5Fc4"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/as-next-insurance-makes-its-first-acquisition-insurtech-looks-energetic/">As Next Insurance makes its first acquisition, insurtech looks energetic</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;As Next Insurance makes its first acquisition, insurtech looks energetic&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/as-next-insurance-makes-its-first-acquisition-insurtech-looks-energetic/embed/#?secret=9xrC9g5Fc4" data-secret="9xrC9g5Fc4" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/level-raises-27m-from-khosla-lightspeed-to-rebuild-insurance-from-the-ground-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139502</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do you need a SPAC therapist?</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/do-you-need-a-spac-therapist/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/do-you-need-a-spac-therapist/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Degreed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equity podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outschool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome back to Equity, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines. Natasha and Danny and Alex and Grace were all here to chat through the week’s biggest tech happenings. It was yet another busy week, but that just means we had a great time putting the show together and recording it. Honestly, we had a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><iframe src="https://player.simplecast.com/66c4a46e-1745-4459-b930-c69b60d5a7d0?dark=true" width="100%" height="200px" frameborder="no" scrolling="no" seamless=""></iframe></p>
<p>Hello and welcome back to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=bjgo57TCQ-uFC38-iTy6HA">Equity</a>, TechCrunch’s venture capital-focused podcast, where we unpack the numbers behind the headlines.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_">Natasha</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/DannyCrichton">Danny</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/gracedenhall">Grace</a> were all here to chat through the week’s biggest tech happenings. It was yet another busy week, but that just means we had a great time putting the show together and recording it. Honestly, we had a lot of fun this week, and we hope you crack a smile while we dig through the latest as a team.</p>
<p>Ready? Here&#8217;s the rundown:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Coinbase direct listing! Here are our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/five-takeaways-from-coinbases-s-1/">notes on its S-1</a>, its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/coinbase-sets-direct-listing-reference-price-at-250-share-valuing-the-company-at-as-much-as-65b/">direct listing reference price</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/coinbase-opens-at-381-per-share-valuing-the-crypto-exchange-at-nearly-100b/">its results</a>. And we even wrote about the impact that it might have on other startup verticals!</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/5-questions-about-grabs-epic-spac-investor-deck/">Grab&#8217;s impending SPAC</a>! As it turns out, Natasha loves SPACs now, and even Danny and Alex had very little to say that was rude about this one.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/nmasc_/status/1381995585591513088">Degreed became a unicorn,</a> proving yet again that education for the enterprise is a booming sub-sector.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/">Outschool also became an edtech unicorn</a>, thanks to a new round led by Coatue and everyone&#8217;s rich cousin, Tiger Global. The conversation soon devolved into how Tiger Global is impacting the broader VC ecosystem, thanks to a fantastic analysis piece that you have to read<a href="https://randle.substack.com/p/playing-different-games"> here. </a></li>
<li>Papa <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/2137375/">raised $60 million</a>, also from Tiger Global. What do you call tech aimed at old folks? Don&#8217;t call it elder tech, we have a brand new phrase in store. Let&#8217;s see if it catches on.</li>
<li>AI chips! Danny talks the team <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/amyfeldman/2021/04/14/ai-chip-startup-groq-founded-by-ex-googlers-raises-300-million-to-power-autonomous-vehicles-and-data-centers/?sh=10fc9bbd65e3">through grokking Groq</a>, so that we can talk about TPUs without losing our minds. He&#8217;s a good egg.</li>
<li>And, finally, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/slice-series-d/">Slice raised more money</a>. Not from Tiger Global. We have good things to say about it.</li>
</ul>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0fd6OrYL9F"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/investors-spac-push-could-revamp-the-private-market-money-game/">Investors&#8217; SPAC push could revamp the private market money game</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Investors&#8217; SPAC push could revamp the private market money game&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/15/investors-spac-push-could-revamp-the-private-market-money-game/embed/#?secret=0fd6OrYL9F" data-secret="0fd6OrYL9F" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>And that is our show! We are back on Monday morning!</p>
<div class="article-content">
<div class="article-content">
<p><i>Equity drops every Monday at 7:00 a.m. PST, Wednesday, and Friday at 6:00 AM PST, so subscribe to us on </i><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/id1215439780"><i>Apple Podcasts</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes1215439780/equity"><i>Overcast</i></a><i>, </i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5IEYLip3eDppcOmy5DmphC?si=rZDFHv2sQUul_g94iCRgpQ"><i>Spotify</i></a><i> and all the casts!</i></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/do-you-need-a-spac-therapist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139249</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google misled consumers over location data settings, Australia court finds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/google-misled-consumers-over-location-data-settings-australia-court-finds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/google-misled-consumers-over-location-data-settings-australia-court-finds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 12:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ACCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[location data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google&#8217;s historical collection of location data has got it into hot water in Australia where a case brought by the country&#8217;s Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) has led to a federal court ruling that the tech giant misled consumers by operating a confusing dual-layer of location settings in what the regulator describes as a &#8220;world-first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google&#8217;s historical collection of location data has got it into hot water in Australia where a case brought by the country&#8217;s Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) has led to a federal court ruling that the tech giant misled consumers by operating a confusing dual-layer of location settings in what the regulator describes as a &#8220;world-first enforcement action&#8221;.</p>
<p>The case relates to personal location data collected by Google through Android mobile devices between January 2017 and December 2018.</p>
<p>Per the <a href="https://www.accc.gov.au/media-release/google-misled-consumers-about-the-collection-and-use-of-location-data">ACCC</a>, the court ruled that &#8220;when consumers created a new Google Account during the initial set-up process of their Android device, Google misrepresented that the ‘Location History’ setting was the only Google Account setting that affected whether Google collected, kept or used personally identifiable data about their location&#8221;.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&#8220;In fact, another Google Account setting titled ‘Web &amp; App Activity’ also enabled Google to collect, store and use personally identifiable location data when it was turned on, and that setting was turned on by default,&#8221; it wrote.</p>
<p>The Court also ruled that Google misled consumers when they later accessed the ‘Location History’ setting on their Android device during the same time period to turn that setting off because it did not inform them that by leaving the ‘Web &amp; App Activity’ setting switched on, Google would continue to collect, store and use their personally identifiable location data.</p>
<p>&#8220;Similarly, between 9 March 2017 and 29 November 2018, when consumers later accessed the ‘Web &amp; App Activity’ setting on their Android device, they were misled because Google did not inform them that the setting was relevant to the collection of personal location data,&#8221; the ACCC added.</p>
<p>Similar complaints about Google&#8217;s location data processing being deceptive &#8212; and allegations that it uses manipulative tactics in order to keep tracking web users’ locations for ad-targeting purposes &#8212; have been <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/27/google-faces-gdpr-complaint-over-deceptive-location-tracking/">raised by consumer agencies in Europe</a> for years. And in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/04/googles-location-tracking-finally-under-formal-probe-in-europe/">February 2020</a> the company&#8217;s lead data regulator in the region finally opened an investigation. However, that probe remains ongoing.</p>
<p>Whereas the ACCC said today that it will be seeking &#8220;declarations, pecuniary penalties, publications orders, and compliance orders&#8221; following the federal court ruling. Although it added that the specifics of its enforcement action will be determined &#8220;at a later date&#8221;. So it&#8217;s not clear exactly when Google will be hit with an order &#8212; nor how large a fine it might face.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="xP3hq8DLYn"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/data-is-the-worlds-most-valuable-and-vulnerable-resource/">Data is the world&#8217;s most valuable (and vulnerable) resource</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Data is the world&#8217;s most valuable (and vulnerable) resource&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/04/data-is-the-worlds-most-valuable-and-vulnerable-resource/embed/#?secret=xP3hq8DLYn" data-secret="xP3hq8DLYn" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The tech giant may also seek to appeal the court ruling.</p>
<p>Google said today it&#8217;s reviewing its legal options and considering a &#8220;possible appeal&#8221; &#8212; highlighting the fact the Court did not agree wholesale with the ACCC&#8217;s case because it dismissed some of the allegations (related to certain statements Google made about the methods by which consumers could prevent it from collecting and using their location data, and the purposes for which personal location data was being used by Google).</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s Google&#8217;s statement in full:</p>
<blockquote><p>The court rejected many of the ACCC’s broad claims. We disagree with the remaining findings and are currently reviewing our options, including a possible appeal. We provide robust controls for location data and are always looking to do more &#8212; for example we recently introduced auto delete options for Location History, making it even easier to control your data.</p></blockquote>
<p>While Mountain View denies doing anything wrong in how it configures location settings &#8212; while simultaneously claiming it&#8217;s always looking to improve the controls it offers its users &#8212; Google&#8217;s settings and defaults have, nonetheless, got it into hot water with regulators before.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/01/21/french-data-protection-watchdog-fines-google-57-million-under-the-gdpr/">Back in 2019</a> France&#8217;s data watchdog, the CNIL, fined it $57 million over a number of transparency and consent failures under the EU&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation. That remains the largest GDPR penalty issued to a tech giant since the regulation came into force a little less than three years ago &#8212; although France has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/10/france-fines-google-120m-and-amazon-42m-for-dropping-tracking-cookies-without-consent/">more recently</a> sanctioned Google $120 million under different EU laws for dropping tracking cookies without consent.</p>
<p>Australia, meanwhile, has forged ahead with passing legislation this year that directly targets the market power of Google (and Facebook) &#8212; passing a mandatory news media bargaining code in <a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1.125rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/">February</a> which aims to address the power imbalance between platform giants and publishers around the reuse of journalism content.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="olnusMD9gF"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/">After Facebook&#8217;s news flex, Australia passes bargaining code for platforms and publishers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;After Facebook&#8217;s news flex, Australia passes bargaining code for platforms and publishers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/after-facebooks-news-flex-australia-passes-bargaining-code-for-platforms-and-publishers/embed/#?secret=olnusMD9gF" data-secret="olnusMD9gF" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/google-misled-consumers-over-location-data-settings-australia-court-finds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139667</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>1Doc3, a Colombian telemedicine startup, raises $3 million</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/1doc3-a-colombian-telemedicine-startup-raises-3-million/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/1doc3-a-colombian-telemedicine-startup-raises-3-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marcella McCarthy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1Doc3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kayyak Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MatterScale Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Startup Battlefield Latin America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The pandemic has made telemedicine video visits in the U.S. almost commonplace, but in Latin America, where broadband isn’t widely available, 1Doc3 is using text and chat to provide access to care. Today, the Colombia-based company announced a $3 million pre-Series A led by MatterScale Ventures and Kayyak Ventures. “I’m on a nice MacBook for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The pandemic has made telemedicine video visits in the U.S. almost commonplace, but in Latin America, where broadband isn’t widely available, 1Doc3 is using text and chat to provide access to care. Today, the Colombia-based company announced a $3 million pre-Series A led by MatterScale Ventures and Kayyak Ventures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m on a nice MacBook for this interview, but that’s not the case of most people in LatAm,” said Javier Cardona, co-founder and CEO of 1Doc3. The company’s name is a play on the phonetics of 1, 2, 3 in Spanish.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reaching your primary care doctor when you’re not feeling well is getting harder and harder, and 1Doc3 aims to solve that problem in LatAm by offering a telemedicine platform powered by AI that does symptom assessment, triage and pre-diagnosis before connecting the patient to a doctor.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In 97% of our consultations, you’re connected to a doctor in a matter of minutes,” Cardona said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After seeing the doctor, the patient can also get their prescriptions delivered to their home through 1Doc3. The startup, like others in the space, is trying to close the loop so patients can get care quickly without having to leave their homes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to Colombia, the company already has operations in Mexico and plans to use part of the funding to expand further in the region as well as building out a marketing and sales team, which it hasn’t had thus far. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">1Doc3 reaches customers directly and by establishing corporate partnerships where the companies themselves pay for their employees’ medical care through the startup. One of Cardona’s goals is to bring the unit economics down so that smaller businesses can also afford 1Doc3, which for corporates, now charges between $3-4 a month/employee.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“For big companies, the money isn’t an issue, but our region is comprised of small to medium-sized businesses,” Cardona said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company, which was founded in 2013 and was a finalist in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/video/1doc3-at-the-finals-of-startup-battlefield-latin-america-2018/">TechCrunch’s Latin American Battlefield</a> in 2018, experienced massive growth in 2020, going from 2,500 to 35,000 consultations per month from February to December 2020, respectively, which led the company to be cashflow positive last year. In March of 2021, the company had $120,000 in MRR.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="p4HGQ81cjk"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/8-vcs-agree-behavioral-support-and-remote-visits-make-digital-health-a-strong-bet-for-2021/">8 VCs agree: Behavioral support and remote visits make digital health a strong bet for 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 VCs agree: Behavioral support and remote visits make digital health a strong bet for 2021&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/21/8-vcs-agree-behavioral-support-and-remote-visits-make-digital-health-a-strong-bet-for-2021/embed/#?secret=p4HGQ81cjk" data-secret="p4HGQ81cjk" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like many startups, the jolt to found 1Doc3 came from a personal experience faced by the founder.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When I was in Tanzania I had a medical need and I was definitely not going to go to a doctor in Tanzania, and I couldn’t reach any doctor online, not even in the U.S., and I became a little obsessed with this problem,” said Cardona, who was working in the Middle East and Africa at the time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This round brings the total raised by 1Doc3 to $5 million. Other investors that participated in the round include Swanhill Capital, Simma Capital and existing investors The Venture City, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">EWA capital (previously Mountain Nazca Colombia) and Startup Health.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/1doc3-a-colombian-telemedicine-startup-raises-3-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139547</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medtronic partners with cybersecurity startup Sternum to protect its pacemakers from hackers</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/medtronic-partners-with-sternum-iot-cybersecurity-startup-to-protect-its-pacemakers-from-hackers/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/medtronic-partners-with-sternum-iot-cybersecurity-startup-to-protect-its-pacemakers-from-hackers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marcella McCarthy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 12:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybersecurity startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medical device]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medtronic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sternum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you think cyberattacks are scary, what if those attacks were directed at your cardiac pacemaker? Medtronic, a medical device company, has been in hot water over the last couple of years because its pacemakers were getting hacked through their internet-based software updating systems. But in a new partnership with Sternum, an IoT cybersecurity startup [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you think cyberattacks are scary, what if those attacks were directed at your cardiac pacemaker? Medtronic, a medical device company, has been in </span><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/medical-device-maker-medtronic-finally-fixes-its-hackable-pacemaker/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">hot water over the last couple of years</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> because its pacemakers were getting hacked through their internet-based software updating systems. But in a new partnership with </span><a href="https://www.sternumiot.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sternum</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an IoT cybersecurity startup based in Israel, Medtronic has focused on resolving the issue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The problem was not with the medical devices themselves, but with the remote systems used to update the devices. Medtronic’s previous solution was to disconnect the devices from the internet, which in and of itself can cause other issues to arise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Medtronic was looking for a long-term solution that can help them with future developments,” said </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Natali Tshuva, Sternum’s founder and CEO. The company has already secured about 100,000 Medtronic devices.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sternum’s solution allows medical devices to protect themselves in real time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There’s this endless race against vulnerability, so when a company discovers a vulnerability, they need to issue an update, but updating can be very difficult in the medical space, and until the update happens, the devices are vulnerable,&#8221; Tshuva told TechCrunch. &#8220;Therefore, we created an autonomous security that operates from within the device that can protect it without the need to update and patch vulnerabilities.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, it is easier to protect new devices than to go back and protect legacy devices. Over the years hackers have gotten more and more sophisticated, so medical device companies have had to figure out how to protect the devices that are already out there.  </span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tiUEdgrsqa"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/israels-cybersecurity-startup-scene-spawns-new-entrants-in-2019/">Israel&#8217;s cybersecurity startup scene spawned new entrants in 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Israel&#8217;s cybersecurity startup scene spawned new entrants in 2019&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/20/israels-cybersecurity-startup-scene-spawns-new-entrants-in-2019/embed/#?secret=tiUEdgrsqa" data-secret="tiUEdgrsqa" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The market already has millions — perhaps billions — of medical devices connected, and that could be a security and management nightmare,” Tshuva added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to potentially doing harm to an individual, hackers have been taking advantage of device vulnerability as the gateway of choice into a hospital’s network, possibly causing a breach that can affect many more people. Tshuva explained that hospital networks are secured from the inside out, but devices that connect to the networks but are not protected can create a way in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In fact, health systems have been known to experience the most data breaches out of any sector, accounting for 79% of all reported breaches in 2020. And in the first 10 months of last year, we saw a 45% increase in cyberattacks on health systems, according to data by </span><a href="https://healthitsecurity.com/news/healthcare-accounts-for-79-of-all-reported-breaches-attacks-rise-45"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Health IT Security</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="SpxW1NnFSI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/medical-device-maker-medtronic-finally-fixes-its-hackable-pacemaker/">Medical device maker Medtronic finally fixes its hackable pacemaker</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Medical device maker Medtronic finally fixes its hackable pacemaker&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/16/medical-device-maker-medtronic-finally-fixes-its-hackable-pacemaker/embed/#?secret=SpxW1NnFSI" data-secret="SpxW1NnFSI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to Sternum’s partnership with Medtronic, the company also launched this week an IoT platform that allows, “devices to protect themselves, even when they are not connected to the internet,” Tshuva said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sternum, which has raised about $10 million to date, also offers cybersecurity for IoT devices outside of healthcare, and, according to Tshuva, the company focuses on areas that are “mission-critical.” Examples include railroad infrastructure sensors and management systems, and power grids.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tshuva, who grew up in Israel, holds a master’s in computer science and worked for the Israeli Defense Force&#8217;s 8200 unit — similar to the U.S.’s National Security Alliance — said she always wanted to make an impact in the medical field. “I looked to combine the medical space with my life, and I realized I could have an impact on remote care devices,” she said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Ht6jMFU50n"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/23/better-know-a-cso-indiana-university-healths-mitch-parker/">Better know a CSO: Indiana University Health&#8217;s Mitch Parker</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Better know a CSO: Indiana University Health&#8217;s Mitch Parker&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/23/better-know-a-cso-indiana-university-healths-mitch-parker/embed/#?secret=Ht6jMFU50n" data-secret="Ht6jMFU50n" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/medtronic-partners-with-sternum-iot-cybersecurity-startup-to-protect-its-pacemakers-from-hackers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook faces &#8216;mass action&#8217; lawsuit in Europe over 2019 breach</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/facebook-faces-mass-action-lawsuit-in-europe-over-2019-breach/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/facebook-faces-mass-action-lawsuit-in-europe-over-2019-breach/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Protection Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Rights Ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2139624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Facebook is to be sued in Europe over the major leak of user data that dates back to 2019 but which only came to light recently after information on more than 533 million accounts was found posted for free download on a hacker forum. Today Digital Rights Ireland (DRI) announced it&#8217;s commencing a &#8220;mass action&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Facebook is to be sued in Europe over the major leak of user data that dates back to 2019 but which only<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/"> came to light recently</a> after information on more than 533 million accounts was found posted for free download on a hacker forum.</p>
<p>Today <a href="https://www.digitalrights.ie/facebook/">Digital Rights Ireland</a> (DRI) announced it&#8217;s commencing a &#8220;mass action&#8221; to sue Facebook, citing the right to monetary compensation for breaches of personal data that&#8217;s set out in the European Union&#8217;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>
<p>Article 82 of the GDPR provides for a &#8220;right to compensation and liability&#8221; for those affected by violations of the law. Since the regulation came into force, in May 2018, related civil litigation has been on the rise in the region.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The Ireland-based digital rights group is urging Facebook users who live in the European Union or European Economic Area to check whether their data was breached &#8212; via the <a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com">haveibeenpwned</a> website (which lets you check by email address or mobile number) &#8212; and sign up to join the case if so.</p>
<p>Information leaked via the breach includes Facebook IDs, location, mobile phone numbers, email address, relationship status and employer.</p>
<p>Facebook has been contacted for comment on the litigation. <strong>Update:</strong> A Facebook spokesperson said:</p>
<blockquote><p>We understand people&#8217;s concerns, which is why we continue to strengthen our systems to make scraping from Facebook without our permission more difficult and go after the people behind it. As LinkedIn and Clubhouse have shown, no company can completely eliminate scraping or prevent data sets like these from appearing. That&#8217;s why we devote substantial resources to combat it and will continue to build out our capabilities to help stay ahead of this challenge.</p></blockquote>
<p>The tech giant&#8217;s European headquarters is located in Ireland &#8212; and earlier this week the national data watchdog <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/">opened an investigation</a>, under EU and Irish data protection laws.</p>
<p>A mechanism in the GDPR for simplifying investigation of cross-border cases means Ireland&#8217;s Data Protection Commission (DPC) is Facebook&#8217;s lead data regulator in the EU. However it has been criticized over its handling of and approach to GDPR complaints and investigations &#8212; including the length of time it&#8217;s taking to issue decisions on major cross-border cases. And this is particularly true for Facebook.</p>
<p>With the three-year anniversary of the GDPR fast approaching, the DPC has multiple open investigations into various aspects of Facebook&#8217;s business but has yet to issue a single decision against the company.</p>
<p>(The closest it&#8217;s come is a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/09/facebook-told-it-may-have-to-suspend-eu-data-transfers-after-schrems-ii-ruling/">preliminary suspension order</a> issued last year, in relation to Facebook&#8217;s EU to U.S. data transfers. However, that complaint long predates GDPR; and Facebook <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/11/facebook-seeks-fresh-legal-delay-to-block-order-to-suspend-its-transatlantic-data-transfers/">immediately filed to block the order</a> via the courts. A resolution <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/facebooks-eu-us-data-transfers-face-their-final-countdown/">is expected later this year</a> after the litigant filed his own judicial review of the DPC&#8217;s processes.)</p>
<p>Since May 2018 the EU&#8217;s data protection regime has &#8212; at least on paper &#8212; baked in fines of up to 4% of a company&#8217;s global annual turnover for the most serious violations.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WCCD9ObAJb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/">Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Understanding Europe&#8217;s big push to rewrite the digital rulebook&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/30/understanding-europes-big-push-to-rewrite-the-digital-rulebook/embed/#?secret=WCCD9ObAJb" data-secret="WCCD9ObAJb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Again, though, the sole GDPR fine issued to date by the DPC against a tech giant (Twitter) is very far off that theoretical maximum. Last <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/15/twitter-fined-550k-over-a-data-breach-in-irelands-first-major-gdpr-decision/">December</a> the regulator announced a €450,000 (~$547,000) sanction against Twitter &#8212; which works out to around just 0.1% of the company&#8217;s full-year revenue.</p>
<p>That penalty was also for a data breach &#8212; but one which, unlike the Facebook leak, <em>had</em> been publicly disclosed when Twitter found it in 2019. So Facebook&#8217;s failure to disclose the vulnerability it discovered and claims it fixed by September 2019, which led to the leak of 533 million accounts now, suggests it <em>should</em> face a higher sanction from the DPC than Twitter received.</p>
<p>However, even if Facebook ends up with a more substantial GDPR penalty for this breach the watchdog&#8217;s caseload backlog and plodding procedural pace makes it hard to envisage a swift resolution to an investigation that&#8217;s only a few days old.</p>
<p>Judging by past performance it&#8217;ll be years before the DPC decides on this 2019 Facebook leak &#8212; which likely explains why the DRI sees value in instigating class action-style litigation in parallel to the regulatory investigation.</p>
<p>&#8220;Compensation is not the only thing that makes this mass action worth joining. It is important to send a message to large data controllers that they must comply with the law and that there is a cost to them if they do not,&#8221; DRI writes on its <a href="https://www.digitalrights.ie/facebook/">website</a>.</p>
<p>It also submitted a complaint about the Facebook breach to the DPC <a href="https://www.digitalrights.ie/complaint-to-dpc-in-relation-to-facebook-data-dump-breach/">earlier this month</a>, writing then that it was &#8220;also consulting with its legal advisors on other options including a mass action for damages in the Irish Courts&#8221;.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s clear that the GDPR enforcement gap is creating a growing opportunity for litigation funders to step in in Europe and take a punt on suing for data-related compensation damages &#8212; with a number of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/14/oracle-and-salesforce-hit-with-gdpr-class-action-lawsuits-over-cookie-tracking-consent/">other mass actions announced last year</a>.</p>
<p>In the case of DRI its focus is evidently on seeking to ensure that digital rights are upheld. But it told <a href="https://www.rte.ie/news/2021/0416/1210188-facebook-data-case/">RTE</a> that it believes compensation claims which force tech giants to pay money to users whose privacy rights have been violated is the best way to make them legally compliant.</p>
<p>Facebook, meanwhile, has sought to play down the breach it failed to disclose in 2019 &#8212; claiming it&#8217;s &#8220;old data&#8221; &#8212; a deflection that ignores the fact that people&#8217;s dates of birth don&#8217;t change (nor do most people routinely change their mobile number or email address).</p>
<p>Plenty of the &#8220;old&#8221; data exposed in this latest massive Facebook leak will be very handy for spammers and fraudsters to target Facebook users &#8212; and also now for litigators to target Facebook for data-related damages.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MPk1QCDA1K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/">Ireland opens GDPR investigation into Facebook leak</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Ireland opens GDPR investigation into Facebook leak&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/ireland-opens-gdpr-investigation-into-facebook-leak/embed/#?secret=MPk1QCDA1K" data-secret="MPk1QCDA1K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6aIqi8LnTE"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebooks-tardy-disclosure-of-breach-timing-raises-gdpr-compliance-questions/">Facebook&#8217;s tardy disclosure of breach timing raises GDPR compliance questions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Facebook&#8217;s tardy disclosure of breach timing raises GDPR compliance questions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/07/facebooks-tardy-disclosure-of-breach-timing-raises-gdpr-compliance-questions/embed/#?secret=6aIqi8LnTE" data-secret="6aIqi8LnTE" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="S66QuWSAAe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/">Answers being sought from Facebook over latest data breach</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Answers being sought from Facebook over latest data breach&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/06/answers-being-sought-from-facebook-over-latest-data-breach/embed/#?secret=S66QuWSAAe" data-secret="S66QuWSAAe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/16/facebook-faces-mass-action-lawsuit-in-europe-over-2019-breach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2139624</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
