<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:39:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">136296444</site>	<item>
		<title>Our favorite startups from YC’s Summer 21 Demo Day, Part 2</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-2/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early stage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early-stage startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Litnerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pre-seed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From beaming actors into the class room to plucking things out of space, the second day of Y Combinator’s S21 Demo Day was a fresh snapshot of what nearly 200 startup teams believe is the future of innovation. Yesterday, the TechCrunch team covered the first half of this batch, as well as the startups with one-minute [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">From beaming actors into the class room to plucking things out of space, the second day of Y Combinator’s S21 Demo Day was a fresh snapshot of what nearly 200 startup teams believe is the future of innovation.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the TechCrunch team <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/here-are-all-the-companies-from-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day-part-1/">covered the first half of this batch,</a> as well as the startups with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29">one-minute pitches that stood out to us</a>. We even<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/y-combinator-s-21-equity/?tpcc=ECTW2020"> podcasted about it!</a> Today, we’re doing it all over again. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/here-are-all-the-companies-from-day-two-of-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day/">Here’s our full list of all startups</a> that presented on the record today, and below, you’ll find our votes for the best Y Combinator pitches of Day Two. The ones that, as people who sift through a few hundred pitches a day, made us go &#8220;oh wait, what&#8217;s this?&#8221;</p>
<h2>Spark Studio</h2>
<p>My experience with Indian culture is that it has a long history of valuing math and science over any other subject, which is why <a href="https://sparkstudio.co/">Spark Studio</a>’s twist on online enrichment was refreshing. The YC company offers live, extracurricular learning classes for kids in Indian households — with a twist: The classes are about music, art and communication. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/14/outschool-series-c-unicorn/">As seen by the success of Outschool,</a> small-group classes for school-going children can be a scalable way to supplement traditional education. Spark Studio is selling to kids between the ages of 5 to 15, which are highly impressionable, exploratory years.</p>
<p>Growing up, I was the only kid in my predominantly Indian family friend group who didn’t gravitate toward STEM. There were no services, other than the local library, to quench my interest in writing and reading. A service like Spark, if it gains the trust of parents, has the potential to make currently unconventional interests more conventional. And with over 400 students, and less than 2% churn, Spark Studio has early inklings it may be onto something. — Natasha</p>
<h2>Litnerd</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2179947" style="width: 949px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2179947" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2179947 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg" alt="" width="939" height="471" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg 939w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=768,385 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=680,341 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 939px) 100vw, 939px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2179947" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Litnerd</p></div></p>
<p>The best books don’t feel like homework, they feel like trips into another universe and hangouts with characters that could be friends. <a href="https://litnerd.com/">Litnerd</a> is trying to scale the feeling of immersive, engaging text to millions of students, while also encouraging better literacy and habit-forming skills. The startup has works read and enacted by actors, making classroom reading into a more entertaining experience for school-age children.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK now expects compliance with children&#8217;s privacy design code</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/uk-now-expects-compliance-with-its-child-privacy-design-code/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/uk-now-expects-compliance-with-its-child-privacy-design-code/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Lomas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Data Protection Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online harms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online retail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulatory compliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2191523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the UK, a 12-month grace period for compliance with a design code aimed at protecting children online expires today &#8212; meaning app makers offering digital services in the market which are &#8220;likely&#8221; to be accessed by children (defined in this context as users under 18 years old) are expected to comply with a set [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the UK, a 12-month grace period for compliance with <a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/key-data-protection-themes/age-appropriate-design-a-code-of-practice-for-online-services/code-standards/">a design code</a> aimed at protecting children online expires today &#8212; meaning app makers offering digital services in the market which are &#8220;likely&#8221; to be accessed by children (defined in this context as users under 18 years old) are expected to comply with a set of standards intended to safeguard kids from being tracked and profiled.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/key-data-protection-themes/age-appropriate-design-code/">age appropriate design code</a> came into force on September 2 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/uk-watchdog-sets-out-age-appropriate-design-code-for-online-services-to-keep-kids-privacy-safe/">last year</a> however the UK&#8217;s data protection watchdog, the ICO, allowed the maximum grace period for hitting compliance to give organizations time to adapt their services.</p>
<p>But from today it expects the standards of the code to be met.</p>
<p>Services where the code applies can include connected toys and games and edtech but also online retail and for-profit online services such as social media and video sharing platforms which have a strong pull for minors.</p>
<p>Among the code&#8217;s stipulations are that a level of &#8216;high privacy&#8217; should be applied to settings by default if the user is (or is suspected to be) a child &#8212; including specific provisions that geolocation and profiling should be off by default (unless there&#8217;s a compelling justification for such privacy hostile defaults).</p>
<p>The code also instructs app makers to provide parental controls while also providing the child with age-appropriate information about such tools &#8212; warning against parental tracking tools that could be used to silently/invisibly monitor a child without them being made aware of the active tracking.</p>
<p>Another standard takes aim at dark pattern design &#8212; with a warning to app makers against using &#8220;nudge techniques&#8221; to push children to provide &#8220;unnecessary personal data or weaken or turn off their privacy protections&#8221;.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>The <a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/key-data-protection-themes/age-appropriate-design-code/">full code</a> contains 15 standards but is not itself baked into legislation &#8212; rather it&#8217;s a set of design recommendations the ICO wants app makers to follow.</p>
<p>The regulatory stick to make them do so is that the watchdog is explicitly linking compliance with its children&#8217;s privacy standards to passing muster with wider data protection requirements that are baked into UK law.</p>
<p>The risk for apps that ignore the standards is thus that they draw the attention of the watchdog &#8212; either through a complaint or proactive investigation &#8212; with the potential of a wider ICO audit delving into their whole approach to privacy and data protection.</p>
<p>&#8220;We will monitor conformance to this code through a series of proactive audits, will consider complaints, and take appropriate action to enforce the underlying data protection standards, subject to applicable law and in line with our Regulatory Action Policy,&#8221; the ICO writes in<a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/key-data-protection-themes/age-appropriate-design-a-code-of-practice-for-online-services/enforcement-of-this-code/"> guidance on its website</a>. &#8220;To ensure proportionate and effective regulation we will target our most significant powers, focusing on organisations and individuals suspected of repeated or wilful misconduct or serious failure to comply with the law.&#8221;</p>
<p>It goes on to warn it would view a lack of compliance with the kids&#8217; privacy code as a potential black mark against (enforceable) UK data protection laws, adding: &#8220;If you do not follow this code, you may find it difficult to demonstrate that your processing is fair and complies with the GDPR [General Data Protection Regulation] or PECR [Privacy and Electronics Communications Regulation].&#8221;</p>
<p>Tn a <a href="https://ico.org.uk/about-the-ico/news-and-events/news-and-blogs/2021/08/as-the-children-s-code-comes-in-what-s-next/">blog post last week</a>, Stephen Bonner, the ICO’s executive director of regulatory futures and innovation, also warned app makers: &#8220;We will be proactive in requiring social media platforms, video and music streaming sites and the gaming industry to tell us how their services are designed in line with the code. We will identify areas where we may need to provide support or, should the circumstances require, we have powers to investigate or audit organisations.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We have identified that currently, some of the biggest risks come from social media platforms, video and music streaming sites and video gaming platforms,&#8221; he went on. &#8220;In these sectors, children’s personal data is being used and shared, to bombard them with content and personalised service features. This may include inappropriate adverts; unsolicited messages and friend requests; and privacy-eroding nudges urging children to stay online. We’re concerned with a number of harms that could be created as a consequence of this data use, which are physical, emotional and psychological and financial.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Children’s rights must be respected and we expect organisations to prove that children’s best interests are a primary concern. The code gives clarity on how organisations can use children’s data in line with the law, and we want to see organisations committed to protecting children through the development of designs and services in accordance with the code,&#8221; Bonner added.</p>
<p>The ICO&#8217;s enforcement powers &#8212; at least on paper &#8212; are fairly extensive, with GDPR, for example, giving it the ability to fine infringers up to £17.5M or 4% of their annual worldwide turnover, whichever is higher.</p>
<p>The watchdog can also issue orders banning data processing or otherwise requiring changes to services it deems non-compliant. So apps that chose to flout the children&#8217;s design code risk setting themselves up for regulatory bumps or worse.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="d8nJRglhBB"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/uk-watchdog-sets-out-age-appropriate-design-code-for-online-services-to-keep-kids-privacy-safe/">UK watchdog sets out &#8216;age appropriate&#8217; design code for online services to keep kids&#8217; privacy safe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK watchdog sets out &#8216;age appropriate&#8217; design code for online services to keep kids&#8217; privacy safe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/22/uk-watchdog-sets-out-age-appropriate-design-code-for-online-services-to-keep-kids-privacy-safe/embed/#?secret=d8nJRglhBB" data-secret="d8nJRglhBB" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In recent months there have been signs some major platforms have been paying mind to the ICO&#8217;s compliance deadline &#8212; with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/instagram-to-default-young-teens-to-private-accounts-restrict-ads-and-unwanted-adult-contact/">Instagram</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/google-to-introduce-increased-protections-for-minors-on-its-platform-including-search-youtube-and-more/">YouTube</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/12/tiktok-to-add-more-privacy-protections-for-teenaged-users-limit-push-notifications/">TikTok</a> all announcing changes to how they handle minors&#8217; data and account settings ahead of the September 2 date.</p>
<p>In July, <a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/giving-young-people-a-safer-more-private-experience/">Instagram said</a> it would default teens to private accounts &#8212; doing so for under 18s in certain countries which the platform confirmed to us includes the UK &#8212; among a number of other child-safety focused tweaks. Then in August, Google announced similar changes for accounts on its video charing platform, YouTube.</p>
<p>A few days later TikTok also said it would add more privacy protections for teens. Though it had also made <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/13/tiktok-update-will-change-privacy-settings-and-defaults-for-users-under-18/">earlier changes</a> limiting privacy defaults for under 18s.</p>
<p>Apple also recently got itself into hot water with the digital rights community following the<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/10/interview-apples-head-of-privacy-details-child-abuse-detection-and-messages-safety-features/"> announcement of child safety-focused features</a> &#8212; including a child sexual abuse material (CSAM) detection tool which scans photo uploads to iCloud; and an opt in parental safety feature that lets iCloud Family account users turn on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/05/new-apple-technology-will-warn-parents-and-children-about-sexually-explicit-photos-in-messages/">alerts related to the viewing of explicit images by minors</a> using its Messages app.</p>
<p>The unifying theme underpinning all these mainstream platform product tweaks is clearly &#8216;child protection&#8217;.</p>
<p>And while there&#8217;s been growing attention in the US to online child safety and the nefarious ways in which some apps exploit kids&#8217; data &#8212; as well as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/19/instagrams-handling-of-kids-data-is-now-being-probed-in-the-eu/">a number of open probes in Europe</a> (such as this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/28/eu-to-review-tiktoks-tos-after-child-safety-complaints/">Commission investigation of TikTok</a>, acting on <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/tiktok-hit-with-consumer-child-safety-and-privacy-complaints-in-europe/">complaints</a>) &#8212; the UK may be having an outsized impact here given its concerted push to pioneer age-focused design standards.</p>
<p>The code also combines with incoming UK legislate which is set to apply a &#8216;duty of care&#8217; on platforms to take a rboad-brush safety-first stance toward users, also with a big focus on kids (and there it&#8217;s also being broadly targeted to cover all children; rather than just applying to kids under 13s as with the US&#8217; <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/rules/rulemaking-regulatory-reform-proceedings/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule">COPPA</a>, for example).</p>
<p>In the blog post ahead of the compliance deadline expiring, the ICO&#8217;s Bonner sought to take credit for what he described as &#8220;significant changes&#8221; made in recent months by platforms like Facebook, Google, Instagram and TikTok, writing: &#8220;As the first-of-its kind, it’s also having an influence globally. Members of the US Senate and Congress have called on major US tech and gaming companies to voluntarily adopt the standards in the ICO’s code for children in America.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The Data Protection Commission in Ireland is preparing to introduce the Children’s Fundamentals to protect children online, which links closely to the code and follows similar core principles,&#8221; he also noted.</p>
<p>And there are other examples in the EU: France&#8217;s data watchdog, the CNIL, looks to have been inspired by the ICO&#8217;s approach &#8212; issuing its own <a href="https://www.cnil.fr/en/cnil-publishes-8-recommendations-enhance-protection-children-online">set of right child-protection focused recommendations this June</a> (which also, for example, encourage app makers to add parental controls with the clear caveat that such tools must &#8220;respect the child&#8217;s privacy and best interests&#8221;).</p>
<p>The UK&#8217;s focus on online child safety is not just making waves overseas but sparking growth in a domestic compliance services industry.</p>
<p>Last month, for example, the ICO announced the first clutch of <a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/certification-schemes-register/">GDPR certification scheme criteria</a> &#8212; including <a href="https://www.ageappropriatedesign.accscheme.com">two schemes which focus on the age appropriate design code</a>. Expect plenty more.</p>
<p>Bonner&#8217;s blog post also notes that the watchdog will formally set out its position on age assurance this autumn &#8212; so it will be providing further steerage to organizations which are in scope of the code on how to tackle that tricky piece, although it&#8217;s still not clear how hard a requirement the ICO will support, with Bonner suggesting it could be actually &#8220;verifying ages or age estimation&#8221;. Watch that space. Whatever the recommendations are, age assurance services are set to spring up with compliance-focused sales pitches.</p>
<p>Children&#8217;s safety online has been a huge focus for UK policymakers in recent years, although the wider (and long in train) Online Safety (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/04/08/uk-sets-out-safety-focused-plan-to-regulate-internet-firms/">neé Harms</a>) Bill remains at <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-publishes-draft-online-safety-bill/">the draft law</a> stage.</p>
<p>An earlier attempt by UK lawmakers to bring in mandatory age checks to prevent kids from accessing adult content websites &#8212; dating back to 2017&#8217;s Digital Economy Act &#8212; was <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/10/16/uk-quietly-ditches-porn-age-checks-in-favor-of-wider-online-harms-rules/">dropped in 2019</a> after widespread criticism that it would be both unworkable and a massive privacy risk for adult users of porn.</p>
<p>But the government did not drop its determination to find a way to regulate online services in the name of child safety. And online a<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ge verification checks look set to be &#8212; if not a blanket, hardened requirement for all digital services &#8212; increasingly brought in by the backdoor, through a sort of &#8216;recommended feature&#8217; creep (as the <a href="https://www.openrightsgroup.org/blog/age-verification-in-the-online-safety-bill/">ORG has warned</a>). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The current recommendation in the age appropriate design code is that app makers &#8220;ta</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">ke a risk-based approach to recognising the age of individual users and ensure you effectively apply the standards in this code to child users&#8221;, suggesting they: &#8220;Either establish age with a level of certainty that is appropriate to the risks to the rights and freedoms of children that arise from your data processing, or apply the standards in this code to all your users instead.&#8221; </span></p>
<p>At the same time, the government&#8217;s broader push on online safety risks conflicting with some of the laudable aims of the ICO&#8217;s non-legally binding children&#8217;s privacy design code.</p>
<p>For instance, while the code includes the (welcome) suggestion that digital services gather as little information about children as possible, in an announcement <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/30/uk-tells-messaging-apps-not-to-use-e2e-encryption-for-kids-accounts/">earlier this summer</a> UK lawmakers put out guidance for social media platforms and messaging services &#8212; ahead of the planned Online Safety legislation &#8212; that recommends they <em>prevent</em> children from being able to use end-to-end encryption.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right; the government&#8217;s advice to data-mining platforms &#8212; which it suggests will help prepare them for requirements in the incoming legislation &#8212; is <em>not</em> to use &#8216;gold standard&#8217; security and privacy (e2e encryption) for kids.</p>
<p>So the official UK government messaging to app makers appears to be that, in short order, the law will require commercial services to access <em>more</em> of kids&#8217; information, not less &#8212; in the name of keeping them &#8216;safe&#8217;. Which is quite a contradiction vs the data minimization push on the design code.</p>
<p>The risk is that a tightening spotlight on kids privacy ends up being fuzzed and complicated by ill-thought through policies that push platforms to monitor kids to demonstrate &#8216;protection&#8217; from a smorgasbord of online harms &#8212; be it adult content or pro-suicide postings, or cyber bullying and CSAM.</p>
<p>The law looks set to encourage platforms to &#8216;show their workings&#8217; to prove compliance &#8212; which risks resulting in ever closer tracking of children&#8217;s activity, retention of data &#8212; and maybe risk profiling and age verification checks (that could even end up being applied to all users; think sledgehammer to crack a nut). In short, a privacy dystopia.</p>
<p>Such mixed messages and disjointed policymaking seem set to pile increasingly confusing &#8212; and even conflicting &#8212; requirements on digital services operating in the UK, making tech businesses legally responsible for divining clarity amid the policy mess &#8212; with the simultaneous risk of <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/14/uk-online-harms-bill-coming-next-year-will-propose-fines-of-up-to-10-of-annual-turnover-for-breaching-duty-of-care-rules/">huge fines if they get the balance wrong</a>.</p>
<p>Complying with the ICO&#8217;s design standards may therefore actually be the easy bit.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VhLPEyPHK8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-publishes-draft-online-safety-bill/">UK publishes draft Online Safety Bill</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;UK publishes draft Online Safety Bill&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/uk-publishes-draft-online-safety-bill/embed/#?secret=VhLPEyPHK8" data-secret="VhLPEyPHK8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="i7lK4a8JA8"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/">The UK&#8217;s plan to tackle Big Tech won&#8217;t be one-size fits all</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The UK&#8217;s plan to tackle Big Tech won&#8217;t be one-size fits all&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/27/the-uks-plan-to-tackle-big-tech-wont-be-one-sized-fits-all/embed/#?secret=i7lK4a8JA8" data-secret="i7lK4a8JA8" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/uk-now-expects-compliance-with-its-child-privacy-design-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2191523</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here are all the companies from Day 2 of Y Combinator’s Summer 2021 Demo Day</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/here-are-all-the-companies-from-day-two-of-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/here-are-all-the-companies-from-day-two-of-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Natasha Mascarenhas]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y Combinator Demo Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YC S21]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to TechCrunch’s continuing coverage of Y Combinator’s Summer 2021 Demo Day! This is Day Two. If you haven’t caught up yet on what happened during the first day, you can read our recap of all the presenting companies here, our favorites from that first set here, and a quick podcast about all of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Welcome back to TechCrunch’s continuing coverage of Y Combinator’s Summer 2021 Demo Day! This is Day Two. If you haven’t caught up yet on what happened during the first day, you <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/here-are-all-the-companies-from-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day-part-1/">can read our recap of all the presenting companies here</a>, our <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/here-are-all-the-companies-from-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day-part-1/">favorites from that first set here, </a>and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/y-combinator-s-21-equity/">a quick podcast </a>about all of the above.</p>
<p>Today we’re back in the action, listening to a few hundred rapid-fire pitches throughout the day. What follows are short overviews of each company based on their one-minute pitch. Elsewhere on the site we’ll soon have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-2/">our Day Two favorites</a> for you to enjoy, so be on the lookout for that!</p>
<h2>Day Two companies</h2>
<p><a href="https://intellect.co">Intellect</a>: A mental healthcare service that provides teletherapy for employers in Asia. They&#8217;ve also got a free consumer app at the top of the funnel that has seen 2.5 million users since launching a year ago. The company says it&#8217;s grown to $500,000 ARR in the last six months.</p>
<p><a href="https://mazumago.com">MazumaGo</a>: Banking and electronics payment service for construction companies. MazumaGo aims to help this antiquated industry move off of traditional banking and into a unified ledger. The banking infrastructure product puts credit and debit cards into customer hands, starting in the United States.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pandai.org">Pandai</a>: Pandai is helping kids in elementary/high school in Southeast Asia boost their grades with a learning app that replaces take-home workbooks. With more than 1,600 paying subscribers using the app for almost an hour a day, Pandai may be on its way to helping thousands more get the A.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197312" style="width: 1625px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197312" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197312 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg" alt="" width="1615" height="715" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg 1615w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg?resize=150,66 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg?resize=300,133 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg?resize=768,340 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg?resize=680,301 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg?resize=1536,680 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/locale.jpg?resize=50,22 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1615px) 100vw, 1615px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197312" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Locale</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.shoplocale.com">Locale</a>: Think that DoorDash doesn’t have enough food options? Locale is betting that some folks want more options and are willing to pay for that access. The startup wants to help restaurants sell farther from their operations, and its model is showing some early traction. The company’s revenue (GMV, perhaps) scaled from $145,500 in July to $192,000 in August. The startup claims 70% retention month to month and an average order of just over $100.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><a href="https://www.projectarrow.co/">Arrow</a>: Arrow is building one-click-checkout-payment infrastructure for online sellers in Southeast Asia aiming to boost social commerce among small sellers. The team behind Arrow helped launch GrabPay and has already scaled GMV at the startup to $150,000.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.talentdrop.com/">Talentdrop</a>: A hiring marketplace where open jobs are posted with &#8220;bounties.&#8221; If someone you refer is ultimately hired and stays a while, you get the bounty. The company says that $1 million in bounties have been posted to the site thus far.</p>
<p><a href="http://infina.vn">Infina</a>: A retail investing app aiming to be the Robinhood of Vietnam. Since launch in January, Infina has reached over $2.5 million in assets under management. Its first focus was breaking open mutual funds and fixed-income products, and now it wants to head into stocks and crypto for its younger user base.</p>
<p><a href="https://blackoak.tv">BlackOakTV</a>: Black millennials are bigger consumers of streaming content than other demographics, but comparatively little of that content is made with them in mind. Black Oak TV is a subscription streaming service by and for Black creators and stars — could the next Dave Chappelle or Issa Rae come from here instead of YouTube or TikTok?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.heo-robotics.com/">HEO Robotics</a>: This startup wants to leverage unused time on existing satellites that monitor the planet to find stuff in space. Not trash, like <a href="https://turionspace.com">the startup that presented yesterday</a> that wants to clean up space around Earth, but things like other satellites. HEO says that it is selling to the Australian government, and executed a live in-orbit demo during Y Combinator. There are going to be many more satellites in space over time, the company says, which could boost demand for its service.</p>
<p><a href="https://getgallery.co">Gallery </a>: Gallery is building a platform to help developers quickly create self-stage staging environments, saving time and energy. The founding team has experience from Facebook and Goldman Sachs and hopes to tackle what it believes is a $5 billion market for mid-sized engineering teams alone.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197308" style="width: 631px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197308" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197308 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Adra.jpg" alt="" width="621" height="476" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Adra.jpg 621w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Adra.jpg?resize=150,115 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Adra.jpg?resize=300,230 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Adra.jpg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 621px) 100vw, 621px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197308" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Adra</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.adra.ai">Adra</a>: AI to help dentists find cavities they might otherwise miss. It can also convert fuzzy X-rays into something a bit easier for patients to understand. Currently in a pilot with 20 dentists.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tantl.com/">Tantl</a>: Low-code APIs are hot, and a team of Google and Apple engineers are building Tantl to make it speedy, too. Tantl enables developers to build faster internal workflows — for $20 bucks a seat. Think skipping repetitive code, easy authentication and customer user interfaces. The SaaS business launched last week and has onboarded three customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://titipku.com">Titipku</a>: A huge amount of people in Indonesia want to do their local shopping online like so many of us already do, and Titipku is ready to make it happen. They&#8217;re &#8220;Instacart for Indonesia&#8221; and that&#8217;s that. Sales are already popping and the model is proven, so let&#8217;s just offer a preemptive congratulations on their success.</p>
<p><a href="https://goflok.com/">Flok</a>: Flok is building what it describes as an Airbnb for corporate offsites. That means the startup is helping connect companies looking to host some IRL activities with a location that will be suitable. In a remote-first area, heading into a remote-friendly future, companies may spend more time and money bringing staff together sporadically. Flok wants to help those events come together. Per the startup, it takes around 15% of bookings and has booked 45 events so far worth around $200,000 in revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://sparkstudio.co">Spark Studio</a>: The team at Spark Studio is building a hub for online extracurricular courses designed for kids, reflecting the COVID-era changes to how kids learn on the web. The team is particularly focused on music, art and communication skills, hoping to streamline the wide offerings of the internet into a platform where high-quality, vetted content lives.</p>
<p><a href="https://hello.brightreps.com/">BrightReps</a>: A no-code tool meant to help you shift your company&#8217;s customer response workflows from flowcharts/spreadsheets into something more easily updated and iterated upon. Founder Brittani Dunlap says the company is profitable with $740,000 in ARR.</p>
<p><a href="https://verihubs.com">Verihubs</a>: Indonesia has a thriving fintech sector, with hundreds of startups and the well-known unicorn Gojek. Verihubs is launching a data and verification platform for regional fintechs to do stuff like authenticate customer identities and access financial data. The service has landed 45 customers, fueling $41,000 in monthly revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://getaleph.com/">Aleph</a>: A lot of banks and fintech companies want to use the latest financial models but also prefer to rely on the good old spreadsheet. Aleph allows ordinary spreadsheets in Excel or Google Sheets to have specialized financial tools built right in and always up to date. The best of both worlds, if you really love spreadsheets and financial models!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sirka.io/">Sirka</a>: Noom is now so big that startups are looking to take its model to new markets. Sirka is one such company, with a focus on the Southeast Asian region. The startup wants to replicate Noom’s science-first approach to weight control, noting that there are 150 million overweight or obese folks in the SEA area. The startup also noted that its users lose 4% of their weight on average. Is that a lot? For me (Alex) at around 160 pounds, that would be around 6.4 pounds.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.watu.email/">Watu</a>: Watu wants to help retailers close the sale they almost made. The platform is building a shopping workflow that lives inside emails and allows shoppers to make a purchase without getting tossed back to the mobile web.</p>
<p><a href="https://stownest.com">Stownest</a>: On-demand, full-service storage spaces for India. They pack up your stuff, store it and bring it back when you need it. The company says it&#8217;s helped over 12,000 customers so far, handling over 20,000 pickups/deliveries.</p>
<p><a href="https://trycomet.com">Comet Health</a>: A digital physical therapy platform that combines telehealth with video-based curriculum. Comet Health is launching with a focus on pelvic floor physical therapy and already ran a proof-of-concept pilot in Virginia.</p>
<p><a href="https://lemonade.finance">Lemonade Finance</a>: Africa&#8217;s banking system is evolving quickly, as we&#8217;ve seen from other startups in this batch. Lemonade Finance is a consequence of that — a bank for the millions of Africans who have left for other shores but still need to interact with accounts or people at home, send or receive money and so on. Having encountered this problem themselves, the founders built Lemonade Finance to make it simpler for the African Diaspora to bank abroad.</p>
<p><a href="http://parallel.bio">Parallel Bio</a>: Coming up with ideas for new pharma products, testing them on non-humans and later scaling up to testing on our species takes a long time and is expensive. Parallel Bio claims to have created a human immune system in a petri dish, which can help with testing new drugs sans using humans on the front lines of testing. As with all biotech concerns, I (Alex) struggle to vet the company’s possibilities of a tech breakthrough, but the concept here is very neat.</p>
<p><a href="https://atmana.org/">Atmana</a>: The team at Atmana is building a platform to help 15-30-year-olds break technology addictions, specifically addictions to gaming, porn and social media. The company is taking a serious approach with its $90 per year treatment plans, which combine support groups, accountability and education.</p>
<p><a href="https://floatpay.com">Float</a>: Supply chain finance — in other words, they pay for your inventory upfront, you pay them back as it sells. Float co-founder Rob LaFave previously co-founded/sold Foodzie, while co-founder Zack Kim was the CTO of Zaarly. Float says they&#8217;ve deployed $50,000 in advances to five customers so far.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.kitchenful.com/">Kitchenful</a>: Led by a former Hellofresh executive, Kitchenful thinks that grocery delivery’s commidification means it’s time for new innovation. The app gives users personalized recommendations for recipes — and then delivers the ingredients straight from a local grocery store. The team has landed partnerships with Walmart, Kroger, Target and REWE for logistics, and has launched in one city so far.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197319" style="width: 993px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197319" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197319 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/transastra.jpg" alt="" width="983" height="521" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/transastra.jpg 983w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/transastra.jpg?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/transastra.jpg?resize=300,159 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/transastra.jpg?resize=768,407 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/transastra.jpg?resize=680,360 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/transastra.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 983px) 100vw, 983px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197319" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> TransAstra</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.transastracorp.com">TransAstra Corporation</a>: Space tugs are a hot item in space: small spacecraft that help get other spacecraft where they need to go. TransAstra, from a former Momentus CEO, is using a new, super efficient &#8220;solar thermal rocket engine&#8221; that he says accomplishes this type of mission better than anything out there. With millions in NASA money and hundreds of millions in LOIs, MOUs and contracts, TransAstra sounds like it&#8217;s well on its way to being the biggest name in space tugs.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.comadre.com.br">Comadre</a>: Nubank won’t control the entire Brazilian neobanking market if Comadre gets its way. The company is building a new digital bank for low-income families, a group of folks that it says have to pool their funds together to pay bills on time, so they need new tech. The startup intends to charge $8 per family per month, in addition to generating interchange incomes. Of course, fintech is a competitive market, but if Comadre can land a customer base, its revenue story writes itself.</p>
<p><a href="https://trytoku.com/">Toku</a>: The startup helps subscription companies collect revenues in Latin America where 15% of recurring charges fail. While traditional options rely on collection agencies, Toku taps cross-channel outreach to connect with subscribers and get them back in the fold.</p>
<p><a href="http://makaniscience.net/">Makani Science</a>: This team has built what it says is the &#8220;world&#8217;s first wireless patch that can accurately and continuously monitor breathing.&#8221; Co-founder Michael Chu says the company expects to get FDA clearance within a year.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.verde.agr.br">Verde</a>: Small and medium-sized farms in Brazil may now have a new favorite credit card. Verde is a fintech platform that wants to make it easier for farmers to request and access loans. Beyond credit cards, Verde’s services include insurance and digital banks.</p>
<p><a href="https://anakin.company">Anakin</a>: Every e-commerce site wants to know exactly how every other e-commerce site is pricing the same goods, but it&#8217;s not always easy to do this systematically and comprehensively. Anakin fills this role, monitoring competing platforms for their clients and providing real-time pricing data so it can be undercut or otherwise responded to in order to snatch up that customer. With three &#8220;multibillion-dollar&#8221; companies paying half a million bucks a year already, Anakin seems well on its way to success. And maybe it&#8217;ll save you a few bucks as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://tagme.pk/">TAG</a>: Tag is building a neobank for Pakistan, a market that it claims features 100 million unbanked individuals out of a population of 250 million. The startup said that it is working with employers to help employees get their wages deposited into their TAG account instead of being handed out in cash. The company has local regulatory approval and is live in its market with a debit card product.</p>
<p><a href="https://firstignite.com">FirstIgnite</a>: The team is building a marketplace that pairs companies with university experts to tackle challenges they&#8217;re facing. The team already has pilots with University of Chicago and Carnegie Mellon, among others.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.perfekto.mx/">Perfekto</a>: Pitched as &#8220;Imperfect Foods for Latin America,&#8221; Perfekto delivers a subscription box of tasty-but-not-necessarily-pretty produce. Co-founder Anahí Sosa previously led the rollout of Uber Grocery in Latin America, and says Perfekto is currently seeing $8,000 in monthly revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://sfatherapeutics.com/">SFA Therapeutics</a>: As digital health matures, SFA Therapeutics is the latest to pitch a new focus on treating the root cause of disease, instead of suppressing symptoms for momentary relief. The team is betting on an oral solution for the over 100 million patients who suffer from autoimmune diseases (and who currently deal with painful injections as a mainstream solution). The therapeutics company has a Phase 1B trial underway and referenced “strong clinical data” on their drug’s use in combating psoriasis.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.levo.mx">Levo</a>: Levo is supercharged savings accounts in Mexico, providing up to three times the average yield (6.5% vs. 2.1%) by combining customers’ accounts and negotiating better deals with the banks and other financial organizations they work with. It&#8217;s a smart idea in use around the world but apparently not for individual savings accounts in Mexico — for now!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.laudable.com">Laudable</a>: The B2B sales process needs to move past the PDF world, Laudable reckons. The startup wants to help its customers find and share videos of their customers using their product to share instead of written testimonials. We have some questions about how its product works, but the startup scaled from $0 to $27,000 in MRR in two months, so it appears to be onto something. Also sales tech tools have raised quite a lot of money in the last year, so there’s likely appetite for Laudable.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.monto.mx/">Monto</a>: Monto&#8217;s team is building a platform that provides companies in Mexico with the ability to give workers &#8220;salary on demand,&#8221; which isn&#8217;t an advance but allows workers to request the salary they have already earned between paychecks. Workers are charged a flat rate of $34.50 + VAT.</p>
<p><a href="http://mindstate.design">Mindstate Design Labs</a>: Mindstate says it&#8217;s working on &#8220;next-gen&#8221; psychedelic therapeutics for treating things like PTSD. One thing they&#8217;re working on is a &#8220;safer MDMA&#8221; that they say doesn&#8217;t cause post-treatment depression and would allow for a &#8220;greater ability to redose for increased efficacy.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://beau.to">Beau</a>: Small businesses have finally been peer pressured into digitizing their operations for more seamless customer experiences — it only took a pandemic. Beau is building a no-code client workflow for customer communications. With Beau, these businesses can collect submissions, files, payments and send messages to build loyalty (and do their jobs). The minimum viable product has been launched to seven paying customers and 65 active companies.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.ruthhealth.com/">Ruth Health</a>: Pregnant women receive a lot of care but once the baby is born, there are months of health issues they still have to deal with — and little support provided by existing medical providers. Ruth Health is a telehealth clinic focused specifically on postpartum care, with $150 out-of-pocket sessions to address common women&#8217;s issues like painful sex and unwanted urination. Their rallying cry is &#8220;for vagina owners, by vagina owners!&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197309" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197309" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197309 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/axolo.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="415" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/axolo.jpg 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/axolo.jpg?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/axolo.jpg?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/axolo.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197309" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Axolo</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://axolo.co/">Axolo</a>: Offering what it calls a “war room for each pull request,” Axolo is a startup building in what we might call the developer productivity space. Its service creates a Slack channel around pull requests that helps engineers avoid swapping from Github back to their internal chats. The company says around 35 organizations are using its product today, and intends to monetize using a freemium model. Axolo will cost around $8 per engineer per month.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.ananya.health/">Ananya Health</a>: The team at Ananya Health is building a portable medical device that can freeze abnormal cells much cheaper than existing solutions. The team is focused specifically on using the device to treat cervical &#8220;pre-cancer&#8221; in regions across the world where medical help is hardest to reach.</p>
<p><a href="https://noloco.io">Noloco </a>: A no-code tool for agencies/real estate firms/small businesses to easily build branded portals for interacting with clients, handling things like communication and file sharing. Co-founder Simon Curran says the company is currently seeing an MRR of $1,500.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.govly.com/">Govly</a>: Red tape has a way of bringing people together. Govly helps companies like Cisco and Nutanix come together to bid on government contracts. It wants to grow beyond a SaaS tool and into a marketplace that helps businesses sell into the government. The team hopes to be a better visualization into the business-to-government procurement space.</p>
<p><a href="https://walrus.club">Walrus</a>: Countless young people in India sign up for their first bank account every year. Walrus thinks it would be nice if they signed up with them — a neobank that offers a simple debit card and tools for saving, budgeting and investing. With a straightforward 1% transaction fee model it could be the simplest way for folks there to start banking.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197314" style="width: 1122px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197314" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197314 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mach9.jpg" alt="" width="1112" height="677" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mach9.jpg 1112w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mach9.jpg?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mach9.jpg?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mach9.jpg?resize=768,468 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mach9.jpg?resize=680,414 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mach9.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1112px) 100vw, 1112px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197314" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mach9</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.mach9.io/">Mach9 Robotics</a>: Ah the modern world, full of wonder and aging infrastructure. Sure, we’ve built a lot, but a lot of our infrastructure is fraying. And that means inspections are a pretty big deal. But inspecting stuff in the ground is a huge pain in the backside. Mach9 uses a thermal camera attached to a car to peer into the Earth and find infrastructure issues. The company claims three paid pilots.</p>
<p><a href="http://algouniversity.com/">Algo University</a>: Algo University is taking the ISA learning model to India, training university students there to become solid software engineers. Students also have the option to pay upfront for the education platform, which teams live classes, assignments and contests to help students pick up skills that hopefully land them at top tech jobs.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.therify.co/">Therify</a>: Therapy works better when you&#8217;re talking to someone that you feel understands you. Therify provides mental healthcare as a benefit to companies, focusing on matching patients with therapists who have similar backgrounds. Co-founder James Murray says it&#8217;s currently running $100,000 in paid pilots with &#8220;four global companies.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.jovian.ai">Jovian</a>: The “Great Resignation” has led companies to get quite nifty with their benefits, with one impact being the rise of investment in employee education. To take advantage of these shifting employer habits, Jovian has an ambitious goal: be the best technical university online. The job-oriented training platform helps professionals shape up on data science and ML skills. It has a monthly revenue of $20,000 and is growing 35% month over month.</p>
<p><a href="https://argonaut.dev">Argonaut</a>: Practically every tech company that wants to scale will need to deploy infrastructure to the cloud, causing words like Kubernetes, Terraform and containerization to be uttered. Argonaut automates this deployment as much as possible to reduce or eliminate the need for specialized engineering work, so even dummies like me can launch a company.</p>
<p><a href="http://abhi.com.pk/">Abhi</a>: Here’s another startup working on the Pakistani market. Abhi wants to offer instant wage access to workers in the country. Early traction appears to be good, with some $15,000 in total payment volume in its first month. The startup claims to have 45 MOUs &#8212; a very non-GAAP sort of contract, if you will &#8212; that represent around 200,000 employees. If it converts a few of those into real agreements, Abhi should have enough volume to truly test its model in the country.</p>
<p><a href="https://dots.community/">Dots</a>: Dots (one of two companies called Dots in this cohort!) is building a software product to help automate online customer communities, plugging into platforms like Slack and Discord and allowing companies to automate certain tasks and help them ensure new community members don&#8217;t slip through the cracks.</p>
<p><a href="https://stackfinance.co/">Stack</a>: Pitched as &#8220;Vanguard for India,&#8221; Stack is trying to make investing easier for the 130 million middle-income households in the region. Launched six weeks ago, they&#8217;ve got 1,000+ users with $250,000 under management.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.epinoma.com/">Epinoma</a>: CRISPR transformed biology, and the world’s understanding of the human genome. Epinoma, led by three biogenetic experts, builds off those learnings to apply them to the world of epigenetics. The first application for its protein is for the liquid biopsy market, which the team estimates is a $50 billion opportunity.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.koshex.com">Koshex</a>: Obviously the middle class in India needs somewhere to put their money. If they don’t want to use Stack (two entries above) then maybe they’ll go for Koshex, which bills itself as “Wealthfront for India.” Integrated with more than 40 financial institutions already, Kosher is prepared to handle billions of dollars worth of Indian small investments.</p>
<p><a href="https://shimmer.care">Shimmer</a>: Therapy is good and if everyone could access regular therapy it would be good for the world. But there aren’t enough therapists, and the service is often too expensive for folks in need &#8212; if they can get access. Shimmer wants to bridge the need-coverage gap by offering online mental health support groups that are run by coaches. Peer support can be pretty key to helping with various issues, as anyone in recovery can tell you. The company has 105 users today and claims 2x the retention of traditional therapy.</p>
<p><a href="https://front.page">FrontPage</a>: Building on the retail investor boom, FrontPage wants to build a Public.com for India, helping market investors and traders find a community of people interested in the finance world while browsing trades, charts and new discussions taking place in real time.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hyperglue.com/">HyperGlue</a>: Once you&#8217;ve got a big audience, keeping track of what your users are saying about you all around the internet gets tough. HyperGlue analyzes things that people share in places like Reddit and Discord to give product managers an automated breakdown of what people are saying about your product  — the things they hate, the features they want, etc.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.oneistox.in">Oneistox</a>: Online-cohort based classes for designers, architects and engineers — sold at roughly $900 bucks a pop. Oneistox wants to fill industry skill gaps through the virtual school, which mainly markets to those in their mid-20s and above. Early completion rates are 82%, dozens of percentage points above industry standards from massive open online course providers — signaling its format may just work.</p>
<p><a href="https://joingreenwork.com">Greenwork</a>: With the huge infrastructure bill coming through, demand for skilled blue-collar labor will be jumping over the next few years. Greenwork wants to organize it with a LinkedIn-like site for these folks, often government-trained experts who need to find a project to apply their skills to. A recruitment and networking platform just for this valuable class of workers could be just the thing to get people back to work.</p>
<p><a href="https://marketfeed.com">marketfeed</a>: This is fun. Marketfeed is an app that trains users in India to trade stocks. Its founder claims to be akin to the Jim Cramer of India, with a boatload of YouTube subs to back up the claim. So far the app has reached around $100,000 in MRR. Seeing how popular trading has become in Europe and the United States in the last few quarters marketfeed’s general thrust makes sense.</p>
<p><a href="https://warrant.dev/">Warrant</a>: Warrant is building a platform that helps developers add authorization and access control to their web and mobile apps. The company&#8217;s API manages the complexity while users are able to define rules that meet the needs of their product.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.salarybox.in/">SalaryBox</a>: Not to be confused with &#8220;SalaryBook&#8221; from yesterday, SalaryBox is <em>also</em> aiming to be Gusto for India, helping the many millions of SMBs there to take their paper-based payroll (etc.) digital. The team says it&#8217;s seeing $18,000 in annual revenue just a few months after launch.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.evidence.dev">Evidence</a>: Code! Code! Code! Evidence helps data teams replace drag-and-drop business intelligence tools with a code-based workflow, which a fancy way to say that it makes work more simple. The company is betting it can build the default front end for data management, as “every company becomes a data company.” Evidence of this? Evidence has 46 active projects after launching last week.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.femaleinvest.com/">Female Invest</a>: Investment is an industry dominated by men, but women command an increasing proportion of investable income. Female Invest aims to educate and mobilize this growing contingent and already has more than 17,000 paying subscribers in its community. Soon they&#8217;ll activate trading as well and fulfill their ambition of becoming the &#8220;Robinhood for women.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.inversionspace.com/">Inversion Space</a>: Instead of taking stuff <em>to</em> space, Inversion Space wants to bring some back <em>from</em> space. That’s an, ahem, inversion of what we tend to hear from space startups. The startup is building a return “capsule” that is four feet in diameter and wants to be able to drop stuff from space back to the planet in under an hour. Notably the startup claims some $225 million worth of LOIs, which may sound like a lot, but given what it costs to do anything in space, keep the number in scale. Inversion is targeting a first launch (drop?) in mid-2023.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.advantageclub.co">Advantage Club</a>: The team is building a wide-ranging platform for employee engagement, teaming perks, exclusive rewards and access to early wages. They&#8217;re hoping to bring multiple benefits into a single platform while catering to top customers with their deep web of more than 10,000 brand partners.</p>
<p><a href="https://digibuild.com">DigiBuild</a>: Construction management software built on the blockchain to give a &#8220;verifiable single version of truth&#8221; to all owners/contractors/subcontractors/etc. Co-founder Rob Salvador says the company is currently seeing an MRR of $58,000, projecting that to grow to $75,000 by October.</p>
<p><a href="https://rivia.ai">Rivia.AI</a>: D2C brands in India need better ways to get their products into ever-impatient consumer hands. Instead of forcing brands to rely on Amazon for two-day delivery speed, Rivia.AI is building its own fulfillment agency to help this customer base get the same outcome, but cheaper. By ignoring Amazon, Rivia.AI is helping e-commerce brands in India achieve two-day shipment, while the startup makes $0.65 on each delivery. Rivia.AI has 2,400 monthly transactions — and a mission to get to the billions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.palla.app/">Palla</a>: Sending money across borders has never been easy. Or rather, if it&#8217;s easy, it&#8217;s expensive. Palla aims to make it both easy and cheap to send money to and from LatAm, from one person to another. They&#8217;re partnering with big fintech and banking companies to get thousands of folks signed up and ready to get cash from out of the country on their debit cards in seconds rather than hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://suplias.com">Suplias</a>: This is cool. There are 13 million small grocery stores in Africa, Suplias says, which it wants to help supply. The startup offers a B2B mobile marketplace that uses third-party logistics providers to get new inventory to small grocers rapidly. The digitization of SMBs in emerging markets is a well-known trend, but this is a bit different. And if the margins are good, it could scale pretty rapidly. Suplias claims $230,000 in GMV per month today, a figure that it says is growing by 40% each month.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rentmarble.com">Marble</a>: Marble helps property owners manage their properties from afar. The platform handles rent collection and maintenance in addition to remote showings, collecting $50 per unit per month, significantly undercutting competitor pricing.</p>
<p><a href="https://zoios.io">Zoios</a>: Analytics for HR that the company says can predict who is going to quit, who is burned out, etc. Co-founder Christian Højbo Møller says they currently have 12 companies as customers paying for 500 seats and have hit an ARR of $24,000.</p>
<p><a href="https://boldvoice.com">BoldVoice</a>: Duolingo may be the best-known language learning app on the market, but BoldVoice has a deep focus in one area that unicorn is missing: smart speech. The startup wants to help non-native English speakers find (and flaunt) their voices. The startup uses short-form videos, taught by Hollywood accent coaches who traditionally help actors, to deliver content. The curriculum is built around three Ps: posture, to help with the physical feel of using an English R versus a Spanish R; phonology, the vowels and consonants; and porosity, which is the musicality of an accent. In two months, it has hit $5,000 in monthly revenue from over 200 paid uses. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/27/boldvoice-y-combinator-pre-seed/">We wrote more about the startup on TechCrunch</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.onsleek.com/">Sleek</a>: Impulse buys on the internet aren&#8217;t actually any easier than big buys. You still have to go through the whole checkout process, except on the few shops that offer one-click fire-and-forget checkout. But what if I told you there was a startup offering a browser extension that makes every online shop have a one-click checkout … AND it gives you cash back? That&#8217;s the pitch with Sleek&#8217;s ML-powered checkout bot. By preventing cart rot they increase sales, collect the commissions and pass on the savings to you. Of course, you&#8217;re still out the cost of that impulse buy you would have left behind … but let&#8217;s not talk about that.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cloudanix.com">Cloudanix</a>: Lots of companies now use more than one public cloud provider. So not just AWS, or just Azure, but GCP and others as well. Cloudanix wants to provide a unified dashboard to help companies keep all their public cloud work secure from a single dashboard. Per its website, the startup provides security monitoring and “remediation workflows” when needed. As the world becomes increasingly a multicloud domain, the company could find itself riding a secular shift.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.fastfarma.com">FastFarma</a>: A digital pharmacy that promises 30-minute medication delivery for Latin America, currently operating in Ecuador and Mexico. Co-founder ​​​​Santiago Ribadeneira says the company is currently doing $20,000 in monthly revenue.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197317" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197317" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197317 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/stipop.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="551" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/stipop.jpg 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/stipop.jpg?resize=150,122 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/stipop.jpg?resize=300,243 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/stipop.jpg?resize=50,41 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197317" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Stipop</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://stipop.io/home">Stipop</a>: An easy-to-install SDK that developers can use to add stickers to their consumer chat apps. Already has 150,000 stickers designed by 5,000 artists and has been integrated into over 100 apps. Stipop monetizes through brand-sticker partnerships.</p>
<p><a href="https://siglo.com/">Siglo</a>: Internet service providers are complicated to work with, which is always a green light for savvy entrepreneurs. Siglo is disrupting the ISP market for urban communities in Latin America. Focusing on easy-to-pay and simplified processes, Siglos’ wireless home broadband service currently connects over 1,700 homes with $26,000 in monthly recurring revenue. Its revenue is growing 30% monthly.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.telivy.com">Telivy</a>: SMBs need cyber insurance, and Telivy wants to give it to them. It&#8217;s as simple as that. They specialize in this and offer better and cheaper coverage so that SMBs can meet compliance and other requirements easier.</p>
<p><a href="https://cartx.io/">CartX</a>: Shopify’s huge growth is drawing startup attention. CartX wants to build something akin to Shopify for the Brazilian market. As companies like Nubank have shown, the Brazilian digital market can prove lucrative. So to see CartX work on its e-commerce infrastructure is not a surprise. The company, now around two years old, is doing just under $1 million in yearly revenue today.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.myhomebreeze.com/l/tankless">HomeBreeze</a>: A home repair marketplace that is aiming to get rid of the annoying back-and-forth estimate process, instead providing up-front fixed/guaranteed prices and instant service scheduling. They&#8217;re focusing on water heaters first. Co-founder Vineet Mehta says the company is seeing over $60,000 in monthly revenue after launching in May.</p>
<p><a href="https://tuli.health">Tuli Health</a>: Tuli Health is building software that helps pharmacies in the U.K. perform in-house diagnostic tests. It started with COVID testing but is now expanding into allergy testing. Co-founder Jiawei Li says the company has onboarded 147 pharmacies that have run over 7,000 diagnostic tests so far, accounting for $400,000 in revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://getalchemy.app/">Alchemy</a>: Sure, Shopify made it easier for businesses to sell online, but how do those same businesses create a dynamic, differentiated experience for their customers? Alchemy is a visual development platform that enables brands to build unique e-commerce experiences, sans the code. It launched in late July and has so far landed 11 initial customers accounting for $2,800 in monthly recurring revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.okani.care">Okani</a>: In LatAm, millions of people without primary care physicians either find a specialist by other means or end up going to the hospital instead. Okani acts as a digital primary care provider living in WhatsApp, so patients can meet with a doctor and get tailored referrals rather than take on the time and expense of a hospital trip.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197310" style="width: 1009px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197310" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197310 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/breakaway.jpg" alt="" width="999" height="509" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/breakaway.jpg 999w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/breakaway.jpg?resize=150,76 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/breakaway.jpg?resize=300,153 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/breakaway.jpg?resize=768,391 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/breakaway.jpg?resize=680,346 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/breakaway.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 999px) 100vw, 999px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197310" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> The Breakaway</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.breakaway.app/">The Breakaway</a>: Ah, do you need more motivation to get back on your indoor bike? Is your Peloton sitting idle because you are worried that <a href="https://www.onepeloton.com/bike/instructors/grannyriri">Matt</a> will judge you for not doing enough Power Zone Max rides? The Breakaway is building a “motivational coaching” application for fitness dweebs like me. Its iOS app will link to your Peloton, so you can, well, cycle more? Better? I would joke that surely the $50 you already pay Peloton is enough, but since we’re already paying that, why not tack on more to perhaps cycle a bit more?</p>
<p><a href="https://hypercontext.com">Hypercontext</a>: This company says it helps managers run better meetings by streamlining their meetings according to their team&#8217;s OKRs and providing a dedicated place for agendas, feedback, follow-up steps, etc. The team says its MRR is currently at $37,000, charging teams $7 per user per month.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.joinfella.com/">Fella</a>: Telehealth for men with obesity. Combines recently FDA-approved medication with health coaching, charging $150 per user per month. The company has worked with 13 patients so far after launching in Texas two months ago.</p>
<p><a href="https://bedrock-ai.com/">Bedrock AI</a>: Some of the best gems sit in the footnotes of corporate filings, from 10-K annual reports to Form D filings. Bedrock AI’s software extracts key factoids to limit information overload and better supplement those who spend their days working though the fine text of public company data.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hiration.com/">Hiration</a>: LinkedIn may have disrupted resumes, but Hiration wants to disrupt LinkedIn’s role in the job search process. The startup is building a way for job seekers to quickly create efficient resumes. Through partnerships with over 80 institutions, including Stanford and The University of Texas at Austin, Hiration created 125,000 resumes in August. It has an annual recurring revenue of $500,000.</p>
<p><a href="https://cellchorus.com">CellChorus</a>: All kinds of medicines, therapies, vaccines and other research processes need to understand what effects they create on a cell-by-cell level, but observing this directly can be very difficult. CellChorus does it, though, and has trained a machine learning model to watch footage of cell interactions and automatically derive conclusions like which cells perform best and why. They&#8217;ve already got traction and have been in multiple prestigious journals, so while it&#8217;s not something you&#8217;ll be using at home, it could be standard issue tech in medical research soon.</p>
<p><a href="https://secoda.co">Secoda</a>: Secoda wants to aggregate your company’s data in a single place, so that internal teams can better work together and share metadata, queries and more. Part of its pitch is that current tools in its domain are more targeted at enterprise-scale companies, while it wants to target smaller startups to start. That’s a standard GTM model for YC startups, but in this case it doesn’t bother us. The company claims $40,000 in ARR today.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.flowly.world/">Flowly</a>: Pairs virtual reality headsets with a heartrate sensor to generate visualizations that the team is proving can reduce pain (and thus, opioid usage). They&#8217;ve got a $1.2 million grant from the NIH, and co-founder Celine Tien says the company is currently seeing over $40,000 in monthly revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.outloud.ai/">outloud.ai</a>: Records and analyzes conversations in drive-thru restaurants to help owners figure out the best ways to upsell. Co-founder Sasha Miagkyi says they&#8217;re currently analyzing 700,000 orders per month at over 50 restaurants.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.getbaraka.com/">Baraka </a>: An investment app built explicitly for the Middle East. Baraka launched one month ago and has attracted over $340,000 in assets under management with 70% week-over-week growth. Its mission is to give local retail investors the ability to put money into the U.S. stock markets.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197311" style="width: 631px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197311" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197311 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/genome-link.jpg" alt="" width="621" height="488" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/genome-link.jpg 621w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/genome-link.jpg?resize=150,118 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/genome-link.jpg?resize=300,236 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/genome-link.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 621px) 100vw, 621px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197311" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Genomelink</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://genomelink.io/">Genomelink</a>: Once you&#8217;ve had your DNA sequenced and analyzed by 23andMe or Ancestry, what else can you do with it? Upload it to Genomelink and you can activate any number of &#8220;apps,&#8221; — other forms of analysis that show more traits that the big companies don&#8217;t list. It&#8217;s your genomic data; you can do what you want with it, right?</p>
<p><a href="https://payze.io/">PAYZE</a>: Pitched as &#8220;Stripe for former Soviet Union countries,&#8221; PAYZE takes the fragmented payment solutions in the region and unifies them into a single payment platform. Co-founder Giorgi Tsurtsumia says they&#8217;re working with 350 merchants 8 months post-launch.</p>
<p><a href="https://revery.ai">Revery AI</a>: Revery is building a &#8220;virtual dressing room&#8221; that helps online shoppers visualize how clothing they&#8217;re shopping for will actually look like on a person, tapping AI to impose clothing images on models while allowing users to customize said model to look more like they do.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.plugpagamentos.com">Plug</a>: One API to process payments across multiple providers. Alex Vilhena says they take a 1% cut while saving teams up to 30% in processing fees and have processed over $230,000 to date.</p>
<p><a href="https://ab.bot">Abbot</a>: This former GitHub team saw firsthand the power of a streamlined, remote-first operating system, and now it’s building tools for other startups to do the same. Abbot makes the traditional team chats on Slack or Discord into a command center to get tasks done. It reacts to messages by running programs, deploying software or, heck, even displaying the weather.</p>
<p><a href="https://mechoautotech.com/">Mecho Autotech</a>: Believe it or not, the global logistics revolution is powered by drivers in actual vehicles, and those vehicles need maintenance, which cuts into earnings. Mecho Autotech is tackling the issue in Nigeria, where truckers sacrifice a lot of income to shoddy or inconvenient repairs. Instead, Mecho will let them summon one of the 2,000 mechanics on demand via a web app to fix things when and where they&#8217;re needed.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.itsmello.co">mello</a>: After the absurd last few years, it&#8217;s no surprise we&#8217;re seeing an uptick in companies focusing on burnout. Mello reduces burnout by regularly checking in with employees, detecting shifts in happiness/productivity and offering up ways you might help them dig their way out. Currently ties into Slack, with plans for Teams/Discord/Google integrations on the roadmap.</p>
<p><a href="http://quest.audio">Quest</a>: An audio Q&amp;A platform where experts can share advice and stories in short audio clips; think a micropodcasting Quora. The startup is focusing specifically on business advice early on and has over 10 hours of content from speakers at companies like YC and Google.</p>
<p><a href="https://concordmaterials.com">Concord Materials</a>: Helps construction companies check invoices for accuracy and detect unauthorized charges. Founder Anthony Valente says they&#8217;ve got contracts in place to verify over $20 million of GMV.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.baubap.com">Baubap</a>: Baubap is a microfinancing platform for the traditionally underbanked in Mexico. The already-profitable mobile-lending app doles out capital to its users with a 90% return rate. Baubap’s mission isn’t small: It wants to become the largest lender in Latin America.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197316" style="width: 1282px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197316" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197316 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/snapcalorie.jpg" alt="" width="1272" height="985" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/snapcalorie.jpg 1272w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/snapcalorie.jpg?resize=150,116 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/snapcalorie.jpg?resize=300,232 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/snapcalorie.jpg?resize=768,595 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/snapcalorie.jpg?resize=680,527 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/snapcalorie.jpg?resize=50,39 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1272px) 100vw, 1272px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197316" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> SnapCalorie</p></div></p>
<p><a href="http://www.snapcalorie.com">SnapCalorie</a>: Nobody likes counting calories, because (A) calories are great and (B) it&#8217;s a pain. But SnapCalorie could at least address B by providing a calorie estimate of a meal from a single image that they claim is more accurate than a nutritionist&#8217;s. The founder also co-founded Google Lens and the Cloud Vision API so he knows of what he speaks. Don&#8217;t make it too convenient though buddy, because then I would have to use it.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.trybree.com/">Bree</a>: Zero interest cash advances (up to $100) in Canada; instead of fees, Bree allows users to tip the service when it&#8217;s been helpful. Co-founder Alexander Li says the company did $14,000 in advances and saw $1,800 of revenue in July.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.getzuma.com/">Zuma</a>: Zuma is building out an &#8220;AI leasing agent&#8221; that helps make the most of web interest by responding and following up on every lead. In eight months, the team has grown to $388,000 ARR.</p>
<p><a href="http://medium.bio">Medium Biosciences</a>: Uses machine learning to find new/novel enzymes for biotech companies. The company says by cutting out much of the trial-and-error, it cuts a 10-week process down to two weeks.</p>
<p><a href="https://hyperseed.com">Hyperseed</a>: Already backed by Silicon Valley investors, Hyperseed makes it easier for finance professionals to create custom pricing and billing applications. The full-stack development environment helps finance teams add their thoughts into tech stacks, doing what the no-code team thinks Excel can’t.</p>
<p><a href="https://glitzi.com.mx/">Glitzi</a>: An alternative to actually going to a salon or spa to get beauty or grooming services, Glitzi is an on-call service that connects beauty professionals directly to clients. The clients get the convenience of home care and the pros make more for the personalized service and no fees or rent for spa space. Everyone wins, and of course everyone is beautiful … that means you!</p>
<p><a href="http://standardcode.io">StandardCode</a>: An API meant to help gaming/social companies deal with COPPA/GDPR compliance, automating the ID/parental approval/age verification process. Charges $0.50 per verification.</p>
<p><a href="https://payhippo.africa/">Payhippo</a>: Payhippo is building a loan platform for small businesses in Nigeria, hoping to help bring access to working capital that can make a difference. They say that many of these businesses they lend to aren&#8217;t able to get loans from the bank due to high collateral requirements and the scarcity of credit scores in the region.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197315" style="width: 934px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197315" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197315 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mayaeats.jpg" alt="" width="924" height="463" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mayaeats.jpg 924w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mayaeats.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mayaeats.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mayaeats.jpg?resize=768,385 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mayaeats.jpg?resize=680,341 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/mayaeats.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 924px) 100vw, 924px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197315" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> MayaEats</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.mayaeats.com/">MayaEats</a>: Pitching itself as &#8220;Uber for kitchens,&#8221; MayaEats works with &#8220;underutilized&#8221; kitchens to analyze their region/potential audience and build a virtual brand to sell on platforms like DoorDash and Uber Eats. Vijayaraj Gopinath says they&#8217;ve already processed over 57,000 orders, accounting for $2 million in GMV and a monthly recurring revenue of $30,000.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.contalink.com/">Contalink</a>: Startups love to build SaaS for sales teams, but Contalink is refreshingly looking at another team for its software-based tool: the accounting department. The platform helps accountants move off of desktop software into the electronic cloud, a shift the team claims will make bookkeeping a much faster task. Starting with a focus on Mexico SMBs, Contalink has landed 2,700 paying users with $50,000 in monthly recurring revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://numary.com">Numary</a>: Moving large amounts of money around within or between organizations is something that needs to be done constantly and flawlessly. Numary wants to be the next standard financial ledger for money movements, starting with an open source base and taking aim at developers — the power behind the power.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.stepful.com">Stepful </a>: Helps those without college degrees train for and find entry-level healthcare jobs. Charging $3,000 per student, co-founder Carl Madi says the company has graduated 36 students to date.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vincoed.com">Vinco</a>: Vinco is a corporate benefits startup aiming to connect employees at Latin American companies with online education opportunities. The startup&#8217;s service is live at more than 30 companies, promising a way to improve employee retention and satisfaction.</p>
<p><a href="https://invezo.com">Invezo</a>: An investing research/analysis tool for stocks and crypto assets, tying social media data (read: hype!) and financial data together. Lets you, for example, track mentions of a cryptocurrency over Reddit/Twitter/Google/etc. Co-founder Emmett Miller says they&#8217;ve doubled weekly active users to over 5,000 in the last month.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.chipax.com">Chipax</a>: Describing itself as a “Quickbooks for SMBs in LatAm,” Chipax wants to give business owners real-time visibility on receivables and payables. The startup is expanding its revenue opportunities with invoicing and B2B payments. It has landed $1.6 million in annual recurring revenue across over 1,100 customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.catenabiosciences.com/">Catena Biosciences</a>: Autoimmune disorders are devastating and difficult to treat. Catena has a new approach born out of work at CRISPR co-inventor Jennifer Doudna&#8217;s lab. By attaching custom proteins to red blood cells, they can retrain the immune system to cease its mistaken and destructive response, potentially providing a treatment for Graves’ disease, celiac disorder, multiple sclerosis and more. Big Pharma is already nosing around, as you might expect, and I predict a large valuation quite soon. (But more importantly, treatments for serious disorders.)</p>
<p><a href="https://kapacity.io">Kapacity.io</a>: Connects to existing devices/products (like HVAC) in a building and controls them via API to reduce electricity costs, aiming for a 25% reduction and taking a cut of the savings.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.ancana.co">Ancana</a>: Ancana is a marketplace for fractional ownership of fully managed vacation homes, taking the idea of timeshares and Airbnb and creating a platform for shared homes where owners actually own a percentage of their property. Users collaborate with their co-owners to book time through the platform instead of relying on fixed timelines.</p>
<p><a href="https://keyri.co">Keyri</a>: A passwordless authentication API that taps your phone, QR codes and FaceID to sign you in to services without any passwords to type/share. Co-founder Zain Azeem says the company has four LOIs signed and is already working with 57 startups.</p>
<p><a href="https://fitia.app/">Fitia</a>: The app creates personalized nutrition plans, using ingredients in local grocers, for LatAm users who want to lose weight. Users pay $55 per year, and the now-profitable startup attracts $70,000 in monthly revenue. Beyond trying to democratize the nutritionist, Fitia is also growing a database of over 1 million Latin American foods and recipes.</p>
<p><a href="https://evidentlyai.com">Evidently AI</a>: Machine learning models are used almost universally in tech stacks, but telling when they&#8217;re failing and how isn&#8217;t as simple and established as something like &#8220;500 Error server not found.&#8221; Evidently wants to make tracking and debugging ML systems simpler and easier, so that faults can be identified and fixed faster. As authors of dozens of ML models themselves, the team thinks they&#8217;ve got the chops to do it. And who will naysay them?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.adaptyvbio.com/">Adaptyv Biosystems</a>: A smaller, faster chip for biotech companies to synthesize and screen proteins. CEO Julian Englert says their chip is 100,000x smaller than existing options, allowing them to screen &#8220;millions of drugs instead of thousands.&#8221;; from the data they&#8217;ll gather, they&#8217;ll build &#8220;the world&#8217;s largest protein database.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.awesomic.io/">Awesomic</a>: The team at Awesomic is building a design freelancing platform with a big emphasis on getting design jobs done quickly without the stress of hiring a designer.</p>
<p><a href="https://mejorcdt.com/">Luable</a>: Helps users in Latin America find saving accounts with better yields. Acting as a broker, Luable takes a 1.5% commission. The team says it currently has over $450,000 under management, averaging 2x growth month over month.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2183596" style="width: 1210px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2183596" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2183596 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/marina.jpg" alt="Render of a Craft aircraft flying over a city." width="1200" height="675" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/marina.jpg 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/marina.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/marina.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/marina.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/marina.jpg?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/marina.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2183596" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Craft Aerospace</p></div></p>
<p><a href="http://www.craft.aero">Craft Aerospace</a>: Craft Aerospace is designing and testing a totally novel new vertical take-off and landing aircraft designed to fly and land in and around cities, making regional travel faster and cheaper. The design of the aircraft is pretty wild, but it actually makes a lot of sense and could help change SF-to-LA into Tenderloin-to-Silverlake (well, maybe not that, but you get the idea). <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/29/craft-aerospaces-novel-take-on-vtol-aircraft-could-upend-local-air-travel/">I wrote more about their new approach here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://snowboard.software/">Snowboard Software</a>: If you know what the &#8220;Snowflake data cloud&#8221; is, Snowboard might be for you. Snowboard is a data catalog for Snowflake, allowing you to dig through your data on the platform faster, find data issues, etc. You can self-host it, or they&#8217;ll host for you; it&#8217;s free to start tinkering with, and you start paying after 1,000 indexed columns. The company says it&#8217;s currently seeing $15,000 ARR with four companies onboarded.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.jupe.com">Jupe</a>: First up, the Jupe founder who presented had an excellent hat. He was also living in a Jupe in a parking lot. Why? Because Jupe sells glamping-in-a-box. The company has booked some $6.5 million in revenue this year and claims to be profitable. It sells software and hardware and takes a pretty big cut of total spend. Er, is glamping a big industry? I have glamped. It was nice. Perhaps it is growing during the COVID era.</p>
<p><a href="https://hera.so">Hera</a>: The team at Hera is building a Calendar app with an emphasis on productivity, with a number of overt and more subtle features aimed at helping people get the most out of their meetings without living in a bloated calendar app.</p>
<p><a href="http://astekdx.com">Astek</a>.: Helps doctors find the right antibiotic faster — an hour, the company says, instead of days — in emergency situations. The company expects to charge $100 per test.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.protegosolutions.io/">Protego</a>: Founded by ex-Rappi entrepreneurs, Protego helps LatAm companies recover lost revenue. It automates the chargeback process, a process that currently requires quite a bit of manual labor. Since launch, it has attracted $4,300 in monthly recurring revenue and has turned its former employer into a pilot customer.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vflowmedicalinc.com/">V-Flow Medical</a>: Millions of Americans suffer from compressed pelvic veins, a dangerous condition usually treated with stents — which have a 20% failure rate. V-Flow has designed a device to treat the huge number of people who need an alternative treatment. With a track record of medical device approvals and exits behind them, the team says they have this whole thing mapped out and hopefully ready to keep hundreds of thousands of people healthy.</p>
<p><a href="https://bloop.ai">bloop</a>: An extension for your code editor that surfaces code examples from each library&#8217;s official documentation. Works with VS Code, with support for other IDEs on the way.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.instacrops.com">Instacrops</a>: An agtech startup focused on helping farmers in Latin America maximize their crop yields using technology like IoT sensors and drones while integrating data sources to help farmers make the best decisions with the best information available.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.biteninja.com">Bite Ninja</a>: Bite Ninja wants drive-thru restaurants to use its freelancers (ninjas) to help others order and receive food (bites), allowing people to take drive-thru orders from home. One of the co-founders ran a BBQ restaurant chain called Baby Jacks, where he built out the initial concept. The team says it&#8217;s currently running pilots with five chains and would make $150,000 per restaurant location.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pylonump.com/">Pylon</a>: One way to stand out in Y Combinator is to be a fully bootstrapped company making nearly double-digit revenue. That’s what Pylon, a platform to help water and electricity companies manage infrastructure, did in its pitch today. The profitable company improves its clients operations by detecting and reducing leakages, consumption theft and uncollected bills.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.clearmix.com/">ClearMix</a>: Organizing an in-person video team at a global company can be tough at the best of times, let alone during a pandemic. ClearMix is a fully remote video production suite that lets video teams record and produce videos quickly and professionally, but entirely online. No doubt it&#8217;s going up against some heavy hitters in the Adobe vein, but the need is clear.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sequincard.com">Sequin </a>: A fintech play, Sequin wants to give women debit cards to help them build credit &#8212; the card features what the company called “live credit reporting” &#8212; so that more women can access debt products. The company plans to eventually build a credit card product as well. Per Sequin, it expects to generate around $60 per user per year thanks to interchange incomes.</p>
<p><a href="https://useteamspace.com/">Teamspace</a>: A remote collaboration platform built by a Facebook product designer who worked on the company&#8217;s Workplace product. The startup hopes to reduce team misalignment by giving them a &#8220;shared canvas&#8221; where they can tackle problems together.</p>
<p><a href="http://repool.io">Repool </a>: Pitched as &#8220;AngelList for hedge funds,&#8221; Repool wants to let more people build hedge funds. &#8220;Focus on trading, we&#8217;ll take care of the rest,&#8221; they say. Co-founder Kevin Fu says the company has two funds onboarded after launching two weeks ago, already accounting for $36,000 in ARR.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sigmaos.com">SigmaOS</a>: A browser designed for work. SigmaOS wants to be the main tool startups use to access the web, with an interface meant to promote multitasking and collaboration. Flagship features include split-screen capabilities, browser-based collaboration pages and focus mode. The productivity software startup charges $10 a month — and claims it&#8217;s gaining one customer every two minutes.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whalesync.com">Whalesync</a>: No-code tools are definitely popular (there have been plenty in the last two days) but they don&#8217;t solve every problem. And it turns out they create at least one new one — keeping data in sync between no-code tools can be tough and your devs end up having to code a data pipeline anyway. Whalesync connects no-code tools with each other, staving off the &#8220;real&#8221; coding for another step or two.</p>
<p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/yummy-venezuela/id1506748350">Yummy</a>: Co-founded by a Postmates alum, Yummy is building a super app for Venezuela that it intends to expand to Peru and Chile. The company’s application includes food, CPG and entertainment products and claims to have expanded to ride-hailing as well. Yummy says that it is doing $1.6 million in monthly GMV, a figure that is growing by 35% each month. If that growth keeps up, expect to hear more about the company.</p>
<p><a href="https://trylevel.app">Level</a>: A fintech financing platform that buys loans from fintech startups helping them gain access to capital to scale faster. The company analyzes the fintech company&#8217;s performance and loan portfolio to source low-risk loans it can purchase at a discounted rate.</p>
<p><a href="https://getinflow.io/">Inflow</a>: A self-help app for helping people manage ADHD. The company is promising symptom improvement on par with in-person treatment while making it &#8220;100x more affordable and accessible.&#8221; Co-founder Levi Epstein says Inflow has 2,700+ paying members and is currently seeing $33,000 in monthly recurring revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.keeper.app">Keeper</a>: Bookkeepers often stick to spreadsheets and email, so Keeper has built a software solution with them in mind. The startup gives bookkeepers a suite of tools to communicate with clients and deliver reports. Focusing on the quiet but complicated has helped Keeper hit $6,400 in monthly recurring revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.jinguhealth.com/">Jingu Health</a>: Millions of women suffer from vaginal infections with no effective treatment, but Jingu Health is coming to the rescue with a powerful tool. They target the underlying cause of these infections by analyzing the microbiome with computational biology tools and reprogramming it (think &#8220;more of this, less of this,&#8221; not bioengineered microorganisms). They claim to have the first pill-based treatment. It&#8217;s even FDA approved even though it doesn&#8217;t need to be … just in case.</p>
<p><a href="https://echoeshq.com">Echoes HQ</a>: This one could prove controversial. Echoes wants to measure engineering output and align time spent to different corporate OKRs. If TechCrunch rolled this out to measure writer output, there would be pitchforks in the streets.* Precisely how much engineers want to have their work monitored so that a manager elsewhere can chide them for whatever they deem to be “less than productive” is not clear. However, given how tight the market is for technical talent, if this introduces any sort of material friction, it would drive regretted employee churn, as they say.</p>
<p>*And by streets we mean various Slack channels.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2179947" style="width: 949px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2179947" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2179947 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg" alt="" width="939" height="471" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg 939w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=150,75 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=300,150 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=768,385 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=680,341 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/litnerd.jpg?resize=50,25 50w" sizes="(max-width: 939px) 100vw, 939px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2179947" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Litnerd</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://litnerd.com/">Litnerd </a>: Litnerd wants to help make kids better readers by keeping them more engaged in reading. They livestream actors into the classroom on a weekly basis to act out and advance stories the kids have spent the last few days reading, provide lesson plans for teachers and more. We <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/litnerd-streams-live-actors-into-the-classroom-to-help-kids-better-connect-with-reading/">wrote about Litnerd here</a>!</p>
<p><a href="https://docvita.com/">DocVita</a>: Telehealth has exploded during the pandemic. DocVita is looking to scale telehealth in India further with a platform that connects consumers with generalists and specialists across a wide network. The founders have experience in the healthcare software industry and have scaled the company to $12,000 in monthly GMV after just a few months on the market.</p>
<p><a href="http://waterplan.com">Waterplan</a>: Tech and water may not usually mix well, unless you’re Waterplan. The startup helps industrial facilities mitigate water risk, a growing threat due to climate change and deterioration. It has $345,000 in annual recurring revenue thanks to 12 pilot customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.moxionpower.com/">Moxion Power</a>: I (Alex) half expect this company to announce a SPAC-led deal to go public in the next month. It’s building large, mobile batteries that construction sites and other commercial operations can use to provide power in locations where they today use generators. Lower emissions is a win. The company expects to get its first production facility online in Q1 2022. Given the huge interest in EV tech more generally today, we like Moxion’s chances of raising the capital it needs to give its business a shot.</p>
<p><a href="https://lightly.ai/">Lightly</a>: A machine learning startup that helps ML teams prioritize the data most in need of labeling, pointing them to the data subsets that will have the biggest impact on their overall model accuracy.</p>
<p><a href="https://beeper.com">Beeper</a>: You probably use like a half dozen chat apps. Beeper merges them all together  — even iMessage, through some hackery involving forwarding messages from a Mac or jailbroken iPhone — and adds things like unified search. Co-founders Eric Migicovsky and Brad Murray previously worked together at Pebble, the early smartwatch company Eric founded.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rendalomaq.com/">Rendalo Maq</a>: A digital broker for construction equipment in LatAm. Clients turn to Rendalo Maq to procure and handle fleet management for construction companies in the region. While the startup’s software is focused on used equipment and rentals, it’s also a marketplace and operating system.</p>
<p><a href="https://getbasis.com">Basis</a>: Look, if you&#8217;re in business automation like me, you understand that a dynamic end-to-end data pipeline is worth its weight in bitcoin. Was that convincing? Okay, I&#8217;m not in business automation but I can guess that with the amounts of data coming in and the number of places it needs to go, you want a big-time solution, and that&#8217;s what Basis wants to be. &#8220;Yes code&#8221; instead of no code, giving superpowers to your dev team so they don&#8217;t have to hire a specialist in data handling just to make things work.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.levro.com">Levro</a>: Something that I’ve noticed among lots of smaller companies is building in many countries at once. That means that business itself is increasingly global. Which is great for remote workers, but a bit wonky when it comes to payments and banking. Levro appears to be prepping to help smooth the currency situation by offering a multicurrency banking service. The company dangled a hook during its pitch, offering free payments up to a transaction cap for folks tuned into Demo Day. Let’s see if that helps it drive early sign-ups. Its website currently only lets folks sign up for updates, so it may be some time until we fully grok Levro’s early traction.</p>
<p><a href="https://zazos.com/en">Zazos</a>: A no-code tool for HR teams that helps them build the exact functionality they need and leave out what they don&#8217;t while allowing customizations across interfaces, permissioning and data integrations.</p>
<p><a href="https://courses.filadd.com/">Filadd</a>: Helps students in Latin America pass their college entrance exams, then provides them with 24/7 access to tutors until they graduate. Co-founder Joaquin Olmedo says the company is currently seeing $800,000 in annual revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://testrigor.com">testRigor</a>: A better way to test for quality assurance. TestRigor has created technology that allows companies to run tests that better emulate the way end users engage with their applications. The software claims to be faster, non-engineer friendly, and thus more scalable for its clients. Netflix is one of the customers fueling testRigor’s $700,000 annual recurring revenue.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.heimdalccu.com">Heimdal</a>: Heimdal pulls valuable minerals out of seawater while simultaneously sequestering carbon dioxide, producing carbon-negative materials for the concrete and glass industries. Cement manufacturing is notoriously a huge polluter, so with regulations coming in, they and everyone else are jonesing for green processes and raw materials. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/heimdal-pulls-co2-and-cement-making-materials-out-of-seawater-using-renewable-energy/">I wrote this up in more detail here!</a></p>
<p><a href="https://unbox.ai/">Unbox</a>: QA doesn’t get enough love in the ML world, but it matters. ML models can be biased as heck, or simply broken. Unbox wants to help ML team members, both technical and not, to find issues in ML models and create tests to check to make sure that fixes work. The team hails from Apple. Unbox did not share growth metrics.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.joinfizz.com/">Fizz</a>: Fizz is building a debit card that helps college students in the U.S. start building out their credit without having to learn lessons about overzealous credit use the hard way. Building good credit early is critical but can be tough for college students operating on tight budgets, Fizz is building a platform designed for college students specifically.</p>
<p><a href="https://mentor.cam/">Mentorcam</a>: A marketplace connecting people with those they admire for advice — sorta like Cameo for 1:1 advice. Charging $20-$300 per video, they saw $7,000 in gross sales in August. Notably, the company says, nearly half of its users are repeat customers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.telm.ai/">Telmai</a>: Data quality can make or break a startup, so Telmai wants to be the reliable sidekick that sniffs out inaccuracies or anomalies before you do. The data observability platform uses a no-code onboarding process and claims it can begin working for clients within minutes. Beyond fighting bad data, Telmai offers high-level visualization, and soon, proactive alerts and user inputs for correctness. For data analytics teams, which are constantly deciding whether to escalate a blip, Telmai is meant to take some of the guesswork out of their days and more broadly simplify operations.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amenli.com/">Amenli</a>: Amenli is the first licensed online insurance broker in Egypt. Able to sign customers up in a few minutes for low-cost premiums around $200 per year, it&#8217;s hard to see how this can be anything but a runaway success assuming they do it right. Go get it, Amenli!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.usenash.com/">Nash</a>: This is fun. Nash has built software atop mass-market delivery APIs (it listed DoorDash and Uber, among others) to allow other companies to offer same-day delivery. Why is it neat? Because SMBs can’t code, having another company plug them into delivery networks could unlock the delivery market for companies that can’t afford an engineering team. Per Nash, it has a 10% take rate and is doing around $60,000 in GMV.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.bytekitchen.io/">Byte Kitchen</a>: Byte Kitchen wants to build ghost kitchens that make the best dishes from the best restaurants in the country, licensing brands and recipes and bringing them access to more markets. Its first kitchen is live, and the team says its has &#8220;20+ LOIs with popular restaurants.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://tenyks.ai/">Tenyks</a>: Helps AI developers figure out how/why their computer vision systems are doing what they&#8217;re doing and build more reliable systems. With both co-founders having Ph.D.s in &#8220;Explainable AI,&#8221; this one seems like a good fit. Founder Botty Dimanov says they&#8217;re currently working with one customer, with four more getting set up now and seven+ on the waitlist.</p>
<p><a href="https://maroo.us/">Maroo</a>: “Save the date” doesn’t exactly scream stable revenue, so Maroo is building a payments service for the wedding industry. The startup is rethinking how the business owners within the wedding industry — from caterers to that charming venue you eye every time you drive past it — receive payments. As for the happy couple, Maroo offers a buy now, pay later service for a more accessible financing option,</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tavus.io">Tavus</a>: Here&#8217;s one that might make you squint a little. Tavus wants to replace written outreach (think sales emails and such) with computer-generated deepfakes. Yes, you read that correctly. Customize the name, company and other aspects and get hundreds of tailored videos that look just like someone recorded a video message just for the recipient. Is it a good idea? We&#8217;ll see … but like it or not it&#8217;s here, and it seems to be effective. Let you and I proceed into this strange new world together, my friend.</p>
<p><a href="https://enso.org">Enso</a>: The team at Enso is building a data processing tool that helps automate developer processes that require a ton of repetitive manual work. The no-code platform wants to put components built by its community of experts into the hands of data scientists.</p>
<p><a href="https://getbritehr.com/">Brite</a>: When your employer offers you a zillion different benefits/insurance options, Brite helps you wade through it and figure out what&#8217;s right. Co-founder Ben Hale says they&#8217;ve already worked with over 400,000 employees (across 250+ employers) and are seeing an MRR of $28,000.</p>
<p><a href="https://metlo.io">Metlo</a>: The truth wins, and that’s a lesson for life and for startups. Metlo, built by former Facebook and Uber engineers, helps companies store their business metrics (like “daily active users”) in a standardized, transparent way across different tools without a bunch of duplicated work. In seven weeks, the startup landed four design partners.</p>
<p><a href="https://mergequeue.com">MergeQueue</a>: When you&#8217;ve got 20 engineers all coding separately to build a new feature, it can take as long to integrate and reconcile their work as it does to do it in the first place. MergeQueue automates code submission workflows to avoid build failures that result in costly code reviews and delays. The team encountered this issue at Google (easy to imagine) and hacked together their own solution there — now they&#8217;ve built something for everyone else to use.</p>
<p><a href="https://costcertified.com/">CostCertified</a>: Bringing price transparency to an opaque market is never too bad an idea. CostCertified wants to make the worlds of construction materials and labor more transparent with a marketplace and “real-time quoting engine” that it has built. Per the startup, it has around $250,000 in ARR from SaaS revenues today and intends to take a 1% cut of GMV in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/here-are-all-the-companies-from-day-two-of-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197301</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Crunch: Researchers claim Fortress S03 home security system can be remotely disabled</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/daily-crunch-57/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/daily-crunch-57/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richard Dal Porto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 22:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Crunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello friends and welcome to Daily Crunch, bringing you the most important startup, tech and venture capital news in a single package.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><em>To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important stories delivered to your inbox every day at 3 p.m. PDT, <a href="http://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">subscribe here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Hello and welcome to Daily Crunch for September 1, 2021. It’s a big day in TechCrunch history in that we’ve been shuffled to a new parent company. More on that in a moment. First, Disrupt attendees, you can <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/fire-up-crunchmatch-today-and-start-networking-with-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-attendees/">now hit up CrunchMatch to meet other cool folks</a>. See you there! &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/alex">Alex</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kRISMX7N10"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/fire-up-crunchmatch-today-and-start-networking-with-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-attendees/">Fire up CrunchMatch today and start networking with TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 attendees</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Fire up CrunchMatch today and start networking with TechCrunch Disrupt 2021 attendees&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/fire-up-crunchmatch-today-and-start-networking-with-techcrunch-disrupt-2021-attendees/embed/#?secret=kRISMX7N10" data-secret="kRISMX7N10" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The TechCrunch Top 3</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/apollo-completes-its-5b-acquisition-of-verizon-media-now-known-as-yahoo/">Hello, Apollo!</a> </strong>TechCrunch is no longer part of Verizon Media Group, a somewhat forgotten subsidiary of the U.S. telco. Instead, we are now part of Yahoo, which is owned, in turn, by Apollo, a large investing company that is publicly traded. Cue the parade. Jokes aside, the long-announced deal has finally been completed. We’ll have more notes on our new overlords as soon as we meet them.</li>
<li><strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/what-amplitudes-choice-to-direct-list-says-about-its-products-growth-and-value/">Inside Amplitude’s IPO filing:</a></strong> TechCrunch’s coverage of the accelerating IPO market continued today with notes on Amplitude’s product-analytics-focused debut. For more on Toast and Freshworks’ filings, <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/30/5-takeaways-from-toasts-s-1-filing/">head</a></strong> here or <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/inside-freshworks-ipo-filing-as-the/">here</a></strong>. Oh, <strong><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/25/d2c-specs-purveyor-warby-parker-files-to-go-public/">and Warby Parker here</a></strong>, if D2C is your jam.</li>
<li>Sticking to the big-dollar news today, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/vista-equity-takes-majority-stake-in-saas-startup-drift-taking-it-to-unicorn-status/"><strong>Vista Equity is buying a majority stake in Drift</strong></a>. Based in Boston, Drift focuses on what it calls “conversational” sales tools. The two parties were being coy to a silly level by not disclosing the price paid for Drift, other than that the majority sale of the company values the former startup at more than $1 billion. Why Drift sold to Vista instead of going public is not clear, but we do feel cheated out of its S-1 filing.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Startups/VC</h2>
<p>As we write to you today, the TechCrunch team is busy writing thousands of words about the second day of startup pitches from Y Combinator’s Demo Day. You can read about <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/here-are-all-the-companies-from-y-combinators-summer-2021-demo-day-part-1/">every startup that pitched yesterday</a>.</p>
<p>Now, to today’s news. First, Berlin Brands, which buys and hopes to scale brands that sell on Amazon, is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/berlin-brands-group-now-valued-at-1b-raises-700m-to-buy-and-scale-merchants-that-sell-on-marketplaces-like-amazon/">now worth north of $1 billion</a> after raising a $700 million equity-and-debt round. There is apparently infinite capital available to finance the purchase of smaller e-commerce brands.</p>
<p>So much so that Forum Brands <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/berlin-brands-group-now-valued-at-1b-raises-700m-to-buy-and-scale-merchants-that-sell-on-marketplaces-like-amazon/"><em>also</em> announced new capital for the activity today</a>. Its $100 million in debt financing may sound small compared to what Berlin Brands just secured, but it’s still nine figures of dry powder.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/blueprint-raises-16m-series-b-to-grow-its-title-focused-insurtech-business/"><strong>Blueprint raises $16M to scale its title insurance business:</strong></a> It turns out that the title insurance business in the United States is too valuable. Blueprint wants to reduce its size by offering lower-priced coverage to customers who buy multiple properties in several states.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/insurify-a-virtual-insurance-agent-raises-100m-series-b/"><strong>Insurify raises $100M as insurtech marketplaces stay hot:</strong></a> Sure, neoinsurance providers have <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/why-have-the-markets-spurned-public-neoinsurance-startups/">taken a bath in the public markets lately</a>, but the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/02/why-vcs-are-dumping-money-into-insurance-marketplaces/">insurtech <em>marketplace</em> game</a> still looks healthy. Insurify, which competes with Zebra and other players, is now $100 million richer.  An indicator, we presume, that it is still finding plenty of market to attack.</li>
<li>If you want more on the insurtech venture capital market, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/11/insurtech-is-hot-on-both-sides-of-the-atlantic/">TechCrunch has your back</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/skit-raises-23m-series-b-round-led-by-westbridge-capital-to-accelerate-its-growth/"><strong>Call center automation is big business:</strong></a> At least for Skit, a startup that just closed a $23 million Series B. Per our own Kate Park, Skit’s tech helps its customers automate nearly all of their voice support calls.</li>
<li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/humane-a-stealthy-hardware-and-software-startup-co-founded-by-an-ex-apple-designer-and-engineer-raises-100m/"><strong>Company we know little about raises lots of money:</strong></a> Have you heard of Humane? Probably not. Born from some ex-Apple folks, the startup &#8212; “which has ambitions to build a new class of consumer devices and technologies,” TechCrunch reports &#8212; has no products in the market. And yet it has raised $100 million this week after raising $30 million last year. What will it build? I guess we’ll find out.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Our favorite startups from YC’s Summer 21 Demo Day, Part 1</h2>
<p>Twice each year, we turn our attention to Y Combinator&#8217;s latest class of aspiring startups as they hold their public debuts.</p>
<p>For YC Summer 2021 Demo Day, the accelerator&#8217;s fourth virtual gathering, Natasha Mascarenhas, Alex Wilhelm, Devin Coldewey, Lucas Matney and Greg Kumparak selected 14 favorites from the first day of one of the world&#8217;s top pitch competitions.</p>
<p>Read their analysis, then come back later today for their rundown of Day Two.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5rEEEDNdg5"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-1/">Our favorite startups from YC’s Summer 21 Demo Day, Part 1</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Our favorite startups from YC’s Summer 21 Demo Day, Part 1&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/our-favorite-startups-from-ycs-summer-21-demo-day-part-1/embed/#?secret=5rEEEDNdg5" data-secret="5rEEEDNdg5" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><em>(Extra Crunch is our membership program, which helps founders and startup teams get ahead.</em><a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/"> You can sign up here</a><em>.)</em></p>
<h2>Big Tech Inc.</h2>
<p>Today’s Big Tech news is mostly focused on feature upgrades. Enjoy!</p>
<ul>
<li>Twitter! The social microblogging-and-newsletter-and-subscription-and-live-audio service is out with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-safety-mode-harassment/">new safety tools</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-super-follows-monetization/">the ability to sell Super Follows</a>.</li>
<li>Twitch! Twitch is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/">dealing with a streamer boycott</a> after many of its popular users were hit with so-called “hate raids.”</li>
<li>And in stuff today that Big Tech companies are doing that we’re not <em>entirely</em> sold on: Apple is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/apple-digital-licenses-privacy/">making digital driver&#8217;s licenses</a>; Google <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/google-appeals-disproportionate-french-copyright-talks-fine/">thinks that France is being too harsh</a>; and Facebook &#8212; which apparently wants to replicate the entire internet, in-house &#8212; is <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/facebook-enters-the-fantasy-gaming-market/">building fantasy sports tech</a>.</li>
<li>From the nightmare files, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/fortress-home-security-rapid7/">this headline:</a> “A popular smart home security system can be remotely disarmed, researchers say.” Ah yes, the future of the smart home. Better known as smart folks tricking your smart home into letting them in.</li>
</ul>
<h2>TechCrunch Experts: Growth Marketing</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2159841" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2159841" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2159841" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?w=680" alt="Illustration montage based on education and knowledge in blue" width="680" height="427" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=300,188 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=768,482 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=680,427 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/GettyImages-1009465486.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2159841" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=creative&amp;photographer=SEAN+GLADWELL" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAN GLADWELL <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>In case you didn’t catch it yesterday: We’re giving away one free ticket to Disrupt through the Experts <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">survey</a>. Check out the schedule for <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2021/">Disrupt</a>, and read on to learn about the giveaway details.</p>
<ul>
<li>Have you already submitted a recommendation? That’s great — we’re counting all previous survey submissions as an entry for the Disrupt ticket.</li>
<li>We’ll also enter the next 100 survey submissions into the giveaway.</li>
<li>Do you want to submit 10 recommendations to increase your chance at winning? We love the enthusiasm, but we ask that you only submit one recommendation for each marketer that you’ve worked with.</li>
<li>Don’t know what to say in your recommendation? Start with what traits they had, what they did to help your company, how their work affected your business and go from there!</li>
<li>We manually go through all entries, so please don’t copy and paste the same response multiple times.</li>
<li>Have a question about the giveaway? Send us an email at <a href="mailto:ec_editors@techcrunch.com">ec_editors@techcrunch.com</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2197234" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197234" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197234 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?w=300" alt="Jonathan Metrick" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg 3012w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jonathan_headshot.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197234" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Jonathan Metrick</p></div></p>
<p>Join Danny Crichton and Mary Ann Azevedo Tuesday, September 7, at 3 p.m. PDT/6 p.m. EDT on <a href="https://twitter.com/i/spaces/1OwxWVXZbLnJQ">Twitter Spaces</a> as they talk with Jonathan Metrick about fintech and growth marketing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/daily-crunch-57/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197203</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 tips to align your values with your startup&#8217;s culture</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/3-tips-to-align-your-values-with-your-startups-culture/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/3-tips-to-align-your-values-with-your-startups-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram Iyer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 21:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ceo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human resource management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership tactics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sailpoint]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Being a CEO is more than building on a vision, a product or an idea. It's about leading your people with values to accomplish mutual goals in a way that doesn't zap them of their morale or dignity.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Mark McClain</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/markmcclainceo">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		Mark McClain is the founder and CEO of <a href="https://www.sailpoint.com/">SailPoint</a>, the leader in cloud enterprise security. 	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">You&#8217;ve heard the phrase &#8220;leading by example,&#8221; but what about &#8220;leading with values&#8221;?</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve always led by example by using my values as my guide. Still, it wasn’t until I founded my first company that I fully understood the importance of embedding those values into the company, too.</p>
<p>Integrity, individuals, impact and innovation are the &#8220;<a href="https://www.sailpoint.com/company/#:~:text=SailPoint's%20success%20is%20directly%20tied,Integrity%2C%20Impact%2C%20and%20Individuals.">4 I values</a>&#8221; that drive my decisions and the actions of those at my company each day. These are not just words on a wall at our HQ or on a mousepad for our remote crew, but values that everyone in the company lives and breathes. Over the last two years, these four values became even more important and continued to guide me, my family and the leaders at our company.</p>
<p>As organizations map out their &#8220;return to the workplace&#8221; (NOT &#8220;return to work,&#8221; because we never stopped working) plans, we should not simply go back to how things were before. Instead, let’s all take a moment to redesign something that sets everyone up for success, with values as the compass. I think you’ll find this approach helps people not only survive, but thrive in the workplace.</p>
<p>Leading with values is, in my experience, the best leadership position to take, and there are three ways to accomplish this goal.</p>
<h2>Leave behind old-school mentalities on workplace hierarchy</h2>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			The tone of the company&#8217;s culture comes from the top. The culture you envision for your company will only come about if your employees believe in the practices that you are asking them to implement.					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>At some point in your career — probably right out of school, a few years in or somewhere in the middle — you experienced a company where treating lower-level employees with less respect is just &#8220;a part of the job.&#8221; Companies with this type of &#8220;paying your dues&#8221; mentality tend to work these lower-level employees like grunts until they burn out and leave.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Or they eventually crawl their way up into management-level positions, and the cycle perpetuates itself as they deride the newer crop of employees, eroding any semblance of a healthy culture.</p>
<p>This is not the way.</p>
<p>As a leader, if you want your work environment to indicate inclusivity, support, collaboration and have the essence of a team mentality, <em>you</em> must set the precedent right away. This means stripping away the hierarchy that accompanies work titles and making it clear that your company values contribution based on merit, regardless of position. You are one team, united in your purpose to deliver on your mission, based on your values. This level setting ensures that everyone has skin in the game, and no one has the leeway to treat people poorly.</p>
<h2>Don&#8217;t get caught in an ivory tower mindset</h2>
<p>Early on in my career, I began sharing an office when I could. Those office spaces were purposely not what anyone would consider cool or nice “digs&#8221; — not the furniture and certainly not the view. Even as CEO now, I’ve had someone on the team describe my current office as a closet. But it gets the job done.</p>
<p>Simple signals like this send a powerful message, and the signal must remain consistent. Don&#8217;t take a limo; rent a cheap car. Don&#8217;t fly first class; fly coach. These may seem like minor details, but one of the biggest pitfalls any CEO can encounter is falling victim to an ivory tower mindset — when you become so out of touch with the people you manage, your employees start to notice.</p>
<p>Make a cognizant effort to know your people. Implement a &#8220;management by walking around&#8221; strategy. Don&#8217;t sit in your office all day; get out on the floor among your people. Drop by their desks and ask them how their day is going. Eat lunch in the break room. Put in the effort to attend new hire onboarding.</p>
<p>Not physically back in the office? Drop into Slack channels and Zoom meetings. I once &#8220;Zoom bombed&#8221; a baby shower for one of our crew members just to hear all the well wishes, and it made my day and theirs. Overall, just be present and humanize your workspace. It pays off in spades.</p>
<h2>Be thoughtful and consistent with workplace practices</h2>
<p>The tone of the company&#8217;s culture comes from the top. The culture you envision for your company will only come about if your employees believe in the practices that you are asking them to implement. More importantly, you will not grow a solid culture if you don’t give these initiatives and practices 100% of your own effort.</p>
<p>For example, one new initiative we rolled out last year is a campaign we call &#8220;<a href="https://www.sailpoint.com/blog/rethinking-work-in-identity/">Free2Focus</a>.&#8221; Twice a week, the SailPoint crew is asked to avoid booking meetings for a couple of hours during Free2Focus time. Not only does this address Zoom fatigue, it also gives our crew the chance to catch their breath whichever way suits them best — whether that&#8217;s taking a walk, helping with their children&#8217;s schooling or just turning off the camera for a bit.</p>
<p>If I want my team to show themselves some grace during the week, I&#8217;ve found that I need to apply the same practice. This means not setting up meetings during Free2Focus, not sending emails all hours of the day and night and not judging people for taking breaks when they need them. I trust my team to get the job done largely on their own time and own their own terms. I promise, your employees’ performance will be better because of it.</p>
<p>Being a CEO is more than building on a vision, a product or an idea. It&#8217;s about leading your people with values to accomplish mutual goals in a way that doesn&#8217;t zap them of their morale or dignity. It&#8217;s easy to get caught up in all the things that come with a job, but if you don&#8217;t put in the effort to immerse yourself and your values into the entire company, you&#8217;ll end up too big for your own good — and certainly too big for your company&#8217;s good.</p>
<p>It won&#8217;t happen overnight, but remember, the smallest things are often the ones that have the biggest impact. If you’re the leader, lead by example. It’s the only way to build teams that stand the test of time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/3-tips-to-align-your-values-with-your-startups-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197038</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How a Vungle-owned mobile marketer sent Fontmaker to the top of the App Store</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/how-a-vungle-owned-mobile-marketer-sent-fontmaker-to-the-top-of-the-app-store/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/how-a-vungle-owned-mobile-marketer-sent-fontmaker-to-the-top-of-the-app-store/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 21:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LinkedIn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spokesperson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vibe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vungle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Does this sound familiar? An app goes viral on social media, often including TikTok, then immediately climbs to the top of the App Store where it gains even more new installs thanks to the heightened exposure. That&#8217;s what happened with the recent No. 1 on the U.S. App Store, Fontmaker, a subscription-based fonts app which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Does this sound familiar? An app goes viral on social media, often including TikTok, then immediately climbs to the top of the App Store where it gains even more new installs thanks to the heightened exposure. That&#8217;s what happened with the recent No. 1 on the U.S. App Store, <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/fontmaker-font-keyboard-app/id1573791613">Fontmaker</a>, a subscription-based fonts app which appeared to benefit from word-of-mouth growth thanks to TikTok videos and other social posts. But what we&#8217;re actually seeing here is a new form of App Store marketing &#8212; and one which now involves one of the oldest players in the space: <a href="https://vungle.com/">Vungle</a>.</p>
<p>Fontmaker, at first glance, seems to be just another indie app that hit it big.</p>
<p>The app, published by an entity called Mango Labs, promises users a way to create fonts using their own handwriting which they can then access from a custom keyboard for a fairly steep price of $4.99 per week. The app first launched on July 26. Nearly a month later, it was the No. 2 app on the U.S. App Store, according to Sensor Tower data. By August 26, it climbed up one more position to reach No. 1. before slowly dropping down in the top overall free app rankings in the days that followed.</p>
<p>By Aug. 27, it was No. 15, before briefly surging again to No. 4 the following day, then declining once more. Today, the app is No. 54 overall and No. 4 in the competitive Photo &amp; Video category &#8212; still, a solid position for a brand-new and somewhat niche product targeting mainly younger users. To date, it&#8217;s generated $68,000 in revenue, Sensor Tower reports.</p>
<p>But Fontmaker may not be a true organic success story, despite its Top Charts success driven by a boost in downloads coming from real users, not bots. Instead, it&#8217;s an example of how mobile marketers have figured out how to tap into the influencer community to drive app installs. It&#8217;s also an example of how it&#8217;s hard to differentiate between apps driven by influencer marketing and those that hit the top of the App Store because of true demand &#8212; like walkie-talkie app Zello, whose recent trip to No. 1 can be attributed to Hurricane Ida.</p>
<p>As it turns out, Fontmaker is not your typical &#8220;indie app.&#8221; In fact, it&#8217;s unclear who&#8217;s really behind it. Its publisher, Mango Labs, LLC, is actually an iTunes developer account owned by the mobile growth company <a href="https://jetfuel.it/">JetFuel</a>, which was <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/06/15/vungle-agrees-to-buy-influencer-marketing-platform-jetfuel/">recently acquired</a> by the mobile ad and monetization firm Vungle &#8212; a <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/08/15/vungle-series-a/">longtime</a> and sometimes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/12/zain-jaffer-sues-vungle/">controversial</a> player in this space, itself <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/15/blackstone-is-acquiring-mobile-ad-company-vungle/">acquired</a> by Blackstone in 2019.</p>
<p>Vungle was<a href="https://www.plugco.in/vungle-announcement"> primarily interested in</a> JetFuel&#8217;s main product, an app called <a href="https://www.plugco.in/">The Plug</a>, aimed at influencers.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Through The Plug, mobile app developers and advertisers can connect to JetFuel&#8217;s network of over 15,000 verified influencers who have a combined 4 billion Instagram followers, 1.5 billion TikTok followers, and 100 million daily Snapchat views.</p>
<p>While marketers could use the built-in advertising tools on each of these networks to try to reach their target audience, JetFuel&#8217;s technology allows marketers to quickly scale their campaigns to reach high-value users in the Gen Z demographic, the company claims. This system can be less labor-intensive than traditional influencer marketing, in some cases. Advertisers pay on a cost-per-action (CPA) basis for app installs. Meanwhile, all influencers have to do is scroll through The Plug to find an app to promote, then post it to their social accounts to start making money.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197102" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197102" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2197102" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="368" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg 2930w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?resize=150,81 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?resize=300,162 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?resize=768,416 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?resize=680,368 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?resize=1536,831 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1109 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.37.49-PM.jpg?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197102" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> The Plug&#8217;s website, showing influencers how the platform works</p></div></p>
<p>So while yes, a lot of influencers may have made TikTok videos about Fontmaker, which prompted consumers to download the app, the influencers were paid to do so. (And often, from what we saw browsing the Fontmaker hashtag, without disclosing that financial relationship in any way &#8212; an increasingly <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/03/tiktok-called-out-for-lack-of-ads-transparency-and-for-failing-to-police-political-payola/">common</a> <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jessedamiani/2020/06/11/tiktoks-format-offers-a-loophole-for-branded-content-disclosures/?sh=64260d421afa">problem</a> on TikTok, and area of concern for the FTC.)</p>
<p>Where things get tricky is in trying to sort out Mango Labs&#8217; relationship with JetFuel/Vungle. As a consumer browsing the App Store, it looks like Mango Labs makes a lot of fun consumer apps of which Fontmaker is simply the latest.</p>
<p>JetFuel&#8217;s website helps to promote this image, too.</p>
<p>It had showcased its influencer marketing system using a case study from an &#8220;indie developer&#8221; called Mango Labs and one of its earlier apps, Caption Pro. Caption Pro launched in Jan. 2018. (App Annie data indicates it was removed from the App Store on Aug. 31, 2021&#8230;yes, yesterday).</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197070" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197070" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2197070" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="213" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg 3176w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?resize=150,47 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?resize=300,94 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?resize=768,241 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?resize=680,213 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?resize=1536,482 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?resize=2048,642 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-12.48.24-PM.jpg?resize=50,16 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197070" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> App Annie</p></div></p>
<p>Vungle, however, told TechCrunch &#8220;The Caption Pro app no longer exists and has not been live on the App Store or Google Play for a long time.&#8221; (We can&#8217;t find an App Annie record of the app on Google Play).</p>
<p>They also told us that &#8220;Caption Pro was developed by Mango Labs before the entity became JetFuel,&#8221; and that the case study was used to highlight JetFuel&#8217;s advertising capabilities. (But without clearly disclosing their connection.)</p>
<p>&#8220;Prior to JetFuel becoming the influencer marketing platform that it is today, the company developed apps for the App Store. After the company pivoted to become a marketing platform, in February 2018, it stopped creating apps but continued to use the Mango Labs account on occasion to publish apps that it had third-party monetization partnerships with,&#8221; the Vungle spokesperson explained.</p>
<p>In other words, the claim being made here is that while Mango Labs, originally, were the same folks who have long since pivoted to become JetFuel, and the makers of Caption Pro, all the newer apps published under &#8220;Mango Labs, LLC&#8221; were not created by JetFuel&#8217;s team itself.</p>
<p>&#8220;Any apps that appear under the Mango Labs LLC name on the App Store or Google Play were in fact developed by other companies, and Mango Labs has only acted as a publisher,&#8221; the spokesperson said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197057" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197057" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2197057" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="425" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg 2510w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?resize=150,94 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?resize=300,187 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?resize=768,480 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?resize=680,425 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?resize=1536,960 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1279 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-08-30-at-6.15.13-PM.jpg?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197057" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> JetFuel&#8217;s website describing Mango Labs as an &#8220;indie developer&#8221;</p></div></p>
<p>There are reasons why this statement doesn&#8217;t quite sit right &#8212; and not only because JetFuel&#8217;s partners seem happy to hide themselves behind Mango Labs&#8217; name, nor because Mango Labs was a project from the JetFuel team in the past. It&#8217;s also odd that Mango Labs and another entity, <a href="https://www.takeoff-labs.com/">Takeoff Labs</a>, claim the same set of apps. And like Mango Labs, Takeoff Labs is associated with JetFuel too.</p>
<p>Breaking this down, as of the time of writing, Mango Labs has published several consumer apps on both the App Store and Google Play.</p>
<p>On iOS, this includes the recent No. 1 app Fontmaker, as well as FontKey, Color Meme, Litstick, Vibe, Celebs, FITme Fitness, CopyPaste, and Part 2. On Google Play, it has two more: Stickered and Mango.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197196" style="width: 324px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197196" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2197196" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?w=314" alt="" width="314" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png 1284w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?resize=69,150 69w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?resize=139,300 139w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?resize=768,1662 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?resize=314,680 314w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?resize=710,1536 710w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?resize=947,2048 947w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Image-from-iOS-3.png?resize=23,50 23w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197196" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Mango Labs</p></div></p>
<p>Most of Mango Labs&#8217; App Store listings point to JetFuel&#8217;s website as the app&#8217;s &#8220;developer website,&#8221; which would be in line with what Vungle says about JetFuel acting as the apps&#8217; publisher.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s odd, however, is that the Mango Labs&#8217; app Part2, links to Takeoff Labs&#8217; website from its App Store listing.</p>
<p>The Vungle spokesperson initially told us that Takeoff Labs is &#8220;an independent app developer.&#8221;</p>
<p>And yet, the Takeoff Labs&#8217; website shows a team which consists of JetFuel&#8217;s <a href="https://jetfuel.it/team">leadership</a>, including JetFuel co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tim-lenardo-2b220579/">Tim Lenardo</a> and JetFuel co-founder and CRO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jj-maxwell-753b5026/">JJ Maxwell</a>. Takeoff Labs&#8217; <a href="https://businesssearch.sos.ca.gov/Document/RetrievePDF?Id=201935710103-27397565">LLC application</a> was also signed by Lenardo.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Takeoff Labs&#8217; co-founder and CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rhai/">Rhai Goburdhun</a>, per his LinkedIn and the Takeoff Labs website, still works there. Asked about this connection, Vungle told us they did not realize the website had not been updated, and neither JetFuel nor Vungle have an ownership stake in Takeoff Labs with this acquisition.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197099" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197099" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2197099" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="405" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg 2812w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?resize=150,89 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?resize=300,179 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?resize=768,457 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?resize=680,405 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?resize=1536,914 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1219 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.35.21-PM.jpg?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197099" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Takeoff Labs&#8217; website showing its team, including JetFuel&#8217;s co-founders.</p></div></p>
<p><a href="https://www.takeoff-labs.com/#Case-Studies">Takeoff Labs&#8217; website</a> also shows off its &#8220;portfolio&#8221; of apps, which includes Celeb, Litstick, and FontKey &#8212; three apps that are published by Mango Labs on the App Store.</p>
<p>On Google Play, Takeoff Labs is the developer credited with Celebs, as well as two other apps, Vibe and Teal, a neobank. But on the App Store, Vibe is published by Mango Labs.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197118" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197118" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2197118" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="396" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg 2866w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?resize=150,87 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?resize=300,175 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?resize=768,447 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?resize=680,396 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?resize=1536,894 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?resize=2048,1192 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Screen-Shot-2021-09-01-at-1.53.34-PM.jpg?resize=50,29 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197118" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Takeoff Labs&#8217; website, showing its app portfolio.</p></div></p>
<p>(Not to complicate things further, but there&#8217;s also an entity called <a href="https://reallabs.io/work/">RealLabs</a> which hosts JetFuel, The Plug and other consumer apps, including Mango &#8212; the app published by Mango Labs on Google Play. Someone sure likes naming things &#8220;Labs!&#8221;)</p>
<p>Vungle claims the confusion here has to do with how it now uses the Mango Labs iTunes account to publish apps for its partners, which is a &#8220;common practice&#8221; on the App Store. It says it intends to transfer the apps published under Mango Labs to the developers&#8217; accounts, because it agrees this is confusing.</p>
<p>Vungle also claims that JetFuel &#8220;does not make nor own any consumer apps that are currently live on the app stores. Any of the apps made by the entity when it was known as Mango Labs have long since been taken down from the app stores.&#8221;</p>
<p>JetFuel&#8217;s system is messy and confusing, but so far successful in its goals. Fontmaker did make it to No. 1, essentially growth hacked to the top by influencer marketing.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Congrats to <a href="https://twitter.com/Rhai_Gb?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Rhai_Gb</a>  &amp; the <a href="https://twitter.com/Takeoff_Labs?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Takeoff_Labs</a>  team- it&#39;s great to be back at #1 overall <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f64c.png" alt="🙌" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Also a huge accomplishment for <a href="https://twitter.com/jetfuel_it?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@jetfuel_it</a> as the only user acquisition source. The first time we&#39;ve single-handedly moved an app to #1 Top Free! <a href="https://t.co/Cl8ahj8Owo">https://t.co/Cl8ahj8Owo</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Tim L (@telenardo) <a href="https://twitter.com/telenardo/status/1430551389193654280?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>But as a consumer, what this all means is that you&#8217;ll never know who actually built the app you&#8217;re downloading or whether you were &#8220;influenced&#8221; to try it through what were, essentially, undisclosed ads.</p>
<p>Fontmaker isn&#8217;t the first to growth hack its way to the top through influencer promotions. Summertime hit <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/26/poparazzi-hypes-itself-to-the-top-of-the-app-store/">Poparrazzi also hyped itself to the top of the App Store</a> in a similar way, as have many others. But Poparazzi has since sunk to No. 89 in Photo &amp; Video, which shows influence can only take you so far.</p>
<p>As for Fontmaker, paid influence got it to No. 1, but its Top Chart moment was brief.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/how-a-vungle-owned-mobile-marketer-sent-fontmaker-to-the-top-of-the-app-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196981</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bright Cellars lands more funding to personalize its subscription-based wine collection</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/subscription-based-bright-cellars-lands-more-funding-to-personalize-its-wines-and-educate-members/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/subscription-based-bright-cellars-lands-more-funding-to-personalize-its-wines-and-educate-members/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Connie Loizos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 20:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bright Cellars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cleveland Avenue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D2C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decentralized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midwest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northwestern Mutual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revolution ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subscription service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bright Cellars, a six-year-old subscription-based wine seller has, like many upstarts, evolved over time. While it once sent its club members third-party wines that fit their particular profiles, Milwaukee, Wisconsin-based Bright Cellars says it&#8217;s now amassing enough data about its customers that it no longer sells wines made by other brands. Instead, while some of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.brightcellars.com">Bright Cellars</a>, a six-year-old subscription-based wine seller has, like many upstarts, evolved over time. While it once sent its club members third-party wines that fit their particular profiles, Milwaukee, Wisconsin-based Bright Cellars says it&#8217;s now amassing enough data about its customers that it no longer sells wines made by other brands. Instead, while some of its &#8220;original&#8221; offerings are admittedly sold by other labels under different names, it is increasingly finding success by directing its winemaker partners to tweak the recipe, so to speak.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re optimizing wine like you might optimize a more digital product,&#8221; says co-founder and CEO, Richard Yau, a San Francisco native whose startup entered into a regional accelerator program early on and stayed, though the company is now largely decentralized.</p>
<p>We talked earlier today with Yau about that shift, which investors are supporting with $11.2 million in Series B funding, led by Cleveland Avenue, with participation from earlier backers Revolution Ventures and Northwestern Mutual. (The company has now raised roughly $20 million altogether).</p>
<p>Yau also talked about industry trends that he&#8217;s seeing because of all that data collection.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="gfda35j362"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/3-issues-to-resolve-before-switching-to-a-subscription-business-model/">3 issues to resolve before switching to a subscription business model</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;3 issues to resolve before switching to a subscription business model&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/24/3-issues-to-resolve-before-switching-to-a-subscription-business-model/embed/#?secret=gfda35j362" data-secret="gfda35j362" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><strong>TC: You&#8217;re building a portfolio of wines. What does that mean?</strong></p>
<p>RY: We don&#8217;t own any land. We&#8217;re working primarily with suppliers [as do big companies like Gallo and Constellation], but at a larger scale than before, so we now get to shape what wines taste like and look like, and we can optimize across variables like how sweet should this wine be? How acidic? What do we want its color and brand and label to look like and which segment of our customers will really enjoy this wine the most?</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><strong>TC: What&#8217;s one of your concoctions?</strong></p>
<p>RY: We have a sparkling wine that’s produced in the Champagne method — not a Champagne wine; it&#8217;s a domestic wine &#8212; using grape varietals that no one uses for sparkling wine, and it’s one of the top-rated wines on our platform. Sparkling wine has been really good for us.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How many subscribers do you have?</strong></p>
<p>RY: We can’t share that, but we saw an acceleration in not just new subscribers throughout the pandemic but also in terms of seeing a larger share of [customers&#8217;] wallets going to D2C, and that impacted us pretty positively. Even as things eased up over the summer, we saw that people were cooking and eating at home more [and drinking wine].</p>
<p><strong>TC: What&#8217;s the average price of a bottle of wine on the platform?</strong></p>
<p>RY: $20 to $25.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Where are your grape suppliers?</strong></p>
<p>RY: A lot are on the West Coast, in Washington and California, but we also have grape suppliers internationally, including in South America and Europe.</p>
<p><strong>TC: How many wines do you offer, and how long do you trial a wine?</strong></p>
<p>RY: We&#8217;ve tested around 600, and at any given time, we&#8217;ll have 40 to 50 wines on the platform. We don’t stock everything forever; those that don’t do as well, we basically eliminate.</p>
<p><strong>TC: A lot of D2C brands eventually branch into real-world locations. You aren&#8217;t doing that. Why not?</strong></p>
<p>RY: It&#8217;s possible that we might at some point, but we like being D2C and it makes a lot of sense in a world where our members now work from home and are home to receive packages. It lines up with e-commerce trends in general. If you’re not buying your groceries at the store anymore, you aren’t buying wines at the store, either.</p>
<p><strong>TC: From where are these bottles shipped?</strong></p>
<p>RY: From a variety of places, but primarily from Santa Rosa [in the Bay Area].</p>
<p><strong>TC: Have you seen the impact the weather is having on California winemakers, some of whom are now <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/18/climate/napa-wine-heat-hot-weather.html">spraying sunscreen</a> on their grapes to protect them?</strong></p>
<p>RY: [Climate change] has certainly affected the wine industry. One of the fortunate things about us is we have flexibility in the suppliers we’re working with, so from a business-health perspective, we haven’t been as affected by that. Because a lot of our operations are in California, we did a couple of years ago have some interruptions with distribution where we weren&#8217;t able to ship some days; we were also impacted by warm temperatures. But fortunately, so far for this year, we haven’t had any operational or supply-chain disruptions.</p>
<p><strong>TC: Have you been approached by one of legacy firms about a partnership or acquisition?</strong></p>
<p>RY: We’ve had conversations, more in terms of partnerships because we have lots of data and can help them. For example, we can launch a new wine and get feedback almost like a focus group to figure out who likes what. We can split test two different blends for a wine and figure out which does better. That’s where conversations with legacy wine companies have happened.</p>
<p><strong>TC: So they&#8217;d pay you for your data.</strong></p>
<p>RY: We&#8217;re not opposed to selling data in the future, but we’ve approached it more like, here’s an opportunity to learn about how innovation works at a larger wine company. We don&#8217;t expect to be able to do what Constellation does well &#8212; with its large salesforce and distributors in every state &#8212; but what we can do in a complementary way is understand the consumer.</p>
<p><strong>TC: What have you learned that might surprise outsiders?</strong></p>
<p>RY: Petite sirah [offerings] do as well, if not better than, cabernet and pinot noir on the platform. Cab and pinot are fully 50 times the market size of petite sirah, but we see that our members really like it.</p>
<p>People also like merlot a lot more than they think &#8212; pretty much across all demographics. People like to hate merlot, but when we look at red blends that do well . . .</p>
<p><strong>TC: What do people have against merlot?</strong></p>
<p>RY: [Laughs.] Have you ever seen &#8220;Sideways?&#8221; That has something to do with it, still. Meanwhile, pinot noir remains popular, but people don&#8217;t like it as much as [other wine sellers] think.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KXXDC5FarhE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/subscription-based-bright-cellars-lands-more-funding-to-personalize-its-wines-and-educate-members/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rocket Lab boosts its space systems division in quest to become an &#8216;end-to-end space company&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/rocket-lab-boosts-its-space-systems-divison-in-quest-to-become-an-end-to-end-space-company/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/rocket-lab-boosts-its-space-systems-divison-in-quest-to-become-an-end-to-end-space-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 20:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial spaceflight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter beck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satellites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Peter Beck hasn’t been shy about his intention to grow Rocket Lab into more than just a launch provider, but a fully vertically integrated space company that makes spacecraft in addition to sending them to orbit. The company, which he founded in 2006, has taken yet another major stride toward that goal with the news [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Peter Beck hasn’t been shy about his intention to grow Rocket Lab into more than just a launch provider, but a fully vertically integrated space company that makes spacecraft in addition to sending them to orbit. The company, which he founded in 2006, has taken yet another major stride toward that goal with the news Wednesday that it will open a new production facility to manufacture satellite components at a larger scale than ever before.</p>
<p>The facility will manufacture reaction wheels, critical attitude and stability control systems on satellites. Rocket Lab says the facility, which will be operational in the fourth quarter of this year, will be capable of producing up to 2,000 reaction wheels annually. Given that spacecraft generally have between three and four reaction wheels, it’s safe to assume that Rocket Lab customers likely have around 500 individual satellites ready in the pipeline to accept these components. “These are large volumes of supply across multiple constellations,” Rocket Lab CEO Beck said in a recent interview with TechCrunch.</p>
<p>The news is a marked expansion for Rocket Lab’s space systems business, which is already kept busy by the in-house Photon spacecraft and was boosted last year when <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/16/rocket-lab-to-acquire-satellite-hardware-maker-sinclair-interplanetary/">the company acquired</a> major satellite hardware manufacturer Sinclair Interplanetary. Rocket Lab also offers bespoke Photons for individual use cases &#8212; it will be designing the vehicles for forthcoming launches with space manufacturing startup <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/11/space-manufacturing-startup-varda-inks-deal-with-rocket-lab-for-three-spacecraft/">Varda Space Industries</a> and two Photons that will be <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/rocket-labs-mars-mission-gets-green-light-from-nasa/">sent to Mars</a> on an upcoming science mission.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vzYkliltnV"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/rocket-labs-mars-mission-gets-green-light-from-nasa/">Rocket Lab&#8217;s Mars mission gets green light from NASA</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Rocket Lab&#8217;s Mars mission gets green light from NASA&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/rocket-labs-mars-mission-gets-green-light-from-nasa/embed/#?secret=vzYkliltnV" data-secret="vzYkliltnV" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Historically, spacecraft components have generally been produced on the scale of tens or hundreds, because the barriers to get to orbit were so high. But as the cost of launch has declined (thanks in part to innovations from companies like Rocket Lab) more and more entities are able to send projects to space. That means more satellites, and more reaction wheels. Even today, there are around 200 Rocket Lab-made reaction wheels in orbit, so 2,000 in a single year is a huge jump in scale.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s all part of Rocket Lab&#8217;s goal of being a fully integrated space services company. A major benefit from the vertical integration for customers, Rocket Lab says, is slashed manufacturing lead times. Beck said that when the company first started producing Photons, they quickly encountered months-long delivery times for reaction wheels, which effectively pushed back their timeline for launching one to orbit.</p>
<p>“If the space economy is to grow in the way that it&#8217;s predicted, then this has to be solved,” he said. “This is a fundamental problem that has to be solved. The whole space supply chain is characterized by small-scale operations that really lack the ability to produce volume in any scale.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Rocket Lab will be hiring more than 16 roles to support the space systems division and the new production facility, which will otherwise be highly automated; the company said in a statement that the production tools and environmental testing workstations will all be automated, and the metal machining is optimized to operate unattended. Beck said these techniques are very much in line with Rocket Lab’s other manufacturing processes &#8212; he pointed to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/13/rocket-labs-new-rosie-the-robot-speeds-up-launch-vehicle-production-by-a-lot/">Rosie the Robot</a> as a cornerstone of the company’s capacity to use automation to rapidly scale its products.</p>
<p>Beck stayed mum about whether the company is planning on scaling the production of other spacecraft components, like the star trackers navigation tool, which Rocket Lab also manufacturers. However, he did say that the company plans on introducing new products &#8212; what those will be, he declined to specify. But Beck’s stated aim when he started the space systems division is that “everything that goes to space should have a Rocket Lab logo on it.&#8221;</p>
<p>That aim goes to Rocket Lab’s larger vision, which is becoming an end-to-end space company: combining launch services with spacecraft manufacturing to be able to build in-orbit infrastructure.</p>
<p>“When you combine those things together, you have an immensely powerful platform that you can use to develop infrastructure in orbit and ultimately provide services,” he said.</p>
<p>But when asked what kinds of services he was thinking of, Beck played it close to the chest, instead choosing to give a well-known example from a competitor: SpaceX’s Starlink internet satellite project, which it builds and launches itself. He stayed mum on what kinds of ventures Rocket Lab might pursue, just saying that the vertical integration gives the company the ability to try new business models.</p>
<p>“The marginal cost for us to experiment is very, very low.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/rocket-lab-boosts-its-space-systems-divison-in-quest-to-become-an-end-to-end-space-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196689</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virtual events startups have high hopes for after the pandemic</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/virtual-events-startups-have-high-hopes-for-after-the-pandemic/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/virtual-events-startups-have-high-hopes-for-after-the-pandemic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Karan Bhasin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 19:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Enterprise Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC investor survey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hemant Mohapatra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightspeed venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Murphy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virtual events have been a temporary measure during the pandemic. But what will their value be as more of the world attempts to return to life before the pandemic?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Few people thought of virtual events before the pandemic struck, but this format has fulfilled a unique and important need for companies and organizations large and small during the pandemic. But what will virtual events&#8217; value be as more of the world attempts to return to life before COVID-19?</p>
<p>To find out, we caught up with top executives and investors in the sector to learn about the big trends they’re seeing — as the sequel to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/17/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-remote-events/">this survey we did in March 2020</a>.</p>
<p>Certain use cases have been proven, they say. Today, you can find numerous small niche events available year-round that might have been buried in the back of a larger in-person conference before 2020. For organizations, internal virtual events can also be instrumental in helping connect and promote engagement for remote-first teams.</p>
<p>However, some respondents acknowledged that low-quality virtual events are growing ever more common, and everyone agreed that there is much more work to be done.</p>
<p><strong>We surveyed:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/xiaoyinqu/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Xiaoyin Qu</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, founder and CEO, </span><a href="https://www.runtheworld.today/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Run The World</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rosieroca/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rosie Roca</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, chief customer officer, </span><a href="https://hopin.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hopin</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hemantmohapatra/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hemant Mohapatra</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, partner, </span><a href="https://lsvp.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lightspeed Venture Partners India</span></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulbz/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paul Murphy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, former investor in Hopin with </span><a href="https://northzone.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Northzone</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (currently co-founder of </span><a href="https://gokatch.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Katch</span></a>)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Xiaoyin Qu, founder and CEO, Run The World</h2>
<p><strong>With the pandemic hopefully becoming more manageable soon, do you feel a return to in-person events is inevitable?<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Certain types of events will go back to in person. Obviously, something to do with a President&#8217;s Club — the company rewards you with a party in Hawaii — that kind of thing will not go virtual. I think events more focused on increasing reach will continue to trend toward virtual.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			&#8220;Hybrid is just another buzzword to say that both online and offline events formats will coexist. Of course they will.&#8221;					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>We’re also seeing that many events are getting smaller, more niche. Before the pandemic, if we look at a general pediatric conference, for example, an attendee may only be interested in two topics out of the 200 offered. But now we’ve seen that there&#8217;s a rise in many niche events that focus on very specific topics, which helps streamline these events for attendees.</p>
<p>I think such events are still going to happen virtually just because they&#8217;re easier to organize and people can have more in-depth conversations. Internal virtual events for employees is another category that is getting more traction, because companies have been going remote. So many the internal events like the company happy hour — events that help employees engage better — we think that&#8217;s still going to happen virtually. So there are a number of use cases we think will continue to be virtual and are probably better virtual.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Help TechCrunch find the best growth marketers for startups.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Provide a recommendation in <a href="https://oathtechevents.typeform.com/to/bwwIWF03">this quick survey</a> and we’ll share the results with everybody.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>What sort of trends do you think will emerge once in-person events are possible again?<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Another important trend we&#8217;re seeing is that a lot of organizers have begun hosting events more frequently. They were doing large conferences in the past, but now they&#8217;re pivoting or they&#8217;re rethinking their strategy. They realize that hosting maybe 10 events a year is better than hosting one big event every year. A traditional conference is usually multiday, with maybe 200 different topics and 100 different speakers. Now a lot of people are thinking about spreading it out throughout the year.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/virtual-events-startups-have-high-hopes-for-after-the-pandemic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196593</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Agility Robotics’ Digit gets a warehouse gig</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/agility-robotics-digit-gets-a-warehouse-gig/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/agility-robotics-digit-gets-a-warehouse-gig/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Heater]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 18:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agility robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fulfillment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new video from Agility Robotics showcases an increasing familiar sight: advanced, autonomous robots performing boring warehouse tasks. It’s not the sort of video that tends to be hugely viral for a company, rather, it’s the sort of meat and potatoes proof of concept that companies like Boston Dynamics wedge between flashy videos of parkour [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A new video from Agility Robotics showcases an increasing familiar sight: advanced, autonomous robots performing boring warehouse tasks. It’s not the sort of video that tends to be hugely viral for a company, rather, it’s the sort of meat and potatoes proof of concept that companies like Boston Dynamics wedge between flashy videos of parkour and highly choreographed dance sessions.</p>
<p>Ultimately, however, this is precisely the sort of tasks the robots’ creators are targeting: the well-known trio of dull, dirty and dangerous. Moving payloads back and forth certainly ticks that first box pretty well. There’s a reason warehouse and fulfillment workers often liken their work to robotics.</p>
<p><iframe class="youtube-player" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jycdks836bY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;fs=1&#038;hl=en-US&#038;autohide=2&#038;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" style="border:0;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
<p>“The conversation around automation has shifted a bit,” Agility CEO Damion Shelton tells TechCrunch. “It’s viewed as an enabling technology to allow you to keep the workforce that you have. There are a lot of conversations around the risks of automation and job loss, but the job loss is actually occurring now, in advance of the automated solutions.”</p>
<p>Digit, the bipedal robot the company announced back in 2020, had its most high-profile moment in the spotlight after Agility announced a partnership with auto giant Ford back at CES. The auto giant currently owns two of the robots, with long-term plans to utilize the technology for delivery.</p>
<p>Today’s video is an attempt to showcase some more short-term solutions, putting Digit to work on more menial tasks.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197116" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197116" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2197116" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Made-for-Work.2021-09-01-13_51_18-1.gif" alt="" width="800" height="450" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197116" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Agility Robotics</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The value and goal of a machine like Digit is the generality,” CTO Jonathan Hurst says. “It’s a robot that can operate in human environments and spaces. It’s a relatively straightforward thing for very structured, repetitive tasks, to say, &#8216;there’s going to be boxes over there. We’re going to tell you which one from a databasing system, and we want you to move it over there.&#8217; Maybe this is something that it does for three or four hours a day and then it goes to a different space and does it three or four hours and then it unloads a tractor trailer.”</p>
<p>The company sees Digit’s value as a more plug and play solution than something like Berkshire Gray’s offerings, which builds a fully automated warehouse from the ground up. There’s still programming involved, of course. An Agility rep will appear on-site to pre-map a location and help the robot execute its repetitive tasks.</p>
<p>“In terms of where we can actually deploy and do useful work for a customer, it turns out a lot of the tasks &#8212; walk from Point A to Point B, pick up and carry a package &#8212; are portable across these environments,” says Shelton. &#8220;There’s no real core piece of technology that you develop, that’s different for an indoor environment versus outdoor. It’s just the level of maturity. I think we’ve reached that pretty quickly on the indoor stuff, so it’s a logical first place for deployment.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197117" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197117" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2197117" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Made-for-Work.2021-09-01-13_48_22.gif" alt="" width="800" height="450" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197117" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Agility Robotics</p></div></p>
<p>Agility hasn’t announced partners beyond Ford, though it says it’s currently working with “major logistics companies.” It hasn’t revealed numbers of Digits sold, either, though it tells TechCrunch that the number is “substantially more” than the dozen Cassie units it sold prior to Digit, largely for research purposes. Sales are largely CapEx at the moment, though the company is exploring other opportunities, such as a RaaS (robotics-as-a-service model).</p>
<p>Agility’s team is currently at 56 people, primarily based in Oregon (the company got its start as part of OSU’s nascent robotics division), where the robots are primarily manufactured.</p>
<p>“We’ve grown pretty rapidly since last December,” says Shelton. “We’re expanding our Pittsburgh office by the end of the year, in addition to the Oregon office. We have a pretty rapid growth rate. As we’ve been increasing the production rate on the robots, we’ve had a fair amount of hiring for that. We just moved into a new facility that we remodeled, back in June.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eKhy4U7jvy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/05/agilitys-two-legged-robot-digit-is-for-sale-and-ford-is-the-first-customer/">Agility&#8217;s two-legged robot Digit is for sale and Ford is the first customer</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Agility&#8217;s two-legged robot Digit is for sale and Ford is the first customer&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/05/agilitys-two-legged-robot-digit-is-for-sale-and-ford-is-the-first-customer/embed/#?secret=eKhy4U7jvy" data-secret="eKhy4U7jvy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dNWhrTWODI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/21/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-manufacturing-and-warehouse-robotics/">Where top VCs are investing in manufacturing and warehouse robotics</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Where top VCs are investing in manufacturing and warehouse robotics&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/21/where-top-vcs-are-investing-in-manufacturing-and-warehouse-robotics/embed/#?secret=dNWhrTWODI" data-secret="dNWhrTWODI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/agility-robotics-digit-gets-a-warehouse-gig/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197107</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter rolls out paid subscription &#8216;Super Follows&#8217; to let you cash in on your tweets</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-super-follows-monetization/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-super-follows-monetization/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 18:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creator tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack dorsey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After opening applications in June, Twitter is rolling out Super Follows, its premium subscription option, starting today. The feature, first revealed in February, will allow users to subscribe to accounts they like for a monthly subscription fee in exchange for exclusive content. For creators, Super Follows are another useful tool in the emerging patchwork of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After opening <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/22/twitter-super-follows-and-ticketed-spaces/">applications</a> in June, Twitter is rolling out <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/">Super Follows</a>, its premium subscription option, starting today.</p>
<p>The feature, first revealed in February, will allow users to subscribe to accounts they like for a monthly subscription fee in exchange for exclusive content. For creators, Super Follows are another useful tool in the emerging patchwork of monetization options across social platforms.</p>
<p>Eligible accounts can set the price for Super Follow subscriptions, with the option of charging $2.99, $4.99 or $9.99 per month, prices fairly comparable to a paid newsletter. They can then choose to mark some tweets for subscribers only, while continuing to reach their unpaid follower base in regular tweets.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2197076" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2197076" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2197076 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?w=680" alt="Twitter Super Follows" width="680" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png 3788w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=1536,1536 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=2048,2048 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/super-follow-example.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2197076" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Paid subscribers will be marked with a special Super Follower badge, differentiating them from unpaid followers in the sea of tweets. The badge shows up in replies, elevating a follower&#8217;s ability to interact directly with accounts they opt to support. For accounts that have Super Follows turned on, the option will show up with a distinct button on the profile page.</p>
<p>Super Follows aren&#8217;t turned on for everyone. For now, the process remains application only, with a waitlist. The option lives in the Monetization options in the app&#8217;s sidebar, though users will need to be U.S.-based with 10K followers and at least 25 tweets within the last month to be eligible.</p>
<p>U.S. and Canada-based iOS Twitter users will be able to Super Follow some accounts starting today, with more users globally seeing the rollout in the coming weeks. On the creator side, Super Follows are only enabled in iOS for now, though support for Android and desktop are &#8220;coming soon.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tI0a228V2l"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/">Twitter&#8217;s &#8216;Super Follow&#8217; creator subscription takes shots at Substack and Patreon</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter&#8217;s &#8216;Super Follow&#8217; creator subscription takes shots at Substack and Patreon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/25/twitters-super-follow-creator-subscription-takes-shots-at-substack-and-patreon/embed/#?secret=tI0a228V2l" data-secret="tI0a228V2l" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Twitter says that Super Follow income will be subject to the standard, though controversial, 30% in-app purchase fees collected by Apple or Google. Twitter will only take a 3% cut of earnings for up to the first $50,000 generated through Super Follows — a boon for smaller accounts getting off the ground or anyone who uses the paid Twitter feature as a way to supplement other creator income elsewhere. After an account hits the $50,000 earnings mark, Twitter will begin taking a 20% cut.</p>
<p>Super Follows aren&#8217;t Twitter&#8217;s first monetization experiment to make it out in the wild. In May, Twitter introduced Tip Jar, a way for accounts to receive one-time payments through integration with the Cash App and other payment platforms. The test is limited to a subset of eligible accounts including &#8220;creators, journalists, experts, and nonprofits&#8221; for the time being.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rgmnMVma4g"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/twitter-starts-to-roll-out-paid-ticketed-spaces-on-ios/">Twitter starts to roll out paid Ticketed Spaces on iOS</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter starts to roll out paid Ticketed Spaces on iOS&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/twitter-starts-to-roll-out-paid-ticketed-spaces-on-ios/embed/#?secret=rgmnMVma4g" data-secret="rgmnMVma4g" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Last week <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/26/twitter-starts-to-roll-out-paid-ticketed-spaces-on-ios/">Twitter rolled out Ticketed Spaces</a> for users who applied for the paid audio room feature back in June. Twitter&#8217;s cut from Ticketed Spaces mirrors the same fee structure it uses for Super Follows and users will be able to charge anywhere from one dollar to $999 for advanced ticketing.</p>
<p>The product is the latest in a flurry of activity from the social platform after a lengthy period of product stagnation. But Twitter has been busy in the last 12 months, from releasing and killing its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/03/twitter-fleets-rip/">ill-fated Fleets</a> to finally <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-safety-mode-harassment/">showing signs of life</a> on the kind of anti-abuse features many people have been calling for for years.</p>
<p>Giving users the ability to charge for premium content is a pretty major departure for Twitter, which mostly stayed the course until activist shareholders <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/twitter-jack-dorsey-ouster-ceo-elliott-management-paul-singer-2020-2">threatened to oust CEO Jack Dorsey</a>. It&#8217;s also a major move for the company into the white-hot creator space, as more platforms add tools to empower their users to make a living through content creation — ideally keeping them loyal and generating revenue in the process.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZcrUazuZof"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/twitter-expands-spaces-to-anyone-with-600-followers-details-plans-for-tickets-reminders-and-more/">Twitter expands Spaces to anyone with 600+ followers, details plans for tickets, reminders and more</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter expands Spaces to anyone with 600+ followers, details plans for tickets, reminders and more&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/03/twitter-expands-spaces-to-anyone-with-600-followers-details-plans-for-tickets-reminders-and-more/embed/#?secret=ZcrUazuZof" data-secret="ZcrUazuZof" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e3mZY06qeJ"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/patreon-business/">The business of Patreon</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The business of Patreon&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2019/02/12/patreon-business/embed/#?secret=e3mZY06qeJ" data-secret="e3mZY06qeJ" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-super-follows-monetization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197069</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Berlin Brands Group, now valued at $1B+, raises $700M to buy and scale merchants that sell on marketplaces like Amazon</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/berlin-brands-group-now-valued-at-1b-raises-700m-to-buy-and-scale-merchants-that-sell-on-marketplaces-like-amazon/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/berlin-brands-group-now-valued-at-1b-raises-700m-to-buy-and-scale-merchants-that-sell-on-marketplaces-like-amazon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ingrid Lunden]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 17:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bain Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin Brands Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197027</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Berlin Brands Group (BBG) &#8212; one of the new wave of e-commerce startups hoping to build lucrative economies of scale around buying up smaller brands that sell on marketplaces like Amazon and using technology to run and scale them more efficiently &#8212; has picked up a big round of funding to fill out that mission. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.berlin-brands-group.com/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berlin Brands Group</a> (BBG) &#8212; one of the new wave of e-commerce startups hoping to build lucrative economies of scale around buying up smaller brands that sell on marketplaces like Amazon and using technology to run and scale them more efficiently &#8212; has picked up a big round of funding to fill out that mission. The startup has closed a round of $700 million, comprising both equity and debt, which it will use in part to continue building its fulfillment and logistics infrastructure, as well as its tech platform, and in part to buy more companies.</p>
<p>BBG confirmed that the investment &#8212; one of the biggest to date in the space &#8212; boosts its valuation to over $1 billion.</p>
<p>Bain Capital is leading the equity portion of this round. The deal will also see it buy out a previous investor, Ardian, for an undisclosed amount that is separate to the $700 million raise.</p>
<p>This funding round is the second announced by BBG this year. In January it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/berlin-brands-group-commits-302m-to-acquire-d2c-and-amazon-merchants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced it would be investing $302 million</a> off its own balance sheet for M&amp;A, and in April it announced a debt round <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/berlin-brands-group-raises-240m-to-buy-and-scale-up-third-party-amazon-marketplace-brands/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">of $240 million</a>. This latest $700 million is different in that it includes the equity component alongside the equity.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="esQ9Mpc7nr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/5-predictions-for-the-future-of-e-commerce/">5 predictions for the future of e-commerce</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;5 predictions for the future of e-commerce&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/21/5-predictions-for-the-future-of-e-commerce/embed/#?secret=esQ9Mpc7nr" data-secret="esQ9Mpc7nr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>BBG got its start initially developing its own products and selling them on Amazon and other marketplaces &#8212; founder and CEO Peter Chaljawski was a DJ in a previous life and started with a focus on audio equipment he developed for himself.</p>
<p>Over time, he saw an opportunity to diversify that into a wider consolidation play, where BBG would also acquire and merge third-party brands into its business, tapping into the opportunity to provide the owners of the third-party businesses an exit route and bring those smaller brands more scale, more marketing nous and more tech to improve the efficiency of their operations.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Today the mix totals 3,700 products and 14 own brands, including Klarstein (kitchen appliances), auna (home electronics and music equipment), Capital Sports (home fitness) and blumfeldt (garden). BBG says it has access to some 1.5 billion e-commerce customers across various marketplaces where it sells goods in Europe, the U.K., the U.S. and Asia. Notably, unlike many others in the same space as BBG, it is focused on more than Amazon, with some 100 channels in 28 countries.</p>
<p>That list of &#8220;many others in the same space&#8221; is a long one and seemingly growing by the day. Yesterday, two of them &#8212; <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/uk-based-heroes-raises-200m-to-buy-up-more-amazon-merchants-for-its-roll-up-play/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroes</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/olsam-raises-165m-to-buy-up-and-scale-consumer-and-b2b-amazon-marketplace-sellers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Olsam</a> &#8212; respectively raised $200 million and $165 million. Others leveraging the opportunity of consolidating merchants that sell via Fulfillment by Amazon include <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/04/suma-brands-raises-150m-to-acquire-more-third-party-brands-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Suma Brands</a> ($150 million), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/12/elevate-brands-banks-250m-to-roll-up-third-party-merchants-selling-on-amazons-marketplace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elevate Brands</a> ($250 million), <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/softbanks-vision-fund-2-leads-775m-investment-in-perch-sets-new-record-for-fastest-company-to-achieve-profitable-unicorn-status-in-the-us-301299324.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Perch</a> ($775 million), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/20/factory14-raises-200m-to-jump-into-the-amazon-marketplace-roll-up-race/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">factory14</a> ($200 million), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/01/thrasio-raises-100m-for-its-amazon-roll-up-play-appoints-retail-cfo-heavyweight-for-its-next-steps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thrasio</a> (currently probably the biggest of them all in terms of reach and money raised and ambitions), <a href="https://heyday.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heyday</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/04/berlins-razor-group-raises-400m-to-buy-and-scale-amazon-marketplace-merchants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Razor Group</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/target-global-leads-150m-round-for-amazon-marketplace-consolidator-branded/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Branded</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/11/19/sellerx-raises-118m-to-buy-up-and-grow-amazon-marketplace-businesses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SellerX</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/28/berlin-brands-group-commits-302m-to-acquire-d2c-and-amazon-merchants/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berlin Brands Group</a> (<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/berlin-brands-group-raises-240m-to-buy-and-scale-up-third-party-amazon-marketplace-brands/">X2</a>), <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/benitago-group-funding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Benitago</a>, Latin America’s <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/16/valoreo-raises-50m-to-roll-up-latam-e-commerce-brands/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Valoreo</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/founded-by-former-carousell-ovo-and-fave-execs-rainforest-raises-36m-to-aggregate-asia-pacific-amazon-marketplace-sellers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rainforest</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/una-brands-launches-with-40m-to-acquire-brands-on-multiple-asia-pacific-e-commerce-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Una Brands</a> out of Asia.</p>
<p>As more startups enter the fray, battling to buy the best of the third-party brands will become more of a challenge, and so the backing of Bain should help BBG shore up against that competition.</p>
<p>&#8220;With Bain Capital&#8217;s commitment and the additional funding secured, we have set our next milestone on our path to building a global house of brands,&#8221; said Chaljawski in a statement. &#8220;This allows us to tackle strategic goals of acquiring and developing brands globally, as well as the operational and logistical expansion. Bain Capital&#8217;s experience working with founders worldwide will help us continue our evolution as a leading e-commerce company in scaling brands.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;BBG is a disruptive leader in the rapidly changing consumer goods space. Their ability to develop and scale brands that meet current consumer trends through their highly efficient e-commerce platform gives the company tremendous growth potential in a fast-growing market,&#8221; added Miray Topay, MD at Bain Capital Private Equity. &#8220;We have partnered with many founder-led management teams and look forward to helping Peter and his team achieve their goal of becoming a global leader in consumer e-commerce&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/berlin-brands-group-now-valued-at-1b-raises-700m-to-buy-and-scale-merchants-that-sell-on-marketplaces-like-amazon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197027</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sphere raises $2M to help employees lobby for green 401(k) plans</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/sphere-raises-2m-to-help-employees-lobby-for-green-401k-plans/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/sphere-raises-2m-to-help-employees-lobby-for-green-401k-plans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Butcher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 17:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ayar labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corporate Social Responsibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heidi Lindvall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pale Blue Dot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private Equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2197086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the United States, a 401(k) plan is an employer-sponsored defined-contribution pension account. However, with legacy institutional investing, most of these have at least some level of fossil fuel involvement, and, let’s face it, very few of us really know. Now a startup plans to change that. California-based startup Sphere wants to get employees to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the United States, a 401(k) plan is an employer-sponsored defined-contribution pension account. However, with legacy institutional investing, most of these have at least some level of fossil fuel involvement, and, let’s face it, very few of us really know. Now a startup plans to change that.</p>
<p>California-based startup <a href="http://oursphere.org">Sphere</a> wants to get employees to ask their employers for investment options that are not invested in fossil fuels. To do that it’s offering financial products that make it easier &#8212; it says &#8212; for employers to offer fossil-free investment options in their 401(k) plans. This could be quite a big movement. Sphere says there are more than $35 trillion in assets in retirement savings in the U.S. as of Q1 2021.</p>
<p>It’s now raised a $2 million funding round led by climate tech-focused VC Pale Blue Dot. Also participating were climate-focused investors including Sundeep Ahuja of Climate Capital. Sphere is also a registered &#8220;Public Benefit Corporation,&#8221; allowing it to campaign in public about climate change.</p>
<p>Alex Wright-Gladstein, CEO and founder of Sphere said: “We are proud to be partnering with Pale Blue Dot on our mission to reverse climate change by making our money talk. Heidi, Hampus, and Joel have the experience and drive to help us make big changes on the short seven-year time scale that we have to limit warming to 1.5°C.” Wright-Gladstein has also teamed up with sustainable investing veteran Jason Britton of Reflection Asset Management and BITA custom indexes.</p>
<p>Wright-Gladstein said she learned the difficulty of offering fossil-free options in 401(k) plans when running her previous startup, Ayar Labs. She tried to offer a fossil-free option for employees, but found out it took would take three years to get a single fossil-free option in the plan.</p>
<p>Heidi Lindvall, general partner at Pale Blue Dot, said: “We are big believers in Sphere&#8217;s unique approach of raising awareness through a social movement while offering a range of low-cost products that address the structural issues in fossil-free 401(k) investing.”</p>
<div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/sphere-raises-2m-to-help-employees-lobby-for-green-401k-plans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2197086</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Streamers are boycotting Twitch today to protest the platform&#8217;s lack of action on &#8216;hate raids&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Silberling]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 17:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberbullying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harassment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hateful content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streamers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trolling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the last month, Twitch users have become increasingly concerned and frustrated with bot-driven hate raids. To protest Twitch&#8217;s lack of immediate action to prevent targeted harassment of marginalized creators, some streamers are going dark to observe #ADayOffTwitch today. Per the protest, users are sharing a list of demands for the Amazon-owned Twitch. They want [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Over the last month, Twitch users have become increasingly concerned and frustrated with bot-driven hate raids. To protest Twitch&#8217;s lack of immediate action to prevent targeted harassment of marginalized creators, some streamers are going dark to observe #ADayOffTwitch today.</p>
<p>Per the protest, users are sharing a <a href="https://twitter.com/LuciaEverblack/status/1432749839641632775">list of demands</a> for the Amazon-owned Twitch. They want the platform to host a roundtable with creators affected by hate raids, allow streamers to approve or deny incoming raids, enable tools to only allow accounts of a certain age to chat, remove the ability to attach more than three accounts to one email address and share a timeframe for when comprehensive anti-harassment tools will be implemented.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hey friendos, I won’t be streaming tomorrow in support of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ADayOffTwitch?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ADayOffTwitch</a>. (Here’s a handy graphic of some of the things those protesting are asking of <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Twitch</a> in case you’re not familiar with what’s going on.) I’ll be back on Thursday for our first swing at Senior Detective! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f49c.png" alt="💜" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/OA9NQlTnq3">pic.twitter.com/OA9NQlTnq3</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Meg Turney (@megturney) <a href="https://twitter.com/megturney/status/1432876805678116864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 1, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>TechCrunch asked Twitch if it has plans to address these demands. Twitch responded with a statement: &#8220;We support our streamers’ rights to express themselves and bring attention to important issues across our service. No one should have to experience malicious and hateful attacks based on who they are or what they stand for, and we are working hard on improved channel-level ban evasion detection and additional account improvements to help make Twitch a safer place for creators.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Twitch </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/20/twitch-unveils-a-suite-of-new-tools-to-help-creators-grow-their-channels-and-make-money/">Raids</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> are a part of the streaming platform&#8217;s culture &#8212; after one creator ends their stream, they can &#8220;raid&#8221; another stream by sending their viewers over to check out someone else&#8217;s channel. This feature is supposed to help more seasoned streamers support up-and-comers, but instead, it&#8217;s been weaponized as a tool for harassment.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0VtALmU52C"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/twitch-updates-its-hateful-content-and-harassment-policy-after-company-called-out-for-its-ownabuses/">Twitch updates its hateful content and harassment policy after company called out for its own abuses</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitch updates its hateful content and harassment policy after company called out for its own abuses&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/twitch-updates-its-hateful-content-and-harassment-policy-after-company-called-out-for-its-ownabuses/embed/#?secret=0VtALmU52C" data-secret="0VtALmU52C" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">In May, Twitch launched 350 new tags related to gender, sexual orientation, race and ability, which users </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://twitch.uservoice.com/forums/310210-discover/suggestions/37011022-trans-tag-request">requested</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> so that they could more easily find creators that represent them. But at the same time, these tags made it easier for bad actors to harass marginalized streamers, and Twitch hasn&#8217;t yet added tools for streamers to deal with increased harassment. In the meantime, Twitch users have had to take matters into their own hands and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22633874/how-to-stop-a-hate-raid-twitch-safety-tools">build their own safety tools</a> to protect themselves while Twitch works on its updates. Twitch hasn&#8217;t shared when its promised anti-harassment tools will go live.  </span></p>
<p>As recently as December, Twitch <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/09/twitch-updates-its-hateful-content-and-harassment-policy-after-company-called-out-for-its-ownabuses/">updated its policies</a> on hateful content and harassment, which the platform said have always been prohibited, yet vicious attacks have continued. After facing targeted, racist hate raids on their streams, a Black Twitch creator, <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/rekitraven">RekItRaven</a>, started the #TwitchDoBetter hashtag on Twitter in early August, calling out Twitch for its failure to prevent this abuse. While Twitch is aware of the issue and said it&#8217;s working on solutions, <a href="https://www.change.org/p/amazon-twitch-do-better-stop-hate-raids-against-people-of-color-and-marginalized-creators?recruiter=60679039&amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=psf_combo_share_initial&amp;utm_term=share_petition&amp;recruited_by_id=cdf10ce0-f224-0130-2417-0022190c02ea">many users</a> find Twitch&#8217;s response to be too slow and lacking.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">We&#39;ve been building channel-level ban evasion detection and account improvements to combat this malicious behavior for months. However, as we work on solutions, bad actors work in parallel to find ways around them—which is why we can&#39;t always share details.</p>
<p>&mdash; Twitch (@Twitch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1428814017779306499?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>Along with streamers LuciaEverblack and ShineyPen, RekItRaven organized #ADayOffTwitch to put pressure on Twitch to make its platform safer for marginalized creators.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hate on the platform is not new,&#8221; Raven told <a href="https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/takeaway/segments/black-content-creators-organize-one_day-boycott-against-twitch">WYNC&#8217;s The Takeaway</a>. But bot-driven raid attacks are more difficult to combat than individual trolls. &#8220;I&#8217;ve had people come in with bots. It&#8217;s usually one or two people who program a bunch of bots, you bypass security measures that are put in place and just spam a broadcaster&#8217;s chat with very inflammatory, derogatory language.&#8221;</p>
<p>While Raven said they have since had a discussion with Twitch, they don&#8217;t feel that one conversation is enough.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Turns out a bunch of LGBTQUIA2+, BIPOC, Disabled, Neurodivergent, and Plural creators really can make a difference by showing up, being loud, and not backing down despite people telling us we won&#39;t accomplish anything. Just remember, we aren&#39;t done yet. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ADayOffTwitch?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ADayOffTwitch</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Lucia Everblack (@LuciaEverblack) <a href="https://twitter.com/LuciaEverblack/status/1430711114761965573?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 26, 2021</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>As part of #ADayOffTwitch, some streamers are encouraging their followers to support them financially on other platforms through the #SubOffTwitch tag. Twitch takes 50% of streamers&#8217; revenue, so creators are promoting their accounts on platforms like Patreon and Ko-Fi, which take a much smaller cut. Though competitor YouTube Gaming takes 30% of revenue, and Facebook Gaming <a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/facebook-no-creator-revenue-split-2023-zuckerberg-1234990191/">won&#8217;t take a cut from creators</a> until 2023, Twitch remains dominant in the streaming space. According to Streamlabs and Stream Hatchet, Twitch <a href="https://blog.streamlabs.com/streamlabs-stream-hatchet-q1-2021-live-streaming-industry-report-eaba2143f492">represented 72.3%</a> of the market share in terms of viewership Q1 2021.</p>
<p>Still, popular creators like Ben Lupo (DrLupo), Jack Dunlop (CouRage) and Rachell Hofstetter (Valkyrae) have recently <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/30/22643215/drlupo-move-from-twitch-youtube-gaming-exclusivity-deal">left Twitch</a> for exclusive deals with YouTube Gaming. If Twitch remains unsafe for marginalized creators, others might be swayed to follow their lead, exclusive deals or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/streamers-are-boycotting-twitch-today-to-protest-the-platforms-lack-of-action-on-hate-raids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ubco 2X2 Adventure Bike review: Utility that shreds</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/ubco-2x2-adventure-bike-review-utility-that-shreds/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/ubco-2x2-adventure-bike-review-utility-that-shreds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Bellan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric bikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micromobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ubco 2x2 adventure bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2187553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company provided me with the Ubco 2X2 Adventure Bike for nearly a month, which gave me plenty of time to put it to the test. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A recent move to Auckland, New Zealand — a city with lackluster public transit and hills that can turn a quick bike ride to the store into a sweaty workout — piqued my interest in e-bikes.</p>
<p>Strong demand and skyrocketing prices, however, made it difficult to access these coveted e-bikes here in Aotearoa, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aotearoa">Land of the Long White Cloud</a>. That changed after learning about Ubco, the New Zealand-based electric utility bike startup that recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/21/electric-utility-bike-startup-ubco-raises-10-million-to-fund-its-global-expansion/">raised $10 million</a> from investors.</p>
<p>The company provided me with the Ubco 2X2 Adventure Bike for nearly a month, which gave me plenty of time to put it to the test.</p>
<p>I may not be Ubco’s target audience, although I did my best to use the bike as its design suggests, and packed it up with bags of books and other heavy things that might simulate the weight of delivered garlic bread, mail and other packages. The Ubco 2X2 Adventure Bike is made for city utility riding, with the option of going off-road, which I would later try with gusto.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s flagship is the Ubco 2X2 Work Bike, an electric dirt bike that was originally designed to help farmers. The fresh capital the company raised in June will be used to expand into existing verticals like food delivery, postal service and last-mile logistics, scale a commercial subscription business and target sales growth in the United States.</p>
<p>Domino’s drivers in Auckland, and I hear in the U.K., can be seen delivering hot pizzas on Ubco bikes, and the company has a range of other national clients, like the New Zealand Post, the Defense Force, the Department of Conservation, and Pāmu, or Landcorp Farming Limited, as well as other local restaurants and stores.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187575" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187575" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2187575 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6054.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187575" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rebecca Bellan</p></div></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<h2>The handoff</h2>
<p>CEO and co-founder Timothy Allan drove out from the company headquarters in Tauranga to hand off the bike personally. It was a sunny day in my neighborhood, and I listened impatiently as he described the various bits and bobs, how to work the machine and how to charge it.</p>
<p>Allan helped me download the Ubco app to pair my phone with the bike, which, among other functionalities, allowed me to select beginner mode, which would cap the vehicle speed at around 20 miles per hour. I made a mental note so that I could write about it here, but was determined to reach the top speed of 30 miles per hour right away.</p>
<p>I did, and it was … pretty sick. I’m not supposed to gush, but man! It’s a sweet ride. Here’s why:</p>
<h2>Appearance</h2>
<p>The Adventure Bike comes standard in white and sits on 17&#215;2.75-inch multiuse tires with aluminum rims, both of which are DOT compliant. My version also had Maori decals on the frame, in a nod to the indigenous people of New Zealand.</p>
<p>The bike’s height is about 41 inches and the seat comes to 32 inches. From wheel to wheel, it’s about 72 inches. The payload, including the rider, is about 330 pounds, so both my partner (6’2” man) and I (5’7” female) rode this bike with ease, needing only to adjust the wide rearview mirrors sticking out of the handlebars. And no, we didn’t ride it together. This bike is designed as a one-seater.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187584" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187584" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2187584 size-full" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6049.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187584" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rebecca Bellan</p></div></p>
<p>That said, there’s a little cargo rack above the back wheel, which holds the license plate (apparently these are classified as mopeds, which require registration in many places) and any other cargo one might carry. I didn’t try, but I reckon it could hold at least five pizza boxes tied down with a bungee cord. The bike rack also allows for saddlebags to be strapped on. Ubco sells what it calls the Pannier Back Pack, a weather-resistant roll-top cargo bag, for $189 that slots in very nicely and is actually a quality bag with 5.28-gallon capacity.</p>
<p>Accessories aside, the alloy frame is lightweight and step-through, which I love in a bike &#8212; it lets me start to shift myself off before I fully park and I feel super agile and swift. Speaking of parking, the rules are different everywhere, I assume, but here, you park it on the street or in parking spaces, not on the sidewalk. It’s got a kickstand to hold it in place, and you can lock the front wheel so no one can just wheel it away. They <i>could,</i> however, probably chuck it into the back of their pickup truck if they so chose, since it’s only 145 pounds.</p>
<p>The appearance of the bike stood out, and not just to me. During my multiweek test drive, numerous tradesmen and bike folks went out of their way to compliment its design, the exact demographic that Ubco is aiming for.</p>
<h2>Rideability</h2>
<p>The lightness of the bike means that it’s easy to take off and find your balance. The battery is also in the middle of the frame, just near where your feet sit, which anchors the bike and gives you a stable center of gravity.</p>
<p>The lightweight nature of the bike is a blessing and a curse. Cutting a turn is easy, but on a windy day and an open road, there were moments I worried that I’d be knocked off it &#8212; but maybe that had more to do with riding next to a 10-wheeler on the street. Because it’s so light, it did feel a bit strange to me to be in the street lane with the other bigger, meaner cars rather than in the bike lanes.</p>
<p>The bike accelerates quickly via the fully electronic throttle control, even up steep hills, due to the high torque geared drivetrain. The drivetrain has two 1 kw Flux2 motors with sealed bearings, active heat management and active venting for residual moisture &#8212; a necessity in this moistest of cities.</p>
<p>The acceleration sound, which mimics those of a gas-powered dirt bike but with a softer electronic tone, was a surprising plus. I didn’t realize how much I relied on my sense of sound to tell how fast I was going until I rode the Ubco.</p>
<p>The braking system was a bit touchy. It felt very sensitive to me, probably because hydraulic and regenerative brakes are operating together on the vehicle. There’s also a passive regenerative braking system, which I gather is what put the brakes on for me when I was just trying to coast down one of those mammoth hills.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187588" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187588" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2187588 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6043.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187588" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rebecca Bellan</p></div></p>
<p>Both the front suspension, 130 mm, and rear suspension, 120 mm, have a coil spring with a hydraulic dampener and have preload and rebound adjustment. In other words, the shocks are awesome. Even when I actively drove myself off sidewalks and over speed bumps, I could barely feel a thing.</p>
<p>To test its off-road capabilities, I took the bike to Cornwall Park, where I ran it at full speed on the grass, swerving between trees, flying over roots and rocks, doing doughnuts in the field. It was good fun and I felt completely in control of the vehicle. I can imagine why farmers have turned to the Work Bike.</p>
<p>When it was time to test out its use as a delivery bike, I packed the two saddlebags with books and groceries and took it for a spin. Still a great ride, although I was a little wobbly turning corners until I got the hang of it.</p>
<h2>Value</h2>
<p>Since the Ubco Adventure Bike doesn’t neatly fit into a specific bike category, it’s not a simple price comparison. An electric moped, like a Lexmoto Yadea or a Vespa Elettrica, could set you back anywhere from $2,400 or $7,000, respectively. Electric dirt bikes could cost anywhere from $6,000 to $11,000 for something like a KTM or Alta Motors. That said, Swedish electric motorbike startup Cake did just come out with its latest made specifically for city riding, the<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/electric-motorbike-company-cake-launches-the-makka-an-e-moped-for-city-riding-at-3500/"> Makka, at $3,500</a>. It looks a lot like the Ubco, but it&#8217;s a bit smaller.</p>
<p>With that in mind, the Ubco Adventure Bike costs $6,999 with a 2.1 kW power supply and $7,499 for a 3.1 kW power supply. Depending on what you want it for, I&#8217;d say it’s somewhere around mid-range for a bike like this. Since you&#8217;d probably use it for work-related activities, it could get a tax write-off. Plus, you want quality in a bike that’s down to do some heavy lifting, and Ubco has plenty of that. It’s not only a handy utility bike, but it’s also got some excellent tech under the proverbial hood, which we’ll get to later.</p>
<p>Ubco estimates a 10- to 15-year life expectancy, depending on use. Over-the-air software updates, replacing parts and full refurbishments can help keep the bike going for longer. The company encourages riders to send back the dead bikes because it&#8217;s committed to full product stewardship.</p>
<p>That said, if you wanted to buy a bike now, it’d be a preorder (unless your local Ubco dealer had some in stock). Ordering now could get you an Ubco by September if you live in the States. The company says it’s still feeling the effects of COVID, with high demand and a stretched supply chain causing delays. The preorder requires a $1,000 deposit.</p>
<p>Ubco also has a subscription model, which is mainly available for enterprise customers at the moment and priced on a case-by-case basis. However, it&#8217;s piloting subscriptions for individuals in Auckland and Tauranga before rolling the program out globally. Subscriptions will start at around NZD $300 per month for a 36-month term.</p>
<h2>Range</h2>
<p>The Adventure Bike comes with either the 2.1 kWh battery pack, which has around 40 to 54 miles of range, or the 3.1 kWh, with 60 to 80 miles.</p>
<p>The battery is run off a management system, called &#8220;Scotty,&#8221; to monitor real-time performance and safety. The battery, which is sealed with alloy and vented during use, is made with 18650 lithium-ion cells, which means it’s a powerful battery that can handle up to 500 charging cycles. Ubco says its batteries are designed to be disassembled at the end of life.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2187590" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187590" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2187590 size-full" style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6055.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187590" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rebecca Bellan</p></div></p>
<p>The 10 amp alloy fast charger can fuel the battery fully within four to six hours. You can charge it while it’s still in the vehicle by just connecting it to a power outlet, or you can unlock the battery and yank it out (it’s a little heavy) and charge it inside. Note: Charging is loud. Not sure if this is standard, but probably is.</p>
<p>I charged it every two to three days, but that will depend on use and where you are. It’s winter in Auckland, so a bit cold, which affects battery life, and the hills are brutal, which also use up a lot of battery life.</p>
<p>I’d ride it downtown and around my neighborhood every day, but I’d wager a delivery driver would need to charge it nightly. As I mentioned earlier, the battery can be removed for charging, so if you take it to work, you can always take it up to the office or wherever to charge while you’re doing other things.</p>
<h2>Tech features</h2>
<h3>Vehicle management system</h3>
<p>The vehicle runs off what Ubco calls its Cerebro vehicle management system, which integrates all electronic and electrical functions of the vehicles and provides control and updates via Bluetooth. Ubco builds with end of life in mind, so the CAN bus is isolated so future CAN devices can be easily integrated.</p>
<p>Now, one of my first questions, given the heftiness of this bike and the likelihood of gig economy workers who would ride it for work living in urban dwellings, was this: How can I ensure no one will steal this thing when it’s on the street, because there’s no way I’m lugging it up to my fifth-floor walkup?</p>
<p>Like I said, you can lock the wheel in place, which would make it far more difficult for someone to wheel it off. If someone did decide to capture the whole cumbersome vehicle, Ubco would be able to track it for you. Each Ubco bike has telemetry, aka a SIM card, hardwired inside, and that can help provide data that can be used for location, servicing, theft, safety, route planning, etc.</p>
<p>This VMS architecture is made for handling fleets via Ubco’s enterprise subscription vehicles, but it obviously has other uses, like providing peace of mind (personally, I’d still lock it up with chains, but I’m a New Yorker and trust no one). Obviously, if you think this telemetry is creepy, you can opt out, but it does come standard with subscriptions, allowing subscribers to track their bike&#8217;s location on the app.</p>
<h3>Display</h3>
<p><div id="attachment_2187591" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2187591" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2187591 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg 4032w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg?resize=150,113 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg?resize=300,225 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg?resize=768,576 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg?resize=680,510 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg?resize=1536,1152 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg?resize=2048,1536 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_6045.jpeg?resize=50,38 50w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2187591" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Rebecca Bellan</p></div></p>
<p>Mounted on the handlebar is an LCD display that shows speed, power levels and more. Also on the handlebars are switch controls for high or low beams, indicators and a horn. I found the indicators to be a bit sticky and sometimes I would slip and hit the horn. What I <i>wish</i> the handlebars also had was a mount for your phone so you could follow directions. I had my headphones in and was listening to Google Maps tell me how to get around, but that felt less safe and efficient.</p>
<h3>Turning it on</h3>
<p>You can turn the power on with a keyless fob by either clicking the button on the fob or the button on the handlebars. I will note that the keyless fob button is weirdly sensitive. At multiple points, I had it in my pocket with my phone or other pocket inhabitants and it must have knocked into the button, turning the vehicle off while I was riding it. Thankfully, that never happened anywhere busy, but that’s something to be wary about.</p>
<h3>App</h3>
<p>As I mentioned earlier, you could pair your phone, as well as other users&#8217; phones, to the bike using the app. The app allows you to choose learner mode or restricted mode, which controls ride settings; turn the bike and lights on and off; change the metrics; and check the status of things like battery life, speed and motor temperature. It&#8217;s basically all the info on the dash, but on an app. I didn&#8217;t really feel the need to use it.</p>
<h3>Lights</h3>
<p>The LED headlights are on at all times when the vehicle is turned on, but there&#8217;s also a high and low beam, as well as peripheral parking lights, all of which are designed for disassembly at the end of life. There are also LED rear, brake and number plate lights, as well as DOT-approved indicator lights.</p>
<h2>Other stuff</h2>
<p>Among the features that don’t fit neatly into the other categories, there’s the field kit, which is fastened to the lift-up seat and contains a user manual and tools to set up and maintain the 2X2, which is really handy. Usually, when people buy an Ubco bike, it comes in a box and there are “a few simple steps to follow to get it ready to ride.” There’s also an <a href="https://www.ubcouniversity.com/courses/how-to-set-up-your-new-2x2-2021-wrk-adv-bikes">UBCO University</a> course that shows how to set it up. If you buy from one of Ubco’s dealers, they’ll unpack it and set it up when you come to collect it.</p>
<h3>Maintenance</h3>
<p>Maintenance comes with the cost of a monthly subscription. Ubco has a network of technicians placed wherever the company sells its bikes if they&#8217;re in need of fixing. If there&#8217;s no authorized mechanic nearby, Ubco&#8217;s head office will work with customers to help them fix the bike. Ubco did not respond to information about how many authorized mechanics are in its network.</p>
<p>Again, being from New York, I&#8217;ve seen probably thousands of delivery riders on bikes and mopeds, oven mitts covered in a plastic bag taped onto the handlebars so drivers can keep their hands warm during the colder months. This bike can handle a hefty load for delivering goods, it&#8217;s quick and agile for weaving in and out of traffic, and it&#8217;s easy to ride and use.</p>
<p>The subscription offering, especially for enterprise, makes this a great city utility bike that can probably handle a range of weather conditions. I already know it can handle rain and mud, so all signs point to success in the sloshy, icy hell of a Northern city winter. And for the adventurer &#8212; the person who just wants to ride something sweet on- and off-road, out of the city and into the wilderness &#8212; this is also a great consumer ride that will last you quite a while.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/ubco-2x2-adventure-bike-review-utility-that-shreds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2187553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEC fines brokerage firms over email hacks that exposed client data</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/sec-fines-brokerage-firms-over-email-hacks-that-exposed-client-data/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/sec-fines-brokerage-firms-over-email-hacks-that-exposed-client-data/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carly Page]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission has fined several brokerage firms a total of $750,000 for exposing the sensitive personally identifiable information of thousands of customers and clients after hackers took over employee email accounts. A total of eight entities belonging to three companies have been sanctioned by the SEC, including Cetera (Advisor Networks, Investment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">The <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/sec/">U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission</a> has fined several brokerage firms a total of $750,000 for exposing the sensitive <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/personally-identifiable-information/">personally identifiable information</a> of thousands of customers and clients after hackers took over employee email accounts.</p>
<p>A total of eight entities belonging to three companies have been sanctioned by the SEC, including Cetera (Advisor Networks, Investment Services, Financial Specialists, Advisors and Investment Advisers), Cambridge Investment Research (Investment Research and Investment Research Advisors) and KMS Financial Services.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2021-169">a press release</a>, the SEC announced that it had sanctioned the firms for failures in their cybersecurity policies and procedures that allowed hackers to gain unauthorized access to cloud-based email accounts, exposing the personal information of thousands of customers and clients at each firm.</p>
<p>In the case of Cetera, the SEC said that cloud-based email accounts of more than 60 employees were infiltrated by unauthorized third parties for more than three years, exposing at least 4,388 clients&#8217; personal information.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Z504V3Hboe"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/pearson-to-pay-1m-fine-for-misleading-investors-about-2018-data-breach/">Pearson to pay $1M fine for misleading investors about 2018 data breach</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Pearson to pay $1M fine for misleading investors about 2018 data breach&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/pearson-to-pay-1m-fine-for-misleading-investors-about-2018-data-breach/embed/#?secret=Z504V3Hboe" data-secret="Z504V3Hboe" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The order states that none of the accounts featured the protections required by Cetera’s policies, and the SEC also charged two of the Cetera entities with sending breach notifications to clients containing “misleading language suggesting that the notifications were issued much sooner than they actually were after discovery of the incidents.”</p>
<p>The SEC’s order against Cambridge concludes that the personal information exposure of at least 2,177 Cambridge customers and clients was the result of lax <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/cybersecurity/">cybersecurity</a> practices at the firm.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>“Although Cambridge discovered the first email account takeover in January 2018, it failed to adopt and implement firm-wide enhanced security measures for cloud-based email accounts of its representatives until 2021, resulting in the exposure and potential exposure of additional customer and client records and information,” the SEC said.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The order against KMS is similar; the SEC&#8217;s order states that the data of almost 5,000 customers and clients were exposed as a result of the company’s failure to adopt written policies and procedures requiring additional firm-wide security measures until May 2020.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Investment advisers and broker-dealers must fulfill their obligations concerning the protection of customer information,&#8221; said Kristina Littman, chief of the SEC Enforcement Division&#8217;s Cyber Unit. &#8220;It is not enough to write a policy requiring enhanced security measures if those requirements are not implemented or are only partially implemented, especially in the face of known attacks.&#8221;</p>
<p>All of the parties agreed to resolve the charges and to not commit future violations of the charged provisions, without admitting or denying the SEC’s findings. As part of the settlements, Cetera will pay a penalty of $300,000, while Cambridge and KMS will pay fines of $250,000 and $200,000 respectively. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>Cambridge told TechCrunch that it does not comment on regulatory matters, but said it has and does maintain a comprehensive information security group and procedures to ensure clients&#8217; accounts are fully protected. Cetera and KMS have yet to respond.</p>
<p>This latest action by the SEC comes just weeks after the Commission ordered London-based publishing and education giant <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/pearson-to-pay-1m-fine-for-misleading-investors-about-2018-data-breach/">Pearson to pay a $1 million fine for misleading investors about a 2018 data breach</a> at the company.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/sec-fines-brokerage-firms-over-email-hacks-that-exposed-client-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196939</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forum Brands secures $100M in debt financing to acquire more e-commerce brands</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/forum-brands-secures-100m-in-debt-financing-to-acquire-more-e-commerce-brands/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/forum-brands-secures-100m-in-debt-financing-to-acquire-more-e-commerce-brands/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary Ann Azevedo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acquisitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forum Brands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[norwest venture partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[triplepoint capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Forum Brands, an e-commerce acquisition platform, announced today that it has secured $100 million in debt funding from TriplePoint Capital. The financing comes just over two months after the startup raised $27 million in an equity funding round led by Norwest Venture Partners. Brenton Howland, Ruben Amar and Alex Kopco founded New York-based Forum Brands [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary"><a href="https://www.forumbrands.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forum Brands</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, an e-commerce acquisition platform, announced today that it has secured $100 million in debt funding from </span><a href="https://www.triplepointcapital.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TriplePoint Capital</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The financing comes just over two months after </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the startup raised $27 million in an equity funding round led by Norwest Venture Partners.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brenton Howland, Ruben Amar and Alex Kopco founded New York-based Forum Brands in the summer of 2020, during the height of the COVID-19 pandemic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We’re buying what we think are A+ high-growth e-commerce businesses that sell predominantly on Amazon and are looking to build a portfolio of standalone businesses that are category leaders, on and off Amazon,” Howland told me at the time of the company’s last raise. “A source of inspiration for us is that we saw how consumer goods and services changed fundamentally for what we think is going to be for decades and decades to come, accelerating the shift toward digital.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since we covered the company in June, Forum Brands says it has acquired several new brands, including </span><a href="https://bonzapet.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bonza</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a seller of pet products, and</span><a href="https://simkarose.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Simka Rose</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a baby-focused brand specializing in eco-friendly products. Simka sells in the U.S. and the EU and is an example of how Forum is expanding globally, Amar said.</span></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rUqsooCnQI"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/forum-brands-raises-27m-as-crowded-amazon-roll-up-space-continues-to-heat-up/">Forum Brands raises $27M Series A as crowded Amazon roll-up space continues to heat up</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Forum Brands raises $27M Series A as crowded Amazon roll-up space continues to heat up&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/29/forum-brands-raises-27m-as-crowded-amazon-roll-up-space-continues-to-heat-up/embed/#?secret=rUqsooCnQI" data-secret="rUqsooCnQI" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Howland and Amar emphasize that the Forum team continues to focus on quality over quantity when evaluating potential acquisitions. Although they meet with 15-20 founders a week, they are selective in which companies they choose to acquire.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We continue to be a quality-first buyer, and not quantity-driven,” Amar said, noting that the company will still help a company build its brand even if it does not yet meet Forum’s quality threshold or if the founders are just not ready to sell.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new funds will be used to, naturally, acquire more e-commerce companies. As part of the debt financing, Sajal Srivastava, co-CEO and co-founder of TriplePoint Capital, will be joining Forum’s board of directors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are impressed not only by Forum’s long-term strategy and ability to leverage technology and deep collective e-commerce and M&amp;A experience but also by how Forum cultivates relationships with their sellers both before and after partnering with them,” he said in a written statement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the time of its June raise, Forum had about 20 employees. As of today, it has about 40.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forum’s technology employs “advanced” algorithms and over 100 million data points to populate brand information into a central platform in real time, instantly scoring brands and generating accurate financial metrics.</span></p>
<p>On August 31, we covered <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/olsam-raises-165m-to-buy-up-and-scale-consumer-and-b2b-amazon-marketplace-sellers/">the news</a> that on the heels of Heroes <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/31/uk-based-heroes-raises-200m-to-buy-up-more-amazon-merchants-for-its-roll-up-play/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announcing</a> a $200 million raise to double down on buying and scaling third-party Amazon Marketplace sellers, <em>another</em> startup out of London aiming to do the same announced some significant funding of its own. <a href="https://olsamgroup.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Olsam</a>, a roll-up play that is buying up both consumer and B2B merchants selling on Amazon by way of Amazon’s <a href="https://sell.amazon.com/fulfillment-by-amazon" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FBA fulfillment program</a>, closed on $165 million — a combination of equity and debt that it will be using to fuel its M&amp;A strategy, as well as continue building out its tech platform and to hire more talent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/forum-brands-secures-100m-in-debt-financing-to-acquire-more-e-commerce-brands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196733</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chrome Beta to experiment with a more powerful New Tab page, web highlights and search changes</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/chrome-beta-to-experiment-with-a-more-powerful-new-tab-page-web-highlights-and-search-changes/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/chrome-beta-to-experiment-with-a-more-powerful-new-tab-page-web-highlights-and-search-changes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chrome beta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freeware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google-Drive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search results]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web search]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google is launching a new version of its Chrome Beta browser today that&#8217;s introducing some fairly notable changes to its user interface and design. The browser will introduce an updated New Tab page, which will now include cards directing you back to past web search activities, instead of only a list of shortcuts to favorite [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google is launching a new version of its <a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/beta/">Chrome Beta browser</a> today that&#8217;s introducing some fairly notable changes to its user interface and design. The browser will introduce an updated New Tab page, which will now include cards directing you back to past web search activities, instead of only a list of shortcuts to favorite websites. Other changes aim to make it easier to navigate search results and to highlight and share quotes from the web.</p>
<p>The New Tab page&#8217;s update will be one of the first changes Chrome beta users may notice.</p>
<p>The idea behind this design change is about getting you back quickly to past web activities without a need to dive into your browsing history to remember which sites you had been using for things like recipes or shopping. It can also help you to return quickly to your recent documents list in Google Drive, in a handy bit of cross-promotion for Google services.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2196948" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2196948" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2196948" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="411" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png 2250w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?resize=150,91 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?resize=300,181 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?resize=768,465 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?resize=680,411 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?resize=1536,929 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?resize=2048,1239 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Docs_Module_Desktop.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2196948" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>The page will now feature what Google is calling &#8220;cards,&#8221; not just links, which could direct you to things like a recently visited recipe site where you had been browsing for ideas, a Google doc you need to finish editing, or a retailer&#8217;s website where you had left your shopping cart filled with things you may like to purchase at a later date. The latter ties into Google&#8217;s larger investment in online shopping, which has already seen the search giant trying to grab more market share in the space by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/04/21/google-switches-its-shopping-search-service-to-mostly-free-listings/">making product listings free</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-partners-with-shopify-on-online-shopping-expansion/">partnering with e-commerce platforms like Shopify.</a></p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bCUEp7TWGf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-partners-with-shopify-on-online-shopping-expansion/">Google partners with Shopify on online shopping expansion</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google partners with Shopify on online shopping expansion&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/18/google-partners-with-shopify-on-online-shopping-expansion/embed/#?secret=bCUEp7TWGf" data-secret="bCUEp7TWGf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Google is rightly concerned about Amazon&#8217;s surging advertising business, which is a large part of the retailer&#8217;s &#8220;Other&#8221; category that grew <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2021/amazons-advertising-business-surging-amid-industry-wide-ad-sales-boom-tech-giants/">87% year-over-year</a> to generate $7.9 billion in the second quarter. Now, it&#8217;s capitalizing on Chrome&#8217;s New Tab real estate to elevate shopping activity in the hopes of pushing users to complete their transactions.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Another change aims to make it easier to do web research. Google says that often, users searching for something on its platform will navigate to multiple web pages to find their answer. The new version of Chrome will experiment with a different way of connecting users to their search results by adding a row beneath the address bar on Chrome for Android that will show the rest of the results so you can navigate to other web pages without needing to hit the back button.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2196952" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2196952" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-2196952" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Webnotes_Mobile.gif?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2196952" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>A new &#8220;quote cards&#8221; experiment, also coming to Chrome Beta on Android, will allow users to create a stylized image for social sharing that features text found on websites. Taking a screengrab of a website&#8217;s text is something that&#8217;s already a common activity, and particularly for people who want to share a key point from a news article they&#8217;re reading with followers on platforms like Twitter, Facebook or Instagram. With this new feature, you&#8217;ll be able to long-press text to highlight it, then tap Share and select a template by tapping on the &#8220;Create Card&#8221; option from the menu.</p>
<p>All features are a part of the Chrome Beta browser. To enable experiments, you can type <em>chrome://flags</em> into the browser&#8217;s address bar or click on the Experiments beaker icon, and then enable the flags. The associated flags for these experiments are #ntp-modules flag (New Tab page), #continuous-search (search results changes) and #webnotes-stylize flag (quote cards).</p>
<p>Experiments don&#8217;t necessarily become Chrome features that roll out more broadly. Instead, they offer Google a way to capture large-scale user feedback about its new design ideas, so the features can be tweaked and fine-tuned before a public release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/chrome-beta-to-experiment-with-a-more-powerful-new-tab-page-web-highlights-and-search-changes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196918</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter is testing a new anti-abuse feature called &#8216;Safety Mode&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-safety-mode-harassment/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-safety-mode-harassment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Taylor Hatmaker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweetdeck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twitter&#8217;s newest test could provide some long-awaited relief for anyone facing harassment on the platform. The new product test introduces a feature called &#8220;Safety Mode&#8221; that puts up a temporary line of defense between an account and the waves of toxic invective that Twitter is notorious for. The mode can be enabled from the settings [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Twitter&#8217;s newest test could provide some long-awaited relief for anyone facing harassment on the platform.</p>
<p>The new product test introduces a feature called &#8220;Safety Mode&#8221; that puts up a temporary line of defense between an account and the waves of toxic invective that Twitter is notorious for. The mode can be enabled from the settings menu, which toggles on an algorithmic screening process that filters out potential abuse that lasts for seven days.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our goal is to better protect the individual on the receiving end of Tweets by reducing the prevalence and visibility of harmful remarks,&#8221; Twitter Product Lead Jarrod Doherty said.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2196998" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2196998" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2196998 size-large" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sm.jpg?w=680" alt="" width="680" height="382" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sm.jpg 1366w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sm.jpg?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sm.jpg?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sm.jpg?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sm.jpg?resize=680,382 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sm.jpg?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2196998" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Twitter</p></div></p>
<p>Safe Mode won&#8217;t be rolling out broadly — not yet, anyway. The new feature will first be available to what Twitter describes as a &#8220;small feedback group&#8221; of about 1,000 English language users.</p>
<p>In deciding what to screen out, Twitter&#8217;s algorithmic approach assesses a tweet&#8217;s content — hateful language, repetitive, unreciprocated mentions — as well as the relationship between an account and the accounts replying. The company notes that accounts you follow or regularly exchange tweets with won&#8217;t be subject to the blocking features in Safe Mode.</p>
<p>For anyone in the test group, Safety Mode can be toggled on in the privacy and safety options. Once enabled, an account will stay in the mode for the next seven days. After the seven-day period expires, it can be activated again.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In crafting the new feature, Twitter says it spoke with experts in mental health, online safety and human rights. The partners Twitter consulted with were able to contribute to the initial test group by nominating accounts that might benefit from the feature, and the company hopes to focus on female journalists and marginalized communities in its test of the new product. Twitter says that it will start reaching out to accounts that meet the criteria of the test group — namely accounts that often find themselves on the receiving end of some of the platform&#8217;s worst impulses.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Twitter announced that it was working on<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/twitter-is-eyeing-new-anti-abuse-tools-to-give-users-more-control-over-mentions/"> developing new anti-abuse features</a>, including an option to let users &#8220;unmention&#8221; themselves from tagged threads and a way for users to prevent serial harassers from mentioning them moving forward. The company also hinted at a feature like Safety Mode that could give users a way to defuse situations during periods of escalating abuse.</p>
<p>Being &#8220;harassed off of Twitter&#8221; is, unfortunately, not that uncommon. When hate and abuse get bad enough, people tend to abandon Twitter altogether, taking extended breaks or leaving outright. That&#8217;s obviously not great for the company either, and while it&#8217;s been slow to offer real solutions to harassment, it&#8217;s obviously aware of the problem and working toward some possible solutions.</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="e16ova89JC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/twitter-is-eyeing-new-anti-abuse-tools-to-give-users-more-control-over-mentions/">Twitter is eyeing new anti-abuse tools to give users more control over mentions</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter is eyeing new anti-abuse tools to give users more control over mentions&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/15/twitter-is-eyeing-new-anti-abuse-tools-to-give-users-more-control-over-mentions/embed/#?secret=e16ova89JC" data-secret="e16ova89JC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="QSQtBMno3i"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/twitter-claims-increased-enforcement-of-hate-speech-and-abuse-policies-in-last-half-of-2019/">Twitter claims increased enforcement of hate speech and abuse policies in last half of 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Twitter claims increased enforcement of hate speech and abuse policies in last half of 2019&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/19/twitter-claims-increased-enforcement-of-hate-speech-and-abuse-policies-in-last-half-of-2019/embed/#?secret=QSQtBMno3i" data-secret="QSQtBMno3i" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/twitter-safety-mode-harassment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goodcall picks up $4M, Yelp partnership to answer merchant inbound calls</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/goodcall-picks-up-4m-yelp-partnership-to-answer-merchant-inbound-calls/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/goodcall-picks-up-4m-yelp-partnership-to-answer-merchant-inbound-calls/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Hall]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personnel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recent Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob Summers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[call assistance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foothill Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goodcall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[index]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merus capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xoogler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yelp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2196339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Goodcall’s free cloud-based conversational platform leverages artificial intelligence to manage incoming business phone calls and boost customer service while assisting to other patrons.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Even without staffing shortages, local merchants have difficulty answering calls while all hands are busy, and <a href="https://goodcall.com">Goodcall</a> wants to alleviate some of that burden from America’s 30 million small businesses.</p>
<p>Goodcall’s free cloud-based conversational platform leverages artificial intelligence to manage incoming phone calls and boost customer service for businesses of all sizes. Former Google executive Bob Summers left Google back in January, where he was working on Area 120 — an internal incubator program for experimental projects — to start Goodcall after recognizing the call problem, noting that in fact 60% of the calls that come into merchants go unanswered.</p>
<p>“It’s frustrating for you and for the person calling,” Summers told TechCrunch. “Every missed call is a lost opportunity.”</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Goodcall announced its launch Wednesday with $4 million in seed funding led by strategic investors Neo, Foothill Ventures, Merus Capital, Xoogler Ventures, Verissimo Ventures and VSC Ventures, as well as angel investors including Harry Hurst, founder and co-CEO of Pipe.com, and Zillow co-founder Spencer Rascoff.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2196344" style="width: 356px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2196344" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2196344" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png?w=346" alt="" width="346" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png 816w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png?resize=76,150 76w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png?resize=153,300 153w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png?resize=768,1510 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png?resize=346,680 346w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png?resize=781,1536 781w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Mobile-Agent-settings.png?resize=25,50 25w" sizes="(max-width: 346px) 100vw, 346px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2196344" class="wp-caption-text">Goodcall mobile agent. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Goodcall</p></div></p>
<p>Restaurants, shops and merchants can set up on Goodcall in a matter of minutes and even establish a local phone number to free up an owner’s mobile number from becoming the business’ main line. The service is initially deployed in English and the company has plans to operate in Spanish, French and Hindi by 2022.</p>
<p>Merchants can choose from six different assistant voices and monitor the call logs and what the calls were about. Goodcall can also capture consumer sentiment, Summers said.</p>
<p>The company offers three options, including its freemium service for solopreneurs and business owners, which includes up to 500 minutes per month of Goodcall services for a single phone line. Up to five additional locations and five staff members costs $19 per month for the Pro level, or the Premium level provides unlimited locations and staff for $49 per month.</p>
<p>During the company’s beta period, Goodcall was processing several thousands of calls per month. The new funding will be used to continue to offer the free service, hire engineers and continue product development.</p>
<p>In addition to the funding round, Goodcall is unveiling a partnership with Yelp to tap into its database of local businesses so that those owners and managers can easily deploy Goodcall. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/21/yelp-says-more-than-500000-new-businesses-opened-in-past-year.html">Yelp data shows</a> that more than 500,000 businesses opened during the pandemic. The company pulls in from Yelp a merchant’s open hours, location, if they offer Wi-Fi and even their COVID policy.</p>
<p>“We are partnering with Yelp, which has the best data on small businesses, and other large distribution channels to get our product to market,” Summers said. “We are bringing technology into an industry that hasn’t innovated since the 1980s and democratizing conversational AI for small businesses that are the main driver of job creation, and we want to help them grow.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GGfWcQrXpd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/ai-startup-investment-is-on-pace-for-a-record-year/">AI startup investment is on pace for a record year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;AI startup investment is on pace for a record year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2021/06/09/ai-startup-investment-is-on-pace-for-a-record-year/embed/#?secret=GGfWcQrXpd" data-secret="GGfWcQrXpd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/01/goodcall-picks-up-4m-yelp-partnership-to-answer-merchant-inbound-calls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2196339</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
